<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570420-20">
               <interp inst="t17570420-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570420-20" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570420-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570420"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570420-20" type="date" value="17570420"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570420-20-off99-c167" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-20-defend202 t17570420-20-off99 t17570420-20-verdict101"></join>
         

               <p>161. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17570420-20-defend202" type="defendantName">
                  Hannah 
                  Philips 
               <interp inst="t17570420-20-defend202" type="surname" value="Philips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-defend202" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-defend202" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17570420-20-deflabel98" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-20-defend202 t17570420-20-deflabel98"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17570420-20-off99" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-off99" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-off99" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing on the <rs id="t17570420-20-cd100" type="crimeDate">11th of March, 1757</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-20-off99 t17570420-20-cd100"></join>, ten yds. of silk lace, called blond-lace, value. 15 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17570420-20-victim204" type="victimName">
                     Henry 
                     Dean 
                  <interp inst="t17570420-20-victim204" type="surname" value="Dean"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-victim204" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-victim204" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17570420-20-victim206" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Potinger 
                  <interp inst="t17570420-20-victim206" type="surname" value="Potinger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-victim206" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-victim206" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            .</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-20-person207">
                  Walter 
                  Post 
               <interp inst="t17570420-20-person207" type="surname" value="Post"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person207" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person207" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Messieurs Dean and Potinger.</p>

               <p>Q. In what capacity?</p>

               <p>Post. I serve them as shopman; on the 11th of March last, about five or six in the evening, the prisoner came into the prosecutors shop and asked me to shew her some blond lace, and I thereupon handed the drawer of blond lace before her, and she handled several pieces of lace which were in the drawer.</p>

               <p>Q. In what manner were the pieces done up?</p>

               <p>Post. They were rolled upon a card, and the prisoner asked me the price of several of the laces, and took some of them out of the drawer and looked at them, some times at one, and some times at another in each hand, and I told her the prices of several of them; she did not buy any, but convey'd out of the drawer two cards or pieces of lace that were therein, and I believe she had one piece of lace in her left hand, when she took the other two out of the drawer with her right hand; she laid the pieces of lace she took out of the drawer on the counter betwixt the drawer and herself.</p>



               <p>Q. How far was the drawer from the edge of the counter ?</p>

               <p>Post. I believe it might be about a foot; after that she sent herself as it were forward over the counter towards the drawer, and took hold on the drawer and drew it nearer to her, and then she brought up with her right hand one of those cards of lace, which she had laid on the counter, and conveyed it under her cardinal.</p>

               <p>Q. Did she continue in that same posture, or alter her position ?</p>

               <p>Post. She was bending then, and she bent up again and look'd me in the face, fearing (as I imagined) that I saw her; she then bent herself over the counter again, and pulled back her cardinal with her left hand, and then drew the piece of lace out with her right from under her cardinal, and laid it on the counter again betwixt herself and the drawer, from whence she had before taken it.</p>

               <p>Q. What did she say ?</p>

               <p>Post. She said nothing to me. After that she put her hand in the drawer and examined several pieces that were there, and passed some time away, but never offered to buy any laces that were in the drawer, and only asked the price of some she had examined; I told her the piece; then she bent herself over the counter again and took with her right hand the same piece of lace as she had before put down, and carried it with a quick motion under her cardinal, and put it as it were under her arm, and held it with her arm, and then she put her hand directly into the drawer, and taking hold of the first piece of lace that lay uppermost, she took it out and asked the price of it.</p>

               <p>Q. Was that the same drawer ?</p>

               <p>Post. The same drawer. I told her the price was sixpence half-penny a yard; she then desired me to cut her off a yard, which I did; she then asked me for some striped ribbons.</p>

               <p>Q. Was this at the same time?</p>

               <p>Post. This was directly following it. I leaned back into the window, and took the first piece of ribbon there out of the window and shewed it her; she desired me to cut off a yard without asking the price of it. I did, and folded up the yard of blond-lace and the yard of ribbon together in one paper, and gave them into her hand; then she desired to know what these was to pay. I told her twelve-pence half-penny, that was six-pence half-penny for the yard of blond lace, and six-pence the ribbon,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200023"></xptr> she paid me the same, and then went out of the shop, and as soon as she was gone out at the door I call'd to 
               <persName id="t17570420-20-person208">
                  John 
                  Mortimore 
               <interp inst="t17570420-20-person208" type="surname" value="Mortimore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person208" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person208" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17570420-20-person209">
                  Godfrey 
                  Major 
               <interp inst="t17570420-20-person209" type="surname" value="Major"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person209" type="given" value="Godfrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person209" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; 
               <persName id="t17570420-20-person210">
                  John 
                  Mortimore 
               <interp inst="t17570420-20-person210" type="surname" value="Mortimore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person210" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person210" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is my masters rider, and was talking to the said Mr. Major backwards in the shop.</p>

               <p>Q. What is Major?</p>

               <p>Post. He is a furrier of whom we buy muffs, and I desired them to step forward immediately, and told them what had happen'd and directly jumped over the counter, followed the prisoner, and overtook her about five doors from my masters, and got her back into my masters shop, by telling her she had left something in the shop, and as soon as I got her into the shop, I directly said to Mortimore, I charge this lady with taking a piece of lace; she directly said to me, Me with a piece of lace, I have not got any such thing, neither do I know any thing about it. I directly said you have, and there is no occasion for you to deny it, for the lace you have got; and then I turn'd back her cardinal, and found the lace hold between her body and her arm, (produced in court, the card of lace so took from her) and he described the manner in which she held it, putting his hand close to his body, and sticking the lower part of the lace between his arm and body, and deposed that he took the lace himself on the prisoner, and from between her body and arm under her cardinal, and gave it to the said 
               <persName id="t17570420-20-person211">
                  John 
                  Mortimore 
               <interp inst="t17570420-20-person211" type="surname" value="Mortimore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person211" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person211" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>

               <p>Q. Were there any things besides under her arm?</p>

               <p>Post. No, there were not.</p>

               <p>Q. Where did she put the paper with the lace and ribbon she brought of you?</p>

               <p>Post. I cannot be positive where she put it, but I imagine she put that in her pocket</p>

               <p>Q. What quantity is there of the lace on the card you took from her?</p>

               <p>Post. There are ten yards.</p>

               <p>Q. What is the length of the card ?</p>

               <p>Post. I believe it is about five inches long.</p>

               <p>Q. Was it of that same sort of lace that she bought ?</p>

               <p>Post. No, of a different lace about half inch wide like what he produced in court, and the lace which the prisoner took was about an inch and three quarters wide.</p>

               <p>Q. What is that lace worth that you charge the prisoner with taking ?</p>

               <p>Post. It is worth about two shillings per yard to any shop-keeper in London. 
               <persName id="t17570420-20-person212">
                  John 
                  Mortimore 
               <interp inst="t17570420-20-person212" type="surname" value="Mortimore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person212" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person212" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             carried the lace up to Mr. Dean, and when he came down and the case was told to him, he sent for a constable, and charged the constable with the prisoner, and I left them and went forward to secure the box of lace that I had left upon the counter, and likewise the other card, that the prisoner had moved from the drawer, and laid on the counter, and then I left Mr. Dean and the prisoner talking together.</p>

               <p>Cross Examination.</p>

               <p>Q. What did the prisoner ask for at first coming into the shop?</p>

               <p>Post. She asked for blond lace.</p>

               <p>Q. How many pieces might there be in the drawer?</p>

               <p>Post. I believe there might be between ten and twenty cards.</p>

               <p>Q. Is this a whole piece, and what is the length?</p>

               <p>Post. I believe it is, the pieces don't run in particular lengths, sometimes they contain more, sometimes less; I believe there was none cut off the card, but it was as my masters bought it.</p>

               <p>Q. Was the end of it so as it is now ?</p>

               <p>Post. I believe it came to my masters so as this is.</p>

               <p>Q. Was there any lace in that drawer of larger quantities than this?</p>

               <p>Post. I can't justly say whether there was or not; I believe there was some of this narrow lace that ran longer in length, and it might be more in bulk.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you observe the prisoner had any other parcel with her when she came into the shop?</p>

               <p>Post. Not that I saw.</p>

               <p>Council. You say you imagine the person might think you saw her take the lace, and then she presently afterwards laid it down and took it up again?</p>

               <p>Post. I do so, and that when she saw I took no manner of notice of her first motion, she ventur'd to take the second resolution.</p>

               <p>Council. Then you imagine she saw herself detected in the first attempt, and after that took it up a second time ?</p>

               <p>Post. To be sure I do imagine she thought I saw her, or she would not have laid it down again.</p>

               <p>Q. Describe the manner of the first taking.</p>

               <p>Post. The first was done with a sort of a slide, and the second with a sudden jirk.</p>

               <p>Q. In what position was you at the time?</p>

               <p>Post. I was right before her all the time.</p>

               <p>Q. How did she put it down again ?</p>

               <p>Post. She drew her cardinal back with her left<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200024"></xptr> hand, and slid the card of lace on the counter with her right, and after she had examined several other cards of lace, then she put her right hand by the side of the drawer, and took the card of lace up again with a sudden jirk, and put it in under her cardinal.</p>

               <p>Q. How wide is your counter?</p>

               <p>Post. It is about a yard wide.</p>

               <p>Council. When you called her back, she came you say very readily ?</p>

               <p>Post. She did so.</p>

               <p>Q. What was done upon that ?</p>

               <p>Post. I immediately charged her with having the piece of lace.</p>

               <p>Q. How far had you followed her ?</p>

               <p>Post. About five ors from ours.</p>

               <p>Q. Where is your shop ?</p>

               <p>Post. It is in Cheapside.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you go before her to your shop ?</p>

               <p>Post. No, I kept behind her, fearing she should drop the lace.</p>

               <p>Q. Did she hold the lace in her hand ?</p>

               <p>Post. No, the lace was not in her hand.</p>

               <p>Q. Have you always given the same account of this as now?</p>

               <p>Post. Yes.</p>

               <p>Q. Had you never a doubt whether you took the lace from out of her hand or from under her arm ?</p>

               <p>Post. No, I never had any doubt about it, I was always very positive that I took it from under her arm.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you remember when you was before the Lord-mayor ?</p>

               <p>Post. Yes, very well.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you then express any doubt whether you took it out of her hand or from under her arm?</p>

               <p>Post. No, I never was in any doubt at all about it; when the prisoner was asked by the Lord-mayor what she had to say for herself, her answer was, that the lace was in her hand. I directly contradicted her, and said it was underneath her cardinal. I was asked by some gentlemen there, whether her hand was under her cardinal or not. I said I was not positive to that.</p>

               <p>Q. Was you never asked the question, whether you took the lace out of her hand or not?</p>

               <p>Post. I was never asked that, or at least I did not understand it so.</p>

               <p>Q. When she came into the shop again with you, and before you took the card from her, what did she say?</p>

               <p>Post. She denied having it, saying she had not got it, and knew nothing of it.</p>

               <p>Q. After this did she tell you who she was, or desire to send for any acquaintance, or whether she had not been buying things at another shop?</p>

               <p>Post. I believe she did, but cannot positively say; I have heard she mention'd something of that kind to Mr. Dean when I was not in the fore shop.</p>

               <p>Q. Did not she say she denied with Mr. Belchier?</p>

               <p>Post. I believe she did.</p>

               <p>Q. Was her request of sending for any acquaintance absolutely denied her.</p>

               <p>Post. I can't say that it was absolutely denied her. I did not hear what answer Mr. Dean gave her.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you remember Mrs. Dean and her daughter coming down stairs?</p>

               <p>Post. I remember Mrs. Dean's coming down, but as for a daughter she has none.</p>

               <p>Q. Can you swear you did not hear Mr. Dean deny her sending for any person living?</p>

               <p>Post. I can, I did not.</p>

               <p>Q. Who was in the shop at the time?</p>

               <p>Post. Mr. Mortimore and 
               <persName id="t17570420-20-person213">
                  Godfrey 
                  Major 
               <interp inst="t17570420-20-person213" type="surname" value="Major"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person213" type="given" value="Godfrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person213" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>

               <p>Q. Were any persons sent for?</p>

               <p>Post. I believe none were sent for, but the person was immediately taken to the Mansion-House to be examined before the Lord mayor.</p>

               <p>Q. What do you mean by saying you can't say she was positively refused sending for any of her friends?</p>

               <p>Post. I can't be positive what answer Mr. Dean made her.</p>

               <p>Q. What did she say before the Lord-mayor?</p>

               <p>Post. She only said she had the lace in her hand.</p>

               <p>Q. Did she give no account how she came to have it in her hand?</p>

               <p>Post. No.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-20-person214">
                  John 
                  Mortimore 
               <interp inst="t17570420-20-person214" type="surname" value="Mortimore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person214" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person214" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Messieurs Dean and Potinger, I am employ'd principally as their rider. I was in the back part of their shop on the 11th of last month, a little after five in the afternoon, talking to 
               <persName id="t17570420-20-person215">
                  Godfrey 
                  Major 
               <interp inst="t17570420-20-person215" type="surname" value="Major"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person215" type="given" value="Godfrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person215" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard Mr. Post say, Mr. Mortimore, pray step forward here, for there is a thief. I came to the door and look'd out, and saw Mr. Post speak to the lady, the prisoner, and she turn'd round, and he followed her very close; when they came into the shop, he said, Mr. Mortimore, this lady has stolen a card of blond lace, on which she said, I have no lace I'll assure you; he said don't deny it Madam, for you have it, then he drew back her cardinal, and there I saw the card of blond lace sticking between her arm and her body; he took it from her and look'd at it, and gave it to me; then I look'd at it, and saw it mark'd with my master's private mark, and the maker's name, T. E. or W. E. and it contained<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200025"></xptr> ten yards. I asked her how she came to take the lace, she said she did not intend to take it. I said I would carry it up stairs to Mr. Dean, who would certainly send for a constable; on which she followed me to the bottom of the stairs, and said pray Sir don't, consider me, I never will offend in this way again. I afterwards went up stairs to Mr. Dean and told him the affair, who came down along with me and order'd me to go for a constable. I went to the Nag's Head tavern where the porters are, for Mr. King, a porter, to go for one, and came back and staid at the shop till the beadle of the ward came and took her into his custody, in order to carry her before the Lord-mayor, but I did not go with them to the Mansion-House.</p>

               <p>Cross Examination.</p>

               <p>Q. How long have you liv'd with the prosecutors?</p>

               <p>Mortimore. I have liv'd with them from the 30th of last June.</p>

               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say when you mentioned sendin g for a constable?</p>

               <p>Mortimore. She said she never would offend in this way again.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you remember when Mr. Dean came down, whether she wanted to send for any of her friends?</p>

               <p>Mortimore. I do, she desir'd Mr. Dean would send for Mr. Ironside or Mr. Belchier, and she mention'd some friends, but I can't remember who. He told her he would not, but as the thing was so clear on her, he would carry her before the Lord-mayor, and she might send there for whom she would.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you remember any thing of Mrs. Dean and another lady coming down stairs?</p>

               <p>Mortimore. I do.</p>

               <p>Q. What did Mr. Dean say to them?</p>

               <p>Mortimore. The prisoner desired they would petition for her, and she never would do so again; the ladies did compassionate her, and Mr. Dean said to them, it is my business to look after this matter, and sent them up stairs.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-20-person216">
                  William 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17570420-20-person216" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person216" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person216" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a porter. On the 11th of last month I was sent for by the last witness to call a constable. I went and brought one to Mr. Dean's shop; there was that lady (pointing to the prisoner) there, and I heard her say to Mr. Dean, pray Sir, I beg you would forgive me, for I never did such a thing before in my life.</p>

               <p>Humphry Ralph. I am about sixteen years of age. I live with Mess. Dean and Potinger, and I was in the shop on the 11th of March, but not when the lady was detected; I came in afterwards, there were Mr. Dean, Mr. Mortimore, Mr. Major, Mrs. Dean, and the ladies that were visiting at Mr. Dean's there, and Mr. Dean desired I would go for a constable, and as I was going out the lady, the prisoner, beg'd she might be forgiven, and said she never did such a thing before, and this she spoke several times.</p>

               <p>Q. What were the words she made use of?</p>

               <p>Ralph. She beg'd he would have compassion on her, and not send her away, and said she never did such a thing before.</p>

               <p>Cross Examination.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you hear her say she had taken the card of lace by a mistake, before you heard her say those words?</p>

               <p>Ralph. I came in almost when she was going to be sent away; after she was committed to the constable I heard her say she had other things, and took it amongst them; but not at that time.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you hear it said by Mr. Dean, or Mr. Potinger, that she had said she had taken it by mistake, as soon as she was charged with it?</p>

               <p>Ralph. I have heard it has been given out so, after she was charged with stealing it; but I did not hear her say so.</p>

               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>

               <p>I am intirely innocent of any intention of stealing; I dined at Mr. Belchier's that day, from whence I went to Mr. Piggot's, and bought a pair of gloves for a lady; from thence I went to the prosecutor's shop, and bought a yard of ribbon for myself, and a yard of blond lace, which I paid for; there lay a great many pieces of lace upon the counter, and in taking up my things I took up the lace, for which I am prosecuted, inadvertently, and went out of the shop. I had not gone far before a man came and said I had left something behind me in the shop, and thereupon I went back and asked what it was; then he directly took the blond lace out of my hand, and charged me with having stolen it. It never was under my arm. I beg'd he would let me send for my friends, and they would testify to him who and what I was. This they would not permit, and I applied to a couple of ladies, which I have heard since were Mrs. Dean and her sister, and beg'd of them to ask Mr. Dean to do it; he said nothing should prevail upon him; then I beg'd of him to send for Mr. Piggot; they said they<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200026"></xptr> would send for nobody, but charged a constable with me, and carried me to the Mansion House, where my Lord-mayor not being at home, they carried me to Wood-street Compter. I had three other little parcels with me, a pair of gloves; a yard of ribbon, and a yard of blond lace, which were produced by her in court.</p>



               <p>Q. to Post. Had the prisoner two or three little parcels in her hand, which she laid on the counter while she was looking at the drawer of lace, that she had bought some where else?</p>

               <p>Post. I did not see one parcel; I am positive there was not one lying on the counter.</p>

               <p>Q. When you took her back had she any parcel in her hand?</p>

               <p>Post. No; I saw no parcel she had, during the whole time.</p>

               <p>Q. When you brought her back, did she say she took it inadvertently?</p>

               <p>Post. She said she did not know that she had it.</p>

               <p>Q. from a juryman. Might not the drawer be so high, between you and her, that it might cover a little parcel from your sight?</p>

               <p>Post. I am positive that I saw no parcel, and that there was none put by her on the counter. I saw the two pieces of lace that lay down between the drawer and herself, and if there had been the least parcel besides, I must have seen it.</p>

               <p>Q. How deep is the drawer?</p>

               <p>Post. I believe it not quite a foot deep, but near it.</p>

               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-20-person217">
                  William 
                  Hodges 
               <interp inst="t17570420-20-person217" type="surname" value="Hodges"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person217" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person217" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mr. Piggot, a haberdasher. He lives about a dozen or fourteen doors from Mess. Dean and Potinger. I remember the prisoner coming to our shop on a Friday in the afternoon, about five o'clock; I don't know the day of the month.</p>

               <p>Q. Was it the day you heard Mr. Potinger lost some blond lace?</p>

               <p>Hodges. It was the same day; she bought a pair of gloves, cost 13 d.</p>

               <p>Q. Look at these (which were produced ) are these the gloves she bought?</p>

               <p>Hodges. This is the sort of leather. I matched them to a pattern glove?</p>

               <p>Q. How were they folded when she took them away?</p>

               <p>Hodges. Just as they are now ( doubling them together.) She asked for some blond lace. I told her it was on the other side, but she said none would suit her. A gentleman's servant came in to buy a pair of gloves for a lady, and I went backwards.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you recollect any thing of her buying any ribbon?</p>

               <p>Hodges. No.</p>

               <p>To her Character.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-20-person218">
                  William 
                  Belchier 
               <interp inst="t17570420-20-person218" type="surname" value="Belchier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person218" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person218" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; I remember her being before the Lord-mayor in the evening, when she was fetch'd from the Compter, and what past there. There was the witness Post there.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you know whether he was asked by any body, whether this blond lace was taken from under her arm?</p>

               <p>Belchier. I particularly ask'd him that question myself, and I'll give the reason why I did ask him. This young lady I have known I believe eighteen years. I had and have still a great regard for her family. I was at the Pope's-Head Tavern that evening, where Mr. Ironside came to me, and said I am come to tell you of a very odd affair. Miss 
               <persName id="t17570420-20-person219">
                  Hannah 
                  Philips 
               <interp inst="t17570420-20-person219" type="surname" value="Philips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person219" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person219" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is in the Compter, she has been at a haberdasher's, and has bought some ribbon and a little piece of lace, and through a mistake she has taken away a piece that she did not buy, and they have charged a constable with her and sent her to the Compter. I desired him to go to Messieurs Dean and Potinger, and give my service, and tell them if they would be so kind as to release her from the Compter. I would be answerable for her appearing before any magistrate; he brought me word back they could not do it; then I sent to the Lord-mayor, and desired he would be so good as to send for her from the Compter, and hear what she was charged with that night, which he comply'd with. I was there when she was examined before the Lord-mayor, and heard her say she carry'd a piece of lace out in her hand which she did not pay for, and I particularly asked the first witness who was examined, whether he found it in her hand or not, to satisfy indeed my own mind, because if I thought her the least guilty I would not have appear'd here on her behalf. I said are you sure where you took this piece of lace from her, he said from under her cardinal; I ask'd was it in her hand or not, he stop'd; then I ask'd him was it under her cardinal or not, it was; did you take it from out of her hand or not, he said I can't tell upon my word whether it was or not. I then went away satisfied that her own story might be true. I have known her from a small infant.</p>

               <p>Q. What is your opinion of her?</p>

               <p>Belchier. I believe none can exceed her as to her integrity and honesty, and as to other things I believe<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200027"></xptr> she is very careless and negligent. I never had any reason to doubt her honesty.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you think her capable of robbing people in the manner she has been charged ?</p>

               <p>Belchier. I do not, and from all the conversation I have had with Messieurs Dean and Potinger, I could never bring any thing to my mind to induce me to believe that she is guilty of what she is charged with.</p>

               <p>Cross Examination.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you hear all the evidence given before the Lord-mayor?</p>

               <p>Belchier. I heard part of it, but not all. She did insist before his Lordship that she had taken it thro' inadvertency.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you hear all Post's evidence there ?</p>

               <p>Belchier. I did not, her excuse there was, that she said, God bless me, I have got it, and I did not know I took it.</p>

               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17570420-20-person220">
                  Edward 
                  Ironside 
               <interp inst="t17570420-20-person220" type="surname" value="Ironside"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person220" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person220" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was before the Lord-mayor, and heard the prisoner say, that when she went into the shop she had taken up a piece of blond lace by accident, or thro' inadvertency.</p>

               <p>Q. How long have you known her?</p>

               <p>Ironside. I believe I have known her ten or twelve years.</p>

               <p>Q. What is her general character?</p>

               <p>Ironside. She has always bore the character of a very honest sober girl, and from the character that she has borne, and from her behaviour that I have known, I do not think her capable of committing the fact laid to her charge. I am so far satisfied with her honesty, that I can't think she did this with intent to defraud. I heard Mr. Belchier ask Mr. Post the question, whether the prisoner had the lace in her hand, or whether it was conceal'd under her arm, and he said he could not tell whether it was or was not, that was his answer; he said it was under her cardinal.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-20-person221">
                  Richard 
                  Neve 
               <interp inst="t17570420-20-person221" type="surname" value="Neve"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person221" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a haberdasher.</p>

               <p>Q. Have not you known mistakes often happen in people's taking things that did not belong to them and carrying them away.</p>

               <p>Neve. I have had two instances of it, one within these three months; one was a lady came into my shop and wanted a pair of silk mittins, I took some out of a drawer and shew'd her. I believe there might be seven or eight pair on the counter. She asked me the price of a pair, I fitted them on, and told her the price was four shillings or four and six-pence; she said can't you take no less, and paid me for them, and took them away. I thought she had taken no more; she return'd in about an hour after, I was in the shop, and said Sir, I have made a very great mistake, you remember I was here to buy a pair of mittins, and I have got two pair instead of one, and delivered one of them to me again.</p>

               <p>Q. How long have you known the prisoner?</p>

               <p>Neve. I have known her I believe seventeen or eighteen years.</p>

               <p>Q. What is your opinion of her?</p>

               <p>Neve. My opinion is that she never could be intentionally guilty of the thing laid to her charge.</p>

               <p>Q. Has she bought things of you?</p>

               <p>Neve. She has.</p>

               <p>Colonel 
               <persName id="t17570420-20-person222">
                  Colliton
               <interp inst="t17570420-20-person222" type="given" value="Colliton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person222" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner from a child.</p>

               <p>Q. In what manner has she behaved?</p>

               <p>Colliton. With great honesty and integrity.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you think she is capable of doing such an act as is laid to her charge?</p>

               <p>Colliton. I don't think she is.</p>

               <p>Captain Best. I have known her between three and four years.</p>

               <p>Q. What is your opinion of her character?</p>

               <p>Best. She has been upon a visit at my house near four months at a time, and in that time I have trusted her with a considerable charge (when I was obliged to go down into the country) with my writings, bonds, money and every thing that I had in my house, and I believe at that time there might be above 1400 l. or near 1500 l in the house; when I came home I found every thing as I left them. She was mistress of my keys, and from what I know of her I verily believe I myself would be guilty of what she is charged with as soon as Miss Philips would. I know she is a little careless, it is a thing I have often told her of, in leaving things about in one place or another where she did not know afterwards to find them.</p>

               <p>Mrs. Ironside. I have known her fourteen or fifteen years, and during that time she has frequently been with me for several weeks together, and has behaved with great integrity and honesty, and I never heard any thing against her character, neither have I the least reason to believe any thing against it; she is a giddy girl, and I have often told her she would one time or other lose her things.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you think she would be guilty of stealing the value of fifteen shillings intentionally?</p>

               <p>Mrs. Ironside. Nothing should have brought me before this court, if I had thought such things of her.</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200028"></xptr>Mrs. Belchier. I have known the prisoner fifteen years, and am of opinion that she is a very honest and good girl.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you think her capable of stealing intentionally any thing to wrong any body?</p>

               <p>Mrs. Belchier. If I did I would not have come here. I know she bought my cousin a pair of gloves that day, which I ordered her to buy, and I paid her for them next morning. I think these are the gloves, which she has produced, they were folded up as they are now.</p>

               <p>Miss Belchier. I have known Miss Philips from a little girl, and have been very well acquainted with her these seven years; she has always bore an exceeding good character, or else I should not have appeared here on her behalf.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you think her capable of committing intentionally the fact laid to her charge?</p>

               <p>Miss Belchier. I think her incapable of it, but think her from inattention and absence of mind to be liable to make a mistake.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-20-person223">
                  Mary 
                  Neve 
               <interp inst="t17570420-20-person223" type="surname" value="Neve"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person223" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person223" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner ever since she was born, I never knew any thing of her but what was extremely good, I think her as incapable of doing it as myself.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you think she would intentionally do it in order to wrong any body?</p>

               <p>M. Neve. No, I do not, I would trust her with all I have.</p>

               <p>Mrs. Thompson. I live with Mrs. Roberts of Hackney, I remember Miss Philips being at her school a year and upwards.</p>

               <p>Q. During that time what character did she bear?</p>

               <p>Mrs. Thompson. A very good one, I never heard the least ill of her.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-20-person224">
                  Ann 
                  Bell 
               <interp inst="t17570420-20-person224" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person224" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person224" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew Miss Philips from a child, she has a very good character, I always thought her a person of honesty and integrity; she has been visiting at my house for weeks together, I think she is not capable of doing intentionally what is laid to her charge.</p>

               <p>Miss Clark. I have known Miss Philips about sixteen years.</p>

               <p>Q. What is your opinion of her honesty?</p>

               <p>Miss Clark. My opinion is that she is very honest. I have been many months with her, and she with me backwards and forwards. I never knew any thing of her but that she has been always very honest.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you think she would intentionally wrong any body of fifteen shillings?</p>

               <p>Miss Clark. I don't think she could.</p>

               <p>Council for the Crown. Where did her father and mother live?</p>

               <p>Miss Clark. They lived in Thames-street, and since her mother lived at Hackney, where she kept a house for lodgers, and now they live at Peckham, and deal in linen drapery.</p>

               <p>Miss Cole. I have known the prisoner a dozen years, I never knew any ill of her, nor don't think her capable intentionally to wrong any body, and I would trust her with any thing I have.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-20-person225">
                  William 
                  Pointz 
               <interp inst="t17570420-20-person225" type="surname" value="Pointz"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person225" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; I have known the prisoner betwixt seven and eight years, and I never knew any harm of her, or thought her capable of doing the thing laid to her charge intentionally.</p>

               <p>Q. What is your general opinion of her?</p>

               <p>Pointz. I would trust her with any thing I have.</p>

               <p>Dr. Cobourn. I have known the prisoner ever since she was a child.</p>

               <p>Q. What is her general character?</p>

               <p>Cobourn. She has a very good character so far as ever I heard or was sensible of, and from my own observation of her I think her to be a woman of honesty and virtue, and that she is incapable of doing the thing laid to her charge intentionally.</p>

               <p>Mr. Kindleside. I have known the prisoner between seven and eight years, and she has been frequently at my house a week at a time and more, I never had the least suspicion of her being guilty of any thing of this kind, I always look'd upon her to be extremely honest.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you think her capable of the crime laid to her charge?</p>

               <p>Kindleside. No, I do not.</p>

               <p>Mrs. Cobourn. I have known Miss Philips above ten years, I always thought she behaved in a very proper manner, and believe her incapable of wronging or injuring any one intentionally.</p>

               <p>Miss 
               <persName id="t17570420-20-person226">
                  Ann 
                  Cobourn 
               <interp inst="t17570420-20-person226" type="surname" value="Cobourn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person226" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person226" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner some time, I think her incapable to wrong any one intentionally, and I never heard she had done any ill thing.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you think she would take fifteen or twenty shillings value from any body?</p>

               <p>Miss Cobourn. No, I do not think she intentionally would.</p>

               <p>Thomas Lane. I have known the prisoner about four years and a half, and she has as good a character as any young lady I ever heard of; and from my own observation of her I think she deserves the character she has always had.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you think her capable of doing what is laid to her charge?</p>

               <p>Lane. I don't think she would do it by any means in the world intentionally.</p>

               <p>Fran. Cook. I have known the prisoner four or<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200029"></xptr> five years, and I always look'd upon her to be a young lady deserving every body's good word, and never thought her capable of what is laid to her charge.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-20-person227">
                  Philip 
                  How 
               <interp inst="t17570420-20-person227" type="surname" value="How"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person227" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-person227" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner ever since she was a girl, and all her family.</p>

               <p>Q. What is your opinion of her as to honesty?</p>

               <p>How. I have always thought, with regard to honesty and integrity, no person ever deserved a better character; her father and mother were very careful to instill such principles into her, that would naturally lead her to behave with integrity.</p>

               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570420-20-verdict101" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-verdict101" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>

               <p>And after the jury so brought in their verdict, the prosecutors by their council moved the court to shew what favour they could in this case to the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570420-20-punish102" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-punish102" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-20-punish102" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-20-defend202 t17570420-20-punish102"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
