<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17540530-33">
               <interp inst="t17540530-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540530-33" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540530-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540530"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540530-33" type="date" value="17540530"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540530-33-off158-c333" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-33-defend389 t17540530-33-off158 t17540530-33-verdict162"></join>
         
               <p>338. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17540530-33-defend389" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17540530-33-defend389" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-33-defend389" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-33-defend389" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17540530-33-off158" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540530-33-off158" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-33-off158" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               that he, together with one 
                     <persName id="t17540530-33-person390">
                        John 
                        Higgs 
                     <interp inst="t17540530-33-person390" type="surname" value="Higgs"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540530-33-person390" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540530-33-person390" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  on the <rs id="t17540530-33-cd159" type="crimeDate">24th of December</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-33-off158 t17540530-33-cd159"></join>, about the hour of three in the night of the same day, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17540530-33-victim392" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Pinkey 
                        <interp inst="t17540530-33-victim392" type="surname" value="Pinkey"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540530-33-victim392" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540530-33-victim392" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-33-off158 t17540530-33-victim392"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did break and enter, and one copper pot, value 10 s. 40 pewter plates, value 27 s. seven pewter dishes, value 7 s. one copper saucepan, value 5 s. one pewter chamber-potand other things, the goods of the said Thomas, did steal, take, and carry away
            </rs>. +.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-33-person393">
                  Thomas 
                  Pinkey 
               <interp inst="t17540530-33-person393" type="surname" value="Pinkey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-33-person393" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-33-person393" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17540530-33-crimeloc160">St. Margaret's-Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17540530-33-crimeloc160" type="placeName" value="St. Margaret's-Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17540530-33-crimeloc160" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-33-off158 t17540530-33-crimeloc160"></join>and <rs id="t17540530-33-viclabel161" type="occupation">keep a publick-house</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-33-victim392 t17540530-33-viclabel161"></join>, the sign of the Cock: I was robbed of the things mentioned in the indictment, and several other thingsbut by who I could not tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were these things?</p>
               <p>Pinkey. Some of the things were in the yard, and some of them in a room that joins to the house: the people who took them got over into the yard, as we supposeby seeing the marks of feet on the wall, and after that got into the room: the window was openand the shutter unbolted, so we imagined they handed the things out that way.</p>
               <p>Q. You have not told me when this was; was it in October, November, or December?</p>
               <p>Pinkey. I think it was November.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see these things again?</p>
               <p>Pinkey. No, nor ever heard of them.</p>
               <p>Q. How did they get into that room ?</p>
               <p>Pinkey. In at the door, I suppose. I advertised the thingsand was sent for to justice Fielding's, and they told me the people were taken up that robbed me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-33-person394">
                  Daniel 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17540530-33-person394" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-33-person394" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-33-person394" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . A short time before ChristmasHiggs, I, and the prisoner, went to this gentleman's house; we had been there several times; there were things lay in the yard continuallyso we got over the wall, and there were a quantity of pewter, brass, and copper in the yard, pots and saucepans, and the like; with that we went into the room joining to the house, lifted up the sash, and unbolted the outside shutter, and this Higgs got in and handed them out to Smith and I.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the door locked?</p>
               <p>Lewis. No, that was open, the window shutter was bolted; we got all we could light of, copper and brass, or any thing else: there was a large pottage pot and saucepan, the pottage pot was in the yard, and some of the plates and dishes were in the room; there were seven or eight dishes. The prisoner and I stood close to the window, it is but a low one, and bundled the things up, and carried them to Smith's house; he deals in this way; he keeps a bit of an iron shop in Great Earl-Street, Seven Dials. He melted the pewter downand the copper and brass he knocked to pieces; so that nobody could distinguish what they were.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you been acquainted with Smith?</p>
               <p>Lewis. About two years and an half; whatever we stole we brought to his house, and he had a candle burning all night to see what we got: he was not always with us, but came to help us to carry off the things.</p>
               <p>Q. What was you taken up for?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175405300028"></xptr>Lewis. The prisoner impeached me about his majesty's chamber guns that fire off on his birth-day: he was selling one of them, and being stopped, gave an account where I was, accordingly they came and took me.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he indicted for that?</p>
               <p>Lewis. No, not here, that was in the county of Surrey.</p>
               <p>The prisoner said nothing in his defence, but called the following witnesses.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-33-person395">
                  Edward 
                  Bowdler 
               <interp inst="t17540530-33-person395" type="surname" value="Bowdler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-33-person395" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-33-person395" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner these ten years; I am a publican, and live in Long-Acre, and have known him for these three years last past since he settled for himselfand always bore a very good character for ought I know; I always found him such in all the dealings I had with him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-33-person396">
                  Thomas 
                  Liddel 
               <interp inst="t17540530-33-person396" type="surname" value="Liddel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-33-person396" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-33-person396" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a barber and peruke-makerand live in Earl-Street, Seven Dials; I have known him about fifteen years.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you lived near him?</p>
               <p>Liddel. I lived within three or four doors of him for 17 years last past, and never knew he did any thing amiss.</p>
               <p>Thomas Street. I have known him above two years; I keep the Barley-Mow in Bow-StreetCovent-Garden.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sufficiently acquainted with him to give him a character?</p>
               <p>Street. No farther than I have bought pewter pots of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Does he make them?</p>
               <p>Street. No, I believe very few men do: he always dealt honestly by meand was counted an honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-33-person397">
                  Joseph 
                  Timewell 
               <interp inst="t17540530-33-person397" type="surname" value="Timewell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-33-person397" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-33-person397" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about three years; I am a publican, and live in Long-Acre, and keep the sign of the Coachmaker's Arms : I have dealt with him for pots, and paid a market pricewhat I paid to other people, and never heard any harm of him in my life.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540530-33-verdict162" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540530-33-verdict162" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was detained to be tried on other indictments.</p>
            </div1>
