<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17520408-17">
               <interp inst="t17520408-17" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520408-17" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520408-17" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520408"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520408-17" type="date" value="17520408"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520408-17-off92-c103" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520408-17-defend134 t17520408-17-off92 t17520408-17-verdict96"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520408-17-off92-c105" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520408-17-defend137 t17520408-17-off92 t17520408-17-verdict96"></join>
         
               <p>225, 226. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17520408-17-defend134" type="defendantName">
                  Margaret, <rs id="t17520408-17-deflabel91" type="occupation">wife of 
                        <persName id="t17520408-17-person135">
                           John 
                           O Brian 
                        <interp inst="t17520408-17-person135" type="surname" value="O Brian"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17520408-17-person135" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17520408-17-person135" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        </persName>
                     
                     </rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520408-17-defend134 t17520408-17-deflabel91"></join>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-17-defend134" type="surname" value="O Brian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-17-defend134" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-17-defend134" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17520408-17-defend137" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Boyle 
                  <interp inst="t17520408-17-defend137" type="surname" value="Boyle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-17-defend137" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-17-defend137" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17520408-17-off92" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520408-17-off92" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-17-off92" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch, value 3 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17520408-17-victim139" type="victimName">
                           Frederick 
                           Zeidenburg 
                        <interp inst="t17520408-17-victim139" type="surname" value="Zeidenburg"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520408-17-victim139" type="given" value="Frederick"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520408-17-victim139" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520408-17-off92 t17520408-17-victim139"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the house of 
                     <persName id="t17520408-17-person140">
                        Elizabeth 
                        Smallman 
                     <interp inst="t17520408-17-person140" type="surname" value="Smallman"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520408-17-person140" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520408-17-person140" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , spinster
            </rs>, <rs id="t17520408-17-cd93" type="crimeDate">March 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520408-17-off92 t17520408-17-cd93"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520408-17-person141">
                  Frederick 
                  Zeidenburg 
               <interp inst="t17520408-17-person141" type="surname" value="Zeidenburg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-17-person141" type="given" value="Frederick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-17-person141" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17520408-17-viclabel94" type="occupation">cabinet-maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520408-17-victim139 t17520408-17-viclabel94"></join>, and live in Great Rupert-street. I was going into the Fox ale-house in Drury-lane, on the 10th of March, about nine at night; (I use that house) 
               <persName id="t17520408-17-person142">
                  Mary 
                  Boyle 
               <interp inst="t17520408-17-person142" type="surname" value="Boyle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-17-person142" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-17-person142" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was at the door; she asked me, if I would give her a pint of beer; I said I did not care if I did; there was one of my countrymen with me, a German</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175204080008"></xptr>Q Had you ever seen her before?</p>
               <p>Zeidenburg. No, my Lord, as I remember; she followed me in, and took up the pint and drank, then she said, will you go along with me? I said I can't leave my company; she said again, will you go? at last I was deluded.</p>
               <p>Q. Did your countryman go with you?</p>
               <p>Zeidenburg. No, he did not; he could not speak a word of English.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to leave your companion behind, who could not talk English?</p>
               <p>Zeidenburg. I said to him, I was coming back presently; the prisoner and I went to <placeName id="t17520408-17-crimeloc95">No. 3. in Orange-court</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17520408-17-crimeloc95" type="placeName" value="No. 3. in Orange-court"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520408-17-crimeloc95" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520408-17-off92 t17520408-17-crimeloc95"></join>, the house of 
               <persName id="t17520408-17-person143">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Smallman 
               <interp inst="t17520408-17-person143" type="surname" value="Smallman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-17-person143" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-17-person143" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; before she went in there, she picked up the other prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you agree she should go too?</p>
               <p>Zeidenburg. No, my Lord, we went into a room up one pair of stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. Did that O Brian go against your inclination?</p>
               <p>Zeidenburg. I thought her a friend of the others, and I did not say she should or should not go.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a publick-house?</p>
               <p>Zeidenburg. It is not, they sell liquor, it is a notorious bawdy-house. When we had been in the room about ten minutes, one of the women asked me what it was o'clock, after that the other asked me; I took out my watch, 
               <persName id="t17520408-17-person144">
                  Mary 
                  Boyle 
               <interp inst="t17520408-17-person144" type="surname" value="Boyle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-17-person144" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-17-person144" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             snatched it out of my hand, and they both ran away with it immediately down stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you shewed them your watch before?</p>
               <p>Zeidenburg. No, they might see the string hang out of my pocket; I cry'd out, Stop thief! I have lost my watch; they took away the candle; I could not find the stairs, but ran against the wall; they got out of the house before I could get a candle to find the way down stairs; when I got down I asked one Mrs. Bourne (a woman that was in the Gatehouse on this affair, but is discharged) where they were; she said she knew nothing of the matter; at that time one Robinson a thief-taker came in, who asked me to describe the woman, which I did; then he said he believed he could find them; we went to the Plough and drank together; we could not find them then. On the 14th of March, I advertised the watch with two guineas reward, after which Robinson sent for me, and said, he and others could help me to the woman and watch too Then we went to Rag-fair, and got a warrant from Justice Gore, and came to the house where I lost my watch in Orange-court, Drury-lane; it was dark; from thence to the Plough again; in a little time they brought me the two prisoners, and the old woman that is released; I said I could not swear to them, for having been drinking about, my head was quite muddled; the old woman said, after the women were gone, why don't you keep them two women? they are the woman that robbed you of your watch; then the thief-takers ran out after them, but could not find them.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you found your watch again?</p>
               <p>Zeidenburg. No, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any of the women confess any thing about it?</p>
               <p>Zeidenburg. No, I have not heard any of them say any thing about it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520408-17-person145">
                  Margaret 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17520408-17-person145" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-17-person145" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-17-person145" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , otherwise Pierce. I live in Orange-court, and rent a room in this house of Smallman's. I saw the two prisoners come in along with the prosecutor on the 10th of March, about nine o'clock; a few minutes after they went up stairs, 
               <persName id="t17520408-17-person146">
                  Margaret 
                  O Brian 
               <interp inst="t17520408-17-person146" type="surname" value="O Brian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-17-person146" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-17-person146" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came down, and asked for a bottle of ale; I told her there was none in the house, she must go out and fetch it; she went out and fetched it, and carried it up; then she came down again, and said, he had got no money about him; she desired to know where Mrs. Smallman was, saying, if he had no money, he had money's worth. Mrs. Smallman desired he might come down stairs; I saw the prisoners both run out together; the prosecutor came into my room; after that he came down stairs, and sat down in a chair; I asked him what he waited for; he said, the two women would come back again quickly; he staid there six or seven minutes; after which, he said, I have been robbed of my watch; I desired him to make himself easy, saying, I would endeavour to help him to it again ; I went out again, and found O Brian; I desired he might have his watch; she said, he offered half a crown for the use of something, and said, they would not give it him without half a crown each, saying, he had had the use of them, and they would have a shilling for the liquor also; her meaning was, that he had pawned it to her for that money; then I said, give it me, least the people that lodge in the house should come into trouble, and you see the man is heavy in liquor, that I may give it to him again; she gave it to me directly; then I came back, and the man was gone; I undressed myself and went to-bed, and heard nothing of it till the 12th; then Mrs. Smallman said to me, I had no business with it,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175204080009"></xptr> and made me give it her; after which she wanted to know where she could sell it: then Margaret O Brian and I went to a Cutler, in Holborn, (
               <persName id="t17520408-17-person147">
                  William 
                  Reason 
               <interp inst="t17520408-17-person147" type="surname" value="Reason"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-17-person147" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-17-person147" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) and sold it for forty six shillings; she received the money, two guineas and four shillings.</p>
               <p>Q. What had you of it?</p>
               <p>M. Edwards. I had fourteen shillings and sixpence of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you taken up upon this?</p>
               <p>M. Edwards. I was, and committed, and in prison about a fortnight, and admitted an Evidence before the justice.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520408-17-person148">
                  Thomas 
                  Rush 
               <interp inst="t17520408-17-person148" type="surname" value="Rush"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-17-person148" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-17-person148" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prosecutor works along with me, he told me on the Wednesday morning he had been robbed of his watch by a couple of men in Drury-Lane; I said to him, it is my belief, it was by a couple of women in some house of ill-same; then he owned it was so , at a bawdy-house, but was a stranger in the place, then I advised him to advertise it as lost and not stole, and wrote the advertisement out for him (it was advertised, lost near the Fox in Drury-Lane) I saw the old woman and the two prisoners at the Plough in Drury-Lane, the two prisoners were discharged, upon his saying he could not sware to them, but the old woman was committed to the Gatehouse for further examination. I heard her say the two prisoners were the persons that robb'd him of his watch.</p>
               <p>O Brian's defence.</p>
               <p>I was taken up in Bow-street about this watch, and taken to the Plough in Drury-Lane, the prosecutor came in: I pull'd my hat off; he looked at me, and said he could not sware to me.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17520408-17-verdict96" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520408-17-verdict96" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
