<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17511016-26">
               <interp inst="t17511016-26" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511016-26" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511016-26" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17511016"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511016-26" type="date" value="17511016"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17511016-26-off126-c178" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-26-defend224 t17511016-26-off126 t17511016-26-verdict130"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17511016-26-off126-c179" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-26-defend226 t17511016-26-off126 t17511016-26-verdict130"></join>
         
               <p>573, 574. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17511016-26-defend224" type="defendantName">
                     Emanuel 
                     Clark 
                  <interp inst="t17511016-26-defend224" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-26-defend224" type="given" value="Emanuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-26-defend224" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17511016-26-defend226" type="defendantName">
                     Weston 
                     Rakes 
                  <interp inst="t17511016-26-defend226" type="surname" value="Rakes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-26-defend226" type="given" value="Weston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-26-defend226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17511016-26-off126" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17511016-26-off126" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-26-off126" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               robbing 
                     <persName id="t17511016-26-victim227" type="victimName">
                        Thomas 
                        Tipping 
                     <interp inst="t17511016-26-victim227" type="surname" value="Tipping"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17511016-26-victim227" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17511016-26-victim227" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-26-off126 t17511016-26-victim227"></join>
                     </persName>
                    on the king's high way of a hat, value 5 s. one penknife, value a penny, and one halfpenny in money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17511016-26-cd127" type="crimeDate">September 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-26-off126 t17511016-26-cd127"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175110160016"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-26-person228">
                  Thomas 
                  Tipping 
               <interp inst="t17511016-26-person228" type="surname" value="Tipping"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-26-person228" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-26-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17511016-26-viclabel128" type="occupation">surgeon</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-26-victim227 t17511016-26-viclabel128"></join>, and live in <placeName id="t17511016-26-crimeloc129">Hatton Garden</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17511016-26-crimeloc129" type="placeName" value="Hatton Garden"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17511016-26-crimeloc129" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-26-off126 t17511016-26-crimeloc129"></join>. On Sunday September 15, between twelve and one at night, about the middle quarter of Hatton Garden. I was coming home I was collared by two persons, with this expression, d - n your eyes, deliver your money, or I'll blow your brains out. I can swear 
               <persName id="t17511016-26-person229">
                  Weston 
                  Rakes 
               <interp inst="t17511016-26-person229" type="surname" value="Rakes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-26-person229" type="given" value="Weston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-26-person229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was one of them, he took hold on me first; out of one of my breeches pockets they took a halfpenny and a penknife, from another a case of lancets and a bunch of keys. Upon my request, Rakes gave me the lancets and keys again. Then they said they must change hats with me; Rakes took off my hat, put his on my head, and bid me a good night; then they ran away. A penknife, which he lost that night, was produced and deposed to.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it light?</p>
               <p>Tipping. There was a lamp on each side me; Rakes faced one of them. They were taken on the Monday; I had word of it; I went to Clerkenwell Bridewell on the Tuesday morning. As soon as I got in, I pointed at Rakes and said, there is one of them. They were carried before Justice Fielding, where they both confessed the fact.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that confession put in writing?</p>
               <p>Tipping. It was not.</p>
               <p>Q. What did they say?</p>
               <p>Tipping. Rakes said Clark took the halfpenny and that he himself took the case of lancets and changed hats; he said I gave him my hat, but I did not.</p>
               <p>Clark said he was equally guilty with Rakes ; ( an old hat produced in court). Rakes owned this hat to be his, and that he left it with me; and that they sold my hat in Rag Fair for four shillings and a pot of beer.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that halfpenny all you had about you?</p>
               <p>Tipping. I had more money, but I had put that in my breast pocket, where they did not search.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you say as to Clark?</p>
               <p>Tipping. I believe him to be the other, but I will not swear to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Had they any arms ?</p>
               <p>Tipping. I saw none but two sticks.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-26-person230">
                  Samuel 
                  Philipson 
               <interp inst="t17511016-26-person230" type="surname" value="Philipson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-26-person230" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-26-person230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I took the two prisoners at the end of Fleet-market, the Monday in the last Sessions. I knew Clark before. I searched his pockets, and in his right hand pocket I found that penknife the prosecutor has sworn to. I was directed to Mr. Tipping on Tuesday morning, by a person who he had told of his being robbed, and he said he believed he should know one of the persons: said I, Do you know your knife? then he described it, saying, there was a flaw at the point of it. (which there was.) We went with them before Justice Fielding the next morning, where Rakes said, Sir, I will tell the truth, adding, Mr. Tipping said we jumped from the step of a door, but we crossed the road, laid hold of him, and robbed him of a hat, knife, and a halfpenny. He was asked if this was his hat which he left with Mr. Tipping; he said it was. The Justice then asked Clark what he had to say for himself; he said he could not deny but both of them robbed the gentleman. When they came away from thence, Clark d - d the other, adding, You might have saved your life, but now you have hanged us both. There were four of us to take them.</p>
               <p>Tipping. I have made enquiry since, and find Rakes to be of a very honest family, and that he had bore an extreme good character. I believe, by his behaviour, that this was his first fact.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-26-person231">
                  William 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17511016-26-person231" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-26-person231" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-26-person231" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I assisted the constable in going before the Justice. I heard the prisoners both confess as beforementioned.</p>

               <p>The prisoners had neither of them any thing to say.</p>
               <p>To Rakes's Character.</p>
               <p>Joseph-Nicholas Smith. I have known him above these six years. He has had an opportunity at our house, by coming to his aunt who lives with us, of taking things of value, but we never missed any thing. He is a very ignorant lad.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-26-person232">
                  George 
                  Randolph 
               <interp inst="t17511016-26-person232" type="surname" value="Randolph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-26-person232" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-26-person232" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him from his birth, but not much of him for these four years last past. I never heard any thing amiss of him before now.</p>
               <p>Mr. Reynolds. I have known him these twelve years, and I always looked upon him to be an ignorant harmless boy. I verily think he is defective in his understanding. He was errant-boy to my father about four years ago. I never heard any thing amiss of him before this.</p>
               <p>Mr. James. His family lives next door to me. He is now an apprentice to a hatter. All the time he was at home I never heard any thing amiss before this.</p>
               <p>Mr. Leaper. I have seen him several times at his father's, and knew nothing amiss of him then, but know very little of him since he has been apprentice.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-26-person233">
                  Charles 
                  Newil 
               <interp inst="t17511016-26-person233" type="surname" value="Newil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-26-person233" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-26-person233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have not known much of him since put apprentice, but he behaved well before.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17511016-26-verdict130" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17511016-26-verdict130" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17511016-26-punish131" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17511016-26-punish131" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-26-defend224 t17511016-26-punish131"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-26-defend226 t17511016-26-punish131"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
