<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17520218-4">
               <interp inst="t17520218-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520218-4" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520218-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520218"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520218-4" type="date" value="17520218"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520218-4-off18-c96" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520218-4-defend102 t17520218-4-off18 t17520218-4-verdict23"></join>
         
               <p>4. 
               
                  <persName id="t17520218-4-defend102" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Ballard 
                  <interp inst="t17520218-4-defend102" type="surname" value="Ballard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520218-4-defend102" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520218-4-defend102" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for the <rs id="t17520218-4-off18" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520218-4-off18" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520218-4-off18" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17520218-4-victim104" type="victimName">
                           Jones 
                           Dawling 
                        <interp inst="t17520218-4-victim104" type="surname" value="Dawling"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520218-4-victim104" type="given" value="Jones"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520218-4-victim104" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520218-4-off18 t17520218-4-victim104"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <placeName id="t17520218-4-crimeloc19">on the high seas, about 15 leagues, from the town of Kelsey in the county of York</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17520218-4-crimeloc19" type="placeName" value="on the high seas, about 15 leagues, from the town of Kelsey in the county of York"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520218-4-crimeloc19" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520218-4-off18 t17520218-4-crimeloc19"></join>, within the Jurisdiction of the Admiralty of England
            </rs>, <rs id="t17520218-4-cd20" type="crimeDate">May 10, 1751</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520218-4-off18 t17520218-4-cd20"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520218-4-person105">
                  Hugh 
                  Heyney 
               <interp inst="t17520218-4-person105" type="surname" value="Heyney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520218-4-person105" type="given" value="Hugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520218-4-person105" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was <rs id="t17520218-4-deflabel21" type="occupation">master of a fishing vessel</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520218-4-defend102 t17520218-4-deflabel21"></join> that belonged to one Mr. Bloys, Jones Dawling was an <rs id="t17520218-4-viclabel22" type="occupation">apprentice on board the vessel</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520218-4-victim104 t17520218-4-viclabel22"></join>; the prisoner ordered him to prepare breakfast for the ship's company, he went about it and did it, according to his orders: either in not stirring fast enough, or what I don't know, the prisoner took up a quarter of a firkin, about three quarters of a pound weight, and flung it at the deceased, not with great violence: it hit him on the fore part of the head, near the temple, the minute he received it, he clapp'd his hands to the side of his head, and said, O you have killed me, you have killed me! he lived about 12 hours afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you believe he died of that wound?</p>
               <p>Heyney. No, I believe he did not; he did his duty six hours after that, and eat afterwards: he received the blow about eight o'clock in the morning, and about 10 minutes after 8 at night he died.</p>
               <p>Q. Did there appear any bruise on his head?</p>
               <p>Heyney. No, there did not; he seemed very drowsey and ill, and stirred very slow, before he received the blow,</p>
               <p>Q. Was the half firkin full or empty ?</p>
               <p>Heyney. It was empty, it was used to put bait in.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you been acquainted with the prisoner at the bar?</p>
               <p>Heyney. About 4 years, he is a very sober man.</p>
               <p>Q. How had he used to behave to you?</p>
               <p>Heyney. He never used me ill, he always made me know my distance, as other masters do servants.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see him strike the boy before?</p>
               <p>Heyney. No, I never did in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520218-4-person106">
                  Benjamin 
                  Baster 
               <interp inst="t17520218-4-person106" type="surname" value="Baster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520218-4-person106" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520218-4-person106" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a foremast hand on board the vessel the prisoner was in; I remember in the month of April, between the hours of 7 and 8 in the morning, the prisoner ordered the deceased to put the fish into the kettle; he bid him stir, he did not stir fast enough to his mind; the prisoner threw a piece of a tub at him straight forward; he was about 14 feet from the deceased, it struck him near the fore part of his head, as he stood sideways to the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he throw it in a passion?</p>
               <p>Baster. He did, the poor lad said O Lord! I am dead! he went on with his work, and died about ten minutes after eight at night.</p>
               <p>Q. When was he buried?</p>
               <p>Baster. He was buried about ten the next day, upon a place called Spoon-Point, that is the first land we were at we sowed him up in 2 Bakers sacks and dug a hole in the ground by the prisoners order.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175202180019"></xptr>Q. Did you see any wound on the deceased's head?</p>
               <p>Baster. I looked on his head and there was no wound at all; I don't think the blow hurt him so as to be the occasion of his death.</p>
               <p>Q. Recollect what evidence you gave at Harwich ?</p>
               <p>Baster. It was to the same purport I do now.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you think he died of?</p>
               <p>Baster. I can't tell, God almighty called him away.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520218-4-person107">
                  James 
                  Dean 
               <interp inst="t17520218-4-person107" type="surname" value="Dean"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520218-4-person107" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520218-4-person107" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an apprentice to Mr. Bloys of Harwich, the master of this vessel: I was in April last under the command of the prisoner; the deceased got up in the morning, and the prisoner ordered him to put some fish in the kettle, he did not stir brisk enough, he called to him 2 or 3 times, he did not seem to stir, after he had stood at the kettle a good while, he takes up a quarter firkin and heav'd it at him not very hard, he was about 14 or 15 feet distance from him, it hit him on the temple, he said, O Lord, my head aches : then the prisoner being in a passion took a piece of rope about the bigness of my finger, and licked him about the back and loyns for about a minute, the boy liv'd 12 hours after this, I saw him after he was dead, and felt, and looked all about his head, and could see no wound.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you think was the occasion of his death ?</p>
               <p>Dean. I can't think he died of that blow, I hope to go under the prisoners command again if he is acquitted.</p>
               <p>Q. Were was this?</p>
               <p>Dean. It was upon deck.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after he flung this firkin at him was it that he struck him with the rope.</p>
               <p>Dean. Immediately after he beat him for crying: I thought it something extraordinary that he should die so suddenly: I was with the deceased the evening before he died, he went down to his cabbin about 3 in the afternoon: he went forward in the vessel, and laid his hand on his head, and said, I shall die, for master Ballard has killed me.</p>
               <p>Q. Who heard this?</p>
               <p>Dean. Only one man and me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you examined before?</p>
               <p>Dean. I was at Harwich.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you there swear that you thought it was the cause of his death?</p>
               <p>Dean. We thought the firkin had done him some damage, because he complained of his head, but I did not hear that was the cause of his death.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you think when he died?</p>
               <p>Dean. I don't know; I looked over his forhead and aback, and could not see a wound or any part discolour'd, he had laid in his cabbin about 3 hours, then he was sent for to come out by the prisoner, and was speechless.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. How did the prisoner behave to him ?</p>
               <p>Dean. Always very kind, only when he did not do as he would have him, he was sometimes in a passion; this was done in a passion, and it did not knock the boy down when it hit him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520218-4-person108">
                  Arthur 
                  Everit 
               <interp inst="t17520218-4-person108" type="surname" value="Everit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520218-4-person108" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520218-4-person108" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I did not see the thing flung, I saw Dawing about 4 hours before he died, the first complaint was, that his head ach'd: about an hour after that he said he should die, his master Ballard had killed him: I could not perceive whether he was sensible or not, these were the last words I heard him speak: I looked upon him after he was dead and saw no bruises.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520218-4-person109">
                  John 
                  Moore 
               <interp inst="t17520218-4-person109" type="surname" value="Moore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520218-4-person109" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520218-4-person109" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about 8 or 9 years, I have been in company with him since April last, I had some conference about the death of this lad 3 months ago: and hearing he had killed this boy, went to Mr. Bloys's, to whom I turned the deceased over, and told Mr. Bloys I heard Ballard had killed the boy; the prisoner came to me, and begg'd of me not to take him up, saying, if I did, he must be hanged, and own'd he knocked him down with a bait tub; then he lay sulky on the deck after that; then he went and licked him with a ratling. 4 times double, the bigness of my finger: after that he sent for Mr. Bloys to come to me; Mr. Bloys had got the gout : Mr. Bloys said the prisoner was a very usefull man, and gets me a great deal of money, and if I took him up he must be hang'd; he said he knew the prisoner had kill'd the boy, I insisted upon Mr. Bloys's taking the deceased up again, or I would : I went directly to the Mayor, and got a Warrant, and took the prisoner up: he own'd before the Mayor he did kill the boy, but did not do it wilfully; this was on a Saturday, and on the Monday the Mayor called a court at the Town-hall, when those lads, the other witnesses, came there, and made affidavit, that the prisoner did kill the boy.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever said, you'd have the prisoner's blood?</p>
               <p>Moore. No, I never did: I said, blood required blood.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you make an information of this affair?</p>

               <p>Moore. As soon as ever I knew it: Lieutenant 
               <persName id="t17520218-4-person110">
                  Farr
               <interp inst="t17520218-4-person110" type="given" value="Farr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520218-4-person110" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was the first that informed me of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any wound on the head, or body, when the body was taken up?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175202180020"></xptr>Moore. I can't say there was any mark on either.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I said to all these witnesses on board, look on him, and see if there is any wound upon him, speak the truth when you go home, and if you think I wrong'd this lad, don't let a drop of blood lie upon me; they all said, master, it could be no such thing, it could not happen from that ; I never saw the Deceased's countenance change till about three or four in the afternoon.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520218-4-person111">
                  Thomas 
                  Basket 
               <interp inst="t17520218-4-person111" type="surname" value="Basket"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520218-4-person111" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520218-4-person111" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Mr. Corbell's head brewer at Harwich : I know Mr. Moore, he keeps a publick house at Harwich : I had some discourse with him concerning the prisoner last Michaelmas Day at night. I went to see the prisoner, and we sent for some beer to the White Horse at Harwich. When I went home, my master sent me to Mr. Alcock's, at the Spread Eigle ; there was Mr. Moore drinking a pint of Bumbo; three of us spent sixpence, as we were walking about the prisoner there, Moore said, you sent for beer from the White Horse for him, but d - n my soul I'll have Ballard's life for it, I have been acquainted with Mr. Moore ever since I have been at Harwich, that is about 6 years; he never had a good character in his life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520218-4-person112">
                  Ann 
                  Bloys 
               <interp inst="t17520218-4-person112" type="surname" value="Bloys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520218-4-person112" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520218-4-person112" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was master of my husband's vessel, I remember the time the prisoner returned from fishing, I asked him how the boy came by his death, and how he was taken; they told me he was taken suddenly in the morning, and died at night; the prisoner is a very honest sober man, I don't think he would designedly do any body harm; I know this Moore to be a very worthless fellow, and one that bears a very bad character.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520218-4-verdict23" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520218-4-verdict23" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
