<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17540717-24">
               <interp inst="t17540717-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540717-24" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540717-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540717"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540717-24" type="date" value="17540717"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540717-24-off117-c196" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-24-defend243 t17540717-24-off117 t17540717-24-verdict120"></join>
         
               <p>370. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17540717-24-defend243" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Mary 
                     Lewis 
                   otherwise <rs id="t17540717-24-alias-5" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-24-defend243 t17540717-24-alias-5"></join>Oats</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-defend243" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-defend243" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-defend243" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17540717-24-deflabel116" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-24-defend243 t17540717-24-deflabel116"></join>, was indicted <rs id="t17540717-24-off117" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-off117" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-off117" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               for stealing ten 36 shilling pieces and 3 guineas, the money of John Knight, privately and secretly from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17540717-24-cd118" type="crimeDate">July 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-24-off117 t17540717-24-cd118"></join>.*</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My name is 
               <persName id="t17540717-24-person245">
                  Ann 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17540717-24-person245" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person245" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person245" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Court. You have pleaded to that of 
               <persName id="t17540717-24-person246">
                  Mary 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17540717-24-person246" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person246" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person246" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-24-person247">
                  John 
                  Knight 
               <interp inst="t17540717-24-person247" type="surname" value="Knight"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person247" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming along the Strand in company with 
               <persName id="t17540717-24-person248">
                  Robert Mitchel 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17540717-24-person248" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person248" type="given" value="Robert Mitchel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , on the 5th of July about 10 o'clock at night, we overtook the prisoner and another woman together, they toss'd up their hoops to let us pass, and the prisoner said, Lord! every body is admiring my breast as they go along. Lord, said I, perhaps they are worth admiring, she turned round and said how do you do, my dear, will you give me a glass of wine, and took hold of my hand; with all my heart, said I, then they brought us down to the Rummer by <placeName id="t17540717-24-crimeloc119">Charing-Cross</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17540717-24-crimeloc119" type="placeName" value="Charing-Cross"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17540717-24-crimeloc119" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-24-off117 t17540717-24-crimeloc119"></join>; when we came in we call'd for a bottle of port, we were in a room below stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. Who call'd for the bottle?</p>
               <p>Knight. I did; and flung down 2 s. for it before we tasted it, then she came to me and turn'd up all her clothes to her navel, and sat down on my knee, and said my dear; I said, my dear, I'll have nothing to say to you, she unbutton'd my breeches before, and pull'd all out shirt and all. Then I turn'd round and button'd<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175407170017"></xptr> them up again; by G - d, said she, I will be st - d by you, and came and unbutton'd them again. Then she said where are you going to, I said to James's-street; then she said come along, we will go with you. Then she said to her companion, d - n you, Moll, why don't you haul up; then she pull'd all up, she was with Edwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the other come near you?</p>
               <p>Knight. No, she did not. Then we went to go out, when we got to the door I turn'd round to my friend Edwards to come along, and though I had seen the two women in the entry as I thought going with us, they were slip'd away in an instant. Then I put my hand to my pocket, and pull'd out my money, and found ten 36 shilling pieces and 3 guineas missing, and some silver, but what quantity I know not. When we found we could not come at them that night, we went home and lay together; the next morning we were advis'd to go to the same house; accordingly we went and called for half a pint of wine; I said to the drawer, do you know my face? he said, yes Sir, you were here together last night with two young ladies, (as he was pleased to call them, but they were two young devils to me) I asked him where they liv'd and their names, he said he did not know either. That did not satisfy me, I had lost my money, but I thought proper to conceal that, and said they gave us directions where to find them, but we had lost it. Then I went to a friend of mine, to whom I told the affair and we went in again, and the same drawer brought in a pot of porter; we asked him again whether he knew any thing of them, he said no. My friend called for the man of the house, who came; he said to him, here is an odd affair happen'd in your house, and told him of it; the landlord said he knew nothing of the women, or where they liv'd, and the mistress of the house said the same. I said if the drawer would tell me where they liv'd that I might see them, I'd give him a guinea or two; he went out and came in again, and with humms and haws directed us to a house in a court in the Strand; we went there with a constable and a warrant; the constable found the prisoner by my describing her; but we could not find the other woman. After the constable had got her, I went in and said, G - d bless your pretty face, don't you know me again? She said yes, you was in company with me last night; she denied nothing that passed but having my money; she said she did not take a brass farthing out of my pocket; no, said I, I had no such thing in it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you search her or her lodgings ?</p>
               <p>Knight. No, we did not; had we found money I could not have sworn to that.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know how much money you had in your pocket at that time?</p>
               <p>Knight. To be sure I did by counting of it.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you count it?</p>
               <p>Knight. A little before we met with them.</p>
               <p>Q. How much had you?</p>
               <p>Knight. Twenty 36 s. pieces, nine guineas, and some silver.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to count it at that time?</p>
               <p>Knight. When I go with such creatures I always do.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you been along with such creatures that night before?</p>
               <p>Knight. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Where had you been before you met with them?</p>
               <p>Knight. I went out of a house in the Strand about three quarters of an hour after nine.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there no women there?</p>
               <p>Knight. There were, but I had not been drinking that night; it was then the beginning of the evening.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you quite sober?</p>
               <p>Knight. I had had some liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you had all this money when you came out of that house?</p>

               <p>Knight. I had.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that?</p>
               <p>Knight. I counted it at coming out.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember your throwing your gold, silver and halfpence about the room?</p>
               <p>Knight. No. I pulled out my money to look for silver, but I tossed none about.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you drop some on the ground?</p>
               <p>Knight. I don't remember any such thing.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you not to pursue these women ?</p>
               <p>Knight. I did not know where to pursue. I turned round for my friend, and when I looked for them they were gone.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you count your money when you went in at the Rummer?</p>
               <p>Knight. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see your gold when you paid for your wine?</p>
               <p>Knight. I know then I had it safe.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-24-person249">
                  Robert Mitchel 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17540717-24-person249" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person249" type="given" value="Robert Mitchel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prosecutor and I were together going along the Strand; we met with the prisoner and another woman; they importuned<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175407170018"></xptr> us to go with them to this Rummer to drink. We both went with them. The prisoner sat on his knee with her cloaths up in an indecent manner, and the other so upon mine. We were there till we drank a glass or two of wine. When we were going out I was talking to my friend, and they slipped away and got off. We went to run after them, but could see nothing of them; we never saw which way they went. As soon as we came out of the house, he told me he had lost ten 36 s. pieces, and three guineas. He had counted it there, but would not make any disturbance about it then. Then we went to his lodgings, and lay together. The next morning we went to the same tavern and asked for the drawer; he would give us no account where we might find them, till we got another friend; then we found the prisoner out, and she was taken up and carried before a Justice of the Peace, but she denied having the money.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the prosecutor take out his money at the Rummer?</p>
               <p>Edwards. I did, and he paid 2 s.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any gold in his hand at that time?</p>
               <p>Edwards. Yes, my Lord, I did.</p>
               <p>Q. How much do you think you saw?</p>
               <p>Edwards. I saw a great deal; there were several 36 s. pieces.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that before the women went away?</p>
               <p>Edwards. It was, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. By the quantity how much do you think there might be?</p>
               <p>Edwards. There might be upwards of 40 l.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-24-person250">
                  Henry 
                  Matthews 
               <interp inst="t17540717-24-person250" type="surname" value="Matthews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person250" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 6th of July in the morning, about 8 or 9 o'clock, I went to 
               <persName id="t17540717-24-person251">
                  John 
                  Knight 
               <interp inst="t17540717-24-person251" type="surname" value="Knight"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person251" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Sister's lodging, near Long-acre; I said to him, Jack, what is the matter? He said, since I saw you last I am 4 or 5 and 20 l. the worse man. I asked him how that came about? He said, there were two women picked up this gentleman and I in the Strand, and had us to the Rummer-tavern, and picked my pocket. I advised him to go there again and enquire for them. We three went, and called for a pot of porter. I said to the drawer, Do you remember these two gentlemen being here last night, he said he did. I asked him after the two women that were with them; he said he knew nothing of them; adding, there were a great many women used the house that they did not know. Then I went to the landlord, and said to him, There is an affair happened here which may be of bad consequence to your house; here is a gentleman has been robbed in it last night of so much money, and I believe your drawer knows it. Said he, I'll call him. I said we had offered him a guinea or two to tell us where to find them. Then the women of the house said she remembered a gentlewoman whose name was Lewis, and she could find it out by that. After that the drawer went to the bar in the yard, and unriddled the affair, and said her name was 
               <persName id="t17540717-24-person252">
                  Mary 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17540717-24-person252" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person252" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person252" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , that she lived in Exeter-Court in the Strand. Then a gentleman followed me and said, I am sorry for your misfortune, I'll endeavour to assist you. We went and found the prisoner; she was standing at her own door in the court. The constable went up to her, and said, I have a warrant against you for a robbery at the Rummer. She owned she was there; then the prosecutor came up, and said, My dear, I know you well.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-24-person253">
                  John 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17540717-24-person253" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person253" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the constable. When I took this woman in Exeter-Court, she said, I know I was in company with that gentleman very well; then the gentleman came up to her, and said, My dear, you have a pretty face, I know it very well, or such like words. She said, I know yours, and she mentioned what actions they had together. Said I, Did you rob the gentleman of so much money? She said, No, not of a farthing. I took her before Justice St. Laurence, there she owned she was in company with him, but denied having a farthing of his money. Then I took her to the Gatehouse; she owned the same there of her being in company, and her actions, but not to the taking his money.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was coming from Westminster by Northumberland-house, a man laid hold of me and kissed me, and put his hand on my breast. There came another woman by in a brown camblet gown. He said, As I have kissed you, you shall go along with me. I begged him not to take me away. When we came into the tavern, he called for a bottle of wine; the woman in the camblet gown and he sat down together; she asked him for a present; he said, I'll give no present; I have been with two woman in Marygold-Court already. Then he rang the bell, and wanted another bottle of wine. He pulled out two shillings and some gold in his hand, and said, there is two shillings for the wine, I am to go to Haddock's bagnio; and away he went.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175407170019"></xptr>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-24-person254">
                  James 
                  Rudd 
               <interp inst="t17540717-24-person254" type="surname" value="Rudd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person254" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person254" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17540717-24-person255">
                  John 
                  Knight 
               <interp inst="t17540717-24-person255" type="surname" value="Knight"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person255" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person255" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was at our house in Marygold-Court the 5th of July; he dined there on beans and bacon. I think, as soon as he dined he went out, and was there again in the evening, I believe, between 9 and 10 o'clock, and supped there.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he sober?</p>
               <p>Rudd. He was very much in liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any quantity of money he had?</p>
               <p>Rudd. I remember his having a parcel of 36 s. pieces, some guineas, and some silver.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he pull them out for?</p>
               <p>Rudd. To send for beer. He dropped some in the plate and some on the floor, and picked it up again two or three times. I desired him to put his gold by itself, or he would lose it.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did he go out of your house?</p>
               <p>Rudd. He went out at near 10 o'clock, and Mr. Edwards along with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was his friend in liquor?</p>
               <p>Rudd. He was likewise.</p>
               <p>Q. What are they?</p>
               <p>Rudd. They are both sea-faring men. I saw them both in the Strand in the evening; they were talking with three women at the end of Halfmoon-Street.</p>
               <p>Q. What women?</p>
               <p>Rudd. I believe they might be women of the town. They had proposed to go back to lie at my house, but they did not.</p>
               <p>To her character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-24-person256">
                  James 
                  Becket 
               <interp inst="t17540717-24-person256" type="surname" value="Becket"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person256" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person256" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner three years, she lives next door but one to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you a housekeeper?</p>
               <p>Becket. I am, and so is she.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her general character?</p>
               <p>Becket. I always took her for an honest woman. My wife was once ill, and if I had not taken the prisoner for an honest woman I would not have entrusted her, as I did, in the shop for a month. I was seldom at home, and I left the care wholly to her. We never missed any thing, no, not the least farthing.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you sell?</p>
               <p>Becket. I sell coffee and tea, and other things.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-24-person257">
                  John 
                  Catley 
               <interp inst="t17540717-24-person257" type="surname" value="Catley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person257" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person257" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a publick-house at the top of Burleigh-Street. I have known the prisoner upwards of three years; she always paid me honestly for what she had of me; I never heard an ill character of her. I have trusted her in a room where plate was, and she has had liquor in a silver tankard; If her reckoning was miss-scored she would take care to rectify it, and has paid me more than I have had on the score.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-24-person258">
                  Thomas 
                  Fortune 
               <interp inst="t17540717-24-person258" type="surname" value="Fortune"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person258" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person258" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a bricklayer; I live in Burleigh-Street, and have known her three years or better. She always behaved very well, and very decently, and paid her rent well; nobody better: I never heard of her robbing any body.</p>
               <p>Jos. Rogers. I keep a coal-shed in Burleigh-Street; I have known the prisoner five years, and never heard but she was reckoned a very honest woman. She has had a great deal of goods from me, and if I had mistaken, and not set them down, she always rectified it, and paid me very honestly.</p>
               <p>Patrick M'Intire. I have known the prisoner about three years last February. I am a shoemaker; she has employed me, and paid me very honourably and honestly; I never heard any thing to her dishonestly before; she is a very good natured agreeable neighbour. My wife and she are very intimate. I live facing her window.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see any such indecency as has been here mentioned by her?</p>
               <p>M'Intire. We never meddle with our neighbours. I believe she is as honest a woman as any in England.</p>
               <p>Q. Should you like your wife should keep her company if she is guilty of such indecency as here mentioned?</p>
               <p>M'Intire. Indeed I should not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-24-person259">
                  Mark 
                  Holbourne 
               <interp inst="t17540717-24-person259" type="surname" value="Holbourne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person259" type="given" value="Mark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-person259" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a pawn-broker; my house and the prisoner's join; I have known her ever since she came there, which is three years. I look upon her to be a very honest woman.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear of her picking pockets?</p>
               <p>Holbourne. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540717-24-verdict120" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540717-24-verdict120" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
