<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510703-45">
               <interp inst="t17510703-45" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510703-45" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510703-45" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510703"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510703-45" type="date" value="17510703"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510703-45-off207-c343" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-45-defend431 t17510703-45-off207 t17510703-45-verdict210"></join>
         
               <p>458. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17510703-45-defend431" type="defendantName">
                     Benj.
                      Woodcock
                  <interp inst="t17510703-45-defend431" type="surname" value="Woodcock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-45-defend431" type="given" value="Benj."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-45-defend431" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for that <rs id="t17510703-45-off207" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510703-45-off207" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-45-off207" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he, in a certain open place near the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17510703-45-victim433" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Kirk 
                        <interp inst="t17510703-45-victim433" type="surname" value="Kirk"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510703-45-victim433" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510703-45-victim433" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-45-off207 t17510703-45-victim433"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, one silver sleeve button, value 6 d. one pair of scissars, value 6 d. and 2 s. 6 d. in money number'd, from his person did steal, &amp;c
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510703-45-cd208" type="crimeDate">July 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-45-off207 t17510703-45-cd208"></join>. *</p>
               <p>Thomas Kirk. I was coming from Doctors-commons, and met the prisoner before I got quite to the new church in the Strand, between the hours of one and two last Tuesday morning. There were two women of the town passing their joaks as I went by, I said, I would charge the watch with them; then the prisoner said, he would assist me to secure them: as I did not secure them the prisoner said, I ought to give him something to drink in gratuity: then I said, I would make him drink, but we could not see a publickhouse open. We saw some pease-scop, and he said, he lik'd that better than drink, so we went in, he had some and I paid for it. Then we went on, and when he was in an alley near <placeName id="t17510703-45-crimeloc209">Horseshoe-alley</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17510703-45-crimeloc209" type="placeName" value="Horseshoe-alley"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510703-45-crimeloc209" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-45-off207 t17510703-45-crimeloc209"></join>, he ask'd me, what money I had about me; I told him very little; he insisted upon knowing how much it was. I took 2 s. 6 d. out of my pocket, he insisted upon having it, then d - d me, took it out of my hand, and insisted<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175107030032"></xptr> upon knowing if I had any more. I once had been attack'd in the street, and as I go home late I always carry a loaded pistol in my pocket, (he had before secretly taken that out of my pocket) I went to seel for it, but he took it out of his own pocket and shewed it to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you mentioned that to him before?</p>
               <p>Kirk. I had said, if I should meet any body that had a mind to rob me, I would shoot them before I would be robb'd. He went away with my half crown, a pair of scissers, one pair of silver buttons, and my pistol.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you give him the scissers ?</p>
               <p>Kirk. He put his hand into my pocket and took them out: He took out a pen-knife and a key, which he returned me upon my asking for them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-45-person434">
                  John 
                  Virtue 
               <interp inst="t17510703-45-person434" type="surname" value="Virtue"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-45-person434" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-45-person434" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prosecutor came to me in the morning, and said, he had been robb'd between one and two o'clock: we set out between ten and eleven at night, he saw the prisoner, and said, that was the man, and I took him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I never saw the prosecutor in my life before.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. The prisoner when we took him first of all spoke to me, and I said, I should have a friend with me at such a time that would have a charge of money about him, and if he robb'd him he should give me half (this I said to have an opportunity to take him) he appointed a place for me to meet him on that account at ten o'clock.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510703-45-verdict210" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510703-45-verdict210" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
