<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570713-15">
               <interp inst="t17570713-15" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570713-15" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570713-15" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570713"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570713-15" type="date" value="17570713"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570713-15-off71-c110" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570713-15-defend134 t17570713-15-off71 t17570713-15-verdict75"></join>
         
               <p>260. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17570713-15-defend134" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Roberts 
                  <interp inst="t17570713-15-defend134" type="surname" value="Roberts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-15-defend134" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-15-defend134" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17570713-15-off71" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570713-15-off71" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-15-off71" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one sword with a silver hilt, value 40 s.
            </rs> the property of a person unknown, <rs id="t17570713-15-cd72" type="crimeDate">June 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570713-15-off71 t17570713-15-cd72"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570713-15-person135">
                  John 
                  Becket 
               <interp inst="t17570713-15-person135" type="surname" value="Becket"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-15-person135" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-15-person135" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a sword-cutler; I can only say there was a sword left at my house to have a scabbard to it, by a person unknown to me, which is the sword now under consideration, but I know nothing of the taking of it away.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570713-15-person136">
                  John 
                  Jeffreys 
               <interp inst="t17570713-15-person136" type="surname" value="Jeffreys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-15-person136" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-15-person136" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Becket, a sword-cutler in St. James's-Street. I was going with a bundle of sword-blades, and a silver hilted sword on the top of the bundle, on the Wednesday in Whitsun week, between nine and ten at night, to the scabbard-maker, to have scabbards made to them, and in <placeName id="t17570713-15-crimeloc73">the Strand</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17570713-15-crimeloc73" type="placeName" value="the Strand"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17570713-15-crimeloc73" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570713-15-off71 t17570713-15-crimeloc73"></join> a <rs id="t17570713-15-deflabel74" type="occupation">soldier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570713-15-defend134 t17570713-15-deflabel74"></join> came and took the silver hilted sword and ran away with it.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know that soldier?</p>
               <p>Jeffreys. I did not see his face; I can't say the prisoner is the man. I call'd out stop thief, but he got off.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570713-15-person137">
                  John 
                  Bland 
               <interp inst="t17570713-15-person137" type="surname" value="Bland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-15-person137" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-15-person137" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mr. Becket. I gave this sword to the last evidence to carry to Mr. Parker's in Drury-Lane, to have a scabbard made to it. Producing a silver hilted sword.</p>
               <p>Q. Whose is it?</p>
               <p>Bland. I don't know whose it is; it was left for a new scabbard to be made to it, and the gentleman was to call again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570713-15-person138">
                  John 
                  Lambert 
               <interp inst="t17570713-15-person138" type="surname" value="Lambert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-15-person138" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-15-person138" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner at the bar came to me with this sword, and ask'd me if the hilt was silver or not, on the 1st of June, at night.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175707130015"></xptr>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Lambert. In Panton-street. I shew'd it to my mistress, who said it was silver; then he said he wanted to know the value of it. She said there is a silversmith near at hand that can tell you. I went with him there, but the person was not at home; then the prisoner said to me, what will you give me for it. I said nothing at all. Said he, don't you know any place where I can sell it, or any person that will pawn it for me for what they can get. As we were going along he laid hide it. I went with him to a silversmith in Piccadilly, and shew'd him the sword (and left the prisoner at the door.) I said this man wants to sell or pawn this for what he can get, I think he does not come honestly by it, and ought to be taken care of. Then I said to him, soldier come in, you are to have three shillings for it; he came in, and I shut the door; then we got a constable, and sent him to the Round-house. We intended to have advertised it, but the serjeant finding the prisoner in custody, he came to us, and by his means we found the shop out from whence it was lost. At first the prisoner said he found it by a stone in a street by Covent Garden, after that he said he found it by New-street, Covent-Garden.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>Going to Piccadilly I pick'd up this sword, I went a little farther, and saw that porter standing at a door; I said to him do you think this is silver, he said yes, I believe it is. He took it into a shop and shew'd it to a young woman, who said it was silver. I said I found it, what do you think it is worth; she said a silversmith lives a little lower, and the porter shall go along with you. We went there; the porter went in, and came out again, and said the silversmith bids you 3 s. for it. I said, what for a silver hilted sword. They ask'd me how I came by it, I said I found it coming along; then he said I must have you before the justice. I said I was not afraid of going before a justice or any body else.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570713-15-verdict75" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570713-15-verdict75" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
