<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17580113-18">
               <interp inst="t17580113-18" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580113-18" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580113-18" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580113"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580113-18" type="date" value="17580113"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580113-18-off102-c162" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-18-defend194 t17580113-18-off102 t17580113-18-verdict106"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580113-18-off102-c163" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-18-defend196 t17580113-18-off102 t17580113-18-verdict107"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580113-18-off102-c164" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-18-defend197 t17580113-18-off102 t17580113-18-verdict107"></join>
         
               <p>75, 76, 77. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17580113-18-defend194" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Hodgkins 
                  <interp inst="t17580113-18-defend194" type="surname" value="Hodgkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-18-defend194" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-18-defend194" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-18-defend194" type="age" value="fourteen years of age"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17580113-18-defend196" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Jenkins 
                  <interp inst="t17580113-18-defend196" type="surname" value="Jenkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-18-defend196" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-18-defend196" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               <persName id="t17580113-18-defend197" type="defendantName">
                  Eleanor 
                  Hodgkins  , otherwise <rs id="t17580113-18-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-18-defend197 t17580113-18-alias-1"></join>Gladman</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-18-defend197" type="surname" value="Hodgkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-18-defend197" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-18-defend197" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17580113-18-off102" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580113-18-off102" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-18-off102" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing twelve china cups, value 6 s. twelve china saucers, value 6 s. and two china basons, value 2 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17580113-18-victim199" type="victimName">
                     James 
                     Head 
                  <interp inst="t17580113-18-victim199" type="surname" value="Head"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-18-victim199" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-18-victim199" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-18-off102 t17580113-18-victim199"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            . <rs id="t17580113-18-cd103" type="crimeDate">Dec. 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-18-off102 t17580113-18-cd103"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-18-person200">
                  James 
                  Head 
               <interp inst="t17580113-18-person200" type="surname" value="Head"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-18-person200" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-18-person200" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17580113-18-crimeloc104">Charles Court, Hungerford Market</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17580113-18-crimeloc104" type="placeName" value="Charles Court, Hungerford Market"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17580113-18-crimeloc104" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-18-off102 t17580113-18-crimeloc104"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business ?</p>
               <p>Head. I am a <rs id="t17580113-18-viclabel105" type="occupation">painter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-18-victim199 t17580113-18-viclabel105"></join>. Last Sunday was a month the things mentioned in the indictment were stole out of our shop.</p>
               <p>Q. What shop do you keep?</p>
               <p>Head. My wife keeps a chandler's shop, and sells china-ware and glasses. We were out that day at dinner, so know nothing of my own knowledge of the taking them ( he produced twelve cups and eleven saucers) one of the saucers is broke since; there were two basons taken away, which I never saw since.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your door left open?</p>
               <p>Head. My son was at home, and the door commonly stands a-jar.</p>
               <p>Q. How old is your son?</p>
               <p>Head. He is about eighteen years of age. There is one of them admitted an evidence, who can give a farther account.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-18-person201">
                  Thomas 
                  Bates 
               <interp inst="t17580113-18-person201" type="surname" value="Bates"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-18-person201" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-18-person201" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My mother is a weaver. I did use to live with her, and work at her business, but she being poor, her goods were seized. Then I and 
               <persName id="t17580113-18-person202">
                  John 
                  Hodgkins 
               <interp inst="t17580113-18-person202" type="surname" value="Hodgkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-18-person202" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-18-person202" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             went to sea. When we came back we went and lodged together in Fleet-Street, in Hanging Sword Alley.</p>
               <p>Q How have you got your living ?</p>
               <p>Bates. I work'd with the plaisterers. When we could not get us masters to go to sea we went in a hoy that traded backwards and forwards. Jenkins was not concerned with us in this affair.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you take these goods ?</p>
               <p>Bates. Hodgkins and I went to Drury-Lane, about two o'clock on a Sunday, about six weeks ago; we wanted some of our play-fellows to go with us to take a walk. We found a broker's apprentice, his name I don't know, and we went together to the park; and going home, Hodgkins said, TomI am very hungry, let us go and get a half penny worth of bread in that chandler's shop, the door is open. This was at the house of the prosecutor. Hodgkins went in first, and I followed him; they said they had no bread.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you see there?</p>
               <p>Bates. There were the prosecutor and his son, both reading by the fire.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was this?</p>
               <p>Bates. I believe it was about six o'clock. We knock'd at the counter, they did not see us at first; we ask'd for bread, and were told they had none; there were two doors to the house, it is a corner house. We went out, they came and shut the door after us, we went round to the other door, and that was open. I went into the shop, we had both seen the china, and agreed to go in for it. Hodgkins<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175801130018"></xptr> came in. I took six cups; and six saucers, and a bason, all china, and handed them to him; then we went out and ran thro' a court.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any body at your going in the second time?</p>
               <p>Bates. No, not in the shop. The young man was reading as before by the fire, and his father by him.</p>
               <p>Q. Could they have seen you?</p>
               <p>Bates. They could if they had look'd. We said we thought that was not enough. He put them into his pocket, and came back again, and I went in and took another half dozen of each, and gave them to him, and we ran away to Covent Garden with them. I took at that time a bason, but it was join'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any body the second time?</p>
               <p>Bates. They were there just as they were before. Hodgkins broke one of the large saucers, and put the little half dozen of cups and saucers in my pocket. Then we went to the shop of Mr. Price, a cook's shop in Drury-Lane, and had some victuals. We asked leave to leave them there, and he said we should be welcome.</p>

               <p>Q. How did you pay for your victuals?</p>
               <p>Bates. We had money in our pockets to pay for that. Mr. Price thought we had the china from on board a ship; and there was a man in the shop that said he would sell them for us, if we would come to him to-morrow. We went the next day, and the man was gone. Then I went to a man with whom I had been servant, and told him we brought the china from on board a ship, but he would not buy them, fearing we did not come honestly by them; he said he hoped we did not steal them, and that he would have nothing to do with them, except I went and brought my mother to him in the morning. We asked leave to leave them there, and went home and told Mrs. Hodgkins, the boy's mother that is now at the bar, and she came along with me to my master; in the morning my master was gone out, and my mistress said, Tom, your master does not chuse to have them. Then I put them into my hat, all together, and then into her apron at the door, and she took them to her house. She put them into papers, and we went into Holbourn and sold them that same night, being Tuesday, for 7 s. 6 d.</p>
               <p>Q. Who sold them?</p>
               <p>Bates. She did, and gave the money to her son, who gave me three shillings and nine-pence; then we went to an alehouse and had two pots of beer, where she asked me to give her a shilling, which I did; after that we fell out, and I ask'd her for it again.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be taken up?</p>
               <p>Bates. The two boys at the bar and I went to Carnaby-market, to make an attempt upon a till, being very hungry, and we were taken up.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. What time did you come home that night ?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I did not come home till near nine o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. to Bates. Can you be exact as to the time you took the china?</p>
               <p>Bates. I think it was about six o'clock. - Jack, what time was it -</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure it was the prosecutor whom you saw?</p>
               <p>Bates. To the best of my knowledge it was.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Have you the person that bought the china?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Justice St. Lawrance granted a warrant to take up that woman, but the grand jury threw out the bill at Hick's-hall.</p>
               <p>John Hodgkins's Defence.</p>
               <p>He went into the shop and gave them to me at the door. I did not go into the shop, and was but fourteen years of age last October.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-18-person203">
                  John 
                  Hodgkins 
               <interp inst="t17580113-18-person203" type="surname" value="Hodgkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-18-person203" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-18-person203" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             
                  <rs id="t17580113-18-verdict106" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580113-18-verdict106" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Jenkins and 
               <persName id="t17580113-18-person204">
                  Eleanor 
                  Hodgkins 
               <interp inst="t17580113-18-person204" type="surname" value="Hodgkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-18-person204" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-18-person204" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             
                  <rs id="t17580113-18-verdict107" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580113-18-verdict107" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17580113-18-punish108" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580113-18-punish108" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-18-punish108" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-18-defend194 t17580113-18-punish108"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-18-defend196 t17580113-18-punish108"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-18-defend197 t17580113-18-punish108"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
