<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570420-22">
               <interp inst="t17570420-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570420-22" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570420-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570420"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570420-22" type="date" value="17570420"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570420-22-off108-c207" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-22-defend245 t17570420-22-off108 t17570420-22-verdict112"></join>
         

               <p>163. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17570420-22-defend245" type="defendantName">
                  Ann 
                  <rs id="t17570420-22-deflabel107" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-22-defend245 t17570420-22-deflabel107"></join> of Francis Merritt, otherwise <rs id="t17570420-22-alias-5" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-22-defend245 t17570420-22-alias-5"></join>Ann Merritt</rs>. otherwise <rs id="t17570420-22-alias-6" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-22-defend245 t17570420-22-alias-6"></join>Jones</rs>, otherwise <rs id="t17570420-22-alias-7" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-22-defend245 t17570420-22-alias-7"></join>Wright</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-defend245" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-defend245" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , spinster, was indicted for <rs id="t17570420-22-off108" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-off108" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-off108" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing thirteen pieces of lawn, containing 110 yards, value 20 l. and one pair of lawn ruffles, value 4 s. the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17570420-22-victim247" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Fryer 
                        <interp inst="t17570420-22-victim247" type="surname" value="Fryer"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570420-22-victim247" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570420-22-victim247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-22-off108 t17570420-22-victim247"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately in his warehouse
            </rs>, <rs id="t17570420-22-cd109" type="crimeDate">February 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-22-off108 t17570420-22-cd109"></join>.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-22-person248">
                  Thomas 
                  Fryer 
               <interp inst="t17570420-22-person248" type="surname" value="Fryer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person248" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17570420-22-viclabel110" type="occupation">linen-draper</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-22-victim247 t17570420-22-viclabel110"></join> and live in <placeName id="t17570420-22-crimeloc111">Bishopsgate-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17570420-22-crimeloc111" type="placeName" value="Bishopsgate-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17570420-22-crimeloc111" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-22-off108 t17570420-22-crimeloc111"></join> Without. On the 22d or 23d of February, the prisoner came to my shop, and said she had taken a house in Shoreditch and was going into the linen trade, and wanted to see some linen goods. I desired her to walk into the warehouse, which she did; I shewed her several pieces, which she laid by to the amount of I believe near 40 l. it began to grow dark; she said she wanted several things more, but as she could not see she would call next day; she went away and came in the afternoon about four o'clock the next day, and then bought other goods to I believe near the same value; then I asked her in what way the bill was to be made. She said in the name of 
               <persName id="t17570420-22-person249">
                  John 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17570420-22-person249" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person249" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who was her husband. I told her it was usual to pay for goods the first time of coming; she said, she intended to do that, and desired I'd make out the bill, and she would call the day following or the day after and pay me; about half an hour after she was gone I laid the goods in order, to make the bill, and found two pieces of lawn which she had laid by were missing; after we had searched and could not find them, I searched the boxes where we generally keep them, and missed nine more; then I was suspicious she had robbed me, and she not coming according to appointment I applied to justice Fielding, who advised me to advertise her. I did, and described her and the goods, she was then very big with child; about four or five days after one of Mr. Fielding's men call'd upon me; and said he had seen the goods, and in the afternoon of that day I was sent for to justice Fielding's; there was a pawnbroker with the goods. I knowing them to be mine swore to them, when the justice ordered the woman to be brought in, and as soon as she saw me she made a curtsey. I said, I find you know me. Yes Sir, said she, I was at your house such a day. I asked her whether or no she had taken away the goods that I had sworn to; she said no, she had them of 
               <persName id="t17570420-22-person250">
                  John 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17570420-22-person250" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person250" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I said, when you was at my house, you said he was your husband. She said. she did tell me so, but that was not true. Mr. Fielding asked her where this 
               <persName id="t17570420-22-person251">
                  John 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17570420-22-person251" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person251" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was. She gave some directions but he could not be found, upon which the justice committed her. I went to see her after she was in New-Prison, where she confessed to me she did take the things.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-22-person252">
                  James 
                  Poupard 
               <interp inst="t17570420-22-person252" type="surname" value="Poupard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person252" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner has come several times to Mr. Poupard, who is my brother in law; he is a jeweller, and keeps a silversmith's shop, and carries on the pawnbroking way.</p>

               <p>Q. Where does he live?</p>

               <p>J. Poupard. He lives in Smock-Alley; on the 22d of February last she came into the shop in order to pawn three pieces of lawn, which she asked 4 l. upon. Mr. Poupard examined them, and said he could not lend any more upon them than 3 l. she several times desired him to lend her 3 l. 10 s. he said he could not stretch any more; he asked her what they might be worth, she said 3 s. and 6 d. or 4 s. per yard. I took her name down, and my brother went to the other side the counter, and paid her the 3 l.</p>

               <p>Q. What name did you take down?</p>

               <p>J. Poupard. It was 
               <persName id="t17570420-22-person253">
                  Ann 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17570420-22-person253" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person253" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person253" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Poupard asked her if they were her own, she said they were.</p>

               <p>Q. What sort of things had she used to bring?</p>

               <p>J. Poupard. Gowns, handkerchiefs, and other; sorts of things; she never brought such kind of things as these before.</p>

               <p>Q. Did she always come in the name of 
               <persName id="t17570420-22-person254">
                  Ann 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17570420-22-person254" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person254" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person254" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>

               <p>J. Poupard. She did [he produced divers parcels in papers] here are three of those which the prosecutor has sworn to, which are sealed up.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-22-person255">
                  Peter 
                  Poupard 
               <interp inst="t17570420-22-person255" type="surname" value="Poupard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person255" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person255" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a pawnbroker, the prisoner has made use of my house six or seven years, to the best of my knowledge always in the name of 
               <persName id="t17570420-22-person256">
                  Ann 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17570420-22-person256" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person256" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person256" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>

               <p>Q. Can you tell what articles she brought at different times ?</p>

               <p>P. Poupard. I really can't charge my memory with that, but on the 22d of February she brought<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200031"></xptr> three pieces of lawn to me, and I lent her 3 l. upon them; she said they were her own. I did imagine she liv'd very near us, but did not know where; the next day she brought two pieces more. I then more particularly asked her how she came by them; she said her husband had taken them for a bad debt, and if he had not taken them he would have had nothing at all, and that he had taken in all eleven pieces. She asked me if it would suit me to buy them, saying she wanted a little money against she lay in. I bought them of her for 3 s. and 6 d. per yard, that was, the five pieces she had brought; she brought to the amount of ten pieces in all. I bought them all of her, the last I did not give quite so much for, the ten pieces cost me in the whole between 11 l. and 12 l. On the 3d of March being at Temple-Bar waiting for a gentleman, I took up a paper, and read an advertisement, in which I found the prisoner described and eleven pieces mentioned; then I went to justice Fielding, and found several of the pieces I had bought answer'd to the numbers. I took the pieces that night to the justice, and the justice told me all I had to do was to discover the person I bought them of. I was oblig'd to go out the next morning, and left word with my wife that if Mrs. Jones came, to call my servant down to stop her; about eleven o'clock she came to the door, my wife call'd her in and desired her to go backwards, and turn'd the key upon her, and set a servant to stand by her till I came home; when I came home I got a porter to my assistance and took her to justice Fielding's in a coach, but call'd at Mr. Fryer's going along, and told him I had detected the person that brought me the things.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-22-person257">
                  Joseph 
                  Baux 
               <interp inst="t17570420-22-person257" type="surname" value="Baux"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person257" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person257" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner twenty years. Mr. Fryer, I and another person went to see her in New-Prison. Mr. Fryer told your lordship of her confession, but did not tell the court the methods made use of in order to induce her to it. I heard her confess she stole these pieces, and I heard her likewise say to the contrary; and the prosecutor said to her, if she would make a free and ample confession he would be favourable to her, upon which account she did say what the prosecutor has deposed.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-22-person258">
                  Joyce 
                  Twine 
               <interp inst="t17570420-22-person258" type="surname" value="Twine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person258" type="given" value="Joyce"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person258" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a milliner in Bishopsgate-street; the prisoner brought three pieces of lawn to me, and asked me if I would buy any of it; I said they were now a drug.</p>

               <p>Q. When was this?</p>

               <p>J. Twine. This was on the 28th of February, she said she had them of a weaver for a debt, and was obliged to turn them into money. I bought them of her, and gave her 4 l. 19 s. for them, here is the bill and receipt ( the three pieces produced in court.)</p>

               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Look on this piece?</p>

               <p>Prosecutor. This is my property. I have looked on the other ten pieces produc'd, they are my property.</p>

               <p>Q. In what name did she sell these three pieces?</p>

               <p>J. Twine. She sold them by the name of 
               <persName id="t17570420-22-person259">
                  Ann 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17570420-22-person259" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person259" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person259" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>

               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>

               <p>I bought these goods of one 
               <persName id="t17570420-22-person260">
                  John 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17570420-22-person260" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person260" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person260" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , but I don't know him; I had them for a bad debt.</p>

               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-22-person261">
                  Robert 
                  Hobins 
               <interp inst="t17570420-22-person261" type="surname" value="Hobins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person261" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person261" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Featherstone street, and am a dealer in cloaths. I have known the prisoner ever since she was born. She had an exceeding good education, and had a good character; she has a very good husband, by whom she has had eleven children, she has six alive now; he is a very good husband, and she has behaved as well.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-22-person262">
                  Joshua 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17570420-22-person262" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person262" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person262" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a weaver by trade. I have known her eighteen years. She was always singularly honest, I have trusted her in my house with things of great value; I never knew her to do a misbehaved thing in my life, no not so much as to call her husband fool in anger, and she has been married seventeen or eighteen years.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-22-person263">
                  Francis 
                  Readhead 
               <interp inst="t17570420-22-person263" type="surname" value="Readhead"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person263" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person263" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live just over-against where the prisoner was born, in Spicer-street, Spittle-fields. I have known her thirty-two years, I have trusted her in my house many a time, and never knew her to do the least thing amiss in my life.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-22-person264">
                  William 
                  Wade 
               <interp inst="t17570420-22-person264" type="surname" value="Wade"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person264" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-person264" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her between fourteen and fifteen years.</p>

               <p>Q. What is her general character?</p>

               <p>Wade. An exceeding good one for what ever I heard.</p>

               <p>Q. What name did she go by?</p>

               <p>Wade. By the name of Merritt.</p>

               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570420-22-verdict112" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-verdict112" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17570420-22-punish113" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570420-22-punish113" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-22-defend245 t17570420-22-punish113"></join>
               Death
            </rs>. Recommended.</p>
            </div1>
