<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17561208-8">
               <interp inst="t17561208-8" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561208-8" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561208-8" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17561208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561208-8" type="date" value="17561208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17561208-8-off37-c57" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-8-defend70 t17561208-8-off37 t17561208-8-verdict39"></join>
         
               <p>8. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17561208-8-defend70" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Freeman 
                  <interp inst="t17561208-8-defend70" type="surname" value="Freeman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-8-defend70" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-8-defend70" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17561208-8-off37" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561208-8-off37" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-8-off37" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one man's hat, value 12 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               <persName id="t17561208-8-victim71" type="victimName">
                  Mungo 
                  Barnes 
               <interp inst="t17561208-8-victim71" type="surname" value="Barnes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-8-victim71" type="given" value="Mungo"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-8-victim71" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-8-off37 t17561208-8-victim71"></join>
                  </persName>
             , <rs id="t17561208-8-cd38" type="crimeDate">Nov. 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-8-off37 t17561208-8-cd38"></join>.* </p> 
               <p>Mungo Barnes. I live in Great Peter-Street, Westminster. I lost my hat out of my shop. The prisoner was suspected, and charged with taking it. He confessed he left his own hat backwards, and carried mine out, and went and pawn'd it for half a crown.</p>
               <p>Mr. Wilkins. The prisoner brought a hat to pawn to me on the 19th of November, and I lent him half a crown upon it. Since that two men came, and told me the prisoner was in the Savoy for desertion, and he had sent them to my house for some goods which he had pawned. They mentioned two shirts, a handkerchief and a hat. They took out the shirt and handkerchief.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Wilkins. This was on the 23d. After that Mungo Barnes's wife came, and demanded the hat, and said it was her son's hat, and that the prisoner<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175612080005"></xptr> was her son; but never said the hat was stolen. I shew'd her the hat. She went away, and after that these two men came again for the hat, and had it out</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561208-8-person72">
                  Ruth 
                  Barnes 
               <interp inst="t17561208-8-person72" type="surname" value="Barnes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-8-person72" type="given" value="Ruth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-8-person72" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to demand the hat. He shew'd it me, but not having the money I left it, and said I'd come again for it the next day.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the hat?</p>
               <p>R. Barnes. I did; it was the same hat my husband had lost. The next day I went for it, but he would not shew it me.</p>
               <p>Q. to Wilkins. Was the hat you shew'd the prosecutor's wife the same which the prisoner pledged with you?</p>
               <p>Wilkins. It was the same.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561208-8-person73">
                  Thomas 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17561208-8-person73" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-8-person73" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-8-person73" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I confined the prisoner in the Savoy as a deserter, and he confessed to me the hat was pawn'd to this Wilkin s. I went there with Mrs. Barnes, and after some difficulty Wilkins's wife did shew it to us. I would not let her take it out, but gave the pawnbroker particular orders not to deliver the hat to any body till we came again the next day. Then I intended to take it with a search warrant, without paying for it. We went with a search warrant. Said Wilkins, have you brought the money. Said the constable, I have something as good as money, and shew'd him the warrant. He gave the constable a punch on the breast, and knock'd him backwards, and in the mean while he ran in, and I suppose concealed the hat, for that was not to be found, although he had ask'd for the money just before.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I went to Mungo Barnes's to be taken measure of for a pair of shoes, and they desired me to help them to remove some goods; they got fuddled, and got me to go and pawn the hat for them, and after that they said they would give me half a crown to fetch it out again. I was taken up for desertion or I had fetch'd it again. I never sent any person for the hat at all.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17561208-8-verdict39" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561208-8-verdict39" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
