<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17500711-59">
               <interp inst="t17500711-59" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-59" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-59" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17500711"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-59" type="date" value="17500711"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500711-59-off268-c381" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-59-defend493 t17500711-59-off268 t17500711-59-verdict271"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500711-59-off268-c382" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-59-defend495 t17500711-59-off268 t17500711-59-verdict271"></join>
         
               <p>486, 487. 
               
                  <persName id="t17500711-59-defend493" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Dunkin 
                  <interp inst="t17500711-59-defend493" type="surname" value="Dunkin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-59-defend493" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-59-defend493" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17500711-59-defend495" type="defendantName">
                     Edward 
                     Brusby 
                  <interp inst="t17500711-59-defend495" type="surname" value="Brusby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-59-defend495" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-59-defend495" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for that they <rs id="t17500711-59-off268" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500711-59-off268" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-59-off268" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               in a certain field, or open place, near the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17500711-59-victim497" type="victimName">
                           Stephen 
                           Macdonald 
                        <interp inst="t17500711-59-victim497" type="surname" value="Macdonald"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500711-59-victim497" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500711-59-victim497" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-59-off268 t17500711-59-victim497"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life; 2 s. 2 d. in money numbered, from his person did steal, take and carry away
            </rs>, <rs id="t17500711-59-cd269" type="crimeDate">June 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-59-off268 t17500711-59-cd269"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-59-person498">
                  Stephen 
                  Macdonald 
               <interp inst="t17500711-59-person498" type="surname" value="Macdonald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-59-person498" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-59-person498" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 10th of June my wife, I, and a man that lodges at my house, took a walk in the fields towards Pancrass. We called upon Mr. Pantelow, the constable of St. George's, Bloomsbury; then we sent for Mr. Campbell, another constable, we agreed to go out on a party of pleasure; as it rained and thundered much my wife and Mr. Pantelow's returned back to his house. Mr. Pantelow charged his brace of pistols. I charg'd three pistols, one the man had with him, one Mr. Campbel had, and one I had. We met another gentleman, he agreed to go with us. There are thieves infest that place, and especially one who has threatened the life of Pantelow, upon the account of his taking up the persons who robbed my lady Albemarle (we had staid drinking at the Spa) Coming back, in <placeName id="t17500711-59-crimeloc270">Pancrass fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17500711-59-crimeloc270" type="placeName" value="Pancrass fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17500711-59-crimeloc270" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-59-off268 t17500711-59-crimeloc270"></join>, before we came to the wooden bridge, I said to them, we had better divide, and not go all in a body; so I said to Mr. Pantelow and Mr. Campbell, and an apprentice to a brazier, do you go on one side of the field, and I and Bready will go on the other. Bready kept behind me about 20 yards. I saw three fellows coming towards the wooden bridge (this was about a quarter of an hour after nine o'clock) one of them came up to me, which I take to be Dunkin, and discharged a pistol, it went over my head. I put my hand in my pocket, and my pistol had got through the lining of my pocket; said the man, swearing out, deliver your money. The other I believe to be Brusby, had a hanger. I said, gentlemen, don't use me ill, I have but 2 s. 2 d. which I delivered to them. Mr. Campbell called out to Pantelow, that there was some disturbance. I believe they hearing the name Pantelow made them run. I pursued, and got ground of them, then the person stopped and shot again at me, so I discharged mine at him. I pursued them still, thinking Mr. Pantelow and the others were after me Then he, which I take to be Dunkin, turn'd back and came up close to me, and put his pistol to me, swearing, take it, and shot again, then ran, and I ran, and pursued them still. I ran about 20 or 30 yards; I did not feel I was shot any more than any gentleman in the court; I put my hand in my bosom and felt blood, then I made a sort of a halt, and I called out to those behind, I was shot. Mr. Bready and Campbell came up, and 
               <persName id="t17500711-59-person499">
                  Robert 
                  Neal 
               <interp inst="t17500711-59-person499" type="surname" value="Neal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-59-person499" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-59-person499" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the apprentice. I said to Mr. Campbell, give me your pistol, for I am a dead man, I'll pursue them as far as life is in me; I ran, and the apprentice followed me, I gathered a great deal of ground. They swore if I came up to them, they'd shoot me. I pursued them round the fields, they got over a hedge. There was a horse, on which one was mounted, and the other was getting up when the apprentice and I got up to them, and took them, and brought them guarded to town.</p>

               <p>[He shewed the wounds on his body, which were three, his waistcoat bloody on the inside, the surgeon was there to be examined, who extracted the slug from one of the wounds, he was not examined,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175007110034"></xptr> the counsel for the prisoners agreed to that part of his evidence, that he had been robb'd and shot.]</p>
               <p>It being a dark night the company divided, as they thought the thieves went; some thought they ran towards London, and some the other way.</p>
               <p>Mr. Pantelow. 
               <persName id="t17500711-59-person500">
                  John 
                  Gaticer 
               <interp inst="t17500711-59-person500" type="surname" value="Gaticer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-59-person500" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-59-person500" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Bready said these could not be the men. There were divers persons appeared for the prisoners characters; and it appeared they had been both on one horse to Highgate, and was upon their return when taken, and that they set out from the Cooper's arms there at half an hour after nine o'clock.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-59-person501">
                  John 
                  Gidings 
               <interp inst="t17500711-59-person501" type="surname" value="Gidings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-59-person501" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-59-person501" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , deposed he went out with them on a single horse, he had been drinking plentifully and rode on the Road, and knew nothing of their being taken up till he came to London. But Macdonald said, and others confirmed it, that he rode side by side with the prisoners, when they were bringing the prisoners to town guarded.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17500711-59-verdict271" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500711-59-verdict271" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
