<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17500711-10">
               <interp inst="t17500711-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-10" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17500711"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-10" type="date" value="17500711"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500711-10-off40-c77" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-10-defend99 t17500711-10-off40 t17500711-10-verdict43"></join>
         
               <p>429. 
               
                  <persName id="t17500711-10-defend99" type="defendantName">
                     Benjamin 
                     Chamberlain 
                  <interp inst="t17500711-10-defend99" type="surname" value="Chamberlain"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-10-defend99" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-10-defend99" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for that he <rs id="t17500711-10-off40" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500711-10-off40" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-10-off40" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               on the king's highway  , on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17500711-10-victim101" type="victimName">
                           George 
                           Powel 
                        <interp inst="t17500711-10-victim101" type="surname" value="Powel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500711-10-victim101" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500711-10-victim101" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-10-off40 t17500711-10-victim101"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life; one metal watch, value 40 s. one pair of silver-buckles, value 5 s. against the will of the said George, from his person did steal, take, and carry away
            </rs>, <rs id="t17500711-10-cd41" type="crimeDate">June 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-10-off40 t17500711-10-cd41"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-10-person102">
                  George 
                  Powell 
               <interp inst="t17500711-10-person102" type="surname" value="Powell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-10-person102" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-10-person102" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 24th of June last, about one in the morning, I was going up <placeName id="t17500711-10-crimeloc42">Chancery-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17500711-10-crimeloc42" type="placeName" value="Chancery-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17500711-10-crimeloc42" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-10-off40 t17500711-10-crimeloc42"></join>, in order to go in at Lincoln's Inn gate; just as I got opposite to the gate, I was surrounded by four men; one of them is here to give evidence; he put a pistol to my face, and bid me stop; they got me up with my back against the houses, and bid me deliver my money; the prisoner at the bar, as I believe him to be the man, stooped down and took my buckles out of my shoes.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a light night?</p>
               <p>Powell. It was a darkish sort of a night.</p>
               <p>Q. By what do you believe the prisoner to be one in company?</p>
               <p>Powell. By his shape and size; not that I can tell him by his face; I believe him to be in the same coat he has on now; he then risled my breeches-pockets, and took out my watch, a pinchbeck metal one, and shagreen case, with an enamel'd dial-plate ; the other stood by; the man that held the pistol ask'd him what he had got; he made answer, his Lodge; then away they went together. I do not swear positively to the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-10-person103">
                  John 
                  Omit 
               <interp inst="t17500711-10-person103" type="surname" value="Omit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-10-person103" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-10-person103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Saturday night, about eleven o'clock, we went out taking a walk.</p>
               <p>Q. Who do you mean by we?</p>
               <p>Omit. The prisoner, 
               <persName id="t17500711-10-person104">
                  Thomas 
                  Blunt 
               <interp inst="t17500711-10-person104" type="surname" value="Blunt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-10-person104" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-10-person104" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17500711-10-person105">
                  James 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17500711-10-person105" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-10-person105" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-10-person105" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and myself; we made a bargain to go out a robbing about Chancery-lane; the prisoner (Chamberlain) agreed, and took a mop-stick at the same time, and cut it in two; he gave one half to 
               <persName id="t17500711-10-person106">
                  Thomas 
                  Blunt 
               <interp inst="t17500711-10-person106" type="surname" value="Blunt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-10-person106" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-10-person106" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and the other he kept himself; this was at his lodging, a house that harbours all whores and thieves; first we went down to Fleetditch side, then to Chancery-lane. I went up to this gentleman, and put the pistol to his head; it was better than an hour and half from our first setting out to the time we stopp'd him; we had been drinking about from gin-shop to gin-shop.</p>
               <p>Q. Whereabouts in Chancery-lane did you meet the prosecutor?</p>
               <p>Omit. It was almost opposite the gate; the gentleman knew me, and I knew him again as soon as I saw him at Justice Fielding's.</p>
               <p>Q. Give us an account of this Robbery.</p>
               <p>Omit. I clapp'd him up against a house, and Chamberlain flung his stick down by the side of the gentleman. After I had clapp'd a pistol to his head, he took the buckles out of his shoes, and after that his watch from his pocket. I ask'd him what he had got; he said his Lodge, meaning his watch. The gentleman proffer'd me some halfpence, and I returned them to him again from out of my hand; then we went one way and he another; we went towards Lincoln's-Inn-Fields, then towards Fleet-market, then to Duke's-place; there we drank. The prisoner sold the watch the next morning to a Jew. The Jew's name is 
               <persName id="t17500711-10-person107">
                  Alexander 
                  Minous 
               <interp inst="t17500711-10-person107" type="surname" value="Minous"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-10-person107" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-10-person107" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ; we were all four together when it was sold.</p>

               <p>Q. What was it sold for?</p>
               <p>Omit. It was sold for 25 s.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. Did you see the person who took the buckles out of your shoes lay something down out of his hand at that time?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. He laid something down, I thought it was a hanger.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you deliver this witness some halfpence which he returned again?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175007110006"></xptr>Prosecutor. He bid me deliver my money ; I delivered him some halfpence into his hand, and he returned them to me again.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence. I never was guilty of any such thing in my life. This Omit is a cruel man to say so much as he has done against me.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500711-10-verdict43" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500711-10-verdict43" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17500711-10-punish44" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500711-10-punish44" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-10-defend99 t17500711-10-punish44"></join>
               death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>See No. 371 in the last Sessions-book.</p>
            </div1>
