<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510523-6">
               <interp inst="t17510523-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510523-6" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510523-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510523"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510523-6" type="date" value="17510523"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510523-6-off35-c50" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-6-defend59 t17510523-6-off35 t17510523-6-verdict38"></join>
         
               <p>356. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17510523-6-defend59" type="defendantName">
                     Judith 
                     Conner 
                  <interp inst="t17510523-6-defend59" type="surname" value="Conner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-6-defend59" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-6-defend59" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17510523-6-deflabel34" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-6-defend59 t17510523-6-deflabel34"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17510523-6-off35" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510523-6-off35" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-6-off35" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch, value 3 l. one half guinea, the goods and money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17510523-6-victim61" type="victimName">
                           Philip 
                           Richards 
                        <interp inst="t17510523-6-victim61" type="surname" value="Richards"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510523-6-victim61" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510523-6-victim61" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-6-off35 t17510523-6-victim61"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling house of 
                     <persName id="t17510523-6-person62">
                        Peter 
                        Farril 
                     <interp inst="t17510523-6-person62" type="surname" value="Farril"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510523-6-person62" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510523-6-person62" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17510523-6-cd36" type="crimeDate">May 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-6-off35 t17510523-6-cd36"></join> *.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-6-person63">
                  Philip 
                  Richards 
               <interp inst="t17510523-6-person63" type="surname" value="Richards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-6-person63" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-6-person63" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17510523-6-viclabel37" type="occupation">brewer's servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-6-victim61 t17510523-6-viclabel37"></join>: On the 14th of May I went to Hammersmith, I staid drinking there till night, being upon my own business; I was much in liquor, and coming by St. Giles's the prisoner pick'd me up; we went and drank together, then we went to her own home and had some liquor there; I gave a shilling for my bed and went up stairs, we sat sometime together, I gave the prisoner a shilling, then we went to bed together; I came down again after that and had some more liquor below.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you pull'd your cloaths off when you went to bed?</p>
               <p>Richards. I had, my Lord. I had my watch and money in my pocket after I had put my cloaths on again. There was another girl in the house, I told her I would give her sixpence if she would go up stairs along with me, so we went to bed together in the same bed, and I locked the door, and put my breeches quite under the middle of the bed. When I awaked in the morning I found my breeches lying on the bed, I search'd them and found that my watch and money were gone. I search'd about the bed and found two shillings in it, I miss'd half a guinea in gold; then I saw there was a door stood a-jarr, there was a little table stood before it which was shov'd back into the room; this door open'd into the room where the prisoner lay, out of which there was a way down stairs, which I did not know of when I went to bed. I call'd to the man of the house, he came to me, I told him the case, so he sent for a constable, and would not let the girls go out of the house till he came; the constable took six of them to the Round-house; there was another girl but she was ill, besides the man's wife, these two were left behind. The six girls were all search'd but nothing found upon them; they were taken before Justice Fielding, and all denied knowing of the watch or money; the Justice wrote a mittimus to send them all to Bridewell, and as they were going along the prisoner said, she knew were the watch was, and would tell if I would release her. We took her back to the Justice, I there heard her say, it was put into a hole in the feather bed where she lay, in the next room to where I lay. The Justice ask'd her, whether any body was with her when she took the watch; she said, no body at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you had the watch, and half guinea, when you went to bed with the other girl?</p>
               <p>Richards. I am certain I had.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know where the prisoner was when you went to bed the second time?</p>
               <p>Richards. No, my Lord, I don't. She could come into her own room without coming into the room where I lay.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know she lay in that room?</p>
               <p>Richards. She said she laid there. Then she said, she gave the watch to another girl that lay with her, and she hid it. The Justice order'd the constable to go and search that place; when he was gone the other girl said, the prisoner had put it into a hole in the bolster; then the Justice sent another person to bid the constable search the bolster.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-6-person64">
                  Arthur 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17510523-6-person64" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-6-person64" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-6-person64" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable: I went by the Justice's order, and two women that were there, and I found the watch in the bolster. I saw them shake it out. The prosecutor, as he described it, lay in the fore room, and this bed was in the back room. The watch was produced in court and deposed to.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Justice put the confession in writing?</p>
               <p>Smith. I believe not.</p>
               <p>Q. to the prosecutor. Did you see the Justice put it in writing?</p>
               <p>Richards. I did not see him write.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>Last Tuesday was se'night at night I had been out, and coming home between eleven and twelve o'clock, with the tail of my gown about my head; the prosecutor took hold of me and push'd me about, and said, I should not go till he had drank with me; so he push'd me into a house, saying, he had but a penny about him, and wanted me to pay a halfpenny, I said I had no money. Then he pull'd out a sixpence, and drank<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175105230005"></xptr> to another man. I went out at the door and he followed me; he ask'd me to go to an inn, and said, he would have some wine, and pay for a bed for us; then he wanted to know where I lodged, so he went with me; we drank some rum, then he went up stairs, paid a shilling for his bed, and gave me a shilling to go to bed with him. I went into bed but left him directly, so he had another young woman, and he gave her sixpence. I saw a green string, and thought it would make me a topknot, so I gave it to another woman; the next morning we were taken before a Justice, she told me the watch was in the bolster of a bed, I told the Justice as soon as she told me so.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510523-6-verdict38" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510523-6-verdict38" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
