<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560915-46">
               <interp inst="t17560915-46" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-46" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-46" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560915"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-46" type="date" value="17560915"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560915-46-off235-c272" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-46-defend360 t17560915-46-off235 t17560915-46-verdict237"></join>
         
               <p>378. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17560915-46-defend360" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Clowes 
                  <interp inst="t17560915-46-defend360" type="surname" value="Clowes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-46-defend360" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-46-defend360" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for the <rs id="t17560915-46-off235" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560915-46-off235" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-46-off235" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               wilful murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17560915-46-victim362" type="victimName">
                           Sarah 
                           Wheeler 
                        <interp inst="t17560915-46-victim362" type="surname" value="Wheeler"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560915-46-victim362" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560915-46-victim362" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-46-off235 t17560915-46-victim362"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , by mixing a certain quantity of laudanum in the liquor which she drank
            </rs>. He stood likewise charged on the coroner's inquest for the said murder, <rs id="t17560915-46-cd236" type="crimeDate">August 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-46-off235 t17560915-46-cd236"></join>.* </p> 
               <p>Sarah Hill. I never saw 
               <persName id="t17560915-46-person363">
                  Sarah 
                  Wheeler 
               <interp inst="t17560915-46-person363" type="surname" value="Wheeler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-46-person363" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-46-person363" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             living in my life. I search'd her after she was dead.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after her death?</p>
               <p>S. Hill. I believe about five hours after.</p>
               <p>Q. Had she any marks of violence upon her?</p>
               <p>S. Hill. She had none at all, no blackness, nothing but the settling of blood in her shoulder.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any reason to conclude she came by an unnatural death?</p>
               <p>S. Hill. No, none at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Had she any blackness on her belly?</p>
               <p>S. Hill. No, she had not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-46-person364">
                  George 
                  Dutton 
               <interp inst="t17560915-46-person364" type="surname" value="Dutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-46-person364" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-46-person364" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a painter. I neither knew the deceased nor the prisoner. On the second of August about half an hour after eleven at night, I saw the prisoner and a hackney coachman take a woman out of the coach, and I took her to be dead. It was in Chick-Lane, at the corner of Cross-Keys Court. The prisoner came out of the coach first. Then he laid hold of the woman's shoulders, and the coachman by the legs, and they carried her down to the house of Mrs. Deal, as they call her; it was her former husband's name, but her right name is Price. They laid her down at the door, on the threshold, and she could not stir hand, foot, nor leg, nor nothing in the world. She had no life in her at all seemingly.</p>
               <p>Court. Have you got the coachman here?</p>
               <p>Coroner. No, we could not find him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's council. We have him and shall call him.</p>
               <p>Dutton. The prisoner ask'd for a lodging for his wife and himself. Mrs. Price came to the door to him. She said, what is all this? what do you want? He said, he wanted a lodging, and they<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175609150027"></xptr> talked a good deal. She said, ther e is no lodging here. He said, don't make yourself uneasy; if any thing should happen I'll give you five guineas (but he pull'd out none.) Then I said, mistress, this woman is a dead woman, and I would not have you take her in upon any account. The prisoner said, dead! no, dead drunk. I said (shaking my head) I was afraid it would be worse than drunk. After more talk, she was admitted into the house. Then the prisoner and coachman carried her into a little room on the left hand side of the entry, where there was a bed. As soon as they had got her into the room the prisoner was for going away. Mrs. Price said, no Sir, if you go away pray take the woman or your wife (one was mention'd, I know not which) away with you. Then he made no more to do but undressed himself, and into bed he went.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he sober?</p>
               <p>Dutton. I believe he was hardly sober.</p>

               <p>Q. Was the woman in the bed?</p>
               <p>Dutton. No. She lay on the floor, by the side of the bed. He turned himself on his left side and call'd for the maid to come and undress the woman, and put her to bed. The maid was then gone to the coach to see what was left in it. She came in with one shoe and two dogs in her hand. Then she went to undress the woman, and I went away.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your opinion, as you saw her lying on the floor, was she dead or not?</p>
               <p>Dutton. Upon my oath I then thought she was a dead woman.</p>
               <p>Elizabeth Green. I am servant to Mrs. Price. I went to undress the woman to put her to bed.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she dead or alive?</p>
               <p>E. Green. Her legs felt very cold, and I did not perceive any breath.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you undress her?</p>
               <p>E. Green. I did; and help'd her into bed. The prisoner got out of bed and took hold on her shoulders and I her feet, and we put her in.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she warm about any part of her?</p>
               <p>E. Green. Her body was warm, her face was cold, and her stomach was warm; but her legs and hands were quite stiff.</p>
               <p>Q. After that, what did the prisoner do?</p>
               <p>E. Green. He went to bed to her.</p>
               <p>Q. How long might they lie together in bed?</p>
               <p>E. Green. The watch had just gone twelve when he went to bed. He staid in bed with her till six in the morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him at six?</p>
               <p>E. Green. No, I call'd my fellow servant up at six. Her name is 
               <persName id="t17560915-46-person365">
                  Ann 
                  Bennet 
               <interp inst="t17560915-46-person365" type="surname" value="Bennet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-46-person365" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-46-person365" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I came to her as soon as the prisoner went away, which was about five minutes after six. I applied and rub'd her with warm cloths, to see if I could fetch her again; but when we came to move her about seven o'clock we found she was quite stiff, and purged very much. We could hardly move her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you help to lay her out?</p>
               <p>E. Green. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any marks of violence upon her?</p>
               <p>E. Green. No, none at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think in your judgment that she came by any violent death, or had a fit, or was drunk, or what?</p>
               <p>E. Green. The blood had settled very much about her, but there were no marks of violence at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did the blood settle?</p>
               <p>E. Green. Upon her arms, her back, and neck.</p>
               <p>Q. Was her belly or stomach swell'd greatly?</p>
               <p>E. Green. No, I did not see her after eleven o'clock.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-46-person366">
                  Ann 
                  Bennet 
               <interp inst="t17560915-46-person366" type="surname" value="Bennet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-46-person366" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-46-person366" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am fellow servant to the last witness. When I went into the kitchen the prisoner was standing by the bedside.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him?</p>
               <p>A. Bennet. I happened to push open the door and saw him. He asked me what business I had there? I asked his pardon. After that I went in to see how the woman did, about six o'clock, and in the mean time he went away, and left two shillings on the board. The woman was really dead.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her after this?</p>

               <p>A. Bennet. I did, there were no marks of violence upon her at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think she died a natural death?</p>
               <p>A. Bennet. I believe so. I never saw the prisoner before or after, till I was taken to his house, and then I knew him again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-46-person367">
                  Jane 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17560915-46-person367" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-46-person367" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-46-person367" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I remember the prisoner and the deceased coming to my house. He took her by the shoulders and the coachman by the feet and brought her along; she was dead as I thought.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to take her in?</p>
               <p>J. Price. He would persuade me she was but dead drunk. I saw her again about six o'clock in the morning. She was just a little warm in her body, but her limbs were quite stiff.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the prisoner then ?</p>
               <p>J. Price. He was then gone. The very moment he came out I ordered the maid to go and see how the woman did.</p>
               <p>Q. What, did not you apprehend she was dead before?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175609150028"></xptr>J. Price. I did apprehend she was dead before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner ever come to your house after that?</p>
               <p>J. Price. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Who buried the woman?</p>
               <p>J. Price. I did, two days after.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to bury her without sending for the coroner?</p>
               <p>J. Price. I thought it was a scheme of some body to bring a woman out of a lodging house for me to bury. I did not think any thing else but that she was dead drunk, there being no marks of violence upon her. She was as fine a corps as ever I saw in my life. There were enough and enough people to see it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not she swell in her stomach?</p>
               <p>J. Price. Not a quarter so much as I have known some; but what liquor she had work'd out at her mouth was very strong.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-46-person368">
                  James 
                  Hambleton 
               <interp inst="t17560915-46-person368" type="surname" value="Hambleton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-46-person368" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-46-person368" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I took the prisoner up in my coach the second of August, and a woman along with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she come into the coach herself, or was she brought in?</p>
               <p>Hambleton. I helped her in.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she alive or dead?</p>
               <p>Hambleton. She groan'd, but did not speak a word.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she drunk?</p>
               <p>Hambleton. Yes she was drunk to be sure.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you take her up?</p>
               <p>Hambleton. I took her up at the White-Horse in Little-Britain.</p>
               <p>Q. How far did you drive her?</p>
               <p>Hambleton. I drove her about one third of a mile. They called coach as I went by the door.</p>
               <p>Q. Who desired you to take her in?</p>
               <p>Hambleton. The prisoner did. He said he was only going to Smithfield. I said I lived in Cold-Bath-Fields, and was going home; he said, then that will not hurt you. I helped him into the coach along with her; he said go gently, and take care of her, do not hurry too fast. When I came into Smithfield I asked him where I must go; he said just into Chick-Lane. I stopped at the place, and helped her out.</p>
               <p>Q. How was she when you helped her out?</p>
               <p>Hambleton. She was much as she was when we put her in. I saw no alteration in her, there was a strange man coming by, and he helped us with her.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you apprehend there was any violence done to the woman ?</p>
               <p>Hambleton. I apprehend there was not. He bid me take care when we helped her out.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17560915-46-verdict237" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560915-46-verdict237" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
