<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17591205-34">
               <interp inst="t17591205-34" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591205-34" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591205-34" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17591205"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591205-34" type="date" value="17591205"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17591205-34-off174-c271" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-34-defend340 t17591205-34-off174 t17591205-34-verdict177"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175912050032"></xptr>38. (L) 
               
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-defend340" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Tipton 
                  <interp inst="t17591205-34-defend340" type="surname" value="Tipton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-defend340" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-defend340" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17591205-34-deflabel173" type="occupation">victualler</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-34-defend340 t17591205-34-deflabel173"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17591205-34-off174" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-off174" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-off174" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               the willful murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17591205-34-victim342" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Walker 
                        <interp inst="t17591205-34-victim342" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17591205-34-victim342" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17591205-34-victim342" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-34-off174 t17591205-34-victim342"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  ; for that he, not having the fear of God before his eyes, but being moved by the instigation of the devil, on the <rs id="t17591205-34-cd175" type="crimeDate">15th of August</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-34-off174 t17591205-34-cd175"></join>, in a certain chamber, called the Club-room, belonging to the alehouse of the said 
                     <persName id="t17591205-34-person343">
                        William 
                        Tipton 
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person343" type="surname" value="Tipton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17591205-34-person343" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17591205-34-person343" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , called the <placeName id="t17591205-34-crimeloc176">Fox and Bird-cage</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-crimeloc176" type="placeName" value="Fox and Bird-cage"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-crimeloc176" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-34-off174 t17591205-34-crimeloc176"></join>, feloniously, willfully, and of malice afore thought, did make an assault, and he, with both his hands, did take the said 
                     <persName id="t17591205-34-person344">
                        William 
                        Walker 
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person344" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17591205-34-person344" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17591205-34-person344" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , and cast and threw him out of the window into the street, upon the pavement of stones, by which means he received a mortal bruise on the fore part of his head, by which bruise he languished from the 15th of August to the 22d of October, on which said day he did die, in London.
            </rs> ||</p>
               <p>Mr. Potts. I am surgeon to St. Bartholomew's hospital; the deceased 
               <persName id="t17591205-34-person345">
                  William 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person345" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person345" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person345" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was brought in there on the 15th of August last. I saw him in about an hour after he was brought in, and found him quite senseless, with a very considerable bruise on the fore part of his head; from the appearances and from the symptoms, I had geat reason to conclude his scull was broke, and on removing the scalp I found it so, in two places.</p>
               <p>Q. What part of the scull was it?</p>
               <p>Potts. They were both in the fore part of the head, and no doubt both produced by the same blow; the two places were little more than a finger's breadth distance. I trapan'd him immedi ately.</p>
               <p>Q. What is that? It is necessary the jury should know.</p>
               <p>Potts. That is making a hole in the scull, and taking a piece out.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he die?</p>
               <p>Potts. About the middle of October.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he die of?</p>
               <p>Potts. Of that fractured scull.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain of that ?</p>
               <p>Potts. I have not the smallest doubt concerning it.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you make any judgment whether he was fuddled at the time that he received the fracture ?</p>
               <p>Potts. It is not possible in those cases to distinguish that, for the symptoms produced by the pressure of this bone, so totally deprive a man of any kind of voluntary action, that it is impossible to know whether he was fuddled or not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear him make any declaration?</p>
               <p>Potts. No; when I first saw him he was incapable of speech, and after that he became capable in a very particular manner, but I never heard him speak sensibly at all during the whole time; I only speak for myself.</p>
               <p>Q. How often did you see him?</p>
               <p>Potts. I certainly saw him every other day, and sometimes every day.</p>
               <p>Q. For how long did you see him every day?</p>
               <p>Potts. Perhaps for the first fortnight.</p>
               <p>Q. During that time did you never find him in his senses ?</p>
               <p>Potts. During that time I did not perceive he was; they appeared to me to be clearly lost.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body attend him besides you?</p>
               <p>Potts. My young man saw him every day; if he had been sensible he would have asked him some question or other, which he never did.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after he was brought in might it be before you saw him?</p>
               <p>Potts. I believe I might see him within the hour.</p>
               <p>Q. From the nature of the fractures and trapanning, whether you think he could be in his senses or not, so as to know what he said?</p>
               <p>Potts. That is impossible for me or any body to answer. I could run over a great many hard words, but I cannot answer that: Sometimes very bad fractures do not deprive people of their senses, and sometimes very trifling affairs of fractures render them totally deprived of their senses.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person346">
                  James 
                  Gordon 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person346" type="surname" value="Gordon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person346" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person346" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an apprentice to Mr. Potts. I saw the deceased within the space of time I could go from our house to the hospital, which was within half an hour after he was brought in.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he sensible at that time?</p>
               <p>Gordon. No, he was not.</p>
               <p>Q. How often did you attend him?</p>
               <p>Gordon. I attended him every day, once or twice a day; the first week or ten days he was there, I was with him twice a day, and the remainder of the time every day</p>
               <p>Q. Did you attend him all the time to his death ?</p>
               <p>Gordon. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see him in his senses?</p>
               <p>Gordon. I never did.</p>
         
               <p>Note, The Last Part of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17591205-34">
                  <interp inst="t17591205-34" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17591205-34" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17591205-34" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17591205"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17591205-34" type="date" value="17591205"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175912050033"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON, And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 5th, Thursday the 6th, and Friday the 7th, of DECEMBER.</p>

                  <p>In the Thirty-third Year of His MAJESTY'S Reign NUMBER I. PART III. for the YEAR 1760. Being the First SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of The Right Honble Sir 
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person347">
                     THOMAS 
                     CHITTY 
                  <interp inst="t17591205-34-person347" type="surname" value="CHITTY"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17591205-34-person347" type="given" value="THOMAS"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17591205-34-person347" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Knt. LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by G. KEARSLY (Successor to the late Mr. Robinson) at the Golden-Lion, in Ludgate-Street, 1759,</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175912050034"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, and Oyer and Terminer, for the City of LONDON, and at the General 
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person348">
                     Sessions
                  <interp inst="t17591205-34-person348" type="given" value="Sessions"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17591205-34-person348" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                     </persName>
                of Gaol Delivery of Newgate, holden for the said City of LONDON, and County of MIDDLESEX, at Justice-Hall in the Old-Bailey, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Q. COULD you form any judgement when he came into the hospital whether he was in liquor, or whether his insensibility proceeded from the blow?</p>
               <p>Gordon. There is no forming any judgement of that.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear any questions asked him?</p>
               <p>Gordon. The people about him have asked him who threw him out of the window, but I did not give any attention to it, thinking him not in his senses.</p>
               <p>Q. Who has asked him any questions when you have been there?</p>
               <p>Gordon. I have been there when the sister of the ward has asked him who threw him out, and he has mentioned the word Tipton, only the word Tipton.</p>
               <p>Q. How often have you heard that question asked?</p>
               <p>Gordon. I cannot pretend to say how often; I have heard it asked.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear him use any continued discourse at any time?</p>
               <p>Gordon. Never. I have heard them ask him whether he would have any food; he has said, yes or no, and to the other question he has said Tipton; yet at no time I thought him sensible.</p>
               <p>Q. When he answered Tipton, did not you apprehend he was in his senses?</p>
               <p>Gordon. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Why?</p>
               <p>Gordon. Because he did not appear to be so.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he in other particulars?</p>
               <p>Gordon. I never asked him any questions.</p>
               <p>Q. Why so ?</p>
               <p>Gordon. Because I did not think him capable of giving any sensible answer.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take him not to be in his senses all the time?</p>
               <p>Gordon. I did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person349">
                  Susannah 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person349" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person349" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person349" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the prisoner at the bar; he lived in Arthur Street, Goswell Street, at the Fox and Bird Cage.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. I lived at Mr. Manning's, a baker, in Arthur Street.</p>
               <p>Q. How near is that to the prisoner's house?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. That is about eight or nine yards from it, facing it, a little on one side.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the deceased?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. I did, by sight.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see him last?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. On the 15th of August last I saw him sitting in the window of the prisoner's house.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you seen him before that day?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. No; this was about four or five o'clock in the afternoon.</p>
               <p>Q. What window was it?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. It was the middle window up one pair of stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a window?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. A sash window.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the sash up or down?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. The sash was up.</p>
               <p>Q. Is there a road along that street ?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. It is a road way, a paved street of rough stones.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he sit in the window?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. He was sitting upon the window seat, leaning with his elbow. [She described it as leaning his elbow on the bottom of the window, higher than the seat he sat upon.]</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you seen him sitting so before the accident happened?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175912050035"></xptr>S. Clark. About five minutes before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him afterwards?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. I saw him lying on the ground.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him sit down in the window at first?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. No, I did not; but I saw him sitting there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him all the time?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. No, only about five or six minutes; after I had seen him sitting I heard the fall.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any body in the room?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. I only saw Mr. Blower in the room besides.</p>
               <p>Q. How wide is the street?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. It may be twelve or thirteen yards wide.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you near enough to hear what was said?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. I heard some high words, but I do not know who they were between; I did not take notice of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell whether they were between the deceased Walker and any body else?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. How many voices did you hear in the room?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you observe at that time whether Walker was sober or fuddled?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. That I cannot tell. for I did not give ear at all to what they were talking of; they were talking aloud, but I did not think what would happen.</p>
               <p>Q. What was you about at the time?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. I was sitting at work with my needle at the window in my room, and heard a talking very loud; they were at a play, which I believe they call rolipoly, that was said afterwards; I did not see them at it, but I heard them. When I heard something fall, I ran down stairs directly, and there saw Walker lying in the street. I looked up directly, and said to Mr. Tipton, how could you fling a man so out at the window?</p>
               <p>Q. Where was Tipton ?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. He was then looking out at window.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Walker lying upon the ground when you was looking from your own window?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Tipton at the window then?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. No, I did not; but when I came down he stood looking out at the window.</p>
               <p>Q. What did Tipton say when you spoke to him ?</p>
               <p>Clark. He d - 'd me for a bitch, and said he did not come out at the window.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say where he came from ?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. He said he was coming from Mr. Strong's along the penthouse, and fell down.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does Mr. Strong live?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. His house is next to Tipton's; there is a penthouse under that window all along, which joins both houses; it is shelving, but people may walk along it, if they take care.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see Walker on that penthouse?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. No.</p>
               <p>Q. What passed next?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. I saw Tipton come down to his own tap-room, and fling up the window; he stood and swore, but I went away to my own room, my child crying, so heard nothing of what he said.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Tipton in the room, while Walker was sitting at the window?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. No.</p>
               <p>Q. How then came you to ask him how he could do so, to throw the man out of the window ?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. Because he is a very dissolute man in swearing and cursing; I have seen him in passions several times, which gave me reason to think so; I had no other reason.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know whether any body saw him fall?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. I can't tell whether any of the other witnesses did or not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person350">
                  Ann 
                  Adams 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person350" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person350" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person350" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I did live at Mr. Tipton's as a servant, just a week.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember the deceased being at your house on the 15th of August?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him come in that day?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he come in?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. I cannot justly remember, he came in the morning first.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he live near your master's house?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. He did.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he stay there the first time?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. I can't tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he dine there?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. No; he went away before dinner, and came again afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did he come after dinner?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. I can't justly tell.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of him, when he came after dinner?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. He was up in the club room.</p>
               <p>Q. Who else was there?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. Nobody but Mr. Blower and Mr. Tipton.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know they were all three there?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175912050036"></xptr>A. Adams. I carried them up a bowl of liquor, the last they had.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was Walker in the room?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. I can't say.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he there above an hour?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. He was.</p>
               <p>Q. How many bowls had they?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. I don't know, I carried up no more than that.</p>
               <p>Q. What were they doing when you went up?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. Mr. Blower was setting the pegs up, Mr. Tipton was standing in the middle of the room, and Mr. Walker sat in the middle window.</p>
               <p>Q. What pegs? explain that.</p>
               <p>A. Adams. Rolipoly pegs.</p>
               <p>Q. How was Walker sitting ?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. In his shirt, and nothing on his head, with his hands doubled before him.</p>
               <p>Q. On what did he sit?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. On the seat of the window, the edge of the window was above where he sat.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was that before he fell?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. About ten minutes, as near as I can guess.</p>
               <p>Q. How came he to be in his shirt?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. He came in his shirt, with his sleeves tuck'd up, and nothing on his head.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know whether he was at play with them ?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. There was never a one at play when I carried up that bowl.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you stay there any time ?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. I came down directly.</p>
               <p>Q. Where they quiet and peaceable at that time ?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. There was never a word said, I heard not a word.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you at the time Walker fell ?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. I was backwards washing, I did not see him fall.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Walker fuddled ?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. I cannot tell whether he was or not ?</p>
               <p>Q. What liquor had they ?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. I cannot tell whether it was brandy and water, or run and water.</p>
               <p>Q. How much did you carry up ?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. The bowl hold a shilling-worth.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the first alarm you heard?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. Mrs. Tipton came out of the bar, and cried and said, the young fellow was either thrown out of the window, or fell out of it.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do upon this ?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. Mr. Blower came down out of the room first, and Mr. Tipton followed him; Mr. Blower wanted to go, and Mr. Tipton said he should not go, for if one went to gaol the other should.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was this after your mistress gave the alarm?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. This was about 5 minutes after.</p>
               <p>Q. Mention Tipton's words, the same he made use of.</p>
               <p>A. Adams. Tipton said, d - n him he should not go, for if one went to gaol the other should.</p>
               <p>Q. What did Blower say to that ?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. Never a word.</p>
               <p>Q. What was done after this?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. They cried out for some water at the door, and I was going to carry some. Mr. Tipton said I should not carry him any, let him lie and be d - d.</p>
               <p>Q. What was done after this ?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. I never saw the deceased afterwards, till they brought him in a shell to Mr. Andrew's house.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he been playing at rolipoly in the morning?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. I cannot say whether he had or not.</p>
               <p>Q. How much liquor had they drank ?</p>
               <p>A. Adams. I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person351">
                  Hannah 
                  Parlament 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person351" type="surname" value="Parlament"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person351" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person351" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Green-harbour-court.</p>
               <p>Q. How near is that to the house of the prisoner at the bar ?</p>
               <p>H. Parlament. It is within a very little way?</p>
               <p>Q. What do you know concerning this matter ?</p>
               <p>H. Parlament. I have heard Mr. Tipton divers times threaten to fling the young fellow out of the window.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear him threaten it the day that this thing happened?</p>
               <p>H. Parlament. No.</p>
               <p>Q. When was it?</p>
               <p>H. Parlament. I cannot say the day of the month, nor the month, but I have heard him threaten it several times.</p>
               <p>Q. What were his words ?</p>
               <p>H. Parlament. I have heard him say, when words have arose, he would throw him out at the window, be it what it will.</p>
               <p>Q. How long before this accidents?</p>
               <p>H. Parlament. Near two months before. I saw him once take him up in his arms to throw him out, and laid hold of him, that he should not.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was this before the accident?</p>
               <p>H. Parlament. This was I believe about a fortnight before; when there has been a squable amongst other people, who was going, and they have<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175912050037"></xptr> had words amongst themselves, Mr. Tipton has taken it up.</p>
               <p>Q. What room was this in?</p>
               <p>H. Parlament. This was the one pair of stairs room; he offered to hurl him out of the same window, that by all account, he was thrown out at.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he make any offer to throw him out?</p>
               <p>H. Parlament. I saw him put his legs out at the window swearing many bitter words that he would hurl him out.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he take him up?</p>
               <p>H. Parlament. He took him up with one hand under his legs, his head lying on his left arm, and said d - n your soul I will burl you out of the window, putting his legs out as far as his thighs.</p>
               <p>Q. What size was the deceased?</p>
               <p>H. Parlament. He was a little man, deformed in his legs, what they call bandy-leg'd, and a weakly man.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at the house the day this thing was done?</p>
               <p>H. Parlament. No, I was not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person352">
                  Henry 
                  Bucher 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person352" type="surname" value="Bucher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person352" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person352" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know but very little of it; the day the thing happened, just after it was done, Tipton and Blower were going into a hackney-coach, to go before the justice.</p>
               <p>Q. About what hour was this?</p>
               <p>Bucher. About 3 or 4 o'clock. I knowing the deceased, said to Tipton as he was going to get in, how came you to throw the poor fellow out of the window? he said he did not know how he came to do it; that was all I heard him say.</p>
               <p>Q. Mention it again, and be sure give the right answer he made?</p>
               <p>Bucher. As he was going to get into the coach, he past by me; I said to him, Tipton, how came you to throw the poor fellow out at the window; he said, I don't know how I came to do it. I am sure he said these words, and in that manner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person353">
                  Richard 
                  Alingham 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person353" type="surname" value="Alingham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person353" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person353" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have been in that room several times, when several people have been there, with Tipton, the prisoner at the bar, and the deceased, and the prisoner has offered to hurl him out of the window 5 or 6 times one after another, and once more than ordinary he catched him up in his arms, and was going to hurl him out, but I laid hold of him and hindred him.</p>
               <p>Q. What room was this in?</p>
               <p>Alingham. In the same room; there is a rolipoly in it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was 
               <persName id="t17591205-34-person354">
                  Hannah 
                  Parlament 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person354" type="surname" value="Parlament"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person354" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person354" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             there at that time ?</p>
               <p>Alingham. She was.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was that before this thing happened?</p>
               <p>Alingham. That was 5 or 6 weeks before.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he take him up?</p>
               <p>Alingham. He had taken him up with his arm under the deceased's head, and with the other hand held him under his hams, and his legs were a little way out of the window?</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17591205-34-person355">
                  Hannah 
                  Parlament 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person355" type="surname" value="Parlament"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person355" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person355" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Was you in the room at the time this witness speaks of?</p>
               <p>H. Parlament. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you be particular as to what time it was?</p>
               <p>H. Parlament. I cannot; I know Mr. Alingham was there at the time, he is my father, and laid hold of Tipton's arm at the time.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. to Alingham. Have you ever play'd there at rolipoly?</p>
               <p>Alingham. I have with the deceased, several times.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he threatened him before this?</p>
               <p>Alingham. He had threatened him 5 or 6 weeks before this was done.</p>
               <p>Q. Were not they perfect friends after that?</p>
               <p>Alingham. The deceased came to the house every day, but they were not friends, for when ever he came Tipton was always quarrelling with him.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he quarrel with him for?</p>
               <p>Alingham. I do not know; Walker used to play at rolipoly, he was then at play, and I along with him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person356">
                  Mary 
                  Setathurt 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person356" type="surname" value="Setathurt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person356" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person356" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming by the window along Arthur-Street under the prisoner's window, with my basket on my head; the deceased with his falling touched my basket; then I looked down, and saw him lying in his shirt, with his eyes fix'd in his head; the man of the alehouse looked out at the window and said d - n him, d - n him, let him lie, three times.</p>
               <p>Q. How did the deceased fall?</p>
               <p>M. Setathurt. He fell with his head foremost, and his legs lay open.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he fall upon?</p>
               <p>M. Setathurt. I cannot tell whether he fell against the step or the ground, but I think he fell with his head foremost.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the man of the house?</p>
               <p>M. Setathurt. I knew him plain enough, when he was before justice Welch; he came down and looked thro' the hole of the window, to see how pretty he lay.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you stay there?</p>
               <p>M. Setathurt. I ran and fetched the surgeon,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175912050038"></xptr> and instead of bringing one I brought two.</p>

               <p>Q. What became of the deceased?</p>
               <p>Mr. Setathurt. They got him first into his master's house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person357">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Gosling 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person357" type="surname" value="Gosling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person357" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person357" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Nurse belonging to St. Bartholomew's hospital; the next day, when Mr. Potts ordered a double watch to be with the deceased, I was one, and on the 24th of August, his master Mr. Andrews came in the morning and said to him, do you know me, Will; he said, yes; then, said he, tell me how the affair happened, and inquired of him whether he jump'd out at the window, or whether he fell out, or how it was; he said, he flung me out; his master said, what he, and he replied, Tipton. Then his master asked him who was in the room besides Tipton and he, and he said Blower; then he asked him if Blower touch'd him, and he said, No; he asked him how he flung him out, and he said he took me up in his arms and flung me out so, putting his arms out. [She describes with her hands how he described it to her.]</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any declarations at any other time?</p>
               <p>E. Gosling. Once at another time I heard him say something of it. I asked him one day, and said, Will, will you tell me how this affair happened? He seemed to be very solitary, and told me he would not tell me.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was it before he died?</p>
               <p>E. Gosling. I believe it was three weeks or a month before he died: I was with him eight weeks before he died.</p>
               <p>Q. What were his words?</p>
               <p>E. Gosling. He said, no. I said, why will you not tell me? He said, it was of consequence, and of great consequence. I said, will you sooner suffer, and lose your own life, than tell who did it? He answered, yes, he would, and said no more.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear him say any thing any other time?</p>
               <p>E. Gosling. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you look upon him at any time to be sensible ?</p>
               <p>E. Gosling. He was sometimes in his senses, and sometimes not; oftentimes he would give a rational answer.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he speak intelligibly?</p>
               <p>E. Gosling. He spoke very intelligibly at the time his master asked him those questions. I can't swear he was ever a very sensible man in his life time, but he gave rational answers.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take him to know what he talked of?</p>
               <p>E. Gosling. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the last time that you asked him that question?</p>
               <p>E. Gosling. That was about three weeks before he died.</p>
               <p>Q. Between the 24th of August to the beginning of October, had any body come to visit him ?</p>
               <p>E. Gosling. Nobody but his acquaintance to look at him.</p>
               <p>Q. Would he ever converse with them?</p>
               <p>E. Gosling. Sometimes he would speak to them, and sometimes not; he appeared upon a sulkish order. Sometimes he would give a rational answer, and sometimes not.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was this conversation between you and him, after that between him and his master?</p>
               <p>E. Gosling. It may be about a week or fortnight after that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person358">
                  George 
                  Penny 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person358" type="surname" value="Penny"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person358" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person358" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was a patient in St. Bartholomew's Hospital.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember Walker being brought in there?</p>
               <p>Penny. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. How soon after he was brought in did you see him?</p>
               <p>Penny. I saw him the minute he was brought in, and the next morning he called out, and beg'd to be lifted up; I went to lend the nurse a hand to lift him up; some persons came in to see him at the same time, one of which said, Bill, who threw you out of the window?</p>
               <p>Q. Who was the person which asked that question?</p>
               <p>Penny. I do not know who it was.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the deceased's answer ?</p>
               <p>Penny. He answered, Tipton; the same person again said, who threw you out of the window? the deceased a second time said, Tipton.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you apprehend him to be in his senses?</p>
               <p>Penny. By the words he made use of, in begging to be lifted up, I apprehend he was in his senses.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person359">
                  William 
                  Andrews 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person359" type="surname" value="Andrews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person359" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person359" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to the hospital on the 22d of August; I put it down in writing, because I would be particular.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you his master?</p>
               <p>Andrews. I was. I asked him whether he knew me, He answered, yes, I was him master Andrews. I said, Will, will you tell me how this unhappy affair happened? He said, yes. I said Will, don't put yourself in a hurry, consider it is a very weighty affair, for here are two lives at stake as well as your's, you might be fuddled, and sit upon the window, and tumble out; to which he answered, no, I did not tumble out, but he threw me out.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he was not fuddled?</p>
               <p>Andrews. No, he did not. I said, what he? He said, Tipton. Then I said, Will, was nobody<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175912050039"></xptr> else in the room besides; He answered, Blower. Then I asked him whether Blower meddled with him. He said, no, Blower was at the other end of the room. After that I might sit for the space of a minute or two, and I asked him for what reason? He said, I scored for him. I said, what did you not score fair, Will? He said, no, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any body by at the time of these declarations?</p>
               <p>Andrews. There were two people by, Mrs. Gosling was one, and one 
               <persName id="t17591205-34-person360">
                  Mary 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person360" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person360" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person360" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the other.</p>
               <p>Q. What was meant by scoring?</p>
               <p>Andrews. That was setting down the game.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he been any time with them before this accident happened?</p>
               <p>Andrews. I had been there with him about two hours before; his shirt was tucked up. I said to him, business is very much in a hurry, I would have you go home.</p>
               <p>Q. How were they then as to friendship?</p>
               <p>Andrews. They were then very good friends; I saw no malice then.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the deceased apt to drink?</p>
               <p>Andrews. He was.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he for liquor when you was with him there?</p>
               <p>Andrews. He was quite sober, having had nothing that day; he might drink once, but he would not go home; his mistress went for him, but he would not go home with her.</p>
               <p>Q. Had not you a right to order him to go home?</p>
               <p>Andrews. He being out of his time, I had no command of him. He was not used to that sort of liquor, which might take effect upon him; but I left him as sober as ever I saw him.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day did you go away?</p>
               <p>Andrews. It was about one o'clock.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person361">
                  Mary 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person361" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person361" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person361" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was one that watched in the hospital, and watched the deceased Walker.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you there the night he was brought in ?</p>
               <p>M. Jones. I was; the nurse was out, and I was in her place. After the operation was over, two or three friends came in to see him, and asked him how he came by this accident. He said, Tipton sing him cut at the window. Twice the first night, and the next morning, upon the return of the nurse, he desired something to drink, so we lifted him up, and gave him something. Upon that, a patient seeing him lifted up, asked him how he happened by that accident. He answered, Tipton flung him out. The person in a minute or two asked him again, and he said Tipton. Some days after, his scull was trapanned again. I was by when Mr. Andrews his master came and asked him some questions; it was in a morning, and the other person also was present: The deceased then had two people constantly by his bedside. His master asked him how he did, and if he knew him. The deceased said, you are Mr. Andrews, my master. He said, Billy, how happened this accident, had you no quarrel with these people? He said, no, but I scored false. Mr. Andrews said, did you fall out of the window, or how was it? He said, no, Tipton took him in his arms, and flung him out so ( extending his arm.)</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>M. Jones. I cannot recollect the day of the month.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell whether the surgeon had been there that day?</p>
               <p>M. Jones. No, it was before their time of dressing.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think he was sensible?</p>
               <p>M. Jones. Sometimes he had intervals of sense, but I do not swear he was sensible, though he was sometimes; generally he was not sensible.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you look upon him to have been in liquor or not, at the time he was brought into the hospital?</p>
               <p>M. Jones. At that time I look'd upon him to be very much in liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you distinguish his being in liquor, or was it from the effect of the blow he received in the fall?</p>
               <p>M. Jones. I never heard any bad language from him but then, when he cursed and swore during the operation.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he curse and swear the second operation?</p>
               <p>M. Jones. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he used to complain at any time?</p>
               <p>M. Jones. He always expressed a very great sense of pain.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the question, Who threw him out, or Did Tipton throw him out?</p>
               <p>M. Jones. The question was, whether he fell out, or whether he had been flung out; he said, Tipton flung him out.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person362">
                  Mary 
                  Guidner 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person362" type="surname" value="Guidner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person362" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person362" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The day after the deceased was carried to the hospital, I went thither; his master and mistress, and myself, were all by his bedside.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>M. Guidner. I am his mother.</p>
               <p>Q. Who do you call his master?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175912050040"></xptr>M. Guidner. Mr. Andrews. Mrs. Andrew stoop'd down to the bed to him and said, Will, do you know me, and he answer'd yes; she said, who am I, and he answer'd, Andrews, Mrs. Andrews; she said, who did this to you, and he answer'd, Tipton. It was towards twelve o'clock, and as the surgeons were coming, I and Mrs. Andrews were put out, and he was trapan'd; when he saw them put me out of the ward, he called Mother, Mother, several times, very loud, I heard him a pretty way off.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you spoke to him then?</p>
               <p>M. Guidner. I had not, but I went every day after that, to see him, according as my time would permit; I went very often, and his sister too.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you find him as to his senses?</p>
               <p>M. Guidner. Sometimes not sensible, and at other times very sensible; he would take me by the hand and ask me to kiss him, and said God bless you several times; they were afraid of his being put into a fever, by talking too much.</p>
               <p>Q. What day was it the master and mistress and you were there?</p>
               <p>M. Guidner. This was on the Thursday; he always knew his sister.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person363">
                  Alice 
                  Cooley 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person363" type="surname" value="Cooley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person363" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person363" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a nurse belonging to the hospital, but was not there the day the deceased was brought in. The next day I was there, when he said he was very dry, and desired to be lifted up to drink; a person that was by asked him who threw him out of the window, and he answer'd Tipton; the same person stood some time longer and then asked him again, when he said Tipton a second time.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was he in the hospital?</p>
               <p>A. Cooley. He was nine week and some odd days; I was with him all the day, and every other night.</p>
               <p>Q. In what condition was he, as to his senses?</p>
               <p>A. Cooley. At the instant he was lifted up he seem'd to speak the two words sensibly, but he did not continue so, sometimes he appear'd a little sensible, and at other times out of his senses.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he mostly in his senses, or mostly not?</p>
               <p>A. Cooley. He spake but little.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you very much with him?</p>
               <p>A. Cooley. I was with him all the day long, but went home every other night; we had a watch then.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What people attended him?</p>
               <p>A. Cooley. There were two people with him night and day for the first fortnight.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he then as to his senses?</p>
               <p>A. Cooley. He was very bad, out of his senses at one time.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Potts. Did you perceive him at any time to have any degree of sense, so as to conclude him rational?</p>
               <p>Potts. He was so very ungovernable, and so irrational, that we were obliged to confine him with what we call a strait waistcoat.</p>
               <p>Council for the Prisoner. I should be glad to know whether you have not in your practice met with persons extremely delirious, who have mentioned particular persons names, as to the recollection of a mother, or any thing of that kind, that might seem to import sense, notwithstanding they were at the same time delirious.</p>
               <p>Potts. They will call out to particular persons without doubt. I can only speak what I said before, that he never gave me a rational or sensible answer, he never gave me any thing like an intelligible answer in my hearing, but these people staid with him a great deal longer than I did; I do not speak this to invalidate what they have said.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I did not fling him out, nor was I near him; I did not see him go out, not miss him out of the room till my wife came up stairs.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person364">
                  Richard 
                  Blower 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person364" type="surname" value="Blower"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person364" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person364" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the prisoner's house that day, I came there at twelve o'clock, his house is in Arthur-street; I had been to take this house of Mr. Tipton some time before, as he was going to leave it, and I was about leaving mine; I had been that day in Petticoat-lane, and met with him at the sign of the crown, a house called my Lord Mills's, I don't know the name of the place; he said, Blower, will you go home along with me; with all my heart, said I, and went along with him; we went up one pair of stairs, and he asked me if I would have a game at rolipoly; I said, with all my heart, and we had a game; I had never seen the game but once before in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you play with?</p>
               <p>Blower. Mr. Tipton.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the deceased in the room when you went there first?</p>
               <p>Blower. No.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you been there when he came in?</p>
               <p>Blower. We had been there about half an hour; when he came in we had no discourse, but just how<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175912050041"></xptr> do you do, and how do you do, for he used Mr. Tipton's house and mine too.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he do upon coming in?</p>
               <p>Blower. He sat down on a chair or a bench, or something of that nature.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he play?</p>
               <p>Blower. He never played while we were there.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember his sitting in the window?</p>
               <p>Blower. I do, very well.</p>
               <p>Q. In what part of the window did he sit?</p>
               <p>Blower. The last time that he sat in the window, he sat in the seat of it, with his arm out upon the ledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he sit before he went to the window seat?</p>
               <p>Blower. Before that he sat upon a chair, in which I believe he scored f or us some time. Mr. Andrews came in, and he played two rubbers with me. After that he said he could stay no longer, and desired his man to go home, as his business was in great haste.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he go home?</p>
               <p>Blower. No, he did not. As soon as Mr. Andrews went out of the room, there was one 
               <persName id="t17591205-34-person365">
                  Jonas 
                  Hubbord 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person365" type="surname" value="Hubbord"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person365" type="given" value="Jonas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person365" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came up stairs and sat down, and I believe he might score for us; I cannot say whether he did or not, but he went out of the room. Then there were only us three, the deceased scored for us; he scored so long that I believe he was in liquor, and when he was in liquor he was quite helpless, you might carry him by his head and legs, and it was impossible to awake him; he had done scoring for us: I told him he did not score right, and desired him to sit down, and we would score for ourselves. He went and sat down in the window seat, with his arm over the window. I took no farther notice of him. We were quite still, and had not an angry word all the time we were in the room, neither one nor other of us. He sat there I believe the best part of an hour; at that time it might be about four o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was he there?</p>
               <p>Blower. He was there about three hours.</p>
               <p>Q. What liquor had you in the time you were there together?</p>
               <p>Blower. I believe we might have about four shillings worth of brandy and water, or rum and water; but I believe it was brandy and water.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of 
               <persName id="t17591205-34-person366">
                  William 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person366" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person366" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person366" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Blower. What became of him I could not tell, for really I did not miss him. Mr. Tipton missing him said, d - n my blood, the first man that goes out of that window again, I will make him suffer for it. I asked him the reason of that. He said, they make it a common practice of going over the penthouse from the window into the next house. Then I did not take any farther notice of the man. In about a minute or two after Mrs. Tipton came upstairs (the person was out of window) and said, how can you play? Why? said I. Said she, there is a man lying dead in the street, and the mob say he was flung through the window; we went down stairs directly.</p>
               <p>Q. What were you doing when she came up?</p>
               <p>Blower. We were playing then, I was going to bowl. I went down stairs, and Mr. Tipton after me; I went and stood in the tap room.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of Mr. Tipton?</p>
               <p>Blower. I believe he might go out at the door; the mob said, d - n him, d - n him, making such a noise, that I could not stay in the tap room any longer. I went backwards into the kitchen, and sat down there, and after a little time Mr. Andrews came into the kitchen (he was headborough) to make inquiry how it was. I said, go your way, take care of the man, and send him to the hospital, for I will not stir.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Mr. Tipton meddle with him in the club room?</p>
               <p>Blower. I don't believe Mr. Tipton ever touched him.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think it possible if any person in that room had taken this man and thrown him out of the room, but you must have seen him?</p>
               <p>Blower. I think it is impossible but I must have seen him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any body lay hands on him?</p>
               <p>Blower. I never saw any body touch him, to the best of my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the man in liquor?</p>
               <p>Blower. He was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you continue your gaming without stoping?</p>
               <p>Blower. We did, and when Mrs. Tipton came up we had bowled twice a piece, which was after this man was gone out of the window, I believe.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you played after he sat in the window?</p>
               <p>Blower. We played for almost an hour and half after he sat there.</p>
               <p>Q. How large is the room?</p>
               <p>Blower. It is but a small place; I believe it is not six yards over. I was never up stairs there but once in my life before. They tell me Mr. Strong's men have gone backwards and forwards there over that place from one house to the other.</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175912050042"></xptr>Q. How long had he left off scoring?</p>
               <p>Blower. He had left off scoring, and continued sitting there half an hour and better.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you continue playing all the time?</p>
               <p>Blower. We did.</p>
               <p>Q. What kind of play is it?</p>
               <p>Blower. In the middle of the room there are fifteen or sixteen brass nails on the floor, and there is a bowl almost in the shape of a bowl dish, which runs round, and comes in any where, where it happens, and knocks down pins which stand upon the brass nails.</p>
               <p>Q. Does one bowl such a number of bowls, and then the other, or how?</p>
               <p>Blower. One bowls first, and then the other.</p>
               <p>Q. At the time you were bowling, when Tipton said he would make them suffer that went out at the window again, what was you doing?</p>
               <p>Blower. I was just going to bowl, and he had just bowled before.</p>
               <p>Q. How long before?</p>
               <p>Blower. I do not believe he had bowled a minute before, nor nothing like it; I bowled as soon as the pins were set up again.</p>
               <p>Q. How many might he knock down?</p>
               <p>Blower. He might knock down four or five.</p>
               <p>Q. Who set the pins up?</p>
               <p>Blower. I believe we both set them up.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure the deceased was not in the window at that time you were setting up the pins ?</p>
               <p>Blower. I am not sure he was not; we were both very eager of play.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was he sitting from the pins?</p>
               <p>Blower. He was sitting just by them.</p>
               <p>Q. How near were the pins from the window?</p>
               <p>Blower. They were about two yards and half from the window.</p>
               <p>Q. How near to the pins do you stand when you bowl?</p>
               <p>Blower. We do not stand half a yard from the pins; the bowl has a bias, and it runs round; when he was bowling he stood on the other side of the pins, not that side which the window is of; the pins were betwixt him and the window when he bowled.</p>
               <p>Q. At the time he bowled, can you say yes or no, whether Walker was still in the window?</p>
               <p>Blower. That I cannot say, I did not miss him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you perceive the deceased had moved?</p>
               <p>Blower. No, I did not; we set up the pins, and fell to play again assoon as they were up.</p>
               <p>Q. How can you take upon yourself to say, Tipton did not move near the window?</p>
               <p>Blower. I don't believe he moved near it, but I can't be sure, for I never thought of any such thing happening.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think it is possible for a man to be in that room and another fling him out of the window, without your seeing him.</p>
               <p>Blower. I think it is impossible.</p>
               <p>Q. What part of the room was he in when he called out?</p>
               <p>Blower. He was between the pins and the window then.</p>
               <p>Q. How far from the window?</p>
               <p>Blower. About two yards from it.</p>
               <p>Q. What posture was he in?</p>
               <p>Blower. He stood still, but seem'd to be in a passion about it; he stood upright, as I do now.</p>
               <p>Q. In what position was you?</p>
               <p>Blower. I was stooping down.</p>
               <p>Q. Which way was your face?</p>
               <p>Blower. My face was towards him and the window.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell how long it was between Tipton's bowling and his calling out?</p>
               <p>Blower. It might be a minute.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think that was the most?</p>
               <p>Blower. I don't believe it was more.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was Walker at the time of his calling out?</p>
               <p>Blower. He was then out at the window.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him out at the window?</p>
               <p>Blower. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. After you missed Walker out of the room, did Tipton go to the window ?</p>
               <p>Blower. Yes, he did, and look'd thro' the window.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say then?</p>
               <p>Blower. I did not hear him say any thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body call to him out of the street?</p>
               <p>Blower. I did not hear any body call to him. I went to the window as well as he after him, but the penthouse being almost a yard broad, we could not see the deceased.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you see?</p>
               <p>Blower. There was a croud of people there. Mrs. Tipton came up to us.</p>
               <p>Q. How soon did she come up after you missed Walker?</p>
               <p>Blower. She came up in a minute or two afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you take upon yourself with certainty, and of your own knowledge, to say that Tipton<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175912050043"></xptr> did not throw this man out of the window?</p>
               <p>Blower. I swear I never saw him touch him.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you swear he did not go towards him, before he went out at the window?</p>
               <p>Blower. I can swear I did not see him meddle with him; we both went towards him, we always went round our pins, and he was very near us.</p>
               <p>Q. You say you can swear you never saw him touch him, will you swear he did not touch him?</p>
               <p>Blower. No, I will not swear that; he might touch him when my back was towards him, but I cannot think he did.</p>
               <p>Q. What distance of time was it between your seeing Walker sitting in the window, and people crying out and the like, as you mention?</p>
               <p>Blower. It might be two or three minutes. I did not miss him till Mr. Tipton spoke as I have mention'd; and he told me it was usual for people to go out of that window upon the penthouse.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person367">
                  James 
                  Bradley 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person367" type="surname" value="Bradley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person367" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person367" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the room these people were playing at rolipoly in.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the middle window?</p>
               <p>Bradley. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Describe that window.</p>
               <p>Bradley. The room is on the first floor, and our workshop is on the same; there is a penthouse that runs along before that window and also our workshop window, we are used to walk along that penthouse from our shop to that window, the two houses are together.</p>
               <p>Q. Whose house do you mean?</p>
               <p>Bradley. Mr. Strong's house and Mr. Tipton's.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know Walker?</p>
               <p>Bradley. I did, mighty well; he used to frequent that house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see Walker make use of that way over the penthouse ?</p>
               <p>Bradley. I can't say I ever did; I have seen Mr. Strong's men go out of that window several times in a day.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person368">
                  Thomas 
                  Burroughs 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person368" type="surname" value="Burroughs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person368" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person368" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know this house.</p>
               <p>Q. How high is the lower frame of the window, to step out upon the penthouse?</p>
               <p>Burroughs. It is but a trifle of a way, not far; I have several times went out at that window, two or three times in a day.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it a place where you could walk safe along?</p>
               <p>Burroughs. I have walked safe along it several times, and another person may do it; I only put my hand against the wall.</p>
               <p>Q. How wide is it?</p>
               <p>Burroughs. I believe it may be a foot and a half wide, or more; I worked in the next house, and was a lodger in the publick house, and sometimes when I was lock'd out I used to go that way.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of any body else that ever went that way besides yourself?</p>
               <p>Burroughs. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. How high is that penthouse?</p>
               <p>Burroughs. If a person was to hang by his hands upon it, his feet might be two or three feet from the ground.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Walker fall?</p>
               <p>Burroughs. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. How soon did you see him after he fell?</p>
               <p>Burroughs. I saw him in a few moments after.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear him say any thing?</p>
               <p>Burroughs. I asked him who threw him out of the window; he said, Tipton and Blower. This was as soon as ever he could speak; whether he was in his senses or not, I cannot say.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person369">
                  Mary 
                  Dhwith 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person369" type="surname" value="Dhwith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person369" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person369" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw Walker at that middle window.</p>
               <p>Q. What day, and what time of the day?</p>
               <p>M. Dhwith. Betwixt three and four in the afternoon of the 15th of August, the day he fell down.</p>
               <p>Q. In what posture did he stand?</p>
               <p>M. Dhwith. I was very busy washing at my own shop, facing Mr. Tipton's house. I went to the door to throw out some water, and saw Walker sitting. I said take care or you'll be down. I went in again, and I never saw him more; he had one leg out at the window, to the best of my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the reason you called to him to take care?</p>
               <p>M. Dhwith. Because I had known him a great while.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you think him in a posture likely to fall?</p>
               <p>M. Dhwith. I don't know; he might sit out at a window and not fall.</p>
               <p>Q. Describe how he was sitting?</p>
               <p>M. Dhwith. To the best of my knowledge he sat with one leg out of the window, and I saw him no more till I saw him in the street.</p>
               <p>Q. Did his legs touch the penthouse?</p>
               <p>M. Dhwith. I don't believe they did, they were too short; I held up my hand and said, take care, you'll be down.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he make you any answer?</p>
               <p>M. Dhwith. No.</p>
               <p>Q. You say one leg was over the window, where was his body?</p>
               <p>M. Dhwith. He sat right up, cross the place, cross the window.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after that did he fall down?</p>
               <p>M. Dhwith. It was not a great while.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175912050044"></xptr>Q. How long?</p>
               <p>M. Dhwith. It might be about fifteen minutes, for he had been down some time before I saw him.</p>
               <p>Q. to Blower. When you saw him sitting in the window seat, the last time you saw him in the room, how was he sitting?</p>
               <p>Blower. He was sitting in the window seat with his arm leaning on the frame.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him sitting cross the window frame?</p>
               <p>Blower. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you at all see him attempt to get out at the window?</p>
               <p>Blower. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. to M. Dhwith. Do you know anything more that is material?</p>
               <p>M. Dhwith. I can't believe otherwise than that Tipton threw him out at the window.</p>
               <p>Q. What makes you believe so?</p>
               <p>M. Dhwith. Because he would not have come down of himself.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person370">
                  Robert 
                  Cambridge 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person370" type="surname" value="Cambridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person370" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person370" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw Walker near 4 o'clock. I went right against the house of Mr. Tipton to fetch an empty basket, shutting the door after me. I saw Walker out at the window. I catch'd the basket up and look'd at him, he was holding by the frame of the window, standing on the penthouse, he was in his shirt, with neither hat nor cap on, but I took the basket and went along.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know Walker ?</p>
               <p>Cambridge. I had seen him before. My master filled the basket with rubbish, and I carry'd it a little way. When I came back again, I saw people running to this house, and said to my master, I cannot think what is the matter at Mr. Tipton's, there are a great many people there. My master went to see what was the matter, and I saw the people running very thick. My master came back to me and said, I wish you had not sent me. I asked him why, and he said because Tipton had push'd a man out at the window; then I said I saw him out at the window before.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was it that you saw him on the penthouse, before you saw the people running?</p>
               <p>Cambridge. It was about five minutes; he was holding by the frame of the window, with his back towards the street.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any body at the window besides him?</p>
               <p>Cambridge. No, I saw nobody at all besides him, no soul else.</p>
               <p>Q. to Blower. Did you see Walker stand upon the penthouse?</p>
               <p>Blower. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person371">
                  Mary 
                  Thomas 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person371" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person371" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person371" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know Tipton's house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the deceased?</p>
               <p>M. Thomas. I did. I remember seeing him at that house on a Wednesday, about four or five o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you mean the day that he fell down?</p>
               <p>M. Thomas. I do. I saw him out at the middle window almost.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you at the time?</p>
               <p>M. Thomas. I was facing the window, standing at a door; he was with his knee on the ledge of the window, with his foot just out, and his right-hand upon the penthouse.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you continue looking at him?</p>
               <p>M. Thomas. I did not continue any time at all; I went home about my master's business.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you call to him?</p>
               <p>M. Thomas. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any noise or disturbance?</p>
               <p>M. Thomas. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any body at the window besides himself?</p>
               <p>M. Thomas. No; I saw nobody there besides himself.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him sitting in the window before?</p>
               <p>M. Thomas. No, I did not; the first that I saw of him was with his knee upon the ledge of the window.</p>
               <p>Q. Which knee was it?</p>
               <p>M. Thomas. His right knee was upon the ledge, his right foot was just over the ledge, and his right-hand down on the penthouse.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was that before the bustle was in the street?</p>
               <p>M. Thomas. To the best of my remembrance it was about a quarter of an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it before the bustle began, or before you heard it?</p>
               <p>M. Thomas. I believe it was before I heard it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any body near him?</p>
               <p>M. Thomas. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. to Blower. What distance is it from the botton edge of the window to the penthouse ?</p>
               <p>Blower. It may be about half a yard.</p>
               <p>Q. Could a man, with his knee on the window, reach down to the penthouse, and not fall ?</p>
               <p>Blower. Yes; the window is stopping.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person372">
                  Jonas 
                  Hubbord 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person372" type="surname" value="Hubbord"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person372" type="given" value="Jonas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person372" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have measured the distance from the penthouse to the street, from the top of<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175912050045"></xptr> the penthouse next to the window cill is 13 feet 10 inche to the ground, and from the top of the penthouse to the window cill is 6 inches, 3 the cill, and 3 the brick work; a person may very well put his hand out and lean upon the penthouse.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you measure it?</p>
               <p>Hubbord. I measur'd it to day twice; the penthouse is 2 foot 2 inches wide, and I believe it is about 12 foot 8 from the penthouse to the ground.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know where the deceased fell, where the jury marked?</p>
               <p>Hubbord. That I measured.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the deceased lie there?</p>
               <p>Hubbord. No, I did not; I was shewn the place where they said his head lay.</p>
               <p>Q. How high is it from the seat of the window, on the inside, to the cill of the window ?</p>
               <p>Hubbord. That I did not measure, but I believe it is 10 or 11 inches, that is, from the window seat to the sash cill of the window, the lower frame; the place where the deceased's head lay is sideways, I do not mean right forwards into the street, but slantways, 7 foot 5 inches from the middle of the window, and it is 5 foot 3 inches from the penthouse, that is, the drip-edge.</p>
               <p>To his Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person373">
                  Michael 
                  Duffel 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person373" type="surname" value="Duffel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person373" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person373" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner between 17 and 18 years, he served me 17 years; he came to me in 1741 and left me in 1758.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Duffel. I live in Chelsea, he was servant in my madhouse.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character?</p>
               <p>Duffel. He is a sober civil quiet man, as ever came into any family; I never had any complaint of him all the time he liv'd with me, he is a very good temper'd mild meek man; I have sent him to families, and I never had any complaint of him; he is as humane a man as any I know.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person374">
                  John 
                  Collins 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person374" type="surname" value="Collins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person374" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person374" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him seventeen or eighteen years.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Collins. I live in Chelsea. I knew him when he was servant with Mr. Duffel; he is a very civil, sober, honest man: I never saw him out of temper in my life; he is a quiet inoffensive man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person375">
                  Thomas 
                  Dixon 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person375" type="surname" value="Dixon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person375" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person375" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about seventeen years; I live in that neighbourhood, and have often been in his company: I always took him to be a very quiet good sort of a man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person376">
                  John 
                  Rudford 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person376" type="surname" value="Rudford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person376" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person376" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him seventeen or eighteen years: he is a very honest, sober, civil, good temper'd fellow, and behaved very well.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person377">
                  Peter 
                  Juskip 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person377" type="surname" value="Juskip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person377" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person377" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him ever since he came to live with Mr. Duffel, in 1741. I was partner with him sixteen years, and I never saw him quarrelsome. If he saw any quarrelling, he would endeavour to asswage it; he is a very humane good natured man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person378">
                  John 
                  Fosset 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person378" type="surname" value="Fosset"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person378" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person378" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about seven or eight years; he is a good natured, sober, civil man as ever I knew, and he always behaved well.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person379">
                  George 
                  Beck 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person379" type="surname" value="Beck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person379" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person379" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him eleven or twelve years, and he is a very good, civil, humane man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person380">
                  Thomas 
                  Duffel 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person380" type="surname" value="Duffel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person380" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person380" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about sixteen years, and he was a very civil, peaceable, quiet man as ever came into a family; he bore a general good character, particularly remarkable for tenderness to every person he had the care of.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person381">
                  Thomas 
                  Bradly 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person381" type="surname" value="Bradly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person381" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person381" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about seventeen years, and he always bore a very good character; he is a very honest, sober, good-natured man, not subject to passion or quarrelling.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person382">
                  Charles 
                  Mundin 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person382" type="surname" value="Mundin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person382" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person382" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him twelve or fourteen years, and he is a very sober, honest, quiet man: I believe him to be a man that would hurt nothing, if he could help it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-34-person383">
                  Henry 
                  Lewer 
               <interp inst="t17591205-34-person383" type="surname" value="Lewer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person383" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-person383" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about eighteen years, and he is an extremely good, honest, quiet man; he bears the best of characters.</p>
               <p>Q. How is he for temper?</p>
               <p>Lewer. Of very agreeable temper; I never saw him quarrelsome in my life.</p>
               <p>Mr. Mulinox, I have known him something better than a year. I am servant to Mr. Whitebread, and have eat and drank with him; he behaved very well, and discharged his debts honestly. I never saw any thing like quarrelsome in him in my life, or any thing malicious.</p>

               <p>
                  <rs id="t17591205-34-verdict177" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17591205-34-verdict177" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
