<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17571207-5">
               <interp inst="t17571207-5" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17571207-5" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17571207-5" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17571207"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17571207-5" type="date" value="17571207"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17571207-5-off19-c50" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571207-5-defend57 t17571207-5-off19 t17571207-5-verdict23"></join>
         
               <p>5. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17571207-5-defend57" type="defendantName">
                     Margaret 
                     Patton 
                  <interp inst="t17571207-5-defend57" type="surname" value="Patton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-5-defend57" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-5-defend57" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17571207-5-deflabel18" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571207-5-defend57 t17571207-5-deflabel18"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17571207-5-off19" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17571207-5-off19" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-5-off19" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing twelve silk handkerchiefs, value 12 s. eight linen handkerchiefs, two holland shifts, one flaxen shift, one duffil coat, twelve metal spoons, one holland sheet, one flaxen sheet, one flannel petticoat, one linen gown, two linen aprons, one copper tea-kettle, and 22 s. in money numbered
            </rs>, the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17571207-5-victim59" type="victimName">
                     Mary 
                     Mansfield 
                  <interp inst="t17571207-5-victim59" type="surname" value="Mansfield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-5-victim59" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-5-victim59" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571207-5-off19 t17571207-5-victim59"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17571207-5-viclabel20" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571207-5-victim59 t17571207-5-viclabel20"></join>, <rs id="t17571207-5-cd21" type="crimeDate">November 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571207-5-off19 t17571207-5-cd21"></join>.*</p> 
               <p>Mary Mansfield. I live in <placeName id="t17571207-5-crimeloc22">St. John's, Wapping</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17571207-5-crimeloc22" type="placeName" value="St. John's, Wapping"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17571207-5-crimeloc22" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571207-5-off19 t17571207-5-crimeloc22"></join>. On the 21st of November I went out, on the other side of the water, for about three hours, and left the prisoner at the bar to take care of my house. She lodged and lay with me. I had taken my cloak out of a wainscot chest to put on at the time, and then saw the great coat lying in the chest. When I returned I missed the coat; 22 s, in silver out of that chest, and a flaxen shift. After that I examined a chest of drawers, out of which I missed several things, as a pair of sheets, some handkerchiefs, and caps. Then I examined a deal box, out of which I missed a shirt, some shifts, and handkerchiefs; a dozen of hard metal spoons out of a little trunk, and a tea-kettle out of the chimney corner. The prisoner was combing her head when I returned, which she soon did up, and was gone in an instant. I took her up about three days after in Shadwell, and charged her with taking the things, but she denied it. She had brought a man to my house on the Friday night before, whom I left in the house with her when I went out that time. When I returned I asked her where that man was. She said he had been gone ever since I went out, but when she was taken up she laid it to him.</p>
               <p>Q. What man was that?</p>
               <p>M. Mansfield. I don't know. She told me he was her brother-in-law's shipmate, that he was afraid of being impress'd, and desired he might<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175712070004"></xptr> lodge at my house, saying, he was a very honest man. She was very great with him.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. You have known me a long time, did you ever know any ill of me?</p>
               <p>M. Mansfield. She lodged with me about six or seven years ago, at which time she behaved as an honest woman.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had she been at your house the last time?</p>
               <p>M. Mansfield. About two or three months.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>She desired me to speak to any body that I knew to get her a lodger. I met a man, who told me he was a seafaring man; that he came from the Downs, and wanted to be private, for fear of the press; so I took him to my landlady, and she was well pleased with him He rob'd her house, and she has swore it was me. I took all the pains I could to find him, but could not.</p>
               <p>To her Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571207-5-person60">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Richardson 
               <interp inst="t17571207-5-person60" type="surname" value="Richardson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-5-person60" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-5-person60" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her not two months; I never heard any ill of her.</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. I desire 
               <persName id="t17571207-5-person61">
                  Giles 
                  Savage 
               <interp inst="t17571207-5-person61" type="surname" value="Savage"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-5-person61" type="given" value="Giles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-5-person61" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             may be examined.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571207-5-person62">
                  Giles 
                  Savage 
               <interp inst="t17571207-5-person62" type="surname" value="Savage"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-5-person62" type="given" value="Giles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-5-person62" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a headborough. When I served the warrant on the prisoner I ask'd her how she came to leave the house, when she had the charge of it. She said the man had wrote a letter to a merchant for 20 or 40 s. and sent her with it, and while she was gone he took the things out of the house. When I was taking her to Bridewell I said, why do you not tell the truth, and get admitted king's evidence. Then she said, if she old get a sheet of paper she would write to the man. Then I said, you know where the man is. After that she said she did not know where he lived.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17571207-5-verdict23" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17571207-5-verdict23" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
