<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17520514-23">
               <interp inst="t17520514-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520514-23" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520514-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520514"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520514-23" type="date" value="17520514"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520514-23-off115-c165" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-23-defend200 t17520514-23-off115 t17520514-23-verdict119"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520514-23-off115-c166" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-23-defend202 t17520514-23-off115 t17520514-23-verdict119"></join>
         
               <p>307, 308. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17520514-23-defend200" type="defendantName">
                  Henry 
                  Pestell 
               <interp inst="t17520514-23-defend200" type="surname" value="Pestell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-23-defend200" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-23-defend200" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
              and 
               
                  <persName id="t17520514-23-defend202" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Johnson 
                  <interp inst="t17520514-23-defend202" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-23-defend202" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-23-defend202" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17520514-23-off115" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520514-23-off115" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-23-off115" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               mixing white arsnic with milk intended for the use of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17520514-23-victim204" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Davison 
                        <interp inst="t17520514-23-victim204" type="surname" value="Davison"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520514-23-victim204" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520514-23-victim204" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-23-off115 t17520514-23-victim204"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , knowing it to be deadly poison, by reason whereof he became sick, diseased, and distemper'd, on the <rs id="t17520514-23-cd116" type="crimeDate">23d of March</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-23-off115 t17520514-23-cd116"></join>, and that he languished till the 29th and then died, that they of malice aforethought the said Davison did kill and murder
            </rs>: They stood also charged on the Coroner's Inquisition for the said murder. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-23-person205">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Davison 
               <interp inst="t17520514-23-person205" type="surname" value="Davison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-23-person205" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-23-person205" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am widow to the deceas'd, on the Thursday before Easter he said, he was afraid the two prisoners had played some tricks with his breakfast; he complain'd he was extremely ill, and I desir'd he'd have some wine done with spice and go to bed. He went to bed, but I was inform'd he groan'd so the rest of the prisoners could not sleep. He was in <placeName id="t17520514-23-crimeloc117">the prison of Ludgate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17520514-23-crimeloc117" type="placeName" value="the prison of Ludgate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520514-23-crimeloc117" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-23-off115 t17520514-23-crimeloc117"></join>. I sent him some breakfast the next morning by his daughter; she came for me, I went and found him in strong convulsion fits, I ran for the Apothecary, he came and gave him a glister and a julep: After that I went to Dr. Lobb, he ordered him a glister, with a little brandy in it, and the glister made of mutton, and to make him white gruel and a little drop of brandy in it, and also to make him jellies and chicken broth; but he could keep nothing upon his stomack hardly. These things agreed with him best, but he grew weaker and weaker every day; his continual complaint was of pains in his bowels and stomach, pointing to his stomach, and would say, Arsnic, Arsnic. We did all that in us lay, but nothing did. On the Sunday morning he desir'd to be got up, and was no sooner in his chair, but he died in a convulsion sit. Johnson has declared before me, and other witnesses, that it was Jallap and Salt of Wormwood, and sometimes he'd say, it was Jallap and Salt of Tartar. My husband several times said, he laid his death to the prisoners charge, and said he should never be well till he was in his coffin.</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175205140020"></xptr>Q. Do you know of their giving him any thing?</p>
               <p>E. Davison. I was not there that breakfast time, as was talk'd on.</p>
               <p>Q. from Johnson. Was he not once something better, and did not the keeper send for us out of our confinement, and tell us if we would pay the expenes we should be forgiven?</p>
               <p>E. Davison. No, there was no such thing mentioned; for he was very bad, and continued bad all along.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you once think him better?</p>
               <p>E. Davison. We once thought so, but he was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your husband ill before the eating this breakfast ?</p>
               <p>E. Davison. No, he was as well on the Saturday night and Sunday morning, as ever he was in his life, and cat as hearty a dinner on the Sunday.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-23-person206">
                  John 
                  Colwin 
               <interp inst="t17520514-23-person206" type="surname" value="Colwin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-23-person206" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-23-person206" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . At the time the deceas'd was a <rs id="t17520514-23-viclabel118" type="occupation">prisoner</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-23-victim204 t17520514-23-viclabel118"></join> in Ludgate and died, I was so unfortunate to be a prisoner also. On Friday the 20th of March in the day time, he complain'd to me that he was out of order, and troubled with a slight illness: I asked him what was his complaint; he said, he thought it was with eating a breakfast with a fellow prisoner of milk and twopenny, or some such thing. This complaint seemed to have left him on Saturday in the afternoon; for he was upon the leads walking with the rest of the prisoners, seemingly in good health. On the Saturday night he seemed to be very free from any complaint. On the Sunday, the 22d, I saw him at dinner, and by what I could see, and what I was told by his companions, he eat a pretty hearty dinner; I saw him eat great part of it, he seemed to eat hearrier than I had seen him before, for he us'd to have no great appetite. On Sunday night I left him in the taproom, when I went up to my room to go to bed, he then was in good health as at any time I had known him, during the time of his confinement. On Monday in the afternoon I saw him, he seemed drooping and complain'd he was ill, what his illness was he did not complain to me. On the Tuesday morning I saw him, he then complained of a violent pain in his stomach and bowels, and said he had been vomiting and purging.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him vomit, &amp;c?</p>
               <p>Colwin. I can't say I did: Towards the evening I saw him again, and conversed with him Then he said he had heard the two prisoners had given him something in his milk on the Monday morning in their ward. On the Wednesday morning, before I was out of bed, two or three people came to me, and said he was in convulsions and extremely ill, and that it was well known the two prisoners had given him something in his milk at breakfast. I immediately got up and went into his ward, where I saw him in a chair, his complexion and voice were very much alter'd, and he appeared very much convuls'd, and almost speechless. After this Mr. Thompson, Mr. West, and myself, waited on the Keeper, to inform him about the circumstances of what we had heard. I believe Mrs. Davison was in the room with us.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is the Keeper?</p>
               <p>Colwin. Mr. Cave is: Upon this he went up and saw Mr. Davison.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>Colwin. This was on the Wednesday morning about ten o'clock. The Keeper returned into his own room, and we with him; he sent immediately for Mr. Johnson, who came. The Keeper told him he had seen Mr. Davison, and thought him in a dangerous condition, and said, he had heard he had given him something in his drink. Johnson at first seemed to deny it, but was in a very great astonishment about it. The Keeper used some little threats, and said, if he would not discover the truth he'd send to the Sheriff, and have him committed to Newgate. Then he said, if I must tell the truth, I must, Pestell got the stuff, and we gave it him. After this Mr. Pestell was sent for by the Keeper.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say what stuff?</p>
         
               <p>The Second Part of these Proceedings will be publish'd in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17520514-23">
                  <interp inst="t17520514-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520514-23" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520514-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520514"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520514-23" type="date" value="17520514"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175205140021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Goal Delivery FOR THE City of LONDON; And also the Goal Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Thursday the 14th, Friday the 15th, and Saturday the 16th, of May.</p>
                  <p>In the 25th Year of His MAJESTY's Reign. BEING THE Fifth SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of the Right Honble 
                  <persName id="t17520514-23-person207">
                     Thomas 
                     Winterbottom 
                  <interp inst="t17520514-23-person207" type="surname" value="Winterbottom"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520514-23-person207" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520514-23-person207" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Esq; LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>NUMBER V. PART II.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by M. COOPER, at the Globe in Pater-noster Row. 1752.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-Pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175205140022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery held for the City of London, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Colwin. No, he did not: Then the keeper was in a good deal of warmth, and ask'd Pestell if he was not a very great rogue to go to do things that he did not know the consequence of? Pestell denied it, then Johnson confronted him, and told him he did it, upon which Pestell recollected, and said, I did it when I was in the room; but I did not think there had been any harm in it. About an hour after this I went again, and saw the deceased, he continued in very great agony, was put to bed, and convuls'd very much. In this time Mrs. Davison had fetch'd Mr. Dalmahoy, who lives on Ludgate-hill, and Mr. Meadows, a surgeon, that was likewise a prisoner with us, was there with him. Mr. Meadows had prescribed some physic for Mr. Pestell, and the general report of the prison was, that from thence Mr. Meadows knew what had been given to Mr. Davison. I said to Mr. Meadows, you see what condition he is in, I beg you'll describe the quality of what Pestell had of you: He immediately said, it was Jallap and Salts of Tartar, or Salts of Worm-wood, he could not tell which, that he had prescribed. Mr. Dalmahoy and Mr. Meadows agreed together what should be done to him. The deceased continued very dangerously ill all the Wednesday; sometimes he was capable of speech, and sometimes he was so convuls'd that he could not speak. I saw him two or three times on the Wednesday in the afternoon, he could only make signs over his breast, wherein it seemed his pain lay. On the Thursday morning I saw him, and went again to see him at noon, then he appeared very much convuls'd. I then said to his brother-prisoner in his ward, that his condition was extremely hard, he not having any relief, nor a physician to assist him. Then one of the prisoners told Mrs. Davison, that if she'd go to Dr. Lobb he'd prescribe something for him: She went, and the Dr. wrote for the deceased. Coming from my own room to go to the deceased, I met her going up; she told me she had been to Dr. Lobb, and had got a prescription, which she gave into my hand, I looked at it, and to the best, of my judgment it was much the same as had been administered before by the others. I then desired she'd let me carry the prescription up to Mr. Meadows; she refused it, and put it in her bosom, and went and got the things accordingly. They were administered, and on Thursday evening, about seven, I found him capable of speech, and seemingly in some spirits, insomuch that I assisted, with his daughter, to give him one of his draughts, he was merry and crack'd a joke, and I was in great hopes of his living. Mr. Meadows and I went up about nine o'clock, he was then much alter'd, for in giving him something out of a cup his convulsions then took him, and he fell down speechless again. I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175205140023"></xptr> then immediately applied myself to Mr. Meadows, and said, do you think there is so material an alteration in his medicines, as to occasion this alteration in his health. Mr. Meadows said, at that time, he thought him a great deal better, but now he could not tell what to say. On the Friday I visited him two or three times again, but found him at no certainty; he continued changing very much, in a fluctuating state, sometimes better, sometimes worse. On the Friday evening Johnson the prisoner happened to be in the room, while I attempted to get him to take down a bit of chicken, Johnson was crying by the fire side: The deceased lay about four yards distance, seemingly not capable of speaking, he saw Johnson, and call'd out the Villain! Then Johnson left the room. I saw him two or three times on the Saturday, when I think he was worse than before, in want of spirits and every thing. On the Sunday morning about 10 o'clock, being the day on which he died, I then found him, as I thought, with symptoms of death upon him very strong. Johnson followed me to the door crying, and asked me whether there was any hopes of recovery. About half an hour after eleven word was brought me he was dead.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him after ?</p>
               <p>Colwin. I did : I attended at the opening of the body. Mr. Meadows open'd it, in presence of Mr. Ruding. There appeared something of an Inflammation on the bottom of the stomach; it was quite opened, as were all the coats of the intestines. I had a doubt upon me whether from the violent vomiting there had any of the material substance passed into his body, from the time he first took it. Upon which Mr. Meadows opened one or two of the guts, and said there was some sign of an Anuras in them, but that it had made no adhesion.</p>
               <p>Q. from Johnson. Did not you say before the Coroner's Jury, God forbid you should think we intended to kill him ?</p>
               <p>Colwin. I did, in answer to a question put to me by one of the Jurymen.</p>
               <p>Q. from Johnson. Did not the Coroner, upon his coming to take a view of the body, declare he saw no marks upon the body, and that he believed he died a natural death?</p>
               <p>Colwin. The Coroner said he did not see any external marks at all. I answer'd, I did not know how external marks should appear in this case.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-23-person208">
                  John 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17520514-23-person208" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-23-person208" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-23-person208" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lay in the same ward the deceased lay in: He complain'd of violent pains on Monday the 23d of March, and likewise on the Tuesday ; on Tuesday night he went to bed, and said he was very ill; Wednesday morning he was very ill, I could have no sleep, he got up between six and seven, in order to go to the necessary-house, and went down, but came up again, and said he could do nothing; he was so very ill he wanted something warm. I got up and got a fire, and made some warm gruel; he drank, I believe, the quantity of a gallon, and as he took it he threw it up again. When we had got him up, between 9 and 10, he fell into a convulsion sit, his wife and I thought he had been dead; he after some time recovered that, but still complained he was very ill. I ask'd him if he could imagine the meaning of it : He said yes, he believ'd Mr. Johnston and Mr. Pestell had given him something in his milk the Monday morning before. I then went down and acquainted Mr. Cave, the keeper, with what was said; he ordered me to call in Mr. Johnston first, which I did. When he was in, he seem'd very unwilling to say any thing; but Mr. 
               <persName id="t17520514-23-person209">
                  Joseph 
                  West 
               <interp inst="t17520514-23-person209" type="surname" value="West"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-23-person209" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-23-person209" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a prisoner in the house, said, Mr. Johnston, don't deny it, you know you told me you had something of a secret you would tell me, if I would not say any thing of it. Then Mr. Cave told him it might become a serious thing, and that if the man died he might be sent to Newgate. Then he said, If I must confess, I and Mr. Pestell did it, or gave him the physic, I don't know which, I then called in Mr. Pestell, who denied it; but at last said, if I must go to Newgate, there are more must go with me. He (the deceased) grew worse and worse, and when I ask'd him any question, he pointed his hand to his throat (I suppose) meaning they might as well have cut his throat, and would say, he was sure he was poisoned by those two men, and when he could not speak he would pull his hand a-cross his throat.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-23-person210">
                  John 
                  Luft 
               <interp inst="t17520514-23-person210" type="surname" value="Luft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-23-person210" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-23-person210" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Monday the 23d of April, between nine and ten in the morning, as we were eating our breakfasts at the window, as I was at the upper end of the ward, I turned my head back and saw Mr. Pestell with his back towards me, stooping towards the fire, and Johnson with his face towards me, stirring something in a china cup, what it was I can't tell; at the same time the unhappy deceased had some milk boiling on the fire.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the deceased at that time?</p>
               <p>Luft. He was at the lower end of the ward, I know no more.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-23-person211">
                  Thomas 
                  Meadows 
               <interp inst="t17520514-23-person211" type="surname" value="Meadows"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-23-person211" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-23-person211" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . As to any thing given to the deceased, I cannot tell. They had given Pestell some Alteratives, and I thought proper to give him some Purgatives he had had a bad leg.</p>
               <p>Q. What purgatives did you give him?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175205140024"></xptr>Meadows. I ordered him a little jallap, and a little salt of tartar, by way of correction, because it should not gripe or act with so much violence, and at Pestell's request I attended the deceased: I was call'd to him on Tuesday about 11 o'clock, and found him pretty much convuls'd; and after s ome little time, Mr. Dalmahoy, a chymist, came in; we consulted together finding he had had a purging upon him, I thought it requisite for him to take a glister, which was a little restringent, but at the same time, a very safe one; it seemed to have a very good effect upon him, and abated his purging, he had not a stool after it for many hours, as he himself declar'd; Mr. Dalmahoy had sent in a medicine, something of a restringent, to take internally, but I imagin'd the stomach not capable to take any thing of that kind; I told Mr. Dalmahoy's servant, (his master not being at home) to make up a little mixture (which had a very good effect) with the addition of some mint-water, and a few other things, this took off his vomiting, and he seemed abundantly better, and could take proper nutriment.</p>
               <p>Q. Of what kind?</p>
               <p>Meadows. He took gruels and seagoe, and jelleys, I thought he was in a mending way, the next day I really thought him quite out of danger, excepting his being weak and low; I was informed that Mrs. Davison had been to Dr. Lobb; Mr. Colwin shew'd me a prescription that she had brought from him, and in that prescription there were some little matter of brandy to be added to the glister, and likewise she told me, it was to be taken by the mouth, as well as to be made use of by way of glister; I gave her a caution, saying it is very odd, that he should prescribe such medicines as this, and not to give his attendance himself, and I told her, I thought too frequent a use of that might be very pernicious, and that the quantity of one spoon-full of brandy, to a person so low, might be worse to him, than a quantity to a person in full strength, but as the doctor had been concern'd, it was not my business to interfere (only by way of precaution) with any thing he intended to give him. The deceased was sometimes better, sometimes worse, after the taking these medicines; I was apprehensive that the looseness returning again, was a good deal owing to the taking such a quantity of spirits, and I did not attend him so frequently as before. On the Sunday morning Mr. Johnson came to me very early, to look upon the poor man; I got up between four and five, and found by his smell, that he had been drinking something very strong, he smelt as strong of rum, as though he had been suffocated with it; he was very weak and low, and in a declining way from that time to the time he expired, which was about 12 o'clock: I opened him several days afterwards, I believe it was 4 days; I found some little inflammation all over the stomach and bowels, both the large and small guts, and the blood vessels, were distended, and look'd inflam'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Who were present?</p>
               <p>Meadows. There were Mr. Ruding, and another gentleman, they approved of it to look within-side of his bowels and stomach, we found some little mucus in the inside of the intestines, and some little matter of excrement; it appeared as if there had been a purging something considerable, but no signs of any thing poisonous, that had been the cause of it; there was no mortification, not so much as a gangrene.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you look upon it, that where poison has been given, something of a gangrene will appear?</p>
               <p>Meadows. Always.</p>
               <p>Q. from Johnson. Whither that witness did not tell me he smelt of rum, so that he might be smelt half the length of the Ward?</p>
               <p>Meadows. I can't say I have smelt rum in that manner, as I did at that time, when I thought he seemed almost suffocated; that was rum; but I believe he frequently drank too much brandy in what he took.</p>

               <p>Q. from Johnson. Had he not complained, that he had been ill before?</p>
               <p>Meadows. I think he did complain he had been ill on the Friday before.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he a man that took drams commonly?</p>
               <p>Meadows. I really don't know that.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Davison. What this Witness speaks of, is in regard to the rum on Saturday night, when my husband complaining of his bowels being cold, we rubb'd him with hot stannels and rum, especially in his stomack, but he took none inwardly, only a little brandy in his white gruel.</p>
               <p>Q. to Meadows. Could you distinguish whether that strong smell proceeded from his body or his breath?</p>
               <p>Meadows. I was very particular, it was his breath which I smelt.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-23-person212">
                  John 
                  Ruding 
               <interp inst="t17520514-23-person212" type="surname" value="Ruding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-23-person212" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-23-person212" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was not concern'd in attending the deceased before he died, but was present when he was open'd ; I had never seen Mr. Meadows before that time: It appear'd upon opening the body, that there was an inflammation on one part of the stomach and bowels.</p>
               <p>Q. Which part of the stomach ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175205140025"></xptr>Ruding. The lower part of it, but that was not so much inflam'd at the bowels.</p>
               <p>Q. When any person dies of poison being given them, in what manner do you observe the intestines to be ?</p>
               <p>Ruding. There is generally a mortification or gangrene appears.</p>
               <p>Q. Did there any gangrene appear here ?</p>
               <p>Ruding. No, there did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon seeing the body, the stomach, and intestines open'd, whether this man died of poison, or not?</p>
               <p>Ruding. It is my opinion he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether there were any marks as if he had been violently troubled with a purging?</p>
               <p>Ruding. Upon opening the intestines, there were some little symptoms as if he had.</p>
               <p>Q. If a person is poisoned, how are the intestines ?</p>
               <p>Ruding. There are generally a mortification or spots, but here were none at all.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-23-person213">
                  Mary 
                  Fordham 
               <interp inst="t17520514-23-person213" type="surname" value="Fordham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-23-person213" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-23-person213" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the Friday before the gentleman died, I was with him, I was recommended to nurse him, his spouse was there, she gave me orders what I should give him, which was a little chicken broth, a little seagoe, and a little flower and water, and when I was to give him this, I was to give him a little brandy or rum, or a little wine in it, so I gave him chicken broth one time, and another time I gave him the other, as he called for them; I advised him to have a little bread in his chicken broth, he eat it, and said, he seemed to be a little better, he never complained to me of any pain any where, he seemed much recover'd and pretty hearty, but would often crave spirituous liquors very much; he once wanted a glass of cold wine, and used to be angry with me at times because I would not give him the things he called for; if I gave him any thing that did him good, then he would crave for the other.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-23-person214">
                  Edward 
                  Thornton 
               <interp inst="t17520514-23-person214" type="surname" value="Thornton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-23-person214" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-23-person214" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was a prisoner in the house at the same time; I was below stairs upwards of two hours on Monday the 16th, when I came up, I saw the man eating milk and bread by the window, just facing the door, as I came in: He was a free good-natur'd man; I said, father, how do you do? he spoke inwardly, something lower than he used to speak, and said, I have not been well, saying, I have had a purging upon me for 4 or 5 days, and I believe the occasion of it is by eating two-penny and milk, I have got nothing in my belly, or bowels, I can't say which ; I saw him eat such on the Friday before with another man.</p>
               <p>Q. from Johnson. What character do I bear in the prison ?</p>
               <p>Thornton. He bares the character of having been out of his senses for sometime; I was walking upon the leads about a fortnight before, and Mr. Dawson was walking also, he was very hot and sat down with his back towards the wall that looks, to Black Friars, he sat till he got cold, they said, he must walk to get hot again, and I verily behave he got cold and was ill from that time by overheating his blood.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-23-person215">
                  Sarah 
                  Dawson 
               <interp inst="t17520514-23-person215" type="surname" value="Dawson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-23-person215" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-23-person215" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Pestell gave me a paper and three half-pence to go to Mr. Dalmahoy's I gave it to his man, he gave me something in a paper; I carried it to Mr. Pestell. I went to him on the Tuesday, he said, he was very ill with the physic I brought him off the Sunday. Mr. Dalmahoy's man said, it was Jallap and Salt of Tartar.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17520514-23-verdict119" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520514-23-verdict119" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
