<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17521206-31">
               <interp inst="t17521206-31" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521206-31" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521206-31" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17521206"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521206-31" type="date" value="17521206"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17521206-31-off149-c201" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-31-defend257 t17521206-31-off149 t17521206-31-verdict152"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17521206-31-off153-c201" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-31-defend257 t17521206-31-off153 t17521206-31-verdict152"></join>
         
               <p>37 (M) 
               
                  <persName id="t17521206-31-defend257" type="defendantName">
                     Edward 
                     Davis 
                  <interp inst="t17521206-31-defend257" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-31-defend257" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-31-defend257" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for that <rs id="t17521206-31-off149" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17521206-31-off149" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-31-off149" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he on the King's highway on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17521206-31-victim259" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Eager 
                        <interp inst="t17521206-31-victim259" type="surname" value="Eager"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17521206-31-victim259" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17521206-31-victim259" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , widow, did make an assault, putting her in corporal fear and danger of her life, 6 s. in money numbered, from her person, did steal, take, and carry away
            </rs>, <rs id="t17521206-31-cd150" type="crimeDate">Nov. 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-31-off149 t17521206-31-cd150"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-31-off153 t17521206-31-cd150"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521206-31-person260">
                  Mary 
                  Eager 
               <interp inst="t17521206-31-person260" type="surname" value="Eager"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-31-person260" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-31-person260" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 16th of Nov. about two in the afternoon, going in a one horse chaise on the road to Twickenham, at a lane end call'd <placeName id="t17521206-31-crimeloc151">Whitten-Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17521206-31-crimeloc151" type="placeName" value="Whitten-Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17521206-31-crimeloc151" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-31-off149 t17521206-31-crimeloc151"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-31-off153 t17521206-31-crimeloc151"></join>, there was one Rebecca Page in the chaise with me; and in another chaise were two other gentlewomen; a man seemed to come out of the lane end on foot, he held a pistol to me, and came up to the chaise-horse; I said, O! you want my money, you shall have it this minute; I stopp'd my chaise, and took out of my pocket 3 or 4 s. and put it in my other hand and said I believed I had more, but pray take that thing away and I'll give it you; in the whole I believe I took out 7 or 8 s. and gave it him.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say to you?</p>
               <p>M. Eager. He said nothing at all to me, I never heard him speak, and went away with the money in his hand to the chaise behind me; I drove on to the house of Mr. Spires, about two or three stones cast from thence, and told the people. we had been robb'd by a footpad, and if they would pursue him they might take him; I could give no other description of him than that he had a very dirty shirt on; I was so much terrified, I did not mind his face, nor can I say the prisoner is the man: the people set out in about ten minutes after I had been robb'd in pursuit, and brought the prisoner in a our a quarter of an hour. I said to him, way do you throw your life away so? he said he had no work. but he would go to work; we went with him before the justice at Isleworth, and he there in some measure denied it. The justice ask'd him how he came by the pistol; he said he found it in a stable as he was cleaning it; he said we did not give him the money, but we threw it on the ground and he took it up.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175212060018"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17521206-31-person261">
                  Rebecca 
                  Hydeman 
               <interp inst="t17521206-31-person261" type="surname" value="Hydeman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-31-person261" type="given" value="Rebecca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-31-person261" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in a chaise behind Mrs. Eager, and saw the come out of Whitten Lane and stop her chaise, and saw a pistol in his hand, and see her likewise shussle her hand in her pocket and put it out towards him; then he came to me with some silver in his hand, I did not hear him speak a word, and I put some halfpence upon the silver.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at the prisoner, is he the man you speak of?</p>
               <p>R. Hydeman. I believe he is the man; for after he was gone we went on to Mr. Spires's house, and told the people there what had happened, and directed them where to go in pursuet; four man went in pursuit, and brought the prisoner to us in about ten minutes time; I told him he was a fool to venture his life for such a trifle; his answer was, it is the first time. We took him to the justice's, who ask'd him many questions; the prisoner said we dropp'd the money and he pick'd it up.</p>
               <p>Drury Brown. I was servant to Mr. Spices, and I heard the gentlewomen say they had been robb'd, I took a stick and went with 
               <persName id="t17521206-31-person262">
                  James 
                  Wiggins 
               <interp inst="t17521206-31-person262" type="surname" value="Wiggins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-31-person262" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-31-person262" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17521206-31-person263">
                  Henry 
                  Rummel 
               <interp inst="t17521206-31-person263" type="surname" value="Rummel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-31-person263" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-31-person263" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and Watt Cheshire; when we came to the prisoner, he told us that a man had ran up that lane as hard as he could.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you said any thing to him?</p>
               <p>Brown. No, I had not; I answered him, I believe you are the man. We brought him up my master ground, for he made no resistance; there we search'd him, and James Wiggins took a pistol out of the prisoner's pocket, (produc'd in court;) when we got him to my master's he sent me to my work.</p>
               <p>Q. to the prosecutrix. Is this the pistol that was held out to you?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix It was such a little thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521206-31-person264">
                  James 
                  Wiggins 
               <interp inst="t17521206-31-person264" type="surname" value="Wiggins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-31-person264" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-31-person264" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Spires, a Gardener, I heard these women call out they had been robb'd. He confirm'd the testimony of Brown with addition, that he went with the prisoner to the justice, and going along, the prisoner desired be might stop till the gentlewomen came up, that he might give them their money again, that they had not taken it from him then, but he pull'd it out of his pocket to give it to the men that were with him; it appear'd to be 6 or 7 s. and some halfpence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521206-31-person265">
                  Henry 
                  Rummel 
               <interp inst="t17521206-31-person265" type="surname" value="Rummel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-31-person265" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-31-person265" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Apprentice with Mr. Spires. I was at the taking the prisoner, and went with him before the justice. He confirm'd the last evidence.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I am a stranger hereabouts, and am of the affair.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17521206-31-verdict152" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17521206-31-verdict152" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a second time indicted for <rs id="t17521206-31-off153" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17521206-31-off153" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-31-off153" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               robbing 
                     <persName id="t17521206-31-victim266" type="victimName">
                        Rebecca 
                        Hydeman 
                     <interp inst="t17521206-31-victim266" type="surname" value="Hydeman"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17521206-31-victim266" type="given" value="Rebecca"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17521206-31-victim266" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   , widow, on the high way of 4d. in money
            </rs>, &amp;c. <rs id="t17521206-31-cd154" type="crimeDate">Nov. 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-31-off149 t17521206-31-cd154"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-31-off153 t17521206-31-cd154"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>The Evidences were the same as on the former trial, to which the reader is referred.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17521206-31-verdict155" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17521206-31-verdict155" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
