<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17581206-12">
               <interp inst="t17581206-12" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581206-12" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581206-12" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17581206"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581206-12" type="date" value="17581206"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17581206-12-off61-c87" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-12-defend103 t17581206-12-off61 t17581206-12-verdict64"></join>
         
               <p>13. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17581206-12-defend103" type="defendantName">
                     Solomon 
                     Peters 
                  <interp inst="t17581206-12-defend103" type="surname" value="Peters"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-12-defend103" type="given" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-12-defend103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17581206-12-off61" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581206-12-off61" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-12-off61" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 4 silver table spoons, value 30 s. 4 silver tea spoons, value 4 s. one pair of silver tea tongs, value 2 s. and one silver strainer, value 2 s.
            </rs> the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17581206-12-victim105" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Wood 
                  <interp inst="t17581206-12-victim105" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-12-victim105" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-12-victim105" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-12-off61 t17581206-12-victim105"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17581206-12-cd62" type="crimeDate">Oct. 28</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-12-off61 t17581206-12-cd62"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-12-person106">
                  John 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17581206-12-person106" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-12-person106" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-12-person106" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the <placeName id="t17581206-12-crimeloc63">two Blue Posts in Bunhill-Row</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17581206-12-crimeloc63" type="placeName" value="two Blue Posts in Bunhill-Row"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17581206-12-crimeloc63" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-12-off61 t17581206-12-crimeloc63"></join>, on the 28th of October I lost 4 silver table spoons.</p>
               <p>Q. What were they worth?</p>
               <p>Wood. They were worth 30 s. I lost also 4 tea spoons, a pair of tea tongs and strainer, all silver.</p>
               <p>Q. What were they worth?</p>
               <p>Wood. They were worth 8 s.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were they taken from?</p>
               <p>Wood. From out of a beaufet in the club-room, up one pair of stairs; I know they were lock'd up there some time before, but I had not seen them for a week before; I was not at home at the time they were taken, I soon came home and was told of it, I went up, and found the lock was forced open.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to suspect the prisoner at the bar?</p>
               <p>Wood. Because I was told that he had been up in that room.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever find this plate afterwards?</p>
               <p>Wood. No, never, he was carried before a magistrate, there he denied it, the Justice committed him to the Gatehouse.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-12-person107">
                  Mary 
                  Humphreys 
               <interp inst="t17581206-12-person107" type="surname" value="Humphreys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-12-person107" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-12-person107" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My mother keeps the two Blue Posts, the prisoner came into our house with 
               <persName id="t17581206-12-person108">
                  John 
                  Madison 
               <interp inst="t17581206-12-person108" type="surname" value="Madison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-12-person108" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-12-person108" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             about three in the afternoon on the 28th of October, they went into the club-room.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any body else in the club-room when they were there?</p>
               <p>M. Humph. No, there were not, there had been no body drinking in it that day, there had been a plaisterer at work in it, who had done his work in it by 11 o'clock; the prisoner and his friend had a tankerd of beer, and wanted something to eat, we told them we had a bit of cold mutton in the house, they desired some of that, I carried it, I open'd the beaufet, and took out a couple of earthen plates.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the beaufet locked then.</p>
               <p>M. Humph. It was, then the plate were all there, there were six silver table spoons in all, and five tea spoons.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe them all to be there?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175812060009"></xptr>M. Humph. I then saw them lying but did not tell them, but I had observed them all after eleven in the morning, when the Plaisterer had done.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you lock the door again, after you took out the plates ?</p>
               <p>M. Humph. I did, and went down stairs; 
               <persName id="t17581206-12-person109">
                  John 
                  Madison 
               <interp inst="t17581206-12-person109" type="surname" value="Madison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-12-person109" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-12-person109" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             did stay but a little time in the room, he came down and left the prisoner there.</p>
               <p>Q. How long might Madison stay in that room?</p>
               <p>M. Humph. About a quarter of an hour, he came down and staid by the fire below stairs; then he went up again, and they soon came down and went away together.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was Madison by your fire below?</p>
               <p>M. Humph. About ten minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was it that they went away?</p>

               <p>M. Humph. The went away about 4 o'clock, then the prisoner came back again by himself, and call'd for a pint of beer, and went up into that room by himself.</p>
               <p>Q. How soon was this after they had went away ?</p>
               <p>M. Humph. This was about ten minutes after.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was the prisoner there alone, then ?</p>
               <p>M. Humph. Almost a quarter of an hour; then Mr 
               <persName id="t17581206-12-person110">
                  Daniel 
                  Blackwell 
               <interp inst="t17581206-12-person110" type="surname" value="Blackwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-12-person110" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-12-person110" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came and ask'd if there were not two gentlemen there, we said one was gone, and the other was up stairs; he went up to him, and staid about 4 to 5 minutes, 6 was the out-side, and they both went away together.</p>
               <p>Q. How soon were the silver spoons and things missing after this?</p>
               <p>M. Humph. In about ten minutes time I had occasion to go up to the beaufet for a little allspice, and miss'd them directly.</p>
               <p>Q. Had any body been in that room but these three persons you mention ?</p>
               <p>M. Humph. No, none.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you find the beaufet door?</p>
               <p>M. Humph. I found it unlock'd; the lock was shot back, the edge of the wood was cut so as to put in a knife to shove back the bolt; then I miss'd 4 table spoons, 4 tea spoons, a pair of tea tongs, and a strainer.</p>

               <p>Q. Was you before the Justice with the prisoner?</p>
               <p>M. Humph. I was, there he denied it.</p>
               <p>Q. What does he do for his livelihood?</p>
               <p>M. Humph. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. From the prisoner. Whether I was not down and left Madison alone in the room?</p>
               <p>M. Humph. Yes, you came down and went into the yard.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he stay in the yard?</p>
               <p>M. Humph. About 3 or 4 minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. Had there been any body in that room while the prisoner was in the house, except Madison and Blackwell?</p>
               <p>M. Humph. No.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-12-person111">
                  John 
                  Madison 
               <interp inst="t17581206-12-person111" type="surname" value="Madison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-12-person111" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-12-person111" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner and I were at Guildhall together.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>J. Madison. He is a gentleman's servant out of place. Then the prisoner and I went to drink together, we went to the two Blue Posts in Bunhill-Row, into a one pair of stairs room; we had a tankard of beer, I was there about a quarter of an hour; I remember the maid opening the beaufet, and gave us out two plates, we had some meat.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe what was in the beaufet?</p>
               <p>J. Madison, No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. to Humphreys. When the beaufet was opened, could they as they sat observe the plate in it?</p>
               <p>Humphreys. They were in sight of all the plate.</p>
               <p>Q. to Madison. Did you observe that the door was lock'd?</p>
               <p>J. Madison. I know she open'd it with a key.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know that she turn'd the key afterwards ?</p>
               <p>J. Madison. I did not observe that: as soon as as I had dined, I went down stairs, and went to the fire, it was very cold; I staid by the fire about a quarter of an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there no fire in the club-room?</p>
               <p>J. Madison. No: after I went up the prisoner went down, then I call'd the people up to pay.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175812060010"></xptr>Q. How long did you stay after you went up stairs again?</p>
               <p>J. Madison. We did not stay above five minutes after that, we both went away together.</p>
               <p>Q. What part of the time was it that he went down and left you in the room?</p>
               <p>J. Madison. He went down to go into the yard after I went up; I had ordered Mr Wood's nephew to bid my countryman meet me at such a place in the Strand, by that means they found me; we had a search warrant and searched the prisoner's lodgings, but nothing was found; and Dr Blackwell and I were discharged.</p>
               <p>Q. Why do you call him doctor?</p>
               <p>J. Madison. He is a Surgeon.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Was not there another person in the room besides us three?</p>
               <p>J. Madison. Yes: there was an acquaintance of Mr Wood's that lodges in his house.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he stay in the room?</p>
               <p>J. Madison. He just came in, but did not stay a moment.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-12-person112">
                  David 
                  Blackwell 
               <interp inst="t17581206-12-person112" type="surname" value="Blackwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-12-person112" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-12-person112" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 28th of October, Mr Peters call'd upon me, to desire I would go with him to Guildhall, he had summoned a person there; when I came into the court, Mr Madison was there; after the trial was over, we came back again; Madison ask'd me to go and see an acquaintance of his at Mr Wood's. I told him I could not possibly go with him there, having business that would take me up above an hour. I told him I would come in about an hour's time. When I found they did not call upon me, I went to the house; when I came there, I ask'd Mr Wood's daughter-in-law, whether there were two gentlemen in the house? she told me there were not two, one was gone, the other was above stairs; I went up, there was the prisoner with a pint of beer before him. I ask'd him how he came to stay? he said, he came back on purpose to wait for me, as I had promised him to come. I told him, I could not stay in the room upon any account, the room being white washing; he went down stairs and paid for his pint of beer, and came up again; I said I would not stay, when I came to the bottom of the stairs, I saw a silver tankard on the table, I spoke four or five times, at last Mrs Wood's daughter spoke; I said, you have workmen about, and there stands a silver tankard. She said we looked like gentlemen, we do not mistrust you.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence. I know nothing of the matter at all; I was in the room with these people, Mr Blackwell has known me a great while.  <rs id="t17581206-12-verdict64" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581206-12-verdict64" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>~ See him tried before for a forgery, No. 6. in the Mayoralty of Sir 
               <persName id="t17581206-12-person113">
                  Charles 
                  Asgill 
               <interp inst="t17581206-12-person113" type="surname" value="Asgill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-12-person113" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-12-person113" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Knt.</p>
            </div1>
