<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560225-27">
               <interp inst="t17560225-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560225-27" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560225-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560225"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560225-27" type="date" value="17560225"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560225-27-off149-c219" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-27-defend269 t17560225-27-off149 t17560225-27-verdict153"></join>
         
               <p>137. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17560225-27-defend269" type="defendantName">
                     Benjamin 
                     Remmer 
                  <interp inst="t17560225-27-defend269" type="surname" value="Remmer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-27-defend269" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-27-defend269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-27-defend269" type="age" value="thirteen years of age"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17560225-27-off149" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560225-27-off149" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-27-off149" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one moidore and 28 guineas
            </rs>, the money of 
               
                  <persName id="t17560225-27-victim271" type="victimName">
                     Joseph 
                     Barnardiston 
                  <interp inst="t17560225-27-victim271" type="surname" value="Barnardiston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-27-victim271" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-27-victim271" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-27-off149 t17560225-27-victim271"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17560225-27-cd150" type="crimeDate">Feb. 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-27-off149 t17560225-27-cd150"></join>* </p> 
               <p>Joseph Barnardiston. This youth at the bar was <rs id="t17560225-27-deflabel151" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-27-defend269 t17560225-27-deflabel151"></join> to me, to run of errands.</p>
               <p>Q. How old is he?</p>
               <p>Barnardiston. He is not thirteen years of age.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>Barnardiston. I am a <rs id="t17560225-27-viclabel152" type="occupation">stationer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-27-victim271 t17560225-27-viclabel152"></join>. On Saturday was se'nnight I left thirty guineas with my head man 
               <persName id="t17560225-27-person272">
                  Samuel 
                  Hows 
               <interp inst="t17560225-27-person272" type="surname" value="Hows"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-27-person272" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-27-person272" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , as running cash. On the Monday following, between eight and nine o'clock, he came into the parlour to me, in a great surprise, and said his cash was gone out of the till; it gave me a good deal of surprise; the boy was missing. He was taken, and the next day in the afternoon 
               <persName id="t17560225-27-person273">
                  James 
                  Lightholder 
               <interp inst="t17560225-27-person273" type="surname" value="Lightholder"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-27-person273" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-27-person273" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came to my house and said he came from Hampstead, and ask'd if this was Mr. Barnardiston's; I said it was; he said I have got your boy and your money, with a horse and saddle for you. There was an apothecary with him. They brought me twenty-eight guineas and a moidore. The apothecary said he was coming by when the boy was taken, and being willing to save my cash, he came; but he is not here now, as I did not think there would be any occasion for him. We took the prisoner to justice Welch, and he committed him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-27-person274">
                  James 
                  Lightholder 
               <interp inst="t17560225-27-person274" type="surname" value="Lightholder"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-27-person274" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-27-person274" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Hampstead. Last Monday was sev'n-night in the evening, the boy at the bar came to my house, and asked for a lodging; he lay there; the next morning he went away, and returned again about one o'clock with a little grey mare, and a bridle but no saddle; he said it was his master's mare, that he had sent him out for an airing for an hour or two, and had order'd him to<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175602250019"></xptr> buy a saddle; which gave me a suspicion things were not right. I sent for a saddler in Hampstead, who brought a saddle, which the boy bought and paid for. I told the saddler afterwards, I did not think the boy was honest. He said he had cross questioned him, and thought there was nothing amiss. I told him, he says his master lives in Chancery-lane, I'll take my horse and ride thither; so we both set out together, that is, the boy and I. When we were come out of Hampstead, he (having the best horse) rode off; but there being a great many people on the road, they stop'd him, and he fell from his horse. There was a gentleman comeing by with a child in his hand, to whom I told my suspicion. We searched the boy, and I counted as I thought 27 guineas and a moidore (which I took from the boy) into the gentleman's hand, but when I came to tell it afterwards, there were 28 guineas and a moidore. The gentleman and I brought him to his master's house. We talk'd to him as we went along, but he would own nothing till he got to his master's, and there he confessed he had taken it out of his master's till.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I am but twelve years and four months old.</p>
               <p>Barnardiston. It has given me a great deal of pain to prosecute him. I hope his tender years will meet with compassion.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-27-person275">
                  Samuel 
                  Hows 
               <interp inst="t17560225-27-person275" type="surname" value="Hows"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-27-person275" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-27-person275" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Barnardiston, and am intrusted with the cash. On Saturday was sev'n-night my master gave me 30 guineas, to put amongst the rest of the cash. The next morning I went to the till, and found the bag and money gone. I had it in my hand but about a quarter of an hour before, to put some more gold into the bag.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the till lock'd ?</p>
               <p>Hows. It was. The boy being missing, we suspected him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the mare your master's?</p>
               <p>Hows. No. We had an account he bought her on the road.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17560225-27-verdict153" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560225-27-verdict153" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17560225-27-punish154" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560225-27-punish154" type="punishmentCategory" value="noPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-27-punish154" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="sentenceRespited"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-27-defend269 t17560225-27-punish154"></join>
               
                     <note>[No punishment. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
