<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560714-18">
               <interp inst="t17560714-18" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560714-18" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560714-18" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560714"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560714-18" type="date" value="17560714"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560714-18-off93-c98" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560714-18-defend128 t17560714-18-off93 t17560714-18-verdict96"></join>
         
               <p>300. ( M) 
               
                  <persName id="t17560714-18-defend128" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Hart 
                  <interp inst="t17560714-18-defend128" type="surname" value="Hart"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-18-defend128" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-18-defend128" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for that <rs id="t17560714-18-off93" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560714-18-off93" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-18-off93" type="offenceSubcategory" value="gameLawOffence"></interp>
               he unlawfully and willfully did hunt , wound, kill, destroy, and carry away two fallow deer, the property of 
                     <persName id="t17560714-18-victim129" type="victimName">
                        Ann. 
                        <rs id="t17560714-18-viclabel94" type="occupation">countess dowager of Albemarle</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560714-18-victim129 t17560714-18-viclabel94"></join>
                        <interp inst="t17560714-18-victim129" type="given" value="Ann."></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560714-18-victim129" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560714-18-off93 t17560714-18-victim129"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , in a place inclosed with pales, where deer are usually kept
            </rs>. <rs id="t17560714-18-cd95" type="crimeDate">July 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560714-18-off93 t17560714-18-cd95"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560714-18-person130">
                  Joseph 
                  Marlbrough 
               <interp inst="t17560714-18-person130" type="surname" value="Marlbrough"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-18-person130" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-18-person130" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the sign of the Harrow, by lady Albemarle's park side, and am tenant to her ladyship.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is in possession of the park at this time?</p>
               <p>Marlbrough. My lady, and the present lord Albemarle.</p>
               <p>Q. Is the park fenced in?</p>
               <p>Marlbrough. It is all round with pales and posts as other parks are. There are ladder stiles, and gates upon them, and there is a park-keeper on purpose to look after the deer. My late lord bought it about 22 years ago; it then was a farm, and he made it a park to keep deer and hares in.</p>
               <p>Q. What have you to say against, the prisoner at the bar?</p>
               <p>Marlbrough. On Sunday was sen'night, about five in the afternoon, the prisoner and 
               <persName id="t17560714-18-person131">
                  Thomas 
                  Cole 
               <interp inst="t17560714-18-person131" type="surname" value="Cole"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-18-person131" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-18-person131" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came to my house and called for a pot of beer, and after that another, which they paid for, and staid about half an hour. After they went away, I thought by their scouting and leering about in the road, on the backside of people's house, and in the fields, that the park would be robbed that night. In the morning, about two o'clock, I got up to go a mowing; and going up the park, I saw a place where there had been a great deal of trampling about, and I smelt something like blood, and saw something on the ground which I ran my hand into, and found it was blood. Then I went to the ladder-stile near it, and found blood on both sides the ladder; and I also found blood upon the wall, about the quantity of three pints. This is a wall to keep the deer from going into the pleasure gardens. I looked over the wall and saw a paunch lying. I then went on the other side of the ladder-stile, and found a place where another buck had been stain, another paunch lying there.</p>
               <p>Q. What place was this in?</p>
               <p>Marlbrough. It was in the garden. I went down the path towards Barnet, where I traced blood on both sides of the stile that goes that way. I ran<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175607140010"></xptr> back to the keeper, and told him what I saw. He came with me with a gun, and we followed the track of the blood out of the park and across two fields. Then he said, I'll turn back and acquaint the Steward. I said, I'd find out the deer if I could. I went into the third field, wherein there were beans, amongst which I found a large white buck lying across the land, covered with the beans, and a little farther I found another buck tied up in a sack. Then I was afraid to stay, so came back and told the keeper what I had found. He came and saw them, and gave me his gun, desiring me to lie under a hedge, and take the person or persons that came if I could. The gun was loaded with pistol balls, and powder. The keeper went away to London to the steward, and came back to me again. I thought it not proper he should go quite up to the deer, fearing it should put the persons by from coming. He went home again, and in about twenty minutes after the prisoner at the bar came over the stile from Barnet way, ran directly to the first buck, and turning himself round drop'd on all fours, in the same manner as a Hawk drops upon a bird, and as quick; he turn'd it, and took it into the furrow.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was you to him?</p>
               <p>Marlbrough. I was about thirty yards from him, or something better.</p>
               <p>Q. How far did the deer lie from the path way?</p>
               <p>Marlbrough. About twenty-five yards.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is the stile from the place where the deer lay?</p>
               <p>Marlbrough. About forty or fifty yards, I believe.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was this?</p>
               <p>Marlbrough. It was about five in the afternoon. I had lain there all that time, there had not a christian gone by but I saw them. I jump'd over the hedge, and went up to him. I said to him, Friend design, I insist upon your life, or your body dead or alive, for you are my prisoner; he ran five or six poles on his hands and knees. I told him, I had rather he'd design than to shoot him. I knew his life was better-than a burying. He had a great stick in his hand. He designed so far as to walk before me up to my house. We walked into the park, where he sat down at the root of a tree, and said, I'll go no farther, you may shoot me if you please; if I have done any thing, shoot me. I hallow'd out for help, and then he took his walk back-towards Barnet. I kept about fourteen yards from him, fearing his stick. When he saw other people coming after him with guns and other weapons; he ran, and I ran and kept distance with him till we came upon the top of Barnet-Common, where he cry'd out murder, and several people came out to assist him. I desir'd them to help me, and said I'd shoot the first man that assisted him, and said he was my prisoner. Then he fell into a ditch, and would not design then. There were some people that I feared would strive to save his life, and take away mine. There was a man on horse back that was on my part. I gave him my gun. The prisoner with his stick, and said he'd beat my brains out. I ran up to him, and flung him down. Then he said sixteen of you shall not bind me, I want only two good fellows. I found all the mob round for taking his part. I got his stick away, and then he was going to fight me with his hands. I took him into an alehouse and bound him, and then carried him to my lady house, and from thence to mine, and kept him there all morning. There was neither constable or a justice to be got in Barnet at that time. We brought him in a cart to justice Fielding's, and he committed him.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say before the justice ?</p>
               <p>Marlbrough. He made himself very innocent; he would not know any thing about it. He said he did not know me or my house, nor the way to my house neither.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does the park-keeper live?</p>
               <p>Marlbrough. His name is Mr. Yakesly; he lives in my lady's house.</p>
               <p>Q. Does my lady live there now?</p>
               <p>Marlbrough. It is two summers ago since my lady has been there. The steward is there may be twice a week.</p>
               <p>Q. Who pays the workmen and servants there?</p>
               <p>Marlbrough. The steward pays me, but whether it is my lady's or my lord Bury's money I know not; it was never my business to enquire into that.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did she live there after my lord was dead?</p>
               <p>Marlbrough. I can't be particular. I know they kill a great deal of venison, some for their own use, and some to make presents of. There was also another buck found with his back and jaw broke; it was the second best buck in the park.</p>
               <p>Mr. Ellis.. I am the officer that had the prisoner in custody, and carried him to justice Fielding. He was delivered into my hands between seven and eight o'clock on Monday was se'nnight at night, and I was with him at the other evidence's house all night; he would not own any thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live ?</p>
               <p>Ellis. At South Mints.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>The other man that was with me, named 
               <persName id="t17560714-18-person132">
                  Thomas 
                  Cole 
               <interp inst="t17560714-18-person132" type="surname" value="Cole"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-18-person132" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-18-person132" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , desired I would go with him to such a place. I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175607140011"></xptr> was very much against it, and said it was a very unfair and unjust thing. He insisted upon my going along with him; so with a great deal of persuasion I went. He lives at Whetstone, and I at Barnet. He turn'd the dogs into the park, and they killed these deer. I would have had him to have left them there.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17560714-18-verdict96" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560714-18-verdict96" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17560714-18-punish97" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560714-18-punish97" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560714-18-defend128 t17560714-18-punish97"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
