<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17581206-26">
               <interp inst="t17581206-26" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581206-26" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581206-26" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17581206"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581206-26" type="date" value="17581206"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17581206-26-off138-c214" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-26-defend256 t17581206-26-off138 t17581206-26-verdict143"></join>
         
               <p>29. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17581206-26-defend256" type="defendantName">
                     Samuel 
                     Cordwell 
                  <interp inst="t17581206-26-defend256" type="surname" value="Cordwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-26-defend256" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-26-defend256" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17581206-26-off138" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581206-26-off138" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-26-off138" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 15 guineas and 3 l. in money, numbered; the money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17581206-26-victim258" type="victimName">
                           Elizabeth 
                           Greenwood 
                        <interp inst="t17581206-26-victim258" type="surname" value="Greenwood"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17581206-26-victim258" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17581206-26-victim258" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17581206-26-viclabel139" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-26-victim258 t17581206-26-viclabel139"></join>; and one pound of worsted, value 10 d. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17581206-26-victim260" type="victimName">
                           Henry 
                           Badcock 
                        <interp inst="t17581206-26-victim260" type="surname" value="Badcock"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17581206-26-victim260" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17581206-26-victim260" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling-house of the said Henry
            </rs>, <rs id="t17581206-26-cd140" type="crimeDate">November 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-26-off138 t17581206-26-cd140"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-26-person261">
                  Henry 
                  Badcock 
               <interp inst="t17581206-26-person261" type="surname" value="Badcock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-26-person261" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-26-person261" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I <rs id="t17581206-26-viclabel141" type="occupation">keep a Hosier's shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-26-victim260 t17581206-26-viclabel141"></join> in <placeName id="t17581206-26-crimeloc142">Bishopsgate-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17581206-26-crimeloc142" type="placeName" value="Bishopsgate-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17581206-26-crimeloc142" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-26-off138 t17581206-26-crimeloc142"></join>; the prisoner had worked for me about a fortnight or three weeks before this happened; he came to my house on the 17th of last month, I left him in a little room with Mrs Greenwood my house-keeper, and went up to my workmen to read the news-paper to them; I did not stay long, and when I came down again, my house-keeper said the prisoner was come up stairs, and he went up very softly; I not seeing him, went up and found him in my house-keeper's room up two pair of stairs; he was scuffling with something in his hands by her bed-side. I said what business have you here? he said he was only looking for a dram. I took him up into the work-shop, he was so much dejected, he could hardly stand; I did not search him; I went down and told my housekeeper of it, and bid her go up and see if she miss'd any thing. She went up, and came down, and said every thing was in the same position as before; and said she belived she had lost nothing. A woman that the prisoner liv'd with came into my shop, he came down, and they went away together. At night, I went to see whether he had not taken any worsted, and miss'd one pound out of a parcel of half a dozen  there I found but 45 skains, which was nine skains short; then I call'd one of my men down, and told him I miss'd a pound of yarn: I shew'd him the parcel, and he saw there was a pound missing. He went and fetch'd him from an ale-house in Holloway-Lane, very much in liquor; I held out the bundle to him and said, You have taken out a pound from it: then he said, Have you a mind to hang me, I wish I was hang'd, I'll cut my throat. He agreed to pay for the worsted, I let him go. On the next Sunday in the forenoon, I was below, my kouse-keeper was above, I heard her fall down into a swoon; I stepp'd to the stairs and ask'd what was the matter? she said, This villain has robb'd me: I went directly and got a constable and apprehended him in Holloway-Lane. At first, his wife said he was not at home, and I should not come in; but I got in, and found him in the necessary-house, and carried him to New-prison, the next day before Justice Keeling, and he was committed. Then the Wednesday following, came his own brother with two gentlemen, they told me I had no occasion to say any more to them about it, for he had confessed the fact. On the Monday after, I and a neighbour, one Mr Collins, went to the prison to him; as soon as he saw me, he burst into a flood of tears, and acknowledged he had taken the money, and said he was very sorry for it; he said, How much money was it? I said, 18 l. odd. Said he, I did not keep count, but spent it as I wanted it: he said also he had taken it before that time that I catch'd him in the room. I said, How could you rob this poor old woman? he said, It was drinking and the temptation of the Devil; but he took all the blame upon himself, he thought it would never be found out, but every thing is brought to light, he said.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What workmen do you keep?</p>
               <p>Badcock. I keep Wool-combers; the prisoner has work'd for me as a Wool-comber.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he leave your service?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175812060029"></xptr>Badcock. I believe he left my service about the beginning of November.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he behave in his business?</p>
               <p>Badcock. Not well at all; always drunk in his business; I lost the selling of many goods upon his account.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he took the money all at once ?</p>
               <p>Badcock. No, he said he took it at separate times, while he worked with me, and he had taken all his wife's cloaths from pawn.</p>
               <p>Q. For what purpose did he come this time to your house?</p>
               <p>Badcock. I verily believe it was to get up into that room.</p>
               <p>Q. How came the yarn in your house-keeper's bed-room?</p>
               <p>Badcock. Sometimes I have not room for all I have in my shop; then sometimes I have half a pack lies there.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you charge the prisoner with at the goal?</p>
               <p>Badcock. I ask'd him if he was guilty of stealing my house-keeper's money? he said he had taken it, but not when I found him in the room, but at separate times before.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any promise of favour made him?</p>
               <p>Badcock. No, none: only I said I'd do what I can for you (my meaning was, to bring him to justice ).</p>
               <p>Q. Was this confession before or after this?</p>
               <p>Badcock. I believe this was after his confession; he confessed voluntarily.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say before the Justice?</p>
               <p>Badcock. He said he would not confess; but whether he liv'd or died Mrs Greenwood should not lose her money; his friends should give her that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-26-person262">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Greenwood 
               <interp inst="t17581206-26-person262" type="surname" value="Greenwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-26-person262" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-26-person262" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am house-keeper to Mr Badcock; I had all my money on the 12th of August, 15 guineas in gold, eight crowns, of which he left two, 20 s. in single shillings, and two half-crowns.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see it last?</p>
               <p>E. Greenwood. I was at my chest one day looking at my things, I thought my box was a little light, but I did not look in it.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>E. Greenwood. This was the week before this came out.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you miss the money?</p>
               <p>E. Greenwood. The Sunday morning after he was taken; he was taken on Friday the 14th, the day he was found in my room; then I went to make my bed, and sweep my room, I went to take a basket from off a chest, and my black silk purse that my gold was in, was lying on the chest; then I looked for my silver, and all were gone but two crown pieces.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the prisoner say any thing about the money?</p>
               <p>E. Greenwood. No, I did not; he told me at the Justice's, he would not confess; but said, Mrs Greenwood, let me live or die, my friends will make you recompence.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you us'd to keep your chest lock'd?</p>
               <p>E. Greenwood. I did, but this time I found it open, and the box that I us'd to put at the bottom of all my cloaths, I found on the top; and I was frighted very much.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the last time you saw the money?</p>
               <p>E. Greenwood. I saw it since the 12th of August, but I did not tell it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you look in your purse that time you look'd in your box?</p>
               <p>E. Greenwood. I saw money in the box, that was silver, but I did not look in the purse; I only can say there was some gold in it, but I did not tell it.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was this before he was found in your room?</p>
               <p>E. Greenwood. This was about a week before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-26-person263">
                  John 
                  Parker 
               <interp inst="t17581206-26-person263" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-26-person263" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-26-person263" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner at the bar rented a room of me, with a woman that he call'd his wife, and her mother liv'd with them; sometimes he work'd along with me for Mr Badcock, but he did not do a great deal of work; he was always drinking, and always had money: about a fortnight before he was taken up, he shew'd me half a guinea and 6 or 7 s. in silver, and said he had met with a friend that he had it of: I ask'd his name, he could not tell, but said he was a Silversmith: he never could work without liquor, and I know he has not earn'd above 4 s. a week, one week with another.</p>
               <p>Q. What could he earn a week?</p>
               <p>Parker. If he would keep sober he would earn eight or nine shillings a week.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175812060030"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-26-person264">
                  John 
                  Stafford 
               <interp inst="t17581206-26-person264" type="surname" value="Stafford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-26-person264" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-26-person264" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 17th of last month Mr Badcock brought the prisoner up into the workshop, and said, he catch'd him in the room under the shop; he said to him, I am surpriz'd what brought you into that room; the prisoner said, I was looking for a pocket-pistol; said Mr Badcock, do you suppose I carry fire-arms; no, said the prisoner, I mean a small phial bottle; Mr Badcock soon went down stairs; the prisoner seemed very much dejected; said my shop-mate, let us contrive to get a little beer for him; said he, I can neither eat nor drink, I do not care if my throat was cut a-cross; he soon went down; when he was taken, he got out of bed and ordered the old woman to bolt the door after him, and he was taken in the necessary-house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-26-person265">
                  James 
                  Collins 
               <interp inst="t17581206-26-person265" type="surname" value="Collins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-26-person265" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-26-person265" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 27th of last November I went with Mr Badcock, to Clerkenwell prison; there I heard the prisoner confess he took the money mentioned, at different times, that he found the keys on the top of the box.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Collins. I am a Linnen-Draper; and went by particular desire of the prosecutor.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any promise made him if he would confess?</p>
               <p>Collins. I think there was some promise of favour.</p>
               <p>Q. Before, or after, he confess'd?</p>
               <p>Collins. Before he confess'd: I think the promise was, that he would be as favourable as he could.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence. I was very much in liquor when I went into this house; Mrs Greenwood was in a little room; I ask'd, if I might step up to the men at work; she said, yes; I stepp'd into the room, on the second story, where the wool used to lay; the men where talking what good work they had been upon, I went to see what sort of wool it was, whether it was better work than my own; I was looking at it I believe ten minutes, my master came and catch'd me there, I had put the door too, because he should not see me looking at the work; he ask'd me what I came there for; I said, for a dram; he took me up stairs; they ask'd me if I would have a pint; I said, I had been drinking all day; we joined for a pint a piece; I went home, and then to the Crown in Holloway-lane for a pint of beer, and Mr Badcock sent a man for me; I went to him, and said, what do you want with me; then he said, what business had you in Mrs Greenwood's room, I have lost some yarn and I lay it to you; I said, I never saw a skain of yarn there in my life; he said, if I would not pay him for it he would have a warrant for me. Then I said, sooner than I would be sandaliz'd I will pay you for it. I went to work on Saturday at Mr Honyborn's, and at night Mr Badcock came with a constable and took me, as I was at the necessary house.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-26-person266">
                  John 
                  Beck 
               <interp inst="t17581206-26-person266" type="surname" value="Beck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-26-person266" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-26-person266" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was before the justice when Mrs Greenwood was examined; she said, she had seen her money about a week or ten days before. She did not mention either gold or silver. I have known the prisoner 12 or 14 years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Beck. To the best of my knowledge he is a good workman; I never heard any thing amiss of him, or any of his family; he has very reputable parents.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-26-person267">
                  William 
                  Hunt 
               <interp inst="t17581206-26-person267" type="surname" value="Hunt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-26-person267" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-26-person267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner above twenty years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Hunt. He has a very good character; I never heard any thing ill of him nor any of his family; I believe he is a very honest fellow; and if he wanted money his friends could let him have it, if it was twenty or thirty guineas.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-26-person268">
                  James 
                  Twitchel 
               <interp inst="t17581206-26-person268" type="surname" value="Twitchel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-26-person268" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-26-person268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner sixteen years, I never knew he was guilty of doing any ill; he was always very honest, I have been in his company many times; his friends are people of credit.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-26-person269">
                  George 
                  Alden 
               <interp inst="t17581206-26-person269" type="surname" value="Alden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-26-person269" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-26-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the White-Hart Inn, St John's street; I did once live at St Alban's, and knew the prisoner's relations, people of good credit; the prisoner bore a good character, only he used to love a little liquor; I never heard any dishonesty of him before this; I could have trusted him with any thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-26-person270">
                  Mr 
                  Finney 
               <interp inst="t17581206-26-person270" type="surname" value="Finney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-26-person270" type="given" value="Mr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-26-person270" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have been acquainted with the prisoner's family for upwards of twenty years; the prisoner was a very honest lad 'till this affair for what I ever heard; but I have had little knowledge of him for this three years last past.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17581206-26-verdict143" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581206-26-verdict143" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-26-verdict143" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder40s"></interp>
               Guilty 39 s
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17581206-26-punish144" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581206-26-punish144" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-26-punish144" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-26-defend256 t17581206-26-punish144"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
