<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570914-26">
               <interp inst="t17570914-26" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-26" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-26" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570914"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-26" type="date" value="17570914"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570914-26-off154-c233" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-26-defend284 t17570914-26-off154 t17570914-26-verdict157"></join>
         
               <p>326. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17570914-26-defend284" type="defendantName">
                  Alvery 
                  Baker 
               <interp inst="t17570914-26-defend284" type="surname" value="Baker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-26-defend284" type="given" value="Alvery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-26-defend284" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17570914-26-off154" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570914-26-off154" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-26-off154" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               sacrilegiously stealing two gold tossels, belonging to the pulpit cushion, the property of the 
                     <persName id="t17570914-26-victim285" type="victimName">
                        <interp inst="t17570914-26-victim285" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-26-off154 t17570914-26-victim285"></join>
                     </persName>
                   of <placeName id="t17570914-26-crimeloc155">St. Bride's</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-26-crimeloc155" type="placeName" value="St. Bride's"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-26-crimeloc155" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-26-off154 t17570914-26-crimeloc155"></join>, it being in the custody of the churchwardens
            </rs>, <rs id="t17570914-26-cd156" type="crimeDate">July 25</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-26-off154 t17570914-26-cd156"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-26-person286">
                  Matthew 
                  Arnold 
               <interp inst="t17570914-26-person286" type="surname" value="Arnold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-26-person286" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-26-person286" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am beadle of the parish of St. Bride's. Mr. Brown, a painter at Newington, came to London on the 2d of September, and enquired for the churchwardens of the parish of St. Bride's, who were not in the way, but one of the overseers brought him to me, and desired I would assist Mr. Brown in taking the prisoner, he having had an information against him on this affair.</p>
               <p>Q. What was lost?</p>
               <p>Arnold. Two gold tossels belonging to the pulpit cushion, from out of a wainscot box in the vestry room.</p>
         
               <p>The Second Part of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17570914-26">
                  <interp inst="t17570914-26" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17570914-26" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17570914-26" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570914"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17570914-26" type="date" value="17570914"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175709140021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON, And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 14th, Thursday the 15th, Friday the 16th, Saturday the 17th, and Monday the 19th of SEPTEMBER.</p>
                  <p>In the Thirty-first Year of His MAJESTY'S Reign. NUMBER VII. PART II. Being the Seventh SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of The Right Honble MARSHE DICKINSON, Esq; LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by J. ROBINSON, at the Golden-Lion, in Ludgate-Street. 1757.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175709140022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, and Oyer and Terminer, for the City of LONDON, and at the General 
                  <persName id="t17570914-26-person287">
                     Sessions
                  <interp inst="t17570914-26-person287" type="given" value="Sessions"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570914-26-person287" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                     </persName>
                of Gaol Delivery of Newgate, holden for the said City of LONDON, and County of MIDDLESEX, at Justice-Hall in the Old-Bailey, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Q. WERE they fix'd to the cushion?</p>
               <p>Arnold. They were.</p>
               <p>Q. When were they missing?</p>
               <p>Arnold. I can't say the exact time.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the last time you saw them?</p>
               <p>Arnold. That was, I believe; about the 22d of April, or the Sunday before; the church was shut up about that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you meet with the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Arnold. I went with Mr. Brown to the Cross-Keys Inn, Gracechurch-Street, where he was at work as a journeyman barber. We took him before a magistrate, where he wanted to be admitted an evidence against Rawson.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say any thing as to the fact he is now charged with?</p>
               <p>Arnold. He acknowledged he came into the vestry room, when Rawson was at work there as a journeyman painter, and could say enough to hang Rawson.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he own he took the tossels ?</p>
               <p>Arnold. I can't directly say whether he did or not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever find the tossels again ?</p>
               <p>Arnold. No, never.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-26-person288">
                  Susannah 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17570914-26-person288" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-26-person288" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-26-person288" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am sextoness of the parish of St. Bride's. The church was open on the 22d of April, two years ago, and then shut up nine months to be beautified. On the 22d of April the gold tossels were there, I had lock'd them up in the box as usual in the vestry, there were four tossels to the cushion; and about two or three months after, the things being exceeding good, I was afraid they would mildew; I unlock'd the box to look at the cushion, and missed two tossels.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find the box lock'd?</p>
               <p>S. Davis. I did, but the tossels could be taken out without unlocking the box; which is a yard or more long, and is made something in a half round, so as to receive the whole as it lies on the pulpit, and each end might be lifted up, so as to get a hand in and take out the tossels, the lock being in the middle; since that we have had a lock put on at each end.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever seen the two tossels since?</p>
               <p>S. Davis. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any other workmen in the vestry room at the time it was beautifying, besides Rawson?</p>
               <p>S. Davis. Yes, a great many. I know he was there for one. There were bricklayers, carpenters, and all sorts of workmen in the vestry.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see the prisoner there?</p>
               <p>S. Davis. No, never to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-26-person289">
                  Robert 
                  Rawson 
               <interp inst="t17570914-26-person289" type="surname" value="Rawson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-26-person289" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-26-person289" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner came to me when I was at work, in painting: the vestry room at St. Bride's Church, and ask'd me how I did; there stood a box by him. He ask'd me what was in it. I said I did not know. He said then he'd soon know what was in it, and lifted up the lid and took out a gold tossel; he shew'd it to me and said, '' This is a pretty booty.'' I mov'd my steps to the door where I was at work, but whether he cut or wrong it off I do not know. He brought it some yards from the box. The next day he came again and took another tossel in the same manner. After that he told me he made six shillings a piece of them; that he sold one at the Flower-Pot in Bishopsgate-Street, and the other in Wood-Street.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any part of the money ?</p>
               <p>Rawson. We had eels together at the Bell, and he gave me 3 s. in part of the money; he said he had lost the money he sold one of them for at cribbige.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you make the first discovery of this?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175709140023"></xptr>Rawson. After I was taken up about the gold watch belonging to Mr. Towle, the prisoner knowing I was taken up went and made a discovery of it to justice Fielding. After I was admitted an evidence I was sent for from prison and told about it, and I was admitted an evidence against Cannington and he.</p>
               <p>John Brown. I went to New Prison to see Cannington, who told me Rawson and the prisoner had stole some gold tassels from out of St. Bride's church, but could not tell the time. I went to the overseer of St. Bride's, who directed me to Arnold, so came at the knowledge of the affair.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the prisoner confess any thing?</p>
               <p>Brown. I heard him say he would discover the whole affair, if they would admit him an evidence, that he saw Rawson burning something; he ask'd him what it was, and he answer'd it was a bit of lace.</p>
               <p>Q. to S. Davis. Did you ever inquire where the evidence says the tossels were sold?</p>
               <p>S. Davis. No. I never did.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>On the 8th of August I went to his worship, and made the discovery of the gold watch stolen by Cannington. When Rawson's mittimus was writing, Mr. Brown said, now is your time to make what discovery you can, and get admitted an evidence Rawson had said he knew of nothing against me, but his making diamonds, in order to deceive the pawnbrokers, which I carried about. His worship order'd me to go home to work, I did, and remain'd there till the 2d of September, when Mr. Brown and that other witness came to me, and said they came to save my life, for Rawson was going to make himself an evidence against me for these tossels. I said I heard Rawson make mention of that, and several more robberies I told them I would go with them where they pleased. We went before Mr. Fielding, and the justice told me I must go to the watch house, and he would hear me in the morning. When he sent for me I was detain'd there two hours before Rawson came up; when he came he was admitted, and swore these two robberies against me.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-26-person290">
                  Joseph 
                  Rowbridge 
               <interp inst="t17570914-26-person290" type="surname" value="Rowbridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-26-person290" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-26-person290" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a barber, and live in the Cross Keys Inn Yard, Gracechurch-street. The prisoner has work'd with me ever since last Whitsun Monday.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Rowbridge. He had a very good one, all the time he was with me he behav'd very well, and was very honest.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-26-person291">
                  John 
                  Ellot 
               <interp inst="t17570914-26-person291" type="surname" value="Ellot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-26-person291" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-26-person291" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about three months, where he was with this master; I was chamberlain at the Cross Keys Inn, and used frequently to call him to shave gentlemen there; he has behaved honestly as far as ever I knew. I never heard any thing amiss of him.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570914-26-verdict157" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570914-26-verdict157" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
