<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17500711-24">
               <interp inst="t17500711-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-24" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17500711"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-24" type="date" value="17500711"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500711-24-off109-c160" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-24-defend207 t17500711-24-off109 t17500711-24-verdict112"></join>
         
               <p>443. 
               
                  <persName id="t17500711-24-defend207" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     More 
                  <interp inst="t17500711-24-defend207" type="surname" value="More"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-24-defend207" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-24-defend207" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17500711-24-off109" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500711-24-off109" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-24-off109" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               stealing one hat and one periwig
            </rs>, the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17500711-24-victim209" type="victimName">
                     Evan 
                     Harris 
                  <interp inst="t17500711-24-victim209" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-24-victim209" type="given" value="Evan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-24-victim209" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-24-off109 t17500711-24-victim209"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            .</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500711-24-cd110" type="crimeDate">June 14</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-24-off109 t17500711-24-cd110"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-24-person210">
                  Evan 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17500711-24-person210" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-24-person210" type="given" value="Evan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-24-person210" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17500711-24-viclabel111" type="occupation">taylor</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-24-victim209 t17500711-24-viclabel111"></join>, I had been taking up fustians and other goods, and returning home between 10 and 12 at night, I left my parcel with an acquaintance in Hatton Garden, it being late. Going from thence up Holborn, just beyond the bars, I met with an acquaintance, he said, be careful how you go home, for it is dangerous walking the streets now at this time of night. I parted with him. The prisoner came up to me, and said, I'll see you home, I believe you are my country man; I said, what countryman are you? He said, I am an Irishman; I said I was not. He said, you are in liquor (but I was not) and he would go along with me. Just as we came by the duke of Newcastle's house he would have me go and drink with him. I said I had no money, which was true. He came up Queen Court with me under the middle archway, there he took off my hat and wig, and ran away with them. I pursued him; he ran cross the way; I got before him, running faster than he; he ran back again, but I overtook him, and stood before him there; he d - d my b - d, and asked me what I wanted with him? then he knock'd me down with his fist, and kick'd and bruised me much; then he crossed the way again, and I pursued him a second time, and met with the same ill usage; then he went away, and crossed the way again; I got up, and ran after him a third time; then I took him by the collar, and we both fell down, and I called out. The watch came up, and took him before I lost my hold of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did the prisoner and you first come together?</p>
               <p>Harris. He overtook me just by Holborn Bars, then I did not like him, and walked apace to get away from him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-24-person211">
                  John 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17500711-24-person211" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-24-person211" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-24-person211" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watchman in Great Wild-street. On the 14th of June, between 11 and 12 o'clock at night, I heard the cry, stop thief, in Great Queen-street; there I saw two men both bare-headed. The prosecutor said, I have been robbed by the prisoner of my hat and wig, and knocked down three times. Then another watchman came to my assistance, we took the prisoner to the constable of the night; then I went and searched in Great Queen-street, and found two hats and one wig under the archway going into Queen Court; they lay together; I brought them to the watch-house, and each took his own; they both charged one another, so they both were sent to the Round-house, then before Justice Fielding, and he committed the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence. As I was coming home from work, about 9 o'clock, Mr. Harris overtook me, and clapped his hand on my shoulder, and said, hollo! where are you going? I am going home, said I; I live in Queen-street; so we went home together. Said he, I have been fighting, and have got a black eye. He had a handkerchief tied round his head; he said, he believed it was one of his countrymen he fought with. We came along together to Queen-street. He said to me, will not you drink some beer before you go home? No, said I, I have drank two pots of beer since I have done my work. Said he, what is the matter you will not? I said, I'll drink none. He said he'd treat me. Said I, I return you thanks, I'll drink none. Said he, you are a scoundrel fellow; he made a blow at me; I stood upon my own defence; I saw no wig; my hat was lost, also my wig, and a handkerchief, which cost 4 s. 6 d. The watchman coming by, he charged me, and I charged him; the watchman went back, and found our hats, but my wig and handkerchief were lost.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-24-person212">
                  William 
                  Robertson 
               <interp inst="t17500711-24-person212" type="surname" value="Robertson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-24-person212" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-24-person212" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going that way, and heard the prosecutor call out, stop thief. I saw the prisoner knock the gentleman down three times, and saw him cross the way &amp;c. but I saw nothing of his meddling with the prosecutor's hat and wig.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500711-24-verdict112" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500711-24-verdict112" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
