<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17580222-16">
               <interp inst="t17580222-16" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580222-16" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580222-16" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580222"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580222-16" type="date" value="17580222"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580222-16-off83-c123" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580222-16-defend148 t17580222-16-off83 t17580222-16-verdict84"></join>
         
               <p>120. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17580222-16-defend148" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Coe 
                  <interp inst="t17580222-16-defend148" type="surname" value="Coe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-defend148" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-defend148" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was <rs id="t17580222-16-off83" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-off83" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-off83" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               indicted for that 
                     <persName id="t17580222-16-person149">
                        Thomas 
                        Lambeth 
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person149" type="surname" value="Lambeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580222-16-person149" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580222-16-person149" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , on the 18th of Nov. in the 30th year of his present majesty, did steal 39 pounds weight of shellack, value 7 l. the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17580222-16-victim151" type="victimName">
                           Arthur 
                           Evans 
                        <interp inst="t17580222-16-victim151" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580222-16-victim151" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580222-16-victim151" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580222-16-off83 t17580222-16-victim151"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , and that he the said Coe the same did receive and have, well knowing the same to have been stolen
            </rs>. ++</p>
               <p>The out-lawry of 
               <persName id="t17580222-16-person152">
                  Thomas 
                  Lambeth 
               <interp inst="t17580222-16-person152" type="surname" value="Lambeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person152" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person152" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             read in court, wherein it appeared he had been demanded five times, and did not appear.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580222-16-person153">
                  Edward 
                  Hammock 
               <interp inst="t17580222-16-person153" type="surname" value="Hammock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person153" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person153" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About three months before the 15th of Nov. 1756, I was employed on board one of the East-India Company's lighters, and on that day I was on board the Eastcourt Indiaman, in Long Reach. 
               <persName id="t17580222-16-person154">
                  Thomas 
                  Lambeth 
               <interp inst="t17580222-16-person154" type="surname" value="Lambeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person154" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person154" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and I consulted together to get some shellack, while the people were at work, and he looked out while I got some out of a chest. I broke it open, and took out about 39 pounds weight. We left it in the lighter till it came up to Botolph wharf.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Hammock. I am a lighterman, so was Lambeth. When we came to the wharf 
               <persName id="t17580222-16-person155">
                  Thomas 
                  Maclockline 
               <interp inst="t17580222-16-person155" type="surname" value="Maclockline"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person155" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person155" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came, and asked me if I had got a chap for it. (We had told him of it before.) We said, no. He said he could help us to a chap. Then Lambeth handed it to me out of the lighter into the skist. I rowed down to Bear Key. Then Maclockline went on shore, and was to come again, but did not. Soon after the prisoner Coe came, who asked me if I belong'd to the green skist. I said, yes. He said, fetch it out; those were his words: he did not say what. I did, and carried it half way to the corner of Love Lane, to an alehouse, when Coe took it. He went with me all the way, and carried it into the alehouse.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know him before?</p>
               <p>Hammock. No, I did not; there I saw Macklockline, Lambeth, and 
               <persName id="t17580222-16-person156">
                  Henry 
                  George 
               <interp inst="t17580222-16-person156" type="surname" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person156" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person156" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He put it between the bench and settle, and then went and lighted a candle.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he know what it was?</p>
               <p>Hammock. I don't know that he did; he went down into the cellar, and I carried the bag after him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body go with you?</p>
               <p>Hammock. No, we were there alone. He unlock'd a cupboard in the cellar, took out a pair of stilliards, and weigh'd it; it weigh'd forty-three pounds.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him open the bag to look at it?</p>
               <p>Hammock. I am not sure. We allowed him four pounds for the bag. I know he emptied it out of the bag after he had paid for it.</p>
               <p>Q. What was he to give you for it?</p>
               <p>Hammock. He was to give half a crown a pound for it, and paid for thirty nine pounds.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he pay you in the cellar?</p>
               <p>Hammock. He did. Then he put it in the cupboard where he took the stilliards from.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see what sort of stuff it was when you took it out of the chest?</p>
               <p>Hammock. I did.</p>
               <p>Council. Look at this in this paper. (Producing a paper, &amp;c.)</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175802220012"></xptr>Hammock. (He looks at it.) It was such sort of stuff as this.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. As you did not know what commodity it was, how came you to take 2 s. and 6 d. per pound for it?</p>
               <p>Hammock. He offered that to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you a right to sell it?</p>
               <p>Hammock. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any thing said in the publick tap room between them and the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Hammock. Not a word as I remember.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is it from Bear-Key to that ale-house?</p>
               <p>Hammock. It may be four or five hundred yards distance.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to row to Bear-Key ?</p>
               <p>Hammock. I was to row to some private place, and Maclockline was to have come to me again.</p>
               <p>Q. How came the prisoner to mention the word it?</p>
               <p>Hammock. Because Maclockline had sent him, and, I suppose, had told him of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Why do you suppose so?</p>
               <p>Hammock. Because he went on shore to help me to a chap, and the prisoner came and asked me if I belong'd to the green skift.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the actual sum that you received, and in what sort of money?</p>
               <p>Hammock. Some of it was gold, but I cannot say how much it amounted to; he paid me for thirty-nine pounds.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do with it?</p>
               <p>Hammock. We did not share it till we went over the water.</p>
               <p>Q. What had you for your share?</p>
               <p>Hammock. I had 4 l or some such matter, for my share.</p>
               <p>Q. How many of you shared that?</p>
               <p>Hammock. There were but two of us that had that. We sold another parcel to the prisoner, and this money was for both parcels.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not you in the Poultry Compter?</p>
               <p>Hammock. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether there was not a person in the same compter for debt, named Ascue, at that time?</p>
               <p>Hammock. Yes, there was.</p>
               <p>Q. Had not you some conversation with him about this affair?</p>
               <p>Hammock. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you recollect whether or not you told him there was a necessity for you to transport this man at the bar, or you should be transported yourself?</p>
               <p>Hammock. I never said such words in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580222-16-person157">
                  Henry 
                  George 
               <interp inst="t17580222-16-person157" type="surname" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person157" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person157" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the Rose and Crown, at the corner of Love-Lane, drinking a pint of beer, where was 
               <persName id="t17580222-16-person158">
                  Tom 
                  Lambeth 
               <interp inst="t17580222-16-person158" type="surname" value="Lambeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person158" type="given" value="Tom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person158" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Maclockline drinking slip in the house, who asked me if I would drink with them. At first I refused. After that I did drink with them. L ambeth said he was just come up from Long Reach, and had got some shellack; that he had it of a mate of a ship, and wanted to dispose of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the prisoner there?</p>
               <p>George. Yes, he was there. Lambeth and Maclockline went at a distance (it is a long room) and talked together about it. I saw Hammock come in with a bag, which I took to be corn.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of the bag?</p>
               <p>George. I don't know.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Hammock and the prisoner go down into the cellar together ?</p>
               <p>George. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Coe light a candle?</p>
               <p>George. I am not sure of that.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any acquaintance with Coe?</p>
               <p>George. No; I only know him by his using that house?</p>
               <p>Q. Does he live there?</p>
               <p>George. No.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had Coe been in the room before Hammock came in?</p>
               <p>George. Coe was there when I went in.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Lambeth come in?</p>
               <p>George. No; he was there also when I went in.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the word shellack mention'd?</p>
               <p>George. I heard Lambeth mention it, who said he had it from on board an Indiaman, of the mate.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you, from what you heard him say, apprehend that he stole it?</p>
               <p>George. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any others hear that as well as you?</p>
               <p>George. There were many that I believe heard it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he speak it publickly, or only to Coe?</p>
               <p>George. He spoke it to the whole company, not to Coe in particular,</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear Coe say any thing to him about it?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175802220013"></xptr>George. Coe said he would give him 2 s. and 6 d. per pound for it, and then he should get but 2 d. per pound by it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this in the publick room?</p>
               <p>George. It was.</p>
               <p>Q. What did Hammock do with that bag which you supposed to have corn in?</p>
               <p>George. He laid it down on the ground in the tap room.</p>
               <p>Q. Privately, or in a publick manner?</p>
               <p>George. It was in the publick room.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did it lie there?</p>
               <p>George. I believe it lay there five minutes before it was taken away.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was it carried to?</p>
               <p>George. I don't know that.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Coe go out of the room?</p>
               <p>George. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any stilliards?</p>
               <p>George. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you saw either Hammock or Coe go down into the cellar?</p>
               <p>George. No; I did not see either of them go down.</p>
               <p>Q. Do mates of Indiamen bring adventures?</p>
               <p>George. They do often; I have bought things of them myself.</p>
               <p>Q. As this was brought into the publick room, as you mention, should you have been willing to have bought it?</p>
               <p>George. I should, if I could have got my thing by it.</p>
               <p>Council for prosecution. Whether you have not, since this prosecution has been depending, declared you saw Mr. Coe light a candle, and he and Hammock go down into the cellar ?</p>
               <p>George. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580222-16-person159">
                  Thomas 
                  Whiteman 
               <interp inst="t17580222-16-person159" type="surname" value="Whiteman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person159" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person159" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to the honourable East-India company.</p>

               <p>Q. In what capacity?</p>
               <p>Whiteman. I am an assistant elder, and have the care of the landing and shipping of goods at Botolph-Wharf. I was ordered to go with Mr. Bean in search of some shellack, which was said to be missing out of a lighter from the Eastcourt Indiaman. On Hammock's confessing this robbery, before Mr. alderman Kite, we went, and a constable with us, to the Rose and Crown, at the corner of Love-Lane, to search for it, where we open'd a place, on the left-hand side in the cellar, and found only three or four stilliard weights. This is all I know of the matter.</p>
               <p>Q. What price did shellack bear at that time?</p>
               <p>Whiteman. That is not in my province; I can't answer that question.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of weights were they?</p>
               <p>Whiteman. They were brass weights for stilliards.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580222-16-person160">
                  John 
                  Fidges 
               <interp inst="t17580222-16-person160" type="surname" value="Fidges"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person160" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person160" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a wax-chandler, and use a great deal of shellack.</p>
               <p>Q. What price did it bear in November, 1756?</p>
               <p>Fidges. Some, I believe, sold for thirty pounds per hundred.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the middling price?</p>
               <p>Fidges. There was some sold for twenty-three, twenty four, and twenty-five pounds a hundred. I bought a lot then for twenty-seven pounds, ten shillings, which is about four shillings a pound, and the finest sort is worth about four shillings and sixpence a pound. The last sale it sold from nineteen to twenty-three pounds a hundred.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you buy it before the duty is paid or after?</p>
               <p>Fidges. We buy it after the duty is paid.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the lowest price given for it in the year 1756?</p>
               <p>Fidges. Some might be sold for eighteen pounds; such as was very black.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you sell the best for per pound?</p>
               <p>Fidges. At five shillings per pound.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you buy by the great hundred?</p>
               <p>Fidges. Our hundred weight is one hundred and twelve pounds.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I had the stilliards in the open room, where I weigh'd it, and paid him for it on the table; but whether Hammock or 
               <persName id="t17580222-16-person161">
                  Thomas 
                  Lambeth 
               <interp inst="t17580222-16-person161" type="surname" value="Lambeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person161" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person161" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             took it up, I cannot be sure.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580222-16-person162">
                  Lydia 
                  Maryate 
               <interp inst="t17580222-16-person162" type="surname" value="Maryate"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person162" type="given" value="Lydia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person162" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Swallow's-Gardens, Goodman's-Fields. I was at the Rose and Crown when Mr. Coe was in company with Lambeth and Maclockline. I saw him and two men making a bargain about something, but I did not know what it was; one of the two said he could help him to some shellack. Mr. Coe asked him how he came by it. He said he had it of a mate of<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175802220014"></xptr> an Indiaman. Mr. Coe asked him what he would have per pound for it. Presently in came a young fellow with some stuff in a bag.</p>
               <p>Q. Should you know that young man was you to see him?</p>
               <p>L. Maryate. I believe I should.</p>
               <p>Q. Look about the court, and see if you can find him?</p>
               <p>L. Maryate. (She look'd about and pitch'd upon Hammock.) I believe this is he.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be there?</p>
               <p>L. Maryate. I work slop work for Mr. Bonus in Thomas Street, and was waiting there for work, as sometimes I do for an hour or two. This young man laid the bag down by the side of the table. Mr. Coe took some of it out, and look'd at it, and said half a crown a pound was the worth of it, and he would not give more. They concluded upon it for that price. Then they both of them went out, and brought in some more in a handkerchief and in their pockets.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see it weigh'd?</p>
               <p>L. Maryate. I did. It was all weigh'd in that room, on the dark side of it, not that side the windows are on, with stilliards.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they go down into the cellar?</p>
               <p>L. Maryate. They did not to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were the stilliards taken from?</p>
               <p>L. Maryate. I can't say that.</p>
               <p>Q. Were any other people in the room besides those you have mentioned?</p>
               <p>L. Maryate. There were several other people. there.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it weigh'd publickly?</p>
               <p>L. Maryate. It was quite publick, every body might see it.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was you at that alehouse?</p>
               <p>L. Maryate. I was there three or four hours. I am obliged to wait sometimes, as I work for the navy.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you there before Mr. Coe came in?</p>
               <p>L. Maryate. No, he was there when I went in.</p>
               <p>Q. When did the two men you mention come in?</p>
               <p>L. Maryate. They came in after I was there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know them before ?</p>
               <p>L. Maryate. No, they were intire strangers to me.</p>
               <p>Q. When did Mr. Coe go away?</p>
               <p>L. Maryate. He staid there all the time I was there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he not go out of the house during the time you was there?</p>
               <p>L. Maryate. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what the shellack weigh'd?</p>
               <p>L. Maryate. I did not see what it weigh'd.</p>
               <p>John Ascue. I saw this witness Hammock in the Poultry Compter, being an unfortunate debtor there at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live now?</p>
               <p>Ascue. I now keep the Swan alehouse at Battersea. I remember I had some conversation with him about his giving evidence against the prisoner at the bar, and upon my seeing his commitment I said to him; this is a very bad affair, which will be of a bad consequence.</p>
               <p>Q. What was he committed for?</p>
               <p>Ascue. He was committed for feloniously stealing of shellack. He said what can I do, I will sooner by half transport all the world than I will transport myself. I said in what manner did you offer it to sale, he said he had it of a mate of a ship, whose private adventure it was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you he told Mr. Coe that he had it of the mate of a ship?</p>
               <p>Ascue. He said he did tell him that, and more than that he offered to lay several sums of money that he would transport Mr. Coe, and get himself off.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580222-16-person163">
                  Thomas 
                  Booth 
               <interp inst="t17580222-16-person163" type="surname" value="Booth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person163" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person163" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about six years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Booth. It was always very good, I never heard any thing ill of him before this affair.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does he live?</p>
               <p>Booth. He lives by the Maypole in East Smithfield and keeps a publick house, the Ship and Star.</p>
               <p>Richard Cowley. I have known him about nine years; he has as good a character as any one in the neighbourhood. I am sure he is an honest man, if he wanted an hundred pounds I would lend it him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580222-16-person164">
                  William 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17580222-16-person164" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person164" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person164" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him eight years; his general character is that of an honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580222-16-person165">
                  William 
                  Bedford 
               <interp inst="t17580222-16-person165" type="surname" value="Bedford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person165" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person165" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was one of his bail, and live in Bishopsgate-street; I am a chemist and druggist. I have known the prisoner eleven or twelve years.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the price of ordinary shellack in the year 1756?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175802220015"></xptr>Bedford. There is a great variation in the goodness of that commodity; as to what it was worth then, I can't really say now.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner's general character?</p>
               <p>Bedford. That of a good honest man.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was he out upon bail?</p>
               <p>Bedford. Sixteen or seventeen months.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any counter-security?</p>
               <p>Bedford. No, I had not.</p>
               <p>Edward M'Farling. I live in East Smithfield, and have known the prisoner ten or eleven years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>M'Farling. It is that of a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580222-16-person166">
                  William 
                  Connup 
               <interp inst="t17580222-16-person166" type="surname" value="Connup"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person166" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person166" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was one of his bail in the sum of an hundred pounds. I have known him fourteen or fifteen years; he is a very honest man. He has work'd for me in cutting tobacco, and he has bought tobacco of me, and paid me very honestly.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580222-16-person167">
                  William 
                  Betsworth 
               <interp inst="t17580222-16-person167" type="surname" value="Betsworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person167" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person167" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about fourteen or fifteen years; he has work'd for me about seven years. He always behaved honestly, and work'd early and late. I look upon him to be a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580222-16-person168">
                  John 
                  Whitlock 
               <interp inst="t17580222-16-person168" type="surname" value="Whitlock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person168" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person168" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him four or five years; he has a very good character, that of an honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580222-16-person169">
                  William 
                  Prophet 
               <interp inst="t17580222-16-person169" type="surname" value="Prophet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person169" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person169" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him upwards of nine years; he is a very honest man as far as ever I knew. I believe in my heart he is a very fair dealing man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580222-16-person170">
                  Henry 
                  Endrsby 
               <interp inst="t17580222-16-person170" type="surname" value="Endrsby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person170" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person170" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him eight or nine years; I live just by him. I believe him to be a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580222-16-person171">
                  Joseph 
                  Wills 
               <interp inst="t17580222-16-person171" type="surname" value="Wills"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person171" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person171" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about ten years; he is a very honest man.</p>
               <p>Q. to Hammock. You hear what Ascue has sworn, what say you to it?</p>
               <p>Hammock. Upon my oath I never had that conversation with him as he has mentioned.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever talk about this affair with him?</p>
               <p>Hammock. No, I never did at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever tell him you had the shellack of the mate of an Indiaman?</p>
               <p>Hammock. No, I did not; for I took it out of the chest myself.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever offer to lay any money about transporting the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Hammock. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. to Ascue. Recollect yourself, and tell the truth.</p>
               <p>Ascue. What I have sworn is truth. There is a gentleman here that heard him say some of the words I mention'd.</p>
               <p>Court. What is his name?</p>
               <p>Ascue. I don't know; I saw him when he was giving evidence, and knew him again.</p>
               <p>Court. Then go and lay your hand on him. (He goes down, and laid his hand on Connup.) This is the man.</p>
               <p>Q. to Connup. Do you recollect, this conversation?</p>
               <p>Connup. I never saw this evidence before I saw him here in my life; he must be mistaken.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear Hammock speak as that witness has said?</p>
               <p>Connup. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Ascue. It was at the Old-Bailey coffee-house door, the first day that I was subpoena'd.</p>
               <p>Connup. I don't remember any thing of it.</p>
               <p>Council for prosecution. We have one 
               <persName id="t17580222-16-person172">
                  Abraham 
                  Jacobs 
               <interp inst="t17580222-16-person172" type="surname" value="Jacobs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person172" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-person172" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             bound over in a recognizance of one hundred pounds, and he is got out of the way; I desire he may be called upon his recognizance. (He is called, but did not appear.)</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17580222-16-verdict84" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580222-16-verdict84" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>[Abraham Jacobs's recognizance ordered to be estreated.]</p>
            </div1>
