<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17520914-40">
               <interp inst="t17520914-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520914-40" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520914-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520914"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520914-40" type="date" value="17520914"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520914-40-off198-c269" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-40-defend345 t17520914-40-off198 t17520914-40-verdict206"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520914-40-off202-c270" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-40-defend346 t17520914-40-off202 t17520914-40-verdict207"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520914-40-off202-c271" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-40-defend348 t17520914-40-off202 t17520914-40-verdict208"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520914-40-off202-c272" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-40-defend350 t17520914-40-off202 t17520914-40-verdict208"></join>
         
               <p>446, 447, 448, 449. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17520914-40-defend345" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Edwards 
                  <interp inst="t17520914-40-defend345" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-defend345" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-defend345" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17520914-40-deflabel195" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-40-defend345 t17520914-40-deflabel195"></join>, 
               <persName id="t17520914-40-defend346" type="defendantName">
                  Benjamin 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17520914-40-defend346" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-defend346" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-defend346" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , 
               
                  <persName id="t17520914-40-defend348" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Edwards 
                  <interp inst="t17520914-40-defend348" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-defend348" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-defend348" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17520914-40-deflabel196" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-40-defend348 t17520914-40-deflabel196"></join>, and 
               
                  <persName id="t17520914-40-defend350" type="defendantName">
                     Millicent 
                     Edwards 
                  <interp inst="t17520914-40-defend350" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-defend350" type="given" value="Millicent"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-defend350" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17520914-40-deflabel197" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-40-defend350 t17520914-40-deflabel197"></join>, were indicted, the first for <rs id="t17520914-40-off198" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-off198" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-off198" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one silver saucepan, val. 3 l. one gold chain for a watch, val. 3 l. four linen sheets, six linen napkins, val. 3 s. the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17520914-40-victim352" type="victimName">
                           Elizabeth 
                           Griffis 
                        <interp inst="t17520914-40-victim352" type="surname" value="Griffis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520914-40-victim352" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520914-40-victim352" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17520914-40-viclabel199" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-40-victim352 t17520914-40-viclabel199"></join>, one silver watch with a tortoise shell case, val. 50 s. one silver milkpail, val. 20 s. one silver egg, val. 10 s. two dimitty petticoats, val. 4 s. one silver snuff box, val. 10 s. a tweezer case, the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17520914-40-victim354" type="victimName">
                           Diana 
                           Barker 
                        <interp inst="t17520914-40-victim354" type="surname" value="Barker"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520914-40-victim354" type="given" value="Diana"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520914-40-victim354" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17520914-40-viclabel200" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-40-victim354 t17520914-40-viclabel200"></join>, in the dwelling house of the said 
                     <persName id="t17520914-40-person355">
                        Elizabeth 
                        Griffis 
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person355" type="surname" value="Griffis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520914-40-person355" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520914-40-person355" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17520914-40-cd201" type="crimeDate">July 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-40-off198 t17520914-40-cd201"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-40-off202 t17520914-40-cd201"></join>. The other three for <rs id="t17520914-40-off202" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-off202" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-off202" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving part of the said goods, knowing them to have been stolen
            </rs>, <rs id="t17520914-40-cd203" type="crimeDate">July 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-40-off198 t17520914-40-cd203"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-40-off202 t17520914-40-cd203"></join>.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175209140018"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17520914-40-person356">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Griffis 
               <interp inst="t17520914-40-person356" type="surname" value="Griffis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person356" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person356" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17520914-40-person357">
                  Ann 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17520914-40-person357" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person357" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person357" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was a <rs id="t17520914-40-deflabel204" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-40-defend345 t17520914-40-deflabel204"></join> with me almost two years, as a <rs id="t17520914-40-deflabel205" type="occupation">nurse and chamber maid</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-40-defend345 t17520914-40-deflabel205"></join>. My plate was ordered to be got together to be cleaned on the middle of July. I missed a silver saucepan, which had not been used during the time she had been in my service; it was not under lock and key, the key was lost. I inquired of her, after I had looked about, where it was, she said, I'll go and look for it; she went to the place where it should have been, and returned again and said it was not there. What, said I, have you moved it, and where? She said indeed, madam, I have took it to keep Benjamin out of prison, and if I would let her go out, she would go and find it. She returned and said it should be got some time the next day. I missed a silver watch and a gold chain fixed to it, which had been a constant plaything for the little girl; I asked what was become of them, she said she had taken and given them to Milley. We missed other things by looking about, a silver milk pail for a tea table, a silver egg, a play-thing of the child. She pretended she knew nothing of them. Then she went and fetched Millicent. After that we missed 4 sheets, and 6 napkins.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520914-40-person358">
                  William 
                  Child 
               <interp inst="t17520914-40-person358" type="surname" value="Child"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person358" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person358" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             produces the goods mentioned. She deposes they are her property, except the watch, the egg and the milk pail. They never were out of my house to my knowledge till she took them away. I knew the sheets were in a store chest about two months ago. I have seen the silver saucepan in the house since she lived with me. I kept her in the house endeavouring to find out the things. I got a constable and took her before the justice ; there she owned all, that she had taken the things she was charged with. Her sister Millicent was taken before the justice at the same time, and was charged with having received them from her sister, and pawning them. She cried and told us the linen was at Mr. Figg's, the saucepan at one Mrs. Hunt's in Orchard street ; I can't say she said she received them, but she did not deny it. The mother came to my house the morning after the discovery, and said she was sorry, and asked ten thousand pardons. She denied seeing any thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520914-40-person359">
                  Diana 
                  Barker 
               <interp inst="t17520914-40-person359" type="surname" value="Barker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person359" type="given" value="Diana"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person359" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am daughter to Mrs. Griffis, I live with her. I lost a silver watch with a tortoiseshell case, a silver milk pail, two dimitty petticoats, one tweezer case, and one silver snuff-box. I did not miss these things till the beginning of July. I asked 
               <persName id="t17520914-40-person360">
                  Ann 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17520914-40-person360" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person360" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person360" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             what was become of them; she owned she had taken them, and lent them to her sister Millicent to pawn, that Millicent came to her in her brother's name. She was sent for the next morning, I charged her with receiving them of her sister and pawning them; she acknowledged the charge, and promised to bring them again. She said some was at Mrs. Hunt's in Orchard street; at that time we could get no more out of her. I was with her before Justice Lediard, Ann confessed there she was guilty of taking the things mentioned in the search warrant which was read to her. She said she had delivered them to Millicent. Millicent owned she had received those things from her sister. The brother and mother were then taken up; she confessed where the plate and chain were; that she had told their distresses to her sister, who had lent her the things and she had pawned them. She likewise confessed that the watch and chain were at Mrs. Sugg's in the Bowling Alley. I think the two dimitty petticoats and silver pail were in Pye street. The mother denied she knew any thing of the matter; then the son denied it, but he afterwards said he knew of it, and that when he was ill, Ann cried to him to have the things taken out, upon which he raised some money and got them out. She looks at the silver watch, this I saw in March last. The silver milk pail, silver snuff-box, and tweezer I saw in Jan or Feb. They are my property.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520914-40-person361">
                  William 
                  Chip 
               <interp inst="t17520914-40-person361" type="surname" value="Chip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person361" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person361" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable. On the 25th of July I was applied to, to take up 
               <persName id="t17520914-40-person362">
                  Ann 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17520914-40-person362" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person362" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person362" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I apprehended her. When I brought her to justice Lediard, she owned the charge laid against her, and cried, and said, had it not been for her sister's persuasion she should not have done it; and said, she feared it would come to this at last, that she never should get the things again.</p>
               <p>Q. Done what?</p>
               <p>Chip. Taken the things and delivered them to her sister Milley. Then I took the other three. Millicent said before the justice that her sister Ann delivered them to her, and she had pawned them. She went with me to Orchard-street to Mrs. Hunt's, there I found a silver saucepan, a tweezer, and two white petticoats. At Mr. Pearson's in Long Ditch I found the silver milk pail, and at Mr. Sugg's a Cornchandler, in Bowling alley, I found a tortoise-shell watch, and a gold chain. In Pye street, one petticoat and four aprons; at Mr. Figg's in Peter-street two pair of sheets, six napkins, four pillowbears, a silver snuff-box, and a silver egg. These goods produced are the same I found.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520914-40-person363">
                  John 
                  Sugg 
               <interp inst="t17520914-40-person363" type="surname" value="Sugg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person363" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person363" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a cornchandler, I know all the prisoners. 
               <persName id="t17520914-40-person364">
                  Mary 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17520914-40-person364" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person364" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person364" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the mother, brought the watch in a tortoise-shell case, and a gold chain to pawn, about ten or twelve days before they<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175209140019"></xptr> were taken up, and said she was in great distress, desiring me to lend her a guinea; I did it out of charity; she told me it was one of her daughter's. They always lived in good credit; I had no mistrust it was stolen.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Hunt. I only know Millicent. I keep a pawnbroker's shop; she brought the silver saucepan three several times within the compass of two years; the last time was the 28th of February. She laid it in the name of 
               <persName id="t17520914-40-person365">
                  Mary 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17520914-40-person365" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person365" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person365" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and said it was her mother's. I lent her two guineas always on it. She brought the tweezer case; that had been pawned a year last August; and two dimitty under petticoats.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Figg. I keep a pawnbroker's shop, and know the three women. Millicent chiefly brought things to me; a silver snuff-box, a silver egg, two pair of sheets, and six napkins; Mary, the mother, brought one of the napkins. They always pawned them as hers and her mother's; Mary only desired so much money. Some was brought September was twelvemonth, some in February, some in May, and some in June. They did bear a good character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520914-40-person366">
                  Anne 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17520914-40-person366" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person366" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person366" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said nothing in her defence.</p>
               <p>Mary's defence.</p>
               <p>I never saw any thing but the watch.</p>
               <p>Millicent's defence.</p>
               <p>I never did any thing with a design to wrong them, but with an intent to bring them again; it was necessity; being out of place, that obliged me to do it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520914-40-person367">
                  Jacob 
                  Hood 
               <interp inst="t17520914-40-person367" type="surname" value="Hood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person367" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person367" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the whole family about 12 years; very honest industrious people as any in the parish. The old woman kept a school.</p>
               <p>Mr. Wright. I have known them twelve or fourteen years, but never heard any thing amiss of them before this unhappy affair.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Fleetwood. I have known them six or seven years, they have a general good character.</p>
               <p>Mr. Maudlin. I have known them about twelve years, but never knew any ill of them before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520914-40-person368">
                  Mary 
                  Schooley 
               <interp inst="t17520914-40-person368" type="surname" value="Schooley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person368" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person368" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known them this dozen years; they have a very honest just character. I never heard to the contrary till this affair.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520914-40-person369">
                  Sarah 
                  Whitehead 
               <interp inst="t17520914-40-person369" type="surname" value="Whitehead"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person369" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person369" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known them about ten years. I never knew any ill of them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520914-40-person370">
                  Hannah 
                  Jefferys 
               <interp inst="t17520914-40-person370" type="surname" value="Jefferys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person370" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-person370" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Ann and Millicent six years; it has been in their power to have wronged me of fifty or sixty pounds; they never wronged me of any thing.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Symons. I have known them about twelve or fourteen years. They are very honest, but very poor.</p>
               <p>Ann <rs id="t17520914-40-verdict206" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-verdict206" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-verdict206" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               guilty of stealing, but not in the dwelling house
            </rs>, Benjamin <rs id="t17520914-40-verdict207" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-verdict207" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>, Mary <rs id="t17520914-40-verdict208" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-verdict208" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs>, Millicent guilty.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520914-40-punish209" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520914-40-punish209" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-40-defend345 t17520914-40-punish209"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-40-defend348 t17520914-40-punish209"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-40-defend350 t17520914-40-punish209"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
