<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17501017-41">
               <interp inst="t17501017-41" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501017-41" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501017-41" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17501017"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501017-41" type="date" value="17501017"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17501017-41-off200-c278" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-41-defend356 t17501017-41-off200 t17501017-41-verdict201"></join>
         
               <p>663. 
               
                  <persName id="t17501017-41-defend356" type="defendantName">
                     Francis 
                     Godd 
                  <interp inst="t17501017-41-defend356" type="surname" value="Godd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-41-defend356" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-41-defend356" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17501017-41-off200" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501017-41-off200" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-41-off200" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one hempen bag, value 12 d. 36 pounds weight of cocoa, value 48 s.
            </rs> the goods of persons unknown.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501017-41-person357">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17501017-41-person357" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-41-person357" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-41-person357" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On last Saturday morning, coming along Radcliff Highway, I saw the prisoner and another person walking together; the other person had a bag on his shoulder; by the appearance of them I imagined the goods were stolen, and so followed them.</p>
               <p>Q. What time in the morning was this?</p>
               <p>Harris. It was betwixt eight and nine o'clock; I observed them to carry this bag into the house of one Macdaniel, a chandler's shop in Rag-fair; they came out again together in about two minutes time; I passed by the door about ten yards to see the event, and there made a stand; I saw them both go into a publick house over the way; I went up to Mr. Macdaniel and said, I hope you are not concerned in the merchant's goods, pray who are the two persons which brought these goods into your house? said he, I know one of them very well; then he called out Dodd, (the prisoner at the bar) who came out; Mr. Macdaniel crossed the way to him and said, pray what goods have you brought into my house, you are the person that brought them in, for I know nothing of the other man; then I took hold on the prisoner and said, I have watched you some time giving him a detail of the matter; said he, I know nothing of this thing; then he wanted me to go to another publick house.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175010170029"></xptr>Q. What house did he come out of?</p>
               <p>Harris. He came out of the Gun and Hollybush, and wanted to go into the Coach and Horses in the Tower liberty; said I, I insist upon keeping you here till I can send for a proper officer; but before one came, there came a neighbour, and he and Macdaniel did engage to keep him whilst I looked for the goods; I went, and in the back part of the house I found these goods. (They were produced in court according to the indictment.) It is the same bag they were carried in, that I am certain of. After the prisoner was taken in charge I had him before alderman Bethel, there he acknowledged he was the person that was intrusted to sell the goods, and that he had them that morning at a publick house at Rotherhith, I think the sign of the George.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you heard since whose goods they are?</p>
               <p>Harris. No, I have not; I advertised them, but have not had any intelligence of an owner?</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>When he took me he asked me what business I had with them goods; I said they were honestly come by; said he, I'll know that; he brought me and left me in the Compter, and went to alderman Bethel, and had a commitment made ready to send me to goal immediately; said I to alderman Bethel, these goods were sold to me, I agreed with Mr. Jenkins and Mr. Wright, I am to give them so much for them; I asked them if they were honestly come by; they said they were, and that no hurt should come to me; they have attended every day this week, and are now hard by; they told me if I would send any body for them when there was occasion, they would come and give their evidence here in court.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501017-41-person358">
                  William 
                  Jenkins 
               <interp inst="t17501017-41-person358" type="surname" value="Jenkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-41-person358" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-41-person358" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live near Rotherhith Church, close by the Stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Jenkins. I do very well, sir, this bag of cocoa Mr. Slocomb, who is steward to the ship Chester, gave us to dispose of for him.</p>
               <p>Q. Who do you mean by us?</p>
               <p>Jenkins. 
               <persName id="t17501017-41-person359">
                  John 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17501017-41-person359" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-41-person359" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-41-person359" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and I.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the captain's name?</p>
               <p>Jenkins. His name is 
               <persName id="t17501017-41-person360">
                  Arthur 
                  Pain 
               <interp inst="t17501017-41-person360" type="surname" value="Pain"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-41-person360" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-41-person360" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you dispose of them?</p>
               <p>Jenkins. Yes, sir, we did to 
               <persName id="t17501017-41-person361">
                  Francis 
                  Dodd 
               <interp inst="t17501017-41-person361" type="surname" value="Dodd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-41-person361" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-41-person361" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , prisoner at the bar, on Saturday morning last.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he pay for them?</p>
               <p>Jenkins. No, he did not; he paid 6 s. in part of payment for them; he was to give 11 d. halfpenny per pound; the remainder came to 24 s. 8 d. it all weighed 34 lb. with the bag, for which we allowed 2 lb.</p>
               <p>[
               <persName id="t17501017-41-person362">
                  John 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17501017-41-person362" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-41-person362" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-41-person362" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed to the same effect with this addition, the ship Chester came from Antigua; we knew the prisoner a great while before the man at the George told us be would buy them.]</p>
               <p>Q. What is the landlord's name?</p>
               <p>Wright. His name is Barker.</p>
               <p>Q. Should not the prisoner have had a permit?</p>
               <p>Wright. I don't know, my lord.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501017-41-person363">
                  William 
                  Slocomb 
               <interp inst="t17501017-41-person363" type="surname" value="Slocomb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-41-person363" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-41-person363" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am steward on board the ship Chester, the came into the river on the 30th of August from Antigua; one John Key and I bought half a hundred weight of cocoa between us in that country, some we made use of in our passage home, and the rest I gave Jenkins and Wright to dispose of for me.</p>
               <p>Q. Are these some of them?</p>
               <p>Slocomb. I can swear to the bag, it was a bread bag with No. 2. upon it. He looked upon it, and said be could swear it was the same be delivered.</p>
               <p>Q. to Harris. What are you?</p>
               <p>Harris. I am an officer in Whitechapel-Court. <rs id="t17501017-41-verdict201" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501017-41-verdict201" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>, and the goods delivered to Harris for him to carry to his Majesty's Custom-house.</p>
            </div1>
