<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17580913-9">
               <interp inst="t17580913-9" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-9" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-9" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580913"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-9" type="date" value="17580913"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580913-9-off33-c54" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-9-defend68 t17580913-9-off33 t17580913-9-verdict37"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580913-9-off39-c58" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-9-defend74 t17580913-9-off39 t17580913-9-verdict41"></join>
         
               <p>265. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17580913-9-defend68" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Wyman 
                  <interp inst="t17580913-9-defend68" type="surname" value="Wyman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-9-defend68" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-9-defend68" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             was indicted for <rs id="t17580913-9-off33" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580913-9-off33" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-9-off33" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing nine china coffee-cups, value 9 d. seventy-two china tea-cups, and seventy-two china saucers, value 4 s.
            </rs> the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17580913-9-victim70" type="victimName">
                     Charles 
                     Vere 
                  <interp inst="t17580913-9-victim70" type="surname" value="Vere"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-9-victim70" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-9-victim70" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17580913-9-cd34" type="crimeDate">July 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-9-off33 t17580913-9-cd34"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-9-off39 t17580913-9-cd34"></join>. ++.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-9-person71">
                  Charles 
                  Vere 
               <interp inst="t17580913-9-person71" type="surname" value="Vere"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-9-person71" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-9-person71" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17580913-9-crimeloc35">Fleet-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17580913-9-crimeloc35" type="placeName" value="Fleet-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17580913-9-crimeloc35" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-9-off33 t17580913-9-crimeloc35"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-9-off39 t17580913-9-crimeloc35"></join>, and <rs id="t17580913-9-viclabel36" type="occupation">keep a china-shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-9-victim70 t17580913-9-viclabel36"></join>; on the 12th of July I lost the China mentioned in the indictment, out of my shop; the prisoner was my servant between two and three months; he was detected by one of my servants. I took him before justice Fielding, and the goods were produced there; he was charged with taking them, and he confessed to the taking them before me and divers others. He made a declaration who was the receiver of these goods in Clare-market; the court of Conservancy was sitting, so that I could not take him before a city magistrate, so was obliged to go before justice Fielding.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-9-person72">
                  James 
                  Anson 
               <interp inst="t17580913-9-person72" type="surname" value="Anson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-9-person72" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-9-person72" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Vere, there had been a china dish missing, my master examined us about it, it could not be found. I mistrusted the prisoner. My master sent us down after this into the warehouse; he went farther in it then I did, and staid some time there; as he came up, I set my foot on his basket, and felt china in it. I put my hand in, and took out a coffee-cup; then I let him take the rest out, there were nine of them; we came home, I told my master of it; he owned he had taken them, and also that he had taken before seventy two cups, and seventy two saucers, my master's property.</p>
               <p>The prisoner had nothing to say in his defence, <rs id="t17580913-9-verdict37" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580913-9-verdict37" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>; <rs id="t17580913-9-punish38" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580913-9-punish38" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-9-punish38" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-9-defend68 t17580913-9-punish38"></join>
               he received sentence to be branded, and was branded accordingly
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>266. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17580913-9-defend74" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Briner 
                  <interp inst="t17580913-9-defend74" type="surname" value="Briner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-9-defend74" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-9-defend74" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17580913-9-off39" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580913-9-off39" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-9-off39" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving seventy two cups, and seventy two saucers, part of the said goods, well knowing them to have been stolen, by the said 
                     <persName id="t17580913-9-person75">
                        Richard 
                        Wyman 
                     <interp inst="t17580913-9-person75" type="surname" value="Wyman"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580913-9-person75" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580913-9-person75" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, July 13. +</p>
               <p>[The record of the trial and conviction of Wyman<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175809130004"></xptr> read in court, wherein it specifies he pleaded not guilty, put himself upon his country, the jurors say Guilty; judgment to be branded in the hand, and he was branded accordingly.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-9-person76">
                  Richard 
                  Wyman 
               <interp inst="t17580913-9-person76" type="surname" value="Wyman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-9-person76" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-9-person76" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was a <rs id="t17580913-9-deflabel40" type="occupation">servant to Mr. Vere</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-9-defend68 t17580913-9-deflabel40"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you convicted for stealing the seventy two cups and seventy two saucers, laid in this indictment.</p>
               <p>Wyman. I was, and some coffee-cups, the coffee-cups were in the basket unknown to me; I had no intention of stealing them; this was on the 13th of July.</p>

               <p>Q. What happened after this?</p>
               <p>Wyman. My master missed a blue china dish out of the house.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of seventy two china cups, and seventy two saucers?</p>

               <p>Wyman. Yes, them I bought of a sailor's wife, I think she was.</p>
               <p>Q. When?</p>
               <p>Wyman. About the 9th or 10th of July.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you buy them?</p>
               <p>Wyman. I met her in the street in Cheapside.</p>
               <p>Q. What did they cost you?</p>
               <p>Wyman. Some cost me 3 s. 6 d. and some 4 s. a half dozen.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you buy them all at one time?</p>
               <p>Wyman. No, I bought them at two different times.</p>
               <p>Q. How many did you buy the first time?</p>
               <p>Wyman. I bought seven half dozens at one time, and five at the other.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you buy the first parcel?</p>
               <p>Wyman. On the 9th of July.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you buy the other?</p>
               <p>Wyman. The next day but one after.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you give for the first parcel?</p>
               <p>Wyman. I gave 3 s. 6 d. per half dozen for part of each parcel. They on the 9th of July cost me 25 s. the other cost me 16 s.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you buy both parcels of one woman?</p>
               <p>Wyman. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day did you buy the first parcel?</p>
               <p>Wyman. I bought them in the afternoon about four o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you buy the second parcel?</p>
               <p>Wyman. In the forenoon.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you going at the time you met this woman?</p>
               <p>Wyman. I was going on some business for my master into the town.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell which way you was going?</p>
               <p>Wyman. I was going down Cheapside when I met her the first time.</p>
               <p>Q. Which way was you going the second time?</p>
               <p>Wyman. I was going along Fleet-street, and met her without Temple-bar in the Strand.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you appoint her to meet you?</p>
               <p>Wyman. No, I did not, I met her both times by accident.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever buy any thing of her before?</p>
               <p>Wyman. No, I never did?</p>
               <p>Q. Did she offer these cups and saucers to you, or did you ask her?</p>
               <p>Wyman. She offered them to me; she saw I had a china-basket on my arm.</p>
               <p>Q. How did she carry her china?</p>
               <p>Wyman. She had it in her apron.</p>
               <p>Q. Were these the very same cups and saucers that you was indicted for this sessions?</p>
               <p>Wyman. They were the very same.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do with them after you bought them?</p>
               <p>Wyman. I went and sold them to the prisoner, 
               <persName id="t17580913-9-person77">
                  John 
                  Briner 
               <interp inst="t17580913-9-person77" type="surname" value="Briner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-9-person77" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-9-person77" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he live?</p>
               <p>Wyman. He lived in Clare-market.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his business ?</p>
               <p>Wyman. He keeps an earthen-ware shop.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you sell them to him?</p>
               <p>Wyman. I sold one parcel the 12th day, and told him I would get him some more.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you sell the first parcel for?</p>
               <p>Wyman. I sold the first seven sets, but we had not agreed, some he was to give 3 s. 6 d. and some 3 s. 9 d. per set. I received a guinea of him in part, we were to agree on that the next time we met. I was in a hurry, and could not stay.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever deal with him before?</p>
               <p>Wyman. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to deliver them without making an absolute bargain ?</p>
               <p>Wyman. I took them with me, it being in my way, and I could not stay, so he gave me a guinea then in part.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this the same day that you bought them?</p>
               <p>Wyman. No, it was the day after but one; I bought them the 9th, and sold them the 12th.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do with them between the 9th and the 12th.</p>
               <p>Wyman. I locked them up in my box, in the room where I lay.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175809130005"></xptr>Q. Did you shew them to any body?</p>
               <p>Wyman. No, I did not, but carried them directly to my box.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you sell the rest?</p>
               <p>Wyman. I sold them a day or two afterwards; I cannot truly say which day that was he bought the five sets.</p>
               <p>Q. For how much did you sell them?</p>
               <p>Wyman. Mr. Briner was not within when I carried them, and I left them with his wife.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you leave any word with her when you left them?</p>
               <p>Wyman. No, I did not, but told her I would call again when he was at home.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever call?</p>
               <p>Wyman. No, I did not, so I never had any thing for them.</p>
               <p>Counsel for prisoner. Did Mr. Briner ever receive of you any cups or saucers, knowing them to have been stolen?</p>
               <p>Wyman. No, never, he had no reason to suspect I stole any.</p>
               <p>C. for prisoner. Did you steal any of them?</p>
               <p>Wyman. No, I did not, I never wronged my master of any thing.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you known him?</p>
               <p>Wyman. I have known him this two years or better.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you live before you lived with Mr. Vere?</p>
               <p>Wyman. I lived with a silversmith before near Temple-bar.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner know that you lived with Mr. Vere at the time he bought these things of you?</p>
               <p>Wyman. He did know that.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he ask you any questions when he bought the first parcel of you?</p>
               <p>Wyman. No, he only asked me who I bought them of; and I said of a sailor's wife.</p>
               <p>Mr. Vere. This evidence confess'd the taking these cups and saucers, and owned they were my property, after he was detected, before abundance of witnesses, that I could produce.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of your own knowledge about it, besides his confession of the prisoner's receiving the goods, knowing them to have been stolen?</p>
               <p>Vere. The cups and saucers were found in the prisoner's house. We had a constable and a search warrant to search his house, from justice Fielding. The evidence, Wyman, went along with us, and took down the china from the different shelves in th e shop, and said it was my property.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the constable's name?</p>
               <p>Vere. His name is 
               <persName id="t17580913-9-person78">
                  Arthur 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17580913-9-person78" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-9-person78" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-9-person78" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-9-person79">
                  Arthur 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17580913-9-person79" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-9-person79" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-9-person79" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had a warrant to search the house of the prisoner, in Clare-market; he was not at home, we found those cups and saucers on different shelves in the shop; (producing the China mentioned in the indictment.)</p>
               <p>Q. Who found them ?</p>
               <p>Smith. The evidence Wyman went to the shelves and took them down, and said they were Mr. Vere's property.</p>
               <p>Vere. These are of the same patterns and kinds that I have a great number of; I cannot swear to the identity of them, for any other of the trade may have of the same patterns; I have nothing to go by, but the confession of Wyman.</p>
               <p>Court. A confession out of court will not go beyond what he swears in court.</p>
               <p>Vere. The prisoner own'd he had bought several sets of china of my servant, and that those he bought of him, and he gave him a guinea for the first seven sets; that the five sets were brought afterwards, which he had not paid him for. Before justice Sydenham he said he did not know that Wyman was my servant, but that he knew he lived with a china-man, but did not know with whom; he afterwards said otherwise, he said he thought by the price that they could not be honestly come by, and he had an intention of coming to me, to acquaint me with it. The second time of examination he said he did not know how he came by the five sets, that he found them in his shop. I asked him what day, he said he believed the Friday or Saturday; this was over night, when examined the next morning, he said he found them on the Friday morning on a bulk.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the value of those seven sets of cups and saucers?</p>
               <p>Vear. They cost me on an average about 4 s. 6 d. a set.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I am innocent of the affair; I bought them, but I did not know them to be stolen; I gave him a guinea in part for the first parcel; I was not at home when he brought the others.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17580913-9-verdict41" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580913-9-verdict41" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The goods were delivered to the prosecutor in court.</p>
            </div1>
