<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17550226-29">
               <interp inst="t17550226-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550226-29" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550226-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550226"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550226-29" type="date" value="17550226"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550226-29-off151-c193" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550226-29-defend242 t17550226-29-off151 t17550226-29-verdict154"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550226-29-off151-c194" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550226-29-defend244 t17550226-29-off151 t17550226-29-verdict159"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550226-29-off155-c194" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550226-29-defend244 t17550226-29-off155 t17550226-29-verdict159"></join>
         
               <p>123, 124. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17550226-29-defend242" type="defendantName">
                     Henry 
                     Marchant 
                  <interp inst="t17550226-29-defend242" type="surname" value="Marchant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-defend242" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-defend242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17550226-29-defend244" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Myers 
                  <interp inst="t17550226-29-defend244" type="surname" value="Myers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-defend244" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-defend244" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted, <rs id="t17550226-29-off151" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-off151" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-off151" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               for that they on the <rs id="t17550226-29-cd152" type="crimeDate">25th of January</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550226-29-off151 t17550226-29-cd152"></join>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550226-29-off155 t17550226-29-cd152"></join>, about the hour of twelve in the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175502260016"></xptr> night of the same day, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17550226-29-victim246" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Price 
                        <interp inst="t17550226-29-victim246" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550226-29-victim246" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550226-29-victim246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did break and enter, and stealing out thence three linen sheets, value 4 s. one fustian frock, value 3 s. the goods of the said John, and one pair of leather breeches, one fustian frock, one linen shirt, and one pair of thread stockings
            </rs>, the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17550226-29-victim248" type="victimName">
                     Robert 
                     Evans 
                  <interp inst="t17550226-29-victim248" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-victim248" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-victim248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550226-29-person249">
                  John 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17550226-29-person249" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-person249" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-person249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have a shop in Clare-market, but I live in <placeName id="t17550226-29-crimeloc153">St. Giles's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17550226-29-crimeloc153" type="placeName" value="St. Giles's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550226-29-crimeloc153" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550226-29-off151 t17550226-29-crimeloc153"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550226-29-off155 t17550226-29-crimeloc153"></join>; on the 25th day of January my maid going to put the child to bed, betwixt eleven and twelve o'clock at night, came down stairs and told me she heard a rumbling; she went up a little higher and saw somebody under a bed in the garret where my men laid; I went up stairs as fast as I could, and my man with me, I saw nobody under the bed, but looking up at the trap-door that goes up to the top of the house, it was open, and I found a bundle of cloaths upon the mens bed; I got out on the top of the houses thro' the trap-door, and at some distance about the value of two or three houses, I could see somebody, I believe, two or three men: the houses join together. I went as fast as I could over the houses after them, and when I got within one house of them I heard murder cried before me, it seemed to come from a place where they dry cloaths upon some leads; I went as fast as I could over the other house, then I saw two women in their shifts on the leads, screaming out, and desired I would come to them as soon as I could, for there were some thieves broke into their house; I desired them to stand on one side, and I jumped down to them, and bid them not be afraid, and said I would go search for them, for they had robbed my house, and I was in search of them. I went and found one of the doors open, I apprehended they were gone thro' that, but I could not find them. On the morrow, about one or two o'clock at noon, 
               <persName id="t17550226-29-person250">
                  Edward 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17550226-29-person250" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-person250" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-person250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , an evidence here, was taken about three houses from that house I pursued them to, in a garret or cock-loft, he was put in the round-house; I went there to him, and asked him how he could do such a thing as to break into my house and rob me? he denied it. I went home, and in about a, quarter of an hour I came again, then he told me that he was at the top of the house and saw me, that betwixt eleven and twelve he and the two prisoners broke into my house; as soon as they entered the door, Marchant drew a knife, and swore he would stab the first that met them; they took the three sheets in the one pair of stairs, and went up into the garrets, there they thought to begin at the top, and strip the house to the bottom, and my wife was ready to lie-in in the two pair of stairs, and that the two prisoners were for strangling her.</p>
               <p>Q. How came they to know of her being there?</p>
               <p>Price. They heard she was then in labour, and had two women with her; then the evidence said, no, no, she has been a good mistress to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he lived with you?</p>
               <p>Price. He had, about two months, some time before; the woman going up disturbed them, so they got out at the trap-door, and made out with the three sheets, they went one way and he another, and he lay betwixt some chimnies all night; then he told me where they were to be found. We went, and carried them before justice Bedwell. Myers owned there he had been along with the other two, and coming down Drury-lane he tried to get in at some houses, but coming to my house he did not go in. Marchant said much the same, he owned he was at my house with Evans, they both said they were not in, and they also said they took nothing away, upon their being charged with the three sheets.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550226-29-person251">
                  Edward 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17550226-29-person251" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-person251" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am sixteen years of age; I have known the two prisoners about three months, their master, Mr. Preston in Brown's-gardens, St. Giles's, is a dust-man, and hires them to go about to take other peoples properties from them. I went to the King's head at the Seven-dials on Saturday the 25th of January, about nine o'clock in the evening, called for a pint of hot there, and saw the two prisoners sitting; they asked me if I would go out a thieving with them?</p>
               <p>Q. Were you by yourselves?</p>
               <p>Evans. Yes, we were in a box by ourselves, they asked me privately, there were two or three other people in the house. I said I would; we went out to rob the first house we could, by breaking it open; we went down St. Martin's-lane, but found no house convenient till we got to Mr. Price's, I had lived servant there, when we got there it was about eleven o'clock. Myers lifted up the latch, and found the door fast, it has a spring-lock to it; they both put their backs to the door, and it flew open. We heard a rumbling up stairs, what it was we could not tell; then Myers drew his knife in the entry, and swore he would kill the first person that offered to make any resistance.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175502260017"></xptr>Q. Are you sure it was Myers ?</p>
               <p>Price. Yes, I am sure it was Myers; then we went and took three sheets in a flat, such as they bring butter in; they were in the entry; then we went up stairs, and I left them in the one pair of stairs, and went up into the garret. Mrs. Price was very bad up two pair of stairs; I bundled up a pair of breeches and a shirt, two frocks, and a pair of stockings.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any thing said relating to her?</p>
               <p>Evans. No, when the woman came up stairs with a little girl, I crept under the bed, and the two prisoners ran out on the tiles at the trap-door. I heard the maid go down, then I crept from under the bed, and went out on the tiles. The two prisoners jumped down on a little sort of a lead, and I saw a door open. Mr. Price came before I could have time to jump down. Mr. Price was near me, and I saw two women come out and cry murder. Mr. Price left off looking any more after us. We had bundled up a pair of leather breeches, and a shirt; but did not take them away.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see a fustian frock taken away?</p>
               <p>Evans. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I lost one, but cannot be sure it was that night. I observed the lock to the outer door was forced the next morning; it was a spring lock.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not there mention made of killing Mrs. Price?</p>
               <p>Evans. No, not as I heard. When Myers talked of killing the first person, I said, may-be my mistress may come down first; she has been a very good mistress to me; don't go to do any murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550226-29-person252">
                  Robert 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17550226-29-person252" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-person252" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mr. Price; when our maid heard a noise in the garret, she sent another person for me to come up; I went up, and met the maid coming down; she said, make haste up, there is somebody under your bed. I looked under the bed, and could find nobody at all. Some of the things bundled up were mine.</p>
               <p>Marchant's defence.</p>
               <p>I never was in company with the evidence in my life.</p>
               <p>Myers's defence.</p>
               <p>I never saw him but once, and that was in Tothil-fields bridewell.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550226-29-person253">
                  Archibald 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17550226-29-person253" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-person253" type="given" value="Archibald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-person253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Marchant is servant to Mr. Preston, a dust-man, near me. I have known him about seven or eight months; his character is very good.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550226-29-person254">
                  John 
                  Preston 
               <interp inst="t17550226-29-person254" type="surname" value="Preston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-person254" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-person254" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Marchant has been a servant to me off and on betwixt five and six years; he has been constant this last twelve-months; he was always an honest man. I have trusted him where there has been things of value in gentlefolk's houses; I never heard any complaint of him.</p>
               <p>- Smith. I have known Marchant five or six months; the man bears a very good character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550226-29-person255">
                  John 
                  Cotton 
               <interp inst="t17550226-29-person255" type="surname" value="Cotton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-person255" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-person255" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Marchant between five and six years; I always looked upon him to be an honest man; he has worked with me many a time.</p>
               <p>Preston. Marchant went to bed at a quarter after eleven that Saturday-night, and I locked the door, and took the key up to bed with me.</p>
               <p>Court. How came it you did not say this in your evidence before?</p>
               <p>Preston. Because the prisoner did not call upon me to mention it.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17550226-29-verdict154" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-verdict154" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>(M.) 
               <persName id="t17550226-29-person256">
                  William 
                  Myers 
               <interp inst="t17550226-29-person256" type="surname" value="Myers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-person256" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-person256" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was a second time indicted for <rs id="t17550226-29-off155" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-off155" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-off155" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one cloth coat, value 2 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17550226-29-victim258" type="victimName">
                     Daniel 
                     Huff 
                  <interp inst="t17550226-29-victim258" type="surname" value="Huff"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-victim258" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-victim258" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17550226-29-cd156" type="crimeDate">Jan. 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550226-29-off151 t17550226-29-cd156"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550226-29-off155 t17550226-29-cd156"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550226-29-person259">
                  Daniel 
                  Huff 
               <interp inst="t17550226-29-person259" type="surname" value="Huff"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-person259" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-person259" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . <rs id="t17550226-29-viclabel157" type="occupation">I keep a chandler's shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550226-29-victim258 t17550226-29-viclabel157"></join> in <placeName id="t17550226-29-crimeloc158">Litchfield-street, St. Anne's Soho</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17550226-29-crimeloc158" type="placeName" value="Litchfield-street, St. Anne's Soho"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550226-29-crimeloc158" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550226-29-off151 t17550226-29-crimeloc158"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550226-29-off155 t17550226-29-crimeloc158"></join>; I missed a great coat on the 26th of January, taken out of my shop; but I know not who took it. (Produced in court, and deposed to). I found it at a pawnbroker's in Bloomsbury on the 28th. I never saw the prisoner till here at the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. Is the pawnbroker here?</p>
               <p>Huff. No; her name is Pain, a widow; I did not know I was to bring her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550226-29-person260">
                  Edward 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17550226-29-person260" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-person260" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-person260" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner and I were coming by the prosecutor's shop on the 21st of January; he said there is a great-coat; he put his hand over, and unbolted the shop-door, and went in and took it; it was lying on a sand-bin.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the night was this?</p>
               <p>Evans. It was about eight at night; he went in to a pawnbroker's, and asked half a guinea; they would not let him have above three half-crowns, as he said, so he came out. He met with 
               <persName id="t17550226-29-person261">
                  James 
                  Weeden 
               <interp inst="t17550226-29-person261" type="surname" value="Weeden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-person261" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-person261" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , that is here to be tried; he gave it him to go and pawn it in Bow-street, Bloomsbury, with Mrs. Pain; he went in and got eight shillings upon it; but came and told us he had only got a crown upon it; he gave the prisoner two shillings, and me one shilling and six-pence, and kept the rest himself; but since he has told me he got eight shillings.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>Evans stole the coat, Weeden pawned it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17550226-29-verdict159" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550226-29-verdict159" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
