<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510911-35">
               <interp inst="t17510911-35" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510911-35" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510911-35" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510911-35" type="date" value="17510911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510911-35-off170-c233" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-35-defend302 t17510911-35-off170 t17510911-35-verdict173"></join>
         
               <p>508. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17510911-35-defend302" type="defendantName">
                     Edward 
                     Bland 
                  <interp inst="t17510911-35-defend302" type="surname" value="Bland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-35-defend302" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-35-defend302" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for that he <rs id="t17510911-35-off170" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510911-35-off170" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-35-off170" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               on the King's high-way, on 
                     <persName id="t17510911-35-victim303" type="victimName">
                        John 
                        Lane 
                     <interp inst="t17510911-35-victim303" type="surname" value="Lane"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510911-35-victim303" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510911-35-victim303" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-35-off170 t17510911-35-victim303"></join>
                     </persName>
                    did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear, &amp;c. one silk purse, value one penny, and one guinea, did steal, &amp;c.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17510911-35-cd171" type="crimeDate">Aug. 31</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-35-off170 t17510911-35-cd171"></join>, ++.</p>
               <p>John Lane. This day fortnight, near four in the afternoon, I was going into the country in my chariot; and about <placeName id="t17510911-35-crimeloc172">a quarter of a mile on this side Acton</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17510911-35-crimeloc172" type="placeName" value="a quarter of a mile on this side Acton"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510911-35-crimeloc172" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-35-off170 t17510911-35-crimeloc172"></join> I heard a stop; and the prisoner at the bar came, directed his pistol into the chariot, and demanded my purse. After I had given him my purse and money, as mentioned in the indictment, he said to my wife, who was in the chariot with me, Madam, have you no purse, or money? or words to that purpose: she then gave him her purse, but what was in it I don't know. After that he went on, and I looked out and saw two stage-coaches immediately following us, who stopt as I did, and I saw him attack one; then he came by my chariot, and rode into the town of Action. I had a black boy with me on horseback; I ordered him to follow him through the town, and raise the town. I saw no more of him till one day this week, when I saw him in the Bail-Dock.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-35-person304">
                  James 
                  Henley 
               <interp inst="t17510911-35-person304" type="surname" value="Henley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-35-person304" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-35-person304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable. I was sent for before the Justice to the prisoner; who there produced two purses, with a guinea in one, and some silver; [both deposed to by the prosecutor] he also produced a horse-pistol, which was delivered to<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175109110018"></xptr> him by the Justice; likewise a watch, a bunch of keys, a pair of scissars, and a paper with some money in it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-35-person305">
                  Thomas 
                  Carpenter 
               <interp inst="t17510911-35-person305" type="surname" value="Carpenter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-35-person305" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-35-person305" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in Old Brentford this day fortnight; between four and five o'clock, people called out a highwayman; I then pursued and followed him to Smallberry Green; the people got him from his horse, and I desired them to hold his hands up; I searched him, and found in his pockets the things produced here, which I delivered to the Justice.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-35-person306">
                  Robert 
                  Eaves 
               <interp inst="t17510911-35-person306" type="surname" value="Eaves"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-35-person306" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-35-person306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming from Cornwall towards London on the 31st of August; the people at Isleworth called out, stop a highwayman ; I asked which was he; they then shewed me him, and told me he was in blue; I then said I would have him, and accordingly rode forward, and going very strong after him, they called out, and told me he had pistols. I said I did not value him, nor his pistols neither. I got up to him, and ask'd him if he would surrender? but he rode on; I then struck him twice with my whip; he went to shoot me with a pistol over his left shoulder; I then took him by the collar, and he fired that instant, and some of the powder blew into my face, for I was behind him. I then pulled him off, and we both fell between the horses, who ran away; I got upon his back, and pulled his hands behind him, and he called out to me not to use him ill, saying he was a dead man; this was on Smallberry green. Then a great many people came up after I had secured him, and Mr. Carpenter searched his pockets, and took out the things produced here. The things were all delivered to the Justice. He was dressed in a large blue coat, a black waistcoat, a light-coloured coat under the great coat, and his hair tied up behind. I did not pursue him above a quarter of a mile.</p>
               <p>Q. to the prosecutor. How was the man dressed that robbed you?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. As the evidence has described.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I am not guilty of any thing they charge me with.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-35-person307">
                  Richard 
                  Leeland 
               <interp inst="t17510911-35-person307" type="surname" value="Leeland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-35-person307" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-35-person307" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in King street, Bloomsbury-square; I know nothing of the fact; the prisoner was my servant when he was apprehended, and had lived with me about four years; he always behaved well. I went out of town that morning, and desired him to stay at home till I returned. I never had any reason to suspect him of such a thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Is that pistol yours?</p>
               <p>Leeland. I believe it is mine.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510911-35-verdict173" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510911-35-verdict173" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510911-35-punish174" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510911-35-punish174" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-35-defend302 t17510911-35-punish174"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
