<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17541204-15">
               <interp inst="t17541204-15" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541204-15" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541204-15" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17541204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541204-15" type="date" value="17541204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17541204-15-off75-c148" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541204-15-defend181 t17541204-15-off75 t17541204-15-verdict78"></join>
         
               <p>19. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17541204-15-defend181" type="defendantName">
                     Terence 
                     Bready 
                  <interp inst="t17541204-15-defend181" type="surname" value="Bready"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-15-defend181" type="given" value="Terence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-15-defend181" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for <rs id="t17541204-15-off75" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17541204-15-off75" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-15-off75" type="offenceSubcategory" value="housebreaking"></interp>
               that he on the <rs id="t17541204-15-cd76" type="crimeDate">29th of November</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541204-15-off75 t17541204-15-cd76"></join>, about the hour of one in the afternoon the dwelling-house of 
                     <persName id="t17541204-15-victim182" type="victimName">
                        Matthias
                         M'Gann
                     <interp inst="t17541204-15-victim182" type="surname" value="M'Gann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17541204-15-victim182" type="given" value="Matthias"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17541204-15-victim182" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541204-15-off75 t17541204-15-victim182"></join>
                     </persName>
                   did break and enter, two linen aprons, one pair of linen sheets, two linen handkerchiefs, one Guinea, and eleven pounds in money, numbered, the goods and money of the said Matthias, in the dwelling-house did steal
            </rs>, &amp;c. ++</p>
               <p>Matthias M'Gann. I live in <placeName id="t17541204-15-crimeloc77">Black-friars</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17541204-15-crimeloc77" type="placeName" value="Black-friars"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17541204-15-crimeloc77" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541204-15-off75 t17541204-15-crimeloc77"></join>; I went out last friday with my wife, and I went out, and she went out, and she was the last that locked the door, and I was the first that came home and found the door broke open. We have two rooms; I found a trunk was carried out of the first room to that backwards, and broke open; I found a knife near the trunk broke, which I had seen in the prisoner's possession before, and know'd it to be his knife, upon which I have got the knife in my pocket here now. (He produced it.)</p>
               <p>Eleanor M'Gann. I am wife to this man; I rent the ground-floor he speaks of. My husband does not know what I lost, or what I gained; he is only a new comer to me on friday last. I left my room door locked between eleven and twelve, and came home at night betwixt six and seven.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner lodge with you at the time you lost the money?</p>
               <p>E. M'Gann. He did not, but he did about a year ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Tell the court what you lost.</p>
               <p>E. M'Gann. When I came home I found the door broke open; I called to my next neighbour, and said I, lord, my door is broke open, and I have lost every farthing.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you miss?</p>
               <p>E. M'Gann. Sir, I'll tell you that. I hope you'll give me leave to speak.</p>
               <p>Court. By all means.</p>
               <p>E. M'Gann. I missed my trunk and box out of my own room, observe I have one room within another, the sheets and blankets were gone off the bed. I went backwards and found the box and trunk, both the locks were broke upon the bed, and one of my own knives I found by the box on the bed. I can't swear to nobody; but they took a guinea in gold, and eleven shilling in silver, and an apron, and carried away my linen, which I value to upwards of nine shillings.</p>
               <p>Q. Where had you put your money before you missed it?</p>
               <p>E. M'Gann. The guinea lay naked on the bottom of the trunk.</p>
               <p>Q. What linen did you lose in the whole? name them.</p>
               <p>E. M'Gann. I lost two sheets, two aprons, and two handkerchiefs.</p>
               <p>Q. Is that all?</p>
               <p>E. M'Gann. No more was gone out of my room.</p>
               <p>Q. Why do you charge the prisoner?</p>
               <p>E. M'Gann. Why, I'll tell you that. My husband got up and went into the room and found this knife, and he brought it to me to ask me if I had seen it before, and I said I never saw it in my life before. I have no other reason to suspect the prisoner at the bar; I don't want to wrong any creature.</p>
               <p>Q. Were any of these things found upon the prisoner?</p>
               <p>E. M'Gann. No, I hope he would not wear sheets, or aprons, or handkerchiefs in the street, please your lordship, if he so kind to hear me, the prisoner is well acquainted with me; he knew what I had almost as well as I did myself.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he been lately in your house?</p>
               <p>E. M'Gann. He was four nights in it of late, and he was the man that had nobody to give him a good word in the world that had dealings with him, but I never saw him guilty of any thing belonging to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you with him before a magistrate?</p>
               <p>E. M'Gann. An't please ye, I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he charged there with taking any of your goods?</p>
               <p>E. M'Gann. No, not in my presence, except he had the money in his pocket, he had nothing, belonging to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Consider, and give an answer. Was he charged before the justice with having any of your goods?</p>
               <p>E. M'Gann. No, nothing in the world, only leaving the knife in the room.</p>
               <p>Q. What said he to that?</p>
               <p>E. M'Gann. I can't say, for I never saw the knife before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say nothing about the knife?</p>
               <p>E. M'Gann. He said before the alderman that he lost a knife before, and that he had a mind<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175412040014"></xptr> to give his wife a licking for it; said the alderman, how long is it ago? he said two or three days ago.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>E. M'Gann. This was on Monday last.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you charge the prisoner with before the alderman?</p>
               <p>E. M'Gann. He was charged, as I am telling you, he gave an answer he lost the knife two or three days before that, and that he'd give his wife a licking for it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that all that was said?</p>
               <p>E. M'Gann. That is all I know.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he not charged about the goods?</p>
               <p>E. M'Gann. He was not as I heard of.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he accused before the alderman of taking these goods?</p>
               <p>E. M'Gann. He was not of any thing that I lost, either money or goods as I know of.</p>
               <p>Q. What was he accused of before the alderman when you carried him there?</p>
               <p>E. M'Gann. He owned he was guilty to the knife, and I know'd no one knew the house, or our way of living better than he did.</p>
               <p>Q. You will not have temper to hear, consider of the questions, and make proper answers. What did you accuse the prisoner with?</p>
               <p>E. M'Gann. Please your lordship I can't answer it. I do not know what is the business I am talking about; I never saw him breaking the door, nor a half worth in his custody, and so I know nothing about it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541204-15-person183">
                  John 
                  Burk 
               <interp inst="t17541204-15-person183" type="surname" value="Burk"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-15-person183" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-15-person183" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the prisoner, but don't know no harm of the man any further than seeing a a knife that I thought was his, but I can't swear to it because it was broke.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing more beside the knife?</p>
               <p>J. Burk. No more my lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know whether these people were robbed?</p>
               <p>J. Burk. I saw the room door broke open, and two locks broke in the house, but who did it God knows. I know nothing of it unless I wrong myself, which I would not do for the world.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>J. Burk. I live in the same house with them. I have the one pair of stairs, and they the ground floor.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of their being robbed?</p>
               <p>J. Burk. I saw nobody a robbing them.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you see?</p>
               <p>J. Burk. I saw a trunk and a box lock broke, and the lock of the door broke.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner lodge in that house?</p>
               <p>J. Burk. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he use to come there?</p>
               <p>J. Burk. He has not very often, he has been once or twice in my room.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you see the knife?</p>
               <p>J. Burk. To the best of my knowledge I saw it before in the prisoner's custody in my room. I can say no farther.</p>
               <p>Q. How did those locks to the box and trunk appear to be opened?</p>
               <p>J. Burk. I was not there to see. I know the mark is withinside, the lid might be opened by a small instrument, as a pair of scissars or a knife.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to see this knife in your room?</p>
               <p>J. Burk. He lay with me two or three nights.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath do you think this trunk and box were both broke open with that knife?</p>
               <p>J. Burk. I will not say so for the world.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541204-15-person184">
                  Margaret 
                  Bnrk 
               <interp inst="t17541204-15-person184" type="surname" value="Bnrk"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-15-person184" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-15-person184" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Gentlemen, I came out of St. Paul's Church-yard betwixt six and seven o'clock last friday night; I went to the baker's that lives in Black-friars to light a candle, and left my basket of fruit at the door, Gentlemen. Eleanor M'Gann came at the same time. When I came again, Gentlemen, she said, what shall I do, my door is broke open. I went in with her into the farther room, Gentlemen, to see if the sheets were gone, and we found the box and trunk broke open, and what was in the box was emptied out upon the bed, Gentlemen; the prisoner that they took up lay two or three nights in our room, Gentlemen.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you wife to the last witness?</p>
               <p>M. Burk. Gentlemen I am.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any reason to suspect the prisoner is the person that broke into the room and opened the box and trunk?</p>
               <p>M. Burk. No, Gentlemen, only on suspicion of seeing his wife buying a knife at the Royal-Exchange; I have seen it up in my room, Gentlemen, and my husband, Gentlemen, offered to swap it for a little penknife, and, Gentlemen, after the time her room was broke open, I saw this knife with the point broke off on it.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you make any judgement whether the box was broke open with this knife?</p>
               <p>M. Burk. Gentlemen I will not for the world. I know no more; I don't, Gentlemen, indeed.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175412040015"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17541204-15-person185">
                  Mary 
                  Bonser 
               <interp inst="t17541204-15-person185" type="surname" value="Bonser"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-15-person185" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-15-person185" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Our entry is a pretty long one; on Friday in the afternoon about one o'clock, I saw a man whip out of the yard into the cellar, it was the prisoner at the bar to the best of my knowledge; when he came out of the cellar I asked him who he wanted? he said he stayed there to meet Mr. Burk, I thought it was a very odd place to meet a man in a cellar.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you lodge in the house of M'Gann ?</p>
               <p>M. Bonser. I am the housekeeper there, I left lodging to M'Gann.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you charged as the owner of this house?</p>
               <p>M. Bonser. I am, and they are all my lodgers in it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17541204-15-verdict78" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17541204-15-verdict78" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-15-verdict78" type="verdictSubcategory" value="fault"></interp>
               The indictment being laid for breaking the dwelling-house of Matthias M'Gann, the prisoner was acquitted without going into his defence
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
