<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560225-42">
               <interp inst="t17560225-42" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560225-42" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560225-42" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560225"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560225-42" type="date" value="17560225"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560225-42-off237-c325" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-42-defend404 t17560225-42-off237 t17560225-42-verdict239"></join>
         
               <p>157. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17560225-42-defend404" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Miller 
                  <interp inst="t17560225-42-defend404" type="surname" value="Miller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-42-defend404" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-42-defend404" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17560225-42-deflabel236" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-42-defend404 t17560225-42-deflabel236"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17560225-42-off237" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560225-42-off237" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-42-off237" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch, value 40 s.
            </rs> the property of a person to the jury unknown, <rs id="t17560225-42-cd238" type="crimeDate">Feb. 14</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-42-off237 t17560225-42-cd238"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-42-person405">
                  Septimus 
                  Mozene 
               <interp inst="t17560225-42-person405" type="surname" value="Mozene"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-42-person405" type="given" value="Septimus"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-42-person405" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am warder in Whitechapple parish. One of the watchmen h appening to meet the prisoner in Story-lane, he came and told me she had shewn him a silver watch. I bid him to tell her, if she would sell it, to bring it to me, and I would buy it of her. This I did in order to detect her, thinking she had stoln it.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Mozene. This was on the 14th instant; he brought her, and I went with her to an alehouse to see it. She deliver'd it to me. I said she had stoln it, and deliver'd her to the officer of the night.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say how she came by it?</p>
               <p>Mozene. She said she found it in Bow church-yard.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you shewn it to any body else, does any body claim it?</p>
               <p>Mozene. The seal and string have been owned by a gentleman, but he will not prosecute.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is he?</p>
               <p>Mozene. He is gone to sea.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-42-person406">
                  William 
                  Sheldon 
               <interp inst="t17560225-42-person406" type="surname" value="Sheldon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-42-person406" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-42-person406" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the prisoner to be a common street-walker. Last Sunday night I met her as I was upon my duty, being a watchman. She said she wanted a piece of candle, shew'd me a watch, and said she would sell it. I went and told the warder, who bid me go to her, and tell her he would buy it; his intent being to stop it, in order to restore it<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175602250037"></xptr> to the right owner. I went, and she brought it. I asked her how she came by it. She said, Gentlemen, I hope you will excuse me, she - for it, and served him right too.</p>
               <p>Mr. Basden. I am constable, and was charged with this woman on the 18th instant, about a quarter after eleven at night. She had got a watch, I asked her how she came by it, and she said she found it in Bow-church-yard; it was deliver'd to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it going when you received it?</p>
               <p>Basden. It was.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any bruises or dirt upon it?</p>
               <p>Basden. No.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of an evening was it, was it clean or dirty?</p>
               <p>Basden. I know it was a dirty evening. I took her before Mr. Alderman Hankey the next day, who order'd her back again to the compter, and directed me to advertise the watch in the Publick Advertiser, which I did three times. Last Saturday a person came and challenged it. I told him Mr. Alderman Hankey had it, in order to find out the right owner, and on Monday I went to the alderman along with the gentleman.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is he?</p>
               <p>Basden. He is not here; he is gone abroad as far as I understand.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17560225-42-verdict239" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560225-42-verdict239" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
