<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17530718-13">
               <interp inst="t17530718-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530718-13" type="year" value="1753"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530718-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17530718"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530718-13" type="date" value="17530718"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17530718-13-off59-c94" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-13-defend117 t17530718-13-off59 t17530718-13-verdict62"></join>
         
               <p>327. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17530718-13-defend117" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Robinson 
                  <interp inst="t17530718-13-defend117" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-13-defend117" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-13-defend117" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17530718-13-deflabel58" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-13-defend117 t17530718-13-deflabel58"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17530718-13-off59" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530718-13-off59" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-13-off59" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing a gold watch, val. 15 l. one silver seal, val. 1 s. and one agate, val. 1 s. the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17530718-13-victim119" type="victimName">
                           Peter Henry 
                           Hansandyke 
                        <interp inst="t17530718-13-victim119" type="surname" value="Hansandyke"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530718-13-victim119" type="given" value="Peter Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530718-13-victim119" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-13-off59 t17530718-13-victim119"></join>
                     </persName>
                     
                  , privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17530718-13-cd60" type="crimeDate">June 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-13-off59 t17530718-13-cd60"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-13-person120">
                  Peter Henry 
                  Hansandyke 
               <interp inst="t17530718-13-person120" type="surname" value="Hansandyke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-13-person120" type="given" value="Peter Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-13-person120" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodge at one Mr. Brown's, a cork-cutter, next the Royal Exchange; I supp'd in Little Tower Street the 14th of June; after supper I look'd at my watch and found it just ten o'clock, so desir'd they would excuse me for I must be going home: coming along, just by the mansion-house, I open'd my waistcoat and walk'd very slowly, 'till coming by <placeName id="t17530718-13-crimeloc61">the trunk-maker's near St. Paul's church-yard</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17530718-13-crimeloc61" type="placeName" value="the trunk-maker's near St. Paul's church-yard"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17530718-13-crimeloc61" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-13-off59 t17530718-13-crimeloc61"></join>, the prisoner came and gave me a slap on the shoulder, and said, How do you do my dear, I turn'd about and felt my watch go, and saw it in her hand at the same time; she ran away, I ran after her and took her, there were two women stood by a door, I call'd out Watch! Watch! several times. As soon as ever the watch came, those two women ran away, then the prisoner gave me a push, and would have run away, but I catch'd, her fast hold by the apron, and held her fast till the watchman came up.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the night was this?</p>
               <p>Hansandyke. About a quarter after ten.</p>
               <p>Q. Well, what did you do with her?</p>
               <p>Hansandyke. We carried her before the constable to the watch-house, under whose Care I left her, and the next day she was carried to Woodstreet-compter, from thence we carried her before the sitting alderman at Guild-hall, there I charged her with having the watch, she would not own any thing, so she was committed to Newgate.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever have your watch again?</p>
               <p>Hansandyke. No, I never had.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-13-person121">
                  Edward 
                  Chency 
               <interp inst="t17530718-13-person121" type="surname" value="Chency"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-13-person121" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-13-person121" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable; the prisoner was brought by the prosecutor to me, the 14th of June, between ten and eleven at night; I asked what she was brought there for, he said she had robbed him of a gold watch in St. Paul's Church-yard ; I searched her, as far as decency would permit ; his wife came some time afterwards, I desir'd her to take her to the other end of the watch-house, and search her; she would not do it, the prisoner cried, and made a very pitiful case, and desired I would call upon two or three of her masters, where she said she had lived, in the Old-Bailey; I went to several, I went to the Queens-head in the Old-Bailey; he said he knew nothing of her, and to several more, who said the same.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-13-person122">
                  Peter 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17530718-13-person122" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-13-person122" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-13-person122" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watchman, on the 14th of June, as I was crying the hour ten o'clock, I heard a gentleman cry, watch! watch! several times, but he not speaking very good English, I thought at first it was coach! coach! I came down, and as I came, I saw the prisoner coming away very fast.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she running away?</p>
               <p>Smith. I cannot say it was running, it was going pretty quick; I stopped her, and the very instant I stopped her, the prosecutor had hold of her by the other arm.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember her being searched by the constable ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175307180008"></xptr>Smith. Yes, she was, as far as decency would allow, but nothing appear'd.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I had been along with a country woman of mine, that was a going into Hertfordshire, as I came back again. I called at the Golden-fleece, in Thread-needle-street; and being out of place, I asked the maid, if she could tell me of ever a place; coming along St. Paul's-Church-yard, I saw a gentleman at the door, I said, pray madam will you give me a draught of beer, she said yes, and desired me to go down and draw some more; I had not been come out above five minutes, before this gentleman took hold of me, and said, I had picked his pocket of a gold watch, and forced me to the watch-house ; there I undrest myself as far as decency would admit, but there was nothing found upon me.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-13-person123">
                  Edward 
                  Parker 
               <interp inst="t17530718-13-person123" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-13-person123" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-13-person123" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner, ever since she was born, she has been where there was things of value, and never meddled with any thing, as I know of.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-13-person124">
                  Honour 
                  Parker 
               <interp inst="t17530718-13-person124" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-13-person124" type="given" value="Honour"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-13-person124" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner this twenty years.</p>
               <p>Q. What have you known of her for this two, three, or four years past?</p>
               <p>H. Parker. I know nothing but what is very honest of her, she has been with me a great while together, I never found any dishonesty by her in my life; she came of very good parents, and had a very good education.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-13-person125">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Thorp 
               <interp inst="t17530718-13-person125" type="surname" value="Thorp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-13-person125" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-13-person125" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about this six months, she lodged with me.</p>
               <p>Q. How does she get her livelyhood?</p>
               <p>E. Thorp. When she lodged with me, she used to get it by going out to day work.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her general character?</p>
               <p>E. Thorp. I never heard but what she was a very honest girl.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-13-person126">
                  Lawrence 
                  Nightingale 
               <interp inst="t17530718-13-person126" type="surname" value="Nightingale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-13-person126" type="given" value="Lawrence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-13-person126" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have know the prisoner this 8 or ten years past, but know not where she has been this two or three years; I never heard any ill of her in my life, I have heard she has gone on very well, and was in service.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-13-person127">
                  John 
                  Metcalfe 
               <interp inst="t17530718-13-person127" type="surname" value="Metcalfe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-13-person127" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-13-person127" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner a great many years, I have not known her much of late, she has lived in several places; I never knew she wronged any body in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-13-person128">
                  Joshua 
                  Ezard 
               <interp inst="t17530718-13-person128" type="surname" value="Ezard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-13-person128" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-13-person128" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her some years, she nursed me when I was sick about a year and half ago: my wife is a mantua-maker, and has trusted her with gowns to carry to gentlemens houses, worth pounds; and she never wrong'd her of any thing in her life.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her way of living?</p>
               <p>J. Ezard. She goes out to days work when she is out of place, I never heard any thing but what was very honest, till this accident happened.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-13-person129">
                  John 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17530718-13-person129" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-13-person129" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-13-person129" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her ever since she was a child, I never knew any harm of her, I have not seen her before now these three years and more.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17530718-13-verdict62" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530718-13-verdict62" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17530718-13-punish63" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530718-13-punish63" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-13-defend117 t17530718-13-punish63"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
