<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17511016-41">
               <interp inst="t17511016-41" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511016-41" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511016-41" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17511016"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511016-41" type="date" value="17511016"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17511016-41-off186-c228" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-41-defend299 t17511016-41-off186 t17511016-41-verdict190"></join>
         
               <p>591. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17511016-41-defend299" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Dowett 
                  <interp inst="t17511016-41-defend299" type="surname" value="Dowett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-41-defend299" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-41-defend299" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17511016-41-deflabel185" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-41-defend299 t17511016-41-deflabel185"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17511016-41-off186" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17511016-41-off186" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-41-off186" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing four silver spoons. value 11 s. two linen shirts, two Holland sheets, one damask table cloth, and one damask napkin
            </rs>, the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17511016-41-victim301" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Evans 
                  <interp inst="t17511016-41-victim301" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-41-victim301" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-41-victim301" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-41-off186 t17511016-41-victim301"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17511016-41-cd187" type="crimeDate">Aug. 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-41-off186 t17511016-41-cd187"></join>. ++ .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-41-person302">
                  John 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17511016-41-person302" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-41-person302" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-41-person302" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17511016-41-crimeloc188">Old Bond-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17511016-41-crimeloc188" type="placeName" value="Old Bond-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17511016-41-crimeloc188" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-41-off186 t17511016-41-crimeloc188"></join>. The prisoner came to me a <rs id="t17511016-41-deflabel189" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-41-defend299 t17511016-41-deflabel189"></join> in the middle of July; she staid till the 29th of August, upon which day I told her my servant, that had lived with me before, was coming again, and ordered to get her things ready that day; there were due to her about 22 or 23 shillings. I sent a guinea to change; the lad could not get it changed, so I did not pay her, but gave her half a crown, and bid her come for the rest in the morning. I looked over the things, and missed one large table spoon, three tea spoons, a strainer, all silver; two shirts, a pair of sheets, two table cloths, and one napkin. She did not come for her money. I sent my boy to enquire amongst her acquaintance after her, why she did not come for her wages; but could not hear of her. I went to Justice Lediard and had a warrant of suspicion; I advertised the things; I had the large silver spoon brought by Mr. Gunston, a pawnbroker in Piccadilly, his boy had stopped it. I desired him to look if he had any other of the things. After that, he brought me two tea spoons, tongs, and strainer; I asked him in what name they were pawn'd; he said in the prisoner's for six shillings; I paid him. Two days after that, I had another pawnbroker from the corner of Coventry Court, with two shirts; in a short time he brought one table cloth and one napkin. About a fortnight after, I had intelligence where the prisoner was; so I got a constable, and took her before Justice Lediard. She acknowledged the taking the things as soon as I took her; she also did the same before the Justice. She had pawned some of them in the name of 
               <persName id="t17511016-41-person303">
                  Mary 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17511016-41-person303" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-41-person303" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-41-person303" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            : she acknowledged there was a pair of sheets at a pawnbroker's (
               <persName id="t17511016-41-person304">
                  Robert 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17511016-41-person304" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-41-person304" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-41-person304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ) on the back of St. Anne's church.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-41-person305">
                  Robert 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17511016-41-person305" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-41-person305" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-41-person305" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live on the back of St. Anne's church; (he produces the sheets) the prisoner brought these to me; the constable and Mr. Evans had them of me; the prisoner brought them on the 16th or 18th of July last. She owned before the Justice they were Mr. Evans's goods, and that she took them out of his house.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175110160020"></xptr>Q. Was her confession taken in writing?</p>
               <p>Davis. No, my lord, it was not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-41-person306">
                  Thomas 
                  Shirley 
               <interp inst="t17511016-41-person306" type="surname" value="Shirley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-41-person306" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-41-person306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable; I heard the prisoner own she pawned the goods at three several pawnbrokers, and that they were Mr. Evans's things.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I did not take them in the way of theft, I was his servant, and when I was short of money, as he would go away three or four days together, being a stranger in the place, as every thing I was to pay for, except meat, bread and beer, was obliged, at times, to carry out these things, but not with an intent to wrong him; I thought to have fetched them home again, and put them in their places when he paid me my bill. I have had but half a crown from the day I went into the house.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Whenever she asked for money she had it. One day she brought a little trifling bill, it was the time she talks of; I had been out two or three days; I then left her half a guinea; and whenever I went out, I always left her as much as I thought necessary.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you owe her?</p>
               <p>Evans. I owed her about 1 l. 3 s.</p>
               <p>Q. What need had you to send a guinea to change, when that and the half crown would have paid her?</p>
               <p>Evans. When the boy came back I said it was as well, and might be lucky it was not changed, for then I could have an opportunity to look over the things before I paid her.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17511016-41-verdict190" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17511016-41-verdict190" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
