<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17550409-28">
               <interp inst="t17550409-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550409-28" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550409-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550409"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550409-28" type="date" value="17550409"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550409-28-off158-c229" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550409-28-defend276 t17550409-28-off158 t17550409-28-verdict160"></join>
         
               <p>184. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17550409-28-defend276" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Basy 
                  <interp inst="t17550409-28-defend276" type="surname" value="Basy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550409-28-defend276" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550409-28-defend276" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550409-28-defend276" type="age" value="nineteen"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17550409-28-off158" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550409-28-off158" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550409-28-off158" type="offenceSubcategory" value="shoplifting"></interp>
               stealing sixteen pair of worsted stockings, value 32 s. the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17550409-28-victim278" type="victimName">
                           Edward 
                           Woodcock 
                        <interp inst="t17550409-28-victim278" type="surname" value="Woodcock"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550409-28-victim278" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550409-28-victim278" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550409-28-off158 t17550409-28-victim278"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the shop
            </rs> of the said Edward, <rs id="t17550409-28-cd159" type="crimeDate">Feb. 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550409-28-off158 t17550409-28-cd159"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550409-28-person279">
                  Edward 
                  Woodcock 
               <interp inst="t17550409-28-person279" type="surname" value="Woodcock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550409-28-person279" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550409-28-person279" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About a quarter after six o'clock, on the 22d of last February, I lost sixteen pair of worsted stockings from out of my shop.</p>
               <p>Q. What were the value of them?</p>
               <p>Woodcock. They were well worth two shillings a pair at the best hand. I was informed about a fortnight ago there was a boy in Clerkenwel-bridewel that impeached, that he, with others, had robbed me. I went to him, he told me he and the prisoner robbed me, mentioning the time, and of what, as I have mentioned here; he said, 
               <persName id="t17550409-28-person280">
                  Richard 
                  Gray 
               <interp inst="t17550409-28-person280" type="surname" value="Gray"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550409-28-person280" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550409-28-person280" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             lived in Black-boy-alley, where I went and took him, and carried him before Mr. alderman Alexander; I remembering the evidence told me they each of them wore a pair of my stockings; I looked at the prisoner's legs, there I found he had these pair of stockings on, (producing a pair) these I verily believe to be one of the sixteen pair which I lost, they answer the description in every respect; I will not swear to them, there being others of the same make, but I am convinced they are a pair of mine.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550409-28-person281">
                  Robert 
                  Duncastle 
               <interp inst="t17550409-28-person281" type="surname" value="Duncastle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550409-28-person281" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550409-28-person281" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about two years.</p>
               <p>Q. How old are you?</p>
               <p>Duncastle. I am sixteen years of age.</p>
               <p>Q. How old is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Duncastle. He is about nineteen; I never had any dealings with him till about six weeks ago, last Saturday, when he and I were going down Fleet-street together he said there was a chance to get a pair of stockings at Mr. Woodcock's shop, he bid me go and pull, I went into the shop and pulled, and down came all the sixteen pair; I gave them to him at the door.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you pull them from?</p>
               <p>Duncastle. From off a shelf; we carried them first to a shop in Field-lane, and left them, and when we came back again to them, the man of the shop said there were but nine pair; we sold one pair to a sailor, another pair the prisoner pawned, and we put each of us a pair on, and sold the rest, being five pair, all together in Chick-lane.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is this person in Field-lane, where you say you lost them?</p>
               <p>Duncastle. His name is Kenter; there is no sign; he buys stolen handkerchiefs; I used to lodge there.</p>
               <p>C. Look at these pair of stockings, (those taken from off the prisoner's legs.)</p>
               <p>Duncastle. I believe they are the same the prison er wore, they are the same colour of those he had.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the person's name that you sold the five pair to?</p>
               <p>Duncastle. I can't tell the woman's name?</p>
               <p>Q. What did you get for them?</p>
               <p>Duncastle. She gave us six shillings and six-pence for them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was at play with that evidence one Saturday-morning in the market, about two months ago; I was a stranger to him; we walked about all day together; when night came on he asked me to go to see my sister? I said she lived towards Temple-bar; and said if she gave me any money I would lend him some. I missed him between there and Shoe-lane. I heard him halloo out; I ran up Poppins-alley and followed him, he had got a parcel in a white paper, I thought he had found it; I called halves, he ran and said I should have none; he went to the house he mentions and threw them under a table, and came out again, and I asked him what they were? he told me they were stockings, and said he was a stocking-weaver by trade, and he knew them better than I did. I had been sick for three weeks, and my mother went to Rag-fair and bought me these stockings that are here.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17550409-28-verdict160" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550409-28-verdict160" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550409-28-verdict160" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder5s"></interp>
               Guilty 4 s. 10 d.
            </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
