<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17571026-14">
               <interp inst="t17571026-14" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17571026-14" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17571026-14" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17571026"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17571026-14" type="date" value="17571026"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17571026-14-off73-c116" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571026-14-defend137 t17571026-14-off73 t17571026-14-verdict76"></join>
         
               <p>389. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17571026-14-defend137" type="defendantName">
                  William 
                  Gilham 
               <interp inst="t17571026-14-defend137" type="surname" value="Gilham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-14-defend137" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-14-defend137" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17571026-14-off73" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17571026-14-off73" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-14-off73" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one silver spoon, value 10 s one linen shirt, value 5 s. one guinea, and one shilling
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17571026-14-victim139" type="victimName">
                     Patrick 
                     Kelly 
                  <interp inst="t17571026-14-victim139" type="surname" value="Kelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-14-victim139" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-14-victim139" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571026-14-off73 t17571026-14-victim139"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17571026-14-cd74" type="crimeDate">October 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571026-14-off73 t17571026-14-cd74"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571026-14-person140">
                  Patrick 
                  Kelly 
               <interp inst="t17571026-14-person140" type="surname" value="Kelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-14-person140" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-14-person140" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 27th of September I went and dined with a friend at Rotherhith, and told him I wanted a boy very much.</p>
               <p>Q. What business are you in?</p>
               <p>Kelly. <rs id="t17571026-14-viclabel75" type="occupation">I keep a publick house</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571026-14-victim139 t17571026-14-viclabel75"></join>. My friend recommended to me this boy at the bar I there agreed to give him 5 pounds a year. He came the next morning about 8 or 9 o'clock. I had put a shilling in the till, and miss'd it that day, but had no suspicion of him. On the Sunday following 
               <persName id="t17571026-14-person141">
                  Joseph 
                  Russel 
               <interp inst="t17571026-14-person141" type="surname" value="Russel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-14-person141" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-14-person141" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             pull'd off a ruffled shirt and deliver'd it to my maid to lay by for him, which she did. I saw it lying in the place. On the Tuesday following his mother and brother came to my house. I desir'd them to dine with me on a leg of mutton and turnips. After dinner he call'd me out at the door and said, master I shall take it as a favour if you'll lend me 20 s. which I did, looking upon him as an honest lad. I went up for the money, and as I was counting it he was soon at my heels. After I had lent it him he went with his mother into the Borough. This was the 5th day of his being with me. On the Thursday following I sent him up to clear the club room, and I went out at the same time. When I came home at night I found the pots were not fetch'd in. I ask'd my maid why the boy had not fetch'd them in, and she told me he had not been in the house half an hour. I call'd him but he made no answer. At last he came and took his hat and away he walk'd; after which I went up stairs and found the beaufet door open, where I miss'd a guinea. The next morning my maid miss'd a silver spoon, and the shirt I mention'd. The boy was not to be found</p>
               <p>Q. In what condition did you find the beaufet ?</p>
               <p>Kelly. The lock was tried at very much on one compartment in it, but was not open'd. I sent two men to his mother's, to know if he was there, who return'd and said he was not; then I went, and found he was there. I left word, that if he would come again I would take no notice of what was past, but in the mean time I went and got a warrant from justice Fielding, and when he came I took him before the justice, where he own'd the silver spoon and shirt, and that he had pawn'd them with Mrs. Edwards, and also that he had taken a guinea out of the beaufet, before the constable and myself.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571026-14-person142">
                  Joseph 
                  Russel 
               <interp inst="t17571026-14-person142" type="surname" value="Russel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-14-person142" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-14-person142" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The shirt was my property; I heard the prisoner own before the justice that he took it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571026-14-person143">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17571026-14-person143" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-14-person143" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-14-person143" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a pawnbroker; the prisoner at the bar pawn'd with me a silver spoon and a ruffled shirt.</p>
               <p>Produced in court, and deposed to by their respective owners.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to take in goods that you did not know to belong to the person that brought them?</p>
               <p>E. Edwards. The prisoner used to come with goods belonging to his mother; and at this time he told me he lived servant with a doctor, that his master had given him two shirts, and this was one of them.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175710260017"></xptr>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I did not know what I did, for I was in liquor; I did not try to break any locks: As I was sweeping the room the door of the beaufet came open, and I saw the guinea lying, so I took it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17571026-14-verdict76" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17571026-14-verdict76" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17571026-14-punish77" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17571026-14-punish77" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571026-14-defend137 t17571026-14-punish77"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
