<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17500711-32">
               <interp inst="t17500711-32" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-32" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-32" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17500711"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-32" type="date" value="17500711"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500711-32-off144-c230" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-32-defend293 t17500711-32-off144 t17500711-32-verdict146"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175007110020"></xptr>453. 
               
                  <persName id="t17500711-32-defend293" type="defendantName">
                     David 
                     Toris 
                  <interp inst="t17500711-32-defend293" type="surname" value="Toris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-32-defend293" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-32-defend293" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17500711-32-off144" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500711-32-off144" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-32-off144" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               stealing one pair of worsted stockings
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17500711-32-victim295" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Hopley 
                  <interp inst="t17500711-32-victim295" type="surname" value="Hopley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-32-victim295" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-32-victim295" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-32-off144 t17500711-32-victim295"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17500711-32-cd145" type="crimeDate">June 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-32-off144 t17500711-32-cd145"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-32-person296">
                  Josiah 
                  Voice 
               <interp inst="t17500711-32-person296" type="surname" value="Voice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-32-person296" type="given" value="Josiah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-32-person296" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 15th of June at two in the afternoon the prisoner was in my master's shop, a gentleman came in to buy a pair of stockings at the same time, I opened a paper with six pair in it, I sold the gentleman two pair; he desired I would give him a skain of worsted to mend them. I walked round a large circumference for the worsted. After the gentleman was gone, there were two pair of stockings missing. I stood behind the counter and desired the prisoner to go to the next door and fetch me a pint of beer. I drank it up and gave him the pot again; he leaned with his right hand upon the counter, and took a pair of stockings from off the counter, and put them into his pocket; then he in a complaisant manner bad me good by; I went to detect him in the public house, but instead of going there he made off another way, and I never saw him for three days after.</p>
               <p>Q. What colour were they?</p>
               <p>Voice. A pair of man's grey stockings. There were three pair lost.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you not to take him up till three weeks after this?</p>
               <p>Voice. My master is able to account for that.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you see him in the shop after this before he was taken up?</p>
               <p>Voice. No, not in the shop, I saw him in the street before the door.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hopley. The reason he was not taken up sooner is, I had information given me by a gentleman that lives at Mile-End, that the prisoner had sold stockings cheaper than I could do. I had not time to go just then to inquire about it; and knowing he was to be seen at any time, and as I knew I had time enough to take him before the sessions came on, made me not in a great hurry in taking him up. He has called upon me, and said, God bless you, several times. He is a Jew.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence. The gentleman has taken a very wrong oath. I have gone in the house very often for messages for the foreman; he has sent me often to carry parcels of goods for him; I have been with goods to the Castle in Aldersgate street, and when the waggoner has been out, I have, for safety, brought them back again. I have been in his house four or five times a week; my character is above doing such a thing.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-32-person297">
                  Benjamin 
                  Dolphin 
               <interp inst="t17500711-32-person297" type="surname" value="Dolphin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-32-person297" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-32-person297" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live next door to Mr. Hopley, I know the prisoner, I remember his coming to my house this day, and he came afterwards as usual, they might have taken him any day; he used to sell snuff now and then, and go of errands; he has received money for me frequently, I never heard any thing amiss of him till now.</p>
               <p>Isaac Le Jiver. When I heard this I was very much surprized, I took him to have a very good character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-32-person298">
                  Moses 
                  Gomisara 
               <interp inst="t17500711-32-person298" type="surname" value="Gomisara"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-32-person298" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-32-person298" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I would trust the prisoner at any time to get his living; I never heard any complaint against him till now.</p>
               <p>Alex. Jacob. The prisoner has bore an exceeding good character, I have trusted him with things of value.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-32-person299">
                  Solomon 
                  Reitea 
               <interp inst="t17500711-32-person299" type="surname" value="Reitea"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-32-person299" type="given" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-32-person299" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never heard any thing ill of him before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-32-person300">
                  Isaac 
                  Gomosoares 
               <interp inst="t17500711-32-person300" type="surname" value="Gomosoares"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-32-person300" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-32-person300" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have dealt with the prisoner, and trusted him several times, I never saw any thing dishonest by him.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500711-32-verdict146" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500711-32-verdict146" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
