<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17520219-10">
               <interp inst="t17520219-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520219-10" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520219-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520219"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520219-10" type="date" value="17520219"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520219-10-off42-c90" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520219-10-defend105 t17520219-10-off42 t17520219-10-verdict46"></join>
         
               <p>140. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17520219-10-defend105" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Davis 
                  <interp inst="t17520219-10-defend105" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-10-defend105" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-10-defend105" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted, for that <rs id="t17520219-10-off42" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520219-10-off42" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-10-off42" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he, on the King's highway, on Elizabeth, <rs id="t17520219-10-viclabel43" type="occupation">wife of 
                        
                           <persName id="t17520219-10-victim107" type="victimName">
                              Francis 
                              Manning 
                           <interp inst="t17520219-10-victim107" type="surname" value="Manning"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17520219-10-victim107" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17520219-10-victim107" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        </persName>
                         
                     
                     </rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520219-10-victim109 t17520219-10-viclabel43"></join>, did make an assault, one linnen handkerchief, one linnen apron, and thirteen pence in money, the property of the said Francis, from her person did steal, &amp;c
            </rs>. <rs id="t17520219-10-cd44" type="crimeDate">July 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520219-10-off42 t17520219-10-cd44"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
               
                  <persName id="t17520219-10-victim109" type="victimName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Manning 
                  <interp inst="t17520219-10-victim109" type="surname" value="Manning"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-10-victim109" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-10-victim109" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            . On the 29th of July, between nine and ten o'clock at night, going home through <placeName id="t17520219-10-crimeloc45">Drury Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17520219-10-crimeloc45" type="placeName" value="Drury Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520219-10-crimeloc45" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520219-10-off42 t17520219-10-crimeloc45"></join>, the prisoner ran after me, and swore G - d d - n your eyes you b - h. stop, and struck me as I was going cross the kennel, I don't know with what, he took my apron and thirteen pence out of my pocket; I cried out murder ; he gave me a second blow, and again said, d - n your eyes you b - h; he cut my eyebrow, and it bled a great deal; he snatched my handkerchief off and ran away; I took great observation of him when he came up to me, so that I knew him by his cloaths and his voice; I knew him as soon as I saw him in the goal from the rest of the prisoners, and he knew me; I charged him with robbing me, and said, I remember your handkerchief was the colour of this, shewing me one he had on; (it was near the colour) and that he cut my apron off; and that afterwards, said he, you thought I went into the Harlequin, but I went into the Fox and spent your money. This was in the presence of the constable and 
               <persName id="t17520219-10-person110">
                  Mary 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17520219-10-person110" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-10-person110" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-10-person110" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I had been in goal two months before she came to me.</p>
               <p>E. Manning. I did not hear he was in goal till about two months after he was taken up for another robbery.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520219-10-person111">
                  Thomas 
                  James 
               <interp inst="t17520219-10-person111" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-10-person111" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-10-person111" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable in St. George, Bloomsbury : I was employed to search for some leather that was lost, which I found in the custody of the prisoner at the bar: In September last he was sent to prison, and detained as an evidence ; when the prosecutrix, I, and Mary Jones, went to see him in prison; she knew him and he likew ise knew her; she said she was sure he was the man that robbed her, and he owned she was the woman that was robbed in Drury-lane.</p>
               <p>Q. How came the prosecutrix to go ?</p>
               <p>James. She came and told me she heard there was a man taken that had committed many robberies in and near Drury-lane, and desired to go to see if she knew him. When she asked him how he did, he said, Dame, I don't know you: said I, don't you remember such a time you robbed me in Drury lane; he said, I know you are the woman, it was of an apron and silk handkerchief, and thirteen-pence in money, and that he cut her over the eye, and pointed up to her eye, saying, it was this eye, I believe. (The prosecutrix shewed a scar, which, she said, he made.) He said also, he went to the Fox and Goose, and spent her money, and shared the things, there being others concerned.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520219-10-person112">
                  Mary 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17520219-10-person112" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-10-person112" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-10-person112" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went with the prosecutrix and constable to the goal. She confirmed that of their conversation there.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was not on the same side the way; there were about sixty people looking at the affair as well as I: I had been drinking in a house with one 
               <persName id="t17520219-10-person113">
                  Peter 
                  Dun 
               <interp inst="t17520219-10-person113" type="surname" value="Dun"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-10-person113" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-10-person113" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , they were to go to bed together, she went along with him arm in arm; she missed her apron in the Fox and Goose in the Play-house Passage, and had a man searched there; I did not act a part in it, or receive a farthing of value from it ; I was not in the same parish when it was done.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520219-10-person114">
                  Hugh 
                  Hurst 
               <interp inst="t17520219-10-person114" type="surname" value="Hurst"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-10-person114" type="given" value="Hugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-10-person114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Church-lane by St. Martin's Church, and am a shoe-maker, so is the prisoner.</p>

               <p>Q. from the prisoner. Ask that witness if he did not see the prosecutor drinking at the Fox and Goose in Drury-lane.</p>
               <p>Hurst. I don't know the woman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520219-10-person115">
                  James 
                  Collings 
               <interp inst="t17520219-10-person115" type="surname" value="Collings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-10-person115" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-10-person115" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a shoe-maker; I live in the parish of St. Martin's; I can't say the day<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175202190008"></xptr> of the month, or the month, but I know it was of a Monday, early in the afternoon, about four or five o'clock, last summer, the prosecutrix was robbed by two men ; the woman was so drunk I did not know what became of her, nor she does not know what became of herself: I live up two pair of stairs, and saw it out of the window: there was a man with a greed waistcoat along with her, pretending to be her husband, who struck her and knocked her down: then, not that man, (pointing to the prisoner) a man far less than he, ran away with her apron: when the people asked her who she was, she opened her mouth and said nothing, she could give no account of herself, I believe it was a drunken robbery.  <rs id="t17520219-10-verdict46" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520219-10-verdict46" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17520219-10-punish47" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520219-10-punish47" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520219-10-defend105 t17520219-10-punish47"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>See No. 7, in this Mayoralty.</p>
            </div1>
