<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17561208-38">
               <interp inst="t17561208-38" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561208-38" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561208-38" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17561208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561208-38" type="date" value="17561208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17561208-38-off190-c249" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-38-defend308 t17561208-38-off190 t17561208-38-verdict195"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17561208-38-off190-c250" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-38-defend309 t17561208-38-off190 t17561208-38-verdict193"></join>
         
               <p>43. 44. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17561208-38-defend308" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Knowlan 
                  <interp inst="t17561208-38-defend308" type="surname" value="Knowlan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-38-defend308" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-38-defend308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             and 
               <persName id="t17561208-38-defend309" type="defendantName">
                  Edward
                   M'Collister
               <interp inst="t17561208-38-defend309" type="surname" value="M'Collister"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-38-defend309" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-38-defend309" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             were indicted for <rs id="t17561208-38-off190" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561208-38-off190" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-38-off190" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               making an assault on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17561208-38-victim311" type="victimName">
                           Charles 
                           Preston 
                        <interp inst="t17561208-38-victim311" type="surname" value="Preston"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17561208-38-victim311" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17561208-38-victim311" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-38-off190 t17561208-38-victim311"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , on the king's highway, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and taking from his person one man's hat, value five shillings, one peruke, value five shillings, two iron keys, value two pence, one brass watch key, value one penny, and one shilling in money
            </rs>, the goods and money of the said Charles, <rs id="t17561208-38-cd191" type="crimeDate">November the 22d.</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-38-off190 t17561208-38-cd191"></join>* </p> 
               <p>Charles Preston. Coming along <placeName id="t17561208-38-crimeloc192">Petticoat-Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17561208-38-crimeloc192" type="placeName" value="Petticoat-Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17561208-38-crimeloc192" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-38-off190 t17561208-38-crimeloc192"></join>, about nine at night, on the 22d of November, I was knock'd down, and rob'd of my hat and wig, one shilling in money, two iron keys, a watch key, a tobacco stopper and a penknife.</p>
               <p>Q. By how many persons?</p>
               <p>Preston. I saw three men. M'Collister was one of them.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175612080027"></xptr>Q. can you say who knock'd you down?</p>
               <p>Preston. No, I cannot; for in knocking me down they funned me. I found myself on my back. One of them had his fingers and thumb in my mouth, attempting to gag me, and I heard these words, By the great Jesus if you stir, or speak, you are a dead man. I saw M'Collister while I lay there, standing on my left hand side.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell who spake those words?</p>
               <p>Preston. No, I cannot.</p>
               <p>Q. What have you to say to the other prisoner</p>
               <p>Preston. I can't say I know him.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you got any of your things again ?</p>
               <p>Preston. I have got my hat again.</p>
               <p>Q. Look carefully at M'Collister and consider.</p>
               <p>Preston. I am sure M'Collister was one of them. I thought it prudent not to resist while lying on my back; but I stretch'd my arms out as if I had been dead or helpless. They all three ran away together. They were not got twenty yards before I jumped up, and pursued them down Smock-Alley, very near them, calling out thieves. At the bottom of the alley is a court which is no thorough-fair, and this M'Collister ran up there. He was coming back again, and I made a blow at him with my fist; but he being upon the full run, and a stronger man than me, he beat me down again. He rather ran over me.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the name of that court?</p>
               <p>Preston. I think that court is call'd Dolphin-Court. I was presently up again, and pursued him to the end of Steward-Street, where I came so nigh him as to endeavour to strike up his heels; but upon missing him I fell down again, and one Mr. Golding coming along laid hold of him, and secured him. We took him to the headborough's house, and secured him there all night; the next morning he was carried before Sir Samuel Gower, and he committed him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you search him?</p>
               <p>Preston. We did; but found nothing about him but a knife.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you get your hat?</p>
               <p>Preston. That was found at the end of Gun-Street, by one Mr. Edwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Is Mr. Edwards here?</p>
               <p>Preston. No, he is not. (The hat produced in court, and deposed to.)</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say for himself before the justice?</p>
               <p>Preston. He had but very little to say.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561208-38-person312">
                  Philip 
                  Golding 
               <interp inst="t17561208-38-person312" type="surname" value="Golding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-38-person312" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-38-person312" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Steward-Street. About nine o'clock at night, on the 22d of November, coming out of my house I heard a cry of stop thief. I saw M'Collister come running from Gun Street, to the corner of Steward-Street. I catch'd hold of him by the arm, but he being on a swift run got from I ran up the footway way in Steward-Street, and with him. At last I jumped full upon him, got him by the, and kept him. He made a struggle. I said I'd keep him. He put his right-hand down to his breeches pocket, which was open. I was afraid he had something there, with which he might do me hurt. I took care of his hand. Presently came up the prosecutor, and other persons. As soon as he saw the man, and heard his voice, he said, '' That is one '' of the men that knock'd me down and rob'd '' me.'' There was a hat taken up at the corner of Gun Street, and deliver'd to the prosecutor I saw the prisoner examined in the headborough's house. There we searched him, and found a large clasp knife in his breeches pocket, where he was endeavouring to put his hand. ( Produced in court.) We carried him before Sir 
               <persName id="t17561208-38-person313">
                  Samuel 
                  Gower 
               <interp inst="t17561208-38-person313" type="surname" value="Gower"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-38-person313" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-38-person313" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , where he was impertinent to the clerk, and said, he'd answer no questions. The clerk asked him how he came here from Ireland. He said, he would not tell him.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Out of which pocket did you take that knife?</p>
               <p>Golding. From out of the prisoner's right-hand pocket.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561208-38-person314">
                  John 
                  Armstrong 
               <interp inst="t17561208-38-person314" type="surname" value="Armstrong"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-38-person314" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-38-person314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I and the two prisoners at the bar were coming down Petticoat Lane, with one Brown along with us. He is not taken. We met the prosecuter. Brown said, I believe this man has got money, let's follow him.</p>
               <p>Q. Which way were you going ?</p>
               <p>Armstrong. We were going towards White Chappel. He went up to the upper end of the lane; Brown and Kimest -</p>
               <p>Q. Who is Kimest ?</p>
               <p>Armstrong. That is the prisoner's right name. They went after him and drag'd him back. When I came up he was lying on his back.</p>
               <p>Q. How did they get him down?</p>
               <p>Armstrong. I can't tell how they got him down. whether he was knocked down or not; I was not time enough to know that. Brown had his hand in his pocket. He drag'd out something which made a jingling. I thought it was his watch. After he took his hand out of his pocket we ran away, and ran up a place where there was<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175612080028"></xptr> no passage. At the end of Petticoat-Lane we were all forced to retu rn back again; by that time there were many people. Brown ran by himself, and did not run up that place. In returning we ran through the croud. Some pursued me, and some Kimest.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure Knowlan was there ?</p>
               <p>Armstrong. He was; but I did not see him meddle with the man at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Which way did you take after you returned from that court?</p>
               <p>Armstrong. I don't know which way. I am a stranger there, but when I stopped I found myself in Rag-Fair.</p>
               <p>M'Collister's Defence.</p>
               <p>I have nothing to say, only as I am a young man I am willing to serve his majesty. I desire a favourable report may be made. Mr. Stanley has put them upon this to swear my life away. This man Armstrong has committed several murders in Ireland, and now he has run away with an heiress from Dublin.</p>
               <p>Knowlan's Defence.</p>
               <p>That fellow Armstrong has been concerned with thieftakers to swear my life away.</p>
               <p>Armstrong. I stood my trial in Ireland for a murder, and was acquitted. Stanley never spake to me about this thing.</p>
               <p>M'Collister <rs id="t17561208-38-verdict193" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561208-38-verdict193" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17561208-38-punish194" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561208-38-punish194" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-38-defend309 t17561208-38-punish194"></join>
               Death
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>Knowlan <rs id="t17561208-38-verdict195" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561208-38-verdict195" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
