<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17540717-25">
               <interp inst="t17540717-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540717-25" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540717-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540717"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540717-25" type="date" value="17540717"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540717-25-off122-c212" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-25-defend261 t17540717-25-off122 t17540717-25-verdict124"></join>
         
               <p>371. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17540717-25-defend261" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Longbottom 
                  <interp inst="t17540717-25-defend261" type="surname" value="Longbottom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-25-defend261" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-25-defend261" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17540717-25-deflabel121" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-25-defend261 t17540717-25-deflabel121"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17540717-25-off122" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540717-25-off122" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-25-off122" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one gold chain, value 3 l. 10 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               <persName id="t17540717-25-victim262" type="victimName">
                  Israel 
                  Buckley 
               <interp inst="t17540717-25-victim262" type="surname" value="Buckley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-25-victim262" type="given" value="Israel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-25-victim262" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-25-off122 t17540717-25-victim262"></join>
                  </persName>
             , <rs id="t17540717-25-cd123" type="crimeDate">June 4</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-25-off122 t17540717-25-cd123"></join>. +</p>
               <p>Israel Buckley. The prisoner came to my house on the 4th of June, to buy a ring; I bid her sit her finger. She looked at one and another; at last she said I fancy this will do. I took it and began to weigh it. Then she said she wanted one of two guineas value. I looked upon her and bid her go about her business, and told her she wanted no such ring. She went out of my shop, I missed a ring, followed and stopped her. She dropped the ring in the kennel. Then I brought her back to my house, and put her into a room where nobody was but she and my girl. The ring was found in<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175407170020"></xptr> the kennel and brought in after she was gone. We missed a gold chain which had been in the room where we put her to search her. I took her in Aldersgate Street, very much fuddled, that same afternoon and carried her to Wood-street Counter; there she was searched, and had gold and silver about her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find the chain upon her?</p>
               <p>Buckley. No, we did not. Then I went to enquire at a pawnbroker's, one Mr. Harrison, and found one row of a gold chain, who said, he took it in of the prisoner. About a week after, the prisoner's mother gave me an account that the prisoner had sold some more of it at other places.</p>
               <p>Q. How many chains were there of it?</p>
               <p>Buckley. There were four; this I found at the pawnbroker's was the uppermost chain, that is the shortest.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the value of that?</p>
               <p>Buckley. It is worth 10 s.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-25-person263">
                  Mary 
                  Buckley 
               <interp inst="t17540717-25-person263" type="surname" value="Buckley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-25-person263" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-25-person263" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am niece to the prosecutor, the chain was mine.</p>
               <p>Q. to the prosecutor. How came you to lay it in the indictment as your property?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. The young woman is my niece; I brought her up, and find her cloaths and every thing as though she was my own.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-25-person264">
                  Mary 
                  Buckley 
               <interp inst="t17540717-25-person264" type="surname" value="Buckley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-25-person264" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-25-person264" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . There was nobody in the room where I had laid the gold chain but the prisoner and I, which is the reason we suspected her taking it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in the room all the time she was?</p>
               <p>M. Buckley. No, I was not, I was once just out at the room door.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-25-person265">
                  James 
                  Stiles 
               <interp inst="t17540717-25-person265" type="surname" value="Stiles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-25-person265" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-25-person265" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Harrison, a pawnbroker in St. Bride's parish. On the 4th of June the prisoner brought this piece of the gold chain and pledged it at our house, producing it.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Look upon that chain, do you know it?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I believe it is part of what I lost, but as one gold chain may be like another I will not swear to it.</p>
               <p>The niece said the same.</p>
               <p>Q. to Stiles. How much did you lend the prisoner upon it?</p>
               <p>Stiles. I lent her 6 shillings.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure it was the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Stiles. I am sure she is the person.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence</p>
               <p>Going down to Fleet-market I saw that piece of a link of a chain lying in a piece of paper; there were two women with roses in their hands, they said halves; I said I believe you may take all, it is nothing but a piece of brass. They said you shall go to a silversmith's and have it tried. I said, no, I would not, I might bring myself into trouble. They then said try it upon a flint stone. I went to the pawnbroker's and asked him if it was gold or not, and he tried it and weighed it. I asked four shillings upon it, and he lent me 6.</p>
               <p>Stiles. She never asked me whether it was gold, she asked me to lend her 6 shillings upon it, which I did.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540717-25-verdict124" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540717-25-verdict124" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540717-25-punish125" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540717-25-punish125" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-25-defend261 t17540717-25-punish125"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
