<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560915-13">
               <interp inst="t17560915-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-13" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560915"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-13" type="date" value="17560915"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560915-13-off71-c80" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-13-defend105 t17560915-13-off71 t17560915-13-verdict74"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560915-13-off71-c81" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-13-defend107 t17560915-13-off71 t17560915-13-verdict74"></join>
         
               <p>335, 336. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17560915-13-defend105" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Ridout 
                  <interp inst="t17560915-13-defend105" type="surname" value="Ridout"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-13-defend105" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-13-defend105" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17560915-13-defend107" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Prosser 
                  <interp inst="t17560915-13-defend107" type="surname" value="Prosser"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-13-defend107" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-13-defend107" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted for <rs id="t17560915-13-off71" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560915-13-off71" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-13-off71" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one silver tankard, value 7 l. the property of 
                     <persName id="t17560915-13-victim108" type="victimName">
                        Alexander 
                        Macdaniel 
                     <interp inst="t17560915-13-victim108" type="surname" value="Macdaniel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560915-13-victim108" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560915-13-victim108" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-13-off71 t17560915-13-victim108"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , in the dwelling-house of the said Alexander
            </rs>, <rs id="t17560915-13-cd72" type="crimeDate">Aug. 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-13-off71 t17560915-13-cd72"></join>.* </p>  
               <p>Alexander Macdaniel. I am a <rs id="t17560915-13-viclabel73" type="occupation">publican</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-13-victim108 t17560915-13-viclabel73"></join>, in the parish of St. Martin in the Fields. On the 15th of August I lost a silver tankard, which cost me 7 l. but as I was not at home at the time, I can give no account of the taking of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you had it again?</p>
               <p>Macdaniel. No, I have not seen it since.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you heard either of the prisoners confess any thing about it?</p>
               <p>Macdaniel. I have heard them both own, that Ridout took it out of my bar, and gave it to Prosser, who carried it away; and Prosser confessed that he and an old cobler sold it for a guinea to one Woodhouse, who is since bail'd out, and that the cobler and Prosser had each half a guinea.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did they confess this?</p>
               <p>Macdaniel. Before justice St. Lawrence.</p>
               <p>Q. What, had Ridout no part of the money?</p>
               <p>Macdaniel. No, he was stop'd immediately, upon the tankard being missing, and carried to prison.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-13-person109">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Macdaniel 
               <interp inst="t17560915-13-person109" type="surname" value="Macdaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-13-person109" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-13-person109" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the prosecutor. I set the tankard on the stairs in the bar, which is in the tap-room, at which time Ridout had been in the house I believe two hours. Prosser came in after he had had two pints of beer. As soon as they were gone I missed the tankard, and pursuing them Ridout was taken in Southampton-Street. I could not overtake the other, but he was taken in about a week after. I heard Ridout confess he took the tankard from the bar, and gave it to Prosser, who ran away with it; and Prosser said he carried it to a cobler, who sold it to one Woodhouse for a guinea, and that he had one half guinea, and the cobler the other.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-13-person110">
                  Mary 
                  Andrews 
               <interp inst="t17560915-13-person110" type="surname" value="Andrews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-13-person110" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-13-person110" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to the prosecutor. I heard Ridout confess he took the tankard from the inside of our bar, and gave it to Prosser; and Prosser said that he and an old cobler at St. Giles's Pound sold it to one Woodhouse for a guinea, that they two divided the money, and Ridout had nothing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-13-person111">
                  Edward 
                  Todd 
               <interp inst="t17560915-13-person111" type="surname" value="Todd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-13-person111" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-13-person111" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a fellow soldier with the prisoner Prosser. On Tuesday night the 15th of August I was standing at my barrack door in the Savoy; (Prosser's barrack was over mine.) I heard something fall. I step'd out and saw something shine. I took it up and held it to a lamp, and saw it was a cover to a silver tankard. Prosser said, that is mine, give it me; which I did. I said to him next morning, do you intend to make a good hand of it? take care of yourself. When we were in St. James's Park, I told one or two of my comrades of it, and said, I fear'd he did not come honestly by it. Then I and two others went to his barrack, and opened the place where he lay; but found nothing. It got to the sergeant major's car, who sent for me. Then I was ordered to go to the colonel next morning; and there I related the whole affair. He ordered the corporal and I to go and confine the prisoner in the Savoy; which we did. He was taken before justice St. Lawrence, where he said the cover was tin. Ridout being there, was asked whether Prosser was the person concerned with him? He said, he was. Then Prosser own'd he carried the tankard to a cobler; that the cobler carried it to the house of one Woodhouse in Oxford-Road, and brought out a guinea for it, gave him a half guinea; and kept the other himself.</p>
               <p>The prisoners had nothing to say in their defence.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17560915-13-verdict74" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560915-13-verdict74" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17560915-13-punish75" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560915-13-punish75" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-13-defend105 t17560915-13-punish75"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-13-defend107 t17560915-13-punish75"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
