<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17521026-19">
               <interp inst="t17521026-19" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521026-19" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521026-19" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17521026"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521026-19" type="date" value="17521026"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17521026-19-off104-c123" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521026-19-defend157 t17521026-19-off104 t17521026-19-verdict107"></join>
         
               <p>519. 
               <persName id="t17521026-19-defend157" type="defendantName">
                  Honor 
                  Furness , otherwise <rs id="t17521026-19-alias-2" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521026-19-defend157 t17521026-19-alias-2"></join>Geary</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-19-defend157" type="surname" value="Furness"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-19-defend157" type="given" value="Honor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-19-defend157" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17521026-19-deflabel103" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521026-19-defend157 t17521026-19-deflabel103"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17521026-19-off104" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17521026-19-off104" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-19-off104" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing one gold watch, with a chrystal seal set in gold, val. 9 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17521026-19-victim159" type="victimName">
                           Peter 
                           Brown 
                        <interp inst="t17521026-19-victim159" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17521026-19-victim159" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17521026-19-victim159" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521026-19-off104 t17521026-19-victim159"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17521026-19-cd105" type="crimeDate">Sept. 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521026-19-off104 t17521026-19-cd105"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-19-person160">
                  Peter 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17521026-19-person160" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-19-person160" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-19-person160" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the first of September, coming from the city to my home in King Street, St. Ann's, I was met with by the prisoner, about eleven o'clock at night, after I had pass'd Temple Bar. She picked me up, and carried me to the <placeName id="t17521026-19-crimeloc106">George alehouse, between St. Clement's Church and Temple Bar</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17521026-19-crimeloc106" type="placeName" value="George alehouse, between St. Clement's Church and Temple Bar"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17521026-19-crimeloc106" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521026-19-off104 t17521026-19-crimeloc106"></join>, one 
               <persName id="t17521026-19-person161">
                  Edward 
                  Black 
               <interp inst="t17521026-19-person161" type="surname" value="Black"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-19-person161" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-19-person161" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             master of it. We had some liquor, and after I had been in her company about half an hour, I miss'd my watch.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you it last?</p>
               <p>Brown. I felt it in my fob about two minutes before she picked me up.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober?</p>
               <p>Brown. I was in liquor; but knew very well what I did. I charged her with picking my pocket of it, and made a great deal of noise.</p>

               <p>Q. Was you in a publick room?</p>
               <p>Brown. No; we were in a room by ourselves. The landlord came in, I told him I had been robbed of a gold watch, and desired him to call a watchman. He said he would not; then came in a little woman, who undressed the prisoner quite to her smock; there was nothing found upon her. I was talking to the landlord, and calling, Watchman, very loud; then the prisoner slipped away. I then said to the landlord, You are a very pretty fellow. He took me by the collar, and pushed me out at the door, and shut it to. Then I called, Watch; the watchman came, I told him I had been robbed at that house, and asked him if he could not get it open? He said, he could not. I said, my cane was on the inside. Mr. Black open'd the wicket, and said, You have not paid your reckoning. I said, Let me in, and I'll pay it. He pushed my cane through, I took it, and went home. The next morning I came there again, and saw Mr. Black sweeping his door. He wanted me to come in. I said, No, I am sober now, I will not. I advertised my watch, four guineas reward, and after that at five guineas. Then there came a porter to the place where it was to be brought, who said he knew of the watch. He produces a gold watch. This is my watch.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you by it?</p>
               <p>Brown. It was brought before Justice Fielding, by 
               <persName id="t17521026-19-person162">
                  William 
                  Hammon 
               <interp inst="t17521026-19-person162" type="surname" value="Hammon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-19-person162" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-19-person162" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Are you a married man?</p>
               <p>Brown. I am, but she picked me up.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Ask him whether he did not give me that watch?</p>
               <p>Brown. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Are not you father to this child, and another that I carry. Holding a child about two years old in her arms.</p>
               <p>Brown. I never saw the prisoner before that night.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Did not you come to my lodgings, and fetch me from thence to the George?</p>
               <p>Brown. She picked me up in the street. I never saw her before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-19-person163">
                  Thomas 
                  Murphet 
               <interp inst="t17521026-19-person163" type="surname" value="Murphet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-19-person163" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-19-person163" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mrs. Bibby, a pawnbroker in Stanhope Street. The prisoner brought a gold watch, something like this. I can't swear this is it. I delivered it to Thomas Bibby, my fellow servant.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it advertised then?</p>
               <p>Murphet. No, it was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it not advertised before you parted with it out of your shop?</p>
               <p>Murphet. I did not know that it was.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175210260010"></xptr>Q. What did you lend upon it?</p>
               <p>Murphet. I lent six guineas upon it.</p>
               <p>Q. What is it worth?</p>
               <p>Murphet. I don't know.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it worth ten pounds?</p>
               <p>Murphet. I don't know the value of it.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know how to lend your money upon goods if you don't know the value of them ?</p>
               <p>Murphet. 
               <persName id="t17521026-19-person164">
                  Thomas 
                  Bibby 
               <interp inst="t17521026-19-person164" type="surname" value="Bibby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-19-person164" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-19-person164" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             lent the money.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it delivered to him on purpose to have it sold, or parted with, there having been some rumour of its being a stolen watch?</p>
               <p>Murphet. She said she brought it from a gentleman.</p>
               <p>Q. Who paid the money again?</p>
               <p>Murphet. I don't know.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Murphet. We did; she once before brought a gold watch, and a gentleman and she had it out again.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her employment?</p>
               <p>Murphet. I don't know that.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a gentleman was that who came with her?</p>
               <p>Murphet. I can't say what sort of a gentleman he was.</p>
               <p>Q. What have you dealt with her before for?</p>
               <p>Murphet. We have for small things.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-19-person165">
                  Thomas 
                  Bibby 
               <interp inst="t17521026-19-person165" type="surname" value="Bibby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-19-person165" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-19-person165" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to my sister-in-law. Her name is Bibby. The prisoner pawned this watch at our shop.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it advertised when you took it in?</p>
               <p>Bibby. There was a watch advertised the day after which was made at Paris; but it did not answer to this, because there was no seal to this.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this made at Paris?</p>
               <p>Bibby. It was.</p>

               <p>Q. Did she fetch it away, or did you go to her with it, after you read the advertisement?</p>
               <p>Bibby. I went to her, and asked her how she got it; she said, she came by it very honestly.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the advertisement lead you to go to her?</p>
               <p>Bibby. It did.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you not to send for the person that advertised it, instead of going to the prisoner, that he might give proper descriptions of it?</p>
               <p>Bibby. I did not think it to be the same, upon account of the hour hand not being described. I told her of the advertisement. She said, it was quite a false, and that she had it of a gentleman whom she knew very well.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you think she came honestly by it?</p>
               <p>Bibby. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Who paid you the money back for it?</p>
               <p>Bibby. I went with her into the city to a gentleman who is here in court.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to go with her, to have it replaced from your shop into the hands of another ?</p>
               <p>Bibby. She said, rather than we should be any way fearful, she had a friend in the city would lend her the money.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know what business she was of?</p>
               <p>Bibby. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you carry the other watch you speak of back to her for her to redeem it?</p>
               <p>Bibby. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she fetch it in three or four days?</p>
               <p>Bibby. I believe she did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-19-person166">
                  John 
                  Oakley 
               <interp inst="t17521026-19-person166" type="surname" value="Oakley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-19-person166" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-19-person166" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am clerk to a factory in Ironmonger Lane, at Mr. Shepherd's. The prisoner and Mr. Bibby came on the fourteenth of September, about one o'clock to the Angel, and sent for me; they were up one pair of stairs. I went, the prisoner told me she had an execution against her for a small debt, which she imagined to be done in spite by some of her neighbours, and this person that was with her had passed his word for her safe return, as she told him she could borrow the money. She said the debt was six guineas. She seem'd very much distressed, and said, if I would lend her the money for three or four days, she should be bound to pray for me, and would leave this gold watch for it. She said, the person had not the money himself, or he would advance it for her.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Bibby in company at this time?</p>
               <p>Oakley. He was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say this watch was pawned to him, and he came in order to get his money?</p>
               <p>Oakley. No, not a word of that. I understood this watch was brought to me to be pledged as the first time. I lent her six guineas, and had the watch.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you deliver the money to?</p>
               <p>Oakley. I delivered it to her; Bibby had the watch. She took that from him, and gave it to me, and gave him the money. Then I call'd up the landlord to be a witness, saying to him, upon the payment of so much money, I am to deliver this watch back. This was on Thursday. On the Monday following she came to the same house in the evening, to pay me the money, and but a few hours before that a person had shewed me the paper with the advertisement, and said he was directed by some people to Ironmonger Lane. He said he understood it was, not honestly come by. I ask'd what must be done in the case? He said, your best way<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175210260011"></xptr> will be to deliver it up quietly; then he said he would go to the person that employed him, and come again to me; in the mean time she came, and paid me the money that I had lent her. I told her what had happened, she replied it was only a sudge, adding, if I was in fear, I might keep it till she came again; so I kept it for my own security.</p>
               <p>Q. Is this the same watch?</p>
               <p>Oakley. It is. Upon finding she was apprehended afterwards, I inquired of an attorney what I must do, and he said my best way would be to deliver it up; so I delivered it to Mr. Hammond, the master of the house, where she sent for me, and the attorney, and desired us to carry it to the justice, and deliver it up.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-19-person167">
                  William 
                  Hammond 
               <interp inst="t17521026-19-person167" type="surname" value="Hammond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-19-person167" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-19-person167" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Angel in Ironmonger-Lane, and remember the prisoner, and 
               <persName id="t17521026-19-person168">
                  Thomas 
                  Bibby 
               <interp inst="t17521026-19-person168" type="surname" value="Bibby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-19-person168" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-19-person168" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , coming to my house on the 15th of September; she came the 14th, and asked for Mr. Oakley, I was called up, and Mr. Oakley said, Look here, I am to return the watch upon receiving six guineas ; afterwards I carried it to Justice Fielding's.</p>
               <p>Q. Is this the same that is here produced?</p>
               <p>Hammond. I really believe it is; the hour and minute hands were gold, and Paris was at the bottom of the plate.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I don't deny but that I had the watch of the prosecutor; he gave it me. I had broke my leg and arm by a fall from a horse, and having two children, he was so kind, one day, as to call at my lodgings. I was not able to stir out of my bed, and was obliged to sell my bed, and pawn all my clothes. He told me he had no money, but he gave me the watch to pawn for three guineas; I took it, and pawned it for six, at which he was very angry, and would not take it out. I told him I would let him have the three guineas again, when my child's father came to town, but he would not agree to fetch it out. The watch was advertised, and Mr. Bibby brought it to me; then I went to Mr. Oakley, and he lent me the money, and I got the money for it again. That very night the prosecutor brought me from my lodgings up as far as the George; I asked him how far he was going to carry me, and said he might as well go to the Fountain Tavern; and he brought me into the top room. I believe he was a little in liquor. He then said, I miss my watch; I replied, Don't go to take any advantage of one you have known so long, you know you gave me the watch. He insisted upon having the watchman called, I was searched, and nothing found upon me; then he would not pay his reckoning, and the man shoved him and I out of doors; I said, Mr. Brown, you had better go home. I went home, and left him there, and was very uneasy about it, but never saw him after that till before Justice Fielding. In our unhappy way of life, it is very seldom we have witnesses by when we take money, and the like.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Upon my oath I never was with her in any place, or saw her, before that night I lost my watch.  <rs id="t17521026-19-verdict107" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17521026-19-verdict107" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
