<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17580628-12">
               <interp inst="t17580628-12" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580628-12" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580628-12" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580628"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580628-12" type="date" value="17580628"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580628-12-off66-c79" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580628-12-defend99 t17580628-12-off66 t17580628-12-verdict69"></join>
         
               <p>230. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17580628-12-defend99" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Mac Kelvey 
                  <interp inst="t17580628-12-defend99" type="surname" value="Mac Kelvey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-defend99" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-defend99" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17580628-12-off66" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-off66" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-off66" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               stealing one silver tankard, value 7 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17580628-12-victim101" type="victimName">
                           Benjamin 
                           Dorrington 
                        <interp inst="t17580628-12-victim101" type="surname" value="Dorrington"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580628-12-victim101" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580628-12-victim101" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580628-12-off66 t17580628-12-victim101"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in his dwelling-house; it was also laid, that he said 
                     <persName id="t17580628-12-person102">
                        Mac 
                        Kelvy 
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person102" type="surname" value="Kelvy"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580628-12-person102" type="given" value="Mac"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580628-12-person102" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   being in the said dwelling-house on the <rs id="t17580628-12-cd67" type="crimeDate">22d of March</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580628-12-off66 t17580628-12-cd67"></join>, about the hour of eight in the night, in the same day, did break the said dwelling-hose to get out of the same
            </rs>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580628-12-person103">
                  Benjamin 
                  Dorrington 
               <interp inst="t17580628-12-person103" type="surname" value="Dorrington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person103" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at <placeName id="t17580628-12-crimeloc68">the Castle, King-street, Cheapside, a public house</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17580628-12-crimeloc68" type="placeName" value="the Castle, King-street, Cheapside, a public house"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17580628-12-crimeloc68" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580628-12-off66 t17580628-12-crimeloc68"></join>. On the 22d of March last, the prisoner, (I believe it was) came to my house, and asked for a tankard of beer, and went into a little room, about a quarter of an hour before eight at night; he had a tankard brought to him; having a light, he cared for the news-paper, which was carried to him I believe he was there about four or five minutes; he threw out the beer, and went out with the tankard at the window.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that, did you see it?</p>
               <p>Dorrington. No, I did not, he could not one any other way out of that room, but must have been seen; and the sash was left up, which I am sure was down before he went into the room a man came immediately, and said, a man had jumped out at my window. My boy and I nt into the room directly and found it as I have- lated.</p>
               <p>Q. Who went in first ?</p>
               <p>Dorrington. The boy did.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175806280009"></xptr>Q. Are you sure he did not put up the window before you got in?</p>
               <p>Dorrington. I am sure there was not time enough for that?</p>
               <p>Q. What is the value of the tankard.</p>
               <p>Dorrington. It cost 7 l. 13 s. being twenty-five ounces, and thirteen pennyweights; we looked about to see if we could see him lurking about, but saw nothing of him; I advertised two guineas reward in the Public Advertiser, and also in the Daily Advertiser; nothing came on it. Some days after, I met a gentleman who asked me if I had heard of what I had lost; and said a gentleman had a tankard cut to pieces, and wrote me a direction where to find him, I went, it was the prisoner that had it in his possession, cut into pieces.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Dorrington. He is a broker.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you or are you not certain as to the prisoner being the man that night?</p>
               <p>Dorrington. I will not swear it.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does he live ?</p>
               <p>Dorrington. He lives in a place called the Devil's Gap, Drury-lane. I told him I was come to look at a tankard that he had got cut to pieces, and that I came from Mr. Sanders, then he shewed it me.</p>
               <p>Q. What was your opinion as to the man when you saw him at his own house?</p>
               <p>Dorrington. Then I thought he was about the size of the man that had stole my tankard; as to his face I did not see it before, but by his speech I thought he must be the man.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he say he came by the pieces?</p>
               <p>Dorrington. He told me two country-men brought it to him, and he stopped it. I asked him why he had not stopped the men as well as the tankard; he did not make any great manner of answer to that; at last he said he would let it alone for them to come again to prove it to be their property.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say it was cut to pieces when they brought it?</p>
               <p>Dorrington. He did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you charge him then?</p>
               <p>Dorrington. No, I did not; I staid till after my boy had seen him; I asked him why he had not advertised it; he said he had had it but a few days; the person that gave me directions, said he had had it nine or ten days. I lost it the 22d of March, and this was the 15th of April, that I first saw it; after this he did advertise it; I could not positively swear to it; I went again after this, and asked him if any body had been to own it; he said there had been a woman, who said, part of it was her's, but she would not swear to it; I desired him to let people publickly come for to see it; he said he would advertise it twice more.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see it advertised afterwards?</p>
               <p>Dorrington. No, I never saw it advertised above once after that: I had information he had sold it to a Jew. I went to see whether he had or not; he was not at home; I saw his wife; she said what can you want to see it any more for, you have seen it twice; the next time I saw him he said he had had the misfortune to have his house broke open, and they had stole the pieces.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this after you had heard he had sold it?</p>
               <p>Dorrington. It was; then I went to the person who informed me he had sold it, and asked him, if he could prove that the prisoner had sold it; he said he could; and could shew me the receipt; here it is (producing one.)</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he say it was stole from?</p>
               <p>Dorrington. He said it was stole out of a cupboard in the house?</p>
               <p>Q. Where had you this receipt?</p>
               <p>Dorrington. Justice Fielding obliged the Jew to deliver it; the Jew is here to be examined.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the Jew say he had done with it?</p>
               <p>Dorrington. He said he had sold it to a refiner.</p>
               <p>Q. How many pieces was it cut into?</p>
               <p>Dorrington. It was cut into sixteen; there were two pieces stuck so tenderly together, that it would come in two, so be seventeen pieces.</p>
               <p>Q. How many pieces did the Jew say there were of them he bought?</p>
               <p>Dorrington. He told me there were sixteen pieces.</p>
               <p>Q. Does the receipt mention the number?</p>
               <p>Dorrington. No, that only says a parcel of pieces.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the Jew's name?</p>
               <p>Dorrington. His name is 
               <persName id="t17580628-12-person104">
                  Joseph 
                  Knighten 
               <interp inst="t17580628-12-person104" type="surname" value="Knighten"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person104" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person104" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. When do you say you lost your tankard?</p>
               <p>Dorrington. About a quarter of an hour before eight in the evening.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175806280010"></xptr>Q. You say you cannot swear to him.</p>
               <p>Dorrington. I cannot swear to his face; but I believe he is the man that took it.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a window is yours?</p>
               <p>Dorrington. It is a sash window?</p>
               <p>Q. Had it a screw to it to keep down the sash?</p>
               <p>Dorrington. No, it had not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it easy to get out at ?</p>
               <p>Dorrington. Any body might get out at it, by putting the sash up.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner offer the pieces to you if you would swear to them?</p>
               <p>Dorrington. He did, but there had been care taken that the marks were cut out.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he advertise it ?</p>
               <p>Dorrington. It was that he had stopped a parcel of silver, and that the owner might have it again upon paying the advertisement.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580628-12-person105">
                  John 
                  Roper 
               <interp inst="t17580628-12-person105" type="surname" value="Roper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person105" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person105" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am about fourteen years of age.</p>
               <p>Q. When was you at church?</p>
               <p>Roper. I was at church about two months ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Then you do not go very often ?</p>
               <p>Roper. No, I do not now. I used to go every Sunday before I lived at a publick house.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what it is to take an oath?</p>
               <p>Roper. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you ever sworn before?</p>
               <p>Roper. I was, before justice Fielding.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the nature of an oath?</p>
               <p>Roper. It is to speak nothing but the truth ?</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what a crime it is not to speak the truth?</p>
               <p>Roper. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Roper. I live with Mr. Dorrington.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Roper. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you first see him?</p>
               <p>Roper. I first saw him the twenty-second of March.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure of that?</p>
               <p>Roper. I am quite sure.</p>
               <p>Q. How, and where did you see him? tell your story, be careful, and keep to what is strictly truth.</p>
               <p>Roper. That I will. The prisoner came into my master's house, and as he was going into a little room, I lighted him in with a candle, and asked him what he would please to have, he said a tankard of beer: I went and asked my master whether I should carry a silver tankard; I had left the door open, and my master looked in, then he said yes, I might. I carried him a tankard; then he asked for the news-paper; I carried it in, and he shut the door, and in about four or five minutes after that, he was gone out at the window.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he dressed?</p>
               <p>Roper. He had a blue surtout coat on.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a waistcoat ?</p>
               <p>Roper. I could not see that, his coat was buttoned over it.</p>
               <p>Q. How else was he dressed ?</p>
               <p>Roper. He had a shabby cocked up hat, and a brown cut wig.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he sit with his hat on or off?</p>
               <p>Roper. He sat with it on.</p>
               <p>Court. Consider what you are about; the man's life depends greatly upon what you say; be careful, and speak nothing but what you know.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there a fire in the room?</p>
               <p>Roper. No, there was a coachman came in, and told us there was a man gone out at the Window. I went into the room, and my master followed me, and found the man and tankard were gone, the sash was put up, and the curtains drawed close.</p>
               <p>Court. Mention the words the coachman said.</p>
               <p>Roper. He said what are not the doors wide enough that people are forced to come out of the window?</p>
               <p>Q. How long was this after you had carried the news-paper in?</p>
               <p>Roper. This was about four or five minutes after.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you that four or five minutes?</p>
               <p>Roper. I was sitting at one of the boxes in the tap-room.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was your master?</p>
               <p>Roper. He was in the bar, I saw him there.</p>
               <p>Q. Supposing your master had not been in the bar, might not the man have come out at the door without your seeing him?</p>
               <p>Roper. I believe he might.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen that man after this?</p>
               <p>Roper. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Where?</p>
               <p>Roper. I saw him come out of his house, and another man with him, and as soon as he saw me he ran down a court.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175806280011"></xptr>Q. What sort of a man was it?</p>
               <p>Roper. I did not mind him much; that man lives next door to him.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that?</p>
               <p>Roper. Because I had seen him go in there before.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you been there before ?</p>
               <p>Roper. I had been after the prisoner the day before, but he was not at home.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see that other man the day before ?</p>
               <p>Roper. I believe I did.</p>
               <p>Q. What is he ?</p>
               <p>Roper. I don't know.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure he is the man you saw the day before?</p>
               <p>Roper. I am not sure, but I think he is the man.</p>
               <p>Q. If you had seen that man the day before, and believed him to be the same man that lives next door to the prisoner, describe what sort of a man he is.</p>
               <p>Roper. He is not very tall, he had a brown coat on the next day, but had a blue one on then. The prisoner said to him, as soon as he set eyes on me, d - n you this is our way, and turned down as I mentioned before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the other man go with him?</p>
               <p>Roper. They both ran together; we went round the other way to see to take them, but they got into some house.</p>
               <p>Q. What should make the other man run?</p>
               <p>Roper. I do not know, they were both going together, they were not running when I first saw them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the prisoner again that day?</p>
               <p>Roper. No, I did not, he was taken up that night; my master went to justice Fielding directly after I had seen the prisoner and knew him.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see the prisoner after this?</p>
               <p>Roper. I saw him the next day at justice Fielding's.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he dress'd?</p>
               <p>Roper. He was dress'd in a brown coat; I knew him again.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you swear to him there?</p>
               <p>Roper. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say?</p>
               <p>Roper. He did not say any thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he not tell you you was mistaken ?</p>
               <p>Roper. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he took the tankard?</p>
               <p>Roper. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Or that he leaped out of the window?</p>
               <p>Roper. No.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure he is the man?</p>
               <p>Roper. I am sure.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he run away when you saw him the second time?</p>
               <p>Roper. He did.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was this after the tankard was lost.</p>
               <p>Roper. I do not know exactly.</p>
               <p>Q. How long do you believe it was?</p>
               <p>Roper. I believe about a month after. He was examined the 18th of May, and that was the day before that I saw him run.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you call running ?</p>
               <p>Roper. He laid hold on the other man's arm, and made off as fast as he could; the gentleman that was with me saw it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he give no account how he came by the tankard before the justice?</p>
               <p>Roper. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in the room all the while?</p>
               <p>Roper. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the justice ask him that?</p>
               <p>Roper. No, I did not hear the justice ask him any questions; I am a little hard of hearing.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you before the justice any other time?</p>
               <p>Roper. I was every time he was there. I was there the next day.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear what the justice said to him then ?</p>
               <p>Roper. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in the room all the time?</p>
               <p>Roper. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you apprehend from what you saw that the justice was talking to him?</p>
               <p>Roper. I believe he was.</p>
               <p>Q. During that four or five minutes you say he was in the room at your master's, did no body call for any beer?</p>
               <p>Roper. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you sit at the same place all that time ?</p>
               <p>Roper. I did, and never stirred out of it till I went to go into the room.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175806280012"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17580628-12-person106">
                  John 
                  Disdel 
               <interp inst="t17580628-12-person106" type="surname" value="Disdel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person106" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person106" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the prisoner's house on the 16th of May, the last witness was with me. Just before we went into the house, I said to the boy, be sure if there is any men there, take particular notice of their faces, and be punctual in what you say. When we came into the room, there was a little back room, there sat the prisoner at the bar and another man along with him, seemingly at breakfast; it was so dark I could not distinguish faces. When we went out, I said to the boy, you could be no judge where you stood. No the boy said, but he said that was much such a man, the nearest to me. We went over the way, and staid some time, the prisoner at the bar and another man came out of the house and walked pretty fast. I and the boy went after them, and the boy ran by them. As soon as the boy got by the man that was with the prisoner, he turned and stared in the prisoner's face; the prisoner look'd at the boy's face, and catched at the other man's sleeve, and away they went down a turning. I said to the boy, do you know either of them; the boy said the biggest in the brown coat, is the man that I served with the tankard of beer. I went down the next turning, and the boy with me, and had they come through where they turned down, we should have met with them, but we could see nothing of them. I went and look'd down Bow-street, and am sure it was impossible for them to get down that street before I got where I did. I fancy they must go into some house.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you before the justice?</p>
               <p>Disdel. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the justice ask him any questions ?</p>
               <p>Disdel. He asked him what was become of the tankard ? he answered he did not know. The justice asked him what Jew he sold it to; he made no answer to any purpose, but said if it was Mr. Dorrington's tankard, he must have it again, that was all he said he knew about it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say any thing of his being in Mr. Dorrington's house and calling for a tankard of beer.</p>
               <p>Disdel. He denied that.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Then you say you saw the prisoner and another man in a dark room?</p>
               <p>Disdel. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they come out publickly at the fore door afterwards?</p>
               <p>Disdel. They did.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in the dark room?</p>
               <p>Disdel. No, I was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not he before the justice give an account how he came by the tankard ?</p>
               <p>Disdel. I don't remember he did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the justice ask him where he had it?</p>
               <p>Disdel. There were some words pass'd but I cannot recollect what.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580628-12-person107">
                  Thomas 
                  Hampshire 
               <interp inst="t17580628-12-person107" type="surname" value="Hampshire"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person107" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person107" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a peruke-maker; I was coming by the Castle in King's-street, I think, on the 22d of March; a man jumped out at the windows and almost knocked me into the kennel; I said, what is there not room enough, but you must come out at the window! A man that was by went in and told the people of the house that there was a man had jumped out at the window.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you swear to that man?</p>
               <p>Hampshire. No, I cannot.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580628-12-person108">
                  Joseph 
                  Knighten 
               <interp inst="t17580628-12-person108" type="surname" value="Knighten"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person108" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person108" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I bought some old silver of the prisoner at the bar; it was a broken silver tankard.</p>
               <p>Q. How many pieces were there of it?</p>
               <p>Knighten. Seventeen pieces, and two small slips.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the weight of it?</p>
               <p>Keighten. It weighed eighteen ounces and sixteen pennyweights; it was tied up in a handkerchief.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you look upon it to be a whole tankard?</p>
               <p>Knighten. No, I suppose it was not, there was no name, no proof, no mark, nothing at all, if there had been the whole tankard, there must have been the mark, name, or proof.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you buy it of him?</p>
               <p>Knighten. I do not know what time I bought it, the receipt will shew that:</p>
               <p>The receipt read:</p>
               <p>May 5, 1758. Then received of 
               <persName id="t17580628-12-person109">
                  Joseph 
                  Knighten 
               <interp inst="t17580628-12-person109" type="surname" value="Knighten"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person109" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person109" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , four pounds four shillings, for silver sold and delivered this day, in full of all demands,</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580628-12-person110">
                  John
                   Mac Kelvey
               <interp inst="t17580628-12-person110" type="surname" value="Mac Kelvey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person110" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person110" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175806280013"></xptr>Knighten. This is the receipt.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. What money did Dorrington offer to you?</p>
               <p>Knighten. I shew'd my receipt to Mr. Dorrington, he said he would give me a note of hand of twenty pounds while he kept it. I said I would not part with my receipt for a hundred pounds. This was at Mr. Dorrington's house; I went away, and in the afternoon, going by his house again, crying old cloaths about, they called me in. I asked if they had heard any farther about it, they said no. About five or six days after that, they took me with a constable, and brought me to justice Fielding's, and from thence to goal, and put me an iron on.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he take you up for?</p>
               <p>Knighten. I do not know, I was cleared on the Monday.</p>
               <p>Q. to Dorrington. On what account was the Jew taken up?</p>
               <p>Dorrington. He would not let me have the receipt to shew to Mr. Fielding on any consideration, and the justice desired he should be examined.</p>
               <p>Counsel for the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you charge this Jew with stealing your tankard ?</p>
               <p>Dorrington. No I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580628-12-person111">
                  Alice 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17580628-12-person111" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person111" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person111" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going by Mr. Dorrington's house, and a man came out at the window.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know whether the prisoner was the man or not?</p>
               <p>Jones. I do not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580628-12-person112">
                  Christopher 
                  Askew 
               <interp inst="t17580628-12-person112" type="surname" value="Askew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person112" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person112" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw Mr. Dorrington the next morning after he had lost the tankard; he told me he had lost a tankard; I said I was very near losing one myself last night.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Askew. I keep the 
               <persName id="t17580628-12-person113">
                  Catherine 
                  Wheel 
               <interp inst="t17580628-12-person113" type="surname" value="Wheel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person113" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person113" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Bishopsgate-street, the prisoner at the bar came in that night about nine o'clock, and called for a negus in a tankard; my wife said to me, I have some suspicion of that gentleman, I don't choose to send him in a silver tankard. She sent it in in a China quart mug. I went in about three or four minutes after, he asked me to drink, there was very little left. I wondered it should be gone so soon I went out again, my house was very full at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he alone?</p>
               <p>Askew. Yes, and went into a room by himself, in the middle of my house. I went in again in about three minutes after, and the liquor was all gone; he called for the boy to shew him up the yard. After he was got to the necessary-house he put the candle out, and bid him go about his business. I imagine he wanted to see whether there was any back way out. After that he came in again, and called for a tankard of beer, and a welch rabbit, they were carried him. My wife being suspicious of him, bid me look out a little sharp. After he had had it about five or six minutes, the beer was drank up, the rabbit eat, the window throw'd up, and the curtains drawn back, and he had got the tankard in his hand, but happily prevented, I did not lose mine.</p>

               <p>Q. Was not you sash up before he went into the room?</p>
               <p>Askew. I am positive it was not; there was a pin to fasten it down, that he took out to throw up the sash.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He swore before the justice that I called for pen, ink, and paper, that is contrary to what he swears now.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I shall call some witnesses.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580628-12-person114">
                  Robert 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17580628-12-person114" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person114" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I deal a little in linen now and then.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Brown. I live in Drury-lane.</p>
               <p>Q. How near do you live to the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Brown. I did live next door to him; in March last, one 
               <persName id="t17580628-12-person115">
                  Edward 
                  Thornton 
               <interp inst="t17580628-12-person115" type="surname" value="Thornton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person115" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person115" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             of Tring in Hertfordshire, being an acquaintance of mine for ten or eleven years, he wanted me to buy an old silver tankard of him; I did not choose to buy it, he said do you know of any acquaintance that I can sell it to; I said upon my word I do not; we went over to the White-horse, and had a tankard of beer; I said there is a broker that lives at next door, perhaps he will buy it of you. I went to him, and said here is an acquaintance of mine come out of the country, has got a tankard to sell; he said he would look at it; then I went to my friend and he said he would buy it; he came two<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175806280014"></xptr> nights after, and brought his son and another man along with him.</p>
               <p>Q. What was that other man's name?</p>
               <p>Brown. His son said that man's name was 
               <persName id="t17580628-12-person116">
                  Richard 
                  Watkins 
               <interp inst="t17580628-12-person116" type="surname" value="Watkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person116" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person116" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a shoemaker in Tring, they shew'd Mr. 
               <persName id="t17580628-12-person117">
                  Mac 
                  Kelvey 
               <interp inst="t17580628-12-person117" type="surname" value="Kelvey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person117" type="given" value="Mac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person117" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the tankard tied up in a handkerchief; there were sixteen pieces, and one of them almost in two; they made a sort of bargain about it, and he gave him a crown earnest before my face, and if it was not honestly come by, he was to have his crown again; he stopt it after that. He said I'll stop it till you bring sufficient proof how you came by it. I went down to Tring after him with a warrant granted by justice Fielding, and took another man along with me; we got it back'd by Esquire Walker of Barkhamstead. While we were at Tring, we found there was word sent to Thornton to keep out of the way. We staid one night, but could not take him. I went down after that, and took Thornton, and brought him to Newgate, where he now is.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580628-12-person118">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17580628-12-person118" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person118" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person118" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the last witness, on Friday morning Thornton and two other men came to my husband, and talked and drank together, but what they said I know not, my husband said this man has lived very well, he owes me some money, and I expect now to get some. They never came that day they appointed, (I mean the countryman) the next day they came and knocked at the door; I said my husband was not at home, but he had spoke to the man at next door, who would buy the tankard; then he said he would bring it in two or three hours, but he never came that day. When I came home I went to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17580628-12-person119">
                  Mac 
                  Kelvey 
               <interp inst="t17580628-12-person119" type="surname" value="Kelvey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person119" type="given" value="Mac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person119" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's shop, he had borrowed a pair of scales. I said to my husband, has he brought the tankard? he said yes, he has brought sixteen pieces, and one almost cut in two. I ran to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17580628-12-person120">
                  Mac 
                  Kelvey 
               <interp inst="t17580628-12-person120" type="surname" value="Kelvey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person120" type="given" value="Mac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person120" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and said suppose he has stole it. Then I went to the alehouse, and sat down and drank with them; the young man was very much upon the watch. In came Mr. Thornton, and swore he would punish Mr. 
               <persName id="t17580628-12-person121">
                  Mac 
                  Kelvey 
               <interp inst="t17580628-12-person121" type="surname" value="Kelvey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person121" type="given" value="Mac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person121" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             for stopping of it. They ran away in a great hurry, affrighted out of their wits. I would not look at the tankard. Mr. 
               <persName id="t17580628-12-person122">
                  Mac 
                  Kelvey 
               <interp inst="t17580628-12-person122" type="surname" value="Kelvey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person122" type="given" value="Mac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person122" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             advertised it, I believe the Monday following.</p>
               <p>Q. What day was it brought to sell?</p>
               <p>E. Brown. I believe it was brought to sell on the Wednesday night; I remember Mr. 
               <persName id="t17580628-12-person123">
                  Mac 
                  Kelvey 
               <interp inst="t17580628-12-person123" type="surname" value="Kelvey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person123" type="given" value="Mac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person123" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             made us come in and look at the paper it was advertised in.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say any body had been to see it, and had described it?</p>
               <p>E. Brown. I believe he said some body had been to see it, but they did not give right descriptions of it. I think he said one man had offered him two guineas to deliver it up.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know one 
               <persName id="t17580628-12-person124">
                  John 
                  Spensley 
               <interp inst="t17580628-12-person124" type="surname" value="Spensley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person124" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person124" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>E. Brown. No.</p>
               <p>Court. Look at that man, (pointing to him.)</p>
               <p>E. Brown. I know him.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you say to him you could swear, if you had a mind to swear?</p>
               <p>E. Brown. I don't know what you mean.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you say you could swear away two men's lives?</p>
               <p>E. Brown. No, I never said any such thing in my life?</p>
               <p>Q. What did you say to him?</p>
               <p>E. Brown. When he said it was about a tankard, I said I knew very well about it, because it was brought by a person that was my husband's acquaintance.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is this ago?</p>
               <p>E. Brown. This was about five or six days after the tankard was brought. The prisoner was my neighbour, I have nothing to say against him in the world.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you say nothing else?</p>
               <p>E. Brown. I said my husband and Mr. 
               <persName id="t17580628-12-person125">
                  Mac 
                  Kelvey 
               <interp inst="t17580628-12-person125" type="surname" value="Kelvey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person125" type="given" value="Mac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person125" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             were country people, and drank together and so, and if I had known what you wanted, I could have sent you there before.</p>
               <p>Mr. Sanders. Mr. 
               <persName id="t17580628-12-person126">
                  Mac 
                  Kelvey 
               <interp inst="t17580628-12-person126" type="surname" value="Kelvey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person126" type="given" value="Mac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person126" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             brought an advertisement to me, and desired I would alter it for him; he told me he had stopped a silver tankard from a person; he left the advertisement with me, but he did not call for it again.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you it was in pieces?</p>
               <p>Sanders. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you understand it to be in pieces by the advertisement?</p>
               <p>Sanders. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen his advertisement in the paper?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175806280015"></xptr>Sanders. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it like that?</p>
               <p>Sanders. No, it was not, it did not say a parcel of pieces, but a silver tankard.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you alter his advertisement?</p>
               <p>Sanders. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that ever printed?</p>
               <p>Sanders. No, he never came for it.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was it after he brought an advertisement to you, that there was one in the paper?</p>
               <p>Sanders. I believe it was five or six days after.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you inform Mr. Dorrington of it?</p>
               <p>Sanders. I did, I was in Fleet-street, and met with Mr. Dorrington, and hearing that he had lost a silver tankard, told him of this, and gave him directions to go to the prisoner; this was the first of Mr. Dorrington's knowing of it I suppose, I knew the prisoner did not keep it a secret, but spoke of it in public company.</p>
               <p>Mr. Spensley. Mrs. Brown, in a public tap room, told it before me and another person ( when she heard what they were upon) that Mr. 
               <persName id="t17580628-12-person127">
                  Mac 
                  Kelvey 
               <interp inst="t17580628-12-person127" type="surname" value="Kelvey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person127" type="given" value="Mac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person127" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and my husband were two great rogues, and it is in my power to hang them both, for a thing that I have in my custody.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Spensley. I am a constable.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take the prisoner up?</p>
               <p>Spensley. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you not expect a reward if he is convicted ?</p>
               <p>Spensley. I expect none; as to Mr. Brown's character, it is noted all over London.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580628-12-person128">
                  Samuel 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17580628-12-person128" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person128" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person128" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the White-horse, Clare market; I have known the prisoner four or five years, he mentioned to me he had stopped a tankard, which he hoped to get something by.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he mention the time he stopped it?</p>
               <p>Harris. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he had advertised it?</p>
               <p>Harris. He did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say any body had been and claimed it?</p>
               <p>Harris. No.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Harris. I never heard but that he is an honest man, he worked very hard for his living.</p>
               <p>Mr. Douglass. I have known him thirty years ago, we were schoolfellows.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Douglass. Always a very good character; I always looked upon him to be a very honest industrious man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580628-12-person129">
                  William 
                  Carr 
               <interp inst="t17580628-12-person129" type="surname" value="Carr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person129" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person129" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him six years; I always looked upon him to be a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580628-12-person130">
                  Charles 
                  Steward 
               <interp inst="t17580628-12-person130" type="surname" value="Steward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person130" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person130" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about twenty five years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Steward. I never heard any thing to blast his character in my life, I always found him honest, I have employed him.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you ?</p>
               <p>Steward. I am a carpenter by trade.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580628-12-person131">
                  John 
                  Denham 
               <interp inst="t17580628-12-person131" type="surname" value="Denham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person131" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-person131" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him nine or ten months, he stopped two pewter plates of mine, and sent to my house; I went and shew'd him a pattern plate, he said I am very right, they are yours, and produced them, and delivered them to me. I would have given him something for his care, he said he had been at no expence, and he desired none of me, and would not take any thing.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17580628-12-verdict69" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580628-12-verdict69" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
