<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570914-33">
               <interp inst="t17570914-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-33" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570914"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-33" type="date" value="17570914"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570914-33-off224-c349" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-33-defend424 t17570914-33-off224 t17570914-33-verdict229"></join>
         
               <p>341. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17570914-33-defend424" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Goldwell 
                  <interp inst="t17570914-33-defend424" type="surname" value="Goldwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-33-defend424" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-33-defend424" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17570914-33-deflabel223" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-33-defend424 t17570914-33-deflabel223"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17570914-33-off224" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570914-33-off224" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-33-off224" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing three silver tea spoons, value 5 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               <persName id="t17570914-33-victim425" type="victimName">
                  William 
                  Titcome 
               <interp inst="t17570914-33-victim425" type="surname" value="Titcome"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-33-victim425" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-33-victim425" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-33-off224 t17570914-33-victim425"></join>
                  </persName>
             , <rs id="t17570914-33-cd225" type="crimeDate">August 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-33-off224 t17570914-33-cd225"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-33-person426">
                  Margaret 
                  Titcome 
               <interp inst="t17570914-33-person426" type="surname" value="Titcome"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-33-person426" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-33-person426" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My husband's name is William, we live in <placeName id="t17570914-33-crimeloc226">Vintry Ward</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17570914-33-crimeloc226" type="placeName" value="Vintry Ward"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17570914-33-crimeloc226" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-33-off224 t17570914-33-crimeloc226"></join>; he is a <rs id="t17570914-33-viclabel227" type="occupation">fruiterer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-33-victim425 t17570914-33-viclabel227"></join>. The prisoner at the bar was <rs id="t17570914-33-deflabel228" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-33-defend424 t17570914-33-deflabel228"></join> to me, her time was up, and she was going away.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had she liv'd with you?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. Five months and four days. I search'd her box and found three silver tea spoons tied up in a cloth, ( produced in court and deposed to.) I turn'd to the light, and read W. M. T. I said how came you by these. She said they are none of yours. I said most certainly they are mine. She snatch'd them out of my hand, and d - n'd me for a bitch, and said I had put them there, and threw them at me. I charged the constable with her, and she was ball'd; while she was in my service I missed several things, and Mr. Titcome insisted upon my looking into her box, but I found none of them.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Had not the prisoner two or three times given you warning?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175709140039"></xptr>M. Titcome. Once she did, but then she desired to stay again as I lay in; she said as she had liv'd with me before, there might be some advantage, and she might as well have it as a stranger.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever search her box before?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never see it open?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. No, never in my life before.</p>
               <p>Q. Had not you words together ?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. No, never. She had words once with my husband on a Sunday, which is a very improper day.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never call her names?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never call her harlot?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. No, nor never had such an expression in my mouth.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Mr. Gaston?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. I do, he is a lodger of mine.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she not mention something about him to you?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. No, never till after she had stolen the spoons. I told her of a man that came after her in a morning several times. She said she might as well be intimate with a single gentleman as I that was married with Mr. Gaston, that was a batchelor; these were all the words that I had with her, good, bad, or indifferent.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever charge her about a napkin?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. I lost a great many, and when I lost them she said she should give herself no trouble about them.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not you in a passion with her about them?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. No.</p>
               <p>Q. How many tea-spoons had you?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. I had no more than five in the kitchen.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see these three spoons before?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. They were at my table at breakfast that day.</p>
               <p>Q. Immediately before this was there any quarrel or words past between you?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. I was in no passion with her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she not say, upon her being charged with the napkin, she would not stay any longer with you?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she not, upon these words, send for a porter to take away her box?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. She herself went for a porter at seven o'clock at night, and she drag'd the box out of her room, to have it taken away unknown to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the porter come?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you then?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. I was drinking tea in the kitchen.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was with you?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. A girl that attended my child.</p>
               <p>Q. Was nobody else there?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not Mr. Gaston there?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. He came in after tea.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he not in the kitchen before the porter came in?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. He was.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the porter's name ?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. His name is Augustine Strickson.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not the trunk brought down for you to search it?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. No; the girl told me where she had drag'd it, so I desired the prisoner to leave it, till I had time to look over it.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath whether you saw her offer to take it away ?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. The girl call'd and told me she was going to take it away, and I found it on the top of the stairs, moved out of her room.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she desire you to open her box?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. She did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you kneel down on your knees to open it?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. No, she opened it herself in my presence.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you search it?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. I took out gowns, petticoats, and other things, till I came to the middle of the trunk; where I found these spoons, wrap'd up in some old stockings, with a forehead cloth.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your back towards her or your face, when you took them out?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. She stood facing me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not she herself say, if they were your spoons, you had put them there?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you missed them?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. No, I did not miss them, till I found them.</p>
               <p>Q. What was done with them after breakfast?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. She put them in the corner cupboard herself.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you drink tea that afternoon in the kitchen?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you miss them then?</p>
               <p>M. Titcome. No; I had two more spoons.</p>
               <p>Q. Who drank tea with you?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175709140040"></xptr>M. Titcome. The girl that attended my child.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-33-person427">
                  Walter 
                  Gaston 
               <interp inst="t17570914-33-person427" type="surname" value="Gaston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-33-person427" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-33-person427" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a coal merchant. On the 3d of August I came home about seven in the evening, to my lodgings, at the prosecutor's, where I saw the maid's trunk standing on the top of the stairs. I enquired who belong'd to it, and they told me the prisoner had convey'd it there. While we were talking in came the prisoner with a porter. Mrs. Titcome told him he should not carry the box out without its being searched. Said the maid I will not have it searched without the constable. We told her, as she said she had nothing in the box but what was her own, she had better let it be searched. She offer'd me the key. I said, Naney, you had better do it yourself. The lid was thrown open, and Mrs. Titcome took out gowns, petticoats, and many-things, till she came to these stockings. Seeing them done up at the ends, and bulky in the middle, she open'd them, and there were three silver tea spoons in the middle. She turn'd herself to the light and read the letters which were on them. Said I, Naney, how came you by these spoons? She said they are none of her's. Said she, here is my name upon them. Then the prisoner in a great rage took them and threw them in the middle of the kitchen, and said, d - n you for a b - h, you put them there to make me a thief.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at tea with Mrs. Titcome?</p>
               <p>Gaston. I saw the tea things standing when I came in, but whether she had drank tea or not I don't know.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you come of your own accord, or was you sent for?</p>
               <p>Gaston. I was sent for home, but by whom I don't know.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you when you was sent for?</p>
               <p>Gaston. At the Castle-Tavern, in Lombard-Street.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the husband when you came home?</p>
               <p>Gaston. He was in the warehouse below.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not the husband as proper a man as you to be sent for, on this occasion?</p>
               <p>Gaston. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think the prosecutrix would be guilty of putting these spoons into her trunk, in order to charge her with a robbery?</p>
               <p>Gaston. Very far from it. She is as sober and modest a woman as any living.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-33-person428">
                  William 
                  Richards 
               <interp inst="t17570914-33-person428" type="surname" value="Richards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-33-person428" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-33-person428" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable. Mr. Titcome came for me. I went to his house, and he told me the maid had rob'd him of three silver spoons. All was over before I came there.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you with her before my Lord-mayor?</p>
               <p>Richards. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did my Lord-mayor or admit her to bail?</p>
               <p>Richards. Yes.</p>
               <p>Mr. Titcome. I am a fruiterer and dealer in cyder. I am often in town and often out. I came home, and my wife satisfied me she had lost several things. I told my wife to discharge the maid at night. After dinner I sat down in a chair, between sleeping and waking, but I really think in my heart I saw the silver tea spoons in my maid's hands, as she sat by the dresser, on the farther side of the kitchen, about three in the afternoon.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Augustine Strickson. I am the porter that was sent for to carry the prisoner's things away. I went with her into the room, there were Mrs. Titcome, Mr. Gaston, and herself; there was a debate between them some time before the box was look'd into; either the prisoner or Mrs. Titcome desired me to draw the trunk to the window. Mrs. Titcome said she would see it search'd, and I drew it thither.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you first see it?</p>
               <p>Strickson. I first saw it in the passage, at the head of the stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. What were the words that passed between them ?</p>
               <p>Strickson. There was an accusation concerning Mr. Gaston and Mrs. Titcome.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the girl do or say about the key?</p>
               <p>Strickson. She laid the key on the trunk, and said, there is the key if you will open it. Said Mrs. Titcome, I shall not open it till such time as a constable comes. I made answer, I imagine there is no call, madam, for this trouble, for I believe the girl has nothing there that she is afraid or ashamed of; said I to the girl, open it yourself immediately, which she did willingly.</p>
         
               <p>The Remainder of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17570914-33">
                  <interp inst="t17570914-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17570914-33" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17570914-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570914"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17570914-33" type="date" value="17570914"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175709140041"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON, And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 14th, Thursday the 15th, Friday the 16th, Saturday the 17th, and Monday the 19th of SEPTEMBER.</p>
                  <p>In the Thirty-first Year of His MAJESTY'S Reign. NUMBER VII. PART III. Being the Seventh SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of The Right Honble MARSHE DICKINSON, Esq; LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by J. ROBINSON, at the Golden-Lion, in Ludgate-Street, 1757.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-pence. ]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175709140042"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, and Oyer and Terminer, for the City of LONDON, and at the General 
                  <persName id="t17570914-33-person429">
                     Sessions
                  <interp inst="t17570914-33-person429" type="given" value="Sessions"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570914-33-person429" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                     </persName>
                of Gaol Delivery of Newgate, holden for the said City of LONDON, and County of MIDDLESEX, at Justice-Hall in the Old-Bailey, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Q. DID the girl take out any thing?</p>
               <p>Strickson. No, not one single thing. Mrs. Titcome come either knelt or squatted down at the end of the trunk, Mr. Gaston on her left hand, and the maid on her right. Mrs. Titcome's pretence was, to search after napkins. She took out petticoats, aprons, shifts, and a great many things, till she came to a small bundle, seemingly to me to be a pair of stockings. She arose from her knees, turn'd her back to me and the girl, and read over W. M. T. W. M. T. W. M. T. Then she turn'd about and said, Nancy, how came you by these spoons? The girl immediately dashed them out of her hand, and said, you b - h, do you want to make me a thief, as you have the rest of your servants. I observ'd she never offer'd to open the bundle till she turn'd her back upon us.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think she could read the letters without turning her back?</p>
               <p>Strickson. I really think if she had missed napkins she would have looked for them, but instead of that she said, I have f ound enough to hang you, so I shall look no farther; it is possible she might turn herself to the light, to have the benefit of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she search no farther?</p>
               <p>Strickson. She search'd no farther, neither did she attempt it, till her husband desired it to be open'd again.</p>
               <p>Q. to Gaston. Did she say, now I have found enough to hang you, I'll look no farther?</p>
               <p>Gaston. I heard no such thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Should you have heard it, had she said so?</p>
               <p>Gaston. I certainly should if she had.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember the expression of the prisoner's damning her and saying she put it in, in order to make her a thief?</p>
               <p>Gaston. Yes; Mrs. Titcome fell a crying immediately and sent for her husband, and he charged the constable with her.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Chitty. I have known the prisoner above seven years; she was servant to me about a year and a half, and behaved extremely well; I look upon her to be an honest person, very much so. I trusted her with every thing in my house.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is this ago?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Chitty. It is about two years ago. She has bore a very good character ever since. I don't think her guilty of such a crime as this.</p>
               <p>Mr. Chitty. I never heard any complaint of her while she lived with me. I believe her to be a very honest person. She has lain in my house ever since this accusation, and might have taken any thing, for nothing was put out of the way on her account. She lay in my house last night.</p>
               <p>Mr. Butler. The prisoner lived servant with me near a year and a half, since she came from Mr. Chitty's. She is a very honest faithful servant, and is as good a girl as ever came into a house. She has been at my house several days and nights since. I would trust her with any thing.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Butler. She behaved very honestly with me, and had the care of every thing. I have been out a considerable time together, and never missed any thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-33-person430">
                  William 
                  Bell 
               <interp inst="t17570914-33-person430" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-33-person430" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-33-person430" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her seven or eight years, ever since she came to town. She has been at my house frequently, and lain there several times. She has a very good character.</p>
               <p>Mr. Dunce. She was servant to me near a year. She is a very honest, sober, quiet girl, as ever came into a house.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570914-33-verdict229" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570914-33-verdict229" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
