<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17540530-1">
               <interp inst="t17540530-1" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540530-1" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540530-1" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540530"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540530-1" type="date" value="17540530"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540530-1-off1-c28" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-1-defend29 t17540530-1-off1 t17540530-1-verdict4"></join>
         
               <p>305. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17540530-1-defend29" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Grimes 
                  <interp inst="t17540530-1-defend29" type="surname" value="Grimes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-1-defend29" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-1-defend29" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17540530-1-off1" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540530-1-off1" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-1-off1" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               committing a rape upon the body
            </rs> of 
               
                  <persName id="t17540530-1-victim31" type="victimName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Salter 
                  <interp inst="t17540530-1-victim31" type="surname" value="Salter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-1-victim31" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-1-victim31" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-1-off1 t17540530-1-victim31"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17540530-1-viclabel2" type="occupation">spinster, an infant nine years of age</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-1-victim31 t17540530-1-viclabel2"></join>, on <rs id="t17540530-1-cd3" type="crimeDate">May the 17th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-1-off1 t17540530-1-cd3"></join>. ||.</p>
               <p>Jane - . The child's father and mother, Grimes and I, all live in one house let out into tenementsin John-Street, Westminster, numb. 10, and sitting at the door last Tuesday was three weeks, to the best of my knowledge, I saw 
               <persName id="t17540530-1-person32">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Salter 
               <interp inst="t17540530-1-person32" type="surname" value="Salter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-1-person32" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-1-person32" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the child, and 
               <persName id="t17540530-1-person33">
                  John 
                  Grimes 
               <interp inst="t17540530-1-person33" type="surname" value="Grimes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-1-person33" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-1-person33" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , go up the street together; but where they went I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was it?</p>
               <p>Jane - . It might be between two and three in the afternoon. They had been gone about three hours, before I saw the child come back again. She set herself down over-against the door, threw her apron over her head, and looked very solitary, but I knew not what was the matter with her then; and last Tuesday was a fortnight the child was examined by a surgeon, whose name is Clark. She was very bad in her private parts, and I observed she looked to be very sore.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she seem to be tore?</p>
               <p>J. - . No, not very much, but looked very red and swelled.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any blood?</p>
               <p>J. - . No, none; but by her shift I saw she had a running upon her, though what that was I am not acquainted with.</p>
               <p>Q. Is the prisoner a married man?</p>
               <p>J. - . He is, and has been ever since he lived in our house, which is about five months; but how long before I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he any children by his wife?</p>
               <p>J. - . No.</p>
               <p>Mary Salter. I am mother to the child.</p>
               <p>Q. How old is she?</p>
               <p>M. Salter. She was nine years on the twenty-fourth of March last. I went out to wash last Tuesday morning was month, I believe, at four o' clock, and left this girl at home in my room. I came home at eight to breakfast, and the child was there then; I went to work again, and she<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175405300003"></xptr> came to me about two in the afternoon, and asked leave of me to go out with 
               <persName id="t17540530-1-person34">
                  John 
                  Grimes 
               <interp inst="t17540530-1-person34" type="surname" value="Grimes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-1-person34" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-1-person34" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to gather some willow chunks; I gave her leave, and when I came home she was in bed. About a week after, putting her on a clean shift, I observed her linnen looked not as it used to do, and examining her about where she had been, she would not confess any thing to me.</p>
               <p>Q. How did her shift appear?</p>
               <p>M. Salter. It had like corrupted matter upon it. I tied her to one of the bed-posts to make her tell who she was with.</p>
               <p>Court. You must not tell what the girl said, that is not evidence.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you examine her body?</p>
               <p>M. Salter. I did, and observed she had a very great sorness upon her.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it inward or outward?</p>
               <p>M. Salter. An inward sore in her private parts.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see a sore, or did you see something come from a sore that was out of sight?</p>
               <p>M. Salter. I saw a running come from her, she was very raw and red, and the part was larger than before. I had the child examined by Dr. Harris, who said she had a bad distemper on her. After this the prisoner was taken up, and had before Justice Manleyand then the child was examined by Mr. Clark.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-1-person35">
                  Samuel 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17540530-1-person35" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-1-person35" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-1-person35" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a surgeon, and was desired by the parents of the child to examine it on Monday or Tuesday last, but I do not know which, and I found it had got what we call a clap. Mr. Manley swore me, to whom I told the same.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any other signs upon the child than the venereal disease?</p>
               <p>Clark. I opened its private parts, but could not see any symptoms of force or violence.</p>
               <p>Q. Can a clap be got without penetration?</p>
               <p>Clark. I believe if any nastiness should lie upon a child's tender parts, it may be.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540530-1-verdict4" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540530-1-verdict4" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>, but ordered to be detained to be tried for an assault, with intent to commit a rape.</p>
            </div1>
