<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560915-45">
               <interp inst="t17560915-45" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-45" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-45" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560915"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-45" type="date" value="17560915"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560915-45-off229-c265" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-45-defend350 t17560915-45-off229 t17560915-45-verdict233"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560915-45-off230-c266" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-45-defend352 t17560915-45-off230 t17560915-45-verdict234"></join>
         
               <p>376, 377. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17560915-45-defend350" type="defendantName">
                     Catharine 
                     Lansdown 
                  <interp inst="t17560915-45-defend350" type="surname" value="Lansdown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-45-defend350" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-45-defend350" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17560915-45-defend352" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Murry 
                  <interp inst="t17560915-45-defend352" type="surname" value="Murry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-45-defend352" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-45-defend352" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             were indicted, the first for <rs id="t17560915-45-off229" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560915-45-off229" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-45-off229" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch, value 42 s. and 6 s. in money number'd
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17560915-45-victim354" type="victimName">
                     Robert 
                     Carpenter 
                  <interp inst="t17560915-45-victim354" type="surname" value="Carpenter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-45-victim354" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-45-victim354" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and the other for <rs id="t17560915-45-off230" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560915-45-off230" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-45-off230" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving the same, well knowing them to have been stolen
            </rs>, <rs id="t17560915-45-cd231" type="crimeDate">September 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-45-off229 t17560915-45-cd231"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-45-off230 t17560915-45-cd231"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-45-person355">
                  Robert 
                  Carpenter 
               <interp inst="t17560915-45-person355" type="surname" value="Carpenter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-45-person355" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-45-person355" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming along Catharine Street last Sunday was seven-night betwixt ten and eleven at night. The prisoner ask'd me if I'd give her any thing. I ask'd her what she would have? She said, give me a glass of wine. So I went with her to a house in <placeName id="t17560915-45-crimeloc232">White-Hart Yard</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17560915-45-crimeloc232" type="placeName" value="White-Hart Yard"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17560915-45-crimeloc232" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-45-off229 t17560915-45-crimeloc232"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-45-off230 t17560915-45-crimeloc232"></join>. She ask'd for a candle to go up stairs. I ask'd if I could lie there all night? Then we went up and had a pint of wine, and I paid a shilling for my bed. We went both to bed, and the next morning about five o'clock she said, she wanted to go down stairs into the yard. Then I thought I would see what a clock it was. I went to look, and found my watch and my money were gone, and my breeches were taken from under my head. She had been gone about four or five minutes. Then I jump'd out of bed, and ran down stairs directly, and told the man of the house how I had been served.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you been a sleep?</p>
               <p>Carpenter. I had.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you perceive her to meddle with your breeches ?</p>
               <p>Carpenter. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What money did you miss?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175609150026"></xptr>Carpenter. I had changed half a guinea in the house, and I missed six-shillings of it. She left me one shilling and six-pence in my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a watch was it?</p>
               <p>Carpenter. A silver watch.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you fuddled when you went to bed?</p>
               <p>Carpenter. No, I was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you had your watch and money when you went to bed?</p>
               <p>Carpenter. I am very sure of that.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you go to bed?</p>
               <p>Carpenter. About eleven o'clock. The man of the house (named 
               <persName id="t17560915-45-person356">
                  Edward 
                  Welch 
               <interp inst="t17560915-45-person356" type="surname" value="Welch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-45-person356" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-45-person356" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) and I ran about to see if we could find the prisoner, and about five in the afternoon we met with her in Drury-Lane, at the King's Head. We carried her before justice Fielding, and he committed her to prison. I went to her there last Tuesday, and Welch with me. There she told me she had given the watch to the other prisoner, Murry. He was in New-Prison at that time. She sent a letter by me to Murry since she has been in Newgate, to know of him where he had pawn'd it, and he sent his mother along with me, to the pawnbroker's. She confessed to me she had the watch and money too our of my breeches, and gave them to Murry under the table in Drury-Lane where we took her, and Murry said, he had the watch of her in the same manner, and said, he was sorry for it, and hoped we would not hurt him.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he say it was pawned?</p>
               <p>Carpenter. He said it was pawned in Leather-Lane at the Three Balls, and I went and found it ( produced in court, and deposed to.) I had advertised it, No. 622, and Scofield, London, on the dial-plate.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-45-person357">
                  William 
                  Bowyer 
               <interp inst="t17560915-45-person357" type="surname" value="Bowyer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-45-person357" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-45-person357" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am apprentice to the pawnbroker where Murry brought this watch, and pawn'd it with me on Wednesday was seven-night at night. I lent him two guineas upon it.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your master's name?</p>
               <p>Carpenter. His name is Coy.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-45-person358">
                  Edward 
                  Welch 
               <interp inst="t17560915-45-person358" type="surname" value="Welch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-45-person358" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-45-person358" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was by when the prisoner was taken, and I believe Murry was by at the time; but I did not see her deliver the watch to him. I went along with the prosecutor to Newgate, to see the prisoner Lansdown, and heard her confess she had taken the watch and given it to Murry under the table, and upon the prosecutor's saying, he would fetch out the watch and pay the money, Murry let him know where it was.</p>
               <p>Lansdown's defence.</p>
               <p>That Welch sends me out to get money for him by bringing people into his house. I met with the prosecutor, and had him home to Welch's house. We went up stairs, and he paid for a pint of wine and a bed to stay all night, and as he was to meet me again (not having money enough about him) he let me have his watch to pawn, and the next time he saw me he was to bring money, and I was to fetch it out again.</p>
               <p>Murry's defence.</p>
               <p>This woman give me the watch to pawn when I was in liquor, and I went and pawn'd it for her.</p>
               <p>Lansdown <rs id="t17560915-45-verdict233" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560915-45-verdict233" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Murry <rs id="t17560915-45-verdict234" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560915-45-verdict234" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
