<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17561208-9">
               <interp inst="t17561208-9" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561208-9" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561208-9" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17561208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561208-9" type="date" value="17561208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17561208-9-off40-c61" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-9-defend75 t17561208-9-off40 t17561208-9-verdict43"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17561208-9-off45-c61" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-9-defend75 t17561208-9-off45 t17561208-9-verdict43"></join>
         
               <p>9. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17561208-9-defend75" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Pallister 
                  <interp inst="t17561208-9-defend75" type="surname" value="Pallister"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-9-defend75" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-9-defend75" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17561208-9-off40" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561208-9-off40" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-9-off40" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one silver quart mug, value 6 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17561208-9-victim77" type="victimName">
                           George 
                           Pratt 
                        <interp inst="t17561208-9-victim77" type="surname" value="Pratt"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17561208-9-victim77" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17561208-9-victim77" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in his dwelling-house
            </rs>, <rs id="t17561208-9-cd41" type="crimeDate">September 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-9-off40 t17561208-9-cd41"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-9-off45 t17561208-9-cd41"></join>.* </p> 
               <p>George Pratt. I lost a silver quart mug on the 30th of September about ten at night; but I was very ill at the time on the bed, so can't say any thing to the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Pratt. I live in <placeName id="t17561208-9-crimeloc42">White-Hart Yard</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17561208-9-crimeloc42" type="placeName" value="White-Hart Yard"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17561208-9-crimeloc42" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-9-off40 t17561208-9-crimeloc42"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-9-off45 t17561208-9-crimeloc42"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the value of it?</p>
               <p>Pratt. It was worth about six pounds.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you heard any thing of it since?</p>
               <p>Pratt. No, I have not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561208-9-person78">
                  Mary 
                  Pratt 
               <interp inst="t17561208-9-person78" type="surname" value="Pratt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-9-person78" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-9-person78" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 30th of September last three men came into my house, when one wanted to go backwards, and I shew'd him the way. The other two went into a room and called for a tankard of beer. The other man staying backwards so long I went to see what he was at. He was looking into my window, and seemingly doing up his breeches. I found every thing safe in my kitchen.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner either of these three men?</p>
               <p>M. Pratt. He was one of the two that called for the tankard of beer, which they had drawn in a silver quart mug.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did they come in?</p>
               <p>M. Pratt. I believe it was between eight and nine at night. The other came in, and sat in the same box along with them, and call'd for a pint of beer. He drank as if he did not belong to them. He paid me for it, and went out, and in about ten minutes came in again, and sat in the same place where he had before. He called for another pint of beer, and desired I'd put it into their tankard. I said it would not hold it. I put some in, and left the other in the pint pot. I was call'd to go into the cellar to tap a butt of beer, and they all three went away together.</p>
               <p>Q. About what time was this?</p>
               <p>M. Pratt. This was about ten o'clock. In going out in haste one of them left this hat ( producing a man's hat) I stumbled over it as it lay in the passage between the two doors. I immediately saw I had lost my tankard, and went to the door to see, but they were gone off.</p>
               <p>Q. How came the prisoner to be taken up?</p>
               <p>M. Pratt. There was an advertisement in the paper of a man's being taken up, and any person that had lost a silver tankard might apply to justice Fielding; upon which I went (that was on the 4th of this instant) and there I saw the prisoner. He ask'd me if I knew him.</p>

               <p>Q. What was your answer?</p>
               <p>M. Pratt. I said, why do you ask? do you know me?</p>
               <p>Q. How long was you out of the room when you went to tap the vessel ?</p>
               <p>M. Pratt. I was not gone ten minutes before they and the mug were gone. I had a mistrust of them before I went down, by hearing them say as I passed by them, ''If we an't him to-night we'll have him another night;'' from which I imagined<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175612080006"></xptr> they were three baliffs, or somebody no better than they should be.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this man ever at your house before?</p>
               <p>M. Pratt. No, never to the best of my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they pay their reckoning?</p>
               <p>M. Pratt. No, they did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner in irons when you saw him at justice Fielding's?</p>
               <p>M. Pratt. Yes, he was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he pointed out to you as a person suspected ?</p>
               <p>M. Pratt. No, he was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Of your own knowledge did you know him?</p>
               <p>M. Pratt. Of my own knowledge I knew his face and person.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you point him out?</p>
               <p>M. Pratt. He pointed me out, for he asked me the first question.</p>
               <p>Q. What was your answer?</p>
               <p>M. Pratt. I asked him again if he knew me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not declare that you did not know him?</p>
               <p>M. Pratt. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561208-9-person79">
                  Celina 
                  Mowet 
               <interp inst="t17561208-9-person79" type="surname" value="Mowet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-9-person79" type="given" value="Celina"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-9-person79" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to the prosecutor. This is one of the gentlemen (looking upon the prisoner) that was in one of our boxes drinking out of the silver mug that was lost that night.</p>
               <p>Court. Be careful, look at him again, and consider.</p>
               <p>C. Mowet. I am sure he is one of the three. They had two tankards and a pint of beer. I was in the room almost every moment.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a mug was it?</p>
               <p>C. Mowet. It was a quart silver mug.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see them go away?</p>
               <p>C. Mowet. No, that was all the time I was out of the room, being with my mistress helping to tap a butt of beer. We made what haste we could. She said, she was afraid something would be lost, as my master was ill a bed.</p>
               <p>Q. How was the prisoner dress that night?</p>
               <p>C. Mowet. He had a blue futcout coat on.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did they come into the house?</p>
               <p>C. Mowet. I don't exactly know the time. It was after candles were lighted.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at justice Fielding's?</p>
               <p>C. Mowet. I was, and knew him at first sight.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you say so then?</p>
               <p>C. Mowet. I said I never saw him but that one time before; but was sure he was one of the three men.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say to that?</p>
               <p>C. Mowet. He bid me look at him two or three times.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I never was in the prosecutor's house in my life. I was taken on board a ship which I belong to, and brought here in irons on suspicion of stealing of tankards. My irons made me remarkable to be known. The justice told me if it cost him a thousand pounds he'd have my life. He ordered every person (as they came in) into his back room, and told them I was the man, and he would open to them a great scene of villainy. He told me I should certainly be hanged, unless I discovered my accomplices.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17561208-9-verdict43" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561208-9-verdict43" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17561208-9-punish44" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561208-9-punish44" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-9-defend75 t17561208-9-punish44"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a second time indicted, by the same name, for <rs id="t17561208-9-off45" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561208-9-off45" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-9-off45" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a silver tankard, value 5 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17561208-9-victim81" type="victimName">
                           Aaron 
                           Young 
                        <interp inst="t17561208-9-victim81" type="surname" value="Young"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17561208-9-victim81" type="given" value="Aaron"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17561208-9-victim81" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling-house of the said Aaron
            </rs>, <rs id="t17561208-9-cd46" type="crimeDate">Oct. 4</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-9-off40 t17561208-9-cd46"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-9-off45 t17561208-9-cd46"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561208-9-person82">
                  Aaron 
                  Young 
               <interp inst="t17561208-9-person82" type="surname" value="Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-9-person82" type="given" value="Aaron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-9-person82" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Monday the 4th of October about eight at night a man well dressed, with a silver scollop'd laced hat on, came into my house, look'd in at the kitchen door, and saw a great deal of company. He turn'd about to another room, and call'd for a light.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Young. <rs id="t17561208-9-viclabel47" type="occupation">I keep the Checquer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-9-victim81 t17561208-9-viclabel47"></join>, in <placeName id="t17561208-9-crimeloc48">Checquer-Court, Charing-Cross</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17561208-9-crimeloc48" type="placeName" value="Checquer-Court, Charing-Cross"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17561208-9-crimeloc48" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-9-off40 t17561208-9-crimeloc48"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-9-off45 t17561208-9-crimeloc48"></join>. I ordered my servant to carry in a light, and went up stairs myself, and in less than half an hour I was informed a man had jumped out of the window with my tankard.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see your tankard again?</p>
               <p>Young. No, never.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you seen it last?</p>
               <p>Young. I had seen it about five minutes before that man came into my house. I can't swear the prisoner is the man. I went to justice Fielding's, and had the man described by those that saw him, and had him and the tankard advertised.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561208-9-person83">
                  Dorothea 
                  Young 
               <interp inst="t17561208-9-person83" type="surname" value="Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-9-person83" type="given" value="Dorothea"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-9-person83" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the prosecutor. I think it was the prisoner that came into our house the 4th of October about eight at night.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you speak with certainty, or can you not?</p>
               <p>D. Young. I really believe the prisoner to be the person. He called for a light, a tankard of beer, and pen, ink and paper, and went into a little room by himself. There was no way of making an<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175612080007"></xptr> escape without being discovered, except that of jumping out at the window. A young woman that stood at the door (waiting for a pint of beer to be drawn) called, and told us a man had jumped out of the window. I went into the room, and found the man, paper, and tankard were gone.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. What is the value of the tankard ?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. It cost me nine pounds five shillings.</p>
               <p>Q. to D. Young. How did you find the window?</p>
               <p>D. Young. The sash was quite thrown up, when he was sitting in the room a writing the sash was down.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in the room when he was ?</p>
               <p>D. Young. I was, when he had wrote two lines and a half on the paper.</p>
               <p>Q. How long before he quitted the room?</p>
               <p>D. Young. I had seen him and the tankard not three minutes before he was gone.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561208-9-person84">
                  Joseph 
                  Saul 
               <interp inst="t17561208-9-person84" type="surname" value="Saul"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-9-person84" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-9-person84" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to the prosecutor, I delivered a tankard of beer to the prisoner, it was a silver one, about eight o'clock on the 4th of Oct. at night.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain as to the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Saul. I am, I know him very well; I saw him at Justice Fielding's since, and knew him at the first sight.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the prisoner come in?</p>
               <p>Saul. No, he was sitting in the parlour when I saw him first, he went in there of himself; I went to him, and ask'd him what he'd please to have; he said, My lad get me a tankard of beer, or porter, I can't say which. I carry'd it to him, then he said, My lad, get me a pen, ink and sheet of paper. I carried them to him; then he said, If one Williamson should come to ask for one Williams, shew him in here. I went and left word at the bar with my mistress immediately; after that I went in to snuff the candle, he was sitting writing, and a little time after that came a young woman for a pint of beer, and change for a shilling. I went to the bar, and desir'd my mistress to get the change ready against I came up with the beer; immediately as I came to the door the young woman said, Joe, what is the matter, there is a man come out at the window. I saw the window open, and candle burning. I ran out into the street to see if I could catch him, but could see nothing of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the sash was down that night?</p>
               <p>Saul. Yes, I know it was, and the shutters put to, but not bolted within side.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see the tankard last?</p>
               <p>Saul. The tankard was standing by him when I went in to snuff the candle.</p>
               <p>Q. from the prisoner. Did not you say the first time you saw me at Justice Fielding's you did not know me?</p>
               <p>Saul. No, I did not; as soon as I saw his face I told Mr. Fielding that was the man, for I knew his face.</p>
               <p>Eliz. Hewit. I went for a pint of beer to the prosecutor's house on the 4th of Oct. at night; while I was standing at the door, I saw the parlour window open, and a man came out at it; he came to me, and ask'd me if I saw any body knock at that window. I said no. He went back, seemingly to get in again, but instead of that he ran directly away into the street.</p>
               <p>Q. If he had been minded to have got in again, was it easy for him so to do?</p>
               <p>Eliz. Hewit. Yes, very easy.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>None of these people ever saw me before they saw me at Justice Fielding's; even that Saul said he could not positively swear to me. I never was in the house in my life. Justice Fielding call'd them all into a private place, and when they came out, then they said to the best of their knowledge I was the man.</p>
               <p>Saul. I was positive to the prisoner before the Justice had spoke a word to me.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17561208-9-verdict49" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561208-9-verdict49" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17561208-9-punish50" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561208-9-punish50" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-9-defend75 t17561208-9-punish50"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
