<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17580405-30">
               <interp inst="t17580405-30" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580405-30" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580405-30" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580405"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580405-30" type="date" value="17580405"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580405-30-off143-c202" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580405-30-defend253 t17580405-30-off143 t17580405-30-verdict145"></join>
         
               <p>186. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17580405-30-defend253" type="defendantName">
                     RIchard
                      William Vaughan
                  <interp inst="t17580405-30-defend253" type="surname" value="William Vaughan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-30-defend253" type="given" value="RIchard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-30-defend253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17580405-30-off143" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580405-30-off143" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-30-off143" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               feloniously forging and counterfeiting a bank note, for the payment of 20l. to 
                     <persName id="t17580405-30-person254">
                        John 
                        Conwallis 
                     <interp inst="t17580405-30-person254" type="surname" value="Conwallis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580405-30-person254" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580405-30-person254" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  ; and also for putting away the same, with intent to defraud the 
                     <persName id="t17580405-30-victim255" type="victimName">
                        governor
                         and company of the bank of England
                     <interp inst="t17580405-30-victim255" type="surname" value="and company of the bank of England"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580405-30-victim255" type="given" value="governor"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580405-30-victim255" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580405-30-off143 t17580405-30-victim255"></join>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>. <rs id="t17580405-30-cd144" type="crimeDate">March 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580405-30-off143 t17580405-30-cd144"></join>.*</p> 

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580405-30-person256">
                  John 
                  Spensley 
               <interp inst="t17580405-30-person256" type="surname" value="Spensley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-30-person256" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-30-person256" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the apprehending of the prisoner. (He produces a parcel of papers.) These were taken upon the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580405-30-person257">
                  William 
                  Cole 
               <interp inst="t17580405-30-person257" type="surname" value="Cole"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-30-person257" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-30-person257" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the searching the prisoner's lodgings. (He produces a parcel of papers.) Some of these were found in a bureau, some in a little closet; here are two copper-plates; (producing one about 5 inches by 3, the other about 3 by 1 and a half) these were found in the closet. There were Mr. Race and Mr. Dod at the finding them.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the closet open or locked?</p>
               <p>Cole. I do not know that.</p>
               <p>Q. to Spensley. Do you remember any keys being delivered by the prisoner at Mr. Fielding's?</p>
               <p>Spensley. I took them out of his pocket, and put them into a hat: but do not know who took them afterwards.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580405-30-person258">
                  John 
                  Corbould 
               <interp inst="t17580405-30-person258" type="surname" value="Corbould"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-30-person258" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-30-person258" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an engraver. About the 1st of last March, the prisoner at the bar applied to me in the name of Sneed, for a copper-plate to be engraved with a promissory note. I cannot remember whether he brought me a written direction, or whether he wrote it in my shop. I engraved him two plates. The direction for the last plate I have here. (Producing it.)</p>
               <p>Q. What became of the direction for the first?</p>
               <p>Corbould. I cannot tell whether he did not take that away with him.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of the first plate?</p>
               <p>Corbould. I have it here. I shewed it the prisoner before it was quite finished, and he made a great many objections to it. One in particular I remember was, the word on at the beginning of the second line, should have been at the beginning of the first line, and the words I promise were placed, he said, too far from the edge of the plate, and the Britannia he did not like; he wanted me to alter the plate; I said I should have more trouble to alter it than to make a new one. Then that was laid aside, and I engraved a second by his direction.</p>
               <p>Q. Now look at this other plate.</p>
               <p>Corbould. This is the second plate. (He delivers it, and the directions for engraving.)</p>
               <p>Q. Have you got a proof from this plate?</p>
               <p>Corbould. Here is one that I had printed off from it. (He delivers that in.)</p>
               <p>A young Lady sworn. The prisoner at the bar delivered me some bills: these are the same. (Producing twelve counterfeit bank notes, sealed up in a cover, for 20l. each.)</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say they were when he delivered them to you.</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. He said they were bills.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you make any observations on them?</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. I said mine were thinner paper; he answered, all bills are not alike.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any conversation with him about the bank?</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. No, none at all.</p>
               <p>Q. What was you to do with them?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175804050023"></xptr>Y. Lady. I was to keep them till after we were married.</p>
               <p>Q. What was to have been done with them then?</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he put them in your hands for?</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. He put them in my hands to shew he put confidence in me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he give you any charge concerning them?</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. He desired me not to shew them to any body; and to sealed them up with his own seal; obliged me oath not to discover them to any body; and I did not till he had discovered them himself</p>
               <p>Q. Was he not to settle something upon you?</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. Yes; he was to settle so much upon me and he was to advance it in stock. ( The not delivered in)</p>
               <p>Q. to Corbould. Look at this note, the body of 22</p>
               <p>Corbould. This is printed from the second copperplate of my engraving; all but these words, For to and company of the bank of England; ved the plate, the prisoner asked me if I can't tell him where a printer lived, and I recommended one Farnworth, a man that prints for me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580405-30-person259">
                  William 
                  Farnworth 
               <interp inst="t17580405-30-person259" type="surname" value="Farnworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-30-person259" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-30-person259" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a copper-plate printer. I remember the prisoner coming to me about the beginning of last March; he said Mr. Jefferys and Mr. Corbould recommended him to me, because had the trouble of proving it.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is Mr. Jeffreys?</p>
               <p>Farnworth. Jeffreys and Corbould are partners. He said he wanted a few prints done; I said I was in a great hurry, and could not finish my business, being Saturday evening. He said he would pay me considerably, if I would do them then. I printed 28 for him, and Mr. Jeffreys paid me.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was present?</p>
               <p>Farnworth. There was only my man that works for me was by. The prisoner staid while they were done, and took away four of them with him.</p>
               <p>Q. What had you for doing them?</p>
               <p>Farnworth. I was paid two shillings for doing them; he made a second application to me the week following, and came and had forty-eight more printed of the same plate.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he present when you printed them?</p>
               <p>Farnworth. He was with me all the time, and took them away as they were done.</p>
               <p>Q. Who paid you for doing them?</p>
               <p>Farnworth. He did; he paid me two shillings for doing them.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon whose paper did you print them?</p>
               <p>Farnworth. I printed them on his own paper, which he brought with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Look upon this note, and the plate, and see whether you can say part of the note was printed off from this plate. (He looks on them.)</p>
               <p>Farnworth. Yes, part of it was.</p>
               <p>Q. Read what words were printed off from this plate?</p>
               <p>Farnworth reads. - I promise to pay to or bearer, Twenty pounds. Here is London also, and the Britannia and No. at the top.</p>
               <p>[The paper produced by Cole looked at. It was very thin, and the words, BANK OF ENGLAND, made in the body of the paper, wanted the second N in England.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580405-30-person260">
                  Charles 
                  Fourdrinier 
               <interp inst="t17580405-30-person260" type="surname" value="Fourdrinier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-30-person260" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-30-person260" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a copper-plate printer and stationer. The prisoner applied to me about the 4th of March last, with three written directions; one directed for the governor and company of the bank of England: another to the East-India company; and the other I know nothing of, to get them engraved for him. I asked him, if he pleased to have them all on one plate, or separate: he considered a little, and said separate. I asked him if he would have one done first, and the rest afterwards. He considered a second time, and said, I might as well do that for the governor and company of the bank of England first. I got it engraved for him, and shewed him a proof of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this smallest plate.</p>
               <p>Fourdrinier. This is the plate: he said the r in governor must be altered, and made into an s; it was altered according to his directions.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this note No. 13840</p>
               <p>Fourdrinier. To the best of my knowledge this is printed from it, For the governor and company of the bank of England. After he had got it, he paid me for it, and went about his business; and I think about a week after, he came to me and asked me, if I could not print him some from the plate; I told him I could: he brought some paper along with him folded up very curiously; so that I could not see what was in them; I was going to take the papers from him, but he said he must go up stairs with me, and see them worked off himself. I took him up stairs; he would not let me have them out of his hands. I took a spunge and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175804050024"></xptr> wetted them, and put them on the plate, in order for printing them. After my boy had done two or three of them, I begged to be excused. Having business to do, I went down stairs, and my boy worked them off.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your boy's name?</p>
               <p>Fourdrinier. His name is 
               <persName id="t17580405-30-person261">
                  John 
                  Nevil 
               <interp inst="t17580405-30-person261" type="surname" value="Nevil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-30-person261" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-30-person261" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the prisoner came down stairs and paid me for them.</p>
               <p>Q. What imagination had you when a man comes with papers folded up, which you are not permitted to see the contents of, for you to print on that same paper, (for the governor and company of the bank of England.)</p>
               <p>Fourdrinier. I then did not suspect any thing, but I shall take care for the future.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580405-30-person262">
                  John 
                  Nevil 
               <interp inst="t17580405-30-person262" type="surname" value="Nevil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-30-person262" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-30-person262" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am apprentice to Mr. Fourdrinier.</p>
               <p>Q. How old are you?</p>
               <p>Nevil. I shall be sixteen years of age next July, my master came to me, and gave me the plate to print off these things; Mr. Vaughan was along with him.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is this ago?</p>
               <p>Nevil. It is about six weeks ago. After I had printed off about three or four, my master went down stairs, Mr. Vaughan bid me print more off.</p>
               <p>Q. How many did you print?</p>
               <p>Nevil. To the best of my knowledge it was forty eight.</p>
               <p>Q. What part of them words on the paper did you print off?</p>
               <p>Nevil. The words were (governor and company of the bank of England.)</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this plate, are you sure this is the plate?</p>
               <p>Nevil. (He takes it in his hand.) This is it.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you see the other words when you printed off these words you mentioned?</p>
               <p>Nevil. No, they were folded up, so that I could not see what was in them.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they brought so to you?</p>
               <p>Nevil. They were brought so up stairs.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580405-30-person263">
                  James 
                  Balanger 
               <interp inst="t17580405-30-person263" type="surname" value="Balanger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-30-person263" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-30-person263" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have been acquainted with the prisoner five or six months.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Balangers. I live in George-yard. About five or six weeks ago as the prisoner and I were coming down Portugal-street, he asked me if I could give him cash for a 20l. bank note. I said I had no cash about me, but I had a relation that could do it. We went to him, and he had not cash; then I said I had a brother on Snow-hill, he has cash. As we were going on, he said the bank note was not about him, but at his brother's; we will go to him; but when we came to his brother's chambers, he nor none of his clerks were there; then we went and drank together, till we thought he might be come in. We went to the chamber again, but no body was there; coming out of the chamber, there happened to be the waiter of the wine cellar on the stairs. He ask'd if his brother was below; he said he was. I said then you may go and ask him for the key. He said he would not, he did not choose it, for he would ask for what he wanted it. About a fort night after that he came to me in my yard and asked me if I had a six stall stable to let I said I had a two stall stable, if that was suit. He said a gentleman of his acquaintance had six saddle horses, and should want such a stable. He asked me when we were together, if I could give him cash for bank bills, saying he had twenty by him for 20 l. each. I said I could not, it is but going to the bank, you may soon get cash there; he said he did not care for that, because he was a bankrupt, and his certificate was not signed.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he shew you any of the notes?</p>
               <p>Balanger. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take the notes he talked of to be all good notes?</p>
               <p>Balanger. Yes, I did.</p>
               <p>Council for the crown. When was this second conversation?</p>
               <p>Balanger. It was about three weeks ago.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580405-30-person264">
                  Thomas 
                  Bliss 
               <interp inst="t17580405-30-person264" type="surname" value="Bliss"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-30-person264" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580405-30-person264" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner offered himself to me as a clerk, about eight months ago, in consequence of my advertising for one. I hired him as such, and he lived with me about three months in that capacity.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you some way concerned for the young Lady.</p>
               <p>Bliss. I am guardian to her; the prisoner had privately made his addresses to her, without my knowledge or consent; after a time he made me acquainted with it, (but not till I had learn'd it from the servants; and I observed by the Girl's behaviour, that she greatly approved him.) I said to him, if he could make it appear that he could maintain her, and if his character, upon close inquiry would bear. (I at that time had no doubt of his character, as a servant, because he had behaved well.) He mentioned his being of a good<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175804050025"></xptr> family, and told me though he had been a bankrupt, yet soon should have his certificate signed; and his brother, an eminent attorney, and his friends that lived at Stafford, would settle an equal sum upon her to her fortune, would rein state him in business, and advance him a considerable sum of money. On these declarations I consented. He had got her consent, what remained was my care to see she did not imprudently throw herself away. Many meetings we had, to treat of this pretended settlement; he applied to his own attorney for a draught of the settlement. It was agreed that 500l. should be settled in trust for her separate use.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he say that was to be raised?</p>
               <p>Bliss. He said his brother and friends would advance him a thousand pounds, and out of that money it was to be raised. The affair of the bank notes came to my knowledge by mere accident. I believe it was on the 22d of March, I was sitting in my parlour, with my wife, by the fire-side; the prisoner and the girl in the same room, which being small, though they whispered, I could perceive Vaughan was very urgent to have something returned, which he said he would call for early next morning. I then thought it something trifling, and not worth particular notice. As soon as he went away, I studied her face, and could perceive much dissatisfaction. I asked her what was the matter; I perceived a tear break out; she would not tell me what the matter in dispute was. This induced me to resolve he should not see her till I found out what he wanted of her. When he came the next morning I took him into the parlour, and said you have given the young lady great uneasiness last night, I desire to know what you demanded of her; he hesitated some time, and said he did not demand any thing. I said this is a matter brought near a conclusion, there shall be nothing a secret till after you are married; tell me candidly what past between you. He still refused upon my second asking. Then I said I in part knew it from her; and said, may be, she has the value of ten or twelve pounds, you might give her to buy a bauble. He said more than that, it was near 300l. in bills, and it was that which he demanded of her again, and for very good reasons, which he could not then tell me; till his certificate was signed, it was not proper any body should know he had got so much, and his brother was to advance it to him when he had got that signed.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say what sort of bills they were?</p>
               <p>Bliss. To the best of my knowledge he did not say what sort, but I understood they were bank bills. I asked him for what intent he left them with her; he said, as I had of late suspected him, he designed to give her a proof of his affection and truth, I said you have demanded them in such a manner, that it must be construed as an abatement of your affection towards her. He still solicited farther. I told him I must ask advice first, as things had gone so far. I desired he would not see her till then, and after that he might call upon me again, and I never saw him till I saw him before the justice. I had no notion at that time that he had imposed on the girl, by giving her any thing that was false.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he mention the number of bills?</p>
               <p>Bliss. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Council for the prisoner. In the common course of negotiating business, is the expression bills, when they mean bank notes?</p>
               <p>Bliss. No, it is not, but I believe they are equally und erstood by bank bills or bank notes.</p>
               <p>Q. If a person owes you money, and was to say he would pay you in bills, should you think it to be bank bills?</p>
               <p>Bliss. I believe bank notes are as commonly called bills.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any thing pass between you about bank bills?</p>
               <p>Bliss. No.</p>
               <p>Q. From the general purport of the discourse with him, could you understand he was to purchase any of this fortune with these bills?</p>
               <p>Bliss. No, he said she might go and take the stock, or to that effect. He equivocated much.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any time of marriage appointed?</p>
               <p>Bliss. The marriage was fixed for the Tuesday in Easter-week.</p>
               <p>Q. to the young Lady. How many notes did the prisoner leave with you?</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. There were twelve of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you count them?</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you read any part of them?</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon what account did he put them in your hands?</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. On the account of my saying I thought he had no value for me; and he put them into my hand to shew me that he had.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175804050026"></xptr>Q. Had there been any dispute between you?</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. Not much.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you what they were?</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. I don't remember that he did.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you take them to be?</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. I took them for bank bills.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you make any observation on them then?</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. Yes, I told him they were thicker than my bank bills were.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you say bills?</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. I said my bank notes were thinner than them, and he made answer all notes were not alike.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you had any conversation about any settlement upon you?</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. He said he was to settle 250 l. on me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you the value of the notes?</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. I think I said they were 20 l. each, to which he noded his head, and that was all.</p>
               <p>Q. What was he to settle on you?</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. He was to settle 500 l. on me, and this was to make up mine 500l.</p>
               <p>Q. What was yours?</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. Mine was 250l.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say that was to make up yours 500l.</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. No, he did not, he insisted on my not telling any body of these bills, and said they were not to be meddled with on any consideration in the world, and he was to go to the bank and transfer it to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the 500l. to be raised on his part?</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember the prisoner asking for these notes afterwards?</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. I do, he begged the favour of having them again.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he call them?</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. He said bills.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. It was, I believe, about the 22d.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you deliver them?</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he demand them after that?</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him after that?</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. No</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Council. Then these were left with you to be returned to him again, were they not?</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. I do not know any thing about that, I was to keep them till after our marriage.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you understand these to be any part of the value he was to settle upon you?</p>
               <p>Y. Lady. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. to Spensley. Was you at the apprehending the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Spensley. I met him in the custody of my brother constable.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any thing that the prisoner did then?</p>
               <p>Spensley. I saw some paper in his mouth, and saw him spit some of it out, and his countenance changed at the time.</p>
               <p>Council. There were fifteen found upon the prisoner, twenty in his room, and these twelve Miss produced, and one we suppose he destroyed in his mouth, come just to the number that were printed.</p>
               <p>Spensley. My brother constable said to me, I am glad you are come, for he has swallowed two bits of paper.</p>

               <p>Council for prisoner. If you were to be charged with a capital offence, would not your countenance change, supposing you innocent.</p>
               <p>Spensley. I suppose it would.</p>
               <p>M. Sabberton. He takes the note in question in hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at the number of this note.</p>
               <p>Sabberton. We have never a number so high as this. This is not a bank note, but there is some resemblance to be sure.</p>
               <p>The Jury look at the plates and the papers found, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17580405-30-verdict145" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580405-30-verdict145" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17580405-30-punish146" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580405-30-punish146" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580405-30-defend253 t17580405-30-punish146"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
