<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17521026-30">
               <interp inst="t17521026-30" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521026-30" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521026-30" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17521026"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521026-30" type="date" value="17521026"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17521026-30-off162-c204" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521026-30-defend266 t17521026-30-off162 t17521026-30-verdict165"></join>
         
               <p>534. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17521026-30-defend266" type="defendantName">
                     Alexander 
                     Bourk 
                  <interp inst="t17521026-30-defend266" type="surname" value="Bourk"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-defend266" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-defend266" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for that <rs id="t17521026-30-off162" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-off162" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-off162" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he, on the king's highway, on 
                     <persName id="t17521026-30-victim267" type="victimName">
                        King 
                        Gold 
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-victim267" type="surname" value="Gold"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17521026-30-victim267" type="given" value="King"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17521026-30-victim267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521026-30-off162 t17521026-30-victim267"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , <rs id="t17521026-30-viclabel163" type="occupation">Esq;</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521026-30-victim267 t17521026-30-viclabel163"></join> did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life; one gold watch, val. 10 l. one guinea and one half guinea, from his person did steal, take, and carry away
            </rs>, <rs id="t17521026-30-cd164" type="crimeDate">Sept. 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521026-30-off162 t17521026-30-cd164"></join>. * </p>
               <p>King Gold. On the first of September, between five and six in the evening, going from Ealing to town, about half a mile from my own house, my<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175210260018"></xptr> coach was stopped by a single highwayman; he had on a brown indifferent great coat, a black piece of silk over his face, and a pistol in his hand; he first demanded that I would deliver my money. I pulled out a purse in which I had only a guinea and half, which he took from me. It was some time before I delivered my watch, he cocked his pistol, and presenting it to my breast, said he'd fire if I did not deliver it immediately; this he repeated several times. He would have my watch, and once attempted to pull it out. I said my hands were very lame, I was a gouty sort of a man, and could not make such haste as he would have me. At last I delivered it; he then presented his pistol to the coachman, and bid him go on.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he speak like an Englishman, or a foreigner?</p>
               <p>Gold. The moment he began to open his mouth I knew him to be a foreigner, and speak as bad English as ever I heard. There were very large holes in the silk for him to look through. He is shewed a pistol. I think I can swear this is the pistol I was robbed with. I believe it is a foreign make, and I thought so then on seeing it.</p>
               <p>Q. How long might he be in committing this robbery?</p>
               <p>Gold. He was a great many minutes in commiting it. I was surprized that there were so many people on the road, and none came up. His coat looked like a coat to disguise him.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at the prisoner. What have you to charge him with ?</p>
               <p>Gold. I verily believe him to be the man. I saw him at Justice Fielding's, and the moment I saw him I thought I knew his eyes.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he his own hair, or a wig?</p>
               <p>Gold. I could not tell that, his great coat was put up. I more particularly remarked his voice, if he speaks watch, no man can be mistaken in him. He is certainly the man, I am certain he is the man that robbed me.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not you surprized at this time?</p>
               <p>Gold. I can't say I was without fear. or I had not delivered my watch; but it was but very little.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the silk cover his whole face?</p>
               <p>Gold. It did to his breast, but there were large eye-holes, and I perceived long eye-lashes, and a full stare with his eye.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the colour of his eye lashes?</p>
               <p>Gold. I can't tell; they seemed to be dark.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the first word he said to you?</p>
               <p>Gold. It was, stop, stop, stop.</p>
               <p>Q. From these words did you take him to be a foreigner?</p>
               <p>Gold. I did; and from the words, deliver your money.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any body with you?</p>
               <p>Gold. There was Mr. Sweet in the coach with me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he robbed at the same time?</p>
               <p>Gold. He took his money first, then he called upon me for mine.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he call out?</p>
               <p>Gold. He said, maak hast.</p>
               <p>Mr. Sweet. I was in the coach with Mr. Gold at this time, on the 1st of September, about half an hour after five in the afternoon. I think the prisoner is the man that did the robbery. The person had a black silk on his face. He clapped his pistol close to my breast and demanded my money, and after that my watch. Then he robbed Mr. Gold of his watch and money. I took a great deal of notice of his speech.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you heard the prisoner speak since?</p>
               <p>Sweet. I have before the justice. He talked about the watch, and to the best of my judgment, the voice is exactly the same. I said he was a foreigner as soon as we were robbed; the holes through the silk were about the size of a crown piece, but I did not take particular notice of his eyes. He had a great coat on of a darkish or brownish colour.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the watch Mr. Gold lost?</p>
               <p>Sweet. I do, I was sent for to Mr. Dunlop's shop to see it, and can swear to that to be the same Mr. Gold lost.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-30-person268">
                  Charles 
                  Dunlop 
               <interp inst="t17521026-30-person268" type="surname" value="Dunlop"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person268" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watchmaker, and live in Spring Garden, Charing-cross. Mr. Gold advertised his watch to be brought to our house, with ten guineas reward ; it was brought and delivered to me by 
               <persName id="t17521026-30-person269">
                  Alexander 
                  Bourk 
               <interp inst="t17521026-30-person269" type="surname" value="Bourk"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person269" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of Clart Holt, on Monday the 13th of this month.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is he?</p>
               <p>Dunlop. That is the prisoner at the bar. His landlord came to me and informed me the prisoner had been out of town, and upon Hounslow Heath he had been robbed, and likewise a Chaise was robbed, and he thought Captain Jasper, who had been robbed some time before, might get intelligence of his watch. On Saturday the 14th, in the evening, the prisoner came in a hackney coach to my door; in one hand he had the advertisement describing the gold watch. I looked upon it and said that was not the watch of Captain Jasper, but<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175210260019"></xptr> that of Mr. Gold. Then he put the gold watch into my hand, I looked upon it and found it to be Mr. Gold's. The prisoner sat down, and told me he had been out of town, and upon Hounslow Heath had been robb'd of 2 guineas and a half, and also that a post chaise with two ladies in it had been robbed of eighteen or twenty guineas. That he (the prisoner) came up to their chaise, and asked them if they had been robbed? They said yes, and pointing said, there goes the highwayman. He likewise told me he offered to borrow a horse of a gentleman ; that he pursued, and being come up with the highwayman by the Duke of Argyle's, the highwayman's horse made a plunge, and he cocked a pistol; that he followed him to the side of the Thames; that the highwayman dropped a pistol, and he took it up; that the highwayman took into the Thames, and finding he could not swim over, came back again, and said, if you'll let me escape I'll give you a gold watch; that the prisoner said, you look to be a good-natured gentleman, if you'll go with me to Hounslow I'll give you a glass of wine; that he took the watch, and they rode on together. When they came there he went to collar the highwayman, who pulled out two pistols; he discharged one at him, and with the other shot himself. I asked him what sort of a person he was that shot himself? He answered, a man about five feet ten inches high, almost six feet, and a d - n'd ugly looking fellow. He looks at the gold watch. This is the watch he brought to me to get the reward; my brother made it.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Gold. Is this the watch you was robbed of on the first of September?</p>
               <p>Gold. It is the same; it had then a fine steel chain, which is not on it now.</p>
               <p>Q. to Dunlop. Is it in the same condition it was when the prisoner brought it to you?</p>
               <p>Dunlop. It is; it had nothing but a silk string on it then. The prisoner seemed uneasy to be gone. I told him the gentleman that owned the watch was a man of great honour, and that he need not doubt having the reward. I sent for Mr. Sweet, and Mr. 
               <persName id="t17521026-30-person270">
                  Charles 
                  Gold 
               <interp inst="t17521026-30-person270" type="surname" value="Gold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person270" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person270" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , son to the proprietor. Mr. Charles was indisposed, and could not come; Mr. Sweet came. He and the prisoner went together to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17521026-30-person271">
                  Charles 
                  Gold 
               <interp inst="t17521026-30-person271" type="surname" value="Gold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person271" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person271" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's house.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he come to you in a publick manner, freely and voluntarily?</p>
               <p>Dunlop. He did, and told me the story I have been repeating.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ask him where he lodged?</p>
               <p>Dunlop. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he had shewed this watch to any body before he brought it to you ?</p>
               <p>Dunlop. No, he did not; nor did I ask him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he talk good English?</p>
               <p>Dunlop. He talked pretty good English.</p>
               <p>Q. Would it be easy to distinguish him to be a foreigner in hearing him speak two or three words?</p>
               <p>Dunlop. Yes, it was very easy ; his landlord had before informed me that he was a foreigner ; but if he had not, it was easily discerned.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-30-person272">
                  Charles 
                  Gold 
               <interp inst="t17521026-30-person272" type="surname" value="Gold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person272" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person272" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My father's watch and seal having been described in an advertisement, with ten guineas reward, and in case the person was discovered they should have five guineas more, on Saturday was se'nnight, between five and six in the afternoon, a messenger came and told me my father's watch was brought to Mr. Dunlop's. I, not being very well, desired they'd come down to me in Privy Gardens. Mr. Sweet and the prisoner came; the prisoner told me what he was come upon, and produced this watch and seal of my father's which has since been in my custody. He told me he had brought my father's watch and seal, as he supposed by the advertisement. I desired him to give me an account how he came possessed of them, after I had taken them. He told me he was upon Hounslow Heath, and pursued a highwayman till he stopp'd and told him he was an unfortunate tradesman, and desired he'd not ruin him, saying, go about your business, here is a watch and seal for you; that he took it and seemed to be friends with him; they then rode on together. I said at last, what am I to do? He produced the news paper, upon which I understood he meant to receive the reward. He gave me his name and place of abode. I gave him a drought on my banker for ten guineas, which he received. I found when I sent to enquire, that he did live at the place he mentioned, having been there four days. The next morning I went to Hounslow, to see the man that lay dead, whether the description answered to what he had said. I found strong reason for suspicion of the prisoner. I got a warrant and the prisoner was taken at his lodgings the next morning.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he not tell you he was robbed himself?</p>
               <p>C. Gold I cannot undertake to say he did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he not tell you that the highwayman had thrown away the money?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175210260020"></xptr>C Gold. I cannot be positive of that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-30-person273">
                  Joshua 
                  Flinden 
               <interp inst="t17521026-30-person273" type="surname" value="Flinden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person273" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person273" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Mr. Gold's coachman. I drove him when he was stopt, which was on the first of September. The man that stopt and robbed him was a well made lusty man, had a silk or crape before his face, with a great coat on, patched under both arms with a different colour, being rather darker. He said, Do, do; I did not understand him; then he cry'd stop in a very great hurry, and said, Maak basi, maak basi, maak basi.</p>
               <p>Q. How long might the person be in committing the robbery?</p>
               <p>Flinden. I believe about ten or twelve minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you heard the prisoner speak since he was in custody?</p>
               <p>Flinden. I have before the justice, and his voice is very much like the person's that committed the robbery. He is also much about the size of the person but his great coat was buttoned up.</p>
               <p>Q Did you see the dead man afterwards ?</p>
               <p>Flinden. I have. That man was not at all of the size of the man that robbed my master; he was a good deal less than the thief; there was no comparison in bulk.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take notice of the horse the highwayman rode on that robbed your master?</p>
               <p>Flinden. I did; it was a black horse, with a star and a grey tail.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen that horse since?</p>
               <p>Flinden. Never before, or since, to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Cross-Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you see any part of his face?</p>
               <p>Flinden. No; but the chin appeared black, and I took him to be a man of a darkish beard.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you distinguish his eyes?</p>
               <p>Flinden. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you have known him again by his face, had you seen him half an hour after?</p>
               <p>Flinden. No, I could not.</p>
               <p>Q. to Sweet. What did the prisoner say to you, when you first saw him at Mr. Dunlop's?</p>
               <p>Sweet. He had the watch in his hand, and said, Here be the watch the gentleman advertised; I am come for the reward of ten guineas; the man is dead.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he himself had been robbed?</p>
               <p>Sweet. He said he was, of two guineas and a half.</p>
               <p>Q. After the man gave him the gold watch, what did he say then?</p>
               <p>Sweet. He said he accepted it; then he said, Give me the money you robbed me of, and he replied, I have thrown it into the kennel.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say was done after that?</p>
               <p>Sweet. Then he said he asked the man to go to Hounslow, and drink a pint of wine; when they came there, he cried stop highwayman; then the man drew a pistol, and snapt it at him, but it did not go off; then he drew another, put it to his left ear, and shot himself dead.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear him charged with having a great coat on that day?</p>
               <p>Sweet. I did; he answered he had not had a great coat on since he came to England the last time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-30-person274">
                  Dawson 
                  Sackvile 
               <interp inst="t17521026-30-person274" type="surname" value="Sackvile"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person274" type="given" value="Dawson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person274" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am clerk to Judge Burnet.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you first see the prisoner at the bar?</p>

               <p>Sackvile. I beg to be excused answering that, lest it should be a prejudice to the prisoner. I know nothing of the robbery, but happened to be at Hounslow when the man shot himself. I saw a crowd of people surrounding two men on horse-back, presently a pistol went off, and I saw a man drop. My postman stopt, and I got out, went to them, and asked what was the reason of this accident; as also who had pursued this man, as they cried out a highwayman. The prisoner was there, and he said, I'll tell you the whole story. Coming along, continued he, there were two ladies in a post-chaise, and seeing a man stop them, I rode up, and asked them if they had been robbed; they answered no, but that that man had attempted to rob us; then I replied, I'll take him for you. I came up with the man in a very little time, he turned about, saying. What do you follow me for? adding, if I did not go off, he'd shoot me through the head. I said I will not hurt you, but if you will go with me, I'll give you a bottle of wine. I asked him how he came to follow this man, as having no arms; to which he replied: In going along upon the heath, the man dropt a pistol out of a leather apron; that he got off his horse, took it up, and rode on to drink a bottle of wine, when this accident happened. Here I left him, and came on towards London.</p>
         
               <p> *** In a few days will be published PART II. of these Proceedings.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17521026-30">
                  <interp inst="t17521026-30" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17521026-30" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17521026-30" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17521026"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17521026-30" type="date" value="17521026"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175210260021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Thursday the 26th, Friday the 27th, Saturday the 28th, and Monday the 30th, of OCTOBER.</p>
                  <p>In the 26th Year of His MAJESTY's Reign. NUMBER VIII. PART II. for the Year 1752. BEING THE Third SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of the Right Honourable 
                  <persName id="t17521026-30-person275">
                     Robert 
                     Alsop 
                  <interp inst="t17521026-30-person275" type="surname" value="Alsop"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17521026-30-person275" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17521026-30-person275" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Esq; LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by M. COOPER, at the Globe in Pater-noster Row. 1752:</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-Pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175210260022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery held for the City of London, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Q. How was he dressed?</p>
               <p>Sackvile. He had a loose great coat on; I saw it was patched under the right arm, and that the patch was rather darker than the coat. I thought it looked very extraordinary, that a man, so well dressed as he was, should wear so shabby a great coat. I then asked him if the highwayman had robbed him; he answered, No, he never offered to rob me; but said, after I had had a little conversation with him, he would not be taken, and that if I attempted it, he would shoot himself.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say any thing of the man riding into the Thames?</p>
               <p>Sackvile. No, not a word.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he had given him a gold watch?</p>
               <p>Sackvile. No, he did not</p>
               <p>Q. Did he to any body else at that time?</p>
               <p>Sackvile. Not at Hounslow, at that time, as I know of. I happened to be there three days after, and there was no body talked about it in my hearing.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you before Justice Fielding?</p>
               <p>Sackvile. I was; there he told his worship he was robbed of two guineas and a half.</p>
               <p>Q. How was the man dressed that was shot?</p>
               <p>Sackvile. He had an old great coat on a very bad wig, and a leather apron. He was much about my size, (which was much less than the prisoner) and his brains were shot out of his head.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear Mr. Gold's coachman say any thing before the justice?</p>
               <p>Sackvile. He there said, he was sure the man that shot himself was not the man that robbed his master.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner say any thing there about his being on horseback ?</p>
               <p>Sackvile. He said he had not been on horseback above once or twice since he has been in England.</p>
               <p>Q. to Charles Gold. What did you hear the prisoner say about his being on horseback ?</p>
               <p>C. Gold. He said before me, and my father, he had been on horseback but three times in the six months he had been in England.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-30-person276">
                  John 
                  Jenkins 
               <interp inst="t17521026-30-person276" type="surname" value="Jenkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person276" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person276" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am ostler to Mrs. Gale; she lets out horses, and the prisoner has had a horse three times at our stable; which I delivered to him. His usual time was to come about a quarter after five in the morning.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is it since the first time?</p>
               <p>Jenkins. I cannot justly say! The first time he had no whip, and I lent him a little cane.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear him make any complaint that night he returned, when the man was shot at Hounslow?</p>
               <p>Jenkins. He complained the same night, in my hearing, he had been robbed that day of four guineas. This was the last time he had a horse.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he tell you he lodged?</p>
               <p>Jenkins. He said in Bond-Street, that night.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-30-person277">
                  Steven 
                  Scot 
               <interp inst="t17521026-30-person277" type="surname" value="Scot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person277" type="given" value="Steven"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person277" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am headborough. I apprehended the prisoner last Monday was se'nnight. I searched his lodgings, and in opening a closet door, I found a pistol loaded: there also I found this hat; [holding one in his hand] and here are the holes where the pins have gone through to pin in crape, or silk, withinside the crown, on the front of it.</p>
               <p>Mr. Gold. (looking at the hat ). This is very much like the hat the man had on that robbed me.</p>
               <p>Scot. I taxed the prisoner about having a great coat, but he denied having any coat at all. [He<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175210260023"></xptr> is shewn the pistol] This is the pistol I found charged in the closet.</p>
               <p>Cross Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not the prisoner open the door without any compulsion to let you go in ?</p>
               <p>Scot. He opened the door to his landlord ; he did not know who was there.</p>
               <p>Q. What ro was he and in what part of the town?</p>
               <p>Scot. A two pair of stairs room in Hanover-Street, Long-Acre. The landlord said he had lodged there four or five days.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-30-person278">
                  Hannah 
                  Gale 
               <interp inst="t17521026-30-person278" type="surname" value="Gale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person278" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person278" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I a livery stable. The prisoner hired a her's cannot say how long ago; the form was before Jenkin's came to be over.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner then say his name was?</p>
               <p>H. Gale. He said his name was Leesham.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure he did not say his name was Bourk ?</p>
               <p>H. Gale. I am sure he did not.</p>
               <p>Cross-Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. How many times had he hired a horse of you?</p>
               <p>H. Gale. He had a horse of me four times in all.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you where he lived ?</p>
               <p>H. Gale. I asked him where he lived, but did not understand him, he speaking very bad English, though I thought he said Brook Street.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he always one horse?</p>
               <p>H. Gale. He had; it was a black brown.</p>
               <p>Mr. Cousseavs. I live in Hanover-Street, Long-Acre. The prisoner lodged at my house at the time of the highwayman's shooting himself at Hounslow. He lodged with me from Tuesday, old Michaelmas-day, to the Monday following. When he came home, after the man was shot, he told me he had been on the other side Hounslow, and coming back he was robbed of two guineas and a half; that afterwards he saw the man rob two ladies in a post-chaise, and seeing some horsemen come up, he desired them to lend him a horse, which they did ; that he pursued him, and seeing a pistol he on the heath, he dismounted, took it up, and mounted again; that presently he came up with him, and desired him to, or he was a dead man; that the other remained he would rather lose his life, or shoot himself; that he answered, Give me then the money you have taken from me, and he said he had thrown it away; that he requested him to put up his pistol, and he would put up his, which being agreed to, they went together towards Hounslow; that there he offered to seize him, but the man turning about, snapt a pistol at him, and with another pistol shot himself.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say any thing to you then about a gold watch?</p>
               <p>Scot. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I am a foreigner, and cannot speak in the speech way. This day I went out to Windsor, to see the prince, and hired a horse at Kensington. I dined of Hounslow Heath about four o'clock, about two miles from the town. I was stopt by a highwayman on a chesnut horse, with a whitish coloured great coat, and a wig ; he was a strong shouldered man; he robbed me of two guineas and a half. He turned round some trees, and saw me a coming after him, upon which I dismounted my horse, covered myself in a hedge, and he passed by me. There was another man passed by, unto whom I said, I have been robbed by that fellow, will you lend me your horse ? which was a brown one; he did not, but gave me a coat to disguise me. There was a post-chaise with two ladies in it, the highwayman gallopped up to it, and I saw it stop. After that he rode away; I went up to the post-chaise, and asked the ladies if that man had robbed them, but they were affrighted, and could not give me an answer ; I went after him, and pursued him. Meeting a gentleman, I asked him to lend me his horse, or help me to pursue the highwayman; said he, I have no arms. I met other people on the road, and a little farther I found a pistol on the heath, and took it up: this gave me courage to pursue him. I went by the house upon Hounslow-Heath, and he went towards the Thames, but his horse would not go over. I then presented the pistol to the highwayman, and he cried out, Pray don't pursue me, I am an unfortunate tradesman ; said I, If you'll give me my money again, I'll let you go. To this he replied, I have no money, I have flung it into the water; but I have got a gold watch, and if you will shoot your pistol off, I will come to you and give it you. No, I said, I will not, but I will put it into my pocket; adding, as you be a good fellow, I will treat you with a bottle of wine ; he replied, I will go with you. When<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175210260024"></xptr> we came to the King's Arms I took him by the right hand, and said, you are my prisoner. He gave his horse a spur and snap'd his pistol, but it did not go off, then he took the other and shot himself dead. I was very sorry that the man should do so, and went to the constable, but he did not understand me. They said, as the man is dead you have no business with it, and asked me no questions, so I said nothing of the watch: When I came home I went to a coffee-house in Long-acre and asked for the Daily Advertiser, there I saw the paragraph about a dead highwayman. I said, I was the man that pursued him, and he gave me a gold watch. I said, if I could not find it I would leave it there to be advertised, but in a little time I found it advertised, and then I said, I would go to the watchmaker, or the gentleman that it belonged to. From thence I went to a perriwig-maker and he dressed my hair. There I shew'd him the watch, and told him I had it of a highwayman. After that I shew'd it in Exeter-street to Mrs. Preston, then I came to Mr. Dunlop's shop, shew'd him the Advertiser and watch, and said, I had it of a highwayman that shot himself dead. He said, the gentleman is in the country. I replied, I will leave it here. Then he sent for the gentleman. I went with him and gave the watch to the gentleman in black clothes, and he gave me a note to go to a gentleman to take the reward. I gave them directions to my landlord, and my name. I thought it was doing justice to your country in pursuing the highwayman.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-30-person279">
                  Sarah 
                  Oaks 
               <interp inst="t17521026-30-person279" type="surname" value="Oaks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person279" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person279" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was attacked in a post-chaise by a single highwayman, which by report was the man that shot himself on the twelfth of this month. There was a gentleman rode up to me, I saw the sleeve of his coat, and was so affrighted when he asked me if I had been robbed that I could not make him an answer. He said he would pursue the villain, or the man.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he had been robbed by the same highwayman ?</p>
               <p>S. Oaks. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he speak like an Englishman, or a foreigner ?</p>
               <p>S. Oaks. I cannot say which.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-30-person280">
                  Thomas 
                  Dean 
               <interp inst="t17521026-30-person280" type="surname" value="Dean"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person280" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person280" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the post boy that drove that lady over Hounslow-heath that time. She was at tacked by a single highwayman but not robbed. After that the prisoner came up to the post-chaise, and asked me if the chaise was stopped. I said, yes. Then he said, he would follow the highwayman, so turned back and rode as hard as he could.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you going?</p>
               <p>T. Dean. To Windsor. The prisoner came from Hounslow after the chaise, so did the highwayman, but the highwayman afterwards turned back again towards Hounslow.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain it was the prisoner that came up to you?</p>
               <p>T. Dean. I am sure it was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he speak like an Englishman, or a foreigner?</p>
               <p>T. Dean. Like a foreigner.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>T. Dean. At the Three Cups in Bread-street.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-30-person281">
                  Patrick 
                  Guy 
               <interp inst="t17521026-30-person281" type="surname" value="Guy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person281" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person281" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a coffee-house in Long-acre. The prisoner came to my house on the thirteenth of October, about eleven or twelve o'clock. He called for a dish of coffee, then took the papers in his hand and read a paragraph about a highwayman that shot himself. Said he, this man I pursued, he had stopped a post-chaise in which were some ladies. After which he rode up to the post-chaise, and said, he would pursue him. He did, and the highwayman dropped his pistol. Then he picked it up and came up to him, and told him he would have his money again.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he mean by that?</p>
               <p>Guy. The money that he had robbed him of. The other told him he had dropped it, but would give him a gold watch to make him amends if he would not pursue him any further. Then he said, put up your pistol, and he put it up. Then the prisoner said, we will go and drink a glass of wine together, thinking to coaks him. When they came into the town he called, stop highwayman ; then the man took a pistol and shot himself.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he ask your advice?</p>
               <p>Guy. He shewed the watch, and asked me whether I knew if it was advertised. I told him there had been several, and one something like it, so I gave him some papers to look over. He said, I should be glad to find it, and if I do not. I will leave it here to be advertised. I said, you may do as you please for that. In about a quarter of an hour he found the advertisement and shewed it me,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175210260025"></xptr> it answered to the watch; then he offered me six-pence for the Advertiser. I said, the paper is more to me, because gentlemen will want it. Then he said, I will bring it again, so he took it with him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-30-person282">
                  Mary 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17521026-30-person282" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person282" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person282" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I remember the prisoner shewed a gold watch to me the Saturday before he was taken up, and said, he would go to the watch-maker's with it. I have known him ever since last June. He was in our house the last day of August, at ten o'clock, and said, as he was going into the city he had hurt his foot with the wheel of a chaise that had run over it, and if it was better he would come again on the morrow, but he did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-30-person283">
                  Philip 
                  Shower 
               <interp inst="t17521026-30-person283" type="surname" value="Shower"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person283" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person283" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner shew'd me a gold watch a fortnight ago to-morrow. He came into our shop and desired me to dress his hair; after that he went over the way and asked for a newspaper ; then he said, he should have some money for a watch, and asked me, if I had not heard of a highwayman that shot himself; he said, he pursued him, and was so close after him that he gave him this watch.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>Shower. It was about one or two o'clock.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-30-person284">
                  Ann 
                  Preston 
               <interp inst="t17521026-30-person284" type="surname" value="Preston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person284" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person284" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner shew'd me a watch it will be a fortnight to-morrow, and said, this is the watch I had of the man that shot himself, and I will carry it home to the gentleman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-30-person285">
                  Mary 
                  Owen 
               <interp inst="t17521026-30-person285" type="surname" value="Owen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person285" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person285" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was at home at his lodgings all day, the first of September, and I was with him. I lodged in the next room to him, at the corner of Dyer-street, at Mr. Harris's. He got up about eight o'clock. He allowed me a trifle to wait on him, and paid me that day, so I set it down in chalk-behind the door, it was sixpence per week ; and he did not go out at all that day.</p>
               <p>Justice Bulstrode. The prisoner came to my house on the twelfth of October, about six o'clock, sometime after the man was shot at Hounslow. I found he spoke not very good English, so I spoke to him in French. He told me, there was a man going to rob, and he pursued him as far as Hounslow ; and at the lower end of the town the man shot himself, so he came to give me an account.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he a great coat on?</p>
               <p>Bulstrode. He had.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-30-person286">
                  John 
                  Roberts 
               <interp inst="t17521026-30-person286" type="surname" value="Roberts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person286" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-person286" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Red Lion at Hounslow next to the Heath. I was at Marlow in Buckinghamshire when this man was shot, I never saw the prisoner at Hounslow in my life. The prisoner was pleased to inclose it in a letter, that I saw the man shoot himself, and subpena'd me, but I saw nothing of it.  <rs id="t17521026-30-verdict165" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17521026-30-verdict165" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
