<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17541204-33">
               <interp inst="t17541204-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541204-33" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541204-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17541204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541204-33" type="date" value="17541204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17541204-33-off165-c259" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541204-33-defend322 t17541204-33-off165 t17541204-33-verdict168"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17541204-33-off165-c260" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541204-33-defend324 t17541204-33-off165 t17541204-33-verdict168"></join>
         
               <p>37. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17541204-33-defend322" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Maddox 
                  <interp inst="t17541204-33-defend322" type="surname" value="Maddox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-defend322" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-defend322" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17541204-33-deflabel163" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541204-33-defend322 t17541204-33-deflabel163"></join>, and 
               
                  <persName id="t17541204-33-defend324" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Jenkins 
                  <interp inst="t17541204-33-defend324" type="surname" value="Jenkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-defend324" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-defend324" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17541204-33-deflabel164" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541204-33-defend324 t17541204-33-deflabel164"></join>, were <rs id="t17541204-33-off165" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-off165" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-off165" type="offenceSubcategory" value="infanticide"></interp>
               indicted for the wilful murder of a certain male infant
            </rs>, <rs id="t17541204-33-cd166" type="crimeDate">June 26</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541204-33-off165 t17541204-33-cd166"></join>. +</p>
               <p>Rice Price. I am the churchwarden of the parish, and am bound over to prosecute, I know nothing of the fact.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541204-33-person325">
                  Sarah 
                  Gasterel 
               <interp inst="t17541204-33-person325" type="surname" value="Gasterel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person325" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person325" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I can't tell how long it is ago since I went to live at Mrs. Maddox's in <placeName id="t17541204-33-crimeloc167">Bow-lane, Cheapside</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17541204-33-crimeloc167" type="placeName" value="Bow-lane, Cheapside"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17541204-33-crimeloc167" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541204-33-off165 t17541204-33-crimeloc167"></join>; I know I went on a Wednesday, and on the Sunday following 
               <persName id="t17541204-33-person326">
                  Sarah 
                  Jenkins 
               <interp inst="t17541204-33-person326" type="surname" value="Jenkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person326" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person326" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came to live there, and on the Wednesday after she was taken very ill towards the evening, and kept her room, and that night I was ordered by Mrs. Maddox to go to bed betimes. I went to bed about nine, and about half an hour after eleven I heard a child cry; I came down into Jenkins's room, and asked Mrs. Maddox if there was not a child cried; she answered, it was a child cried in the street. While I stood with the door in my hand just going out of the room, I heard a child cry again, then I went to the bed-side, there was 
               <persName id="t17541204-33-person327">
                  Sarah 
                  Jenkins 
               <interp inst="t17541204-33-person327" type="surname" value="Jenkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person327" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person327" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sitting up in her bed, and there lay a little child naked alive in the bed, Mrs. Maddox said, d - n you, you bitch, if you speak of it, I'll arrest you, and put you in the Compter. 
               <persName id="t17541204-33-person328">
                  Sarah 
                  Jenkins 
               <interp inst="t17541204-33-person328" type="surname" value="Jenkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person328" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person328" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             took the child on her knees, and asked her what she should do, for if her husband should know of the child, he would say it was none of his own, and she should be killed, and said she would serve it as she did the other, and desired Mrs. Maddox to give her her handkerchief; Maddox said she should have one of her own, and took a handkerchief out of a red and white hat-box which stood upon a drawer, and tied it round the child's neck, with a knot behind, and pulled it together as hard as she could pull it, as it lay on 
               <persName id="t17541204-33-person329">
                  Sarah 
                  Jenkins 
               <interp inst="t17541204-33-person329" type="surname" value="Jenkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person329" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person329" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's knee, and the handkerchief was about its neck till it was quite dead.</p>
               <p>Q. When she asked for a handkerchief, did she say what was to be done with it?</p>
               <p>S. Gasterel. No sir; but it was on purpose to kill it, because she said she would serve it as she had the other. After the child was dead, Mrs. Maddox took and turned the foul linen out of the hat-box, and put the child into it, and put a piece of brown paper over it, and tied it down with a piece of packthread; then she desired me to go down stairs, and fetch up some water to wash the boards that were stained; which I did. Then she desired me to go to bed; but before I went up, I heard her say, that after the watchman was gone about at three, she would go out with the child.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear her say where she was to carry it?</p>
               <p>S. Gasterel. No, I did not; after I went up to bed I heard the door unlock, and lock after her; and about half an hour after I heard her come back again.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know it was she?</p>
               <p>S. Gasterel. I think it was she, because the door would not go of itself.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you stay in the house after this?</p>
               <p>S. Gasterel. About a month after this; I was there five weeks and four days.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the first time of your speaking of this?</p>
               <p>S. Gasterel. It was about a week after I came out of the hospital, and was in the workhouse, I told the minister of Bow church of it; Mrs. Maddox had been taken up for keeping a disorderly house before I went to the hospital.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after this night you speak of, was it that she was taken up?</p>
               <p>S. Gasterel. About a month after; I went to the hospital, about five weeks after I was taken up, and put into Bow workhouse, to appear against Mrs. Maddox, and there I was taken ill, and then put into the hospital. I went into the hospital on the Thursday, and Mrs. Maddox came there to me on the Tuesday following, and desired me to be as favourable in speaking as I could; and also desired me to make it up, and not to appear against her about keeping a disorderly house, and not to mention any thing of the murder of the child. I told her I would not mention that a great many times.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any servants or lodgers in the house besides you three when this was done?</p>
               <p>S. Gasterel. There had been a maid, but she was sent to Billingsgate for some shrimps, and ran away with them about a fortnight before this thing. There was also a son of Mrs. Maddox's, about fifteen years old, that was a-bed in the garret the same night; but he knew nothing of it.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the reason you did not speak of this for above twelve or fourteen weeks ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175412040038"></xptr>S. Gasterel. Mrs. Maddox was always crying and begging of me not to speak of it; and threatening me, before I was taken up, to put me in the Compter, for a debt.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon whose information was she taken up?</p>
               <p>S. Gasterel. My father and mother did not know where I lived; I went into Honeylane-market, and my cousin saw me, and watched me home, and told my father, and he came and desired the door to be opened; she at first refused it, and said I was not there.</p>
               <p>Q. How many houses of this kind have you been in?</p>
               <p>S. Gasterel. This is the first.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you into the house?</p>
               <p>S. Gasterel. I was hired as a servant; she did keep a fish-stall in the Fleet-market, and she hired me there.</p>
               <p>Q. When you were taken up, she could do you no harm, what was the reason you did not mention this fact then ?</p>
               <p>S. Gasterel. I was very loth to mention it; fearing I should hang her.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you at last to mention it?</p>
               <p>S. Gasterel. The minister of Bow church came to me; I had violent fits, and he asked me if I had nothing on my mind that made me bad? I did not tell him at first; but upon his asking me two or three times, I told him. It was at the first time of his coming.</p>
               <p>Q. You are now upon your oath, and I hope you know the obligation of an oath, and the great sin you would be guilty of, to accuse a person of such a crime, if it is not truth.</p>
               <p>S. Gasterel. It is very true indeed.</p>
               <p>On her cross-examination, she said she never was in the prisoner Maddox's house till she went to live there, and did not know she kept a disorderly house till she had been there about a week; that she was to have three pounds per year; that every night girls used to be bringing men into the house; that Jenkin's room was up one pair of stairs; that when she went into the room, the door was upon the latch; that she saw a mould or mock on the left side of the child's belly, almost as big as a farthing; that she saw it was a male child. Being asked whether she was the person talked of to be bewitched, she said, she had been in a very odd way, being tied with cords in her bed at the workhouse, and untied, and did not know by who, but said she was certain no living person could do it. She was sometimes tied to the bed, and sometimes her legs were tied, but not to the bed, and it was very rare but she was thus tied every night, and sometimes a great many times in a night, and she in her senses at the time, and that Mr. 
               <persName id="t17541204-33-person330">
                  Samuel 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17541204-33-person330" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person330" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person330" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had been with her and others, who were eye-witnesses to some of those tyings; that she had violent fits for thirteen weeks; that the first of her having fits was about a week after she went to the workhouse.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541204-33-person331">
                  Sarah 
                  Orpwood 
               <interp inst="t17541204-33-person331" type="surname" value="Orpwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person331" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person331" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in George-yard by Bow-lane, next door but one to Maddox's. I was sitting at my door, I think it was on a saturday, I don't know the month, it was in the summer, when cherries were plenty, Jenkins was coming by, she desired I would wash her a cap, apron and handkerchief, and desired I would go with her to the alehouse, and she would give her a pot of beer; we went together to the Crown and Cushion in Trinity-lane, into a room by ourselves. She began to tell me her husband was come home from sea, and she was with child, and did not choose to live with him, till she was delivered, and had put it away, for he should never have to say he maintains another man's child; I said, I don't believe you are with child; she said, I am sure I am, but nobody can tell by my bulk. I said again, I cannot believe it; then she pulled her bulk out of her stays, and said, will you believe it now; then I said, I believe you are. She said, I have not above a month to go, and pulled out her left breast and milked some milk into her left-hand. She left her bulk at my house two or three days, and said it hurted her. Some little time after that; at the alehouse, I asked her if she knew whose child it was, she said yes, it was 
               <persName id="t17541204-33-person332">
                  Tom 
                  Warners 
               <interp inst="t17541204-33-person332" type="surname" value="Warners"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person332" type="given" value="Tom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person332" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I thought it strange for her, a common woman, to know whose it was.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known her?</p>
               <p>S. Orpwood. I have known her about two years, or not quite so much.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know her husband ?</p>
               <p>S. Orpwood. I never saw him in my life. She then lived at Mrs. Field's house, next door to Maddox's, that is the person that lately stood in the pillory in Cheapside for keeping a disorderly house; after that she told me, she and Field had fell out, and she was gone to live with Maddox.</p>
               <p>On her cross-examination she said, she herself had never been with child, but said the milk did not come so free as if she suckled; that she remebers that time she was at the Crown and Cushion was after Quarter-day.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541204-33-person333">
                  James 
                  Chantril 
               <interp inst="t17541204-33-person333" type="surname" value="Chantril"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person333" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person333" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The man that cohabited with Jenkins at that time, desired her to give him a note of indemnification, fearing charges upon the account of her being with child, as he suspected;<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175412040039"></xptr> he and I have worked together; we are brush-makers, his name is 
               <persName id="t17541204-33-person334">
                  Thomas 
                  Warner 
               <interp inst="t17541204-33-person334" type="surname" value="Warner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person334" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person334" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I heard her say in June last that she cohabited with him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541204-33-person335">
                  Thomas 
                  Wilks 
               <interp inst="t17541204-33-person335" type="surname" value="Wilks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person335" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person335" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner Jenkins used to come to our house, over-against Aldersgate-church, in Little-Britain: she said in my hearing, she was with child.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is that ago, that you heard her say that?</p>
               <p>T. Wilks. To the best of my knowledge this was about six months ago; she was once drinking with my wife and I at an alehouse; she said she had got a bulk, that keeps down her belly so flat that no body can tell that she was with child, till she comes to the last month: she lost the busk at my house, and I burnt it before she was taken up: she at that time mended her stays.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you burn it?</p>
               <p>T. Wilks. Because I wanted something to light my fire.</p>
               <p>Barbara his wife confirmed the evidence of her husband.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541204-33-person336">
                  William 
                  Watson 
               <interp inst="t17541204-33-person336" type="surname" value="Watson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person336" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person336" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw Jenkins last monday was six weeks, and went to have a pint of beer with him in Cheapside, and another woman; out of a joke I said, Sally, what is become of the kid ? She said, that is all gone off: she was a little in liquor then.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to ask about that ?</p>
               <p>W. Watson. Because, when I worked upon Snow-hill, I was acquainted with Tom. Warner, and so became acquainted with her; and I heard her say she was with child just after last Easter; I don't know the day of the month.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Warner by when she said she was with child?</p>
               <p>W. Watson. No, he was not.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the occasion?</p>
               <p>W. Watson. That I can't say.</p>
               <p>On his cross-examination he said, he apprehended by her saying it was gone off, that she had had a miscarriage.</p>
               <p>Brook Heckston. I am curate of Bow-parish; I heard 
               <persName id="t17541204-33-person337">
                  Sarah 
                  Gasterel 
               <interp inst="t17541204-33-person337" type="surname" value="Gasterel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person337" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person337" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was under trouble of mind; she was represented to me as being an extraordinary person. I imagined something black; I went to her, the day I can't recollect; taking with her, I thought proper to touch upon the subject of murder, then I found her agonies increase; then she made this Information, it varied but a little from that she made before my Lord mayor, only with this difference; she told his lordship she went to Maddox's on a wednesday, and to me she said it was on a friday; but then she recollected herself : she appeared to be quite in her senses, when out of her fits : she told me just the same she has here, as to the time she and Jenkins went to Maddox's, and what happened there.</p>
               <p>On his cross-examination, he said he heard of her being tied down in her bed, and that he went in order to detect the cheat; that before she made this confession, he desired she would tell him nothing but the truth, and not let innocent people be taken up for so heinous a crime; and that her fits were real, and not counter feit ones.</p>
               <p>The prisoners in their defence denied the fact.</p>
               <p>For the prisoners.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541204-33-person338">
                  Margaret 
                  Hendrick 
               <interp inst="t17541204-33-person338" type="surname" value="Hendrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person338" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person338" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who had known Maddox ten or twelve years; 
               <persName id="t17541204-33-person339">
                  Richard 
                  Robins 
               <interp inst="t17541204-33-person339" type="surname" value="Robins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person339" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person339" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             two or three; 
               <persName id="t17541204-33-person340">
                  Edward 
                  Parker 
               <interp inst="t17541204-33-person340" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person340" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person340" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             some years; 
               <persName id="t17541204-33-person341">
                  Elizabeth 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17541204-33-person341" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person341" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person341" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ten years; 
               <persName id="t17541204-33-person342">
                  Robert 
                  Nash 
               <interp inst="t17541204-33-person342" type="surname" value="Nash"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person342" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person342" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             six years; and 
               <persName id="t17541204-33-person343">
                  Samuel 
                  Sare 
               <interp inst="t17541204-33-person343" type="surname" value="Sare"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person343" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person343" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             one year; each gave her a good character. 
               <persName id="t17541204-33-person344">
                  Martha 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17541204-33-person344" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person344" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person344" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had known Jenkins two or three years, and 
               <persName id="t17541204-33-person345">
                  Edward 
                  Parker 
               <interp inst="t17541204-33-person345" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person345" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person345" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             eight years, who gave her a good character; the latter owned she was a little lightish.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541204-33-person346">
                  Thomas 
                  Warner 
               <interp inst="t17541204-33-person346" type="surname" value="Warner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person346" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person346" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I have known 
               <persName id="t17541204-33-person347">
                  Sarah 
                  Jenkins 
               <interp inst="t17541204-33-person347" type="surname" value="Jenkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person347" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person347" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , three years, and have been conversant with her pretty much; I have laid by her side almost two years.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you her husband?</p>
               <p>T. Warner. No; but I bought her of her husband for a gallon of beer.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you done any thing to support her?</p>
               <p>T. Warner. Yes, I have, and thought it my duty so to do; if she had been with child, I would have maintained it all the same as if she had been my lawful wife.</p>
               <p>Q. Has she never been with child to your knowledge?</p>
               <p>T. Warner. She was last Bartholomew-fair was twelve-month, and miscarried; since that I absconded from her; then she said she was with child, and I went and took a shop-mate with me, and went to her; then she said she never was with child.</p>
               <p>Q. You appear in no good light on his trial, pray what are you?</p>
               <p>T. Warner. I am a journeyman brushmaker.</p>
               <p>Q. What can you get per week ?</p>
               <p>T. Warner. Sixteen or eighteen shillings.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is this shop-mate you speak of?</p>
               <p>T. Warner. It is 
               <persName id="t17541204-33-person348">
                  James 
                  Cantril 
               <interp inst="t17541204-33-person348" type="surname" value="Cantril"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person348" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person348" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Then there was a talk of her being with child, was there not?</p>
               <p>T. Warner. Yes, and I asked her for a note; but I went and lived with her after that.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you absconded from her?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175412040040"></xptr>T. Warner. For about a week. She would come fuddled to the shop to me, and also abused me at a public-house.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this talk of her being with child?</p>
               <p>T. Warner. It was in pea-season, I don't knew justly the time.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did she lodge at the time you left her?</p>
               <p>T. Warner. In Pye corner</p>
               <p>Q. Did she not once live at Field's, in George-yard, Bow-lane ?</p>
               <p>T. Warner. I don't know that she did; she never lay there a night to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not she at Mrs. Maddox's ?</p>
               <p>T. Warner. I know nothing at all of Mrs. Maddox, or her being there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541204-33-person349">
                  Adam 
                  Goodman 
               <interp inst="t17541204-33-person349" type="surname" value="Goodman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person349" type="given" value="Adam"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person349" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and his wife deposed on the part of the prosecutor, that 
               <persName id="t17541204-33-person350">
                  Sarah 
                  Gasterel 
               <interp inst="t17541204-33-person350" type="surname" value="Gasterel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person350" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-person350" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             behaved well when chairwoman to them four or five years ago; but neither had seen her for a year and half or two years past.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17541204-33-verdict168" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17541204-33-verdict168" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Maddox was tried at the adjourment of the sessions at Guildhall, for keeping a disorderly house, and found guilty, and sentenced to stand on the pillory at the end of Queen-street, Cheapside on the 18th of this instant, and to be imprisoned in Newgate for three months.</p>
            </div1>
