<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17550515-27">
               <interp inst="t17550515-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550515-27" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550515-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550515"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550515-27" type="date" value="17550515"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550515-27-off130-c194" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-27-defend246 t17550515-27-off130 t17550515-27-verdict133"></join>
         
               <p>235. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17550515-27-defend246" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17550515-27-defend246" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-27-defend246" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-27-defend246" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17550515-27-deflabel129" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-27-defend246 t17550515-27-deflabel129"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17550515-27-off130" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550515-27-off130" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-27-off130" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one three-pound-twelve-shilling piece, and five shillings in money, numbered, privately from the person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17550515-27-victim248" type="victimName">
                           Jane 
                           Meredith 
                        <interp inst="t17550515-27-victim248" type="surname" value="Meredith"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550515-27-victim248" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550515-27-victim248" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-27-off130 t17550515-27-victim248"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , her property, <rs id="t17550515-27-cd131" type="crimeDate">Aug. 17</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-27-off130 t17550515-27-cd131"></join>.
It was laid over again for stealing one cloth cloak, one linen apron, one silk handkerchief, one linen handkerchief, one three-pound-twelve-shilling piece, and five shillings in money, numbered, the goods and money of 
                     <persName id="t17550515-27-person249">
                        Jane 
                        Meredith 
                     <interp inst="t17550515-27-person249" type="surname" value="Meredith"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550515-27-person249" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550515-27-person249" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , in the dwelling-house
            </rs> of Peter Ginnard. *</p>
               <p>Jane Meredith. I live with Mr. 
               <persName id="t17550515-27-person250">
                  Peter 
                  Ginnard 
               <interp inst="t17550515-27-person250" type="surname" value="Ginnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-27-person250" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-27-person250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in <placeName id="t17550515-27-crimeloc132">Fountain-court, Aldermanbury</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17550515-27-crimeloc132" type="placeName" value="Fountain-court, Aldermanbury"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550515-27-crimeloc132" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-27-off130 t17550515-27-crimeloc132"></join>; the prisoner came to our door on the Monday before last Bartholomew-fair; there had been a gentleman at our house, that dealt in Rapee-snuff, he was going out just as she came up to the door. She asked me, as I was standing at the door, if I wanted any lace? I said I did not. She said she had some that was very fine. I told her I wanted none at all. Then she told me she saw something in my face, from which she knew I little thought of coming in this place to live, or even living as a servant. I said I thought so too once. She said she would tell me a great deal more, if I would let her come in. I let her come in, and she and I went into the compting-house together; we sat down fronting the windows upon two leather chairs. She told me I was born to good fortune, and she understood all that by extrology; and that there was money hid in that house, in the cellar, and had been there for a long time, and that the time was expired when it<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175505150025"></xptr> was to be found, and it was to be my good fortune to find it. She said there were of it forty pounds in gold, and forty pounds in silver, two gold rings, two silver spoons, and such a gold cup as they used to receive the sacrament in in old times. She said she did not like to be in that room to talk with me, and asked if any body was in the house? I said there was no body in the house but us. Then I took her up into the dining-room, where she said, if I would trust her with six-pence to go out of the doors, to consult her books, she could tell me a great deal more when she came in. Accordingly I let her have six pence; she went out, and staid some time; and when she came in, she said, I was born to exceeding good fortune, and desired me to trust her with a couple of shillings more, and she could tell me more, which I did. She told me, before she went out, I must get two guineas in gold. I told her I had not so much. She asked me if I could get so much? I said I believed I could. Then she went out, and I went to madam Dunbar's to borrow two guineas. The young man told me he had no such money; but I was welcome to a three-pound-twelve-shilling piece, which he lent me, and I returned. She had before bid me put three pepper-corns in a little salt, and go into the farther part of the cellar, put it all together, and tie it all in the corner of a silk handkerchief, which I did accordingly; after which she came in with the two shillings, and asked me if I had got the money? I said I had not two guineas, but I had a three-pound-twelve shilling piece, and five shillings in silver. She said it would do just the same as in case I had five pounds. She and I went down into the cellar, to the place where I had been before, and took up a little of the dirt, put it into a handkerchief, and came up stairs with the money into the kitchen. She put up three-penny-worth of halfpence she had of her own in a little bit of a rag, and I put the three-pound-twelve, and five shillings in silver in another rag, with the dirt and pepper-corns, and the salt, as she had ordered me to do. She asked me if that silk handkerchief was the best I had? I said it was. She put as I thought, the half-pence and gold up in that together, and ordered me to keep it in my pocket till four o'clock, then she would come, and the stones were to turn all on one side, and the money was to come in a copper pot in the cellar. She asked me then to bring down the best gown I had, saying, she could have the same impression on the gown as on my person. She said she would only take it with her, and bring it again about four o'clock; I was not to look at the money in my pocket till she came at four o'clock. I believe she did not stay above five minutes after I came down stairs. After the woman was gone some time, I was willing to know my good fortune; I put my hand in my pocket, and to my great surprize, found only three penny-worth of halfpence, and some country dirt, not such as is in London, and some salt.</p>
               <p>Q. How long, after the woman was gone, was it that you went to look at the money?</p>
               <p>J. Meredith. I believe it was hardly half an hour after she was gone; then I came down stairs out of the dining-room, and looked about to see if she had not got something else. There were some drawers in the kitchen, in which were a good many silk stockings, I found them all safe; then looking round, I missed my cloak, a white linen apron, a silk handkerchief, and a white one, all my property.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see them last?</p>
               <p>J. Meredith. I had had the silk handkerchief and white apron on that morning at breakfast, and there had been no body near them from that time to the time I missed the things, but the prisoner and myself.</p>
               <p>Q. Is there any other woman or servant belonging to the house besides yourself?</p>
               <p>J. Meredith. No, none but myself, and both my masters were out at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever met with your cloak, handkerchief, or apron since?</p>
               <p>J. Meredith. No, I have not.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see the prisoner at the bar since?</p>
               <p>J. Meredith. Never till yesterday; except once I saw a woman, which I thought was she, at a chandler's shop; I went soon to see for her, but she was gone. I laid a trap for her at the Baptist's-head, that if ever she came there again, I would give half a guinea to have her taken.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you charge her with taking your cloak, money, and other things yesterday ?</p>
               <p>J. Meredith. I charged her with all the things and money I lost. She had an apron on, that was altered, and is an old thing now, but I knew it to be made of mine.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure that this is the woman that took the money and things from you?</p>
               <p>J. Meredith. I am sensible this is the very woman.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175505150026"></xptr>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I never saw her with my eyes; I am not guilty. Please your honour, I don't know what I shall say, I had not time to send for any witnesses, I was committed but yesterday.</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. This is the very woman that I talked to, that I gave the money to, and that returned me the money two different times.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17550515-27-verdict133" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550515-27-verdict133" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>She was detained to be tried next sessions for robbing a person of twenty-four guineas, in a dwelling-house, Jan. 13, in the 23rd year of his present majesty.</p>
               <p>(Compare this with the trial of 
               <persName id="t17550515-27-person251">
                  Mary 
                  Norman 
               <interp inst="t17550515-27-person251" type="surname" value="Norman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-27-person251" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-27-person251" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a gypsey, for a crime of the same nature on Mr. Huntley's servant at Edmonton, No. 424, in alderman Cockayne's mayoralty. )</p>
            </div1>
