<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17520408-5">
               <interp inst="t17520408-5" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520408-5" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520408-5" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520408"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520408-5" type="date" value="17520408"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520408-5-off31-c60" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520408-5-defend70 t17520408-5-off31 t17520408-5-verdict34"></join>
         
               <p>213. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17520408-5-defend70" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Sheel 
                  <interp inst="t17520408-5-defend70" type="surname" value="Sheel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-5-defend70" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-5-defend70" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17520408-5-off31" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520408-5-off31" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-5-off31" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing two guineas, one half guinea, and one ruby stone, the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17520408-5-victim72" type="victimName">
                           Ruben 
                           Adolphus 
                        <interp inst="t17520408-5-victim72" type="surname" value="Adolphus"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520408-5-victim72" type="given" value="Ruben"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520408-5-victim72" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520408-5-off31 t17520408-5-victim72"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , secretly from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17520408-5-cd32" type="crimeDate">March 11</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520408-5-off31 t17520408-5-cd32"></join>. *</p>
               <p>Ruben Adolphus. I was at the oratorio in <placeName id="t17520408-5-crimeloc33">Covent Garden</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17520408-5-crimeloc33" type="placeName" value="Covent Garden"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520408-5-crimeloc33" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520408-5-off31 t17520408-5-crimeloc33"></join>, March 11, the prisoner was near me, besides whom there was none but good company: I felt her hand about my breeches; when she was gone, I put my hand down for my purse, and found it gone, I went down to an orange girl at the door and described the prisoner; she said, the prisoner was then up stairs, I went up and found her, I told her, she had picked my pocket; I desired to have her searched; I left her in custody; I went up stairs to that part of the gallery, where I was informed she had concealed herself; there I found my purse and a little bit of paper by it, which paper I believe to be the paper the ruby stone was wrapt in; I came down again, and asked her what she had done with my money. She said she knew nothing of it. The constable said, he believed she had dropped something under her; I looked down, and there found my ruby stone; she was taken to the round house and searched, of which the woman who searched her will give an account.</p>
               <p>Q. What money did you loose?</p>
               <p>Adolphus. I had three half guineas and one guinea in gold in my pocket, in my purse, which were gone, when I felt in my pocket.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520408-5-person73">
                  John 
                  Rice 
               <interp inst="t17520408-5-person73" type="surname" value="Rice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-5-person73" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-5-person73" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable. I was called to take charge of the prisoner, I had her under the stairs at the door, while the prosecutor went up to look for his purse with the gallery keeper: I saw her fumbling about her pocket, then I imagined she wanted to drop something out of it; he came down, and said, he had found the purse, and bid me take her before the justice. I bid him look under her, saying, I thought she had dropt something, he took the candle and looked, and there he found the ruby stone. (The stone produced and deposed to by the prosecutor.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520408-5-person74">
                  Joyce 
                  Carey 
               <interp inst="t17520408-5-person74" type="surname" value="Carey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-5-person74" type="given" value="Joyce"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-5-person74" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was brought to Covent Garden watchouse, they were going to search her; I desired the men to go away and I would: I did, and found half a guinea conceal'd in her mouth, there were only a shilling and some half-pence in her pocket.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I am a very honest girl, I came up from out of the country for a service about three weeks before.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520408-5-verdict34" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520408-5-verdict34" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
