<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17521206-36">
               <interp inst="t17521206-36" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521206-36" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521206-36" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17521206"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521206-36" type="date" value="17521206"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17521206-36-off178-c226" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-36-defend293 t17521206-36-off178 t17521206-36-verdict181"></join>
         
               <p>43. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17521206-36-defend293" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Cross 
                  <interp inst="t17521206-36-defend293" type="surname" value="Cross"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-36-defend293" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-36-defend293" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17521206-36-off178" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17521206-36-off178" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-36-off178" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one trunk value 3 s. eight linnen shirts value 15 s. ten holland stocks value 3 s. three pair of thread stockings value 2 s. two pair of cotton stockings value 2 s. one holland waistcoat value 7 s. one silver snuff-box value 18 s. one Portugal piece of gold, and two guineas, the goods and money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17521206-36-victim295" type="victimName">
                           Edward 
                           Price 
                        <interp inst="t17521206-36-victim295" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17521206-36-victim295" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17521206-36-victim295" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-36-off178 t17521206-36-victim295"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  ; one promissory note signed under the hand of Margaret Wright, spinster, bearing date 1751, value 100 l. by which note the said Margaret did promise to pay the sum of 100 l. upon demand, at 4 per Cent. to the said Edward, in the dwelling house of Robert Hall
            </rs>, <rs id="t17521206-36-cd179" type="crimeDate">November 20</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-36-off178 t17521206-36-cd179"></join>. *</p>
               <p>Edward Price. I lodge at Mr. Hall's house in <placeName id="t17521206-36-crimeloc180">Eagle-Street, St. James's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17521206-36-crimeloc180" type="placeName" value="Eagle-Street, St. James's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17521206-36-crimeloc180" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-36-off178 t17521206-36-crimeloc180"></join>, near the church. About seven or eight weeks ago I lost a shirt taken off a line, and about three weeks after that I lost a pair of shoes from out of the bar (it is a publick house); on the 25th of November I lost my trunk out of my bedchamber with the goods mentioned in the indictment. He names them by name, and their value is laid, and a note of hand produced in court and real to this purport.</p>
               <p>September 20, 1751. Borrowed of 
               <persName id="t17521206-36-person296">
                  Edward 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17521206-36-person296" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-36-person296" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-36-person296" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the sum of one hundred pounds, which I promise to pay upon demand, with lawful interest at 4 per Cent. Witness my hand,</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521206-36-person297">
                  Margaret 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17521206-36-person297" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-36-person297" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-36-person297" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
         
               <p>The Second Part of these Procedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17521206-36">
                  <interp inst="t17521206-36" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17521206-36" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17521206-36" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17521206"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17521206-36" type="date" value="17521206"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175212060021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Goal Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the Goal Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 6th, Thursday the 7th, and Friday the 8th of December,</p>
                  <p>In the 26th Year of His MAJESTY's Reign, BEING THE First SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of the Right Honble Sir CRISP GASCOYNE, Knt. LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>NUMBER I. PART II.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by M. COOPER, at the Globe in Pater-noster Row. 1752.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-Pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175212060022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Goal Delivery held for the City of London, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Q. WHEN did you see these things you mention last?</p>
               <p>Price. I saw them on the Friday, the day before they were lost.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the trunk lock'd?</p>
               <p>Price. It was, and I had the key in my pocket. The prisoner and I lay together; I never knew him before he came there; I suspected him and took him up when I missed the trunk, which was on the Sunday morning. I had him before Justice St. Lawrence, but he would not confess; the Justice sent him to the Round-house; before he went in he turned his head, and said to Mr. Hall, I don't know what to do, I'd speak with you; then he said, I have made such a vow, for which I am d - d for ever. Then he said, one How fetched the trunk down, and he stood in Piccadilly, at the end of the street, and received it, and went to open it in a Court, and was not quick enough, then How opened it with a crooked nail; that one took the 36 s. piece, and the other the two guineas; then he went to Salisbury-Court, and lodged the trunk at a Green Grocer's all night; the next day he went to the Cross Key's in Wood-street, and sent it down to Stratford upon Avon, with the other things in it. I sent an evidence that is here, and it was brought up to town last Monday; there were in it, when it came back, five shirts, ten stocks, the silver snuff-box, two razor-cases, four razors, and the note of hand. The money and two shirts were gone. This How is out of the way and not to be found.</p>
               <p>Robert Hall. On Saturday the 25th of November the prosecutor complained he had lost the things mentioned, upon which I went up stairs to see if the trunk was not misplaced, but could not find it; after that Cross (the prisoner) and I went into the yard together; I said to him, I suspect you to have it, and if you'll confess it and bring it again, perhaps you may save your life; he answered, here is Archbolt, (a man that lay in the same room) it must be either he or I, but I have it not; I went for a warrant to take him up, he went out with a pretence to have his wig comb'd, and when I return'd he was gone; one Monday morning I saw him near Golden-Square and took him up; and had him before the Justice, he confess'd nothing there, we took him to the round-house; just before he was going in, he desir'd to speak with me; so we went on one side, he then said he had made so black an oath that he should be d - d for ever if he declar'd it; he pull'd the 36 s. piece out of his shoe and gave it me, (produced in court) and said it was taken out of the trunk, and that 
               <persName id="t17521206-36-person298">
                  Edward 
                  How 
               <interp inst="t17521206-36-person298" type="surname" value="How"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-36-person298" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-36-person298" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had the two guineas; 
               <persName id="t17521206-36-person299">
                  Edward 
                  How 
               <interp inst="t17521206-36-person299" type="surname" value="How"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-36-person299" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-36-person299" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came on the Saturday night and drank two pints of beer with the person that was robb'd; the prisoner said How went up stairs and brought the trunk down to him at the corner of Eagle-Street Picadilly ; then he said they went with it into Gibson's-Court, and he would have opened it, but could not do it quick enough; that then How said, I'll open it in a minute; that he took a crooked nail out of his pocket and opened it, and then they shared the money. Then the prisoners took the box to Salisbury-Court and lodged it at a green grocer's all night; the next morning he carried it to the Cross-Keys<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175212060023"></xptr> in Wood-Street, and wrote a direction on it with his own hard, and delivered it to 
               <persName id="t17521206-36-person300">
                  Richard 
                  Darby 
               <interp inst="t17521206-36-person300" type="surname" value="Darby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-36-person300" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-36-person300" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to go down to Stratford upon Avon in the waggon; we sent down William Archbolt after it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521206-36-person301">
                  William 
                  Archbolt 
               <interp inst="t17521206-36-person301" type="surname" value="Archbolt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-36-person301" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-36-person301" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knowing the trunk was sent to Stratford upon Avon for this box, which I found at Wheatley by Oxford in the waggon. I had Cross's hand writing with me for it and the justice's warrant; the trunk was brought into the kitchen at an inn there and opened before me. The things produced here were in it.</p>
               <p>Q. How was it directed?</p>
               <p>Archbolt. It was directed to 
               <persName id="t17521206-36-person302">
                  William 
                  Cross 
               <interp inst="t17521206-36-person302" type="surname" value="Cross"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-36-person302" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-36-person302" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to be left at such an inn at Stratford upon Avon.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you bring it up?</p>
               <p>Archbolt. No, my lord, they mistrusted me, and thought I was a confederate of Cross's, and were going to send me to goal; it was returned by Mr. Roberts the Banbury carrier, and delivered by the owner before justice Lediard.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know it again?</p>
               <p>Archbolt. This is the same produced here.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521206-36-person303">
                  Richard 
                  Darby 
               <interp inst="t17521206-36-person303" type="surname" value="Darby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-36-person303" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-36-person303" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I belong to the waggon; the prisoner at the bar brought this box to me last Sunday was se'nnight, it was locked and directed for himself, to be left at the Crown in Stratford, but my directions, which I received from him, were to leave it at the White Lion in Stratford. I nailed the direction on it, and loaded it into the waggon.</p>
               <p>The prisoner had nothing to say in his defence.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521206-36-person304">
                  Charles 
                  Chillingworth 
               <interp inst="t17521206-36-person304" type="surname" value="Chillingworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-36-person304" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-36-person304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner lived with me as an errand-boy about three quarters of a year, and behaved himself very honestly then. I know nothing of him since.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17521206-36-verdict181" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17521206-36-verdict181" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17521206-36-punish182" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17521206-36-punish182" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-36-defend293 t17521206-36-punish182"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
