<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17500711-33">
               <interp inst="t17500711-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-33" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17500711"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-33" type="date" value="17500711"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500711-33-off147-c237" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-33-defend302 t17500711-33-off147 t17500711-33-verdict149"></join>
         
               <p>454. 
               
                  <persName id="t17500711-33-defend302" type="defendantName">
                     Anthony 
                     Barnes 
                  <interp inst="t17500711-33-defend302" type="surname" value="Barnes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-33-defend302" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-33-defend302" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17500711-33-off147" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500711-33-off147" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-33-off147" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               making an assault on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17500711-33-victim304" type="victimName">
                           Elizabeth 
                           Hodgkin 
                        <interp inst="t17500711-33-victim304" type="surname" value="Hodgkin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500711-33-victim304" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500711-33-victim304" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-33-off147 t17500711-33-victim304"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , spinster, and her, the said Elizabeth, did ravish and carnally know
            </rs>, <rs id="t17500711-33-cd148" type="crimeDate">June 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-33-off147 t17500711-33-cd148"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. How old are you?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-33-person305">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Hodgkin 
               <interp inst="t17500711-33-person305" type="surname" value="Hodgkin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-33-person305" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-33-person305" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am eleven years old.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the consequence of taking a false oath?</p>
               <p>Eliz. Hodgkin. Yes, I shall go to hell if I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the prisoner at the bar?</p>
               <p>E. Hodgkin. Yes, I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Tell us what he did to you at any time ?</p>
               <p>E. Hodgkin. I went up stairs for my doll on Whitsunday in the afternoon, and Mrs. Avery pull'd me into her room and locked me in, and took up a pot and said she would go and fetch some beer.</p>

               <p>Q. Was the prisoner in the room?</p>
               <p>E. Hodgkin. Yes, he was. She set down the pot and did not fetch any beer.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner do to you?</p>
               <p>E. Hodgkin. He threw me down on the bed, and pull'd up my coats, covered my eyes, and stopp'd my mouth, because I called to Mrs. Avery and another of our lodgers. He hurt me very much, he pull'd down his breeches.</p>
         
               <p>At this sessions above 80 prisoners were tried, some of which trials being long and very remarkable, we thought it would be more agreeable to our readers (who we shall at all times be desirous of obliging) to have as full an account as possible, so shall print the whole in two four-penny books.</p>
               <p>N. B. The second part will be published on Friday next the 27th instant.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17500711-33">
                  <interp inst="t17500711-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17500711-33" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17500711-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17500711"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17500711-33" type="date" value="17500711"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175007110021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX,</p>
                  <p>HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY,</p>
                  <p>On Wednesday the 11th, Thursday the 12th, Friday the 13th, and Saturday the 14th of July.</p>
                  <p>In the 24th Year of His MAJESTY's Reign.</p>
                  <p>PART II. of NUMBER VI. for the Year 1749.</p>
                  <p>BEING THE Second SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of the</p>
                  <p>Right Honble 
                  <persName id="t17500711-33-person306">
                     John 
                     Blachford 
                  <interp inst="t17500711-33-person306" type="surname" value="Blachford"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500711-33-person306" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500711-33-person306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Esq; LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by M. COOPER, at the Globe in Pater-noster Row. 1750.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175007110022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery held for the City of London, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Q. IN what manner did he hurt you?</p>
               <p>E. Hodgkin. He hurt me very much.</p>
               <p>Q. Whereabouts did he hurt you?</p>
               <p>E. Hodgkin. In the place where I make water.</p>
               <p>Q. With what did he hurt you?</p>
               <p>E. Hodgkin. With what he makes water, that part went into me; he made me very sore.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find yourself sore immediately?</p>
               <p>E. Hodgkin. Yes, I did, I could hardly walk.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you bloody?</p>
               <p>E. Hodgkin. No, not bloody.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you so very sore ?</p>

               <p>E. Hodgkin. The foreness was in that part where I make water.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he lie upon you?</p>
               <p>E. Hodgkin. Above a quarter of an hour; after that he held me on the bed, and told me, if I would not promise him that I would not tell any body, he would kill me then; and if I did tell any body, he'd kill me afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you first tell your relations?</p>
               <p>E. Hodgkin. I told my mama first, about a fortnight after.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did not you tell her sooner ?</p>
               <p>E. Hodgkin. I was afraid he would kill me.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you tell her then?</p>
               <p>E. Hodgkin. Because she examined me very much.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know him before ?</p>
               <p>E. Hodgkin. I knew him by his coming to our lodger before.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he stop your mouth with?</p>
               <p>E. Hodgkin. With his handkerchief, and I believe that covered my eyes too.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Mr. Avery in the room at that time?</p>
               <p>E. Hodgkin. If he was, he must be in the closet, for I did not see him in the room.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you use to see him after this very frequently going up and down?</p>
               <p>E. Hodgkin. Yes, Sir, I did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-33-person307">
                  Mary 
                  Hodgkin 
               <interp inst="t17500711-33-person307" type="surname" value="Hodgkin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-33-person307" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-33-person307" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am mother to the child. I know nothing of the prisoner any farther than his coming to our lodger, who was his cousin, he was seldom out on a Sabbath-day. I perceived the child very ill, and sick at her stomach; and one day I sent her out as far as Spittlefields, she staid three hours, and she used to go and come again in an hour. I asked her why she staid so long? she said she could not tell me what was the matter; and I had no suspicion of any thing, till I found a great running upon her; then I gave her some turpentine pills, yet she was no better. Her first shift she pulled off I did not observe, but the next was very bad; she shifts once a week. Then I advised with Mrs. Emory, who desired me to go to a surgeon; I did. She told me something of it before I went to the surgeon, and said she had a running in three days after he had used her so. At the surgeon's she told more about it, and is continually telling us more of it.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the prisoner taken up?</p>
               <p>M. Hodgkin. The child confessed it on the Saturday, and I never attempted to take him up till the Thursday following. He came the Sunday following.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did not you take him up sooner?</p>
               <p>M. Hodgkin. The reason was, I was told I could do nothing without the approbation of a surgeon to assist me upon the trial. Indeed, I had hardly patience to forbear him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it known in the house before you took him up?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175007110023"></xptr>M. Hodgkin He had been charged with it before I took him up. The child would sit all on one upon a chair, and at last of all, she told me she should be murdered if she told.</p>
               <p>Thomas Hill. I am an apothecary. I was applied to about 15 days since; I examined the parts, and found them very much inflamed and swelled; she had a considerable running upon her, I looked upon it to be venereal. She is now in a very good way of doing well, but not perfectly well.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the parts been lacerated?</p>
               <p>Hill. They had, my lord, and I thing she could not have been in the condition she was, without some person having carnal knowledge of her.</p>
               <p>Q. Could these parts be lacerated, and no blood appear ?</p>
               <p>Hill. That is very extraordinary to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Could a man have a penetration, and no blood appear?</p>
               <p>Hill. I think not; I cannot conceive but there must have been blood.</p>
               <p>Q. Could not the infection be taken by a contraction of the parts without penetration.</p>
               <p>Hill. I believe not to so great a degree as she had it; there was a considerable discharge from the internal parts.</p>
               <p>M. Hodgkin. My other witness can give no other account, only testify the child is a sober child. The prisoner has taken physick every two or three days since that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there no blood on the child's linen, are you sure?</p>
               <p>M. Hodgkin. There might or might not be blood for aught I know; I did not then (as I said before) observe: when we took the prisoner up, Mrs. Avery said he would be killed, because he had taken physick the day before. I said, why, what is the matter? she said her husband knew what was the matter.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence. I am innocent, I know nothing of the affair.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-33-person308">
                  Richard 
                  Avery 
               <interp inst="t17500711-33-person308" type="surname" value="Avery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-33-person308" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-33-person308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never all the time on Whit-sunday was out of my room, from the time I got out of my bed, to the time I went to bed again at night. The prisoner was with me all the day.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the little girl in the room any time that day?</p>
               <p>Avery. Yes, she was; my wife never left the girl in the room with the prisoner alone.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-33-person309">
                  Mary 
                  Avery 
               <interp inst="t17500711-33-person309" type="surname" value="Avery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-33-person309" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-33-person309" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The last witness is my husband. I remember the prisoner's coming to our room on Whitsunday; I was not out at all, but was there from the time the girl came into the room to the time she went out; I never fetch'd a draught of beer that day; there were only my husband, the prisoner and me in the room ; I was not down stairs all the afternoon, nor did I lock her in the room; and my husband was never down stairs from the time he got up to the time he went to bed.</p>
               <p>Mr. Brown. I am a shoemaker, and the prisoner's master. He has worked for me best part of two years; I took a vast deal of notice of him on account of his sobriety : when he was ill, I took him into my house, and he eat as I did; I never heard any bad character of him, or heard him say any bad words.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-33-person310">
                  Robert 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17500711-33-person310" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-33-person310" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-33-person310" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know nothing at all of the prisoner. The mother of the child told me she would stick as close by him as the shirt to his back, except he would come down and give the child a good fortune, and send her into the country, that it might not blast her character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-33-person311">
                  Michael 
                  Morand 
               <interp inst="t17500711-33-person311" type="surname" value="Morand"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-33-person311" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-33-person311" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner lived some time in my house; I have known him about half a year: I always esteemed him as a sober man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500711-33-verdict149" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500711-33-verdict149" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
