<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17550409-10">
               <interp inst="t17550409-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550409-10" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550409-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550409"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550409-10" type="date" value="17550409"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550409-10-off54-c77" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550409-10-defend90 t17550409-10-off54 t17550409-10-verdict57"></join>
         
               <p>162. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17550409-10-defend90" type="defendantName">
                  Thomas 
                  Lloyd 
               <interp inst="t17550409-10-defend90" type="surname" value="Lloyd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550409-10-defend90" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550409-10-defend90" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17550409-10-off54" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550409-10-off54" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550409-10-off54" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing two shillings and three-halfpence in money numbered
            </rs>, the money of 
               
                  <persName id="t17550409-10-victim92" type="victimName">
                     Humphrey 
                     Nightingale 
                  <interp inst="t17550409-10-victim92" type="surname" value="Nightingale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550409-10-victim92" type="given" value="Humphrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550409-10-victim92" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550409-10-off54 t17550409-10-victim92"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17550409-10-cd55" type="crimeDate">March 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550409-10-off54 t17550409-10-cd55"></join>.* </p> 
               <p>Humphrey Nightingale. The prisoner has been my <rs id="t17550409-10-deflabel56" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550409-10-defend90 t17550409-10-deflabel56"></join> about fifteen or sixteen months; about a month before I detected him I had reason to suspect him of robbing my till, and in order to detect him, I ordered my servant, 
               <persName id="t17550409-10-person93">
                  Samuel 
                  Tompkins 
               <interp inst="t17550409-10-person93" type="surname" value="Tompkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550409-10-person93" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550409-10-person93" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to mark some halfpence and some silver, which he did; he marked forty-five shillings in silver, and five shillings in halfpence.</p>
               <p>Q. How were they marked?</p>
               <p>Nightingale. He marked them with a cross.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him mark them?</p>
               <p>Nightingale. I saw them after they were mark'd; then, on the 29th of March, I made an appointment with some friends to go out of town the next day. This I did in the prisoner's hearing. I got up the next morning, and I ordered Tompkins, my other servant, to go and dress himself, as if he was going out too. When he came down stairs, I ordered him to go and open the street-door, and shut it again, as if he had gone out; after that I did the same. I bid Tompkins go down into the cellar, and shut himself up in the vault there, and I went and concealed myself in the parlour behind the shop.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this marked money at this time?</p>
               <p>Nightingale. It was then in my till in the shop. I had not been in the parlour a quarter of an hour before the prisoner came down stairs, and went into the cellar; presently after I saw him in the shop; he went behind the counter and drew out the till; I saw his hand in the till, and heard the halfpence jink. After that I saw him put his hand into his pocket twice; then he put the till in again, and was returning back. I rushed out of the parlour in order to take him,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175504090008"></xptr> but he was too nimble for me, and got down the hole.</p>
               <p>Q. What hole was that?</p>
               <p>Nightingale. It was a hole through which we shoot down the coals. Tomkins being below he got hold of the prisoner's legs, and held him till I came. I bid him examine his left-hand pocket, and there he would find some money; he then pulled out some marked halfpence and two sixpences.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the silver and halfpence all in one till.</p>
               <p>Nightingale. There were three or four partitions in the till to separate the halfpence, the silver, and the gold. After that I counted the halfpence and found he had taken thirteen-pence-halfpeny in marked halfpence; I charged him with taking the money out of my till, he owned he had, and also that he had been there before, but had not taken much.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he mention any sum?</p>
               <p>Nightingale. He said he had not taken above ten shillings in all.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550409-10-person94">
                  Samuel 
                  Tompkins 
               <interp inst="t17550409-10-person94" type="surname" value="Tompkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550409-10-person94" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550409-10-person94" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was concealed in the vault in the cellar at this time; I saw the prisoner come down into the cellar, and through the hole up into the shop, and I heard him move after he was in the shop; then I heard my master go towards him; then he came down the hole again, and I seized him. I examined his pockets, and took part of the money from him there; and part above, which I counted before his face, the halfpence were all marked; there were thirteen-pence-halfpeny and two six-pences in his pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the six-pences marked?</p>
               <p>Tompkins. No, they were not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I am guilty of the fact.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17550409-10-verdict57" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550409-10-verdict57" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17550409-10-punish58" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550409-10-punish58" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550409-10-defend90 t17550409-10-punish58"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
