<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17540911-12">
               <interp inst="t17540911-12" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-12" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-12" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-12" type="date" value="17540911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540911-12-off64-c94" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-12-defend115 t17540911-12-off64 t17540911-12-verdict69"></join>
         
               <p>424. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17540911-12-defend115" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Haines 
                  <interp inst="t17540911-12-defend115" type="surname" value="Haines"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-12-defend115" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-12-defend115" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17540911-12-off64" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540911-12-off64" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-12-off64" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he, on the king's highway on 
                     <persName id="t17540911-12-victim116" type="victimName">
                        Deadot, <rs id="t17540911-12-viclabel65" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-12-victim116 t17540911-12-viclabel65"></join> of John Quane<interp inst="t17540911-12-victim116" type="given" value="Deadot"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540911-12-victim116" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-12-off64 t17540911-12-victim116"></join>
                     </persName>
                   did rob putting her in corporal fear and, and one silk purse, val. 2 s. with eight guineas, the property of the said John, from the person of the said Deadot, did steal, take and carry away
            </rs>, <rs id="t17540911-12-cd66" type="crimeDate">Aug. 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-12-off64 t17540911-12-cd66"></join>. +</p>
               <p>Deadot Quane. On the 18th of August last, between three and four in the afternoon, and I was going to Windsor in my carrot, I was stopp'd between <placeName id="t17540911-12-crimeloc67">Hounslow Heath</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17540911-12-crimeloc67" type="placeName" value="Hounslow Heath"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17540911-12-crimeloc67" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-12-off64 t17540911-12-crimeloc67"></join> and <placeName id="t17540911-12-crimeloc68">Cranford Bridge</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17540911-12-crimeloc68" type="placeName" value="Cranford Bridge"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17540911-12-crimeloc68" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-12-off64 t17540911-12-crimeloc68"></join>, it being a very hot day, and my blinds being down: When my chariot stopp'd I fancied my coachman was going to water the horses. I lifted up the bd on the right side to look out and bid him go on, and there saw the prisoner on horseback with a pistol pointing in at the window. His hand shook very much, and I expected by the motion of it the pistol would have gone off every minutes. He said, Deliver up your money, or I'll How your bins out. I was taking off a bracelet from my right hand, and told him at the same time that he should not have it; the spring being very difficult to undo, I could not get it off in less than two or three minutes. Then I put my hand into my pocket, and took out a blue silk purse and gave to him. I think there were nine guineas in it, but I can swear to eight. A gentleman, Monsieur Debreau, whom I was carrying to shew him Windsor, and who is since returned to France, gave him, as he thought, about 26 s. He took up a pistol, and was very angry with me that I would not let him shoot the prisoner. I asked the prisoner how long he had been of this business; he said that was the first time of his robbing on the highway, and he must have been arrested if he had not done it. He said, he hoped I'd do him no harm, but I told him I should do as I thought proper as to that. I had an opportunity to examine his horse in this time, and found he was lame. As he went off he turned down into a lane on the right hand. I called to my servant, and told him I thought it was easy to take him. We stopped and I got out of my chariot. We saw a coach and fix with some servants on horseback coming, which was Sir Kendal Clayton's. When they came up I told the gentleman I had been robbed, and desired he'd let his servants go to help in taking the highwayman. He consented to it, but there was no horse for my servant to mount; till a young man happening to come upon the road on horseback, I begg'd he'd lend me his horse, which he did. My servant mounted him, and went after the other two servants. I went on to Cranford Bridge and ordered my dinner, and in about a hour from the time of the robbery was brought in at Cranford Bridge Bridge was asked what could induce him to vous a practice. He and, he had three children in necessity, and begg'd for mercy.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he know you in ?</p>
               <p>D. Quane. He did instantly, and said, I could but take away his life. I answered, we did not intend to do any thing more with it. Then we took him to Justice Birkhead, where he was searched, and denied having the purse. I said, how can you have the impudence to deny it? be honest once in your life before you are and tell me what you have done with it. He said than he had put it under his saddle upon his horse. But I should have told your Lordship, that going with him to the justice's he pretended to faint, and tumbled from his horse. There was a soldier in a chaise. I desired him to take him into his chaise, which he did, and this soldier being at the justice's. I desired him to go to the stable and see for the purse. He went, but whether the soldier play'd a trick upon the highwayman or not, I don't know; but he brought me the purse empty.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-12-person117">
                  William 
                  Carlton 
               <interp inst="t17540911-12-person117" type="surname" value="Carlton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-12-person117" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-12-person117" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             produces a purse.</p>
               <p>D. Quane. This is the purse.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he own the robbery before the justice?</p>
               <p>D. Quane. He did not deny it.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any arms found upon him?</p>
               <p>D. Quane. There was a pistol prodigiously loaded. and some shot and powder found upon him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he masked or unmasked ?</p>
               <p>D. Quane. Unmasked. I am very certain that man who stands at the bar is the man who robbed me.</p>
               <p>Q. How long might he be by the side of your chariot?</p>
               <p>D. Quane. He might be there five or six minutes.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-12-person118">
                  William 
                  Robertson 
               <interp inst="t17540911-12-person118" type="surname" value="Robertson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-12-person118" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-12-person118" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am footman to the prosecutrix. On the 18th of August last, between three and four in the afternoon, I was behind the chariot on Hounslow Heath. I first saw the prisoner at about a hundred yards from us. When he came pretty near he looked round me and went past the chariot, and peep'd in; then he sell back five or six yards. I kept a very strict eye upon him, and saw him put his hand into his right hand coat pocket, and saw the end of a pistol coming out.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175409110008"></xptr> Then he rode up to the chariot and called to the coachman to stop. The coachman said, ha! Stop, said the prisoner. The coachman seeing the pistol, stopped. My lady looked out, and the pistol was presented to her.</p>
               <p>Q. How near the chariot was the prisoner ?</p>
               <p>Robertson. He was within two yards of it then. He said, Your money. My lady said, ha! Your money, said he, directly, or I'll blow your brains out. My lady said, Very well, you shall have my money. I saw her give him a blue purse, and saw gold shine through it, and some silver given him afterwards. After he had received it he put that and the pistol into his pocket, and rode on half a mile a little distance from the chariot. When he got between the two heaths he turned down on the right hand side towards Butchers Grove. I begged of my lady to let me have one of the pistols out of the chariot to go and pursue him. I saw a coach and six coming behind. My lady desired the gentleman to let me have a horse to pursue. He was not willing to that, but sent his two servants after the prisoner. A young gentleman coming by, my lady begged of him to let me have his horse, which he did. I mounted, and taking a brace of pistols, followed. I found in about a mile and half that the two servants had stopped him, I rode up with a pistol, telling him, if he did not resign I would blow his brains out directly. He said, he had resigned. Then we tied his hands, and took him to Cranford Bridge to my lady. After that we went back to Hounslow to the justice, and there he owned where the purse was. Mr. Clayton's servant and a soldier went to see for it, and I saw the purse taken from under the saddle of the horse, as I had hold of the horse.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at the prisoner again, are you certain he is the man?</p>
               <p>Robertson. I am sure of it, my lord.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-12-person119">
                  William 
                  Gascoyne 
               <interp inst="t17540911-12-person119" type="surname" value="Gascoyne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-12-person119" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-12-person119" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was driving the chariot with my lady in it on the 18th of August, and aboat the middle of Hounslow Heath the prisoner came to us. He first came opposite to me, then drew his horse back, and then came up again, biding me stop. I said, ha! He said, stop coachman. I stopped, and my lady putting her head out at the chariot door, he said, Your money, madam. He had his pistol in his hand, cocking it at the time. I saw the money in a purse delivered to him. He put it in his pocket, and was going on, but turned back and said to the gentleman in the chariot, Sir, I hope you will not hurt me; for it was necessity that drove me to it, and if I had not done this I must have gone to prison. He rode on about half a mile before the chariot, and at the first turning on the right hand he struck off. Then we stopped and my lady got out of the chariot, and Sir Kendal Clayton coming by with two servants - .</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure the prisoner is the man that did the robbery ?</p>
               <p>Gascoyne. I am certain he is the man.</p>
               <p>Q. What colour was his periwig ?</p>
               <p>Gascoyne. He had, I believe, a grey wig on, not the same he has on now (Which was a black one).</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-12-person120">
                  William 
                  Carlton 
               <interp inst="t17540911-12-person120" type="surname" value="Carlton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-12-person120" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-12-person120" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17540911-12-person121">
                  William 
                  Clayton 
               <interp inst="t17540911-12-person121" type="surname" value="Clayton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-12-person121" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-12-person121" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , it was his coach and horses, not Sir Kendal's. As we were coming almost to the eleventh mile stone upon Hounslow Heath some people on foot told us a lady had been robbed, and said the man might be soon taken. We went on and saw the chariot and the lady standing by it; my master stop'd his coach to see what was the matter. We were told she had just been robbed, and were shewn which way the highwayman was gone. They desired my master's horses to pursue, and he accordingly ordered me and my fellow servant to go after him. About half a mile down the lane we found the prisoner dismounted standing by his horse, and seized him directly. We asked him if he had not robbed a lady in a chariot. He said, he had, and that necessity drove him to it, and begged we'd let him go. I said we must take him to the lady at Cranford Bridge, which we did then, and before the justice.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he confess any thing there ?</p>
               <p>Carlton. He did not deny but that he took the money, but he did not know what he had done with it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was going down to Reading. The day being very hot, I denied at Brentford, and stopp'd at three or four places besides, and drank some cyder mixed, what we call on board shangaree. I found myself in liquor, and going down this lane thought of easing myself, and got off my horse. I hope you will consider, whether, if I had been guilty of so great a crime as laid to my charge, I should have been so stupid as not to have got off at that time. One of the men said, he'd blow out my brains if I did not surrender, saying, I was the man by my coat and horse; I had three pistols cock'd to my head at once. The reason I had a pistol in my pocket was, because I had been confined in a mad house three times, and was told I should be<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175409110009"></xptr> taken and put in again; so I carried that every day to defend myself.</p>
               <p>prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-12-person122">
                  James 
                  Svn 
               <interp inst="t17540911-12-person122" type="surname" value="Svn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-12-person122" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-12-person122" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in May Fair. The prisoner has worked with me some year. I sell and a copper; his right name is Savage. I never knew any thing dishonest of him b.</p>
               <p>Elizabeth nton. I have lodged at the prisoner or four years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character ?</p>
               <p>L. He is a drunken mad fellow, and has been four time in a mad house, but he is a very honest man as far as I know. As to this affair I can say nothing.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-12-person123">
                  Sarah 
                  Lenton 
               <interp inst="t17540911-12-person123" type="surname" value="Lenton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-12-person123" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-12-person123" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him almost four years. He has been in a mad house several times, and has certainly lost his reason, but has a very good character is to honesty.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540911-12-verdict69" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540911-12-verdict69" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17540911-12-punish70" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540911-12-punish70" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-12-defend115 t17540911-12-punish70"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
