<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17521026-18">
               <interp inst="t17521026-18" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521026-18" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521026-18" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17521026"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521026-18" type="date" value="17521026"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17521026-18-off97-c109" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521026-18-defend142 t17521026-18-off97 t17521026-18-verdict101"></join>
         
               <p>518. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17521026-18-defend142" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Simon 
                  <interp inst="t17521026-18-defend142" type="surname" value="Simon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-defend142" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-defend142" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17521026-18-off97" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-off97" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-off97" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing one pair of silver buckles, val. 5 s. one guinea. and 5 s in money, privately and secretly from the person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17521026-18-victim144" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Grear 
                        <interp inst="t17521026-18-victim144" type="surname" value="Grear"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17521026-18-victim144" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17521026-18-victim144" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521026-18-off97 t17521026-18-victim144"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, his property, <rs id="t17521026-18-cd98" type="crimeDate">Oct. 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521026-18-off97 t17521026-18-cd98"></join>. * </p>
               <p>Thomas Grear. The prisoner came into the <placeName id="t17521026-18-crimeloc99">Six Bells at Kensington</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17521026-18-crimeloc99" type="placeName" value="Six Bells at Kensington"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17521026-18-crimeloc99" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521026-18-off97 t17521026-18-crimeloc99"></join>, where I was drinking, about two o'clock in the morning, the nineteenth of October. He complained he was dry and cold, I ordered<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175210260008"></xptr> him a pint of beer. He is a <rs id="t17521026-18-deflabel100" type="occupation">soldier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521026-18-defend142 t17521026-18-deflabel100"></join>. Another soldier came after him; they wanted a quartern of gin, I ordered them a quartern. I had part of a bowl of punch before me, and said to them. Take and drink it, it is paid for; so I went out at the door, and sat down on a bench to sleep.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober?</p>
               <p>Grear. I was a little in liquor, but more distracted in mind than drunk.</p>
               <p>Q. What about?</p>
               <p>Grear. Because my wife and I had had some words. I was awaked by something busy about my shoes; I got up in a sort of amaze, but saw nobody, and found my silver buckles were taken out of my shoes. I felt in my pockets and found them cut, and a guinea and 5 s. 6 d. in money gone. Then I came into that house again; the landlord and I went to Mr. Newbolt's, and coming back, there was the prisoner drinking a pint of purl with another soldier. I said, That is the man that I believe has robbed me. They search'd him, and found my silver buckles in his bag that he carries his things in. Produced in court, and deposed to. The prisoner delivered a guinea to the constable in the watchhouse, and said it was mine, that he had robbed me, and was sorry for it, but begged that I'd not take his life away. The guinea produced in court. He said he had distributed the 5 s. 6 d. among the rest of his comrades, one of whom got a hundred lashes for it yesterday.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was he when he confessed this?</p>
               <p>Grear. It was in the watch-house.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Whereabouts was you when these things were taken from you?</p>
               <p>Grear. It was four doors from the alehouse where we had the liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. What time of the night?</p>
               <p>Grear. It was not half an hour over or under two o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. What time did you see me first of all?</p>
               <p>Grear. A little after twelve o'clock. I was going from my own house, and met with him just by the corner of the King's Arms alehouse, going up to the parade at Kensington. I gave him one pot of beer then, taking but one draught of it, and left him there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-18-person145">
                  John 
                  Dale 
               <interp inst="t17521026-18-person145" type="surname" value="Dale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-person145" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-person145" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Six Bells at Kensington. The prosecutor, a watchman, and two soldiers, came together to my house about one o'clock the nineteenth of October, in the morning. They called me up, saying they wanted some liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner one of the soldiers that came in at that time?</p>
               <p>Dale. No, he was not. The prosecutor treated them with a pint of beer and a dram, and had a pint of beer himself; after that he called for a shilling bowl of punch. After that he call'd for another; I had not made that long before in came the prisoner. The prosecutor made him and me drink each a little of that; he sat a little time, considering as it were, seeming very much vex'd; he went out, and gave the remainder of the punch to Simon the prisoner, who, I believe, sat half an hour in my house after the prosecutor was gone out. I remember he asked me, whether the prosecutor had changed a guinea to pay for the punch? I told him he had not. There were some other people came in, and Simon went out about half an hour after two. The Newbury coach stopp'd at three at my house; about half an hour after in came the prosecutor, and said, I have been robbed. I asked him, what company he had been in last night ? He said, he had been with the prisoner and two others at the centry box, and at the King's Arms. Then I desired him to go to the guard, and secure them. I called up my wife rather sooner than ordinary, and went with him to Mr. Newbolt's house, the constable; coming back, who should be in my house but the prisoner and another soldier; then the prosecutor pointed to the prisoner, and said, There is the man. The constable searched him, and I saw him take these silver buckles out of his cartouch box. He said the other man had the guinea; but when he was taken in charge, he himself pulled it out and gave it to the constable, confessing that he himself stole it from the prosecutor, and the buckles too, and desired he'd be merciful to him. This is the guinea produced which he gave to the constable.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-18-person146">
                  John 
                  Newbolt 
               <interp inst="t17521026-18-person146" type="surname" value="Newbolt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-person146" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-person146" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable. Last Thursday morning, about five o'clock, the prosecutor and last evidence called me out of my bed. I went with them to Mr. Dale's house, and the prosecutor gave me charge of the prisoner there. I searched him, and found these buckles in the thing that he carries his cartridges in. I put him into the round house, and went into the guard house to see the faces of the other soldiers, as the prisoner had said there was another man along with him when he robbed the prosecutor, who had part of the money. I brought that man to Mr. Dale's house; then the prisoner began to be sorry, and said, if he'd be merciful he'd give him the guinea again, and pulled it out of the waistband of his breeches; he gave it to me, and owned that he had taken it, and that he had given thirteen pence of the money to the other soldiers.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175210260009"></xptr>The prisoner had nothing to say.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-18-person147">
                  Edward 
                  Parker 
               <interp inst="t17521026-18-person147" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-person147" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-person147" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him five years, and have trusted him to carry out beer, money, and other things; he is as honest a man, when he is sober, as any in the world.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-18-person148">
                  George 
                  Viner 
               <interp inst="t17521026-18-person148" type="surname" value="Viner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-person148" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-person148" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him upwards of four years; he bore a very good character during that time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-18-person149">
                  Henry 
                  Simpson 
               <interp inst="t17521026-18-person149" type="surname" value="Simpson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-person149" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-person149" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him almost three years; I never heard but a good character of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-18-person150">
                  William 
                  Mathews 
               <interp inst="t17521026-18-person150" type="surname" value="Mathews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-person150" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-person150" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him going on with three years. He is a very honest, industrious, sober man, who loves to work hard for his bread.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-18-person151">
                  William 
                  Parkin 
               <interp inst="t17521026-18-person151" type="surname" value="Parkin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-person151" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-person151" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him upwards of two years; in which time he behaved like an honest man. His wife was servant to me a year and half, in which time he used to come twice or thrice a week; he always behaved well and sober.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-18-person152">
                  Robert 
                  Haines 
               <interp inst="t17521026-18-person152" type="surname" value="Haines"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-person152" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-person152" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him two years, but never heard any ill of him, only sometimes getting in liquor.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-18-person153">
                  Robert 
                  Sneath 
               <interp inst="t17521026-18-person153" type="surname" value="Sneath"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-person153" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-person153" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am groom to Sir 
               <persName id="t17521026-18-person154">
                  Robert 
                  Levelon 
               <interp inst="t17521026-18-person154" type="surname" value="Levelon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-person154" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-person154" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             Gower. I have known him five years, and never heard any ill of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-18-person155">
                  Benjamin 
                  Stroud 
               <interp inst="t17521026-18-person155" type="surname" value="Stroud"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-person155" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-person155" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him three years, and never heard but he was an honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521026-18-person156">
                  George 
                  Crew 
               <interp inst="t17521026-18-person156" type="surname" value="Crew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-person156" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-person156" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him a year and half, have tried him in several things, and always found him honest.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17521026-18-verdict101" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-verdict101" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17521026-18-punish102" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17521026-18-punish102" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521026-18-defend142 t17521026-18-punish102"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
