<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17540227-52">
               <interp inst="t17540227-52" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540227-52" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540227-52" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540227"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540227-52" type="date" value="17540227"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540227-52-off274-c378" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540227-52-defend481 t17540227-52-off274 t17540227-52-verdict277"></join>
         
               <p>109. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17540227-52-defend481" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Warsh 
                  <interp inst="t17540227-52-defend481" type="surname" value="Warsh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540227-52-defend481" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540227-52-defend481" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17540227-52-off274" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540227-52-off274" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540227-52-off274" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing nineteen wether sheep, val. 20 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17540227-52-victim483" type="victimName">
                     Joseph 
                     Hailey 
                  <interp inst="t17540227-52-victim483" type="surname" value="Hailey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540227-52-victim483" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540227-52-victim483" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540227-52-off274 t17540227-52-victim483"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17540227-52-cd275" type="crimeDate">Jan. 31</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540227-52-off274 t17540227-52-cd275"></join>. ++.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540227-52-person484">
                  Joseph 
                  Hailey 
               <interp inst="t17540227-52-person484" type="surname" value="Hailey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540227-52-person484" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540227-52-person484" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at <placeName id="t17540227-52-crimeloc276">Hendon</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17540227-52-crimeloc276" type="placeName" value="Hendon"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17540227-52-crimeloc276" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540227-52-off274 t17540227-52-crimeloc276"></join>. I lost nineteen wether sheep on the 19th of January. The prisoner lives about a mile and half from me; I had heard that he had sold eleven at Acton, and had drove eight to Chelsea, upon which I suspected that he had stole mine. I had a warrant of Justice Beauvais at Hammersmith, and took up him and two of his brothers; he was examined before the justice, and said he bought 36 sheep in Smithfield, some horn'd and some poll'd ones, some large and some less. He said the large ones cost him 15 s. 6 d. each, and the small ones 8 s. 6 d. but he could not tell how many there were of a sort as to horn'd ones or large ones. He owned he sold four of them at Chelsea to a butcher, and that his Brother Natsold the other four, and was concerned in buying and driving them away: but when Nat was examined he declared he knew nothing of the matter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540227-52-person485">
                  Joseph 
                  Brownsworth 
               <interp inst="t17540227-52-person485" type="surname" value="Brownsworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540227-52-person485" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540227-52-person485" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a sheep salesman. The 1st of January one 
               <persName id="t17540227-52-person486">
                  John 
                  Cooper 
               <interp inst="t17540227-52-person486" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540227-52-person486" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540227-52-person486" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             told me the prosecutor had lost 19 sheep. They were advertised several days, and I got some bills printed by his desire to give about into the country, and last Saturday was se'nnight one Hill, a skinman, told me he was informed there was a man at a publick house who had killed four sheep in a stable, and had sold them to Mr. Dobney in Fleet Market, and that the man once did keep the clutterhouse in Edgware Road; I then suspected the prisoner, as he had formerly kept that house; the skins were described to be large ones. After this Mr. Hill inform'd me he had heard that the same man had sold some to one Kem, a butcher at Acton; on the Tuesday following I went and told the prosecutor all I had heard; then he, I, Cooper and Weedon went to Acton to see for the skins: we saw one skin in Mr. Chandler's slaughter-house; it was okered in a very odd manner from the head to the tail, and pitched on each side, so that we could not be positive to it; but by the size of the skin and staple of the wool we took it to be one of the skins of the sheep lost, for I think no honest man would smear a skin in such a manner. We then went to a selmonger's yard in the town, and there saw four or five more, which the man said he had from out of Mr. Kem's shop; they were reddled as the other was. We looked them carefully over, and there seemed to be an old oker mark on two of them over the loins, which there was on some of the sheep the prosecutor lost; we got one of them washed, and the mark then appeared more plain. We then got a warrant, and took up the prisoner with four of his brothers; the prisoner was charged with stealing the nineteen sheep, and was asked how he came by those he had sold there, but gave a very bad account; he said he bought 36 at Smithfield, some great some small; for some he gave 15 s. 6 d. and some 8 s. 6 d. He could not tell how many great or little ones there were, or what he gave for the whole, or where he paid for them, he only said it was at a house near the hospital gate. He said he had sold four there, and after that seven; that he killed eight of them at Chelsea, of which last he sold four at 20 d. a stone to Mr. Dobney in the New Market, and that Mr. Dobney had the fat of all the eight at the same price, and that his brother Nathaniel sold the other four at Carnaby Market, but he could not tell to whom; and that Nat was with him when he bought and paid for them, and helped to drive them to his father's ground, where they were a week, and from thence he took them to keeping in turnips at Uxbridge, and from thence to Acton and Chelsea. We took up Nat, and he denied the whole of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540227-52-person487">
                  John 
                  Cooper 
               <interp inst="t17540227-52-person487" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540227-52-person487" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540227-52-person487" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was to have brought these nineteen sheep to Smithfield for the prosecutor. I had<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175402270034"></xptr> took them from among 60, and put them in a field by themselves near Edgware Road. When I went to fetch them out Jan. 31, about three in the morning, I found the gate open, and they gone. I then went to Smithfield, and made all the inquiry I could. He went on, and confirmed the evidence given by Mr Brownsworth.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540227-52-person488">
                  William 
                  Kem 
               <interp inst="t17540227-52-person488" type="surname" value="Kem"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540227-52-person488" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540227-52-person488" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I bought seven sheep of the prisoner, and after that four more, the first last Saturday was three weeks, and the others last Saturday was fortnight; they were great poll sheep, with long staple wool. There was some pitch mark upon them, but what I can't tell, with a great deal of red oker, I think more than common.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540227-52-person489">
                  Abel 
                  Dobney 
               <interp inst="t17540227-52-person489" type="surname" value="Dobney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540227-52-person489" type="given" value="Abel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540227-52-person489" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I bought four sheep of the prisoner at the bar in February, I believe on the 7th, at 20 d. per stone, fat and all. They were very poor ones.</p>
               <p>Cooper. The prosecutor had some very good, and some but midling; those I draw'd out that were lost were midling.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540227-52-person490">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Marsh 
               <interp inst="t17540227-52-person490" type="surname" value="Marsh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540227-52-person490" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540227-52-person490" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am brother to the prisoner, and saw him buy 36 sheep in Smithfield market, which he paid for at the pen. I don't remember the day, but it is about six weeks ago. I don't know where he sold any of them. He paid for twenty at 15 s. 6 d. each, and sixteen at 8 s. 6 d. each.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I bought 36 sheep, all of one man, in Smithfield. I put 28 of them to keeping at Hesson to one Mr. Gale, a farmer.</p>
               <p>He called 
               <persName id="t17540227-52-person491">
                  John 
                  Pain 
               <interp inst="t17540227-52-person491" type="surname" value="Pain"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540227-52-person491" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540227-52-person491" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who had known him above twenty years, 
               <persName id="t17540227-52-person492">
                  John 
                  Field 
               <interp inst="t17540227-52-person492" type="surname" value="Field"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540227-52-person492" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540227-52-person492" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             from a child, 
               <persName id="t17540227-52-person493">
                  Thomas 
                  Adams 
               <interp inst="t17540227-52-person493" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540227-52-person493" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540227-52-person493" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             upwards of six years, and 
               <persName id="t17540227-52-person494">
                  Henry 
                  Blanch 
               <interp inst="t17540227-52-person494" type="surname" value="Blanch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540227-52-person494" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540227-52-person494" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             three years, to his character. The first said he never knew him any other than a very honest man; the second would not be prevailed upon to say whether his general character was good or bad; the third said he knew but little of him; and the fourth that he had had dealings with him, and he behaved as an honest man to him.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540227-52-verdict277" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540227-52-verdict277" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
