<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17591205-25">
               <interp inst="t17591205-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591205-25" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591205-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17591205"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591205-25" type="date" value="17591205"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17591205-25-off127-c204" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-25-defend251 t17591205-25-off127 t17591205-25-verdict129"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17591205-25-off130-c204" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-25-defend251 t17591205-25-off130 t17591205-25-verdict129"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17591205-25-off133-c204" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-25-defend251 t17591205-25-off133 t17591205-25-verdict129"></join>
         
               <p>28. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17591205-25-defend251" type="defendantName">
                     Aaron 
                     Davids 
                  <interp inst="t17591205-25-defend251" type="surname" value="Davids"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-defend251" type="given" value="Aaron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-defend251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17591205-25-off127" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-off127" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-off127" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               carnally knowing, and feloniously abusing 
                     
                        <persName id="t17591205-25-victim253" type="victimName">
                           Frances 
                           Moses 
                        <interp inst="t17591205-25-victim253" type="surname" value="Moses"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17591205-25-victim253" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17591205-25-victim253" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17591205-25-viclabel128" type="occupation">spinster, an infant, under four years of age</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-25-victim253 t17591205-25-viclabel128"></join>
               
                  </rs>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-25-person254">
                  Frances 
                  Moses 
               <interp inst="t17591205-25-person254" type="surname" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-person254" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-person254" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the elder. I live at the upper end of Houndsditch.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you a husband?</p>
               <p>F. Moses. I have; he travels the country, sometimes with necklaces, and sometimes with muffs and tippets.</p>
               <p>Q. How old is that child in your arms?</p>
               <p>F. Moses. She is almost four years old. The prisoner at the bar did live in Woolpack Alley, which but a step from my house; my child went to school with his sister-in-law, and he used to fetch and carry the child to and from school sometimes; he lodged at Ann Davids's, his sister's house. About six weeks ago she came home, and was very red and hot in her face; after that she would not go to school any more, but was taken very bad; she tumbled about, and could not make water.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had she gone to that school then?</p>
               <p>F. Moses This was about four or five weeks after she had first gone to school. Then I took her in my lap, looked at her, and found she was much swelled. and began to break out in her private parts.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe that she was torn?</p>
               <p>F. Moses. She was not torn, but she had the soul disease.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that?</p>
               <p>F. Moses. I sent for 
               <persName id="t17591205-25-person255">
                  Hannah 
                  Jacobs 
               <interp inst="t17591205-25-person255" type="surname" value="Jacobs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-person255" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-person255" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a midwife, and it was her opinion. I put my child an outpatient in the hospital.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any thing upon the child's linen?</p>
               <p>F. Moses. No. When I asked the child how she came to be so, she said Aaron hurted her in her private parts; but I could not talk to Aaron about it, my heart ached so.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell the school-mistress that your child had got the foul disease?</p>
               <p>F. Moses. I did</p>
               <p>Q. When you told her that, did you agree for a surgeon to examine her?</p>
               <p>F. Moses. She advised me to go Dr. Cole, but I was for going to the midwife.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the midwife say upon inspecting her?</p>
               <p>F. Moses. She said a man had meddled with her, and that she had the soul disease. I went to Mr. Waley, who laid the child on a table, and examined her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-25-person256">
                  Sarah 
                  Solomon 
               <interp inst="t17591205-25-person256" type="surname" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-person256" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-person256" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Woolpack Alley, near Gravel Lane, and work with Mrs. Moses by the week; the child could not make water, but cried and roared, and tumbled about like a mad thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever inspect the child?</p>
               <p>S. Solomon. No, never.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see the prisoner and child together?</p>
               <p>S. Solomon. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear him say any thing about the child?</p>
               <p>S. Solomon. No.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-25-person257">
                  Hannah 
                  Owen 
               <interp inst="t17591205-25-person257" type="surname" value="Owen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-person257" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-person257" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a midwife, and saw this child about two or three days after it was taken ill; it had a sort of a running and gleer upon it; but I cannot say that the child is hurt, for the body is safe. I will not take upon me to say it had got the foul disease.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by hurt?</p>
               <p>H. Owen. It was never entered into.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is it ago since you examined the child?</p>
               <p>H. Owen. It is above three months ago.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17591205-25-verdict129" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-verdict129" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175912050024"></xptr>(L.) He was a second time indicted for <rs id="t17591205-25-off130" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-off130" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-off130" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               feloniously abusing, and carnally knowing 
                     
                        <persName id="t17591205-25-victim259" type="victimName">
                           Sarah 
                           Jacobs 
                        <interp inst="t17591205-25-victim259" type="surname" value="Jacobs"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17591205-25-victim259" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17591205-25-victim259" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17591205-25-viclabel131" type="occupation">spinster, an infant, about the age of seven years</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-25-victim259 t17591205-25-viclabel131"></join>. ||
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-25-person260">
                  Sarah 
                  Jacobs 
               <interp inst="t17591205-25-person260" type="surname" value="Jacobs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-person260" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-person260" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the elder. I live in Houndiditch, near the Angel in Woolpack Alley. My husband is a taylor, and I am a necklace maker; we are near neighbours to Mrs. Davids, the school mistress, who is married to the prisoner's brother. My daughter, whom I have in my arms, is going in the eighth year of her age, and went to school at Mrs. Davids's. The prisoner helped his sister to learn the children to read. My child coming home sickly, I took her alone, and looked at her. She said I must tell nothing, I shall be hang'd up, and put her hands up to her eyes. At last she told me every thing that 
               <persName id="t17591205-25-person261">
                  Aaron 
                  Davids 
               <interp inst="t17591205-25-person261" type="surname" value="Davids"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-person261" type="given" value="Aaron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-person261" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             did to her. I found her abused and torn terribly, and was very sore upon her private parts. She was more like a woman than a child, her parts being torn open. I went to the school, and beat the prisoner well. My child was always crying out, of her bowels and her limbs, and she could not make water. I found upon her under petticoat something like spots of blood.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you understand that your child had the foul disease?</p>
               <p>S. Jacobs. That you must ask the surgeon, for I do not understand it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever declare to any body, after you found your child in this condition, that she had the foul distemper?</p>
               <p>S. Jacobs. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you say so to one Mrs. Walker ?</p>
               <p>S. Jacobs. I do not know her.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon what day was it you found your child first in this manner?</p>
               <p>S. Jacobs. About three months ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you recollect what day you went to Mrs. Davids's house about it?</p>
               <p>S. Jacobs. It was about a week afterwards; it was the day after I found it out, when I beat the boy.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was at Mrs. Davids's at that time?</p>
               <p>S. Jacobs. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you say to Mrs. Davids?</p>
               <p>S. Jacobs. I said I wanted to take the child away. She said she would make me suffer for it, that I spake like the rest, and one had catched the pox of the father, the other of the mother, and the other wanted money.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-25-person262">
                  Timothy 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17591205-25-person262" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-person262" type="given" value="Timothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-person262" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an apothecary and chymist. 
               <persName id="t17591205-25-person263">
                  Sarah 
                  Jacobs 
               <interp inst="t17591205-25-person263" type="surname" value="Jacobs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-person263" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-person263" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             brought her child to me about two months ago (this is the child that is here) and complained it had got the foul disease, by a ravishment, and desired I would let her have a few medicines for the case; I did not examine the child.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you not?</p>
               <p>Davis. Because the child refused it, and cry'd and said I should not; so I never examined her so far as to absolutely know the case was either a ravishment or the foul disease; the second time she lay in her mother's lap, I just look'd withinside her thighs and saw a few pimples that were broke out.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell whether there was a laceration?</p>
               <p>Davis. I can not.</p>
               <p>Q. How came it you did not look farther?</p>
               <p>Davis. I did not chuse it, thinking they had surgeons of their own, and I thought it most requisite for them to do it. I gave her some medicines to cool the heat of her body. I could not cleverly say she was a patient of mine. The mother came and had a shilling-worth of medicines now and then.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you or can you not say whether she had the foul distemper?</p>
               <p>Davis. I cannot say it was that, I apprehend it might be occasioned by heat of body. I asked the child several questions; she had but one symptom of a venereal disease, and that was the scalding of her water.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing at all about it.</p>
               <p>At the Jury's request the child is set up and examined, but not sworn.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body hurt you?</p>
               <p>Child. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Who?</p>
               <p>Child. 
               <persName id="t17591205-25-person264">
                  Aaron 
                  Davids 
               <interp inst="t17591205-25-person264" type="surname" value="Davids"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-person264" type="given" value="Aaron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-person264" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Where does he live?</p>
               <p>Child. He lives in Woolpack Alley.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is he now?</p>
               <p>Child. (Pointing to him.) There he is.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is it ago that he hurted you?</p>
               <p>Child. A good while.</p>
               <p>Q. How long?</p>
               <p>Child. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it last week?</p>
               <p>Child. No, Sir, a good while longer.</p>
               <p>Q. How much longer?</p>
               <p>Child. Almost four months.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after you was hurt, did your mother find it out?</p>
               <p>Child. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. Did your mother ever find it out?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175912050025"></xptr>Child. It came out by another child.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never complain to her?</p>
               <p>Child. No.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you not to complain?</p>
               <p>Child. Because he said the rats and mice would eat me up.</p>
               <p>Q. to the mother. Did you ever apply to 
               <persName id="t17591205-25-person265">
                  Hannah 
                  Owen 
               <interp inst="t17591205-25-person265" type="surname" value="Owen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-person265" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-person265" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ?</p>
               <p>Mother. Yes, once to look at my child.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was that after you had found it out?</p>
               <p>Mother. That was ten weeks, or two months ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she look at it?</p>
               <p>Mother. She did.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Owen. I did not examine this child; the mother shew'd me it as she lay in her lap, but I cannot say I saw any thing the matter with it; I did not examine it so strictly as I did the other child; the mother told me the affair, but I never touched the child: I did examine the other two, and they were both found, no man ever had to do with them; but as for this I will not take upon me to swear, because I did not examine it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17591205-25-verdict132" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-verdict132" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>(L.) He was a third time <rs id="t17591205-25-off133" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-off133" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-off133" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               indicted for the like offence
            </rs>, on the body of 
               
                  <persName id="t17591205-25-victim267" type="victimName">
                     Hannah 
                     Hart 
                  <interp inst="t17591205-25-victim267" type="surname" value="Hart"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-victim267" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-victim267" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17591205-25-viclabel134" type="occupation">spinster, an infant, under seven years of age</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-25-victim267 t17591205-25-viclabel134"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-25-person268">
                  Mary 
                  Hart 
               <interp inst="t17591205-25-person268" type="surname" value="Hart"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-person268" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-person268" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am sister to the child; my mother is not here. The child came home from Mrs. Davids's school about four months ago, and went to the pot, and cry'd out sadly. My mother asked her what was the matter. She answered, Aaron pushed her with a broomstick. The child went to that school afterwards for upwards of a week or a fortnight, but was not very well, and broke out upon her face.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is your mother?</p>
               <p>M. Hart. She was here, but is gone I know not where. It is not a young woman's place to take notice what is the matter: I know nothing of it; I thought she was gall'd, and put a piece of fullers earth to her.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17591205-25-verdict135" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17591205-25-verdict135" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
