<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510116-70">
               <interp inst="t17510116-70" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510116-70" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510116-70" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510116-70" type="date" value="17510116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510116-70-off325-c453" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-70-defend579 t17510116-70-off325 t17510116-70-verdict328"></join>
         
               <p>179. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17510116-70-defend579" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Hughs 
                  <interp inst="t17510116-70-defend579" type="surname" value="Hughs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-70-defend579" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-70-defend579" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for that he <rs id="t17510116-70-off325" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510116-70-off325" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-70-off325" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               in a certain alley, or open place, near the king's high-way, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17510116-70-victim581" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Lawrance 
                        <interp inst="t17510116-70-victim581" type="surname" value="Lawrance"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510116-70-victim581" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510116-70-victim581" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-70-off325 t17510116-70-victim581"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault; putting him in bodily fear and danger of his life, one hat value one shilling, from his person did steal, take and carry away
            </rs>, <rs id="t17510116-70-cd326" type="crimeDate">Dec. 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-70-off325 t17510116-70-cd326"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-70-person582">
                  William 
                  Lawrance 
               <interp inst="t17510116-70-person582" type="surname" value="Lawrance"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-70-person582" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-70-person582" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Old Windsor, in the great park; when I am in town I always lodge at the Four bells in shoe-lane. I was coming from the Blue-coat hospital on the 27th of December, to Shoe-lane, where I lodge, about 12 at night; I was got about two pole out of the market, going up <placeName id="t17510116-70-crimeloc327">Harp-alley</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17510116-70-crimeloc327" type="placeName" value="Harp-alley"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510116-70-crimeloc327" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-70-off325 t17510116-70-crimeloc327"></join>; I received a blow on the back of my head, and made me bite my tongue; I turned myself about and put my hand up to my head, he struck me two blows more; and as my hand was up, he snatched my hat from between my hand and my head, and I saw him go out of the alley with it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner say any thing to you?</p>
               <p>Lawrance. No, not a word, my lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Which way did he go?</p>
               <p>Lawrance. Into Fleet-market; I cried, stop thief ! he ran up the market towards Ludgate-hill, and a man stop'd him.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his name that stop'd him?</p>
               <p>Lawrance. His name is 
               <persName id="t17510116-70-person583">
                  Thomas 
                  Lingard 
               <interp inst="t17510116-70-person583" type="surname" value="Lingard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-70-person583" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-70-person583" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; the prisoner was in my sight all the time.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it light or dark?</p>
               <p>Lawrance. It was a moon-light night, my lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain the prisoner is the man?</p>
               <p>Lawrance. I looked him full in the face, when he turned about, and I am very sure of him, he was carried to the watch-house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see your hat again?</p>
               <p>Lawrance. I know nothing what became of it, it was not upon him when he was taken.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sobe r at this time?</p>
               <p>Lawrance. I was very sober, my lord.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he strike you with?</p>
               <p>Lawrance. With his fist I suppose, my lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Lawrance. Not to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-70-person584">
                  Thomas 
                  Lingard 
               <interp inst="t17510116-70-person584" type="surname" value="Lingard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-70-person584" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-70-person584" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Two days after Christmas-day, near 12 o'clock at night, I had just come out of an alehouse, the King's arms in the Fleet-market; I met the prisoner in the market coming from Harp-alley, and a little boy with him; the prisoner said to the boy, d - n you run, or else we are taken. I saw the prosecutor after him, calling stop thief! he got a head of the boy.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was you off of Harp-alley when you saw the prisoner first?</p>
               <p>Lingard. About 12 or 14 yards. I saw him come out of the alley; I was in the middle of the market going towards Harp-alley; the prisoner<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175101160034"></xptr> and prosecutor were both running. I overtook the prisoner and the boy; I believe the boy was about eight or nine yards from the prisoner: when they ran by the prison gate, I ran down near the side of the market houses; when he saw I crossed upon him; he turned round and stop'd; said he, what do you want with me? Said I, you have robb'd the man, and you shall go to him.</p>
               <p>Q. How far did he run in the market?</p>
               <p>Lingard. I followed him about 100 yards or better; I overtook him just on the top of the market  the prosecutor was just after me; said he, when I had took hold of the prisoner, I am robb'd; said I, do you know the man? Said he, I have lost my hat, and this is the man that robbed me of it.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say?</p>
               <p>Lingard. He said nothing for himself.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the boy taken?</p>
               <p>Lingard. He was, but the man that took him is not here. The alderman cleared the boy, because the prosecutor could not say any thing against him.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the prisoner e'er a hat in his hand when you took him?</p>
               <p>Lingard. He had not, the prosecutor was without a hat.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-70-person585">
                  Thomas 
                  Plaster 
               <interp inst="t17510116-70-person585" type="surname" value="Plaster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-70-person585" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-70-person585" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was constable for the night. The prisoner was brought to me at the watch-house for robbing Mr. Lawrance of a hat; there was a boy about 14 years of age brought with him; the prisoner and Mr. Lawrance said, they knew nothing of the boy. Lawrance said, the boy was with the prisoner, when he robbed him of his hat; I asked the prisoner how he came to run? He said, he run because somebody cried out stop thief! I sent the prisoner to the Compter and the boy to Bridewell.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prosecutor sober?</p>
               <p>Plaster. He was very sober, as he is now?</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Lawrance. Did you see a boy when you was robbed?</p>
               <p>Lawrance. There was a boy, he went out at the end of the alley with the prisoner; they ran both together.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I came over from Boston in New England; I was born there; the ship I came in was then at Stoney-stairs ; I came on shore with the captain, and had been drinking with some of my shipmates, and coming away, I was running to make the best of my way to Stoney-stairs; this gentleman cried out stop thief ! and that man was in the market, and he ran and called to another man that came out of an alehouse; he came towards me and said stop, I stop'd; said I, what do you want with me? Said he, you are the man that robbed him; then said I, if he says so I'll go back to him; I told the same story at the watch-house; there was a boy taken up, whom I never saw before; the boy said, he used to go a begging for his father and mother; I have not been in London above a month.</p>

               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510116-70-verdict328" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510116-70-verdict328" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17510116-70-punish329" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510116-70-punish329" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-70-defend579 t17510116-70-punish329"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
