<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17581025-24">
               <interp inst="t17581025-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581025-24" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581025-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17581025"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581025-24" type="date" value="17581025"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17581025-24-off115-c178" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581025-24-defend227 t17581025-24-off115 t17581025-24-verdict119"></join>
         
               <p>347 (.) 
               <persName id="t17581025-24-defend227" type="defendantName">
                  David 
                  Bell 
               <interp inst="t17581025-24-defend227" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-24-defend227" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-24-defend227" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for that <rs id="t17581025-24-off115" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581025-24-off115" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-24-off115" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               he on the 16th of October , about the hour of eight in the night on the same day, the dwelling house of the <rs id="t17581025-24-viclabel116" type="occupation">Right Hon. Lord 
                        <persName id="t17581025-24-victim228" type="victimName">
                           Vere 
                           Beauclerk 
                        <interp inst="t17581025-24-victim228" type="surname" value="Beauclerk"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17581025-24-victim228" type="given" value="Vere"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17581025-24-victim228" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        </persName>
                      , Baron of worth</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581025-24-victim228 t17581025-24-viclabel116"></join> did break and enter, four linen shirts value 20 s. five neckcloths, one silk handkerchief, one silk purse, and four guineas, the goods and money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17581025-24-victim230" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Somerfield 
                        <interp inst="t17581025-24-victim230" type="surname" value="Somerfield"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17581025-24-victim230" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17581025-24-victim230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , did steal, take and carry away
            </rs>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581025-24-person231">
                  William 
                  Somerfield 
               <interp inst="t17581025-24-person231" type="surname" value="Somerfield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-24-person231" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-24-person231" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live <rs id="t17581025-24-viclabel117" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581025-24-victim230 t17581025-24-viclabel117"></join> with the Right Hon. Lord Vere, I lost four linen shirts, five muslin neckcloths, a silk handkerchief, a silk purse, and four guineas in a gold, on the 16th of this month.</p>
               <p>Q. Why do you charge the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Somerfield. I was informed he was seen on the road the next morning coming towards London with a small parcel under his arm and a clean shirt and neckcloth on.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know him before?</p>
               <p>Somerfield. Yes, I succeeded him at my Lord Vere's he was <rs id="t17581025-24-deflabel118" type="occupation">coachman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581025-24-defend227 t17581025-24-deflabel118"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Who gave you this intelligence?</p>
               <p>Somerfield. One 
               <persName id="t17581025-24-person232">
                  Richard 
                  Holmes 
               <interp inst="t17581025-24-person232" type="surname" value="Holmes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-24-person232" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-24-person232" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , then my Lord's steward and I came to town.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you missed your things?</p>
               <p>Somerfield. I missed them the same night that they were taken away; we took the prisoner the next morning, we found him under a manger in a stable belonging to Mr. Beckford in St. James's street, he had one of my shirts and neckcloth on; we charged him with taking the things, and he owned where the rest of the things and three guineas of the money was; we went and found them accordingly; then we took him before justice Fielding, there he owned the three guineas were part of the money he had stole from me.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say about the goods?</p>
               <p>Somerfield. He was not asked about them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say how he got them?</p>

               <p>Somerfield. He said he got in at the stable window; there was a pane of glass we found had been taken out, and the room door withinfire was burst open.</p>
               <p>Q. Is that room part of my Lord Vere's dwelling house?</p>
               <p>Somerfield. It is, it is over the stable; my box was broke open.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he broke it open?</p>
               <p>Somerfield. No, he did not, (he produced a silk purse,) this we took out of the prisoner's pocket, it is my property.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581025-24-person233">
                  Richard 
                  Holmes 
               <interp inst="t17581025-24-person233" type="surname" value="Holmes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-24-person233" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-24-person233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming from Brentford market on the day following the robbery, I met the prisoner between Smallberry-green turnpike and Brentford bridge between eight and nine o'clock with a little bundle under his arm.</p>
               <p>Q. Name the day of the month?</p>
               <p>Holmes. It was last Tuesday was sennight; I asked him how he did, he stopped and asked me the same, but did not seem much for talking: I came home and in the afternoon about half an hour after four o'clock, I saw my Lord Vere's postillion, he told me the coachman's room in the stable had been broke open, and linen and money taken away, and that it must be done by some man that knew the stable and room very well; then I said I met the prisoner this morning with a quantity of goods much the same he had mentioned; after the postillion was got home, my Lord Vere's steward sent for me and I told him the same.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581025-24-person234">
                  Mary 
                  Graham 
               <interp inst="t17581025-24-person234" type="surname" value="Graham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-24-person234" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-24-person234" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner came up into my room on the 17th of this month with a bundle and desired I would take care of it, I said let me see what I must take care of, I asked him where he came by them after I had seen them, he said he had been amongst his friends, and I had no business to ask him any questions.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Graham. I live in Swallow-street, he also brought 3 guineas in gold and left them in my hands.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they in the bundle?</p>
               <p>Graham. No they were not, he took them out of his pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. What was in the bundle?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175810250023"></xptr>Graham. There were three shirts, and four cravats wrapped in a red handkerchief.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there a silk purse in the bundle?</p>
               <p>Graham. No, there was not.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do with that bundle?</p>
               <p>Graham. I kept it in my custody. and delivered it to the prosecutor when he came for it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you give it him for asking for?</p>
               <p>Graham. There was the prisoner came with him.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say?</p>
               <p>Graham. I do not know that he spoke, the prosecutor said the things were his.</p>

               <p>Q. Did he say it was his in the prisoner's presence?</p>
               <p>Graham. To be sure he did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner say nothing to that?</p>
               <p>Graham. He said they were that man's goods, (the goods produced in court and deposed to by the prosecutor.) Mrs. Graham delivered these also to me. (Producing three guineas.)</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs. Graham. Are they the same you delivered to the prosecutor?</p>
               <p>Graham. I cannot say these are the very same.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you deliver the same three guineas which the prisoner delivered to you to the prosecutor?</p>
               <p>Graham. I did.</p>
               <p>The prisoner said nothing in his defence, but desired my Lord's steward might be called.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581025-24-person235">
                  William 
                  Hewet 
               <interp inst="t17581025-24-person235" type="surname" value="Hewet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-24-person235" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-24-person235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am steward to my Lord Vere, the prisoner lived in my Lord's service six years in the capacity of coachman.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Hewet. We could never lay any thing of dishonesty to his charge.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has he been discharged from my Lord's service?</p>
               <p>Hewet. He was discharged in June last.</p>
               <p>Q. How came he to be discharged?</p>
               <p>Hewet. He did not do so well as he ought to do; we could not lay any thing to his charge of theft before this; he came to London twice without leave.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. This I saw taken out of the prisoner's pocket, (producing a silk purse.) This is the same purse which my money was in.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the night did he break into the room?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. He broke into the place about eight at night.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it dark then?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor, It was dark.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17581025-24-verdict119" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581025-24-verdict119" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17581025-24-punish120" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581025-24-punish120" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581025-24-defend227 t17581025-24-punish120"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
