<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17580913-58">
               <interp inst="t17580913-58" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-58" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-58" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580913"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-58" type="date" value="17580913"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580913-58-off288-c415" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-58-defend519 t17580913-58-off288 t17580913-58-verdict291"></join>
         
               <p>315. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17580913-58-defend519" type="defendantName">
                  
                     John 
                     Read 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17580913-58-alias-4" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-58-defend519 t17580913-58-alias-4"></join>Hoskins</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-58-defend519" type="surname" value="Read"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-58-defend519" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-58-defend519" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for that <rs id="t17580913-58-off288" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580913-58-off288" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-58-off288" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he on the king's highway, on 
                     <persName id="t17580913-58-victim521" type="victimName">
                        Ann, <rs id="t17580913-58-viclabel289" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-58-victim521 t17580913-58-viclabel289"></join>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-58-person522 t17580913-58-viclabel289"></join> of 
                           <persName id="t17580913-58-person522" type="victimName">
                              Robert 
                              Odell 
                           <interp inst="t17580913-58-person522" type="surname" value="Odell"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17580913-58-person522" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17580913-58-person522" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        </persName>
                        
                        <interp inst="t17580913-58-victim521" type="surname" value="Odell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580913-58-victim521" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580913-58-victim521" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , did make an assault, putting her in corporal fear and danger of her life, and taking from her person, one pound weight of mutton, value 3 d. one silk handkerchief, value 6 d. and 6 d. in money, the goods and money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17580913-58-victim524" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Odell 
                        <interp inst="t17580913-58-victim524" type="surname" value="Odell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580913-58-victim524" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580913-58-victim524" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , against the will of the said Ann
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17580913-58-cd290" type="crimeDate">August 25</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-58-off288 t17580913-58-cd290"></join>.* </p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-58-person525">
                  Ann 
                  Odell 
               <interp inst="t17580913-58-person525" type="surname" value="Odell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-58-person525" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-58-person525" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 25th of August, I had been to buy some mutton to make some broth for my husband; I had got some turneps and some bread; I went into a chandler's shop and the prisoner at the bar was there.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was this?</p>
               <p>Odell. It was about nine at night; I had these things in my lap; I sat down, the prisoner took my meat and ran out of the shop; the man of the shop said lay it down, it is the woman's, then the man said be so good as to go out of the house.</p>
               <p>Q. What is that man's name?</p>
               <p>Odell. It is 
               <persName id="t17580913-58-person526">
                  Edward 
                  Southard 
               <interp inst="t17580913-58-person526" type="surname" value="Southard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-58-person526" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-58-person526" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. What did you go in there for?</p>
               <p>Odell. Only for a halfpenny worth of bread; the prisoner said if he had me out at the door, he would kick me from d - l to d - l; he watch'd me out at the door, then when I was in the street he knock'd me down, and put his hand upon my body; he took away my meat, and my handkerchief, and 6 d. in money, and tore my cloaths all off my back, and left me there for dead; I calling out, he ran away; when I took him up he fell down on his knees, and asked my pardon, and said he would give me a crown.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the handkerchief worth?</p>
               <p>Odell. It was not worth much.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. What did I knock you down with?</p>
               <p>Odell. With your hands to be sure.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. She is a very drunken woman, all her neighbours know it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-58-person527">
                  Edward 
                  Southard 
               <interp inst="t17580913-58-person527" type="surname" value="Southard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-58-person527" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-58-person527" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 25th of last month in the evening, the prisoner came into my shop and asked for some bread and cheese upon credit; I refused letting him have it; he asked for a pint of beer, I drew it, he drank it, and would not pay for it; I desired him to go out, this woman came in, she had got a bit of meat, which she laid down on the compter, and asked for a halfpenny worth of bread; after I had served her the prisoner took up the bread and meat, and ran out of the door with them; I called after him and said it belonged to me, then he brought it back and laid it down; he still kept calling her bitch and whore; she kept the things in her lap, he said if he had her out at the door he would kick her from d - l to d - l; when I thought he was quite gone, I went to the door; I said to the woman she might go very safe; she went away, after which I heard the cry of murder, I went to the door, she call'd stop thief; I went to her, there lay the woman, I saw her nakedness down below her navel, she said the man had stripp'd her of her victuals, and turneps, a handkerchief from off her neck, and some money; she came and staid in the shop till she came to herself, then I went to go home with her a second time.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>This woman that swears against me, has hired two thief catchers, to take away my life; she met me in the street, and said brother craft will you give me a pint of beer, I said I would, we went into the king's arms in White-cross-street, she said my dear let's have a pot, then two or three of her acquaintance came in, the pot was soon out, come said she we will have another, she pat her hand in her pocket, and said I have got no snuff; she went out, and left me five pints to pay for. I did not see her for a week after. When I came into that chandler's shop, there she sat, said I you are a slut; she called me old rogue, and son of a bitch; I called her again; I drank my beer and went out about my business. By the time I got home and up stairs (I live behind Cripplegate church,) the clock struck ten. I went to work the next morning; at last came a man and said I had rob'd and stripp'd the woman; that afternoon she and two thief-catchers laid hold of me; there they made me spend my money, and then took me to New-prison please to enquire into the woman's character, she is drunk every day: I had many of the best of Cripplegate parish to give me 2 character, but it being late they are gone.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17580913-58-verdict291" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580913-58-verdict291" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17580913-58-punish292" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580913-58-punish292" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-58-defend519 t17580913-58-punish292"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
