<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560915-23">
               <interp inst="t17560915-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-23" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560915"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-23" type="date" value="17560915"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560915-23-off124-c135" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-23-defend180 t17560915-23-off124 t17560915-23-verdict129"></join>
         
               <p>349. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17560915-23-defend180" type="defendantName">
                     Young 
                     Rogers 
                  <interp inst="t17560915-23-defend180" type="surname" value="Rogers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-23-defend180" type="given" value="Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-23-defend180" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17560915-23-off124" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560915-23-off124" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-23-off124" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing eleven 36 s. pieces, two moidores, sixteen guineas and one half guinea, the money of 
                     <persName id="t17560915-23-victim181" type="victimName">
                        Samuel 
                        Green 
                     <interp inst="t17560915-23-victim181" type="surname" value="Green"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560915-23-victim181" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560915-23-victim181" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-23-off124 t17560915-23-victim181"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , in the dwelling house of the said Samuel
            </rs>, <rs id="t17560915-23-cd125" type="crimeDate">August 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-23-off124 t17560915-23-cd125"></join>. +</p>
               <p>Samuel Green. I live in <placeName id="t17560915-23-crimeloc126">Kentish-Town</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17560915-23-crimeloc126" type="placeName" value="Kentish-Town"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17560915-23-crimeloc126" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-23-off124 t17560915-23-crimeloc126"></join>, and am a little bit of a <rs id="t17560915-23-viclabel127" type="occupation">farmer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-23-victim181 t17560915-23-viclabel127"></join>. Last Sunday was three weeks my wife and I were both out, and the prisoner being my <rs id="t17560915-23-deflabel128" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-23-defend180 t17560915-23-deflabel128"></join> was left at home. I returned about half an hour after seven in the evening; and ordered Rogers to come in to supper, and go to bed. He would not, but kept out all night. The next morning about seven he came in, and wanted to treat this body and that body, that were in the house. I had missed my money before he came in.</p>
               <p>Q. From where did you miss it?</p>
               <p>Green. I had put it on the bricks in the cellar, just under the kitchen floor, in a bag.</p>
               <p>Q. How much was there of it?</p>
               <p>Green. There were eleven thirty-six shilling pieces, two moidores, sixteen guineas, and one half guinea.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you usually put your money in that place?</p>
               <p>Green. I did put it there then. I had made it up for my landlord.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was it from the small beer tub?</p>
               <p>Green. Not a great way. About three yards.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you lay it there in order to hide it?</p>
               <p>Green. I did. My wife did not know where it was.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether any body that went to draw small beer could perceive it or not ?</p>
               <p>Green. They might go twenty times and never see it, it lay so close. There was but just room to put it in, and it was in a dark brown bag.</p>
               <p>Q. How high is the cellar?</p>
               <p>Green. The cellar is just high enough for a but to stand in.</p>
               <p>Court. Then your money lay just about as high as a man's eye when he stands up?</p>
               <p>Green. Yes, it did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find any of your money afterwards?</p>
               <p>Green. The prisoner produced it. It is now in the constable's hands. I accused him with taking it, and he surrender'd eleven thirty-six shilling pieces,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175609150010"></xptr> sixteen guineas, and 2 twenty-seven shilling pieces, which was all but one half guinea, which he had spent a trifle of.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say for himself?</p>
               <p>Green. Master, said he, it is not your money; I broke no lock nor drawer, I found it. I told him the number and value of the pieces before he produced it.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had he had it in his possession?</p>
               <p>Green. About twenty-four hours.</p>
               <p>Court. Then he had time enough to have gone off with it ?</p>
               <p>Green. Yes, he had.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he a yearly servant?</p>
               <p>Green. He is. He has been with me a year next Christmas.</p>
               <p>Q. How has he behaved while in your service?</p>
               <p>Green. He has behaved well. I never found any thing amiss of him before this, and if he is cleared I'll let him to work again.</p>
               <p>Q. If this money had been laid in a proper drawer, or place where money is used to be put, whether you think he'd have taken it ?</p>
               <p>Green. I think he would not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-23-person182">
                  Thomas 
                  Edge 
               <interp inst="t17560915-23-person182" type="surname" value="Edge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-23-person182" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-23-person182" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ( the constable) produced the money.</p>
               <p>Court to prosecutor. Tell it over.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor ( tells it over.) It is very right.</p>
               <p>Court. Take care where you put it for the future.</p>
               <p>The prisoner was not call'd upon to make his defence.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17560915-23-verdict129" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560915-23-verdict129" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
