<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560915-27">
               <interp inst="t17560915-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-27" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560915"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-27" type="date" value="17560915"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560915-27-off145-c154" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-27-defend206 t17560915-27-off145 t17560915-27-verdict148"></join>
         
               <p>354. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17560915-27-defend206" type="defendantName">
                  
                     John 
                     Canney 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17560915-27-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-27-defend206 t17560915-27-alias-1"></join>Benney</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-27-defend206" type="surname" value="Canney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-27-defend206" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-27-defend206" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17560915-27-off145" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560915-27-off145" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-27-off145" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               making an assault on 
                     <persName id="t17560915-27-victim208" type="victimName">
                        Hannah, <rs id="t17560915-27-viclabel146" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-27-victim208 t17560915-27-viclabel146"></join>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-27-person209 t17560915-27-viclabel146"></join> of 
                           <persName id="t17560915-27-person209" type="victimName">
                              William 
                              Smart 
                           <interp inst="t17560915-27-person209" type="surname" value="Smart"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17560915-27-person209" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17560915-27-person209" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                           <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-27-off145 t17560915-27-person209"></join>
                        </persName>
                        
                        <interp inst="t17560915-27-victim208" type="surname" value="Smart"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560915-27-victim208" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560915-27-victim208" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-27-off145 t17560915-27-victim208"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , and her the said Hannah did ravish and carnally know, against her will
            </rs>, <rs id="t17560915-27-cd147" type="crimeDate">Sept. 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-27-off145 t17560915-27-cd147"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-27-person210">
                  Hannah 
                  Smart 
               <interp inst="t17560915-27-person210" type="surname" value="Smart"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-27-person210" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-27-person210" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am subject to fits. Last Friday was seven-night being in one, this man came up to assist me; when I came to myself I found him concern'd with me.</p>
               <p>Q. How came the prisoner into your room?</p>
               <p>H. Smart. I can't tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Explain what you mean by being concern'd with you.</p>
               <p>H. Smart. I felt him in my body, in the very act, before I had power to speak; as soon as I spoke he went out of the room. I went and sat down, and felt my body very sore.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sensible of any thing that came from him?</p>
               <p>H. Smart. I can't say there did. My two children were in the room at the same time; the girl five years old, the boy three.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was your husband?</p>
               <p>H. Smart. He was not come from work. A girl that sells oisters at our door came up stairs, and ask'd<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175609150012"></xptr> me how I did. I said a man had been up and used me very ill, so that I could not sit in my chair. [The thing was transacted in an elbow chair.] The prisoner lodges in the garret, and I live up two pair of stairs; I never was in his room, nor he in mine before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever drink together?</p>
               <p>H. Smart. No; I have no manner of acquaintance with him, any more than good night or good morrow, as I saw him go up stairs and down.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you very subject to fits ?</p>
               <p>H. Smart. I have for many years, and have been an out-pensioner at Bartholomew's hospital.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was it after the affair happened before you took this man up?</p>
               <p>H. Smart. I went and made my complaint to justice Fielding the next day.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell any body of it before ?</p>
               <p>H. Smart. Nobody but the woman who came up, my husband (whom I told of it aswsoon as he came home) and one 
               <persName id="t17560915-27-person211">
                  Hannah 
                  Godier 
               <interp inst="t17560915-27-person211" type="surname" value="Godier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-27-person211" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-27-person211" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who would have had me not to have told my husband of it. The mob was so violent when I was coming from Mr. Fielding's, that they had like to have torn me to pieces; the constable had a hard piece of work to save my life. My neighbours are all Irish people, of the prisoner's country, that were so violent with me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I only endeavour'd to keep her from her fits.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you been in your own room before you fell into your fits?</p>
               <p>H. Smart. I fell into a fit assoon as I got in, finding myself very sick before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did this man ever before come into your room, to assist you when in fits?</p>
               <p>H. Smart. No, never to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the woman's name that sells oisters?</p>
               <p>H. Smart. 
               <persName id="t17560915-27-person212">
                  Betty 
                  Billington 
               <interp inst="t17560915-27-person212" type="surname" value="Billington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-27-person212" type="given" value="Betty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-27-person212" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never offer, that if he would give you some money you would not hurt him ?</p>
               <p>H. Smart. I never offer'd any thing to him about such a thing, nor he to me. My husband took him at the door that night.</p>
               <p>Q. How old is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>H. Smart. I have heard in the neighbourhood he is 65 years of age.</p>
               <p>Q. Are these fits occasioned by drinking strong liquors?</p>
               <p>H. Smart. I had drank nothing but small beer and ale that day.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-27-person213">
                  William 
                  Smart 
               <interp inst="t17560915-27-person213" type="surname" value="Smart"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-27-person213" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-27-person213" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am husband to the last witness. I was at work last Friday was seven-night, and came home at the usual time. We lay by at seven o'clock, I am a taylor. I found my wife in a single chair, when she said, My dear, I have been treated very ill, the rabbit merchant has used me so and so; I spoke to him, and he ran down stairs. I went down to my landlady, to ask her if she knew where he was, and desired her to let me know when she saw him. I heard from above soon after, that he was below. I went down and laid hold of him, and they offer'd to help me with him to the stone house. He was very unwilling at first, but afterwards he went willingly enough.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there an opportunity for him to have made his escape, after your landlady had told him of it?</p>

               <p>Smart. No, I ran down directly.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did your child of five years old tell you of it?</p>
               <p>Smart. No. she never did.</p>
               <p>Q. Does she know the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Smart. I believe she does not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-27-person214">
                  Esther 
                  Winington 
               <interp inst="t17560915-27-person214" type="surname" value="Winington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-27-person214" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-27-person214" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mrs. Smart's little girl came down stairs, and said her mamma was in a fit. I went up with a gentleman's girl that lives backwards, of eight years of age, when the woman was in a fit, in a two arm chair. 
               <persName id="t17560915-27-person215">
                  John 
                  Canney 
               <interp inst="t17560915-27-person215" type="surname" value="Canney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-27-person215" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-27-person215" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             also went up stairs with me, to help her.</p>
               <p>Q. Who desired you to come here?</p>
               <p>E. Winington. My landlady. She struggled and he held her arms in the arm chair. I went down stairs, and when I went up again the man had come down, which must have been in about four minutes. He said, Lord bless me, I can't hold her; she is too strong for me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he come down in a hurry?</p>
               <p>E. Winington. No, not at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she complain he had used her ill?</p>
               <p>E. Winington. Yes she did, about a quarter of an hour after the man was gone.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you leave the two children in the room?</p>
               <p>E. Winington. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say to you?</p>
               <p>E. Winington. She said he had torn her, but did not say where.</p>

               <p>Q. What is the prisoner's character ?</p>
               <p>E. Winington. He is esteem'd to be a very quiet honest man.</p>
               <p>Q. Does this woman use to drink gin?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175609150013"></xptr>E. Winington. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see her fuddled?</p>
               <p>E. Winington. No, but sometimes pretty near it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe she was so that day?</p>
               <p>E. Winington. Yes, Sir. A neighbour asked her for some money, and she went up stairs, and flung herself into that fit. I saw her fuddled that night.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of night was this?</p>
               <p>E. Winington. It was just duskish.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever known this woman have fits before ?</p>
               <p>E. Winington. Yes. she has had them once or twice since I have been there.</p>
               <p>Q. How came the man to go up?</p>
               <p>E. Winington. I heard 
               <persName id="t17560915-27-person216">
                  Hannah 
                  Godier 
               <interp inst="t17560915-27-person216" type="surname" value="Godier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-27-person216" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-27-person216" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             say to him, Go up, for my husband is subject to fits, and I don't care to go myself, left I should be flung into them; upon which he went up.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17560915-27-verdict148" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560915-27-verdict148" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
