<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17590912-13">
               <interp inst="t17590912-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590912-13" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590912-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17590912"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590912-13" type="date" value="17590912"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17590912-13-off85-c109" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-13-defend138 t17590912-13-off85 t17590912-13-verdict88"></join>
         
               <p>259. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17590912-13-defend138" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17590912-13-defend138" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-defend138" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-defend138" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for the <rs id="t17590912-13-off85" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-off85" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-off85" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               wilful murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17590912-13-victim140" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Hillar 
                        <interp inst="t17590912-13-victim140" type="surname" value="Hillar"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590912-13-victim140" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590912-13-victim140" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-13-off85 t17590912-13-victim140"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17590912-13-cd86" type="crimeDate">July 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-13-off85 t17590912-13-cd86"></join>.*</p> 
               <p>Valentine Marrington. I am son-in-law to 
               <persName id="t17590912-13-person141">
                  John 
                  Hillar 
               <interp inst="t17590912-13-person141" type="surname" value="Hillar"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person141" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person141" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the deceased; he was brought home dead on the twenty-first of July.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any marks or bruises upon the body?</p>
               <p>Marrington. No, none as I saw.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590912-13-person142">
                  John 
                  Baston 
               <interp inst="t17590912-13-person142" type="surname" value="Baston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person142" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person142" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Saturday the 21st of July about four in the afternoon I was in Mr Smart's field, and went with Mr Smart pretty near a rick of hay that was making; there were some men he had employ'd to unload some trusses of hay out of a barge to carry upon the rick.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>Baston. It was at <placeName id="t17590912-13-crimeloc87">Limehouse</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17590912-13-crimeloc87" type="placeName" value="Limehouse"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17590912-13-crimeloc87" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-13-off85 t17590912-13-crimeloc87"></join>; I saw Hillar the deceased upon the rick with others; 
               <persName id="t17590912-13-person143">
                  Richard 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17590912-13-person143" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person143" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person143" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was bringing a truss of hay to the rick.</p>
               <p>Q. How high was the rick at that time?</p>
               <p>Baston. It was about 9 feet from the ground. Smith went up the plank about 14 or 15 feet long. When he was got upon the top of the rick he went cross the rick; there was the deceased on the other side the rick, Smith pitch'd the truss of hay directly at the deceased.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he do it on purpose?</p>
               <p>Baston. On purpose, that is certain, with design to hit him; but I do not think it was with a design to kill him.</p>
               <p>Q. What makes you think he threw it purposely at him?</p>
               <p>Baston. By his manner of throwing it; and having crossed the rick to where Hillar was. Hillar was within about 3 feet of the side of the rick. The truss hit Hillar and knock'd him over the rick; he being a very tall man could not recover himself, he came down head and shoulders to the ground, and lay as dead on the ground.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say any thing to the deceased when he threw the hay?</p>
               <p>Baston. No words passed on either side; there was no appearance of ill or good-will. Mr Smart stood just by me; he call'd out to the other people on the rick, for they all had their backs towards him, and said Smith had murdered the man; he had knocked him off the rick. Smith came down from off the rick and said, he hoped not, and seem'd to be in a very great confusion, and was much frighted. He said, if Mr Smart would send for a surgeon, he would make good the damage. The men jump'd from the rick, and went to help the deceased up. The deceased went by the nickname of Pash. Mr Smart called out, Pash; to hear if he could speak. Hillar spoke, but I can't tell what he said. He was taken up and carried into Mr Smart's house and set in a chair.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175909120013"></xptr> Mr Smart sent for a surgeon. The deceased complained of his legs, and had quite lost the use of them. We lifted him up in the chair. When the surgeon came he found there was nothing broke. He lived about three quarters of an hour after, and died in the chair.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you think was the occasion of his death?</p>
               <p>Baston. I do not suppose that the fall of the truss of hay upon him kill'd him, but that his death was occasioned by his fall to the ground.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any previous circumstance between these two people that could lead to this?</p>
               <p>Baston. No. The prisoner was attending the deceased, and seemed very much concerned, and did not go off after the man died; the young man went to his friends, and so surrendered.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How many people were there on the rick besides the deceased?</p>
               <p>Baston. I believe there were three people there besides him.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the prisoner employed about?</p>
               <p>Baston. To carry the trusses of hay out of the lighter to the rick.</p>
               <p>Q. How large might the top of the rick be?</p>
               <p>Baston. I can't tell; it might be 20 or 30 feet square.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the deceased standing or stooping?</p>
               <p>Baston. He had been stooping; and I believe he was rising up to receive that truss that came from the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Whereabouts did the truss hit the deceased?</p>
               <p>Baston. It touched about the back part of his shoulders.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the truss hit any body besides the deceased?</p>
               <p>Baston. I do not believe it touched any body but the deceased.</p>
               <p>Q. Had these people been making merry on the hay-stack?</p>
               <p>Baston. I do not know; it was all done in 2 or 3 minutes time.</p>
               <p>Q. What were the expressions that the prisoner made use of when he found what had happened?</p>
               <p>Baston. He said, he hoped he had not killed him; if they would send for a Surgeon he would satisfy him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590912-13-person144">
                  Richard 
                  Ambrough 
               <interp inst="t17590912-13-person144" type="surname" value="Ambrough"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person144" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person144" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the barge, where we took the hay from. Smith came laughing into the barge, and said, I'll take this truss of hay and sling it at old Pash, meaning 
               <persName id="t17590912-13-person145">
                  John 
                  Hillar 
               <interp inst="t17590912-13-person145" type="surname" value="Hillar"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person145" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person145" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see what happened on the rick?</p>
               <p>Ambrough. No, I did not; I was fourscore or a hundred yards from that.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you imagine this was spoke by way of pastime?</p>
               <p>Ambrough. They used frequently to play those tricks upon hay-stacks: that I have seen when I was young.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you apprehend the thing was meant out of pastime?</p>
               <p>Ambrough. I did not imagine he meant any harm by it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590912-13-person146">
                  Richard 
                  Mason 
               <interp inst="t17590912-13-person146" type="surname" value="Mason"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person146" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person146" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was on the hay-stack at the same time: there was for about the space of 6 or 7 minutes a sort of a scrambling. The deceased was thrown down, and Smith upon him, and there was a little scramble among them in the middle of the hay-stack, between Hillar, 
               <persName id="t17590912-13-person147">
                  Simon 
                  Stiles 
               <interp inst="t17590912-13-person147" type="surname" value="Stiles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person147" type="given" value="Simon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person147" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it by way of quarrel?</p>
               <p>Mason. No quarrel; one pushed one down, and another another down, and a little hay was thrown upon them: This is a common case upon hay-stacks, in jest.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any thing said?</p>
               <p>Mason. I believe the deceased did say, D - n you, what did you throw me down for? or some such words.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did he say this to?</p>
               <p>Mason. To 
               <persName id="t17590912-13-person148">
                  Simon 
                  Stiles 
               <interp inst="t17590912-13-person148" type="surname" value="Stiles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person148" type="given" value="Simon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person148" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; and I believe he gave Stiles a pinch on the chin; then Richard Smith got up, and all the fray was over, and he went down the board to the lighter to fetch another truss of hay: they all followed him in the same manner. The deceased was then making the hay-stack (being the maker); he was laying the outside course to keep it upright;<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175909120014"></xptr> presently after I saw Smith come with a truss of hay up the board, and the moment that I looked at him he looked at Hillar, who was stooping over the outside the stack, so near the outside, that he was putting in the edge of the stack with his hands, in order to keep it upright; another man, named 
               <persName id="t17590912-13-person149">
                  John 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17590912-13-person149" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person149" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person149" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was assisting him, with hay to lay round the edge of the stack; the moment my head was turn'd to throw some hay another way, the deceased was knock'd off. I heard a hideous groan; and after that, the first word I heard was, Mr Smart said, You villain, you have knock'd this man willfully off the hay-stack, and you'll be hang'd for it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear Smith say any thing in answer to that?</p>
               <p>Mason. I cannot say that I heard him say any word at all, then Hillar was upon the ground.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner jump down after him?</p>
               <p>Mason. I cannot say that; I did not see him jump down.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you believe the thing was done in jest or earnest ?</p>
               <p>Mason. I believe it was done no other way than in jest.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they in good friendship ?</p>
               <p>Mason. I saw no difference between them.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a man is the prisoner as to his character ?</p>
               <p>Mason. He has lived with Mr Smart 4 or 5 years, and I am not in the same branch that he is (although I live there). Mr Smart is the properest man to give him a character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590912-13-person150">
                  John 
                  Hamlen 
               <interp inst="t17590912-13-person150" type="surname" value="Hamlen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person150" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person150" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 21st of July, between 4 and 5 in the afternoon, I was employed in carrying some hay for Mr Smart, I saw a scuffle on the hay-stack between 
               <persName id="t17590912-13-person151">
                  Samuel 
                  Stiles 
               <interp inst="t17590912-13-person151" type="surname" value="Stiles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person151" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person151" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and the deceased. I said to Stiles, you had better desist, and let us go about our lawful employment. He did; and he and I and the prisoner at the bar, were going from the hay-stack to fetch more hay. Smith said to 
               <persName id="t17590912-13-person152">
                  Stiles, D<interp inst="t17590912-13-person152" type="given" value="Stiles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person152" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             - n him, had I been in your place, I would have thrown him off the stack: he got a truss of hay, and returned with it, and that same truss he knock'd him off the hay-stack with. I was just behind him, but did not see it done, he being upon the rick before me; then I heard an out-cry, that the man was off the stack before I got upon it. I jump'd off the plank and went to Hillar's assistance. I ask'd him who had done it, he said 
               <persName id="t17590912-13-person153">
                  Richard 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17590912-13-person153" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person153" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person153" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I and another man carried him into the house. I never heard him speak after to the time of his death, only once he said, Lord, have mercy on me; Lord, have mercy on me. He fainted away in about 8 or 10 minutes after he was in the house in a fit. Mr Smart said to the prisoner, You have wilfully killed the man, and you will be hanged for it. Then Smith cry'd out, Lord, have mercy on me; what have I done? then Smith went away immediately, and we could not see nor hear of him that night; he surrendered the next day.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you believe was the cause of Hillar's death?</p>
               <p>Hamlen. I believe the fall was.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Who were on the stack at the time of that scuffle.</p>
               <p>Hamlen. I believe Stiles, Smith, and Hillar were there alone, I saw no body else. Smith came up after the tustle was begun.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not you there?</p>
               <p>Hamlen. I was.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I did not know that the truss of hay hit any body when I threw it from off my back, 'till my master called out.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590912-13-person154">
                  Thomas 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17590912-13-person154" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person154" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person154" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was upon the hay-stack when this accident happened, on the 21st of July, much about four in the afternoon. 
               <persName id="t17590912-13-person155">
                  Richard 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17590912-13-person155" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person155" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person155" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             threw a truss of hay, and it touched my shoulder and hit 
               <persName id="t17590912-13-person156">
                  John 
                  Hillar 
               <interp inst="t17590912-13-person156" type="surname" value="Hillar"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person156" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person156" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and knocked him off the stack.</p>
               <p>Q. Had they been playing on the stack together?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175909120015"></xptr>Taylor. They had a little before. Master had given each of us a glass of ale, and we stood up to drink it; some were on the haystack, and some were not.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was upon the hay-stack?</p>
               <p>Taylor. 
               <persName id="t17590912-13-person157">
                  Samuel 
                  Stiles 
               <interp inst="t17590912-13-person157" type="surname" value="Stiles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person157" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person157" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17590912-13-person158">
                  John 
                  Hillar 
               <interp inst="t17590912-13-person158" type="surname" value="Hillar"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person158" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person158" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , they had been throwing one another down on the stack.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any quarrel, or bad words?</p>
               <p>Taylor. No. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you look upon it to be done in play?</p>
               <p>Taylor. I do. I threw hay upon them when they were down.</p>
               <p>Q. Whereabouts did the hay hit the deceased?</p>
               <p>Taylor. It grazed my shoulder, and turned me about a little, and hit Hillar on the hams, as he was stooping.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was the deceased from you?</p>
               <p>Taylor. About half a yard.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you imagine, if it had not hit you it would have hit Hillar ?</p>
               <p>Taylor. That I can't say.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think the prisoner intended it for Hillar?</p>
               <p>Taylor. I can't say that he intended to hit him.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you stand?</p>
               <p>Taylor. I was between Hillar and Smith, I saw Hillar fall from the stack.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think the truss of hay hitting Hillar was accidental?</p>
               <p>Taylor. That is what I cannot say.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your opinion of it?</p>
               <p>Taylor. My opinion is, I heard no bad words upon the stack; what past below that I cannot say; he might design to throw it at me, or him, or down: it might be accidental.</p>
               <p>Q. Does not a truss of hay, sometimes, roll out of the place where it falls?</p>
               <p>Taylor. Very often.</p>
               <p>Q. If it might be accidental, how came it over your shoulder; could that be by accident?</p>
               <p>Taylor. I did not hear any bad words; I stood with my back towards Smith; I do believe it was accidental.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the deceased doing when the truss hit him?</p>
               <p>Taylor. He was just turning the corner of the stack.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the blow a slight or a violent blow?</p>
               <p>Taylor. It graz'd me pretty hard.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you imagine he would have fell with that blow had he not been at the edge of the stack ?</p>
               <p>Taylor. I said, if you do not draw that corner in you will have it too far out, and he was stooping down. I believe in the position he was in, the value of a pound weight would have thrown him off.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the prisoner after the deceased fell down ?</p>
               <p>Taylor. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him jump off the stack?</p>
               <p>Taylor. No: I saw him go to the deceased, but do not know what he said.</p>
               <p>Q. What is th e prisoner's general character?</p>
               <p>Taylor. I never heard any thing of him but that of a good one.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he a quiet, well-behaved, man?</p>
               <p>Taylor. He always behaved well to me, and was in friendship with all the others as far as I know.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590912-13-person159">
                  Simon 
                  Stiles 
               <interp inst="t17590912-13-person159" type="surname" value="Stiles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person159" type="given" value="Simon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person159" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was upon the hay-stack, a little before the accident happened; but was not there at the time; we had been at play together; Hillar pushed me down, and I happened to turn him; he took hold on my chin, and after that my throat, but in no anger, neither he with me nor I with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it usual on hay-stacks to be playing together ?</p>
               <p>Stiles. It is.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you when the accident happened?</p>
               <p>Stiles. I was behind Smith going up upon the stack; I did not see him pitch it down.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you told Smith how Hillar had thrown you down and used you?</p>
               <p>Stiles. Very likely I might?</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the deceased after he was in your master's house?</p>
               <p>Stiles. I was there with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the prisoner there?</p>
               <p>Stiles. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he behave?</p>
               <p>Stiles. He was seemingly very sorry.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the deceased and he in friendship ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175909120016"></xptr>Stiles. I never heard they had any words in anger in my life; and I have lived there going on four years.</p>
               <p>Q. to Baston. How did the prisoner behave?</p>
               <p>Baston. He always behaved quiet and sober; a man of good character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590912-13-person160">
                  Benjamin 
                  Crofts 
               <interp inst="t17590912-13-person160" type="surname" value="Crofts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person160" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person160" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner I believe fifteen or sixteen years.</p>
               <p>Q. What has been his behaviour?</p>
               <p>Crofts. I never knew him but quiet and sober as any man in England.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you take him to be a man of humanity?</p>
               <p>Crofts. I take him to be as good a Christian that way as any man on earth. I have been very much acquainted with him for some years.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590912-13-person161">
                  Abraham 
                  Farrin 
               <interp inst="t17590912-13-person161" type="surname" value="Farrin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person161" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person161" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about twelve years; I always looked upon him to be a modest, peaceable, man; and a very sober, well-behaved man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590912-13-person162">
                  Richard 
                  Syres 
               <interp inst="t17590912-13-person162" type="surname" value="Syres"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person162" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-person162" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him five or six years, and been very intimate with him; he is a quiet, peaceable, man. I keep a public house, he has come with his fellow-servants, and always appeared good-natured and humane.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17590912-13-verdict88" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-verdict88" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-verdict88" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17590912-13-punish89" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-punish89" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-13-punish89" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-13-defend138 t17590912-13-punish89"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
