<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510911-62">
               <interp inst="t17510911-62" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510911-62" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510911-62" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510911-62" type="date" value="17510911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510911-62-off300-c397" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-62-defend512 t17510911-62-off300 t17510911-62-verdict303"></join>
         
               <p>540. 
               <persName id="t17510911-62-defend512" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Alice 
                     Dempsey 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17510911-62-alias-9" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-62-defend512 t17510911-62-alias-9"></join>M'daniel</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-62-defend512" type="surname" value="Dempsey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-62-defend512" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-62-defend512" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             
                  <rs id="t17510911-62-deflabel299" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-62-defend512 t17510911-62-deflabel299"></join>, was indicted, for that she, <rs id="t17510911-62-off300" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510911-62-off300" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-62-off300" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               in a certain  place called the White-horse-yard, near the King's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17510911-62-victim515" type="victimName">
                           Elizabeth 
                           Murphy 
                        <interp inst="t17510911-62-victim515" type="surname" value="Murphy"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510911-62-victim515" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510911-62-victim515" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting her in bodily fear, and taking from her one pair of gold ear rings, and 6 d. in money
            </rs>, the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17510911-62-victim517" type="victimName">
                     Patrick 
                     Murphy 
                  <interp inst="t17510911-62-victim517" type="surname" value="Murphy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-62-victim517" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-62-victim517" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17510911-62-cd301" type="crimeDate">Aug. 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-62-off300 t17510911-62-cd301"></join>. +</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-62-person518">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Murphy 
               <interp inst="t17510911-62-person518" type="surname" value="Murphy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-62-person518" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-62-person518" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Wild-street, and my husband's name is Patrick. I am mother to the <rs id="t17510911-62-viclabel302" type="occupation">child</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-62-victim515 t17510911-62-viclabel302"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-62-victim517 t17510911-62-viclabel302"></join>; she will be seven years of age the 8th of next January. On the 30th of August, about eight o'clock in the morning, I sent her with 6 d. for some tea, and I am sure she had her gold earrings on then; she was not gone above a quarter of an hour before she was brought home without her ear rings and money: we searched the prisoner, but found nothing upon her. I said, if she would let me have the child's ear rings, she should go about her business, but she told me, she did not take them; she then said she had two pair at home, and would give me one pair, if I would let her go.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-62-person519">
                  George 
                  Hatfield 
               <interp inst="t17510911-62-person519" type="surname" value="Hatfield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-62-person519" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-62-person519" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never saw the child before the 30th of August, between seven and eight in the morning. I saw the prisoner bring her down Wild-street, and carry her into the White-horse-yard behind the gate, one was shut, and the other open, and in half a minute I heard the child scream out; she brought it out, and said, hush, hush. Let me go home to my mamma, said the child ; (I was dressing a horse there) I thought it was not the prisoner's own; I saw a woman, and asked her if she knew the child; then I went and laid hold of the prisoner, who said it was her child, and that I had no business to lay hold of her in the street. She would not deliver the child till I made her; then took them both to the child's friends.</p>
               <p>Q. to E. Murphy. Did the ear rings hook round her ears, or were her ears bored?</p>
               <p>E. Murphy. Her ears were bored thorough where the ear rings were put.</p>
               <p>Q. to Hatfield. Do you know what was the occasion of the child's screaming out?</p>
               <p>Hatfield. I do not; nor did I know the child had any ear rings on, till I delivered her to her mother.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-62-person520">
                  John 
                  Clare 
               <interp inst="t17510911-62-person520" type="surname" value="Clare"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-62-person520" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-62-person520" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw this woman coming down Wild-street, and go into White-horse-yard; after she was in a little time, she came out with the c hild in her arms, and the child cried out, pray let me go to my mamma, pray let me go to my mamma. I heard the prisoner say, it was her child: I then went with Mr. Hatfield to the child's mother, and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175109110038"></xptr> there the prisoner offered her a pair of gold ear rings she had at home, if she would let her have her liberty.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs. Murphy. Were the child's ears hurt ?</p>
               <p>E. Murphy. They were not, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the ear rings use to fall out of themselves at any time?</p>
               <p>E. Murphy. One of them unlocked once, and but once, as I know of.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is the White-horse from your house ?</p>
               <p>E. Murphy. I live opposite Little Wild-street, and the White-horse is the length of Little Wild-street from my house.</p>
               <p>Prisoners Defence.</p>
               <p>I was passing along, and thought no harm; the child was crying, and said a woman took her ear rings and six-pence; then two men came and said, is this the woman; the child said, I don't know; then they took and searched every inch of me, pulled off my shoes and stockings into my shift, and found nothing upon me: I went into that place to do that which was not proper to do in the street.</p>
               <p>Q. to Hatfield. Which way was the bringing the child ?</p>
               <p>Hatfield. She brought it from homewards to the White-horse.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-62-person521">
                  Edward 
                  Conner 
               <interp inst="t17510911-62-person521" type="surname" value="Conner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-62-person521" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-62-person521" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner ten years, she is a working girl, and I know nothing dishonest of her till now.</p>
               <p>Charles M'Daniel. I have known her these fifteen years, and she is as honest a girl as ever I bred.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-62-person522">
                  Sarah M 
                  Daniel 
               <interp inst="t17510911-62-person522" type="surname" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-62-person522" type="given" value="Sarah M"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-62-person522" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her since she was born ; she is very true and honest; I saw her truly married : I am an honest endeavouring woman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-62-person523">
                  Catharine 
                  Matthews 
               <interp inst="t17510911-62-person523" type="surname" value="Matthews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-62-person523" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-62-person523" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her a good while, and I never knew any thing by her, but what is true and honest.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510911-62-verdict303" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510911-62-verdict303" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
