<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570914-40">
               <interp inst="t17570914-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-40" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570914"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-40" type="date" value="17570914"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570914-40-off261-c417" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-40-defend501 t17570914-40-off261 t17570914-40-verdict264"></join>
         
               <p>348. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17570914-40-defend501" type="defendantName">
                     Philip 
                     Riley 
                  <interp inst="t17570914-40-defend501" type="surname" value="Riley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-40-defend501" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-40-defend501" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17570914-40-off261" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570914-40-off261" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-40-off261" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing four pair of buckskin breeches, value 3 l. 3 s. two silk handkerchiefs, value 7 s. three 36 s. pieces, one 18 s. piece, five guineas, and 12 s. 6 d. in money numbered, the goods and money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17570914-40-victim503" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Perkins 
                        <interp inst="t17570914-40-victim503" type="surname" value="Perkins"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570914-40-victim503" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570914-40-victim503" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-40-off261 t17570914-40-victim503"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling house of 
                     <persName id="t17570914-40-person504">
                        John 
                        Duglass 
                     <interp inst="t17570914-40-person504" type="surname" value="Duglass"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570914-40-person504" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570914-40-person504" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17570914-40-cd262" type="crimeDate">Aug 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-40-off261 t17570914-40-cd262"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-40-person505">
                  John 
                  Perkins 
               <interp inst="t17570914-40-person505" type="surname" value="Perkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-40-person505" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-40-person505" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mr. Duglass. He keeps livery stables. I lost four pair of buckskin breeches, my money, and all that I had.</p>
               <p>Q. Why do you charge the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Perkins. He was a <rs id="t17570914-40-deflabel263" type="occupation">bricklayer's labourer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-40-defend501 t17570914-40-deflabel263"></join> there.</p>
               <p>Q. Why do you suspect him?</p>
               <p>Perkins. He had no money when he work'd in our house, but after my things were lost he was full of money. I took him up on suspicion, and carried him to the Round-house, and the next morning before justice Fielding, where I charg'd him with taking my boxes and money. The justice said, Riley what have you been doing; he answer'd, I have been doing that which I shall never do any more, and he acknowledged the whole affair.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-40-person506">
                  John 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17570914-40-person506" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-40-person506" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-40-person506" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am one of the beadles of the parish of St. George's. On the 4th of August it happen'd to be my watch night. Humphry Hyate, the constable, desir'd me to go with him to Hide Park Corner, where a robbery was committed, at the house of Mr. Duglass. We found the prisoner, and brought him to the watch-house. Then the prosecutor with some others went out, and found out the house where the prisoner lodg'd, at one Bowyer's in Brig-street; we went there about twelve o'clock, and found the two boxes, and brought them as we found them, with the woman of the house, to the watch-house. We open'd the boxes before the prisoner in the watch-house. Then he confess'd the fact, that he was the person that stole the things mention'd.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you find ?</p>
               <p>Lewis. We found three 36 s. pieces, one 18 s. piece, five guineas in gold, two crown pieces, and half crown, four pair of buckskin breeches and two handkerchiefs. In the morning we took the prisoner in a coach to Mr. Fielding's; he told us going along he had pawn'd half the things. [There were many things which he own'd he had taken, that are not in the indictment.]</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you find the things and money you mention?</p>
               <p>Lewis. In the boxes. The prisoner acknowledged before justice Fielding that he was employ'd as a night watcher at Mr. Duglass's, and that he took the boxes from thence, and carried them to his lodgings, and said he was just come from Ireland.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Was you by at the time all was said and done, which this evidence has mention'd.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I was, and it is all truth.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Where did you keep these boxes?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. In my own room, at Mr. Duglass's, in a garret in his dwelling house.</p>
               <p>Humphry Hyate. I am petty constable of St. George's, Hanover-Square. On the 4th of August, about half an hour after nine at night, I fetch'd Mr. Lewis to Mr. Duglass's, the prosecutor having charg'd the prisoner with having rob'd him. I left the prisoner in custody with two or three labourers, and we went and found the boxes at the prisoner's lodgings. I open'd them at the watch house, and after the prisoner saw them open, he own'd he was the person that brought them from Mr. Duglass's.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Did not I tell you that Rogers brought the boxes at ten o'clock to me?</p>
               <p>Hyate. No, I don't remember that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-40-person507">
                  Christian 
                  Gwyre 
               <interp inst="t17570914-40-person507" type="surname" value="Gwyre"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-40-person507" type="given" value="Christian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-40-person507" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the first of August the prisoner brought the little box into my house, this was on a Monday night, and he came to lodge with me but the Saturday before. (One box produced in court.) On the Tuesday morning he came to me, and ask'd me if I had any thing that would break open his box, for he had lost the key. I let him try my key, and it would not do; then he took a hammer and went to break it, but whether he did or did not, I can't say.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. My linen and stockings were in one box, they are not found; the breeches and money were in another, that box is here.</p>
               <p>C. Gwyre. I saw him bring only one box, but there were two found when the constable came.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-40-person508">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Venables 
               <interp inst="t17570914-40-person508" type="surname" value="Venables"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-40-person508" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-40-person508" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the prisoner bring one box to the house of 
               <persName id="t17570914-40-person509">
                  Christian 
                  Gwyre 
               <interp inst="t17570914-40-person509" type="surname" value="Gwyre"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-40-person509" type="given" value="Christian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-40-person509" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I never took the things. if I suffer for it; the man is here that gave them to me, but I don't<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175709140051"></xptr> want him here. If I had but a little time, I could make it appear that my character is as good as the best man's in court. I serv'd my time with the earl of Kildare. I'll tell the truth, I can't be worse than I am: This Rogers brought the box to me about four o'clock in the afternoon to my lodgings, and bid me keep it till the morrow. The next day was a rainy day; he said he would not be kept under by his brother, and so brought his things away. He lay in my bed that night. Then he said he had lost the key of his box, and did not know how to get at his things, and desir'd me to get a hammer. I did, and he bid me tell my landlady it was my box; she gave me the hammer and I took out the things; said he, this woman may make a discovery that I am going to pawn my things. I said I'll take and carry them out. I went with them to the pawnbroker's; and he said he'd go and stay in the cook's cellar till I return'd, and said I might put them in either his or my name. The pawnbroker ask'd me whose goods they were, I said they belong'd to another man that had need of money. He said you must come and release them, then I said he might as well put them in my name. On the Wednesday following Rogers came again, and said, will you take care of the watchman till I pass him, for fear he should take me up with this box. Said I what are you afraid of; he said it was his own box, and he wanted to lodge with me that night. I said I could not carry the box in, they were all in bed. He came and gave me the box at the door, and left it in the room. The next day he came with a hatchet in his hand, and said, now Riley I have a secret to relate to you, if you will keep it I will make a man of you, and you will live well. Said he, I saw the ostler taking out money from a purse in a box, and I thought the first box was it, but now I have it, and there are a great many cloaths in it, and you and I will go away to Portsmouth, and I'll be under no dread of my brother. He fell on his knees to me, and prevailed on me not to tell; said I, see and get some money that will redeem the things already pawn'd, and carry them back. He said he brought them down a ladder three story high, and would not carry them back: I would not have brought the boxes down that ladder if you would give me twenty thousand pounds.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570914-40-verdict264" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570914-40-verdict264" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17570914-40-punish265" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570914-40-punish265" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-40-defend501 t17570914-40-punish265"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
