<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17541023-16">
               <interp inst="t17541023-16" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541023-16" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541023-16" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17541023"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541023-16" type="date" value="17541023"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17541023-16-off75-c83" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-16-defend111 t17541023-16-off75 t17541023-16-verdict78"></join>
         
               <p>481. 
               
                  <persName id="t17541023-16-defend111" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     James 
                  <interp inst="t17541023-16-defend111" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-16-defend111" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-16-defend111" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17541023-16-off75" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17541023-16-off75" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-16-off75" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing one linen handkerchief, val. 12 d. the property of 
                     <persName id="t17541023-16-person112">
                        John 
                        Neal 
                     <interp inst="t17541023-16-person112" type="surname" value="Neal"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17541023-16-person112" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17541023-16-person112" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17541023-16-cd76" type="crimeDate">Oct. 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-16-off75 t17541023-16-cd76"></join>.*.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541023-16-person113">
                  John 
                  Neal 
               <interp inst="t17541023-16-person113" type="surname" value="Neal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-16-person113" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-16-person113" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Saturday se'nnight I was going through <placeName id="t17541023-16-crimeloc77">St. Paul's Church-yard</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17541023-16-crimeloc77" type="placeName" value="St. Paul's Church-yard"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17541023-16-crimeloc77" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-16-off75 t17541023-16-crimeloc77"></join>; just by the chapter-house a person that stood with a basket to sell fruit, told me I had lost my handkerchief out of my right hand pocket, and said, - yonder goes the man that took it; I felt and said I had lost it, and desired he would not go away till I had laid hold of him; I then went and took hold of the prisoner, and held him by both wrists, and insisted on his giving an account of himself; he struggled to get away; the other man then came up and took hold of him behind. The mob grew pretty great. I said, we'll go and take him to a publick-house; the prisoner reply'd, what will you go without your handkerchief? I saw a man toss it within the rails, and pointed to something as well as he could; I still held his wrists, and desired a friend of mine to put his stick within the rails and know what it was, seeing something lye there, but it was only a cabbage leaf. I took the prisoner into an ale-house, and he had not his hands at liberty above a minute before the handkerchief was between his feet, lying on the ground; upon that he was taken before Sir 
               <persName id="t17541023-16-person114">
                  John 
                  Barnard 
               <interp inst="t17541023-16-person114" type="surname" value="Barnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-16-person114" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-16-person114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and committed.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him drop the handkerchief?</p>
               <p>J Neal. I can't say I did.</p>
               <p>Q How came you to let his hands go before you had felt pockets?</p>
               <p>J. Neal. I had sent for a constable, so did not think it so well to search him till the constable came, and seeing I had got him safe in the house, I let go his hands.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say for himself?</p>
               <p>J. Neal. He said but very little; he pretended to say a man in the room dropped it, but that man was known in the house to be a man of reputation.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the value of the handkerchief ?</p>
               <p>J. Neal. It cost two shillings, and it is almost new.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it worth one shilling?</p>
               <p>J. Neal. To be sure it is worth that (produced in court, and deposed to.)</p>
               <p>J. Bust. I had a basket of fruit against a post near the chapter house; I saw the prisoner take the handkerchief out of the prosecutor's pocket as he was going by, on a Saturday night about 7 o'clock; the prosecutor was walking along with another gentleman, and the prisoner went between them, and with his right hand took the handkerchief out of the prosecutor's right hand pocket; he made an attempt to put it under his arm. I ran to Mr. Neal and told him his pocket was pick'd, and went and held the prisoner fast by the neck till Mr. Neal came to him; after that, I saw the prisoner drop the handkerchief in the Crown ale-house.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you saw the handkerchief fall from him?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175410230008"></xptr>Bust. I am sure I did, it fell just by the fire place, as soon as he had got his hand at liberty.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541023-16-person115">
                  Samuel 
                  Magniac 
               <interp inst="t17541023-16-person115" type="surname" value="Magniac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-16-person115" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-16-person115" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Saturday was 7 night, I was along with Mr. Neal, I had hold of his arm, going by the chapter house, a man dressed in blue, I suppose it was this last evidence, said to Mr. Neal, you have had your pocket picked of a handkerchief. Mr. Neal ran and took hold of the prisoner's wrists and I his right arm. The prisoner said I saw a man throw a handkerchief into the rails, I felt with my stick and found it to be a cabbage leaf. We took him into a public house: Mr. Neal then let go his hands, after which I saw a handkerchief lying under his feet.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see it fall?</p>
               <p>Magniac. No, my lord, I did not. By the position it lay on the ground, it appeared as if it had slid down from under his coat.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was in that house, there were twenty or thirty people, one said here is a handkerchief lies here, now he has dropped it; another said, no, he has not, I was looking at him all the time. A gentleman said, turn him out of the door, I said don't turn that man out. When he was out, I said, let that man in again, but they said he should not come in.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17541023-16-verdict78" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17541023-16-verdict78" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17541023-16-punish79" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17541023-16-punish79" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-16-defend111 t17541023-16-punish79"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
