<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17520625-33">
               <interp inst="t17520625-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520625-33" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520625-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520625"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520625-33" type="date" value="17520625"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520625-33-off143-c168" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520625-33-defend222 t17520625-33-off143 t17520625-33-verdict146"></join>
         
               <p>360. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17520625-33-defend222" type="defendantName">
                     Frances 
                     Monday 
                  <interp inst="t17520625-33-defend222" type="surname" value="Monday"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-33-defend222" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-33-defend222" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17520625-33-deflabel142" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520625-33-defend222 t17520625-33-deflabel142"></join>, was indicted for that <rs id="t17520625-33-off143" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520625-33-off143" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-33-off143" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               she, in a certain place to the jurors unknown, on 
                     <persName id="t17520625-33-victim223" type="victimName">
                        John 
                        Hall 
                     <interp inst="t17520625-33-victim223" type="surname" value="Hall"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520625-33-victim223" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520625-33-victim223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520625-33-off143 t17520625-33-victim223"></join>
                     </persName>
                    did make an assault, putting him in danger of his life, and stealing from his person one half guinea in gold
            </rs>, <rs id="t17520625-33-cd144" type="crimeDate">June 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520625-33-off143 t17520625-33-cd144"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>John Hall. Last Thursday se'nnight I had been in the Borough, staid late, and was in liquor. I could not get into my lodgings in Grey's-Inn-lane. I was going from thence to Westminster to an acquaintance there, and passing by the new church in the Strand this woman came cross the way to me and asked me to go with her and drink some Dorchester ale. I went to a place which she said was the Black Swan between the new church and Exeter Change. I drank but one glass of beer. She then asked me to give her some shrub. which I did, and a bottle to take home with her. I staid there about half an hour, and paid three shillings for what we had, I changed a guinea, and I believe in pulling out that she saw another which I took out with it. She wanted me to go home with her, which I did to a house <placeName id="t17520625-33-crimeloc145">next door to the red house in Exeter Court</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17520625-33-crimeloc145" type="placeName" value="next door to the red house in Exeter Court"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520625-33-crimeloc145" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520625-33-off143 t17520625-33-crimeloc145"></join>. I sat down in<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175206250013"></xptr> a chair, and she asked me what I would give her, I gave her four shillings. She seemed to speak as though I should not have to do with her for that; I said I did not desire it I only wanted to go to bed for the conveniency of the bed, and said, give me my money again. Presently she said, you shall give me half a guinea; she slapped my face and gave me several blows. Then I came to my senses. She said, I will have your money, and there are them in the house that will prevent your telling tales, if you don't give it me, and affected a hem, calling Dick. She put her hand into her pocket and said, if you don't give it me I'll rip your guts out directly. I told her I was as strong as she; upon which she said, I should be murdered if I did not comply, so I pulled out all I had in one pocket, which was half a guinea and four or five pennyworth of halfpence, and laid them on the table ; she scrabbled it up, put it in her pocket, and said, she would have more, and that I had a guinea more. I told her I had not, and desired her to give me the halfpence again for a breakfast, but she still insisted upon having a guinea more or I should never go out of the house. At last I got out by swearing I never would take her before a justice or meddle with her. I immediately got a watchman, who talked to her as she looked out at the window. She told him he was no constable. Then came a beadle, to whom an old woman opened the door. They took the prisoner to the Roundhouse. The woman of the house offered me my money again.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>The gentleman made me a present of it. After he had what he desired of me, he said he would have it again, or he'd swear a robbery against me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-33-person224">
                  William 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17520625-33-person224" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-33-person224" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-33-person224" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the Old Bailey. I was at the house next door to where the prisoner lives, and going out to make water I heard her voice, (I knew her before.) I also heard a man say, give me my halfpence; she answered, did not you give it me? he said, I know that, but if you don't I'll swear a robbery against you.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-33-person225">
                  Mary 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17520625-33-person225" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-33-person225" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-33-person225" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I opened the door and let the prisoner and that man in that night.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her name?</p>
               <p>M. Smith. I can't tell her sirname, her Christian name is Jane. I have known her about a fortnight; she lived there at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Who keeps the house?</p>
               <p>M. Smith. I can't tell, the gentleman lives in Westminster.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>M. Smith. I am a chairwoman and washerwoman.</p>
               <p>Q. Who lives in the house?</p>
               <p>M. Smith. There are two men and their wives. I was in the passage and heard him say to her, what will you have? she said, half a guinea; he said, there it is for you, take it. I know no more.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520625-33-verdict146" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520625-33-verdict146" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
