<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17580510-17">
               <interp inst="t17580510-17" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580510-17" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580510-17" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580510"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580510-17" type="date" value="17580510"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580510-17-off87-c195" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580510-17-defend228 t17580510-17-off87 t17580510-17-verdict90"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580510-17-off91-c195" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580510-17-defend228 t17580510-17-off91 t17580510-17-verdict90"></join>
         
               <p>216. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17580510-17-defend228" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Barnard 
                  <interp inst="t17580510-17-defend228" type="surname" value="Barnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-defend228" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-defend228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <placeName id="t17580510-17-defloc85">late of the parish of St. James, within the city and liberty of Westminster</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17580510-17-defloc85" type="placeName" value="late of the parish of St. James, within the city and liberty of Westminster"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17580510-17-defloc85" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580510-17-defend228 t17580510-17-defloc85"></join>, in the county of Middlesex, <rs id="t17580510-17-deflabel86" type="occupation">yeoman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580510-17-defend228 t17580510-17-deflabel86"></join>, was indicted, for that <rs id="t17580510-17-off87" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-off87" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-off87" type="offenceSubcategory" value="extortion"></interp>
               he being an ill-dispos'd person, and seeking wicked gain, and little regarding the laws and statutes of this kingdom, or the pains and penalties therein contain'd; after the first day of June, in the year of our Lord 1723, to wit, on the <rs id="t17580510-17-cd88" type="crimeDate">3d day of December, in the 31st year of the reign of our sovereign Lord George the second, King of Great-Britain</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580510-17-off87 t17580510-17-cd88"></join>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580510-17-off91 t17580510-17-cd88"></join>, &amp;c. with force and arms, at the parish aforesaid, in the country aforesaid, knowingly, unlawfully, wickedly, and feloniously, did send a certain letter in writing with a fictitious name, to wit, with the fictitious name of Felton thereto signed and subscribed, to the most noble 
                     <persName id="t17580510-17-victim229" type="victimName">
                        Charles 
                        <rs id="t17580510-17-viclabel89" type="occupation">Duke of Marlborough</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580510-17-victim229 t17580510-17-viclabel89"></join>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580510-17-victim263 t17580510-17-viclabel89"></join>
                        <interp inst="t17580510-17-victim229" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580510-17-victim229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580510-17-off87 t17580510-17-victim229"></join>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580510-17-off91 t17580510-17-victim229"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , and directed to the said Duke, by the title and description of his Grace the Duke of Marlborough, demanding therein a certain valuable thing, to wit, a genteel support for the life of him the said 
                     <persName id="t17580510-17-person230">
                        William 
                        Barnard 
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person230" type="surname" value="Barnard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580510-17-person230" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580510-17-person230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , against the form of the statute in such case made and provided, to the evil example of all others, in the like case offending, and against the peace of our said Lord the King, his crown and dignity
            </rs>. *</p>
               <p>THE DUKE OF MARLBOROUGH SWORN.</p>
               <p>I receiv'd this letter from an unknown hand, dated the 29th of November, and directed to me, appointing me to meet the writer on a certain spot in Hyde Park.</p>
               <p>The letter read.</p>
               <p>To his Grace the Duke of Marlborough, with care and speed.</p>
               <p>XXVIIII November.</p>
               <p>' My Lord,</p>
               <p>' as ceremony is an idle thing upon most ' occasions, more especially to persons in my ' state of mind, I shall proceed immediately to ' acquaint You, with the motive &amp; end, of addressing ' this epistle to You, which is equally ' interesting to us both: You are to know then, ' that my present situation in life, is such, that I ' should prefer annihilation, to a continuance in it: ' desperate diseases, require desperate remedies, ' and You are the man I have pitched upon, either ' to make me, or to unmake Yourself; as I ' never had the honour to live among the great, ' the tenour of my proposals, will not be very ' courtly, but let that be an argument, to enforce ' the belief, of what I am now going to write; ' it has employed my invention for some time, ' to find out a method to destroy another, without ' exposing my own life, that I have accomplished, ' and defy the law; now for the application of ' it, I am desperate, and must be provided for; ' You have it in your power, it is my business to ' make it your inclination to serve me; which ' You must determine to comply with, by procuring ' me a genteel support, for my life, or ' your own, will be at a period, before this sessions ' of parliament is over: I have more motives, ' than one, for singling You out first, upon this ' occasion; and I give you this fair warning, because ' the means I shall make use of, are too ' fatal, to be eluded by the power of physick: if ' you think this of any consequence, You will ' not fail to meet the Author, on Sunday next, at ' ten in the morning, or on Monday (if the ' weather should be rainy on Sunday) near the ' first Tree beyond the Stile in Hyde-Park, in ' the foot walk to Kensington: secresy and compliance ' may preserve You, from a double danger ' of this sort; as there is a certain part of the ' world, where your death has more than been ' wished, for upon other motives; I know the ' world too well, to trust this secret, in any breast, ' but my own; a few days determine me, your ' friend or enemy.</p>
               <p>' Felton.</p>
               <p>' You will apprehend that I mean you should be ' alone, and depend upon it that a discovery of ' any artifice in this affair will be fatal to You, ' my safety is insured by my silence, for confession ' only can condemn me.'</p>
               <p>Q. What did your Grace do upon the receipt of this letter?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. I went to the place at the time appointed. It was at the first tree near the style in Hyde Park, in the way to Kensington, at the end<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175805100020"></xptr> of the Serpentine water, betwixt that water and a little pond. I was there some time, and saw nobody stop that I could suspect to be the person; upon which I was going away: but as I came to Hyde Park corner, I turn'd my horse and saw a person stand loitering, and looking at the water over the bridge. This was, I believe, within twenty yards of the tree, and this induc'd me to go back again. I rode up to the person very gently, and passed by him once or twice, expecting him to speak to me; he did not: I made him a bow, and ask'd him if he had something to say to me? he said No, I don't know you. I said I am the Duke of Marlborough: Now you know me, I imagine; you have something to say to me: he said No, I have not. Then I rode away.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your Grace arm'd?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. I had pistols before me.</p>
               <p>Q. Had your Grace any great coat on?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. No, I had not. My star might easily be seen.</p>
               <p>Q. Does your Grace see any body here that you saw there?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. It was the prisoner at the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. Had your Grace any servant or attendant with you?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. I had no servant with me, there was a person, a friend of mine, at a good distance in the Park. A day or two after, I can't be sure whether it was the next day or the day after that, I receiv'd a second letter.</p>
               <p>It is read.</p>
               <p>To his Grace the Duke of Marlborough.</p>
               <p>' My Lord,</p>
               <p>' You receive this as an acknowledgement of ' your punctuality as to the time and place of ' meeting on Sunday last tho' it was owing to ' You, that it answered no purpose, the pageantry ' of being armed, and the ensign of your ' order, were useless, and too conspicuous, You ' needed no attendant, the place was not calculated ' for mischief, nor was any intended: if ' You walk in the west isle of Westminster-Abbey, ' towards eleven o'clock on Sunday next, ' your Sagacity, will point out the person, whom ' you will address, by asking h company, to take ' a turn or two with You; You will not fail, on ' enquiry, to be acquainted with the name, and ' place of abode, according to which directions, ' You will please to send, two or three hundred ' pound bank Notes, the next day by the penny ' post; exert not your curiosity too early it is ' in your power to make me grateful on certain ' terms I have friends who are faithful, but ' they do not bark before they bite.</p>
               <p>' I am &amp;c. ' &amp;c. ' F.'</p>
               <p>Q. What did your Grace do upon the receipt of this second letter?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. I went to Westminster Abbey at the time the letter appointed. I had been walking there about five or six minutes before I saw any body that I suspected; then I saw the person I had seen before in Hyde Park, and another person who seemed to be a good looking man, a substantial tradesman: they came in and look'd on the monuments. I knowing the person again, went and stood by them; but the prisoner said nothing to me: soon after they both of them went towards the choir; the stranger, I may call him, went into the choir, and the prisoner turn'd back and came towards me, but did not speak to me. Then I ask'd him if he had any thing to say to me, or any commands for me? He said No, my Lord, I have not. I said, sure you have, he said No, my Lord; he walk'd up and down one side the isle, and I the other to give him a little more time; but he did not speak, then I went away out at the great door, and left him in the Abbey. I look'd back to see if he watched me going out, but I did not see him.</p>
               <p>Q. Had your Grace any body with you in the Abbey?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. There were two or three people placed in disguise, ready, if I had given them the signal, to have taken him up. Though I was certain it was the same person which I had seen and spoke to in the Park, thought not proper to give the signal, but to run a little longer risk rather than to take up an innocent man. Very soon after this I receiv'd another letter, this is it.</p>
         
               <p>N. B. The Second Part of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17580510-17">
                  <interp inst="t17580510-17" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17580510-17" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17580510-17" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580510"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17580510-17" type="date" value="17580510"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175805100021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 10th, and Thursday the 11th, of MAY.</p>
                  <p>In the Thirty-first Year of his MAJESTY'S Reign. NUMBER V. PART II. for the YEAR 1758. Being the Fifth SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of THE RIGHT HONOURABLE Sir 
                  <persName id="t17580510-17-person231">
                     CHARLES 
                     ASGILL 
                  <interp inst="t17580510-17-person231" type="surname" value="ASGILL"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580510-17-person231" type="given" value="CHARLES"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580510-17-person231" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Knt. LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed and sold by M. COOPER, at the Globe, in Pater-noster Row. 1758.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175805100022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, for the City of LONDON, and at the General 
                  <persName id="t17580510-17-person232">
                     Sessions
                  <interp inst="t17580510-17-person232" type="given" value="Sessions"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580510-17-person232" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                     </persName>
                of Gaol Delivery of Newgate, holden for the said City of LONDON, and County of MIDDLESEX, at Justice-Hall in the Old-Bailey, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>The third Letter read.</p>
               <p>To his Grace the Duke of Marlborough.</p>
               <p>' My Lord,</p>
               <p>' I Am fully convinced you had a companion on ' Sunday, I interpret it as owing to the weakness ' of human nature, but such proceeding is far ' from being ingenuous, and may produce bad ' effects whilst it is impossible to answer the end ' proposed: You will see me again soon, as it ' were by accident, and may easily find where I ' go to, in consequence of which by being sent ' to, I shall wait on your Grace, but expect to be ' quite alone, and to converse in whispers, You ' will likewise give your honour upon meeting, ' that no part of the conversation shall transpire, ' these, and the former terms complied with, ' ensure your safety: my revenge in case of ' non-compliance, (or any scheme to expose me) ' will be slower, but not less sure, and strong ' suspicion, the utmost that can possibly ensue ' upon it, while the chances would be ten-fold ' against you. You will possibly be in doubt ' after the meeting but it is quite necessary the ' outside should be a mask to the in, the family ' of the BLOODS is not extinct, tho' they are ' not in my scheme.'</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. At about two months after the receipt of this, I receiv'd another letter, this is it.</p>
               <p>The fourth Letter read.</p>
               <p>To his Grace the Duke of Marlborough.</p>
               <p>' May it please your Grace</p>
               <p>' I have reason to believe that the son of ' one Barnard a surveyor in Abingdon Buildings ' Westminster is acquainted with some secrets ' that nearly concern your safety, his Father is ' now out of town which will give you an opportunity ' of questioning him more privately; ' It would be useless to your Grace as well as ' dangerous to me to appear more publickly in ' this affair</p>
               <p>' Your sincere friend. ' ANONYMOUS.</p>
               <p>' He frequently goes ' to Storeys-Gate ' coffee-house.'</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. There is no date to this letter. About a week or ten days after I receiv'd this letter, I sent a message to the Coffee-house, by Mr. Merrick, who return'd and told me he found Mr. Barnard there, and that he said, what could the Duke of Marlborough want with him? he had spoke with him once in Hyde Park, and another time in Westminster Abbey. The messenger told me, he said he'd wait on me, which he did at Marlborough-house, about half an hour after ten o'clock. I think, on the Friday following.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. It was Thursday, my Lord.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175805100023"></xptr>D. of Marlb. I can't be sure as to the day. When he came in, I knew, at first sight; it was the same person that I had seen in the Park and in the Abbey. I desir'd him to walk with me into a room, and immediately shut the door when we were in. I ask'd him as before, he said he had nothing to say to me; then I told him of the last letter I receiv'd, that it mentioned his name, and that he knew something concerning my safety; he said he knew nothing of it. Then I recapitulated all the letters, beginning with the first, and remark'd to him that it was strange to me, that a man that wrote so very correct, without false English in any shape, should be guilty of so low an action; he said a man may be very learned and very poor. I then took notice of the second letter, and said there must be something very odd in the man; he said I imagine the man must be mad; I said he seems surpriz'd that I should have pistols; said he, I was surpriz'd to see your Grace with pistols, and your Star on. I said, why was you surpriz'd at that? his answer was, after stopping a moment, It was so cold a day; I wonder'd you had not a great coat on: then I afterwards shew'd him the letter again where his name was mention'd, and walk'd with him to the window, and as I read it, when I came to that part where it said his father was out of town; he said it is very odd, my father was then out of town. I said nothing to him of that, though it struck me a good deal, as there was no date to the letter. I said, if you are innocent, it behaves you much more than me to find out the author of those letters, particularly the last: for it was an attempt to blast his character behind his back; he seem'd to give me a smile and away he went. I did not apprehend him then.</p>
               <p>Counsel for the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. In what manner did your Grace receive this first letter ?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. I am Master of the Ordnance. Some body or other had put it under the door of the office in the night time, and the keeper of the door sent it to me the next day.</p>
               <p>Q. As to the second letter, which way did your Grace receive that?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. That was sent the same way, by being put under the door as the other.</p>
               <p>Counsel. In consequence of the first letter, your Grace went into the Park on horseback, and was there some time without seeing any body you suspected; Were there not people there ?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. I saw several people on horse back, and some few walking in a hurry on foot.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray my Lord Duke, after you had seen this person lostering, was there any thing going forward, such as hunting a duck, or the like?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. No, nothing in the world as I saw, it was a very cold day.</p>
               <p>Q. Your lordship said there was another person at a distance, an attendant on your Grace; how far might that person be off when you was speaking to the prisoner?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. I cannot tell exactly. I had spoke to him to keep a great way off.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he in view of your Grace?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. I dare say he was.</p>
               <p>Q. Might not any person equally see that person as well as your Grace?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. I suppose they might.</p>
               <p>Q. Might it not be observable to any third person that your Grace spoke to Mr. Barnard?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. I suppose it might.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your Grace there at the time?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. I was there rather before the time, I believe.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he in the least offer to follow your Grace?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. No, he seem'd to go the other way.</p>
               <p>Q. With respect to the second letter, your Grace went according to appointment to Westminster Abbey, and saw the prisoner and another person come into the Abbey, before that other person had left him, had your Grace been near him?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. I had, I stood by him in hopes he wou ld speak to me, if he was the person that wrote the letters.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether the circumstance was not such, that that other person might very well believe your Grace wanted to speak to the prisoner?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. That I can't tell, I stood very near the prisoner wanting him to speak to me; it is possible he might think so.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether there was not at that time several persons attending on your Grace?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. There were two or three.</p>
               <p>Q. Did your Grace speak to either of them in the Abbey ?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175805100024"></xptr>Q. Whether if there was any other person in Westminster Abbey at that time, whether that third person might not have taken Mr. Barnard for your Grace's companion, as your Grace spoke to him?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. Upon my word I can't tell that.</p>
               <p>Q. Could there be a person to whom that expression, in the third letter, might be apply'd, referring to your Grace's companion, besides Mr. Barnard?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. Yes, It might be apply'd to a gentleman that went away with me in the coach from the Abbey.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether your Grace did not bow several times to the prisoner before you spoke?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. No, I don't think I did.</p>
               <p>Counsel. With respect to the third letter, your Grace heard no more of that till the 4th came.</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. I did not, and when the 4th came I sent to Mr. Barnard.</p>
               <p>Q. Did your Grace know Mr. Barnard before you receiv'd these letters ?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. No, I did not at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Does your Grace now know whether he was a person in such situation in life, as answered to the description in the letters?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. I don't know the least thing of him, either character or circumstance.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Then, abstracted from these circumstances, should your Grace have entertained any suspicion of him more than of any other person?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. I did not know there was such a man in the world.</p>
               <p>Q. When he came to your Grace's house, did he come in very readily?</p>

               <p>D. of Marlb. He did.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether his answer was, I was surpriz'd to see you arm'd too, or I was surpriz'd to see you arm'd?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. I can't take upon me to say whether he laid such an emphasis on it or not.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Then he made no secret of seeing your Grace in the Park.</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. No.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Nor in the Abbey?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Your Grace mention'd, he said, it is very odd my father was out of town then! could your Grace apply that in the manner it was spoke, that his father was out of town when the message came to him?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. I really understood him, that he knew his father was out of town at the time of his writing the letter.</p>
               <p>Q. Did your Grace mention the time you receiv'd it?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. No, I did not mention any time.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he come punctually to his time?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. He did, I think the messenger said he would wait on me about half an hour after ten.</p>
               <p>Q. In what manner was he apprehended?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. I do not know; I understood he was summoned.</p>
               <p>Q. It has been said, he went away with a smile; pray, my Lord Duke, might not that smile express the consciousness of his innocence as well as any thing else?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. I shall leave that to the Great Judge.</p>
               <p>Q. He said, a man might be very learned, and very poor; does your Grace know whether this person at the bar is either learned or poor?</p>

               <p>D. of Marlb. I do not know indeed.</p>
               <p>Q. May not that expression fall from any man whatever?</p>
               <p>D. of Marlb. I cannot say as to that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580510-17-person233">
                  James 
                  Merrick 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person233" type="surname" value="Merrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person233" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was directed from his Grace to carry a message to Story's Gate coffee-house; I went, and there was the prisoner at the bar: I told him, the Duke of Marlborough wanted to speak with him; he expressed some surprize at what the Duke should want with him, but no fear.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Merrick. This was on Tuesday, the 25th of April, in the evening; and he said, he would wait on the Duke on the Thursday following, between 10 and 11 o'clock.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What reason did he give for not waiting on his Grace sooner?</p>
               <p>Merrick. His excuse was, he was going out of town.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say any thing to you of his having seen the Duke before?</p>
               <p>Merrick. He did. He said, he had seen his Grace three times in his life, once in Hyde-Park, and once in Westminster Abbey, and once at the camp at Byfleet; he said, he did not know the Duke when he saw him in Hyde-Park, till the Duke himself told him who he was.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175805100025"></xptr>Q. Did he tell you what had passed either in the Park or in the Abbey?</p>
               <p>Merrick. He told me that in the Park the Duke rode up to him, and asked him, Sir, do you want any thing with me? His answer was, No. Then the Duke asked him, If he knew who he was? he answered No again. Then the Duke told him, he was the Duke of Marlborough; then he made his bow: and in Westminster Abbey he told me, he thought the Duke had spoke to him; but on turning about he said, he did not; and he turn'd and went away.</p>
               <p>Q. Where had you this conversation?</p>
               <p>Merrick. This was in a room in the coffee-house by ourselves.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you this voluntarily?</p>
               <p>Merrick. He did. At first he seem'd surprized, and then said, he recollected these circumstances.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he express any signs of fear?</p>
               <p>Merrick. No; but he seemed much surprized.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580510-17-person234">
                  William 
                  Marsden 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person234" type="surname" value="Marsden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person234" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person234" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was appointed by his Grace the Duke and justice Fielding to watch the Duke in Westminster Abbey, and had two constables there in order to apprehend the person, if his Grace had thought proper to give the signal.</p>
               <p>Q. Were you all together?</p>
               <p>Marsden. No, but so dispersed that our intention might not be known; I was within the choir hearing the prayers for some time; there was a gentleman near the Duke with a sword, whom I thought the person at first, but I learned afterwards, he was an acquaintance of his Grace's; I was not apprized that any such person would attend him: I saw Mr. Barnard and another person come in, and his eye was fix'd on his Grace as he walk'd in the isle; they walk'd down the middle isle, not directly to his Grace; in a little time I observed his Grace to meet them, and as I thought by the behaviour of Mr. Barnard, that he spoke first to the Duke presently after that Mr. Barnard's partner went off from him; then Mr. Barnard went and stood looking at the Duke; then I thought Mr. Barnard was the person; so I did not mind the other: I saw his Grace speak to him again, but was not near enough to hear what they said: after that, his Grace walk'd backwards and forwards once or twice, and went out at the door he came in at; the other gentleman immediately followed the Duke; I followed to see what pass'd; the gentleman, the Duke's acquaintance, walk'd opposite to the Duke, Mr. Barnard was got looking behind a post, any body that was on that side he was on could see him; but a person on that side his Grace was on could not, I believe it was impossible for his Grace to see him at that time, he look'd after his Grace a considerable time, then walk'd back: I followed his Grace and told him what observations I had made; his Grace immediately told me, the man in black was the man that he had seen in Hyde-Park: then I said, I wonder your Grace did not give the signal to have him apprehended; his Grace said the same as repeated here, He would rather let it be a little longer, than to take up an innocent man; he should hear of him again he apprehended, for he seem'd to be afraid to speak to him at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he apprehended after this?</p>
               <p>Marsden. He was. I procured him to come before justice Fielding, by a sham summons, in which he was accused with assault and battery: he was not taken up till he came there, then he seemed surpriz'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you about any thing that happen'd in Westminster Abbey?</p>
               <p>Marsden. I was with him in the dining room at Mr. Fielding's, in order to take his examination; I went as it were out of complaisance to him not to leave him alone, he talk'd a good deal, but I did not make such observations of it as I should have done if I had thought of his coming here: I remember he said he order'd his friend to walk off, that he might see what the Duke wanted with him, and said he thought the Duke must come there by appointment: he mentioned something about the Duke's giving him a place or post; I think he said he ordered his friend to walk off, to see if the Duke would give him some place; or, perhaps, the Duke wants to give me a place.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure he said the Duke wanted to give him a place? or, that his friend said, Go towards him, perhaps the Duke wants to give you some place?</p>
               <p>Marsden. I cannot be sure which; I know the word place was mentioned.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is the summons ?</p>
               <p>Marsden. This is the summons, ( producing one;) I did not serve it on the day it bears date; it was made out on Saturday the 29th of April. I was to have given him it that afternoon, but I was told he was gone to Brentford; so I went early on Monday<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175805100026"></xptr> morning following, and gave it him: this was only made out as a decoy; the name in it is one of the constables that was fix'd in Westminster Abbey, named 
               <persName id="t17580510-17-person235">
                  Roger 
                  Bowsher 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person235" type="surname" value="Bowsher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person235" type="given" value="Roger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Did he shew any unwillingness to come?</p>
               <p>Marsden. No, none at all; he look'd at it and said, it is a summons from Mr. Fielding; he read it over and said, Roger Bowsher! I know nothing of him; give my compliments, tell him I'll wait on him.</p>
               <p>Q. As to this place that he look'd thro', which door is it at?</p>
               <p>Marsden. It is the west gate near the Gate-house, just at the corner there is another gate, and next to the wall is a sort of a post, which is what he look'd through, or by.</p>
               <p>Q. Is not that gate, as you call it, a close wainscoted door?</p>
               <p>Marsden. It is a door, but the place where I mean is a post; he peep'd between the post and the wall. I have never been since to look at it; if there is not a hole between that and the wall, he must look by the other side of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Which way was his head?</p>
               <p>Marsden. That was towards the gentleman who was close to the wall, opposite him; he must have turned his head farther from the wall to have seen his Grace, as his Grace was going to take coach.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I am intirely innocent of this affair with which I am charged. I leave it to the court and the jury, with the evidence that will be produced.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580510-17-person236">
                  John 
                  Barnard 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person236" type="surname" value="Barnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person236" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am father to the prisoner at the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his employ?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580510-17-person237">
                  John 
                  Barnard 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person237" type="surname" value="Barnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person237" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person237" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He is employ'd in my business as a builder and surveyor principally; in not only that, and drawing plans, but also in receiving great sums of money.</p>
               <p>Q. Have his accounts always stood right and clear ?</p>
               <p>John Barnard. They always have.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you look upon him to be a sober man ?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580510-17-person238">
                  John 
                  Barnard 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person238" type="surname" value="Barnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person238" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have had great reason to believe him such, more particularly lately.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he been possess'd of large sums of money ?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580510-17-person239">
                  John 
                  Barnard 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person239" type="surname" value="Barnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person239" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He has, of considerable sums; I have oftener asked him for money than he me.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any occasion to send him to Kensington on Sunday the 4th of December.</p>
               <p>J. Barnard. I had nothing, but circumstance; brought the day to my mind since: I gave him an order on that Sunday morning, when we were at breakfast, to go to Kensington, to know whether there was some money paid by the treasurer of the turnpikes for gravel: I have a brother there, named Joseph; he went there and did his business, and dined with my brother.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that ?</p>
               <p>J. Barnard. Because he told me so; and the solicitor of the turnpike told me he had been with him, and in consequence of which I had my money afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever heard your son take any notice of his meeting with the Duke of Marlborough that day?</p>
               <p>J. Barnard. When he came home he told me, he had met the Duke of Marlborough, and these circumstances of his Grace's taking notice of him; he mentioned it as an extraordinary thing. I ask'd him, if he had not look'd a little impudently (as he has a near sight) at him, or pull'd his glass out? He said, he saw another gentleman at a distance, and the Duke was arm'd; and he imagin'd there might be a duel going forwards; he has from that time to this mentioned it as a very strange event, several times in my house, without any reserve at all.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. At the time you sent your son to Kensington on the 4th of December, suppose you had not given him an order to go there, whether he was not at liberty to go where he pleased?</p>
               <p>J. Barnard. Yes; I never restrain him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he was surpriz'd to see the Duke without a great coat?</p>
               <p>J. Barnard. I can't remember that particular.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear him mention his seeing the Duke of Marlborough in Westminster Abbey?</p>
               <p>J. Barnard. I have very often, and very publickly, and with some surprize, as he has that in Hyde-Park. I said to him, I would not have you be public in speaking of things of this kind, left an use be made of it to your disadvantage.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580510-17-person240">
                  Thomas 
                  Barnard 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person240" type="surname" value="Barnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person240" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am first cousin to the prisoner at the bar. On Saturday the 3d of December, I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175805100027"></xptr> was at Kensington, and lay at my uncle's house there, and dined there. On the Sunday the prisoner came there before dinner, he said he had been to do some business that way. He dined with us, there were my uncle, aunt, he, and I; he related that circumstance to us of meeting with the Duke of Marlborough in Hyde-Park; he said he rode up to him, and asked if he knew who he was; he answered no; he replied I am the Duke of Marlborough; he related it with some chearfulness, tho' as matter of surprize.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known the prisoner?</p>
               <p>T. Barnard. From his birth: he is in business with his father; I always understood he would succeed his father; I never knew him to behave any otherwise than well in my life. I never thought him extravagant, nor never heard so; I had always looked upon him to be an honest man; his father is in very great business.</p>
               <p>Q. Should you look upon it, that a small place would be equal to the chance of succeeding his father in his business?</p>
               <p>T. Barnard. I should never have thought of such a thing; I look upon his situation in life to be a very extraordinary thing: I thought he would give the preference to that above any thing else.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think he would refuse a good place?</p>
               <p>T. Barnard. No man would refuse a place that is to his advantage?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580510-17-person241">
                  Joseph 
                  Barnard 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person241" type="surname" value="Barnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person241" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am uncle to the prisoner at the bar; I live at Kensington; my nephew, 
               <persName id="t17580510-17-person242">
                  Thomas 
                  Barnard 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person242" type="surname" value="Barnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person242" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , lay at my house on the Saturday night, and dined with the prisoner at the bar on the Sunday. I remember he then mentioned having met with the Duke of Marlborough in Hyde-Park, while we were sitting at dinner. I said I was surprized he should meet with him that day; he said he saw but one gentleman at a distance, and the Duke was armed; and his Grace looked him full in the face, very earnestly, (which he seemed to speak with a great deal of pleasure to me) he is very near sighted, he can see nothing at a distance without the use of a glass. I have heard him since speak four or five times of seeing the Duke in Westminster-Abbey.</p>
               <p>Q. How long ago?</p>
               <p>Jos. Barnard. About a month ago. He is brought up under his father in very considerable business, and a man of some property besides, and was employed as his clerk or book keeper?</p>
               <p>Q. Is he a sober man?</p>
               <p>Jos. Barnard. Very sober; I never heard to the contrary; neither did I ever hear his father speak of him as idle or dilatory.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580510-17-person243">
                  Thomas 
                  Calcut 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person243" type="surname" value="Calcut"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person243" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person243" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Kensington: I remember the prisoner coming there on a Sunday morning; a very cold foggy morning; with some message from his father to me, to know whether the solicitor had paid some money or not. He was under his father, as I am under mine; he desired me to go with him; I said stay and dine with me; he said he could not promise, because he had promised to dine with his uncle Joseph: he went into the parlour, and said it is vastly cold. There has been the oddest accident happened as I came over the Park; the Duke of Marlborough came up to me, and asked me if I knew him, I said no; he asked me if I wanted any thing with him, I told him no; he said I am the Duke of Marlborough, if you want any thing with me; then the Duke went away, and he came there. He expressed a great surprize at it, and I thought it a very odd affair.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580510-17-person244">
                  Henry 
                  Clive 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person244" type="surname" value="Clive"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person244" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person244" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; I have known the prisoner two years; I remember dining with him on the 8th of December, at his father's house, with a great deal of company; I heard him then say at dinner, that some few days before, he had met the Duke of Marlborough in Hyde-Park; that the Duke asked him if he had any business with him, he said no; he then told him who he was, and asked him the same again, he said no; that the Duke seemed in some confusion and was armed; and he thought he was about a duel; and indeed I thought it was a very great lie. I have gone very frequently to his father's in relation to Brentford bridge. I have no other acquaintance with him, only going to his father's, so can't say any thing to his character either frugal or extravagant.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you name any body that dined there that day?</p>
               <p>Mr. Clive. Yes, there was Mr. Wilson and his lady, Mr. Tunstall and his lady, another gentleman and his wife, and the prisoner's younger brother that is at Westminster school.</p>
               <p>Mrs. 
               <persName id="t17580510-17-person245">
                  Mary 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person245" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person245" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person245" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I dined at Mr. Barnard's on Thursday the 8th of December; the prisoner, I remember, said he had been in Hyde-Park some days before, and there he saw a gentleman on<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175805100028"></xptr> horse-back come up to him, and asked him if he had any thing to say to him, he said no; then he said I am the Duke of Marlborough, now you know me, have you any thing to say to me? he said no. He talked of this very freely to all.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580510-17-person246">
                  James 
                  Greenwood 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person246" type="surname" value="Greenwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person246" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Deptford, with a relation in the brewing way; I came from Deptford on Saturday to the prisoner's father's; and on the Sunday following I was there at breakfast; I solicited the prisoner to get himself dressed to go with me into the Park, being to meet a person at twelve o'clock; I with a good deal of difficulty got him to dress himself; I put my shirt on in the parlour, and after that he put on his; I fancy we breakfasted about 9 o'clock; when we got to the end of Henry the VIIth's chapel, the prisoner would have gone the other way into the Park without going thro' the Abbey, I took hold of his sleeve, and said, Barnard, you shall go thro' the Abbey; this was a little after eleven; this was no unusual thing; we have several times walked in the Park, and some times parted.</p>
               <p>Q. Which is the nearest way to the Park?</p>
               <p>Greenwood. I do not know which is the nearest way, thro' the Abbey, or by the side of it, this was the first time I believe that I ever saw the monument of general Hargrave; after that we walked down to the monument, erected at the public expence for captain Cornwall; the preacher was in the pulpit; when we were standing at capt. Cornwall's monument, the prisoner made some observations on the execution of it in his own way. After we had staid there some time, I saw his Grace the Duke of Marlborough, who was got pretty near us: upon seeing the Duke I jogged him by the elbow, and said, step this way, he seemed to look at him.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you heard what happened in Hyde-Park, previous to this?</p>
               <p>Greenwood. I had; I believe it was told to me by the prisoner at the bar; on my jogging him we walked up the middle isle towards the choir, I said did you see that gentleman in the blue coat, or do you know him ? no said he, not I; no, said I, it is the Duke of Marlborough! we will walk to the monument again; the Duke came, and placed himself pretty near me a second time, after this we walked away. I believe we walked some considerable time in that isle, in which is the monument of sir 
               <persName id="t17580510-17-person247">
                  Godfrey 
                  Kneller 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person247" type="surname" value="Kneller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person247" type="given" value="Godfrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , there I believe we pass'd and repass'd again.</p>

               <p>Q. Why did you jog him ?</p>
               <p>Greenwood. Because he is very near sighted. At last I think it so happened, we pass'd the Duke between two of the pillars; and as I had hold of his arm walking together, there was barely room for three people to pass a breast; the Duke rather gave way, and made as I thought a kind of a bow. Upon this I said the Duke of Marlborough's behaviour is extremely particular; he certainly has something to say to you; I suppose he does not chuse to say it while I am with you, I will go into the choir, and do you walk up and down here, and possibly he will speak to you. While I was there I looked; the first thing I saw was the Duke of Marlborough and the prisoner at the bar with their heads bowing together, as if it was the first salutation.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the prisoner the least inclination to go into the Abbey before you proposed it to him ?</p>
               <p>Greenwood. No; he did not discover any ?</p>
               <p>Q. Did he discover any inclination to be left alone, when you proposed to go into the choir ?</p>
               <p>Greenwood. No, he did not in the least; in some few minutes after, the prisoner and I met together, he told me the Duke of Marlborough was gone out of the Abbey, he had seen him go out; I said what pass'd, to which he replied the Duke said did you speak to me, or who spoke first I can't tell.</p>
               <p>Q. In this transaction did the prisoner appear openly, or as if he had some secret transaction to do with the Duke?</p>
               <p>Greenwood. No, it was open and clear.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the Duke come in?</p>
               <p>Greenwood. No, I did not; we were employed at looking at the monuments; we looked at several.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do when you first came in?</p>
               <p>Greenwood. We walked along and looked on the monuments.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the prisoner's eye fixed on any person ?</p>
               <p>Greenwood. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Is Mr. Barnard very near sighted ?</p>
               <p>Greenwood. He is; I question whether he can be able to see a person across this room.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you go, when you went out of the Abbey?</p>
               <p>Greenwood. We went immediately, into the Park, and after walking there, we met with two Ladies whom I knew and to whom Mr. Barnard was not unknown, to whom we related this affair; he always repeated these things, that is, this<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175805100029"></xptr> and that in Hyde-Park, as matter of great curiosity.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you been acquainted with him?</p>
               <p>Greenwood. I have been acquainted with him seven years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character?</p>
               <p>Greenwood. I know nothing to the contrary but that he is an industrious sober young man.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear that he was a profligate expensive man?</p>
               <p>Greenwood. No; never.</p>
               <p>Q. His father is in great business: is he not?</p>
               <p>Greenwood. His father's business is a very considerable thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580510-17-person248">
                  William 
                  Ball 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person248" type="surname" value="Ball"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person248" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the master of Story's Gate coffee-house. I remember Mr. Merrick coming to my house, to inquire for Mr. Barnard; he ask'd me, if Mr. Barnard was at my house? I said, Leave any message, I'll deliver it to him; he said, he wanted to see him that evening; he left his message, I delivered it to him, and he came rather before 8 o'clock to him. He has used my house some years, always a well-behaved man; I never perceived any extravagancy in him, always a sober regular man. I have heard him speak of having met the Duke of Marlborough, but not till after this; he said he had been to his Grace at his Grace's house; this was as he called at my house, after he had been there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he mention what had passed?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580510-17-person249">
                  William 
                  Ball 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person249" type="surname" value="Ball"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person249" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . No, he did not, only that he had seen his Grace.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he not tell you any thing that pass'd?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580510-17-person250">
                  William 
                  Ball 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person250" type="surname" value="Ball"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person250" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He did not tell me a syllable of it.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you say to him?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580510-17-person251">
                  William 
                  Ball 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person251" type="surname" value="Ball"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person251" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I told him, may be he was going to have a commission; he said, he would not thank his Grace, except it was a very good one.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he appear as to chearfulness, or dullness, or the like?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580510-17-person252">
                  William 
                  Ball 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person252" type="surname" value="Ball"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person252" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He seem'd to be very chearful, not in the least concern'd, the same as usual, compos'd, rather more chearful.</p>
               <p>Counsel. We will now shew his behaviour after he was apprehended.</p>
               <p>Mr. Ford. While he was in custody, Mr. Fielding did me the honour of sending for me, he told me it was upon some business which concerned the Duke of Marlborough's life; he asked me to go along with him and Mr. Box to New Prison, which I consented to; we went together in a coach; this was about 12 at night, and Mr. Barnard was then in bed; I have really forgot what day it was: Mr. Fielding told him, he had omitted examining his pockets at the time he was before him; he then search'd his pockets, in order to see whether he had any letters or any writings that might give light into the affair; he very readily let me look into his pocket-book and papers. Mr. Fielding with great candour told him, he was in the hands of a very honourable prosecutor, and one that would be as glad to discover his innocence as his guilt. Mr. Fielding asked him for his keys, and he gave him the keys of his escrutore and compting-house with great readiness; and I remember that I then told him, that, if he was guilty, some copies might be found to correspond with the original letters; and if nothing of that sort did appear, it would be a circumstance in his favour.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you or Mr. Fielding tell him he was not oblig'd to part with his keys, and did he do it as matter of choice?</p>
               <p>Mr. Ford. I don't recollect that; I know he parted with them very readily.</p>
               <p>The Revd. Dr. Markham. I have known the prisoner some years; I have always considered him as a young man of remarkable sobriety and attention to business: I have had some experience of him; I intrusted him with the execution of some matters of importance relating to myself, in regard to surveying and valuing estates, in which he acquitted himself ably and honestly; that is the character he always had: he lives in my neighbourhood, his father is a man of considerable property, and carries on a large business.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Then you don't suppose the prisoner to be in distressed circumstances?</p>
               <p>Dr. Markham. I never supposed it, I have no reason to imagine it; if he had come to me, wanting money, he might easily have imposed on me; he is one of the persons I chiefly trusted, and I don't know a man on whom I would have had a greater reliance: I thought him remarkably able in his business, and very likely to be a considerable man; and I never was more astonished in my life than when I heard this strange story.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580510-17-person253">
                  Samuel 
                  Cox 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person253" type="surname" value="Cox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person253" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; I have known Mr. Barnard about the space of three years last past. The beginning of my acquaintance was on the account of his surveying of houses in the New Square Dean's<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175805100030"></xptr> yard; the surveys were generally made by him; he did his business with such accuracy, that I have always thought him a man very attentive to his business, and very unlikely to be charged with this fact; and upon his being employ'd upon publick schemes, I employ'd him in my own affairs; I employ'd his father to finish some houses for me at Hammersmith, the son was constantly employ'd till the 6th of April last; I have at different times paid to Mr. Barnard about 700 pounds, all, except 50 or 79 pounds, paid into the hands of the prisoner. He has appear'd as the person that manag'd his father's business; If he had come to me, and mentioned any want of money, upon his father's being out of town, or the like, he might have had 2 or 300 l. at any time. When I first was acquainted with him, I observed he had a remarkable short sight; when he has look'd full at me, I have thought he snear'd at me; he has such a fall with his eye-lids on the account of his short-sightedness; I have found his eye so fix'd upon me, that I have been going to speak to him, which, by a long acquaintance with him, I since found was only an accident.</p>
               <p>Robert Vansitturt, Esq; I have known Mr. Barnard about 5 or 6 years; my acquaintance with him was by being acquainted with his father, who was employ'd in carrying on a large building for Mr. Lee an acquaintance of mine in Oxfordshire, and this five years I have been acquainted with the son, and frequently in company with him. In the beginning of April he was in my chamber, putting up some book-cases; I remember one morning at breakfast he told me the circumstance of meeting the Duke of Marlborough in Hyde-Park and in Westminster Abbey, in the same way as the court has been told from his Grace and the rest of the witnesses: it appear'd to me to be a very strange story, and he seem'd to tell it as such, as I or any body else would have told it; I suspended my judgment upon it, and never related it to any body, only to my father and another gentleman, and they look'd upon it as a great lie that Barnard had invented; I knowing his character did not take it as such, but thought he must have known it to be as he said.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your opinion of him as to his business?</p>
               <p>Vansittart. From my own personal acquaintance with him, and from the many surveys, I have seen of his, he certainly is very capable and master of his business. I never heard any thing ill as to his private character.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see him write?</p>
               <p>Vansittart. No, he draws very well, I have seen him draw.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580510-17-person254">
                  John 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person254" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person254" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person254" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; I have known him eight or ten years, and his father's family twenty-five. He always appeared an industrious, sober, diligent man; particularly within this four or five years, since he has come into business with his father. I considered him as a very promising genius, in his way, and one capable of conducting his business with reputation and character.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you look upon him likely to be driven to distress, or in want of a place?</p>
               <p>Smith. No, I did not. I can with great truth say, most of the payments in my compting-house, on his father's account, have most of them been paid by the hands of this young man; except the last five hundred pounds: then Mr. Barnard and his wife came over and dined with me and paid it; and then I blamed him for not bringing his son.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Smith. I am a timber merchant.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580510-17-person255">
                  Joshua 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person255" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person255" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person255" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am in partnership with my father, the last evidence. I have known the prisoner several years; I always thought him a very honest, sober man, capable in his profession: the money that has been paid to us lately, except that five hundred pounds has been by him; they never paid less than a hundred pounds at a time except once.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any reason to imagine him in desperate circumstances?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580510-17-person256">
                  Joshua 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person256" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person256" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person256" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . There is no reason as I know of to imagine so.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580510-17-person257">
                  Robert 
                  Tunstall 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person257" type="surname" value="Tunstall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person257" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person257" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; I have known him two years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Tunstall. He is industrious and very capable of his business. His behaviour has been prudent; he is the principal man in his father's business in drawing and scheming.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580510-17-person258">
                  Peter 
                  Brushel 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person258" type="surname" value="Brushel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person258" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person258" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him from a child.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character?</p>
               <p>Brushel. I always took him to be a very sober, honest man. His father has done a great deal of business for me, and is now at work for me.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you generally pay the money to?</p>
               <p>Brushel. I generally paid the father; if the prisoner had apply'd to me, I would have let him have a hundred pounds at any time.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he capable of his business?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175805100031"></xptr>Brushel. He is very capable. He drew a plan for me last Saturday was se'nnight.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you look upon him to be in desperate or distress'd circumstances?</p>
               <p>Brushel. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he been always a visible man?</p>
               <p>Brushel. Always.</p>
               <p>Mr. Jelse. I am the King's mason. I have known the prisoner seven years and more.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you look upon him to be capable of his business.</p>
               <p>Jelse. I believe he is a very capable man in his business.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Jelse. Always a very worthy, honest man.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see him guilty of any extravagancy?</p>
               <p>Jelse. No, never.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you live near him?</p>
               <p>Jelse. I am a very near neighbour to him, and keep him company on evenings, within this year or two more particular.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580510-17-person259">
                  William 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person259" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person259" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person259" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; I have known him about six or seven years.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he a person capable of his profession ?</p>
               <p>Robinson. I believe he is.</p>
               <p>Q. What has been his behaviour?</p>
               <p>Robinson. I always look'd upon him to be a very sober, diligent, frugal man.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you look upon him to be in desperate circumstances?</p>
               <p>Robinson. No, not at all.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580510-17-person260">
                  Thomas 
                  Kynaston 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person260" type="surname" value="Kynaston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person260" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person260" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; I have known him six or seven years.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Kynaston. I belong to the board of works.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your opinion of the prisoner's situation?</p>
               <p>Kynaston. I think he is in a good one.</p>
               <p>Q. What has been his behaviour?</p>
               <p>Kynaston. That has been always good.</p>
               <p>Keynton Cowse. I have known him seven years, and been in his company many times.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character?</p>
               <p>Cowse. He is a very worthy young man, sober and industrious, always attending his father's business?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580510-17-person261">
                  George 
                  Ufford 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person261" type="surname" value="Ufford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person261" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person261" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about six or seven years; he is a sober, sedate, young man as ever I met with. I have done business for him several times.</p>
               <p>Mr. Brent. I have known him upwards of three years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character?</p>
               <p>Brent. He has a good character, he is a very industrious man; I have frequently paid him money.</p>
               <p>Mr. Jones. I have known him several years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Jones. He is a very honest; no ways extravagant, that could lead him into a desperate state; he is as moral a man as any I know, and has as good a character.</p>
               <p>Mr. Wilson. I have known him about seven years.</p>
               <p>Q. What has been his behaviour during that time?</p>
               <p>Wilson. It has been always very well. I always look'd upon him as an honest man.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever look upon him to be in a desperate way in his fortune?</p>
               <p>Wilson. No, never.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Barnard the elder. Where was you when your son was sent for to the Duke of Marlborough's?</p>
               <p>Mr. Barnard. I was then out of town. I have not been in town above one week this five or six weeks.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17580510-17-verdict90" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-verdict90" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He stood a second time indicted by the same name of 
               <persName id="t17580510-17-person262">
                  William 
                  Barnard 
               <interp inst="t17580510-17-person262" type="surname" value="Barnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person262" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-person262" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , for <rs id="t17580510-17-off91" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-off91" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-off91" type="offenceSubcategory" value="extortion"></interp>
               feloniously sending another letterto the most noble 
                     <persName id="t17580510-17-victim263" type="victimName">
                        Charles 
                        <rs id="t17580510-17-viclabel92" type="occupation">Duke of Marlborough</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580510-17-victim229 t17580510-17-viclabel92"></join>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580510-17-victim263 t17580510-17-viclabel92"></join>
                        <interp inst="t17580510-17-victim263" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580510-17-victim263" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580510-17-off87 t17580510-17-victim263"></join>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580510-17-off91 t17580510-17-victim263"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , sign'd F. demanding two or three hundred pounds
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>No evidence appearing against him, he was <rs id="t17580510-17-verdict93" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-verdict93" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580510-17-verdict93" type="verdictSubcategory" value="noEvidence"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
