<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570713-46">
               <interp inst="t17570713-46" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570713-46" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570713-46" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570713"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570713-46" type="date" value="17570713"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570713-46-off227-c373" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570713-46-defend451 t17570713-46-off227 t17570713-46-verdict229"></join>
         
               <p>296. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17570713-46-defend451" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Taylor 
                  <interp inst="t17570713-46-defend451" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-46-defend451" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-46-defend451" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17570713-46-deflabel226" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570713-46-defend451 t17570713-46-deflabel226"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17570713-46-off227" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570713-46-off227" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-46-off227" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pettyLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one child's linen frock, value 4 d. two linen handkerchiefs, value 5 d. one lawn cap, one flannel petticoat, and one pair of child's shoes
            </rs>, the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17570713-46-victim453" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Southal 
                  <interp inst="t17570713-46-victim453" type="surname" value="Southal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-46-victim453" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-46-victim453" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570713-46-off227 t17570713-46-victim453"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17570713-46-cd228" type="crimeDate">May 28</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570713-46-off227 t17570713-46-cd228"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570713-46-person454">
                  John 
                  Southal 
               <interp inst="t17570713-46-person454" type="surname" value="Southal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-46-person454" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-46-person454" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a poor working man, and my wife works with me at the same business as I do. The prisoner work'd for me for 3 s. and 6 d. per week. On the 8th of May, at night, I missed the things mention'd in the indictment (mentioning them by name.) I followed her to her father's house, and call'd in another voice. She ask'd at the window who was there. I said, 
               <persName id="t17570713-46-person455">
                  John 
                  Southal 
               <interp inst="t17570713-46-person455" type="surname" value="Southal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-46-person455" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-46-person455" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Her father said she had not been there. Then I got into the house, and on my calling the watchman and constable she appear'd, surrender'd herself, and acknowledged taking the things, but would not tell us where they were. She was taken to Clerkenwell-Bridewell, and the next day before justice Chamber-lane at Islington, where she confessed every thing, and how she took the things from me; the things were found and brought to the justice's house.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were they found?</p>
               <p>Southal. I can't tell that, her mother brought them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570713-46-person456">
                  William 
                  Riley 
               <interp inst="t17570713-46-person456" type="surname" value="Riley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-46-person456" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-46-person456" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , The constable going out, he desired me to go and take the prisoner from Bridewell to the justice's. I went and did accordingly. ( goods produced.) Her mother brought these things to the justice's. I heard the prisoner acknowledge she took them from the prosecutor's house.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175707130040"></xptr>Prosecutor. These things produced here are my property.</p>
               <p>Q. to Riley. What did the prosecutor charge her with?</p>
               <p>Riley. With taking the things from out of his house.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I liv'd servant with the prosecutor, to take care of three children, himself and his wife. After I had been there a week or a fortnight, I had one night forgot to wash that frock. I lay at my father's house, and took the frock with me to wash along with some things of mine, as I had used to do. He came and ask'd me for the things, I told him I had them; he said he would not have them, so I sent them to his house; he sent them back again, and said he would not make it up without being paid for his time. I ask'd him how much he expected, he said 12 s. and 6 d.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Did you want to make it up?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I said I would not make it up without being paid for my time.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570713-46-verdict229" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570713-46-verdict229" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
