<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570420-42">
               <interp inst="t17570420-42" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570420-42" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570420-42" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570420"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570420-42" type="date" value="17570420"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570420-42-off216-c364" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-42-defend440 t17570420-42-off216 t17570420-42-verdict219"></join>
         

               <p>187. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17570420-42-defend440" type="defendantName">
                  Daniel 
                  Lackey 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-defend440" type="surname" value="Lackey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-defend440" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-defend440" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17570420-42-deflabel215" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-42-defend440 t17570420-42-deflabel215"></join>; was <rs id="t17570420-42-off216" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-off216" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-off216" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               indicted for feloniously committing a rape upon the body of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17570420-42-victim442" type="victimName">
                           Christian 
                           Streeter 
                        <interp inst="t17570420-42-victim442" type="surname" value="Streeter"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570420-42-victim442" type="given" value="Christian"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570420-42-victim442" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-42-off216 t17570420-42-victim442"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , spinster, on the <rs id="t17570420-42-cd217" type="crimeDate">2d of October</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-42-off216 t17570420-42-cd217"></join> last, against the statute
            </rs>.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-42-person443">
                  Christian 
                  Streeter 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person443" type="surname" value="Streeter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person443" type="given" value="Christian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person443" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 2d of October last, as I was walking alone in St. James's Park, the prisoner came up to me and ask'd me my name, and where I liv'd. I told him I liv'd in Berkley-street. He said, I was a country girl, and ask'd me if I had dined, and I said I had.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you tell him who you liv'd with?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No, I did not. He said if I would go along with him, his man should see me safe home, for as I was a country girl it would be very dangerous for me to walk alone, and therefore I went with him, and he had me to the sign of the Hercules over Westminster-bridge.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you walk it?</p>

               <p>Streeter. We did.</p>

               <p>Q. Where is Berkley-Street, where you said you liv'd?</p>

               <p>Streeter. It is very near Piccadilly.</p>

               <p>Q. What past as you went to the Hercules ?</p>

               <p>Streeter. He talk'd to me how dangerous it was for me to walk alone, and how happy it was that I had fallen into such good hands; and when we came to the Hercules, he had a fry'd rabbit for dinner.</p>

               <p>Q. What time of the day was this?</p>

               <p>Streeter. Between three and four o'clock. I did not know but that was his home.</p>

               <p>Q. What past after you got there?</p>

               <p>Streeter. He was inquiring where I came from in the country, and where my friends were, and who I was with in town, and where; and he ask'd the drawer if his man was come from Greenwich, and finding he was not, he said he imagined he was gone home; and nothing else past till we went to his lodgings.</p>

               <p>Council. Then he did not pretend that the Hercules was his lodgings?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No. He took a coach between the Hercules and the bridge.</p>

               <p>Q. Where did he carry you to?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I went with him to <placeName id="t17570420-42-crimeloc218">Rider-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17570420-42-crimeloc218" type="placeName" value="Rider-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17570420-42-crimeloc218" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-42-off216 t17570420-42-crimeloc218"></join>, to his lodgings.</p>

               <p>Q. How do you know that was his lodgings?</p>

               <p>Streeter. He said so. When we came there he got out of the hackney coach and bid me sit till he went and knock'd at the door. He ask'd at the door whether his man was come home, and some body said no; then he bid me get out.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you go willingly with him into his lodgings?</p>

               <p>Streeter. Yes, I did. He said he would send his man home with me, and said it was a dangerous thing for me to be alone. He had me up one pair of stairs into a dining-room, and the maid came up with two candles, which she lighted and then went down.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you express any uneasiness that you wanted to be at home?</p>

               <p>Streeter. Yes; but he desired I'd make myself easy, for I was safe, and the minute the man came home he should go home with me.</p>

               <p>Q. What time did he come home?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I believe he came home about an hour after. He brought a letter and gave it to his master, and went out of the room directly; after that I desired him to let the man go home with me, and then he said by G - d I should not go.</p>

               <p>Q. What past after that?</p>

               <p>Streeter. He strip'd off all my cloaths, and I screamed and cried, so that any body might have heard me in the street.</p>

               <p>Q. Was you sitting or standing, when he began to pull your cloaths off?</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200043"></xptr>Streeter. He took hold of my legs and pulled my shoes off, and set his knees against me so that I not power to get out of the chair; then he pulled all my cloaths off.</p>

               <p>Q. What pass'd after that?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I fainted away while he was undressing me, and he took me up in his arms and put me into bed.</p>

               <p>Q. Were all your cloaths off then?</p>

               <p>Streeter. Yes they were.</p>

               <p>Q. What past after that?</p>

               <p>Streeter. He brought something for me to smell to, for I was not able to speak. I did not know he had carried me to bed, but when I came to myself I found myself there, and he was standing by the bed-side, holding something for me to smell to.</p>

               <p>Q. What past after this?</p>

               <p>Streeter. He undress'd himself and got into bed.</p>

               <p>Q. What happened after that?</p>

               <p>Streeter. He had carnal knowledge of my body against my will and consent.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you make any resistance on this occasion?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I did, and scream'd out till I was quite gone.</p>

               <p>Q. Did any body come to your assistance?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No, no-body.</p>

               <p>Q. What past after this?</p>

               <p>Streeter. After he had used me thus he rung the bell, and his man came; and he ordered the man to bring him something to drink, and to take care of my cloathes. I made a mourning noise but was not able to speak.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you attempt to get away from him then?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I was not able.</p>

               <p>Q. How long did you continue with him?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I continued with him all night.</p>

               <p>Q. Did he make any more attempts in the night?</p>

               <p>Streeter. Yes, several times, but I prevented his having carnal knowledge of my body after that.</p>

               <p>Q. What was it he did to you at the time you say he had carnal knowledge of your body. You must tell particulars.</p>

               <p>Streeter. He hurt me very much. I found what he had in my body.</p>

               <p>Q. What was that?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No answer.</p>

               <p>Council. Then I'll ask you, Was it his private parts?</p>

               <p>Streeter. It was.</p>

               <p>Q. Did any thing come from him?</p>

               <p>Streeter. Yes.</p>

               <p>Q. Was you wet ?</p>

               <p>Streeter. Yes.</p>

               <p>Q. What past in the morning ?</p>

               <p>Streeter. In the morning he got up and left me in bed. I put what cloaths I had on, and went into the dining-room, and he brought me there my cloaths, by a piece at a time, and I put them on in the dining-room. After I had all my cloaths on he ordered his man to cut my hair.</p>

               <p>Q. And did he?</p>

               <p>Streeter. Yes.</p>

               <p>Q. Was that by way of dressing it?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I don't know, he bid the man cut it off and put it by.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you object to it?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No, I was afraid of being murdered every minute, from the usage I met with from him the night before.</p>

               <p>Q. Was it merely from the usage you met with, or was it from any thing else?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you observe any arms?</p>

               <p>Streeter. There was a sword hung by the bedside.</p>

               <p>Q. Was there any thing else?</p>

               <p>Streeter. There was a blunderbus by the closet-door. I sat down to breakfast with the prisoner, and drank two dishes of tea. I cry'd, and he ask'd me what I cry'd for, and put his hand into his pocket, and took out and gave me a guinea, which I laid down on the table and told him I did not want money, and I refused to take it three times; on which he told me, if I did not take it, I should not go home, and for that reason I took it; after that he let me go, and gave me directions to write to him by the name of Douglas, at the Cocoa-tree, Piccadilly.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you take that direction?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I did, but I did not say I would write to him.</p>

               <p>Q. Did he send his man with you home?</p>

               <p>Streeter. He did. He went before me, and when I came to the house I rap'd at the door.</p>

               <p>Q. Who was in the house in Berkley-street, when you lodged there?</p>

               <p>Streeter. 'Squire Ladd, he was not in town then, I saw Mrs. Fletcher as soon as I came in.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you acquaint her with what past?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No, because there were a great many people there, men and women. But I acquainted a Person with it that brought me to town, her name is Box; she was housekeeper to Mr. Ladd.</p>

               <p>Q. How soon after you came in did you acquaint her with it?</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200044"></xptr>Streeter. In about half an hour or an hour.</p>

               <p>Q. What past upon that?</p>

               <p>Streeter. She took no notice of it.</p>

               <p>Q. Was any body else present?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you acquaint any body else?</p>

               <p>Streeter. About four o'clock on the same day, I told Mrs. Hatchet, who keeps the Albemarle's Head in Piccadilly. Mrs. Box wanted to take me the next day to Greenwich, but I was not well enough to go.</p>

               <p>Q. What was that illness owing to?</p>

               <p>Streeter. To his usage. I went from Mr. Ladd's house.</p>

               <p>Q. What was your reason for going away?</p>

               <p>Streeter. Because the housekeeper left Mrs. Fletcher and me alone, and as the prisoner had said he would send his servant, I was afraid to stay in the house. I lay there on Sunday night, and went the next day, being Monday, to Mrs. Hatchet's.</p>

               <p>Q. When did you find out the person that had used you thus?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I found him out the next day.</p>

               <p>Q. Did he send you the direct way home from Rider-Street ?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No, he did not, but thro' the Green-Park.</p>

               <p>Q. What method did you take to find his lodging?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I went to the Hercules, and saw 
               <persName id="t17570420-42-person444">
                  James 
                  Speed 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person444" type="surname" value="Speed"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person444" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person444" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; ask'd him the name of the gentleman that I was with, he told me his name was Lackey, and lodged in Rider-street.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you go from thence to Rider-street ?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No, but I wrote to my father on the Tuesday. When he came up, we went to see this house in Rider-street.</p>

               <p>Q. Who went with you?</p>

               <p>Streeter. My father, Mr. Hutchinson, and Mrs. Hatchet.</p>

               <p>Q. What is Speed?</p>

               <p>Streeter. He is a waiter at a coffeehouse; when we came to the house we ask'd if such a gentleman lodged there, they said yes. We went up stairs to see if it was the same place, he was there and another gentleman; I said that was the gentleman ( meaning the prisoner.) We went away directly to Mr. Welch the Justice.</p>

               <p>Q. How many days was this after this ill usage?</p>

               <p>Streeter. That was on the Saturday, and I wrote to my father on the Tuesday. When I was before Mr. Welch, I acquainted him with what had happened, and he granted me a warrant.</p>

               <p>Q. Were there any endeavours made to apprehend him?</p>

               <p>Streeter. Yes there were, but he absconded.</p>

               <p>Q. At the time you came there with your father, did the prisoner appear to be under any concern when you came into the room?</p>

               <p>Streeter. He was very much surprised, and could hardly speak.</p>

               <p>Q. Was the prisoner sensible that he had used you in this way?</p>

               <p>Streeter. Yes.</p>

               <p>Q. How came he to ask you what you cry'd for?</p>

               <p>Streeter. That I don't know.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you expect his man would come to your lodgings?</p>

               <p>Streeter. He told me he would send his man by the door, and if the people used me ill there I should come away with him: I did not know but that he might send him, and it was upon that account that I chang'd my lodgings to Mrs. Hatchet's.</p>

               <p>Q . What advice did Mrs. Box give you when you acquainted her of it at first?</p>

               <p>Streeter. She took no notice of it; but bid me say nothing about it.</p>

               <p>Cross Examination.</p>

               <p>Q. What o'clock was it on the 2d of Oct. that you met him in the Park?</p>

               <p>Street. Between three and four in the afternoon.</p>

               <p>Q. Had you dined then?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I had.</p>

               <p>Q. Had you ever been in the Park before?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I had several times, but never alone till that day.</p>

               <p>Council. Then you knew your way from Berkley-street to the Park?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I did.</p>

               <p>Q. How came it that you did not know the way back again?</p>

               <p>Streeter. Because he took me farther about.</p>

               <p>Q. What part of the Park was it he met you in?</p>

               <p>Streeter. In the Bird-cage walk.</p>

               <p>Q. Had you ever been in that part of the Park before?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No, I had been in the Mall.</p>

               <p>Q. Did not you know the way cross the Park from the Bird-cage walk to the Mall?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No.</p>

               <p>Q. Had you any gloves on?</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200045"></xptr>Streeter. No, as we were going to the Hercules, he said I should look like a woman of the town to go without gloves; so he took me into a shop and bought me a pair. I offered to pay for them, but he would not let me.</p>

               <p>Q. Did he say any civil things to you in the Park?</p>

               <p>Street. He only told me what danger there was in walking alone, and what a very wicked place London was, and how happy to be in his hands, and asked me where I came from, and how long I had been in town.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you tell him you had a sweetheart, and was come to London in order to forget him?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I told him I had a sweetheart.</p>

               <p>Q. Did he offer to kiss you in the Park?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No, he did not.</p>

               <p>Q. Did not you tell him you came to town to cure yourself of love?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No.</p>

               <p>Q. Did he not talk of his liking you?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No, he did not.</p>

               <p>Q. At the Hercules, when you got there what past?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I sat by while he dined, I had dined before</p>

               <p>Q. How long might you have been there?</p>

               <p>Streeter. About an hour and a half.</p>

               <p>Q. Did he kiss you there?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No, nor offer to touch me.</p>

               <p>Q. Was you in any fear all this time ?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No, he gave me no room to be afraid.</p>

               <p>Q. What time was it when you came to his lodging?</p>

               <p>Streeter. It was candle-light then.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you think yourself safe then?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I did.</p>

               <p>Q. Was not the maid that brought up the candles alone with you in the room?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No, when we went up stairs the maid came just behind us.</p>

               <p>Q. Did not he quit the room?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No, he did not at all.</p>

               <p>Q. What time did the man bring the letter?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I believe it was after we had been there about an hour.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you scream in the dining-room before you got into the bed-chamber?</p>

               <p>Streeter. Yes, the moment he began to undress me.</p>

               <p>Q. Does the dining-room front the street?</p>

               <p>Streeter. It does.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you remember a circumstance of Mr. Lackey's going down stairs, as if to make people believe he was going to take leave of you, and in going down stairs saying my dear I wish you a good night, opening the door and shutting it again?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No, I remember no such thing.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you not know how you got into bed?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No.</p>

               <p>Q. What was the first thing you observed when in bed?</p>

               <p>Streeter. It was his holding something for me to smell to.</p>

               <p>Q. How long had you been in bed before you might recollect yourself and recover your senses?</p>



               <p>Streeter. I did not recover myself all night. I was in my senses sometimes, but not in my right senses all the night.</p>

               <p>Q. Did not you sleep?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I never shut my eyes to sleep till morning.</p>

               <p>Council. Then in the morning you slept?</p>

               <p>Streeter. In the morning I fell asleep.</p>

               <p>Q. What did you scream for after he got into bed?</p>

               <p>Streeter. Because he hurt me.</p>

               <p>Q. In what manner did he hold you, when he hurt you?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I was not able to struggle.</p>

               <p>Q. When the man came up, you said, you made a mourning noise; what hindred your speaking?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I don't know, I was not able to speak, he had ravished me before the man came up.</p>

               <p>Council. You say he made several attempts on you that night?</p>

               <p>Streeter. He did; but when I recover'd myself, I was more able to resist him.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you cry out afterwards?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I did several times, when he offer'd it.</p>

               <p>Q. What times of the night did you cry out?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I can't tell the times.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you hear the family go to bed?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you know Mrs. Cox, the woman of the house?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I never saw her.</p>

               <p>Q. Was not the cutting off your hair, in order to dress it in the French way?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I don't know. It was cut all off to about two inches long or thereabouts; his servant turn'd it up with an iron.</p>

               <p>Q. Did he powder it?</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200046"></xptr>Streeter. No, he did not.</p>

               <p>Q. Did not you look in the glass, when the servant was dressing your hair?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No, I never did.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you remember Mr. Lackey's coming to you and kissing you, and saying it was very pretty?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No, he did not do any such thing.</p>

               <p>Q. How came you to have your hair cut?</p>

               <p>Streeter. The reason was, I was afraid of being murder'd.</p>

               <p>Q. Was it at Breakfast you cry'd?</p>

               <p>Streeter. It was.</p>

               <p>Q. Had he threatened you?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No, not in the morning; he forced me, and said by G - d I should not go.</p>

               <p>Q. Did he threaten to do you any other kind of hurt?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No.</p>

               <p>Q. What answer did you give him, when he ask'd you what you cry'd for?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I made no answer.</p>

               <p>Council. Then you did take the guinea?</p>

               <p>Streeter. He make me take it, and said I should not go without it.</p>

               <p>Q. Did not the servant and you talk together going home?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I had not a word with him going home.</p>

               <p>Q. Why did not you give the man the guinea to carry it to his master?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I was afraid of him.</p>

               <p>Council. Then you never returned it?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I have it now.</p>

               <p>Q. How came it to pass, that he should tell you he would send a servant to know if the people had used you ill, and if they had you should come again to him; how is that consistent with the supposition of his having used you ill ?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I don't know.</p>

               <p>Q. What discourse had you with him in the morning ?</p>

               <p>Streeter. He told me he would send for a milliner and dress me up, and I should have a coach to ride in; also the buttons on his waistcoat, which he said cost twenty guineas a piece, to button my gown, if I would stay. I told him I had rather go.</p>

               <p>Q. How long had you been with Mrs. Fletcher, before you saw Mrs. Box?</p>

               <p>Streeter. They were all together.</p>

               <p>Q. Why did not you speak of it to Mrs. Fletcher?</p>

               <p>Streeter. Mrs. Fletcher was a stranger to me, and Mrs. Box was not.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you tell Mrs. Box, you had lain all night with a gentleman?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I did.</p>

               <p>Council. I think Mrs. Box and you had been acquainted before?</p>

               <p>Streeter. Mrs. Box brought me to town, she is an acquaintance of my father's. She had been at my father's house in the country.</p>

               <p>Q. What was her advice?</p>

               <p>Streeter. She advised me to go home to my father's.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you know 
               <persName id="t17570420-42-person445">
                  Susannah 
                  Ellis 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person445" type="surname" value="Ellis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person445" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person445" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>

               <p>Streeter. Yes, she was there.</p>

               <p>Q. Who let you in ?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I really do not know.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you mention it to 
               <persName id="t17570420-42-person446">
                  Susannah 
                  Ellis 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person446" type="surname" value="Ellis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person446" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person446" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I did not speak to her about it.</p>

               <p>Q. Was not she by when you spoke to Mrs. Box?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No.</p>

               <p>Q. Whether you did not tell Mrs. Box you had lain out all night with a woman?</p>

               <p>Streeter. The first opportunity I had I began telling her, which was about half an hour or an hour after I came into the house; when I first came in they all set at me to know where I had been.</p>

               <p>Q. How many were there of them?</p>

               <p>Streeter. Seven or eight of them, people in the house, and people besides. I told them I did not know where I had been, nor whom I had been with.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you give no other answer?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No.</p>

               <p>Q. Was 
               <persName id="t17570420-42-person447">
                  Abraham 
                  Hatchet 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person447" type="surname" value="Hatchet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person447" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person447" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in the house at that time?</p>

               <p>Streeter. Yes.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you remember, that upon people's asking you where you had been all night, 
               <persName id="t17570420-42-person448">
                  Abraham 
                  Hatchet 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person448" type="surname" value="Hatchet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person448" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person448" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said, don't be too harsh with her at first; and then he asked you whether any body had used you ill?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I don't remember such a question.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you tell them you had been used very civilly?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No, I did not.</p>

               <p>Q. Did not you call for a pen and ink, and tell either Mrs. Box, or Mrs. Ellis, you'd write the gentleman a letter by the penny post?</p>

               <p>Streeter. No, I did not.</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200047"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-42-person449">
                  Amelia 
                  Fletcher 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person449" type="surname" value="Fletcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person449" type="given" value="Amelia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person449" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at Mr. Ladd's, I kept his house. Mrs. Box brought 
               <persName id="t17570420-42-person450">
                  Christian 
                  Streeter 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person450" type="surname" value="Streeter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person450" type="given" value="Christian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person450" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             out of the country from her father's. She was there ten days. She asked Mrs. Ellis and Mrs. Box to take a walk with her into the Park with her after she had dined.</p>

               <p>Q. Had she been in the Park before?</p>

               <p>A. Fletcher. She had been there several times with one of them.</p>

               <p>Q. What answer was made?</p>

               <p>A. Fletcher. Mrs. Box said she was sleepy, and would go up and lie down. Mrs. Ellis said she would not go; so she went by herself.</p>

               <p>Q. What time of the day was this?</p>

               <p>A. Fletcher. This was about three o'clock, but I don't remember the particular day. It was on a Saturday.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you remember her coming home?</p>

               <p>A. Fletcher. I was there when she came home, but can't recollect any thing about the conversation.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-42-person451">
                  Jane 
                  Hatchet 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person451" type="surname" value="Hatchet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person451" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person451" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mrs. Box came to my house on the second of October, at night, and told me Christian Streeter had been gone out to take a walk in the Park, and was not come home; and she was afraid some ill had come to her. I said, she is a pretty girl, and a sober girl. Yes, said she, a very sober girl, I brought her from her home, and she never was from home in her life before. In the morning before I was up, my husband came to my bed side, and told me that Mrs. Box was there, and begged of me to go into the Park, and inquire of the guards whether they heard any noise there. I did not come down soon enough, and she begged that Mr. Hatchet would go with Mr. Hutchinson to justice Fielding, and ask his advice. While they were concluding about it she came home, which was about one o'clock at noon.</p>

               <p>Q. On what day?</p>

               <p>J. Hatchet. On the Sunday. I went and drank tea with them, and observing the girl to sit in a vast deal of misery I said, if you have been with any body all night, you had better tell it. Mrs. Box said, if you have done a fault, you had better own it. Then tears ran out at her eyes, and she said to Mrs. Box, Madam, if you'll let me speak to you I should be obliged to you. They went together; after that Mrs. Box came in and said she wanted to write to Greenwich, and had no paper. She went to get a sheet of paper. Then the girl told her story, and it was so melancholly that I cried. The girl was in such an agony, I never saw any thing like it.</p>

               <p>Q. What was it she said?</p>

               <p>J. Hatchet. She said a gentleman met her in the Park, and asked her what country girl she was; she told him from Sussex; he said he had a servant that was a Sussex man, from Lewes, and asked her if she had no relations. She said none but one brother, who was with her father. He said may be you may know my servant, and if you'll go with me I'll take care that he shall see you home. So she went with him; he had a fryed rabbit, and he pressed her to eat some, but she would not. He poured out a glass of wine, and made her drink it. This was at the Hercules. Coming away he asked the drawer whether he had seen his man. When they got a little way, he called a coach, and they went to his lodgings; and that she sat in the coach, and heard him ask if his man was come home; somebody said no, he was not. Then he came out, and desired her to walk up stairs. She did, and after a while she began to grow uneasy. He told her as soon as his servant came in, he should go home with her. The servant came in with a letter. She said, he had said so much about young girls being in danger to walk alone, that she could have trusted herself with any body, and thinking this man a Lewes man, she said she thought she should be taken care of by him. When the prisoner had read the letter, she asked him if he'd let the man go home with her. He answered, '' by G - d she should not;'' and then he got his knees close to her, and pulled off her shoes and undressed her. I began to examine her out of compassion, and talked to her as much as I could. I have since lain with her on nights, and talked to her time after time. She is a stranger to me, but I found her always in one story. She said he undressed her, and she fainted away; so that her head lay quite on her shoulder. He took her in his arms, and carried her to bed; and when she came to recover, she found something at her nose, and he by the bed-side. He undressed himself, and got into bed. I being married asked particulars. She made it appear he lay with her, as much as is possible for a man to do. I examined her linen, and have kept it ever since. I did not find a vast deal upon it. but she said the sheets were bloody. I asked her whether it was not about her times; she said, that was about a fortnight before she came to London.</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200048"></xptr>Q. What did you judge by the appearance of her linen?</p>

               <p>J. Hatchet. I judged she was a very virtuous girl, and I dare say she was a virgin.</p>

               <p>Q. Was she always consistent in the relation she gave?</p>

               <p>J. Hatchet. She always was upon my oath. I have talked to her for an hour together; and after that I have gone up again, and told her she had said things that she had not said, to see if she would tell a story, because I knew nothing more of Lackey than I did of her; and I thought I was doing my duty as much as I could. She always said to me, Mrs. Hatchet, how could I say so. She always stuck to the story she first told. On the Sunday in the afternoon, after she told me the story, she said, Madam, the gentleman said he'll send his man by. If Mrs. Box should go to-morrow, I am not well, and if my father was to know, I am sure he would right me for being used so barbarously. The girl desired to come and live with me, and my husband gave her leave; and as I never had a good opinion of Mrs. Box, I for that reason invited her to come to our house. The girl was desirous to find Mr. Lackey out. I said to her, do you think you should know the house again on the other side of the bridge. She said, yes, I believe I could. We took a coach, and went to the Hercules. There stood a man at the door. The girl ticked me, and said, that was the drawer. We went in. I said, has there been a gentleman here, that was along with this gentlewoman, to inquire for a couple of women? He said, no. I asked at the bar if they knew that gentleman's name. The man and his wife could not make it out. Then I called for a gill of wine, and said, I'd stay till he came. The girl said, I am sure the drawer must know him, for he asked him whether his man was come. Then I called him in again, and mentioned that particular; and he said his name is Lackey, and he lives in Rider-street. I desired he'd give it me in writing, which he did. He said to me he was a good for nothing man, and had used him very ill; but bid us not to tell his name, fearing he should come to any hurt. I said I should let her father know it, and he might do as he would.</p>

               <p>Q. What was that person's name ?</p>

               <p>J. Hatchet. His name was 
               <persName id="t17570420-42-person452">
                  James 
                  Speed 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person452" type="surname" value="Speed"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person452" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person452" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , we went to subpoena him, and found that he was dead. He told me he looked at the girl, seeing her look with a country look, and was surprized seeing her with him, and fear'd he should hear a noise every moment, and said if he had he would have gone up to her assistance. I asked him if the girl eat any thing there. He said, no. From the Hercules we went cross the Park; and at the end of Rider-street, I asked where a gentleman, named Lackey, lived, and said he kept a man. I was told he lived at the house of Mrs. Cox, and was shewed it. I went with her five or six times to see if she could find the way she was carried to the Green-park, but she never could. She persisted she was carried a round-about way. She said she did not come out at the end of the street, which I carried her in at, which was the right way. We could not write to the father 'till Tuesday, and he was at our door about eight at night on the Thursday following.</p>

               <p>Q. Who wrote the letter?</p>

               <p>J. Hatchet. Mr. Hutchinson did.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you inquire whether the gentleman was at home when you was there?</p>

               <p>J. Hatchet. No, I did not. I thought it better for the father to do that when he came to town. Mr. Hutchinson, her father, she, and I, went to Mr. Lackey's lodging in a hackney coach. We went all four into his room, and saw him there.</p>

               <p>Q. Was it the same person you now see at the bar?</p>

               <p>J. Hatchet. It was. His veins arose so prodigious high, and his voice was so he could hardly speak. Mr. Hutchinson said to the girl, is that the man? She answer'd yes; said he to him, do you know this girl? he said yes.</p>

               <p>Q. Did the girl mention any money to you?</p>

               <p>J. Hatchet. She said he gave her a guinea and she gave me it, and I gave it to Mr. Hutchinson, and he sealed it up, she gave me also the gloves; we went from thence home, and after dinner to Justice Welch's, and from thence to a constable that he recommended us to.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you charge Mr. Lackey with this offence, when you was there?</p>

               <p>J. Hatchet. No. I never spoke till I got upon stairs; then I said any body may see by your looks what you be.</p>

               <p>Q. Was he charged by any body?</p>

               <p>J. Hatchet. The father told him he ha d used a child of his very barbarously. Mr. Hutchinson said, don't let us stand thus, we have seen the man; that is enough.</p>

               <p>Q. What did Mr. Lackey say?</p>

               <p>J. Hatchet. He said she had been there, and he thought he had used her very well. The girl<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200049"></xptr> was in such an agony, we were some time in getting her up stairs.</p>

               <p>Cross Examination.</p>

               <p>Q. How many times might you have seen the girl after this affair before she told you this story?</p>

               <p>J. Hatchet. I really can't say, whether I had seen her once or twice before she came one night with Mrs. Box to our house, and they ordered some beer; I don't know that I spoke to her then.</p>

               <p>Jos. Hutchinson. The Friday after the affair happened I went with her, her father, and Mrs. Hatchet, in a hackney coach, from Mrs. Hatchet's door to Mr. Lackey's lodging.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you know the person that kept the house where he lodged?</p>

               <p>Hutchinson. No, I did not. I do now: her name is Cox. When the coach stop'd at the door, I ordered the girl to sit at the corner of it, that she should not be observed, and bid her look out as carefully as she could at the person that opened the door. A servant opened the door. I asked him if Mr. Lackey was at home, he said yes. He desired I'd send up my name, I said my name was Hutchinson. He went up. I step'd back to the coach, and asked the girl if she knew that servant, she said that was the gentleman's man.</p>

               <p>Q. What was his name?</p>

               <p>Hutchinson. His name is 
               <persName id="t17570420-42-person453">
                  William 
                  Ellis 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person453" type="surname" value="Ellis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person453" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person453" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I got them all out of the coach, and up stairs as soon as I could: I met the servant upon the stairs, who bid me walk up. I jumped up very quick, fearing he might see the girl get out of the coach: when I got up, there stood Mr. Lackey. I stood close to him, and said nothing at all to him. The girl was a good while in getting up, being affrighted. I said, come along, come along. When he saw the girl he retreated into his room. I followed him, and took the girl by her left arm, and carry'd her within half a yard of him, and said, Sir, do you know this lady? he shook and fluttered a good deal, and said, Yes Sir I do, and I think I used her very well.</p>

               <p>Q. Did he appear to be in any degree of a fright or terrour?</p>

               <p>Hutchinson. He seemed to be apprehensive of some mischief coming to him, he seemed as much in a fright as ever I saw a man in my life.</p>

               <p>Q. What do you mean by fluttering ?</p>

               <p>Hutchinson. His speech was altered.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you accuse him with any thing?</p>

               <p>Hutchinson. I said no more. I accused him with nothing. Then I asked her again, if that was the man, she said yes.</p>

               <p>Q. What did the father say.</p>

               <p>Hutchinson. The father introduced himself thus: Sir, you have used a daughter of mine extremely ill. That was all I heard him say?</p>

               <p>Q. What answer did Mr. Lackey make to that?</p>

               <p>Hutchinson. I don't recollect: that was spoke before I spoke.</p>

               <p>Q. Then who was his answer given to?</p>

               <p>Hutchinson. That answer was given to me.</p>

               <p>Q. How came you to have knowledge of this affair at first?</p>

               <p>Hutchinson. On the 3d of October Mr. Hatchet came to me and told me, Mrs. Box had brought a girl out of the country, and she had let her walk out alone, that she was lost, and they were in a deal of concern about it, and he wanted me to direct them in some method to go into the Park, and ask the officers and people of the guard, to know if she might be taken away by violence. In the evening I went over to Mr. Hatchet's house, and Mr. Hatchet told me, the poor girl that her husband told me of was come home, and treated very cruelly.</p>



               <p>Q. Did the prosecutrix give you any account of her treatment?</p>

               <p>Hutchinson. She did, the same she has now. I wrote to the father, and he came to town.</p>

               <p>Q. Did she give the same account before Mr. Welch as she has done in court?</p>

               <p>Hutchinson. She did, I heard the last examination, it was as near it as could be. Mr. Welch advised me to go to see for Mr. Lackey, I went and found he was absconded, and I could not hear where he was. I took a great deal of pains to find him out. The last account I had of him was, that he was in Holland.</p>

               <p>Q. When was this bill of indictment found?</p>

               <p>Hutchinson. It was found at Hicks's-hall in October last.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-42-person454">
                  John 
                  Streeter 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person454" type="surname" value="Streeter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person454" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person454" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am father to 
               <persName id="t17570420-42-person455">
                  Christian 
                  Streeter 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person455" type="surname" value="Streeter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person455" type="given" value="Christian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person455" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I am acquainted with Mrs. Box. My girl was brought up intirely with me in the country, and was never in town before. Mrs. Box requested of me several times to let her come up before I consented. When I permitted her to come to town, she promised me to take care of her. My girl was well brought up and very modest, and never till lately in any body's company.</p>

               <p>Q. How old is she ?</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200050"></xptr>Streeter. I believe she is in the twentieth year of her age.</p>

               <p>Q. When did you come to town?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I came to town the Thursday after this happened.</p>

               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I live at Stenying, in Sussex. I came directly upon receiving a letter; the morning after I came I endeavoured to find out the house where the prisoner lived: We went there. Mr. Hutchinson got out of the coach, and knocked at the door; a gentleman's servant came. Mr. Hutchinson asked if his master was at home, he said, yes. Mr. Hutchinson sent up his name. The servant returned, and asked him to go up. We got out of the coach, and followed him. Mr. Lackey asked the reason of our coming. I told him he had used a daughter of mine very ill: He said, he thought he had used her very well; he seemed very much affrighted upon our coming up stairs, and looked very pale; his words seemed to shake. We went all out of the room directly after Mr. Hutchinson, and asked the girl if that was the man, and she said, yes.</p>

               <p>Q. Is the prisoner the same person ?</p>

               <p>Streeter. I believe he is.</p>

               <p>Council for Prosecution. We have several witnesses to 
               <persName id="t17570420-42-person456">
                  Christian 
                  Streeter 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person456" type="surname" value="Streeter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person456" type="given" value="Christian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person456" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's character; if they attack that, we shall call them.</p>

               <p>Council for Prisoner. We don't intend to attack it.</p>

               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>

               <p>On the second of October, about three in the afternoon, as I was coming along the Birdcage-walk, in the Park, I overtook this girl near Rosamond's-pond; she looked up to my face and laughed in a very light manner; at that time of the day (it is known very well ) people walk there with an intent to be picked up. I took her for such. I said will you go and dine; she said she had dined. I said will you give me your company. I was coming from Westminster, she turned back with me. I was ashamed to walk with her. She had no gloves on. She followed me 'till I came to the street that fronts the bridge. I went into a shop and gave her a pair of gloves; she thanked me. I believe the person of the shop will give an account of my behaviour and her's, to your lordship and the jury; so it is unnecessary for me to tell it. I asked her at the glove-shop, what sort of gloves she chose to have; the woman brought some, and she chose mittens; the woman drew them on and smiled; then we went to the Hercules tavern, I had what the girl mentioned for dinner, and two or three glasses of wine. I talked with her about whence she came, she told me. I found her what I imagined her to be. I asked her what was the cause of her coming out of the country; she said there was a young man that I was in love with, and he disappointed me; he slighted me, and I was ready to break my heart, so I came up to London to forget him. I said you'll probably have a lover here in town. I asked her if she would see a play; she said she would. I had her in my arms when the drawer came in, but I was dressed in a manner not fit to go with her. She went home with me. We took a coach pretty near the bridge. I handed her in; and when I came to my lodgings it was about the beginning of dusk, between six and seven. I was anxious to know whether my man was returned from Greenwich, where I had sent him. I was not polite enough to give her my hand, I forgot to hand her out of the coach, but left her there; she came out of it herself, and followed me in, and up stairs, knowing she had been some time in my company; I left her up stairs with the servant maid, and went down to talk to my land lady to put things in order for tea, and the maid carried up a couple of candles. When my servant came home, I told him here is a girl that came from Sussex, perhaps she is some relation of your's. She undressed herself, and I went into the bed-chamber; at the time she was undressing herself at the table in the dining-room there was I believe five-hundred pins. I said what do you do with all these; she said my gown pins on. I protest to God she was no more in a sit than I am now, as your lordship will find. After we had been some time in bed, I rung the bell, and ordered a negus; my man brought it up with a candle; and put it on a mahogany waiter. He stood by with the candle. I said, my dear, will you drink; she said no I thank you, I am not dry. In the morning we had a couple of muffins for breakfast; then she had her hair cut by my servant; I asked her which way she would have it cut, or in what fashion: she said, Sir, you are the best judge, cut it as you please. Afterwards I said, you are a pretty girl, and kissed her. I could not get her to stand away, from the glass. Then my music master came to play some tunes with me; I said, I beg you would excuse me this morning from practising in music. I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200051"></xptr> should have observed to your lordship before, that I said, Child I must not keep you here all night, if it is known Mrs. Cox will not like it, because I never did such a thing here. I rung the bell, and went down stairs; the man met me, I opened and shut the door, and said good night, I wish you well home my dear. This I did to deceive my landlady; here are gentlemen that visit me, who know it is impossible to talk with a tone of voice as I do now, but they may be heard. I gave her a guinea, which she thanked me for; she put it three times on the table, which shewed how fond she was of a guinea. The evidence that will come before your lordship, will make it insignificant for me to take up your time. I sent her home the direct way. There was a deal of stress laid on my taking her a round about way, and the like; I had keys for St. James's Park-place, and I ordered my man to carry her through that way, which was a great deal the nighest way to her home. I walked after her myself, and asked my servant at his return what she said, whether people would be affrighted at her being out all night; she said, no, they would not; she was familiar with me, and told me what cloaths she had, what gowns, what petticoats, and said, she would come to me again. My rooms are so situated, that had she made any noise at all my landlady must have heard her. When they came into my room to me, they came in a tumultuous manner, and said, '' I'll do for you,'' and Mrs. Hatchet said, '' I'll have you torn to pieces.'' I did not know what they might be provoked to swear; but I hope in the course of the evidence, the court will see there never was such a piece of iniquity as this.</p>

               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-42-person457">
                  Dorothy 
                  Armitage 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person457" type="surname" value="Armitage"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person457" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person457" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a glover's shop, in Bridge-street, Westminster.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you recollect the prisoner coming to your house with a young woman?</p>

               <p>D. Armitage. I believe I do.</p>

               <p>Q. When did you see her last?</p>

               <p>D. Armitage. I saw her here when she gave her testimony. I can't be particular to the day, it might be about the second of October.</p>

               <p>Q. Which came in first?</p>

               <p>D. Armitage. Really I can't say that. I believe the young woman did. I was then at dinner. I believe it might be about three o'clock. I arose from my dinner, and the gentleman asked me if I sold gloves. I took down some mittens, and drew them on her hand, and he paid me for them.</p>

               <p>Q. How were they dressed?</p>

               <p>D. Armitage. I did not observe that. I did not make any great observation. I took him for a gentleman, but I did not take her for a gentlewoman. What she was I did not know.</p>

               <p>Q. Did she seem to be frighted?</p>

               <p>D. Armitage. No, she did not. He asked her, how she came to come without her gloves; and she said, she forgot them. They had no other conversation in the shop as I can remember.</p>

               <p>Cross Examination.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you remember whether she offered to pay for them?</p>

               <p>D. Armitage. I don't remember that.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-42-person458">
                  John 
                  Gibson 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person458" type="surname" value="Gibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person458" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person458" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Hercules-tavern, on the other side the bridge.</p>

               <p>Q. Where is your wife?</p>

               <p>Gibson. She lies in.</p>

               <p>Q. Where is your waiter 
               <persName id="t17570420-42-person459">
                  James 
                  Speed 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person459" type="surname" value="Speed"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person459" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person459" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>

               <p>Gibson. He was my waiter, he is dead.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you remember any thing of the girl's coming to your house with Mr. Lackey?</p>

               <p>Gibson. I was not at home at that time. I remember her coming to enquire after Mr. Lackey. I asked her particularly about him. She said he behaved extremely well to her there. I said, and I hoped he did at your own house too. She smiled and said nothing.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-42-person460">
                  Mary 
                  Head 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person460" type="surname" value="Head"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person460" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person460" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mrs. Cox, in Rider-street.</p>

               <p>Q. What is her business ?</p>

               <p>M. Head. She lets out lodgings.</p>

               <p>Q. How long have you lived there?</p>

               <p>M. Head. Between eleven and twelve years</p>

               <p>Q. What sort of lodgers does she take in?</p>

               <p>M. Head. Good sort of gentlemen, creditable people.</p>

               <p>Q. Did Mr. Lackey lodge there?</p>

               <p>M. Head. He did; he has lodged there two years and a quarter last Christmas, I believe.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you remember the second of October, when his servant was gone to Greenwich?</p>

               <p>M. Head. I do.</p>

               <p>Q. What happened on that day?</p>

               <p>M. Head. I was in the dining-room, and heard somebody knock with a double knock. My mistress<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200052"></xptr> opened the door. Mr. Lackey came in first; he came up stairs to me, and the young woman followed him up stairs immediately.</p>

               <p>Q. What rooms had he in your house?</p>

               <p>M. Head. He has got the first floor, a dining-room, and a lodging-room, and another higher up for his man. The first floor consists of those two rooms. He pulled off his sword, and laid it down on the table, then went down stairs, left me with the young woman.</p>

               <p>Q. How long was you with her alone?</p>

               <p>M. Head. Ten or twelve minutes.</p>

               <p>Q. What past between you?</p>

               <p>M. Head. I said not a word to her nor she to me. I cleaned my chairs, then went down stairs, and lighted a couple of candles, and as I was going up Mr. Lackey followed me.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you see any more of that young woman that night?</p>

               <p>M. Head. He desired I would shut the windows, and draw the curtains, which I did. Then he said pray go down and make the water boil for tea, which I did. I came up again in about half an hour, the door was open. Then he told me he could not make tea, his servant had the key; so there was no tea at all. I saw no more of the young woman that night. The servant came home between six and seven.</p>

               <p>Q. What is his name?</p>

               <p>M. Head. His name is 
               <persName id="t17570420-42-person461">
                  William 
                  Ellis 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person461" type="surname" value="Ellis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person461" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person461" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he has lived with him better than three years.</p>

               <p>Q. What time did the family go to bed?</p>

               <p>M. Head. I believe about ten or eleven.</p>

               <p>Q. How many were there of you?</p>

               <p>M. Head. There were only me and my mistress besides them in the house that night.</p>

               <p>Q. How long was the street-door open after Mr. Lackey came in?</p>

               <p>M. Head. It was open a great while after that.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you hear any body at the door after you came down?</p>

               <p>M. Head. I believe I did hear somebody say, I wish you a good night.</p>

               <p>Q. Can you recollect whose voice it was?</p>

               <p>M. Head. No, I can't.</p>

               <p>Q. What time might that be?</p>

               <p>M. Head. It was I believe about nine o'clock.</p>

               <p>Q. Where does Mrs. Cox lie?</p>

               <p>M. Head. She lies up two pair of stairs. Her bed-chamber is over Mr. Lackey's.</p>

               <p>Q. Where do you lie?</p>

               <p>M. Head. I lie in the garret, on the same floor as Mr. Lackey's man does.</p>

               <p>Q. Is this a double house?</p>

               <p>M. Head. There is only a door opens, no passage between the dining-room and the lodging-room. It is a very small shell of a house.</p>

               <p>Q. Is Mr. Lackey's lodging-room by the side of the stair-case?</p>

               <p>M. Head. There is a door comes from that to the side of the stair-case.</p>

               <p>Q. Where Mrs. Cox lies, is it possible to hear any noise in Mr. Lackey's bed-chamber?</p>

               <p>M. Head. She can hear any noise there, when he and his servant have been talking we could distinguish their two voices there.</p>

               <p>Q. Suppose they were in the dining-room, could you?</p>

               <p>M. Head. We have heard Mr. Lackey walk about there.</p>

               <p>Q. Then any screaming can be heard in any part of the house?</p>

               <p>M. Head. Yes, that it must.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you hear any noise that night?</p>

               <p>M. Head. No, I did not, not a word.</p>

               <p>Q. Have you more than one stair-case in that house?</p>

               <p>M. Head. No, we have but one. We all pass by the door of his lodging room to go up stairs.</p>

               <p>Q. Had there been a noise of any screaming either in the lodging room or dining-room that night?</p>

               <p>M. Head. No, there had not, if there had we must have heard it.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you go to sleep as soon as you got into bed or not?</p>

               <p>M. Head. I can't say whether I did or not.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you remember any thing of 
               <persName id="t17570420-42-person462">
                  William 
                  Ellis 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person462" type="surname" value="Ellis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person462" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person462" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's coming for wine or lemons, or any thing to make a negus?</p>

               <p>M. Head. Yes, that was between eight or nine o'clock that night; he came down for a little wine and water, and I fetched him a lemon; this was before I went to bed.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you see the young woman the next morning ?</p>

               <p>M. Head. No.</p>

               <p>Q. Did Ellis go up to his master often?</p>

               <p>M. Head. The bell rung two or three times, and he went up and came down again.</p>

               <p>Q. Who attended at breakfast?</p>

               <p>M. Head. Mr. Lackey's servant.</p>

               <p>Q. Is Mrs. Cox's a sober house?</p>

               <p>M. Head. Very sober.</p>

               <p>Q. Would Mrs. Cox have admitted any woman to have come into her house to lie with Mr. Lackey ?</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200053"></xptr>M. Head. No, I never heard that of her in my life time.</p>

               <p>Q. Mention some of the lodgers that used to lodge at your house?</p>

               <p>M. Hea d. We had Mr. Hubert, his Lady, and children.</p>

               <p>Q. Is your house for the reception of sober, not vicious people?</p>

               <p>M. Head. We never took in any but sober people.</p>

               <p>Cross Examination.</p>

               <p>Q. When you was in the kitchen, and they in the one pair of stairs, is it not possible a person might scream, and you not hear it?</p>

               <p>M. Head. No, we can hear people walk there very plain.</p>

               <p>Q. You say you heard somebody say they wished a good night; where was you at the time ?</p>

               <p>M. Head. I was in the kitchen.</p>

               <p>Q. Where was Mr. Lackey then?</p>

               <p>M. Head. He was then in the first floor.</p>

               <p>Q. Who was it that wished a good night?</p>

               <p>M. Head. Who it was I can't tell.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you make the beds?</p>

               <p>M. Head. Yes.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you observe any thing when you made Mr. Lackey's bed?</p>

               <p>M. Head. I did not know of anybody's lying there, so I took no notice.</p>

               <p>Q. How did the girl seem while she was there ?</p>

               <p>M. Head. She seemed very happy, and very well pleased, when I was with her about ten minutes.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you look upon her to be a woman of the town?</p>

               <p>M. Head. No, I did not; we should not have admitted her, if we had suspected her to be one of that sort.</p>

               <p>Council for Prisoner. If there had been any thing of this kind done, would not there have been something to be seen on the sheets?</p>

               <p>M. Head. Yes, to be sure, but I observed nothing.</p>

               <p>Q. Who did you take the girl to be?</p>

               <p>M. Head. I took her to be an acquaintance of his, I did not know what she was.</p>

               <p>Rose Cox. I live in Rider-street, St. James's, and keep a lodging house. Mr. Lackey has lodged with me a year and three quarters.</p>

               <p>Q. What sort of company used to visit him?</p>

               <p>R. Cox. He always had very good company used to come.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you remember any thing particular on the second of October?</p>

               <p>R. Cox. Nothing. only a young woman came with him; I opened the door for him; it was some time before she came out of the coach; he asked me if his servant was come home, I told him no.</p>

               <p>Q. Was you in court when Mr. Lackey made his defence ?</p>

               <p>R. Cox. No, I was not.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you remember the girl coming out of the coach?</p>

               <p>R. Cox. I do; he came and stood upon the step, and she came and stood by his side; he said, pray Miss will you walk in.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you see them walk up stairs?</p>

               <p>R. Cox. I can't say I did, I called the maid down stairs to bring a light, which she did.</p>

               <p>Q. How long might she have been up stairs?</p>

               <p>R. Cox. She might have been there almost a quarter of an hour.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you remember Mr. Lackey's coming down again?</p>

               <p>R. Cox. I do; he was some time in my room, and asked me if I could think what was the reason his man was not come back.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you see Mr. Lackey after that, that night?</p>

               <p>R. Cox. No, I did not. I remember the servant coming home between seven and eight o'clock, his going into the room when the bell rung, and his coming for wine and water; there were some negus made.</p>

               <p>Q. Where was you then?</p>

               <p>R. Cox. I was then in the kitchen.</p>

               <p>Q. Was it carried up?</p>

               <p>R. Cox. I believe it was.</p>

               <p>Q. What room do you lie in?</p>

               <p>R. Cox. I lie up two pair of stairs over the gentleman's head.</p>

               <p>Q. If there had been a violent noise made in his apartment, could you have heard it in the kitchen?</p>

               <p>R. Cox. Yes, very easily; if any body talks there, I can hear them; I can distinguish whose voices they are, but cannot tell what they say.</p>

               <p>Q. What time did you go to bed that night?</p>

               <p>R. Cox. I went to bed about eleven, or after.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you pass close by his door to go to bed?</p>



               <p>R. Cox. Yes, I do.</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200054"></xptr>Q. Can you hear if any body talks in his lodging room, when you are in yours?</p>

               <p>R. Cox. If any body snores in his room I can hear them in mine.</p>

               <p>Q. You know what Mr. Lackey is charged with; if the young woman had screamed should not you or your maid-servant have heard it?</p>

               <p>R. Cox. I think I must, I am very wakeful, and if I hear a noise I get up.</p>

               <p>Q. What time did you go to sleep that night, can you recollect ?</p>

               <p>R. Cox. I did not go to sleep soon that night, I was angry with my maid that she did not go up sooner, and I remember I heard Mr. Lackey's man go to bed.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you hear your maid go to bed?</p>

               <p>R. Cox. I did; she went to bed about half an hour after me. I believe Mr. Lackey's man and she went up soon after one another.</p>

               <p>Q. When you went to bed was you apprehensive there was any body in your house besides Mr. Lackey?</p>

               <p>R. Cox. No, I was not.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you ever know before this, that he had any body lay with him?</p>

               <p>R. Cox. No, nor I would not have admitted that, if I had known it, tho' he had left my house.</p>

               <p>Q. Who lodged in that apartment before him?</p>

               <p>R. Cox. Mr. Hubert did.</p>

               <p>Q. If there had been a screaming, must not you have heard it?</p>

               <p>R. Cox. If there had, I think it impossible but I must have heard it.</p>

               <p>Q. Who lodged with you besides Mr. Lackey at that time?</p>

               <p>R. Cox. I have no body but Mr. Hubert's son lodges with me now, and a gentleman, that is now in the country, who has been with me eleven years; there was no body in the house that night but my servant and I.</p>

               <p>William Ellis. I am Mr. Lackey's footman. I have lived with him almost four years. I remember being sent to Greenwich, on the second of October. I returned about eight at night. When I came home I knocked at the door, and Mrs. Cox's maid opened the door. I asked if my master was at home; she said, in the dining-room, and a gentlewoman with him. I went there and saw my master walking about, and the girl sitting in a chair, by the fire side. I delivered a letter to my master, the door was open; I might stay about five minutes in the room.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you observe any thing particular ?</p>

               <p>Ellis. No, I went down, and went up again in about ten minutes; when he asked me if I delivered the letter to the person I carried it to. I said, no. He asked me whether I received the letter, and whether the person seemed to be in spirits. I said, yes. Then he asked me if I had any relations at Lewes, in Sussex. I said no. Then he said is not your name Ellis? I said, yes, and then went down stairs again.</p>

               <p>Q. Did he mention that the lady was a Sussex woman?</p>

               <p>Ellis. No.</p>

               <p>Q. Was you in that room after that?</p>

               <p>Ellis. I was, three or four times</p>

               <p>Q. Do you remember any conversation between your master and the lady about supper ?</p>

               <p>Ellis. Between nine and ten o'clock he rung the bell, I went up and he asked her if she would have any supper, or drink any thing; she said, she did not choose any thing.</p>

               <p>Q. Did not she signify she wanted to go home?</p>

               <p>Ellis. I did not hear any thing of that.</p>

               <p>Q. What do you know else that past that night?</p>

               <p>Ellis. I heard my master's dining-room bell ring some time after ten o'clock; it might be half an hour past ten. I went up stairs into the bed-chamber, and I there saw my master and Miss Streeter in bed together</p>

               <p>Q. Was this before or after Mrs. Cox and her servant were gone to bed?</p>

               <p>Ellis. It was before my master bid me mix some wine, water, and sugar together, and bring it up to him. I went down stairs, and sent Mrs. Coxs maid for a lemon, and got some water and wine, and carried it up stairs. Master arose in the bed, and tasted it, and said it is very good, and said Miss will you drink with me. No, said she.</p>

               <p>Q. Had you heard any screaming before this?</p>

               <p>Ellis. No, I had not.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you observe by her looks or anything hat she said, any uneasiness at her being there ?</p>

               <p>Ellis. None at all, she smiled at me, and I thought quite the reverse.</p>

               <p>Q. Did she speak faintly, or chearfully?</p>

               <p>Ellis. I thought quite chearfully.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you see them any more that night ?</p>

               <p>W. Ellis. No, not till next morning, when he rung the bell, I believe about eight o'clock. I went up and found master in the dining-room, alone.</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200055"></xptr>Q. Was you ordered by your master to take care of the young woman's cloaths?</p>

               <p>Ellis. No, I was not. I touched none of her cloaths.</p>

               <p>Q. Are you sure of that?</p>

               <p>Ellis. I am.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you see her in a fit?</p>

               <p>Ellis. I know nothing of her being in a fit</p>

               <p>Q. Did you observe any tears in her eyes?</p>

               <p>Ellis. No.</p>

               <p>Q. No signs of grief?</p>

               <p>Ellis. No.</p>

               <p>Q. Was your master dressed when you went up?</p>

               <p>Ellis. He had his coat and waistcoat on loosely about him in the dining-room; he said, William are breakfast things ready, get them ready. went down stairs and got them ready, and about half an hour after that master rung the bell again; I went up and he was in the dining-room, and the bed-chamber door wide open; I got two muffins, he usually has one for his breakfast.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you see the lady then?</p>

               <p>Ellis. I did, I saw her in the bed chamber putting on her cloaths; he said put by the breakfast a little, for miss will have her hair cut. I brought my things up and cut her hair.</p>

               <p>Q. Are you a barber?</p>

               <p>Ellis. I was bred a barber.</p>

               <p>Q. Did the lady submit to have her hair cut ?</p>

               <p>Ellis. She came out of the bed-chamber, sat down, and I cut it: I asked her how she would have it cut, she said just as I pleased: she took off her cap, which was loosely upon her head, and sat facing the glass: it took up half an hour to cut it I did it according to the best of my skill, in the fashion: she seemed very well pleased: master talked to her and kissed her once or twice, and stroke her over the face.</p>

               <p>Q. Did she express any thing of her liking it?</p>

               <p>Ellis. When I had pressed her hair she got up, (there were three glasses in the room) and went to a glass; master said, well, how do you like it miss'd very well she said. I cut a good deal off, and did it properly as it should be done.</p>

               <p>Q. Did she eat any mussin ?</p>

               <p>Ellis. They were both eat, I know not by whom: master hardly eats a whole one: he ordered me to take the things away, and I dressed him.</p>

               <p>Q. What time did she go away?</p>

               <p>Ellis. She went away about twelve o'clock.</p>

               <p>Q. Did she put on her gloves on the Sunday morning?</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-42-person463">
                  Ellis 
                  When 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person463" type="surname" value="When"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person463" type="given" value="Ellis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person463" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I was dressing my master, she got up, and put her hat and gloves and sat down again till I had done dressing master desired me to see her home, and I did.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you go the nearest way with her to Berkley-street ?</p>

               <p>Ellis. I did; he said, take these keys and go thro' the Green-park, it is the cleanest and nearest way.</p>

               <p>Q. Is it so?</p>

               <p>Ellis. It is the cleanest, the nearest, and the best way.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you purposely carry her thro' any bye alleys or by any bawdyhouses ?</p>

               <p>Ellis. No, I went thro' Piccadilly, where masster met some gentlemen: when I got into Piccadilly, I asked her if she was not afraid to go home after being out all night, she said no: she knocked at the door where she lived, and I saw her go in.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you say any thing else to her as you went along?</p>

               <p>Ellis. I told her, I should come by that way about five or six o'clock, and asked her, to be at the door: she smiled, but what she said I did not understand.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you in the morning observe any signs of terrour?</p>

               <p>Ellis. No, not in the least.</p>

               <p>Q. When did you see this girl next?</p>

               <p>Ellis. I saw her on the Friday following: I opened the door, when she and others came in, and went up stairs to my master.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of the conversation ?</p>

               <p>Ellis. No, I do not.</p>

               <p>Cross Examination</p>

               <p>Q. Do you live with Mr. Lackey now?</p>

               <p>Ellis. I do.</p>

               <p>Q. Have you not been turned away since this affair ?</p>

               <p>Ellis. No.</p>

               <p>Q. Have you not been absent from him some time?</p>

               <p>Ellis. I have, but not turned away.</p>

               <p>Q. How long had you been absent from him ?</p>

               <p>Ellis. About a fortnight.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you go the direct way with this young woman to her home, or round about?</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200056"></xptr>Ellis. I went the nearest way a man could go, est.</p>

               <p>Q. Is this house of Mrs. Cox's a house where persons unmarried to lie together?</p>

               <p>Ellis. I never knew it before.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you know 
               <persName id="t17570420-42-person464">
                  John 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person464" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person464" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person464" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>

               <p>Ellis. I can't say I do</p>

               <p>Q. Do you remember your telling any person you had left your master, and he was fled to Holland for a rape?</p>

               <p>Ellis. No.</p>

               <p>Q. Where did your master go after this?</p>

               <p>Ellis. I believe he went to Holland.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you go with him there?</p>

               <p>Ellis. I did.</p>

               <p>Q. Upon what account did he go there?</p>

               <p>Ellis. I can't tell, he did not tell me his business.</p>

               <p>C. for prisoner. Have you never left your master's service?</p>

               <p>Ellis. No, not at all: I came over from Holland to England to his attorney, in order to consult with him.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-42-person465">
                  Susannah 
                  Ellis 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person465" type="surname" value="Ellis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person465" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person465" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Berkley-street, and am servant to Miss Brement: I was once servant to Esq; Lad. I saw 
               <persName id="t17570420-42-person466">
                  Christian 
                  Streeter 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person466" type="surname" value="Streeter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person466" type="given" value="Christian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person466" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             when she came to town, about three weeks before this accident happened. I went several times in the Park with her: she asked me at dinner one Saturday to go into the Park with her, I said I would not.</p>

               <p>Q. What was your reason for that?</p>

               <p>S. Ellis. Because she had so many airs which made the gentlemen take notice of her. I said if I went with her, people would give me a bad character, and no body would take me into their service.</p>

               <p>Q. What were the airs you mean?</p>

               <p>S. Ellis. She wink'd and laugh'd at people that looked at her: she certainly did behave so, and Mrs Box and another woman heard me give that reason.</p>

               <p>Q. What did she say when you said you would not go?</p>

               <p>S. Ellis. She said she would go by herself.</p>

               <p>Q. What time of the day was this?</p>

               <p>S. Ellis. As nigh, as I can guess it was betwixt one and two o'clock; when we found she was missing we were very uneasy, we neither of us pulled off our cloths all night. As soon as it was light we both of us went into the Park, asked, everybody we saw, and described her dress to the pentinels, but no body gave us any account. She came home the next day, being Sunday, about the same time she went out the day before; I let her in. She saw me in a surprize. I shook when I let her in, and she said, Lord. what is the matter I said, are not you ashamed to stay out all night, to nefright Mrs. Box and me out of our wits. She said, what matter is it where I have been, here I am now. She went into the kitchen. Mrs. Box said to her, are not you dirty; she said no, she had not walked a great way, and pull'd up her coats to shew that she was not dirty. I said have you been in a bed; she said yes; I said with whom. she said with a woman. Mr. Hatchet said, don't be so harsh with her: My dear, if you have been misused confess it, and don't be afraid, we'll vindicate your cause: she said, no body has used me ill, far from it; then I went away. Coming in again, the lady at next door came for me to go and drink tea, and after that in my absence I was told she had confessed to Mrs. Box. I went up stairs where she was all alone. Some body knocked at the door; said she, Mrs. Box says it is a gentleman, but the gentleman that I have been with is more of a gentleman than he, for every button that he has got in his wastcoat cost twenty guineas. I looked at her and laughed, and said, do you think such a gentleman can mean you any good; she said, he means me no ill, but if Mrs. Box uses me ill, I'll go to him again. She asked me for a pen and ink, and said she'd write to the gentleman.</p>

               <p>Q. What gentleman did she mean?</p>

               <p>S. Ellis. The gentleman that she had lain with: I said as you are under Mrs. Box's jurisdiction let her do as she pleases; I'll have no hand in it. I said, how will you direct to him; she said, she would put it into the penny post; I said where will you find one, she said at the corner of every street there was one.</p>

               <p>Q. Did she tell you what the gentleman had given her?</p>

               <p>S. Ellis. She said nothing to me of that.</p>

               <p>Q. How came she out of the custody of Mrs. Box to go to Mrs. Hatchet ?</p>

               <p>S. Ellis. I don't know.</p>

               <p>Cross Examination.</p>

               <p>Q. Pray, what kind of airs were those she made use of?</p>

               <p>S. Ellis. When any body look'd at her she'd look in their face; she said to me, don't you think<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200057"></xptr> it is very pretty to cock your eye at gentlemen that take notice of you.</p>

               <p>Q. Might not that be owing to simplicity?</p>

               <p>S. Ellis. It might for what I know.</p>

               <p>Q. Who was present at this conversation?</p>

               <p>S. Ellis. Mrs. Box, Mrs. Fletcher, and Mrs. Hatchet.</p>

               <p>Q. Was this after she had told you she had been in bed with a man?</p>

               <p>S. Ellis. It was. I found her undaunted, and went out of the room directly.</p>

               <p>Q. How was she to direct to the gentleman ?</p>

               <p>S. Ellis. I don't know.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-42-person467">
                  Anne 
                  Box 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person467" type="surname" value="Box"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person467" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person467" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the person that brought 
               <persName id="t17570420-42-person468">
                  Christian 
                  Streeter 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person468" type="surname" value="Streeter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person468" type="given" value="Christian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person468" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to town. I am acquainted with her father.</p>

               <p>Q. How long had she been in town before the 2d of October?</p>

               <p>A. Box. She had been in town near a fortnight before.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you hear 
               <persName id="t17570420-42-person469">
                  Susannah 
                  Ellis 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person469" type="surname" value="Ellis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person469" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person469" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's reason why she would not walk in the Park with her?</p>

               <p>A. Box. I did. She told her, she did not chuse to walk with her, searing people should take notice of her, and she should lose her character.</p>

               <p>Q. What had the girl done?</p>

               <p>A. Box. S. Ellis told her, that gentlemen took notice of her behaviour.</p>

               <p>Q. How did she behave?</p>

               <p>A. Box. I can't tell.</p>

               <p>Q. Did the girl go alone?</p>

               <p>A. Box. She did immediately. Whether she asked me to go with her I know not, but if she did, I denied her.</p>

               <p>Q. When did you see her afterwards?</p>

               <p>A. Box. I never saw her after that, 'till about one the next day.</p>

               <p>Q. Who let her in?</p>

               <p>A. Box. Sukey Ellis let her in.</p>

               <p>Q. How long had she been in the house before you saw her?</p>

               <p>A. Box. Not above five minutes.</p>

               <p>Q. Who was in the house at the time?</p>

               <p>A. Box. There was Mrs. Fletcher and Sukey Ellis.</p>

               <p>Q. Was 
               <persName id="t17570420-42-person470">
                  Abraham 
                  Hatchet 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person470" type="surname" value="Hatchet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person470" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person470" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             there?</p>

               <p>A. Box. No, he was not at first, he came in afterwards.</p>

               <p>Q. Had she ever lain out a night before that?</p>

               <p>A. Box. No: we could not guess where she was gone. When she came home, I enquired of her where she had been? Her answer was, It was no matter where she had been, here is your pincushion.</p>

               <p>Q. What did she mean by that?</p>

               <p>A. Box. She heard me say the day before I wanted one. I asked her where she had been all right, and where she had lain? She told me, she had lain with a woman.</p>

               <p>Q. Did she mention what woman?</p>

               <p>A. Box. No, she did not. I did not ask her any more questions at that time. I asked her if she was dirty; she pulled up her coats, and shewed me she was not, and said, she had not gone far. We went up stairs together; there I began to enquire where she had been. She sat down, and made no answer. I said again, Where have you been? She said, If you talk too much, I'll go again. I got up, and lock'd the door, and said she should not Then she went and sat down in the window. I again asked her where she had been; she said, What did that signify? Said I, Did you lie with a woman all night? She said, No. Did you lie with a man, said I ? She said, Yes. I said, Kitty. how could you do so? She said, she was bewitched. She asked me whether I would give her leave to write to him? I said, No. She asked whether I would give her leave to speak to his servant; and said he would come by the door. I don't remember she mentioned what time. I said, How will you write to the gentleman, and took hold of her pocket. Said she, It is not there. Then she took a paper out of her bosom, and gave it me; it had wrote upon it, To 
               <persName id="t17570420-42-person471">
                  Wm 
                  Douglas 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person471" type="surname" value="Douglas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person471" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person471" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq: at the Cocoa-tree, Pall-mall. I said, Did you see the gentleman write this? She said, she did, and it is not his name, but it is his mother's name. The next day I was to go to Greenwich.</p>



               <p>Q. Did she shew you the guinea?</p>

               <p>A. Box. No, not just then. Mrs. Hatchet came, and she advised me to take the girl into the country to her friends, which I thought not proper, thinking her friends would wonder what was the matter. I intended to do it, but not in a hurry. Mrs. Hatchet desired I'd take a post-chaise next day, with pretence to take her to Greenwich, and so take her into the country. When I would not agree to that, then she desired me to leave the girl with her, which I agreed to. That night she gave me the guinea, and said the gentleman gave it her. Said I, And did you take it? She said, He threw it down on the table, and bid me take it. I asked, What answer did she make? She said, She made none, but refused it; and he threw it three times on the table, and bid her take it; and at last said, If that would not do, she should have more. I gave it her again the next day.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200058"></xptr> When I came from Greenwich, I went to demand her, and they would not let her go with me. Mrs. Hatchet insisted upon letting her father know, if I took her out of the house.</p>

               <p>Cross Examination.</p>

               <p>Q. What was you in Mr. Lad's house?</p>

               <p>A. Box. I had been his housekeeper, tho'at that time I was not, but had leave to stay in the house.</p>

               <p>Q. Did not the girl at any time tell you of any rudeness that was committed upon her by the prisoner?</p>

               <p>A. Box. Not as I remember. She told me no farther than this. - She was walking in the Park, the gentleman met with her, and they went from thence to the New Inn, on the other side Westminster-bridge; going along, as she had no gloves, the gentleman took her into a shop, and gave her a pair. At the New Inn he had a rabbet for dinner, and he drank to her three times, and they took a coach. I asked if they were coming home; she said she knew she was not coming home. He said, when they came to his lodgings his servant should come home with her. He took her out of the coach, and handed her up into his own room. The servant came home with a letter to him, and went down stairs. He took and undress'd her, taking every thing out of her cloaths, even the buckles out of her shoes; and she cried and sereamed murder very much.</p>

               <p>Q. Did not she ask you your advice what was proper to be done on this occasion ?</p>

               <p>A. Box. No, she did not, but begged for God's sake her father might not know of it, for he would be the death of her. She asked me for no assistance, only to hide it from her parents.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you know one Grissith of Steyning?</p>

               <p>A. Box. Yes, I do.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you ever write any letter to him, or shew him one?</p>

               <p>A. Box. Yes.</p>

               <p>Q. In that letter did you mention Mr. Lackey's offering any sum of money for a compromise?</p>

               <p>A. Box. Yes.</p>

               <p>Q. How much money was he to give for the compromise?</p>

               <p>A. Box. I think a hundred, or a hundred and fifty pounds.</p>

               <p>Q. Did she not tell you, that after she was in bed she was ravished against her will and consent?</p>

               <p>A. Box. She did not mention any thing of it to me. She said, he unpin'd her cloaths, and put her to bed against her will, and after that got into the bed to her; that she cried and screamed out murder, and was so hoarse that she could not speak.</p>

               <p>Q. Did she say she cried and scream'd before she was in bed, or after ?</p>

               <p>A. Box. I really can't say whether she said it was before or after.</p>

               <p>Council. You said he put her into bed against her will.</p>

               <p>A. Box. I imagine so; by her talking of screaming and crying, it was so.</p>

               <p>Q. Who was this sum of money to have been paid to, for compromising this affair?</p>

               <p>A. Box. I really can't say who it was to be paid to. The coachman that was in the house where I lived, was asked by a gentleman where he went, who he last lived with; he told him: the gentleman asked him if he knew any thing of this affair; he said, No. The gentleman told him he heard Mr. Lackey wanted to give so much money to compromise it. This he told me, and I put it into the letter.</p>

               <p>Q. Have not you told this to several people?</p>

               <p>A. Box. I don't know but that I have.</p>

               <p>Q. Was you ever offered any sum of money by any person for your giving evidence on this affair ?</p>

               <p>A. Box. No, never in my life.</p>

               <p>Council. Nor no promise at all?</p>

               <p>A. Box. No.</p>

               <p>Council for the Prisoner. When was it that the girl told you of having screamed out? Was that her first story?</p>

               <p>A. Box. This was in the afternoon.</p>

               <p>Q. When? before or after she had seen Mrs. Hatchet?</p>

               <p>A. Box. I am not certain.</p>

               <p>Council for the Prisoner. What authority had you to write any letter at all of their offering a hundred, or a hundred and fifty pounds?</p>

               <p>A. Box. I don't know that I had any at all.</p>

               <p>Council for the Prisoner. Where does that coachman live now?</p>

               <p>A. Box. He lives now with the duke of Leeds.</p>

               <p>Council for the Prisoner. Was it any body that belong'd to Mr. Lackey?</p>

               <p>A. Box. No.</p>

               <p>Council for the Prisoner. How came you to write this letter?</p>

               <p>A. Box. I wrote it to a friend of mine, that it might come round to the girl's friends, and they might have it.</p>

               <p>Council for the Prisoner. Did you ever see Mr. Lackey before?</p>

               <p>A. Box. No, I never did in my life. I don't know him.</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200059"></xptr>Council for the Prisoner. Did any body ever hint to you to give false evidence?</p>

               <p>A. Box. No, nobody.</p>

               <p>Council for the Prisoner. Have you any expectation from giving evidence in any shape whatsoever?</p>

               <p>A. Box. No, I have not</p>

               <p>Council for the Prisoner. Did the prosecutrix, (when she owned she had been in bed with a gentleman that night ) tell you those circumstances of going over the new bridge, and buying a pair of gloves, and then going to his lodgings?</p>

               <p>A. Box. She told me all that I have said at that time.</p>

               <p>To the Character of Mrs. Cox.</p>

               <p>Mr. Hubert. I know Mrs. Cox extremely well, I have lodged at her house four years last past, at times, when I came to town for a month or six weeks together, with my wife and daughter with me.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you take it to be a sober house?</p>

               <p>Hubert. I certainly did, or I had not suffered my wife and daughter to come there.</p>

               <p>Q. How long have you known Mrs. Cox?</p>

               <p>Hubert. I have known her I believe five years.</p>

               <p>To the Prisoner's Character.</p>

               <p>The Earl of Litchfield. I have known Mr. Lackey about twelve years.</p>

               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>

               <p>A.. I apprehend him to be a gentleman, and one who has always behaved himself well.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you look upon him to be a man of honour?</p>

               <p>A. I do.</p>

               <p>Lord 
               <persName id="t17570420-42-person472">
                  Ward 
                  I 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person472" type="surname" value="I"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person472" type="given" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person472" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             have known Mr. Lackey near twenty years.</p>

               <p>Q. What is your opinion of him?</p>

               <p>A. I always looked upon him as a person of honour, and a well-behaved gentleman.</p>

               <p>Sir 
               <persName id="t17570420-42-person473">
                  John 
                  Philips 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person473" type="surname" value="Philips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person473" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person473" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner a great many years, and I always looked upon him to be a very well-behaved gentleman. I have taken him down into the country to my house, where he has tarried sometimes, and always behaved extremely well.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you imagine him capable of commiting the fact laid to his charge?</p>

               <p>A. I do not.</p>

               <p>Sir 
               <persName id="t17570420-42-person474">
                  John 
                  Hind 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person474" type="surname" value="Hind"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person474" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person474" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             Cotton. I have known the prisoner ten years. He is a man of honour, and a good-natured man.</p>

               <p>The Honourable 
               <persName id="t17570420-42-person475">
                  Robert 
                  Lee 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person475" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person475" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person475" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; I have known the prisoner about fourteen or fifteen years, and during my acquaintance with him I always looked upon him as a gentleman, and a man of honour and a good-natured man; and as such I have him company.</p>

               <p>Sir 
               <persName id="t17570420-42-person476">
                  Charles 
                  Kemys 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person476" type="surname" value="Kemys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person476" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person476" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Bart. I have known the prisoner some time, and I always thought him a man of honour; he has always behaved as a man of honour during my knowledge of him.</p>

               <p>Colonel 
               <persName id="t17570420-42-person477">
                  Fortster
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person477" type="given" value="Fortster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person477" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about twenty years, as well as I can recollect, and I always looked upon him as safe as any man alive against any accusation of this kind.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-42-person478">
                  Anthony Langley 
                  Swimmer 
               <interp inst="t17570420-42-person478" type="surname" value="Swimmer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person478" type="given" value="Anthony Langley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-person478" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; I have known the prisoner for ten years, and I think him utterly incapable of committing such an action as he has been charged with.</p>

               <p>Sir Crisp Gaycoyne. My acquaintance with the prisoner was throught my son. He has often come to my house with and without my son, and always behaved as a man of honour, and with great decency; and I always esteemed him and behaved him to be a man of honour and character.</p>

               <p>Mr. Alderman Blakiston. I have known the prisoner thirteen or fourteen years, and always looked upon him to be a gentleman of as much honour as any I ever knew in my life.</p>

               <p>Bamber Gascoyne, Esq; I have known the prisoner ever since I can remember, and I do not think he would do any thing to corrupt a lady morals or virtue.</p>

               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570420-42-verdict219" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570420-42-verdict219" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
