<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17580222-50">
               <interp inst="t17580222-50" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580222-50" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580222-50" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580222"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580222-50" type="date" value="17580222"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580222-50-off255-c330" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580222-50-defend411 t17580222-50-off255 t17580222-50-verdict259"></join>
         
               <p>157. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17580222-50-defend411" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Robinson 
                  <interp inst="t17580222-50-defend411" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-50-defend411" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-50-defend411" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17580222-50-deflabel254" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580222-50-defend411 t17580222-50-deflabel254"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17580222-50-off255" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580222-50-off255" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-50-off255" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one linen handkerchief, one cotton handkerchief, two linen aprons, one linen cap, and 11 s. in money number'd
            </rs>, the goods and money of 
               
                  <persName id="t17580222-50-victim413" type="victimName">
                     Mary 
                     Beaumont 
                  <interp inst="t17580222-50-victim413" type="surname" value="Beaumont"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-50-victim413" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-50-victim413" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580222-50-off255 t17580222-50-victim413"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17580222-50-viclabel256" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580222-50-victim413 t17580222-50-viclabel256"></join>, <rs id="t17580222-50-cd257" type="crimeDate">Oct. 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580222-50-off255 t17580222-50-cd257"></join>.*</p> 
               <p>Mary Beaumont. In October last I lived at Mr. Alveringo's, in <placeName id="t17580222-50-crimeloc258">St. Mary Axe</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17580222-50-crimeloc258" type="placeName" value="St. Mary Axe"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17580222-50-crimeloc258" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580222-50-off255 t17580222-50-crimeloc258"></join>. On the 24th of that month the prisoner came and knock'd at the door, which I went and open'd. She asked me if I had any china to mend. I said no. Then she said it was a blessed moment, the first time I ever saw you, will you have your fortune told? I said, I did not want to have it told. She said she could tell me of things that would do me a great deal of good, and also to a person that had been dead a long time, to give that soul rest, and went on with a good deal of this discourse. I said I did not believe what she talk'd of. She said, it is as true as God is in Heaven, telling me of a pot, in which was 200 l. hid by that deceased person. She told me I must go down into the cellar, fetch up a bit of earth, and put it in a handkerchief, which I did. When I came up again she asked me if I had any silver in my pocket. I said, I had. She bid me pull it out, and hold it in my hand with the blessing of God. She said, she did not desire a farthing. I pull'd out a crown piece, and six shillings in silver. She said, I must put it into these things, then pull'd out a bit of earth and some black dust, put it into the handkerchief, and, as I thought, put it into my bosom; but I found afterwards, when I went to look, it was only some halfpence, and a medal piece. (Producing the medal.) She said also that the must have some of my cloaths, or else she could not recover the things, nor give the spirit rest; so I gave her a white apron, a silk handkerchief, a linen one, a cotton one, a colour'd apron, and a cap. She said she would come with them again in the evening. I never saw her afterwards, till last December, when she knock'd at my master's door again (I knew her as soon as I saw her) and ask'd me if I would buy any lace. I said, no; I did not want any. Then she ask'd me if I would have my fortune told. I said, no. She put her hand against the door, and came in; young woman, said she, and began her stuff as before. She said, have you got any halfpence in your pocket? I said, I believed I had got one halfpenny. Said she, will you trust me with it? I said, no. Have you any silver in your pocket said she? I said, I had, and pull'd out half a crown. Said she, hold it in your hand, you must fetch some dust, and I will tell you your fortune. I said, I would not fetch any. She said, then fetch some salt. Then I said, you have rob'd me before, and I will acquaint my master of it before you go out of the house. Then she made a great clamour. Our people came down, secured her, and had her committed.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you deliver these things to her that you charge her with?</p>
               <p>M. Beaumont. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never propose to make this matter up with her?</p>
               <p>M. Beaumont. No, I never did; but her friends have offered me money if I would.</p>
               <p>[It appearing not to be a felony, she was <rs id="t17580222-50-verdict259" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580222-50-verdict259" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>, and the prosecutrix bound over to find a bill against her for a misdemeanor, for which she is to be tried at Guildhall.]</p>
            </div1>
