<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570420-47">
               <interp inst="t17570420-47" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570420-47" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570420-47" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570420"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570420-47" type="date" value="17570420"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570420-47-off252-c456" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-47-defend545 t17570420-47-off252 t17570420-47-verdict256"></join>
         
               <p>196 (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17570420-47-defend545" type="defendantName">
                     Peter 
                     Huck 
                  <interp inst="t17570420-47-defend545" type="surname" value="Huck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-defend545" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-defend545" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17570420-47-off252" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-off252" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-off252" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               that he, on the <rs id="t17570420-47-cd253" type="crimeDate">31st of March</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-47-off252 t17570420-47-cd253"></join>, about the hour of three in the morning, on the same day, the dwelling house of 
                     <persName id="t17570420-47-victim546" type="victimName">
                        Judith 
                        Gatehouse 
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-victim546" type="surname" value="Gatehouse"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570420-47-victim546" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570420-47-victim546" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-47-off252 t17570420-47-victim546"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , <rs id="t17570420-47-viclabel254" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-47-victim546 t17570420-47-viclabel254"></join>, did break and enter, and steal three pieces of cheque, value 4 l. 19 s. two pieces of printed linen, value 19 s. two pieces of dawn, value 16 s. ten linen handkerchiefs, value 5 s. thirty six silk and cotton handkerchiefs, value 3 l. 10 s. and twenty four silk handkerchiefs, value 5 l the goods of the said Judith, in her dwelling house
            </rs>.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-47-person547">
                  Judith 
                  Gatehouse 
               <interp inst="t17570420-47-person547" type="surname" value="Gatehouse"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-person547" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-person547" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17570420-47-crimeloc255">White Chapple, almost facing Red-Lion-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17570420-47-crimeloc255" type="placeName" value="White Chapple, almost facing Red-Lion-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17570420-47-crimeloc255" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-47-off252 t17570420-47-crimeloc255"></join>, and am a single woman. on the 31st of March last, in the morning about three o'clock, I was alarm'd by a loud knocking at my door. I got up, threw up my sash, and call'd to a lodger that lay in a two-pair of stairs room backwards to get up. We went down stairs. When I got into my shop I found the counter slap open, and the counter about a quarter empty. It was full of goods when I went to bed. I shut the counter down about eight o'clock.</p>

               <p>Q. Give an account of the goods you missed, and their value.</p>

               <p>J. Gatehouse. There were three pieces of cheque, value about 5 l. two pieces of printed linen, value about 19 s. two pieces of lawn, value about 16 s. ten linen handkerchiefs, value 5 s. thirty six silk and cotton handkerchiefs, value about 3 l. 10 s. and two dozen of silk handkerchiefs, value 5 l. I opened the door. Three men were waiting for us. The cellar window, that leads to the inside of the counter, was broke open, and the wainscot between the window and counter was broke also; so that a man might pass through.</p>

               <p>Q. How was the cellar window fasten'd before you went to bed ?</p>

               <p>J. Gatehouse. There was an iron bar cross the door, and a large padlock on it; the cellar is under my shop.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you rent the whole house ?</p>

               <p>J. Gatehouse. I do; there is a trap door to the cellar window, that people in the street tread upon, and the door opens first before that can be taken up, and when that flap is open there are steps down into the cellar.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you observe that to be fast the over night?</p>

               <p>J. Gatehouse. I can't say I did; but I know it was, because it being in the high street, if the lock had been off, the bar would have tumbled down.</p>

               <p>Q. Was the outward door broke?</p>

               <p>J. Gatehouse. The lock was wrench'd off, and flung away.</p>

               <p>Q. How came you to have any suspicion of the prisoner ?</p>

               <p>J. Gatehouse. He was taken in the cellar, and brought out to me.</p>

               <p>Q. Where were the goods?</p>

               <p>J. Gatehouse. They were all found in the cellar likewise.</p>

               <p>Q. What time did you go to bed the over night?</p>

               <p>J. Gatehouse. I believe about twelve o'clock. When we took the prisoner before Sir 
               <persName id="t17570420-47-person548">
                  Samuel 
                  Gower 
               <interp inst="t17570420-47-person548" type="surname" value="Gower"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-person548" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-person548" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             he asked him where he liv'd. He wrote<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200070"></xptr> to the justice that he liv'd in Abel's-Buildings; but upon examination we found he liv'd in Spital-fields.</p>

               <p>Q. Where is Abel's-Buildings?</p>

               <p>J. Gatehouse. It goes into Rag-Fair; there was also found in the cellar an iron instrument, with which I suppose the door was open'd. (Produced in court an iron with two strong forks, and an iron tooth about eight or nine inches long, on one side.)</p>

               <p>Cross Examination.</p>

               <p>Q. How do you know that the padlock was thrown away?</p>

               <p>J. Gatehouse. Because we could not find it.</p>

               <p>Q. How do you know he was taken in the cellar?</p>

               <p>J. Gatehouse. Because I was at the street door when he was brought out to me.</p>

               <p>Q. Is there a way out of your shop into the cellar?</p>

               <p>J. Gatehouse. No; there is none without going out at the street door, except you break a door that has been fastened up some years.</p>

               <p>Q. Is it not possible for a man in the street to tread on the door, and fall into the cellar?</p>

               <p>J. Gatehouse. No, he cannot.</p>

               <p>Q. What use do you put the cellar to?</p>

               <p>J. Gatehouse. To no use at all. I can take my oath the door has not been opened but once these three years. (The goods produced in court, and deposed to:)</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-47-person549">
                  William 
                  Cooper 
               <interp inst="t17570420-47-person549" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-person549" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-person549" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a paviour's labourer, I and 
               <persName id="t17570420-47-person550">
                  Richard 
                  Rawlins 
               <interp inst="t17570420-47-person550" type="surname" value="Rawlins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-person550" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-person550" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             were going to work on London-Bridge, between three and four o'clock, on the 31st of March; we saw the prosecutrix's cellar window open four or five inches, and the iron instrument by the slap of the door. My master went to call the watch, and I staid by the door till the watchman came.</p>

               <p>Q. Did any body go in while you stood there ?</p>

               <p>Cooper. No; I clap'd my back against it. We call'd up the people of the house, and the prosecutrix came down to the door. Then my master and the watchman went into the cellar with a candle; I look'd down and saw a man lying upon the stairs under the door as if he was asleep, and the goods in a sack in the cellar by him. They pull'd him up out of the cellar. We carried him and the goods before the justice, and did not take the goods out of the sack till we came there.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you know that man if you should see him?</p>

               <p>Cooper. It was the prisoner at the bar.</p>

               <p>Q. Was the prisoner in his senses?</p>

               <p>Cooper. He could not speak.</p>



               <p>Q. to prosecutrix. Did you look at the goods before the justice?</p>

               <p>Prosecutrix I did; these are the same.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-47-person551">
                  Richard 
                  Rawlins 
               <interp inst="t17570420-47-person551" type="surname" value="Rawlins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-person551" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-person551" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a paviour. I was with Cooper on the 31st of March going by the prosecutrix's house. I observ'd her cellar door open about six inches. I stoop'd down and took up this iron instrument, which lay on the flap of the door. The iron bar was laid up carefully against the wall of the next house, as it somebody had open'd it that belong'd to it. I shut it to. I left my man there, and went up to the watch-house, and brought Ellick Pearson a watchman. We alarm'd the house, and the prosecutrix came down. We found a flap that open'd into the shop, and bolted with two bolts, was broke open. The watchman went down into the cellar, and I followed him, and saw the prisoner lying on his face, just by the foot of the stairs; there were some pieces of handkerchiefs lying out of the sack, and the sack about a yard from him, with the rest of the goods in it. This is the sack (taking it in his hand.) We brought him up into the house, and the sack with the things in it. He wrote in the shop that he had lost his speech four years ago, that coming by and hearing a noise he fell into the cellar. We took him before the justice, and there he wrote that he was going to look after a captain, and coming by the door he heard a noise; he crossed the way, and there were two men; one pull'd up the flap, and the other open'd the door, and he fell down into the cellar. But I pull'd up the flap in order to get him out, it had not been open'd before.</p>

               <p>Cross Examination.</p>

               <p>Q. In what condition did he seem to be?</p>

               <p>Rawlins. He seem'd to be quite sensible; he could hear any thing as quick as I could.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you think the prisoner was able to have got out of the cellar with the goods, had you not open'd the flap?</p>

               <p>Rawlins. I think he was. I brought out the goods; they were about half a hundred weight.</p>

               <p>Q. Was it possible for a man to tumble in there ?</p>

               <p>Rawlins. No, a child could hardly tumble down there.</p>

               <p>Q. Suppose a man was to cross from the opposite side of the street, might not he fall down there, by making a safe step?</p>

               <p>Rawlins. There was a lamp just by it.</p>

               <p>Q. Could a man get out of that cellar with a bundle on his back?</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200071"></xptr>Rawlins. No; but he might put the bundle out first, and then get out himself.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-47-person552">
                  John 
                  Ems 
               <interp inst="t17570420-47-person552" type="surname" value="Ems"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-person552" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-person552" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a night-man; I saw much such a sort of a man as the prisoner standing at the end of Castle-street with a bag on his arm that night.</p>

               <p>The prisoner's defence, which he wrote on paper, and delivered to the court:</p>

               <p>What observation I made on the witness is, they are very different from one another, but I am not acquainted with the laws of this nation; I hope my Lord and gentlemen of the jury will consider it is impossible for me to answer in such a short time, therefore I hope, when I have called several gentlemen, which are in court, to justify my character, you will find it is good, and I hope you will inquire into the character of my witnesses.</p>

               <p>To his Character.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-47-person553">
                  Michael 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17570420-47-person553" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-person553" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-person553" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a victualler, and live near Nightingal-Lane; I have known the prisoner between six and seven years.</p>

               <p>Q. What is he?</p>

               <p>Smith. He prosessed to be a surgeon, ever since I knew him. I knew him some years before he lost his speech.</p>

               <p>Q. How did he lose it?</p>

               <p>Smith. He let me know by writing, that he lost it by a fit.</p>

               <p>Q. Is he subject to sits?</p>

               <p>Smith. I can't tell that he is; I believe him to be an honest man. I never heard to the contrary till this affair happened.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you know the occasion of his being out on the 30th of March?</p>

               <p>Smith. He was at my house that afternoon. I once recommended him to a captain of a ship, to cure him of the venereal disease.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-47-person554">
                  Thomas 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17570420-47-person554" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-person554" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-person554" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a weaver at Bethnal Green, and have known the prisoner seven years; I never heard any thing dishonest of him before this.</p>

               <p>Q. How long has he lost his speech?</p>

               <p>Price. I believe it is about three or four years ago. He has work'd for me ever since he has lost his speech, till within these three or four months.</p>

               <p>Gebriel Pomear. I am a silver-smith. and live at Bethnel-Green. I have known the prisoner about ten years. He has a very good character. He was a baker, and I used to buy bread of him.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-47-person555">
                  Simon 
                  Goran 
               <interp inst="t17570420-47-person555" type="surname" value="Goran"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-person555" type="given" value="Simon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-person555" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a baker, and live in Christ-Church parish, Spitalfields; I have known him very well these ten years. I never heard any bad character of him till this present affair.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-47-person556">
                  James 
                  Cardinue 
               <interp inst="t17570420-47-person556" type="surname" value="Cardinue"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-person556" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-person556" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner some years; he had a very good character.</p>

               <p>Mr. Benney. I have known him about nine years. I never heard to the contrary, but that his character was very good; I have trusted him in my house, and never missed any thing.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-47-person557">
                  Henry 
                  Thackery 
               <interp inst="t17570420-47-person557" type="surname" value="Thackery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-person557" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-person557" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him almost twenty years; he is a very honest man. He has paid me a great deal of money for wood, to heat his oven with. I keep a wharf, and sell wood and coals.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-47-person558">
                  John 
                  Adams 
               <interp inst="t17570420-47-person558" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-person558" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-person558" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a taylor, and have known him eight or nine years; he is a very honest man. I never heard any thing amiss of him.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-47-person559">
                  Isaac 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17570420-47-person559" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-person559" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-person559" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a jeweller, and have known him betwixt eight and nine years; I look upon him to be an honest man.</p>

               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570420-47-verdict256" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-verdict256" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17570420-47-punish257" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570420-47-punish257" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-47-defend545 t17570420-47-punish257"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
