<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17520514-10">
               <interp inst="t17520514-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520514-10" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520514-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520514"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520514-10" type="date" value="17520514"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520514-10-off46-c53" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-10-defend68 t17520514-10-off46 t17520514-10-verdict50"></join>
         
               <p>290. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17520514-10-defend68" type="defendantName">
                  Joseph 
                  Sisterron 
               <interp inst="t17520514-10-defend68" type="surname" value="Sisterron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-10-defend68" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-10-defend68" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted, for that <rs id="t17520514-10-off46" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520514-10-off46" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-10-off46" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               he, with a certain musket did make an assault upon 
                     <persName id="t17520514-10-victim69" type="victimName">
                        William 
                        Pratt 
                     <interp inst="t17520514-10-victim69" type="surname" value="Pratt"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520514-10-victim69" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520514-10-victim69" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-10-off46 t17520514-10-victim69"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, with an intent the money of the said William to steal, &amp;c.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17520514-10-cd47" type="crimeDate">December 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-10-off46 t17520514-10-cd47"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-10-person70">
                  William 
                  Pratt 
               <interp inst="t17520514-10-person70" type="surname" value="Pratt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-10-person70" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-10-person70" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 18th of December, as I was going over <placeName id="t17520514-10-crimeloc48">Marybon-fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17520514-10-crimeloc48" type="placeName" value="Marybon-fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520514-10-crimeloc48" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-10-off46 t17520514-10-crimeloc48"></join>, between 7 and 8 at night, the prisoner clapp'd his piece to my breast, and demanded my money; I told him, I had only a few half-pence, and he was welcome to them, he swore if I offerr'd to stir, he'd blow my brains out; he stopt me about 6 or 7 minutes, and asked me, which way I had been, and who I was? when I went to go away,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175205140008"></xptr> he would not let me go forwards nor back again, but said, d - n your eyes, go that way, and pointed towards Marybon Bason, I went to go that way, he followed me over another field, and asked me, if I had no more money than a few half pence? I said, I had not; he swore I had, and he would blow my brains out, I begg'd my life of him, and said I had no more: after he found I had n o more, he admitted me to come nearer to him; then I ask'd him, if he would not go to some house and drink ? he made use of a great many desperate words, and at last was prevail'd upon to go to the Turk's-head with me, just by Marybon bason, he drank share of 2 pints of beer there: he had got his bayonet and sword, (note, the prisoner was a soldier) There were only a woman and two boys in the house, I beckon'd to the woman to come in the kitchen, and I told her the affair, and ask'd her if she had any body she could send for an officer, she was aftrighted, and said, she had no body to send, but that she know'd him, and where he was quarter'd, and desired I would do nothing farther at that time. I went and sat opposite to him, look'd him full in the face, that I might know him again, and ask'd him, if he had at that time any intent to have shot me? he made this reply, d - n your eyes, I would have blow'd your brains out. I said, are you loaded? he said, yes, with a ball, and pull'd out six or seven more, and shewed me near half a pound of gunpowder.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he been from you between the time he stopp'd you, and the time of your being in that alehouse?</p>
               <p>Pratt. From that time, to the time of being in the alehouse, he was never from me, except the time I beckon'd the woman into the kitchen to ask her for somebody to send for an officer.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was you with him in the alehouse?</p>
               <p>Pratt. I staid there, I believe, about half an hour at least, the woman begg'd of me to let him go, for he had got his piece, and was going to blow the ceiling down.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say in answer to your question, that he would blow your brains out if you offerred to resist, in the hearing of any body else?</p>
               <p>Pratt. He did before the woman and the two boys.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to ask him to drink with you?</p>
               <p>Pratt. I thought to take him into the house, in order to get some-body to take him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take him to be foolish.</p>
               <p>Pratt. No, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he present his piece?</p>
               <p>Pratt. He put it to his shoulder, and presented it to my breast.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the woman's name that keeps the house?</p>
               <p>Pratt. Her name is Pitt.</p>
               <p>Q. Is she here ?</p>
               <p>Pratt. No, she is not. I went and acquainted the prisoner's officer with the affair, and the prisoner absconded for about two months, to that I could not see him in that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was his quarters?</p>
               <p>Pratt. His quarters were at the Green Man, in Marybon Parish.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you go to his quarters?</p>
               <p>Pratt. The very next day, in the morning, and saw him.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did not you take him up then?</p>
               <p>Pratt. I had not a warrant against him then, I could not. I went for a warrant, and when I returned, he was gone.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was coming from guard that day, with all my arms and accoutrements upon me, and my grenadier cap on: going to my quarters at the Green-Man, I had happen'd to stay along with two or three of my comrades. I was singing as I went along: I met the prosecutor, I said, who is there? said he, a friend: then said I, let's see who the friend is, he came up within about 20 yards of me; said I, have you got any thing to do me damage? said he, I have nothing but a stick, and then said, what is the reason you ask me? I said, because about three months ago I was almost murder'd in those fields, and was obliged to be carried to the Hospital, and lay there near a month. Said he, what do you want further ? I said, nothing; then he said I'll throw my stick away; said I, have you any half-pence about you, if you have, we will go and have a pint of beer together, he asked me where I was going, I said, to my quarters, he asked where, I said at the Green-Man, he said, he had just been drinking there, and said, he did not care to go back; then I said, I would go along with him, which I did, and we staid in that house almost an hour ; there were several people there all the time, he there abused me and called me all the names he could think of.</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175205140009"></xptr>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-10-person71">
                  Lewis 
                  Richards 
               <interp inst="t17520514-10-person71" type="surname" value="Richards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-10-person71" type="given" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-10-person71" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I carried a young lady the next door to the ale-house they were drinking at that night, and went in there; there was the soldier and prosecutor drinking and quarrelling.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you there when they came in?</p>
               <p>Richards. No, my lord, I was not. They had not call'd for any beer when I came in, there were other people in the room, besides the landlady and two boys.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you go in?</p>
               <p>Richards. About seven o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you recollect that?</p>
               <p>Richards. Because I was ordered to be there at seven.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you stay there?</p>
               <p>Richards. I staid better than a quarter of an hour, the soldier was very much in liquor, and the prosecutor said, he had stopped him in the fields; afterwards the soldier said, I did, but not with an intent to rob you; then the prosecutor said, No, I believe not, indeed.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body else hear this besides you?</p>
               <p>Richards. There was another chairman, that brought the lady with me, we went there to have a pot of beer ; the next day after I brought my lady from the play: I and the other chairman went to the Turks-head again: between ten and eleven at night the prosecutor and another soldier and the landlord at the Green-man came with a gun loaded to take the prisoner, said Pratt to them, we will hang the soldier for the reward, I asked them the reason they brought the gun, they said, for their safety, because a man was abused in the fields the night before.</p>
               <p>Q. to Pratt. When was you there again?</p>
               <p>Pratt. It was the night after.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this evidence drinking in the house when you went in?</p>
               <p>Pratt. I believe he was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you speak such words as he has declared ?</p>
               <p>Pratt. I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any body else in the room at that time ?</p>
               <p>Pratt. There was the landlord, landlady, and these chairmen; I don't remember any body else. The landlord at the Green Man was with me, he had a gun.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-10-person72">
                  Patrick 
                  Cravie 
               <interp inst="t17520514-10-person72" type="surname" value="Cravie"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-10-person72" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-10-person72" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a chairman, and was in the Turk's-head drinking part of a pot of beer along with the other witness, we had carried the Dutchess of Bridgwater's daughter home from the play, when the prosecutor and the landlord at the Green Man came in between 10 and 11 o'clock, I can't tell the day of the month; they had a gun loaded and seemed to be very much fuddled ; they play'd tricks with the gun, and said, We'll do for the soldier, we'll hang him, and have the reward.</p>
               <p>Q. Which said so?</p>
               <p>Cravie. The prosecutor said so.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he say so?</p>
               <p>Cravie. In the open tap-room.</p>
               <p>Q. To who?</p>
               <p>Cravie. To none in particular: They told how they had taken out a warrant for him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the soldier before?</p>
               <p>Cravie. I never saw him in my life before to day, as I know of.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-10-person73">
                  John 
                  Pitt 
               <interp inst="t17520514-10-person73" type="surname" value="Pitt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-10-person73" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-10-person73" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the landlord at the Turk's-Head; I was not at home when the soldier and prosecutor came in together: the morning after this fray was, the prosecutor came down, he had a pint of beer, and told me he was going home and met a soldier about the middle of the fields going towards the country, that the soldier levelled his piece at him, and asked him, who he was, and what business he had there? that he replied, he was going home; then the soldier said, he should not go any farther without he would let him know who he was; then Pratt asked him, what he desired of him: he said, he had received damage in, or near that place, and may be, he might be one of them that did it; then Pratt answered he had nothing but a stick and he had thrown that down, that when he came near, the soldier asked what money he had in his pocket, he answered, as much as would pay for a pint or two of beer and you are welcome to take part of it, then they came to my house; I went with him to shew him where the soldier lodged, going along, I said, what do you think his intention was to have done you any damage? he said, I don't believe the fellow had any intention to hurt me, but he threaten'd me, that if I stirred he would blow me to pieces; we went up to Mr. Dixon's, there the soldier quartered, he was at home: I had never seen him before ; I asked him the meaning of his last night's proceedings,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175205140010"></xptr> he said, he did not know he had offered any violence to Mr. Pratt, saying, he was in liquor. Mr. and Mrs. Dixon were desirous to have the soldier moved out of their house, and he said, he was willing to go any where else ; so we went to the constable to have his quarters changed, but the constable then was not at home. Pratt went there along with us.</p>
               <p>Morduck Mackenzey. When we heard there was a warrant out against a soldier to whom I belong, we went to his quarters, there was the prosecutor along with the landlord, he told us much the same story he has now; I asked him if he thought the soldier had any intent to rob him; he said, he did not think he had, and that he took nothing from him.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>Mackenzey. This was at the Green-Man in Marybon-fields.</p>
               <p>Q. When was it?</p>
               <p>Mackenzey. I think it was before Christmas, I do not exactly know the time. I asked him what he thought to do in this affair ? he said, if he was paid for his day's work he had lost, and what expences he had been at in looking after him, he did not know but he might forgive him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner ever abscond?</p>
               <p>Mackenzey. He did his duty every day when it came to his turn, he was called upon the parade as an honest soldier, and never absconded a moment from the company.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-10-person74">
                  John 
                  Brooks 
               <interp inst="t17520514-10-person74" type="surname" value="Brooks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-10-person74" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-10-person74" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Between three weeks and a month ago, in the evening, the prisoner was going to his quarters, he was knocked down and used ill, and was obliged to be sent to the Regimental Hospital; the next evening after he came out he was going over the place again and this affair happened; after this, Mr. Pratt came to my room and made his complaint to me; I asked him, whether he thought the prisoner had really a mind to hurt him? he said, he really believed not: the <rs id="t17520514-10-deflabel49" type="occupation">soldier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-10-defend68 t17520514-10-deflabel49"></join> never missed being under arms twice a week, all the time, till he was taken up.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520514-10-verdict50" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520514-10-verdict50" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
