<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17580113-34">
               <interp inst="t17580113-34" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580113-34" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580113-34" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580113"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580113-34" type="date" value="17580113"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580113-34-off197-c353" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-34-defend414 t17580113-34-off197 t17580113-34-verdict202"></join>
         
               <p>100. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17580113-34-defend414" type="defendantName">
                     Lucy 
                     Roberts 
                  <interp inst="t17580113-34-defend414" type="surname" value="Roberts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-34-defend414" type="given" value="Lucy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-34-defend414" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17580113-34-deflabel196" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-34-defend414 t17580113-34-deflabel196"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17580113-34-off197" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580113-34-off197" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-34-off197" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               feloniously aiding and assisting, comforting and abetting, a person unknown, to commit a rape on the body of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17580113-34-victim416" type="victimName">
                           Ann 
                           Cooley 
                        <interp inst="t17580113-34-victim416" type="surname" value="Cooley"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580113-34-victim416" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580113-34-victim416" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-34-off197 t17580113-34-victim416"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17580113-34-viclabel198" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-34-victim416 t17580113-34-viclabel198"></join>
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17580113-34-cd199" type="crimeDate">Dec. 25</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-34-off197 t17580113-34-cd199"></join>.* </p>
               <p>Ann Cooley. The prisoner lives in <placeName id="t17580113-34-crimeloc200">Exeter-street, next door to the Blackmore's Head</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17580113-34-crimeloc200" type="placeName" value="Exeter-street, next door to the Blackmore's Head"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17580113-34-crimeloc200" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-34-off197 t17580113-34-crimeloc200"></join>. I had been a <rs id="t17580113-34-viclabel201" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-34-victim416 t17580113-34-viclabel201"></join> to her about a week. On Christmas day last she dressed me up in a blue and white linen gown with ruffled cuffs, and a round-ear'd cap, without a caul; this was about two o'clock in the day, I asked her what I was dressed up so for. She said I was to go into company to drink a glass of wine, when the ladies had any company. I said I was ashamed. About eight o'clock she call'd me up to her, into the back parlour; she bid me sit down, and made me drink three glasses of red stuff, I believe it was red port; About nine o'clock a young gentleman came and knock'd at the entry door, which always stands open. She came and called me into the entry to him. When he had look'd at me she bid me go in again. She went up stairs with him. The ladies were in company with four gentlemen. The prisoner soon came to me and bid me go up stairs. I had got up one stair, and was going to sit down, but she forced me up. When she had got me into the room she said, here is your girl, shut the door, went away, and the gentleman put a chair against it. There was a bed in the room, on which he bid me lie down, but I would not. He took me up in his arms, then flung me on the bed, took up my coats, and -</p>
               <p>Q. Did you cry out ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175801130055"></xptr>A. Cooley. I did; I did not consent to it, and made all the resistance I could, but I don't believe any body below stairs heard me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see that man before?</p>
               <p>A. Cooley. No never, he was a little man. He flung me half a guinea afterwards, and I would not take it, but flung it down on the ground. He came into the room again, and laid it on-the table. I went down in about half an hour after he was gone; being ashamed, was the occasion I did not go down sooner. I met the prisoner at the bottom of the stairs, and she asked me what the gentleman had given me; I did not tell her directly, but said nothing at all; at last I told her, but said I would not take it. She said, you must give it me, and when I was going to give it her, she took it out of my hand, and bid me say nothing to any body of what had been acted; and said, if I did, she would deny it. I staid there almost a week after this, and she wanted me to be dressed up again. I said would not. Then she turned me out at nine o'clock at night. I went and got me a lodging. The people where I was sent word to my mother where I might be found, and my father and my uncle came for me I was very bad, and my mother examined my body. I had a very bad distemper after this affair, and have it still very much.</p>
               <p>On her cross examination she said, her father and mother lived by London-Wall, that she left them without their knowledge and consent, and that she had been at the prisoner's house before she hired herself to her, and that the knew it to be a bad ho use before she went to live there.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17580113-34-verdict202" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580113-34-verdict202" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>She was sent to the hospital for a cure, and the house order'd to be indicted.</p>
            </div1>
