<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17540911-32">
               <interp inst="t17540911-32" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-32" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-32" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-32" type="date" value="17540911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540911-32-off178-c247" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-32-defend306 t17540911-32-off178 t17540911-32-verdict182"></join>
         
               <p>447. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17540911-32-defend306" type="defendantName">
                     Charles 
                     Fleming 
                  <interp inst="t17540911-32-defend306" type="surname" value="Fleming"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-32-defend306" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-32-defend306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17540911-32-off178" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540911-32-off178" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-32-off178" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he, on the king's highway, on 
                     <persName id="t17540911-32-victim307" type="victimName">
                        Eliz.
                         Hughes
                     <interp inst="t17540911-32-victim307" type="surname" value="Hughes"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540911-32-victim307" type="given" value="Eliz."></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540911-32-victim307" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-32-off178 t17540911-32-victim307"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , <rs id="t17540911-32-viclabel179" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-32-victim307 t17540911-32-viclabel179"></join>, did make an assault, putting her in corporal fear, and danger of her life, and one metal watch, val. 4 l. the property of the said Eliz. from her person did steal
            </rs>, &amp;c. <rs id="t17540911-32-cd180" type="crimeDate">Apr. 26</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-32-off178 t17540911-32-cd180"></join>.* </p> 
               <p>Eliz. Hughes. I was going from one <placeName id="t17540911-32-crimeloc181">Ealing</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17540911-32-crimeloc181" type="placeName" value="Ealing"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17540911-32-crimeloc181" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-32-off178 t17540911-32-crimeloc181"></join> to the other between seven and eight o'clock in the evening of the 26th of April. There came a man with a mask on. He asked me for my watch and money, and I delivered my watch and some money.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see his face ?</p>
               <p>E. Hughes. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. to Oroonoko. As you are a black, what religion are you of?</p>
               <p>Oroonoko. I have been in England these four years, and have always gone to church.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you been instructed in the christian religion?</p>
               <p>Oroonoko. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you believe in God?</p>
               <p>Oroonoko. I do, and his son Jesus Christ.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you instructed in the christian religion ?</p>
               <p>Oroonoko. From the pulpit, but I never was christened.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the nature of an oath?</p>
               <p>Oroonoko. Yes, I do, and should think myself obliged to speak the truth, or I should not go to heaven.</p>
               <p>He is sworn.</p>
               <p>Oroonoko. I am servant to Mrs. Hughes, and was<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175409110026"></xptr> with her when she was robbed. The man who robbed her had a mask on, but he passed by me twice without it. I had taken notice of his horse, and observed his great coat.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the prisoner at Mr. Fielding's?</p>
               <p>Oroonoko. I did. He is the man that passed by me in Ealing twice, and he is the man that robbed my mistress with a mask on. I am sure he rode the same horse also.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was it after you had seen him ride by that your mistress was robbed?</p>
               <p>Oroonoko. 'Twas about a quarter of an hour after.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you observe of the horse?</p>
               <p>Oroonoko. I observed he had fine legs. When he passed me the second time I looked the man in the face.</p>
               <p>Q. When was he taken ?</p>
               <p>Oroonoko. I don't know.</p>
               <p>Q. What coat had he on before the justice?</p>
               <p>Oroonoko. He had the same great coat on that he had before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the horse after that time?</p>
               <p>Oroonoko. No. But I knew him again when he came to the chariot side. I knew him directly.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is it since you saw him at Justice Fielding's?</p>
               <p>Oroonoko. 'Tis about a fortnight ago.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-32-person308">
                  Thomas 
                  Stockdale 
               <interp inst="t17540911-32-person308" type="surname" value="Stockdale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-32-person308" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-32-person308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner came our shop and offered this watch to pledge. [producing a metal one.]. He asked 36 shillings upon it. I shewed it to two or three gentlemen that came into my shop, and we talked about the dial-plate; it was a remarkable one, and instead of the twelve figures on it, there were the letters 
               <persName id="t17540911-32-person309">
                  EDWARD 
                  HUGHES 
               <interp inst="t17540911-32-person309" type="surname" value="HUGHES"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-32-person309" type="given" value="EDWARD"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-32-person309" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . While we were talking the prisoner went out, and left the watch behind. After that he sent me a letter and gave me descriptions of the watch, desiring me to send it by the next post.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutrix. Look at this watch. Do you know it?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. I have wore it three or four years. 'Tis my son's, and his name is round the dial-plate. This is the watch I was robbed of.</p>
               <p>Q. to Stockdale. When did he bring this watch to you?</p>
               <p>Stockdale. He brought it to me the first of August.</p>
               <p>Thomas Alderidge. I remember seeing the prisoner at Ealing last April, but can't say the day; I know it was the day. Mrs. Hughes was robbed.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any conversation with him there?</p>
               <p>Alderidge. I had. He asked me what house that was; I said, Captain Hughes's. He asked me whether he was in town, and whether they entertained any company there; I said, no.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was this?</p>
               <p>Alderidge. 'Twas about three in the afternoon.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know this was the day Mrs. Hughes was robbed?</p>
               <p>Alderidge. Because the coachman told me that day they had been robbed.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he on horseback, or on foot?</p>
               <p>Alderidge. He was on horseback, but I can't remember the horse.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he a great coat on?</p>
               <p>Alderidge. No, he had not. But he had one buckled behind him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him after this?</p>
               <p>Alderidge. Yes, I saw him at Justice Fielding's.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. What colour was his coat that was buckled behind him ?</p>
               <p>Alderidge. 'Twas of a darkish colour.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the colour of the coat he had on?</p>
               <p>Alderidge. 'Twas a dark blue grey. I think a close-bodied coat.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure he is the same man?</p>
               <p>Alderidge. I am.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know him when you saw him at the justice's?</p>
               <p>Alderidge. I did by his face.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to remember him so well?</p>
               <p>Alderidge. Because when I heard the coach was robbed, he was not then out of my memory.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-32-person310">
                  Peter 
                  Moley 
               <interp inst="t17540911-32-person310" type="surname" value="Moley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-32-person310" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-32-person310" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I remember that the day in the evening of which Mrs. Hughes was robbed I went into the King's Arms at Ealing between six and seven o'clock; there I saw the prisoner. He had a great coat on. He asked me where I lived, and who I worked for; I answered; that I worked for every family in the town. He said, Do you work for Captain Hughes? I answered, that I did; to-which he replied, that he knew him very well.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>Moley. I believe he got upon his horse to go away betwixt six and seven o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take notice of the horse?</p>
               <p>Moley. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Which way did he ride?</p>
               <p>Moley. Towards Brentford, and Mrs. Hughes's chariot was gone that way before. He asked, whose chariot it was, and I said, Captain Hughes's. I met the chariot in the lane after it had been robbed.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he a great coat on when he went away ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175409110027"></xptr>Moley. He had; the landlady helped him on with it. That was brought out of the stable with the horse.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I am not the person that did the robbery, neither do I know any of these faces that swear against me. My father lived at Kendal in Westmoreland; he is now living at Whitehaven. I have a brother a clergyman in Bedfordshire. I live with my father-in-law; he is a butcher.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-32-person311">
                  John 
                  Upton 
               <interp inst="t17540911-32-person311" type="surname" value="Upton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-32-person311" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-32-person311" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a victualler, and live in Oxford Road; I have known the prisoner above fifteen months, and never heard a bad character of him.</p>
               <p>Q. What is he?</p>
               <p>Upton. I took him to be a gentleman of a little fortune.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he live?</p>
               <p>Upton. In Swallow-street.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-32-person312">
                  Richard 
                  Beel 
               <interp inst="t17540911-32-person312" type="surname" value="Beel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-32-person312" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-32-person312" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Leeson Green, am a farmer, and have known the prisoner better than a year. I have often been in his company; he always behaved well; he was never extravagant; we all of us, neighbours, were fond of his company.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know how he gets his living?</p>
               <p>Beel. We took him to be a gentleman of a little fortune. We used to say, how agreeable it was to live so frugal as he did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-32-person313">
                  Daniel 
                  Eastmund 
               <interp inst="t17540911-32-person313" type="surname" value="Eastmund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-32-person313" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-32-person313" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Prince's-street, Cavendish-square, and have known the prisoner about fifteen months. I never heard any thing of him but that of a very civil young gentleman.</p>
               <p>Q. How does he get his livelihood ?</p>
               <p>Eastmund. I know nothing how he supplies himself. We took him to be a gentleman of a small fortune.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-32-person314">
                  Thomas 
                  Whitehead 
               <interp inst="t17540911-32-person314" type="surname" value="Whitehead"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-32-person314" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-32-person314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Princes-street, am a coach-maker. I believe I have known the prisoner above six months, and always took him to be a very civil gentleman. I used the house where he did, and never heard any thing but that of a civil man of him before this. I never saw him offer to be extravagant. He used to be publick in an open room.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does he live?</p>
               <p>Whitehead. I know not where he lives.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-32-person315">
                  John 
                  Bird 
               <interp inst="t17540911-32-person315" type="surname" value="Bird"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-32-person315" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-32-person315" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Cavendish-square, and have known the prisoner about four years. I was always fond to drink a glass of wine or bottle of beer with him. Every body that used the house where he did, were glad to be in his company. He behaved like a gentleman.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540911-32-verdict182" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540911-32-verdict182" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
