<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17550116-25">
               <interp inst="t17550116-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550116-25" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550116-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550116-25" type="date" value="17550116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550116-25-off131-c217" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-25-defend268 t17550116-25-off131 t17550116-25-verdict135"></join>
         
               <p>76. (M. 1.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17550116-25-defend268" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Moody 
                  <interp inst="t17550116-25-defend268" type="surname" value="Moody"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-defend268" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-defend268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, <rs id="t17550116-25-off131" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-off131" type="offenceCategory" value="breakingPeace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-off131" type="offenceSubcategory" value="wounding"></interp>
               for that he with a certain pistol, loaded with a leaden bullet, did wilfully and maliciously shoot off at 
                     <persName id="t17550116-25-victim269" type="victimName">
                        Rose 
                        Moody 
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-victim269" type="surname" value="Moody"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550116-25-victim269" type="given" value="Rose"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550116-25-victim269" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-25-off131 t17550116-25-victim269"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , his <rs id="t17550116-25-viclabel132" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-25-victim269 t17550116-25-viclabel132"></join>, in the dwelling-house of 
                     <persName id="t17550116-25-person270">
                        Constantine 
                        Phipps 
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-person270" type="surname" value="Phipps"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550116-25-person270" type="given" value="Constantine"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550116-25-person270" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , Esquire, with intent the said Rose to kill and murder
            </rs>, <rs id="t17550116-25-cd133" type="crimeDate">Jan. 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-25-off131 t17550116-25-cd133"></join>.* </p> 
               <p>Anne Russel. On the 2d of January, between nine and ten o'clock in the evening, the prisoner came up stairs into a room where I and his wife were, at Constantine Phipps, Esq; at <placeName id="t17550116-25-crimeloc134">Sion-hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17550116-25-crimeloc134" type="placeName" value="Sion-hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550116-25-crimeloc134" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-25-off131 t17550116-25-crimeloc134"></join> near Brentford, I live with a lady that is there, the prisoner's wife waits upon Mr. Phipps's lady, and he was principal servant there; he asked his wife why she did not go to bed? her answer was, she could not go for her lady was not in bed; she said, Moody, why don't you go to bed, you have got a nack of sitting up on nights, and my master is afraid you should fall asleep, and is afraid of an accident by fire, and she said she should let her master know it; he said he should not go to bed yet, for he had something else to do.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the words he had something else to do, or there was something else to do?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. He had something else to do. After that, she perceiving something in his breast, clapped her hand upon the top of it, she cried out, Mrs. Russel, Mrs. Russel, here are pistols, and immediately took hold on his waistcoat at the right-side collar, and tore either that or his shirt by pulling of him. I immediately went and laid hold on his left-arm, he strove with me and pushed me away; after that he catched hold on her left-arm, and said, d - n you, here is one for you, and the other for me; he had then a pistol in his hand, and immediately laid it down on the table, and took out the other; she was at the foot of the bed, he still having hold on her, she stooped her head down on the inside of the curtain, he struck the pistol over her head, I heard it snap, but I did not see the fire. I was then at one corner of the feet of the bed on the outside the curtain, which prevented my seeing it.</p>
               <p>Q. Then you do not know whether the pan flashed, or whether the cock went down only, do you?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. That I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. After you heard the cock go down, what was the next thing you observed?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. He immediately let go her arm, and cocked the pistol again.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him cock it?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. I saw him a cocking of it; she, as soon as he had let go her arm, ran round the back of him, and she and I both made our escape out of the room.</p>
               <p>Q. Which went out first?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. Really I can't tell that, there was a sort of a push at the door which of us should get out first, and the moment we were out of the door, I believe we had not got three steps out, before the pistol went off, we were about two yards in the passage from the door.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any body in the room at this time, except the prisoner and you two?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. No, there was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you smell any thing of smoak or fire?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. Both; and I heard and saw the flash of the pistol about my cloaths.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing where the ball went?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. The ball made a hole in the wainscot not half a quarter of a yard from the door, on the right-hand of it where it locks; the door opens to the left into the room.</p>
               <p>Q. Which way did the prisoner's wife run when you got into the passage?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. We turned on the left-hand in order to go down stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the door quite open after you were out ?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. His wife, at coming out, gave the door a little pull, which made it stand not quite open.</p>
               <p>Q. Which stairs did you attempt to go down? the great or back-stairs.</p>
               <p>A. Russel. The back-stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner follow you?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. He ran after us, and as we were upon the first landing-place on the back-stairs, Mrs. Moody being first, whether he came down any stairs, or whether he put his hand over the banisters I know not, but he there let off another pistol.</p>
         
               <p>The second Part of those Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17550116-25">
                  <interp inst="t17550116-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550116-25" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550116-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550116"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550116-25" type="date" value="17550116"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175501160021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY OF LONDON; And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Thursday the 16th, Friday the 17th, Saturday the 18th, Monday the 20th, and Tuesday the 21st of JANUARY.</p>
                  <p>In the Twenty-eighth Year of His MAJESTY'S Reign. NUMBER II. PART II. for the YEAR 1755. Being the Second SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of THE RIGHT HONOURABLE 
                  <persName id="t17550116-25-person271">
                     STEPHEN THEODORE 
                     JANSSEN 
                  <interp inst="t17550116-25-person271" type="surname" value="JANSSEN"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550116-25-person271" type="given" value="STEPHEN THEODORE"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550116-25-person271" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Esq; LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by M. COOPER at the Globe, in Pater-noster Row. 1755.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175501160022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery held for the City of LONDON, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Q. WAS he in such a position that he could see her?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. I cannot say where he stood, so I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a stair-case is it ?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. There are two landings.</p>
               <p>Q. How near might he be to you at the second fire?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. I cannot tell whether he was at the top, or nearer, because I did not see him.</p>
               <p>Q. Is there a door that shuts the passage up?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. There is, it shuts it up from the back-stairs, that door was open.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what became of the ball of the second pistol?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. I have it here, it was delivered to me by Mr. Vernon as such, I know nothing of this being it of my own knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any other person see any thing of this affair?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. 
               <persName id="t17550116-25-person272">
                  Elisabeth 
                  Lawson 
               <interp inst="t17550116-25-person272" type="surname" value="Lawson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-person272" type="given" value="Elisabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-person272" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came out of the next room to us in the mean time the first pistol was held over the prisoner's wife's heads. I was begging of him at the same time, saying, for heaven's sake, Mr. Moody, pray Mr. Moody don't.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is this 
               <persName id="t17550116-25-person273">
                  Elisabeth 
                  Lawson 
               <interp inst="t17550116-25-person273" type="surname" value="Lawson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-person273" type="given" value="Elisabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-person273" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. She is servant to Mr. Phipps.</p>
               <p>Q. Explain what you mean by holding over her head?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. She saw that, I did not.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell who of you two were first out of the room?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. I cannot tell of a certainty.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was you got at the time the first pistol went off?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. We might be got about two yards, or not quite so much.</p>
               <p>Q. You made use of an expression, be so good as to rehearse it; when she cried out, Mrs. Russel, Mrs. Russel, here are pistols?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. I immediately ran up to him, and she catched hold of his waistcoat at his collar.</p>
               <p>Council. It was after that.</p>
               <p>A. Russel. He said to his wife, here, d - n you, here is one for you, and another for me.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is that me?</p>
               <p>A. Russel, Meaning himself.</p>
               <p>Council for prosecution. How long is that passage before you come to the door?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. It is a pretty long passage, not so long as this court, but longer than the table ( which is about four yards long.)</p>
               <p>Council for defendant. When did you see the ball that struck against the wainscot?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. About an hour after, that same night.</p>
               <p>Q. How big was the hole it made in the wainscot?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. I believe I could put my two fingers in it?</p>
               <p>Q. How big was that ball?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. It was about the bigness of this I have here.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was that ball found you have in your hand?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. It fell between the wainscot and a post, it did not stick in the wall, but rebounded; the mark it made was on the second landing-place.</p>
               <p>Q. After the pistol was snapped, did you observe it to be primed again?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. He was cocking it when I left the room.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175501160023"></xptr>Q. Did you observe any smoke or fire at the first snapping?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Is the stair-case wainscoted?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. It is wall all the way down.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-25-person274">
                  Elisabeth 
                  Lawson 
               <interp inst="t17550116-25-person274" type="surname" value="Lawson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-person274" type="given" value="Elisabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-person274" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant in Mr. Phipps's family; I heard an expression of a pistol that night, being in the next room to where this disturbance was, I heard Mrs. Russel say, dear Mr. Moody, for heaven's sake; the doors being both open I ran to the door of the room where Mr. Moody and his wife were.</p>
               <p>C. Tell the court what you saw.</p>
               <p>E. Lawson. I saw Mr. Moody holding his wife.</p>
               <p>Q. How had he hold on her?</p>
               <p>E. Lawson. I can't tell, he presented a pistol to her, and she was with her head down behind the curtain; I heard it snap, and saw the fire also.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the pistol go off?</p>
               <p>E. Lawson. I believe it did not, I heard a little noise of a snap.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you perceive any smell?</p>
               <p>E. Lawson. I did not at all.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you see pass after that?</p>
               <p>E. Lawson. I shrieked, and ran along the landing-place towards the great stair-case, and heard the report of a pistol go off before I got to the top of the stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you perceive the smoak?</p>
               <p>E. Lawson. I did, it was a sort of a smoak following me.</p>
               <p>Q. What distance is the head of the great stairs from the door of the room you came out at?</p>
               <p>E. Lawson. About four yards; after this I went down stairs into the hall, there I met with my master.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any other explosion of a pistol?</p>
               <p>E. Lawson. I did not, I went from the hall to the parlour.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you give your master an account of what you saw and heard.</p>
               <p>E. Lawson. I cannot say I did, I was so affrighted.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you go with an intent to tell him?</p>
               <p>E. Lawson. I went with intent for help.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the place where that ball penetrated ?</p>
               <p>E. Lawson. I did, it was in the wainscot of the room.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was it to the door-case?</p>
               <p>E. Lawson. I never rightly examined it, I was much affrighted, and can't say how near.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the mark of any other ball?</p>
               <p>E. Lawson. I did, it was on the landing-place on the back-stairs by the window.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see either of the balls?</p>
               <p>E. Lawson. I saw them yesterday, and not before.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. You say upon hearing Mrs. Russel cry out, Moody's wife seemed to have her head down behind the curtain; did you see her face?</p>
               <p>E. Lawson. No, sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the curtain betwixt she and you?</p>
               <p>E. Lawson. He seemed to be next to me, the foot of the bed fronts the door where I was, I do not know which way she turned her face.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her head?</p>
               <p>E. Lawson. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Then how do you know he presented the pistol to her head?</p>
               <p>E. Lawson. I saw him holding his pistol presented thus (holding her elbow out, and her hand directed slanting downwards.)</p>
               <p>Q. Which part of the landing-place was the mark the ball made?</p>
               <p>E. Lawson. It was facing as you go down the first part of the stairs.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-25-person275">
                  Thomas 
                  Jeffling 
               <interp inst="t17550116-25-person275" type="surname" value="Jeffling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-person275" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-person275" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Phipps, so was the prisoner.</p>
               <p>C. Give my Lord an account whether you saw any mark or hole supposed to be made with a bullet.</p>
               <p>T. Jeffling. I saw a hole about a foot from the door-case in the room.</p>
               <p>Q. Which way does the door open?</p>
               <p>T. Jeffling. It opens into the room.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this hole on the right-side, or on the left ?</p>
               <p>T. Jeffling. It was on the right-side coming out of the room.</p>
               <p>Q. Has the ball been searched for?</p>
               <p>T. Jeffling. Yes, sir, the carpenter searched for it and found i t, I was by.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was it found?</p>
               <p>T. Jeffling. It was found upon the ground behind the wainscot, it had penetrated through it, and fell down behind, here it is ( producing one.)</p>
               <p>Q. Was the wainscot deal or oak ?</p>
               <p>T. Jeffling. It was oak.</p>
               <p>Q. How large was the hole ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175501160024"></xptr>T. Jeffling. It was as if bored with a large gimlet, and there were splinters broke from the hole.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was it before they went to search for the ball ?</p>
               <p>T. Jeffling. It was searched for last Wednesday night.</p>
               <p>Council for prosecution. Had you any time before that seen the hole in the wainscot?</p>
               <p>T. Jeffling. Yes, sir, I saw it in fifteen minutes after it was made, that is, the hole the ball was taken up behind.</p>
               <p>John Brown. (Produced a pair of pistols with barrels about eight inches) these I generally make use of, they are Mr. Phipps's; I am his servant, I was in the kitchen when this begun, the first I heard was the maid-servant shrieked out, I went forward into the servants hall, and almost to the bottom of the back-stairs, then I heard a pistol go off, I turned back again and went into the pantry, which is in the servants hall, to search for my pistols, or get something in my hand; I thought there were thieves in the house. I came out again, and went to the bags in the servants hall, where I had hung them. I then found they were both gone, then I went into the kitchen to a scullery there, then I heard the servants calling murder, then I imagined thieves were got into that part of the house, so I turned back again, and met one of the maids, and she mentioned something about Mr. Moody; the next I met with was my master, I imagined when I heard Mr. Moody's name, he had been mad, or something of that sort.</p>
               <p>Q. What reason had you to imagine he had been mad?</p>
               <p>J. Brown. I can't tell your lordship.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you observed any madness in any part of his behaviour before?</p>
               <p>J. Brown. He would drink pretty much sometimes.</p>
               <p>Q. How would he behave then?</p>
               <p>J. Brown. No way outrageous.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by drinking pretty much?</p>
               <p>J. Brown. I mean by that, that he would drink to excess.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you go, after you met your master?</p>
               <p>J. Brown. I went again into the servants hall, my master there desired me to take hold of Mr. Moody, who was in his own room, which is called the steward's room; I went into that room, there Mr. Moody was, leaning on his hand by the side of the door; he turned his back to me as soon as ever he saw me; I took hold of him, and turned him round, and held him by both his arms. Then I saw pistols lying on the right-hand going in, upon a shelf. I brought him out of that room, and some of the other servants got hold of him, and my master and we all went into the parlour. My lady was in a very great fright, and asked him if he was mad? He gave her some answer, but I don't know what. Then we brought him to the Coach-and-horses, a public-house near, and I was ordered to stay with him all that night.</p>

               <p>Q. Where did you meet with those pistols you have in your hand?</p>
               <p>J. Brown. I am not sure whether I took them out of the steward's room, or whether I found them in the pantry.</p>
               <p>Q. In what condition were they?</p>
               <p>J. Brown. The pans were open, and the cocks down.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take notice of those pistols that you saw on the shelf, that they were in that position?</p>
               <p>J. Brown. Yes, I did; I was close by them; two days before, to the best of my remembrance, I cleaned them, and dropped oil in the pans, drew the charges, and fired off some powder in the yard, and put them into the bags unloaded, and hung them up.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they appear when you first met with them, to have had any powder in them?</p>
               <p>J. Brown. I found them in the same position as I saw pistols in his room; I will not swear them to be these.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they appear to have been clean?</p>
               <p>J. Brown. They appeared as if they had been discharged.</p>
               <p>Q. What reason have you to say they had been discharged?</p>
               <p>J. Brown. The pans had powder over them, and the powder looked greenish, the oil being in the pans.</p>
               <p>Q. How did their muzzles appear?</p>
               <p>J. Brown. I did not put my finger into the muzzles, so I can't say as to that.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was very much in liquor, and did not know what I did.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175501160025"></xptr>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mr. Phipps. The prisoner has lived about nine years in my family as my principal servant; he had the total trust of every thing; he has behaved in the best manner in the world; but for some months past he has got into a habit of drinking, and not so careful as he used to be. He was always extremely honest; but not so diligent in my affairs.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any thing of lunacy or disorder of mind upon him, when he was sober ?</p>
               <p>Mr. Phipps. I can't say any thing at all of lunacy.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think he could distinguish between good and evil?</p>
               <p>Mr. Phipps. I think he could. I never saw any thing outrageous ? but at times seemed rather flushed with liquor.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-25-person276">
                  Richard 
                  Greening 
               <interp inst="t17550116-25-person276" type="surname" value="Greening"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-person276" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-person276" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner from the year 1733, lately I have been very intimate with him.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>R. Greening. The best of characters.</p>
               <p>Q. What's his temper?</p>
               <p>R. Greening. Always mild and meek.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen any alteration in him of late?</p>
               <p>R. Greening. Lately, since the family came out of Yorkshire, which is, I believe, about six weeks ago, I have observed he has had a little heaviness on his mind, and he has drank a little too freely.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you call heaviness on his mind?</p>
               <p>R. Greening. That is as if something grieved him. I think him to be quite a different man from what he was when he went into Yorkshire.</p>
               <p>Q. In what respect?</p>
               <p>R. Greening. In his drinking; and seemed, I thought, disturbed in his mind.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you been frequently in his company since his coming from Yorkshire?</p>
               <p>R. Greening. I have not seen him very often since.</p>
               <p>Q. How often?</p>
               <p>R. Greening. Six or seven times.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever observe any difference when he had not been drinking?</p>
               <p>R. Greening. No; only when he had been drinking.</p>
               <p>C. for prosecution. Then when he had not been drinking, he behaved like other men?</p>
               <p>R. Greening. Yes; only discontented, which was the reason of his drinking. He seemed lower in his spirits than he was before he went into Yorkshire, when he had not been drinking.</p>
               <p>Q. Will you venture to swear he was ever out of his senses?</p>
               <p>R. Greening. No; I will not undertake that, only discontented.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-25-person277">
                  Robert 
                  Greening 
               <interp inst="t17550116-25-person277" type="surname" value="Greening"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-person277" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-person277" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am his majesty's gardener at Kew. I believe I have been acquainted with the prisoner eighteen years at least; I have been very often in his company; he once lived in our family; he always behaved with great honesty and honour; I never, to my knowledge, saw him in liquor; he was always very chearful, till within these two years. I invited him some time ago to bring his wife to my house, out of respect to the family, he being an old servant. He brought her. After that, I asked him to come several times since, and he has been several times. This last Christmas he was at my house, I had the honour of seeing Mr. Phipps, who came along with him. I then pressed him to drink, as it was Christmas-time; but he would not; I believe he did not drink above two glasses that time. I never heard any man speak ill of him in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you lately observed any difference in his behaviour?</p>
               <p>R. Greening. I have; a discontentedness of mind; that time I speak of, last Christmas, he was very melancholy; I could hardly get a word out of him. And I remember, about three weeks ago, I met him coming out of Brentford on horseback, without a saddle, with his stockings about his heels; he had a little net, and a couple of carp in it. I asked him that day to dine with me; he said he could not, because he expected the family, and was about to get some fish.</p>
               <p>Q. How far might he be then from his home?</p>
               <p>R. Greening. I believe it was not quite half a mile. On my oath, to my opinion I have observed him much altered; he before seemed very chearful, and at those times I could hardly get a word out of him, especially that time at Christmas.</p>
               <p>Q. Should you, from the acquaintance you have had with him, conceive him capable of shooting a person, if he was in his right mind?</p>
               <p>R. Greening. I could never have thought it.</p>
               <p>C. for prosecution. Have you at any time thought him out of his mind, so as to be capable of doing such a thing?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175501160026"></xptr>R. Greening. It is impossible to judge of that; he did not act and behave as he used to do.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he give you sensible answers, when he did speak to you?</p>
               <p>R. Greening. He did; but would not speak freely, or be chearful.</p>
               <p>Q. Is that a token of his being out of his mind?</p>
               <p>R. Greening. I can't say that.</p>
               <p>Q. From what you observed of him, did you take him at any time to be a person out of his mind, and had not the right use of his understanding?</p>
               <p>R. Greening. I never took any notice of him, but that day I saw him was the first, to see a gentleman's steward in such a condition, without a saddle, and his stockings down, and the like.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was that?</p>
               <p>R. Greening. I believe it was between nine and ten in the morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you believe he was sober then?</p>
               <p>R. Greening. I sincerely believe he was.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-25-person278">
                  William 
                  Howel 
               <interp inst="t17550116-25-person278" type="surname" value="Howel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-person278" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-person278" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him, I believe, about six years, and have seen him frequently in that time.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>W. Howel. His character is as good as ever I heard; I believe he never did an ill thing but this in his life.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his temper?</p>
               <p>W. Howel. His temper is exceeding good.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen any difference in him of late?</p>
               <p>W. Howel. He was at my house twice since he came out of Yorkshire; I think the first time was about three weeks or a month ago; he was very much in liquor in the morning about ten o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen him sober since he came out of Yorkshire?</p>
               <p>W. Howel. He called another time after that; he seemed then to be in liquor, but not quite so much. I can't say I have seen him sober since he came out of Yorkshire.</p>
               <p>Q. How often have you seen him since he came out of Yorkshire?</p>
               <p>W. Howel. I have seen him but twice.</p>
               <p>C. for prosecution. Do you apprehend him to be out of his senses, any farther than liquor has made an alteration?</p>
               <p>W. Howel. I do not know really.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-25-person279">
                  Thomas 
                  Porter 
               <interp inst="t17550116-25-person279" type="surname" value="Porter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-person279" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-person279" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about three or four years; I thought he behaved as well as any man in England till he came out of Yorkshire; I have been in his company but once since, and that was at Charing-cross; he was in a very deplorable manner, as I thought; I asked him some questions more than once or twice; I could get but one word of answer from him, and then I thought him very much in liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was this?</p>
               <p>T. Porter. This was about ten in the morning.</p>
               <p>Mr. M'Culloch. I have known him almost twenty years; I have seen him a great many times; his character is exceeding good, none better.</p>
               <p>Q. How is he as to temper?</p>
               <p>Mr. M'Culloch. I never saw him out of temper in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen him lately?</p>
               <p>Mr. M'Culloch. No, I have not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-25-person280">
                  John 
                  Parker 
               <interp inst="t17550116-25-person280" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-person280" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-person280" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , one of the jury. I know something of the prisoner; may I be sworn now, and tell it before my brother jurymen go out?</p>
               <p>Court. Swear him. (He is sworn.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-25-person281">
                  John 
                  Parker 
               <interp inst="t17550116-25-person281" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-person281" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-person281" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I think, to the best of my knowledge, about a fortnight before Christmas, I was in Litchfield-street, which leads from the end of St. Martin's-lane, towards Graston-street, the prisoner at the bar came riding along, I thought a good deal confused, his cloaths were dirty as if he had fell from his horse. I asked him how he did? he said, his horse had fell with him at Hyde-park corner; I think I asked him where he was going, he said, home, which I imagined to be Burlington-street, where Esquire Phipps lives, when in town. I wondered much at seeing him come that way, which was quite out of his way from Hyde-park corner to Burlington-street.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he appear to be in liquor?</p>
               <p>J. Parker. I did apprehend he might be in liquor?</p>
               <p>Q. from a juryman. We want to know whether there was ever any quarrel between the prisoner and his wife?</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17550116-25-person282">
                  Anne 
                  Russel 
               <interp inst="t17550116-25-person282" type="surname" value="Russel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-person282" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-person282" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . How long have you been in Mr. Phipps's family?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. About two years.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe during that time any uneasiness betwixt the prisoner and his wife?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. I always thought the prisoner to be a very honest good-natured sort of a man, till about a year and half ago, then he became brutish; I can't say he has used her well at all since that time; if I speak the truth, I can say no other, he has used her very ill at times.</p>
               <p>Q. How used her ill?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. He used to give her bad language.</p>
               <p>Q. What did that purport?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175501160027"></xptr>A. Russel. He used to call her names.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any provocation given by the wife for that language?</p>
               <p>A. Russel. No, my lord, far from it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17550116-25-verdict135" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-verdict135" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17550116-25-punish136" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550116-25-punish136" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-25-defend268 t17550116-25-punish136"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
