<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17580913-29">
               <interp inst="t17580913-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-29" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580913"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-29" type="date" value="17580913"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580913-29-off147-c210" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-29-defend263 t17580913-29-off147 t17580913-29-verdict149"></join>
         
               <p>286. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17580913-29-defend263" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Fish 
                  <interp inst="t17580913-29-defend263" type="surname" value="Fish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-29-defend263" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-29-defend263" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17580913-29-off147" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580913-29-off147" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-29-off147" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one iron scale-beam, value 3 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17580913-29-victim265" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Gibson 
                        <interp inst="t17580913-29-victim265" type="surname" value="Gibson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580913-29-victim265" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580913-29-victim265" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-29-off147 t17580913-29-victim265"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately in his warehouse
            </rs>, <rs id="t17580913-29-cd148" type="crimeDate">August 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-29-off147 t17580913-29-cd148"></join>.* </p>
               <p>Robert Gibson. I live in Leather-lane Holborn, I have a house a repairing, we do not live in it, but make use of it as a warehouse; I lost an iron scale-beam out of it, worth 3 l. between the 23d and 24th of August. I advertised it a guinea reward; the prisoner at the bar came and asked me if I did not lose such a scale-beam, I told him I had, he told me if I would give him fifteen shillings I should have it again. I agreed to give him that money, I went along with him, I asked him which way he came by it; he told me a man brought it to him; but he could not tell me who he was, nor where he lived, but said he look'd like a countryman, in his own hair.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you mention in your advertisement, that the man should not be prosecuted?</p>
               <p>Gibson. No, I did not. I took him before the justice to have him examined, he would not own any thing; but said he believed he could find the man.</p>

               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he had let the man have 10 s. that brought it?</p>
               <p>Gibson. He did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-29-person266">
                  George 
                  Bethel 
               <interp inst="t17580913-29-person266" type="surname" value="Bethel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-29-person266" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-29-person266" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This day three weeks, I was coming down Chick-lane, between 5 and 6 o'clock, the prisoner call'd after me, and said he would give me a pint; he and I, and his wife, drank a pint together: he told me he had a jobb for me to do, and he would call me in the morning to do it; he did, I got up, he took me in Leather-lane with him, and stoped at a house, and said I have<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175809130024"></xptr> bought a scale-beam here, and if you will get up I will tell you where it is; he lifted me up to a window and shewed me where to give it him out; I gave it him: he asked me if I could not give him out any thing else? I said, there was nothing but a glue-pot, a carpenter's ax, and a bag, which I gave him; he took the beam and the rest of the things to his own house, and told me to come to his house at night, and he would pay me for my trouble; I went, he gave me 5 s. and 6 d. I gave him a pint of beer, and he would be a pint with me; then I call'd for another, and I paid the 4 d. halfpeny.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-29-person267">
                  Robert 
                  Caple 
               <interp inst="t17580913-29-person267" type="surname" value="Caple"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-29-person267" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-29-person267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner came to my house, and told me he had a scale-beam to dispose of, on the 26th of August.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he not say which way he came by it?</p>
               <p>Caple. No, he did not. I went and look'd at it, but said it would not suit me.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>Caple. I am a scale-beam maker.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-29-person268">
                  Robert 
                  Griffin 
               <interp inst="t17580913-29-person268" type="surname" value="Griffin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-29-person268" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-29-person268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Turnmill-street, at an Gronmonger's, named Wilkerson; I remember this man (meaning the evidence) Bethel, he brought a scale-beam wrapped up in a cloth to Mr. Fish's, and left it there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Fish give him any money?</p>
               <p>Griffin. There was something mentioned about half a guinea betwixt them.</p>
               <p>Bethel. The prisoner gave me half a guinea at the Raven in Chick-lane to change.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-29-person269">
                  James 
                  Eadey 
               <interp inst="t17580913-29-person269" type="surname" value="Eadey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-29-person269" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-29-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about 14 months, he did live in Chick-lane; he buys and sells old iron.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character?</p>
               <p>Eadey. He always appear'd to me to be a poor honest man.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Eadey. I live in Clerkenwell.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-29-person270">
                  John 
                  Thomas 
               <interp inst="t17580913-29-person270" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-29-person270" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-29-person270" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner between 5 and 6 months; I always took him to be an honest industrious man. I have lent him some pounds to carry on trade, which he has paid me very honestly; was he out now, I would lend him 20 l.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-29-person271">
                  Henry 
                  Feather 
               <interp inst="t17580913-29-person271" type="surname" value="Feather"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-29-person271" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-29-person271" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about half a year, I never heard any ill of him; he is a housekeeper, and lives in credit, and bears the character of an honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-29-person272">
                  Patrick 
                  Carrol 
               <interp inst="t17580913-29-person272" type="surname" value="Carrol"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-29-person272" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-29-person272" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him between 3 and 4 months; I have dealt with him, and always found him just and honest in his dealings.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-29-person273">
                  John 
                  Bennet 
               <interp inst="t17580913-29-person273" type="surname" value="Bennet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-29-person273" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-29-person273" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him half a year; he is a hard-working industrious man, who works early and late.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17580913-29-verdict149" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580913-29-verdict149" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
