<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17501017-34">
               <interp inst="t17501017-34" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501017-34" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501017-34" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17501017"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501017-34" type="date" value="17501017"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17501017-34-off164-c232" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-34-defend294 t17501017-34-off164 t17501017-34-verdict166"></join>
         
               <p>654. 
               
                  <persName id="t17501017-34-defend294" type="defendantName">
                     Eleanor 
                     Digsby 
                  <interp inst="t17501017-34-defend294" type="surname" value="Digsby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-34-defend294" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-34-defend294" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17501017-34-deflabel163" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-34-defend294 t17501017-34-deflabel163"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17501017-34-off164" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501017-34-off164" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-34-off164" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing one linen bag, value one penny; one half guinea, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17501017-34-victim296" type="victimName">
                           Andrew 
                           Saunders 
                        <interp inst="t17501017-34-victim296" type="surname" value="Saunders"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17501017-34-victim296" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17501017-34-victim296" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-34-off164 t17501017-34-victim296"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   from his person secretly and without his knowledge
            </rs>, <rs id="t17501017-34-cd165" type="crimeDate">October 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-34-off164 t17501017-34-cd165"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501017-34-person297">
                  Andrew 
                  Saunders 
               <interp inst="t17501017-34-person297" type="surname" value="Saunders"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-34-person297" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-34-person297" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 5th of this month I was coming from Kensington to London, I went into a publick house and drank two or three pints of beer, this woman happened to be in the same house; dropping into company I staid longer than ordinary; I pulled my money out at that house and said I was going to London to buy me a new hat; I went from thence to the halfway house betwixt that place and Knightsbridge; there I drank part of two or three pints of beer; finding myself a little later than ordinary I had a mind to go back again ; I went back again to the house in Kensington where I came from; there I put my hand into my pocket for my bag and half guinea, but could find neither; the landlord was gone out; the prisoner came in with the bag and half guinea; I can swear to the bag; she was in company with me when I lost it, and when I came back the pretended to go along with me to take care of me.</p>
               <p>Q. What time do you count you lost it?</p>
               <p>Saunders. between eight and nine o'clock at night; then she gave me the drop.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you perceive the woman put her hand towards your pocket?</p>
               <p>Saunders. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. How came she to be thus long in your company?</p>
               <p>Saunders. I cannot tell that, I never saw her in my life before.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober?</p>
               <p>Saunders. I was very sober.</p>
               <p>James Hill. I keep the Thistle and Crown at Kensington. This woman works in the king's ground; the prosecutor came into my house to drink a pint of beer, and she came to ask my wife to trust her for a halfpenny worth of gin; the man owed me a shilling, over night he pulled out a bag with a half guinea and some silver in it; I saw him put the bag into his pocket before he went out of my house. After that I went to Smithfield; when I came home this woman came into my house and asked for a pint of hot; my wife went and made it; then she wanted change for a half guinea; some of my lodgers said, such a man was robbed of a half guinea on the road; I locked the door and kept her in custody, and sent for the prosecutor; he came; we sent for a constable and searched her and found this purse upon her (it was<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175010170024"></xptr> produc'd in court, the prosecutor depos'd to it: in the struggle the half guinea fell from her; but we never saw it after that; before the Justice she said, she found it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prosecutor sober when he went out of your house, to go towards London?</p>
               <p>Hill. I believe he was not in liquor.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was in that gentleman's house; I call'd for a pennyworth of beer, but I never drank with the man; I was coming along towards Knightsbridge ; this man came along and said, dame will you go and drink? I said, I had no money; he gave me part of three pints of beer, and a quartern of gin; then he insisted on my going back with him again, to see him safe home ; going along, he wanted to lie with me; he wanted to give me some money, and I would not take it; and after the struggle, I found this bag in the high road.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17501017-34-verdict166" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501017-34-verdict166" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
