<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17500530-39">
               <interp inst="t17500530-39" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500530-39" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500530-39" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17500530"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500530-39" type="date" value="17500530"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500530-39-off181-c201" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500530-39-defend279 t17500530-39-off181 t17500530-39-verdict183"></join>
         
               <p>410. 
               
                  <persName id="t17500530-39-defend279" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Williams 
                  <interp inst="t17500530-39-defend279" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-39-defend279" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-39-defend279" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17500530-39-off181" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500530-39-off181" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-39-off181" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch, value 5 l. one silver seal, value 12 d. from the person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17500530-39-victim281" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           English 
                        <interp inst="t17500530-39-victim281" type="surname" value="English"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500530-39-victim281" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500530-39-victim281" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500530-39-off181 t17500530-39-victim281"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , secretly, without his knowledge
            </rs>, <rs id="t17500530-39-cd182" type="crimeDate">May 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500530-39-off181 t17500530-39-cd182"></join>.</p>
               <p>The prosecutor depos'd, he lost his watch the 15th of May, betwixt three and four o'clock. A watch was produced in court with the maker's name, Herring, on the dial plate, but the name and number on the works ras'd out. He said, he believed it to be his, but could not swear to it: saying the greatest reason he had to believe it was his, was certain marks on the outside case, where he used to open it with his teeth, he having but one hand, and that he advertised it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500530-39-person282">
                  Thomas 
                  Bibby 
               <interp inst="t17500530-39-person282" type="surname" value="Bibby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-39-person282" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-39-person282" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 24th of May, the man that keeps the black dog in Drury-lane, (I think his name is Scott,) brought this watch to pawn to me. I saw the name and number ras'd out. I would not lend any money upon it. I saw in the papers, there was one advertis'd in the name of Herring, and I saw the same on the dial-plate of this. I sent for Mr. Herring; the man at the black dog said he had it of one Bignal, who was going to sell it to him, so he went and brought Bignal. Bignal said he had had it three months, and it was lost but the 14th of May, and that he had before had it in pawn with one Mr. Harrison. I took the watch to Mr. Harrison, and he said that was not it which he had had.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500530-39-person283">
                  Mary 
                  Bignal 
               <interp inst="t17500530-39-person283" type="surname" value="Bignal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-39-person283" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-39-person283" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The first of May, the prisoner brought me a watch to sell, which is this very watch. She ow'd me twenty eight shillings, which she had borrow'd out of my pocket. I told her, I would not buy the watch, without she would tell me how she came by it, she said it was her husband's. I offer'd it that very night to 
               <persName id="t17500530-39-person284">
                  James 
                  Smart 
               <interp inst="t17500530-39-person284" type="surname" value="Smart"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-39-person284" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-39-person284" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             for sale, he bought it, but did not take it into possession untill the 12th day of the month; he gave me half a guinea in part of payment, and was to pay me at half a guinea a fortnight, but my husband and his wife had some words, he happened to come in upon that, his wife made him give me the watch again, and I return'd the half guinea. This was Tuesday was sevennight. There was another man about the watch, before Mr. Smart had it. Then Mr. Scott, at the black dog, had it of me, and the next night he agreed with me for three pound. He told me he would not pay the money for it, till he had it twenty-four hours upon trial; he not having the money to pay me, as far as I understand, he went and pawn'd it.</p>
               <p>Q. What business do you follow?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175005300019"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17500530-39-person285">
                  Mary 
                  Bignal 
               <interp inst="t17500530-39-person285" type="surname" value="Bignal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-39-person285" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-39-person285" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a sort of a broker's shop, and a rag shop.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500530-39-person286">
                  Joseph 
                  Herring 
               <interp inst="t17500530-39-person286" type="surname" value="Herring"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-39-person286" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-39-person286" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I sold Mr. English a watch the 10th of November, 1748. for five guineas, No 1090. as the name and number are fil'd out of this, I will not swear it is the watch I sold him. I know it is one of my make.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500530-39-person287">
                  Dennis 
                  Murphy 
               <interp inst="t17500530-39-person287" type="surname" value="Murphy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-39-person287" type="given" value="Dennis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-39-person287" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Headborough, I was charg'd with the prisoner, and had her before Sir Samuel Gore over night, then the prisoner said, she knew nothing of the watch, I carry'd her to the watch-house, and lock'd her up till morning, then I had her before the Justice again; then she said, she found the watch on May day in the morning at the bottom of Well close-square. The first time she came from the Justice's, Mr. and Mrs. Bignal were there, I ask'd Mr. Bignal, how long he had had that watch ? he said he had had it six months in his custody; the woman contradicted that, and said it was but three months; he said, hold your tongue, if you will be rul'd by me, I will save the watch and woman too.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500530-39-person288">
                  James 
                  Smart 
               <interp inst="t17500530-39-person288" type="surname" value="Smart"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-39-person288" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-39-person288" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I rent a lower apartment of Mr. Bignal, last Friday was fortnight, I should have paid the last half guinea for this watch; Mrs. Bignal said to me, I have got a Loach for you; when she shew'd it me, there was the name Herring and number withinside, and a small silver seal with a bird and branch; and after that, when it was deliver'd to me last Friday was fortnight, the name and number were then fil'd out. I put a ribbon on it, the same that is now, and I went afterwards for the seal Mrs. Bignal said, she would make a move of that. I went down to a pawn-broker, and ask'd him what he would lend upon it, he said he would not take the watch in his pocket for ever so much, for fear of coming into trouble by the name being done out. Said my wife, get rid of it if you can. I went home, Mr. Bignal and his wife were quarrelling. She came running into my shop, my wife ran betwixt them; then said my wife, if you don't deliver the watch, and take the half guinea, I'll stamp it to pieces. So I deliver'd it up last Thursday was a week.</p>
               <p>Q to 
               <persName id="t17500530-39-person289">
                  Mary 
                  Bignal 
               <interp inst="t17500530-39-person289" type="surname" value="Bignal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-39-person289" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-39-person289" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Is your husband here?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500530-39-person290">
                  Mary 
                  Bignal 
               <interp inst="t17500530-39-person290" type="surname" value="Bignal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-39-person290" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-39-person290" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . No, he is not, my Lord.</p>

               <p>Q. Was the name and number on the inside of the watch when you bought it?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500530-39-person291">
                  Mary 
                  Bignal 
               <interp inst="t17500530-39-person291" type="surname" value="Bignal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-39-person291" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-39-person291" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . No, my Lord, it was not.</p>
               <p>Smart. Upon my oath they were.</p>
               <p>The prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I deal in old cloaths. Last May day in the morning, I went into Sugar-house yard to make water. I sat down, and I saw a watch lying by me, I took it up, there was another woman along with me, she and I went both to Mr. Bignal's in the morning. I said, glory be to God, I had got something that would get me bread for my poor children. I sold it to her for a guinea and a half. When I was before the Justice, the man would not swear me.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500530-39-verdict183" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500530-39-verdict183" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
