<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17580628-17">
               <interp inst="t17580628-17" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580628-17" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580628-17" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580628"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580628-17" type="date" value="17580628"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580628-17-off92-c128" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580628-17-defend155 t17580628-17-off92 t17580628-17-verdict95"></join>
         
               <p>235. (M). 
               <persName id="t17580628-17-defend155" type="defendantName">
                  Anne, <rs id="t17580628-17-deflabel91" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580628-17-defend155 t17580628-17-deflabel91"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17580628-17-person156">
                        John 
                        Donnolly 
                     <interp inst="t17580628-17-person156" type="surname" value="Donnolly"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580628-17-person156" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580628-17-person156" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
                     <interp inst="t17580628-17-defend155" type="surname" value="Donnolly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-17-defend155" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-17-defend155" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17580628-17-off92" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580628-17-off92" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-17-off92" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing five pewter plates, value 2 s. one copper saucepan val. 10 d.
            </rs> the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17580628-17-victim158" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Malsby 
                  <interp inst="t17580628-17-victim158" type="surname" value="Malsby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-17-victim158" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-17-victim158" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580628-17-off92 t17580628-17-victim158"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17580628-17-cd93" type="crimeDate">May 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580628-17-off92 t17580628-17-cd93"></join>. *</p>
               <p>Han. Malsby. I can only say the goods are mine.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you miss them?</p>
               <p>H. Malsby. I missed them the 23d of May last, about half an hour after eight o'clock in the morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you a husband ?</p>
               <p>H. Malsby. I have; his name is William.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see the prisoner in your house?</p>
               <p>H. Malsby. No, never to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>H. Malsby. I live at <placeName id="t17580628-17-crimeloc94">Fulham</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17580628-17-crimeloc94" type="placeName" value="Fulham"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17580628-17-crimeloc94" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580628-17-off92 t17580628-17-crimeloc94"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580628-17-person159">
                  John 
                  Taafe 
               <interp inst="t17580628-17-person159" type="surname" value="Taafe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-17-person159" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-17-person159" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodge at the prosecutor's house; I got up in the morning, and went for some rolls for her breakfast and mine.</p>
               <p>Q. What day?</p>
               <p>Taafe. I cannot tell the day of the month.</p>
               <p>Q. What month?</p>
               <p>Taafe. It was in May, I believe the 23d of May, but I cannot be exact. When I came back with the rolls, she went towards the pantry, and returned directly, and said she was robbed of some plates, and desired me to step down the town to see if I could see any body with such things.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175806280019"></xptr>Q. What house does the prosecutrix keep, a public or private one?</p>
               <p>Taafe. It is the Black Bull, a publick house; I went, and returned, and said, I saw no such person. About an hour or two after, she called to me, and said she heard a woman had been selling her plates at Putney, and desired me to go there to (I think) the Fox and Hounds. I went, and took a waterman with me to the two houses, the Fox and Hounds, and also the Hare and Hounds. The landlady of one of the houses (I cannot tell which) said, there was a woman there that had sold some plates, and had been gone from her house about half an hour; but if I would go up higher in the town, perhaps, I might find her there. The waterman and I went, and were told they had seen a woman go by about a quarter, or half an hour before, we went on to Putney Bowling Green; there I asked if they had seen a woman with a red cloak and red gown on, go by, (she having been described so to me) they said yes, and shewed me which road she took, we went a little farther, and there saw a woman sitting on the ground, the prisoner at the bar; I asked her if she was the woman that stole the plates at the Bull at Fulham, she said no. I said she was the woman that had been described to me, that had stole some plates there; so I brought her along with me to the Black Bull at Fulham.</p>
               <p>Q. Had she any thing upon her when you took her?</p>
               <p>Taafe. No, she had nothing at all, she had a red sort of a gown, and a red cloak on.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580628-17-person160">
                  Thomas 
                  Terry 
               <interp inst="t17580628-17-person160" type="surname" value="Terry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-17-person160" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-17-person160" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming from Richmond-Park, I think it was on the 23d of May, I called at the Fox and Hounds at Putney, and had some beer; I saw this woman at the bar (I believe it is the same) she is not dressed now as she was then. She was sitting on a bench crying, she had sold five plates to one 
               <persName id="t17580628-17-person161">
                  George 
                  Duck 
               <interp inst="t17580628-17-person161" type="surname" value="Duck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-17-person161" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-17-person161" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who is a shuffling fellow, and she said he had got them, and had ran away with them from her, and would not pay her. I went after him, and took the plates from him, and brought them back to her, and gave them to her. She had got a letter she said from her husband, at the Isle of Wight, directing her to go there to him, she cryed and said, she had not a farthing in the world: she said she had a dozen of those plates in all, that her mother had se her out of the country a great way off. I believe Mrs. Whetstone asked her questions for a quarter of an hour, to know whether she had stole them or not; by her answers we thought them to be her own. She said she must sell those to carry her down to her husband. Then it was put to about four or five of us to know the value of them, and I bought them of her at the door.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you give her for them?</p>
               <p>Terry. I gave her 18 d. for them, and a pot of beer; there was a saucepan found afterwards, which she sold at the Hare and Hounds, (five plates produced in court and deposed to by the prosecutrix.)</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. Mrs. Miller at the Hare and Hounds bought the saucepan of the prisoner at the bar for 10 d. She was here yesterday, but on account of her business, could not attend to-day; (the saucepan produced and deposed to.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580628-17-person162">
                  Andrew 
                  Forrest 
               <interp inst="t17580628-17-person162" type="surname" value="Forrest"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-17-person162" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-17-person162" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going over to breakfast at the Fox and Hounds at Putney, between eight and nine in the morning, there was the woman at the bar sitting at the door, with the plates in her hand; after that I went to Fulham, there the prosecutrix told me she had lost some plates. I told her I had seen a woman at the Fox and Hounds door at Putney, with five plates; by that means they got intelligence of, and took the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was to go to the Isle of White to my husband, when I was got part of the way from Putney, the men came and brought me back, and said there were five plates lost, but I know nothing at all of the matter.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Eleaner Dudgen. The prisoner lived three years servant with me, and behaved very well, none better; I had a good character with her, I never heard any harm of her before she was charged with this fact; I would employ her again was she at liberty.  <rs id="t17580628-17-verdict95" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580628-17-verdict95" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17580628-17-punish96" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580628-17-punish96" type="punishmentCategory" value="corporal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-17-punish96" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="whipping"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580628-17-defend155 t17580628-17-punish96"></join>
               
                     <note>[Whipping. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
