<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17500912-11">
               <interp inst="t17500912-11" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500912-11" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500912-11" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17500912"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500912-11" type="date" value="17500912"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500912-11-off52-c69" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-11-defend88 t17500912-11-off52 t17500912-11-verdict55"></join>
         
               <p>513. 
               
                  <persName id="t17500912-11-defend88" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Wright 
                  <interp inst="t17500912-11-defend88" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-11-defend88" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-11-defend88" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for that <rs id="t17500912-11-off52" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500912-11-off52" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-11-off52" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he, together with two other persons not yet taken, on the king's high way, upon 
                     
                        <persName id="t17500912-11-victim90" type="victimName">
                           Charles 
                           Coleman 
                        <interp inst="t17500912-11-victim90" type="surname" value="Coleman"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500912-11-victim90" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500912-11-victim90" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-11-off52 t17500912-11-victim90"></join>
                     </persName>
                     
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, one hat, val. 2 s. one perriwig, val. 1 s. and one shilling in money, numbred, from his person and against his will, did steal, take, and carry away
            </rs>, <rs id="t17500912-11-cd53" type="crimeDate">Sept. 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-11-off52 t17500912-11-cd53"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-11-person91">
                  Charles 
                  Coleman 
               <interp inst="t17500912-11-person91" type="surname" value="Coleman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-11-person91" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-11-person91" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Saturday was sen'night in the Morning I was <placeName id="t17500912-11-crimeloc54">coming from Moorfields, facing Bedlam gate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17500912-11-crimeloc54" type="placeName" value="coming from Moorfields, facing Bedlam gate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17500912-11-crimeloc54" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-11-off52 t17500912-11-crimeloc54"></join>, the prisoner stop'd me. There were two other men with him, they got behind me; he took my hat and wig and toss'd them to the other men; after that he put his left hand to my left hand pocket, and took out a shilling. After he had put his hand in my pocket some time, the others put my wig before my eyes; then I said, gentlemen, you have no occasion to blind me, I have but one shilling about me, and if it was ten times as much I would give it you; then they ordered me to go along, and not to come or look back. Then when I was got from them, I called to a watchman to come to my assistance, and after that another; but they did not care to go with me after them. Then came Mr. Chennery to go over the fields, I told him if he did, he would be robb'd as I had been. He said he must go across the fields. I called to some more watchmen and told them the affair; one of them had got a sailor's jacket on; I asked him to lend it me to put on, that the men might not know me again; he did, and put on my coat; then one of them lent me a hat, but none of them would lend me a staff. Mr. Chennery said he would go along with me. We went together, and the watchmen followed us. When I came betwixt the posts, I saw them all three sitting upon the Wall that parts the middle fields from the quarters. When I came near them, I pull'd the jacket by the fore parts, and pulled it close round me, and held my head down; they asked us what we wanted; Mr. Chennery said money and manners; he repeated it twice. I knew the prisoner to be the man that stood before me, and robb'd me, as soon as I saw him again; then they said, can't we sit here upon the wall for all you. Mr. Chennery said, and can't we stand here for all you. They began then to whistle, and the other two jump'd from the wall and run away. Then said I to the prisoner you are the man that robbed me, and you shall not go if the others do. Then I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175009120005"></xptr> took hold of him, and left him to the care of Mr. Chinnery, while I ran after the others. When I came back, they were both on the ground together, having had a Scuffle; then the Watchmen came up, and they took him to the watchhouse. I ran over the fields after the other two, but could not find them; it was a moon light night, and there were six lamps round the place; I am very certain he is the man that robb'd me; he was taken in less than a quarter of an hour after he robb'd me. He was searched in the watch-house, and a single shilling was found in his pocket; there were no arms found upon him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-11-person92">
                  Charles 
                  Chennery 
               <interp inst="t17500912-11-person92" type="surname" value="Chennery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-11-person92" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-11-person92" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed to the same of their taking him, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence. I was going up Grubstreet between 10 and 11 o'clock, and met a gentleman like man that seemed to be in liquor; he asked me the way to Bishopsgate-street; I told him he was going wrong, saying he must go back again. He asked me to shew him the way, I did not much care to go along with him; he said if I would, he should be obliged to me. I went with him; he asked me to drink part of a pot of beer. We went to Skinner-street, and drank four full pots of beer together. When I parted with him it was betwixt 12 and 1 o'clock. I was coming home. I had occasion to ease myself under the wall in Moorfields. There came three or four Men, and looked over the wall; up came my prosecutor, and two or three more. I asked what they wanted; they said money and manners. I said I had no money. Then the prosecutor said to me, you are the man that robb'd me; and insisted I had got a pistol about me. They searched me, and found nothing upon me. I lost 5 d. out of my pocket.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500912-11-verdict55" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500912-11-verdict55" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>
                  <rs id="t17500912-11-punish56" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500912-11-punish56" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-11-defend88 t17500912-11-punish56"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
