<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17511204-44">
               <interp inst="t17511204-44" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511204-44" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511204-44" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17511204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511204-44" type="date" value="17511204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17511204-44-off255-c348" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511204-44-defend440 t17511204-44-off255 t17511204-44-verdict258"></join>
         
               <p>55. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17511204-44-defend440" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Still 
                  <interp inst="t17511204-44-defend440" type="surname" value="Still"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-44-defend440" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-44-defend440" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17511204-44-off255" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17511204-44-off255" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-44-off255" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               ripping and stealing 200 pounds weight of lead, val. 14 s. fixed to a certain empty house belonging to 
                     
                        <persName id="t17511204-44-victim442" type="victimName">
                           Joseph 
                           Turner 
                        <interp inst="t17511204-44-victim442" type="surname" value="Turner"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17511204-44-victim442" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17511204-44-victim442" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511204-44-off255 t17511204-44-victim442"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , against the statute
            </rs>, <rs id="t17511204-44-cd256" type="crimeDate">Nov. 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511204-44-off255 t17511204-44-cd256"></join>. *</p>
               <p>Jos. Turner. I have an empty house in <placeName id="t17511204-44-crimeloc257">Shoe-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17511204-44-crimeloc257" type="placeName" value="Shoe-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17511204-44-crimeloc257" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511204-44-off255 t17511204-44-crimeloc257"></join>, the lead was taken from the gutter; one hundred and a quarter and 24 pounds were taken away, on Monday the 22d of November, about 6 in the morning.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511204-44-person443">
                  Nicholas 
                  Gethings 
               <interp inst="t17511204-44-person443" type="surname" value="Gethings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-44-person443" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-44-person443" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watchman; going home about half an hour after six in the morning, Nov. 22d, I saw a door open in Shoe-lane, facing the back-door of St. Andrew's Church; it is an empty house; I pushed the door, there was somebody within pushed against me, and bolted me out; it is a yard-ddoor. I called out for assistance to my brother watchmen; there came 3 of them, I stood at the door, they went round to the other door.</p>
               <p>W. Farrow. I am headborough. I was gone home, and one of the watchmen came and called me out of bed, and told me they had taken a thief; when I got to the watch-house, there were the prisoner, the lead, Henshaw, Cooper and Bennet.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511204-44-person444">
                  John 
                  Henshaw 
               <interp inst="t17511204-44-person444" type="surname" value="Henshaw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-44-person444" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-44-person444" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watchman. I was one in pursuit after the prisoner, we were about an hour and half after him; somebody saw a Man on the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175112040029"></xptr> houses, and two men got up, but could not get him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511204-44-person445">
                  Henry 
                  Bennet 
               <interp inst="t17511204-44-person445" type="surname" value="Bennet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-44-person445" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-44-person445" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The 22d of Nov. in the morning, Gethings alarm'd us. There was a door open in a passage that had been fasten'd up some time, which we had an order to take care of. Gethings said, here is a man has fasten'd the door against me. We knock'd at the door; some of the neighbours came to their doors; I went to call up a tallow-chandler to get in backwards, I got in there and let four or five of the watchmen into the yard. We found four pieces of lead folded up, a basket, and a hammer. They lay as we went into this empty house. Cooper, I, and a carpenter, got upon the house. I had the glance of a man upon it. I think the prisoner is the man; he was near a chimney when we missed him. We had notice brought us by Mr. Downes's servant, one 
               <persName id="t17511204-44-person446">
                  John 
                  Tranter 
               <interp inst="t17511204-44-person446" type="surname" value="Tranter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-44-person446" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-44-person446" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , that a man had tap'd at the maid's window, and desired to be let in. Henshaw, and I, went with him, he brought the prisoner down stairs, I seiz'd him in the shop, we carry'd him to the watchhouse.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is Mr. Downes's house from this empty house?</p>
               <p>Bennet. It is about 4 or 5 houses from it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511204-44-person447">
                  William 
                  Tranter 
               <interp inst="t17511204-44-person447" type="surname" value="Tranter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-44-person447" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-44-person447" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner desired to be let in at the maid's garret window, at Mr. Downes's. He said, he had made his escape from the bailiffs. The maid was afraid to let him in, she call'd to me. I ran to the watchhouse to inquire, before I let him in, thinking he had broke some house open. I was told by the watchmen in Shoe lane, a man had strip'd a house of lead. I told them, they followed me to my master's house. I went up, and let the man in, he followed me down stairs, and they secured him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511204-44-person448">
                  Richard 
                  Dancer 
               <interp inst="t17511204-44-person448" type="surname" value="Dancer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-44-person448" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-44-person448" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going to work in the morning about six, the watchmen called for assistance, I went into the empty house with them, there was this lead lying, with a hammer, and basket. We search'd about and could not find any body. There was a man or a woman, looking out at a window, said, the man is upon the house, I went upon the house, and a watchman followed me. The prisoner at the bar, as nigh as I can guess, made his escape from one house to another, it was between daylight and dark, he got behind some chimneys, at last we lost him, I was in pursuit when the watchmen call'd, and said, they had got him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him get in at a window?</p>
               <p>Dancer. No, my Lord, I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511204-44-person449">
                  Edward 
                  Bellamy 
               <interp inst="t17511204-44-person449" type="surname" value="Bellamy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-44-person449" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-44-person449" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was called to their assistance I stood below, I never saw the man till he was brought to the watchhouse.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511204-44-person450">
                  Charles 
                  Cooper 
               <interp inst="t17511204-44-person450" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-44-person450" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-44-person450" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner is the person as nigh as I can guess, which I saw on the top of the house, I followed him from house to house, till we lost sight of him. We pursued so close, that had he not got in at the window, we must have taken him upon the house.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was formerly a housekeeper. I was indebred to a man 17 l. 17 s. I had a writ after me this half year. I lodg'd in St. Martins-lane. They came after me several times. I had notice they were after me at that time, they were over the way at the Plough. I staid till 12 o'clock. I went down into the city, and went in at a nighthouse there, and staid, thinking I was safe, I had been there about three hours. There came in a sheriff's officer, he fell in discourse with me. I knew him by sight, but not his name. In his discourse he pretended to quarrel. I saw him send out a boy. I made my escape. This was about five in the morning, I turn'd up into Shoe-lane, there lives an acquaintance of mine, one Jones, on the left hand upon a turning, they lodge in a garret. I thought to get there for cover. Just as I got to the door, I met the man going to work. I told him my reason for calling, he said, go up into my room, I did with him, the officers followed him as fast as they could. The garret window being open, I went out into a gutter, climb'd over the houses, there I staid till daylight; when it came to be light, where was I, but at the bottom of Holbourn-hill. I dont believe I have any witnesses. They waited all day yesterday. Your Lordship, and the Gentlemen of the Jury, may as you please, I am very easy about it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17511204-44-verdict258" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17511204-44-verdict258" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
