<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560225-19">
               <interp inst="t17560225-19" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560225-19" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560225-19" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560225"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560225-19" type="date" value="17560225"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560225-19-off96-c156" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-19-defend188 t17560225-19-off96 t17560225-19-verdict100"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560225-19-off96-c157" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-19-defend190 t17560225-19-off96 t17560225-19-verdict100"></join>
         
               <p>127, 128. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17560225-19-defend188" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Sharp 
                  <interp inst="t17560225-19-defend188" type="surname" value="Sharp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-defend188" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-defend188" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17560225-19-defend190" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Sharrat 
                  <interp inst="t17560225-19-defend190" type="surname" value="Sharrat"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-defend190" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-defend190" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted for <rs id="t17560225-19-off96" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-off96" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-off96" type="offenceSubcategory" value="shoplifting"></interp>
               stealing three dozen of handkerchiefs made of silk and cotton, value 3 l. five dozen of linen handkerchiefs, value 40 s. and twelve yards of lawn, value 12 s. the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17560225-19-victim192" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Mason 
                        <interp inst="t17560225-19-victim192" type="surname" value="Mason"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560225-19-victim192" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560225-19-victim192" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-19-off96 t17560225-19-victim192"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately in the shop
            </rs> of the said James, <rs id="t17560225-19-cd97" type="crimeDate">January 28</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-19-off96 t17560225-19-cd97"></join>.* </p> 
               <p>James Mason. I am a <rs id="t17560225-19-viclabel98" type="occupation">linen draper</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-19-victim192 t17560225-19-viclabel98"></join>, and live in <placeName id="t17560225-19-crimeloc99">Vere-Street, Clare-Market</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17560225-19-crimeloc99" type="placeName" value="Vere-Street, Clare-Market"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17560225-19-crimeloc99" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-19-off96 t17560225-19-crimeloc99"></join>. On the 28th of January last I went out in the evening about 100 yards below my shop to a butcher's in Clare-Market. I was not gone above ten minutes before a young woman, who is here, came running after me (her name is 
               <persName id="t17560225-19-person193">
                  Mary 
                  Carrol 
               <interp inst="t17560225-19-person193" type="surname" value="Carrol"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person193" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person193" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) and desired me to come home, for my shop was rob'd by two men; when I came home I ask'd what like men they were; my wife told me one of them was a butcher in Clare Market, who had been at our shop before. I went and got a warrant, and pursued the prisoners; this was the same evening; I found them at Mr. Butler's, the King's Arms, in Horton-Street (I was informed they used that house) this was near about eight o'clock. I told them they were the men I wanted, for they had been in my shop, and I had lost a bundle of handkerchiefs, and that they must be the men that had taken them. I went to take the warrant out of my pocket, but found I had lost it. I desired them to stay there, and I staid along with them. 
               <persName id="t17560225-19-person194">
                  William 
                  Tomlinson 
               <interp inst="t17560225-19-person194" type="surname" value="Tomlinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person194" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person194" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             went again to justice Fielding for another warrant; he came back and said the justice desired them to be brought before<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175602250013"></xptr> him without a warrant; my wife was there at this time, she knew Sharrat, but she did not directly know the other. I went and got another warrant, and left the prisoners in the house. When I came back I found Sharrat there, but Sharp was gone; Sharp come in again in about half an hour. They used me very ill; I took them up that night, and put them in the Round-House; the next morning we carried them before Mr. Welch, at justice Fielding's, where I charged them with my goods, but they made no answer.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. After you came there the first time and charged them with the robbery, did they attempt to run away?</p>
               <p>Mason. They came to the door and said, would I stop them? I said I would. Sharp said he had a good mind to knock me down.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was you gone for the warrant, and who did you leave in charge of the p risoners?</p>
               <p>Mason. I was not gone long; I left no body in charge of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Sharp brought back to the house, or did he come of his own accord?</p>
               <p>Mason. He came of his own accord, as far as I know.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not your wife and servant declare you had taken up the wrong people?</p>
               <p>Mason. My wife swore to one of them; and said the other was in the same dress, only when he was in the shop, his hat was about his ears.</p>
               <p>Isabella Mason. I am wife to the last witness. On the 28th of January I was standing in my shop, folding up some cloth; the prisoners came into my shop, pretending to buy cloth for a shirt; they ask'd to see a piece, there was some laying on the counter; they said that was too good, and desired me to lift up my hand and reach down another piece; I told them I thought it strange they should come to my shop, when they had been there about a week before and could not agree. Then one of them went to the end of the counter, where the handkerchiefs were standing; I saw them move, and they were gone; there were 3 dozen of them; the prisoners bought nothing of me.</p>
               <p>Q. How far off was the other prisoner at that time?</p>
               <p>I. Mason. As high as they could stand. I cried out immediately they were gone, they d - n'd me for a b - h, and said they had not got them</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any body in the shop besides yourself and the prisoners?</p>
               <p>I. Mason. Not a soul; they saw my husband go out. Then I call'd this 
               <persName id="t17560225-19-person195">
                  Mary 
                  Carrol 
               <interp inst="t17560225-19-person195" type="surname" value="Carrol"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person195" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person195" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to gong dure to the market to my husband, for I had been rob'd, upon which he came up.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of the two men?</p>
               <p>I. Mason. They ran away. I sent a man after them; when my husband came he went after the man, in pursuit of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any thing else taken besides these handkerchiefs at that time?</p>
               <p>I. Mason. Nothing that I know of.</p>
               <p>Q. Which of the two prisoners took the handkerchiefs?</p>
               <p>I. Mason. I saw them move between them, but I cannot tell who took them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever get your handkerchiefs again?</p>
               <p>I. Mason. No, I never saw them since.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it nearer five, or nearer six when they came in?</p>
               <p>I. Mason. It was about six or seven minute before six.</p>
               <p>Q. You say they had been at your house a week before, how long have you known them?</p>
               <p>I. Mason. I never saw them before that time.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to know Sharp lived in Clare-Market?</p>
               <p>I. Mason. My husband, knew that.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it light when they were in your shop?</p>
               <p>I. Mason. It was not light.</p>
               <p>Q. When you came to the justice's, what did you say there?</p>
               <p>I. Mason. I said I could not swear to Sharrat; but I took Sharp out from among them.</p>
               <p>Q. When they were in custody that night did not you desire your husband to desist, and said you did not think they were the persons?</p>
               <p>I. Mason. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not they go at their own liberty after they were first taken into custody?</p>
               <p>I. Mason. I don't know, my husband was with them, I was not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-19-person196">
                  William 
                  Tomlinson 
               <interp inst="t17560225-19-person196" type="surname" value="Tomlinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person196" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person196" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . As I was coming down Vere-Street, Clare-Market, on the 28th of January, between the hours of five and six, I met Mr. Mason's maid, who told me her master had been robbed of a bundle of handkerchiefs. I ran and overtook Sharp in Sheer-Lane. I tap'd him upon the shoulder (not thinking he was guilty of the thing, for I knew him.) I told him Mr. Mason had been robbed, and ask'd if he saw two men run; he said he was sorry for it, and that no body ran that way, only he and his<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175602250014"></xptr> partner had been running. I then went back to Mrs. Mason, and told her I had been of a fool's errand. Then she described the men to me, before I told her whom I met; so I and Mr. Mason went again after them, but could not find them. We went to the Advertising house, where he lost his warrant. We came back to the market, and on inquiry heard that they used Mr. Butler's, at the King's-Arms, where we found them.</p>

               <p>Q. How long was it after you first went out after them, that you found them at Butler's?</p>
               <p>Tomlinson. About two hours.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoners endeavour to conceal themselves?</p>
               <p>Tomlinson. No, they did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they searched?</p>
               <p>Tomlinson. No, they were not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-19-person197">
                  Mary 
                  Carrol 
               <interp inst="t17560225-19-person197" type="surname" value="Carrol"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person197" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person197" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodge in Mr. Mason's house. I saw Sharp come into the shop, but did not see him take any thing away. Mrs. Mason called me down stairs, and said she had been rob'd; and I went and told her husband; I can say no further.</p>
               <p>Sharp's defence. I was at Mr. Butler's all that afternoon till three quarters after five, when Sharrat and a young woman came to Butler's to me. I went with the young woman to the Horseshoe in Fleet-street, and from thence into Sheer-lane, where we bid one another good night. I turn'd about and said to Sharrat, I must go to St. Dunstan's church for my coat, which is at the taylor's. We ran about half way down Sheer-lane, when Tomlinson overtook me. He asked me if I saw two men run. I said, nobody but I and my friend before. I called him, and asked if he saw any body run; he said, he saw nobody. Then Tomlinson said Mason's shop had been rob'd, wishing us a good night, and we then went to St. Dunstan's church, I took the coat, and paid for it. After that, I went to Butler's again, and when I had been there about half an hour, the men came in, and the prosecutrix said we were the men who had rob'd her shop: I was not at the shop.</p>
               <p>Sharrat's defence. I had been at work-all that day till five o'clock in the evening, at one Mr. Grace's, in Brook's market; at that time I went to Clare-market, and met the young woman Sharp has mentioned, who said she was looking for Sharp. I went with her to the King's-Arms, where Sharp was, and called him out, and we went to the Horseshoe, and from thence for his coat; we ran half way down Sheer-lane, when Tomlinson overtook us, and ask'd if we saw two men running. Sharp said, none but he and I. Then we went for the coat, and came back to the King's-Arms. I was not in the shop, nor don't know where it is.</p>
               <p>Q. to I. Mason. Did you see Sharrat in your shop the day you lost the things ?</p>
               <p>I. Mason. They were both in the shop that day, I assure your lordship.</p>
               <p>For the prisoners.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-19-person198">
                  Henry 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17560225-19-person198" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person198" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person198" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know both the prisoners at the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Lewis. I am a bricklayer. I was at the publick house with them where they were taken, betwixt six and seven at night. The prosecutor's wife came in, and while she was inquiring Sharp went up to her, and asked if he was the man. She said, No. Then Sharrat said, Am I the man? No, said she, you are not the man, but you are very much like him.</p>
               <p>Q. to I. Mason. Did you say he was not the man, but like him?</p>
               <p>I. Mason. No, my Lord, I never said so.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-19-person199">
                  John 
                  Patten 
               <interp inst="t17560225-19-person199" type="surname" value="Patten"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person199" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person199" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the King's-Arms on a Wednesday evening, and saw the prisoners and prosecutrix. Sharp went up to her and said, Am I the man? She said, No Then Sharrat put the same question, to which she replied, no.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-19-person200">
                  John 
                  Butler 
               <interp inst="t17560225-19-person200" type="surname" value="Butler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person200" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person200" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the King's-Arms. Sharp was at my house from two o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he there till between five and six?</p>
               <p>Butler. I can't be sure of that, being myself backwards and forwards. The prisoners were both there, when Mrs. Mason came to take them up.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear her say they were the people that rob'd her, or what did she say?</p>
               <p>Butler. I was not there then.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-19-person201">
                  William 
                  Shepherd 
               <interp inst="t17560225-19-person201" type="surname" value="Shepherd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person201" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person201" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the King's-Arms when the prisoners were there, and Mrs. Mason came to apprehend them.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Shepherd. I am hostler there. I saw her look at Sharrat, and heard her say he was not the man, but very much like him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-19-person202">
                  John 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17560225-19-person202" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person202" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person202" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a taylor, and live near St. Dunstan's church, Fleet-street. On the 28th of January both the prisoners at the bar came to my house for a coat, betwixt six and seven at night.</p>
               <p>John Hall. I am a butcher. I have known Sharp 12 or 14 years; he has a good character, I never heard any harm of him.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175602250015"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-19-person203">
                  Richard 
                  Dennis 
               <interp inst="t17560225-19-person203" type="surname" value="Dennis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person203" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person203" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Sharp 12 years. I have had dealings with him; he always behaved honestly to me, and bears a good character.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Weatheril. I have known Sharp about half a year; he lodged with me 17 weeks, and behaved very honestly and justly in my house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-19-person204">
                  Catherine 
                  Leagit 
               <interp inst="t17560225-19-person204" type="surname" value="Leagit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person204" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person204" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Sharp lodged with me ever since Christmas. I never heard any harm of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-19-person205">
                  John 
                  Grace 
               <interp inst="t17560225-19-person205" type="surname" value="Grace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person205" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person205" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Sharrat work'd for me on the 28th of January last.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business ?</p>
               <p>Grace. I am a glazier, and live in Brook's market; he behaved very honestly as far as I ever knew.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he work with you?</p>
               <p>Grace. He was with me but two days; I had no more for him to do.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-19-person206">
                  Robert 
                  Thomas 
               <interp inst="t17560225-19-person206" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person206" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person206" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Sharrat ever since he wore a frock; I never heard any thing of him but that he was very honest, and was surprised to hear this 'thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-19-person207">
                  John 
                  Shenton 
               <interp inst="t17560225-19-person207" type="surname" value="Shenton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person207" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person207" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Sharrat from a child, and never heard any complaint of him before this affair.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-19-person208">
                  George 
                  Swinington 
               <interp inst="t17560225-19-person208" type="surname" value="Swinington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person208" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person208" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Sharrat these last two years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Swinington. That he was always very honest and sober.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-19-person209">
                  Johnson 
                  Gerrat 
               <interp inst="t17560225-19-person209" type="surname" value="Gerrat"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person209" type="given" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-person209" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Sharrat about 12 years. I have employed him, and always found him very honest.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17560225-19-verdict100" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560225-19-verdict100" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
