<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17501017-10">
               <interp inst="t17501017-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501017-10" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501017-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17501017"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501017-10" type="date" value="17501017"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17501017-10-off53-c97" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-10-defend114 t17501017-10-off53 t17501017-10-verdict56"></join>
         
               <p>628. 
               <persName id="t17501017-10-defend114" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Mary 
                     Wilks 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17501017-10-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-10-defend114 t17501017-10-alias-1"></join>Boswel</rs>, <rs id="t17501017-10-deflabel51" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-10-defend114 t17501017-10-deflabel51"></join>, otherwise <rs id="t17501017-10-alias-2" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-10-defend114 t17501017-10-alias-2"></join>Mary Griffiths</rs>, <rs id="t17501017-10-deflabel52" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-10-defend114 t17501017-10-deflabel52"></join>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-10-defend114" type="surname" value="Wilks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-10-defend114" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-10-defend114" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17501017-10-off53" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501017-10-off53" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-10-off53" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one silk gown, value 4 s. one linen gown, six yards of fustian, two aprons, one cloth coat, four linen caps, one petticoat, and other things
            </rs>, the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17501017-10-victim117" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Mullings 
                  <interp inst="t17501017-10-victim117" type="surname" value="Mullings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-10-victim117" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-10-victim117" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-10-off53 t17501017-10-victim117"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17501017-10-cd54" type="crimeDate">October 4</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-10-off53 t17501017-10-cd54"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501017-10-person118">
                  William 
                  Mullings 
               <interp inst="t17501017-10-person118" type="surname" value="Mullings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-10-person118" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-10-person118" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17501017-10-crimeloc55">Crown-court, Butcher-hall lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17501017-10-crimeloc55" type="placeName" value="Crown-court, Butcher-hall lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17501017-10-crimeloc55" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-10-off53 t17501017-10-crimeloc55"></join>. The 29th of September I had been drinking with some friends, and met with this woman in Newgate-street, she asked me where I was going; said I, I am going home; said she, you seem to be in liquor, I'll take care of you. After I was at home, she insisted upon my giving her something to drink.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in liquor?</p>
               <p>Mullings. I was, my lord, I gave her 3 d.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you stop to drink by the way?</p>
               <p>Mullings. I did not, I had nothing but a 6 d. in my pocket. She began to make a great noise; said I, take the 6 d. and give me the 3 d. she went off, I never saw her more till the 4th of this month; then she came to my door and knocked, I opened it, she told me it was six o'clock, she had not been there a minute before the clock struck seven, [this was in the morning ] she came in, I insisted upon her going out of the room; she said she was come to make a return for running away with my 6 d. I told her she might go about her business; then she insisted upon my going to drink a dram with her; I said I never drank a dram in a morning; she said you shall; I said no; I dressed myself; my wife was out of town; I bid the prisoner go about her business, and turned her out of doors; then I never saw her again, till I saw her at Guildhall.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Mullings. I am wife to the prosecutor. I was nursing a gentlewoman that was sick ; I had been out ten days; I happened to come home that Thursday morning; my husband says she was in with him; I found my door broke open, it had been double locked.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you the whole house?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Mullings. Only a lower room; the house is let out in tenements ; I found the staple burst out, and a looking-glass was broke with forcing the door open. I went into the room; my neighbour told me the prisoner (naming her name) had come out of my room dressed in a white gown, with a great bundle in her hand before her.</p>
               <p>Q. Mention what goods were lost.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Mullings. There were a blue silk gown, a white gown, a quilted petticoat, two linen aprons, a red short cloak, a shift which she has on her back, four caps (the goods were produced in court) I went to the brandy shop near Newgate, and gave it out there I had been robbed; from thence I went to my husband and told him my room was robbed.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was he?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Mullings. He was at work in Lime-street; this was about a quarter before eight in the morning; my husband gave me the key of the door, he had that in his pocket. I went the same night to Newington-green ; then there was a porter came to me and told me the prisoner was taken; I came to town again; we took her out of the Compter, and carried her to Goldsmith's-hall, and from thence to Guildhall. Some of the things were found upon her, and she told us the other things were at Harris's in St. Bride's-lane. She had on a white gown, a linen cap, and a white quilted petticoat. The constable went with me to St. Bride's-lane, there I found the blue silk gown, six yards of fustian, and a white linen apron.</p>
               <p>Q. to the Prosecutor. Did you lock the door when you went out?</p>
               <p>Mullings. I did, my lord, and had the key in my pocket.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Nichols. I live in Crown-court, Butcher-hall-lane. On the fourth of this month I saw Mr. Mullings go out about seven o'clock, and about half an hour after I saw the prisoner go out dressed in a white gown, a red cloak, and a bundle in a handkerchief, she carried it before her.</p>
               <p>Q. What distance of time was it betwixt Mr. Mullings and the prisoner's going out?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Nichols. It was a full half hour, that I am very sure of.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175010170010"></xptr>Prisoner's Defence. The prosecutor said he was a barber and perriwig-maker. I am an unfortunate girl; he carried me home, and gave me that white gown; if it is the same, it is dagged at the tail [she takes it up and looks on it] it is the same ; he gave me a silk gown, and two yards of fustian ; he lay by himself; he has carried me home nights after nights, and I have lain with him; he desired me to carry these things to pawn to Mr. Harris's, in Bride's-lane, which I did for 8 s. That milk-woman saw me carry them out, and the gown he put on my back. He broke a glass in pulling them down; then he locked me in; I was there four hours; then I took a poker and drew the staple and let myself out. This is true, and there are no witnesses on his side or mine. I have been with him a great many and a great many times.</p>
               <p>Q. to the Prosecutor. Did you give the prisoner any of these things?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No, my lord, I never did; the looking-glass was hanging up when I went out.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17501017-10-verdict56" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501017-10-verdict56" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
