<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17531205-47">
               <interp inst="t17531205-47" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531205-47" type="year" value="1753"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531205-47" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17531205"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531205-47" type="date" value="17531205"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17531205-47-off224-c280" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531205-47-defend370 t17531205-47-off224 t17531205-47-verdict230"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17531205-47-off226-c280" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531205-47-defend370 t17531205-47-off226 t17531205-47-verdict230"></join>
         
               <p>56. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17531205-47-defend370" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Hambleton 
                  <interp inst="t17531205-47-defend370" type="surname" value="Hambleton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-defend370" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-defend370" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted <rs id="t17531205-47-off224" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-off224" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-off224" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               for that he together with 
                     <persName id="t17531205-47-person371">
                        Allen 
                        Lattey 
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person371" type="surname" value="Lattey"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17531205-47-person371" type="given" value="Allen"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17531205-47-person371" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , since dead, did murder 
            </rs> 
            
               
                  <persName id="t17531205-47-victim373" type="victimName">
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-victim373" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531205-47-off224 t17531205-47-victim373"></join>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531205-47-off226 t17531205-47-victim373"></join>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17531205-47-cd225" type="crimeDate">September 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531205-47-off224 t17531205-47-cd225"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531205-47-off226 t17531205-47-cd225"></join>. he was a second time indicted for that <rs id="t17531205-47-off226" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-off226" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-off226" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he together with 
                     <persName id="t17531205-47-person374">
                        Allen 
                        Lattey 
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person374" type="surname" value="Lattey"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17531205-47-person374" type="given" value="Allen"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17531205-47-person374" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   in the king's highway on 
                     <persName id="t17531205-47-person375"> Datleft Christopher Krause</persName>
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and stealing from him one watch, value 40 s. seven guineas and one half guinea, his property
            </rs>, September 17.*</p> 
               <p>James Edrop. I am servant to my lord Harrington; the deceased Krause lived with my Lord in the Capacity of <rs id="t17531205-47-viclabel227" type="occupation">Cook</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531205-47-victim373 t17531205-47-viclabel227"></join>; I saw him with his boots on at our country house at Petersham, on the 17th of September, in order to go to London that day.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531205-47-person376">
                  William 
                  Clare 
               <interp inst="t17531205-47-person376" type="surname" value="Clare"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person376" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person376" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live near Bloody-bridge in the king's road between <placeName id="t17531205-47-crimeloc228">Chelsea</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17531205-47-crimeloc228" type="placeName" value="Chelsea"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17531205-47-crimeloc228" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531205-47-off224 t17531205-47-crimeloc228"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531205-47-off226 t17531205-47-crimeloc228"></join> and <placeName id="t17531205-47-crimeloc229">St. James's park</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17531205-47-crimeloc229" type="placeName" value="St. James's park"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17531205-47-crimeloc229" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531205-47-off224 t17531205-47-crimeloc229"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531205-47-off226 t17531205-47-crimeloc229"></join>; on the 17th of September I heard three fire-arms go off at about a quarter after seven at night.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you judge them to be, guns or pistols?</p>
               <p>W. Clare. I judged them to be pistols; I went out, but saw nobody; about half an hour after I met a party that had got the horse; I had seen the Cook ride by my house towards London a gallop about five or six minutes before the pistols went off.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531205-47-person377">
                  Charles 
                  Rider 
               <interp inst="t17531205-47-person377" type="surname" value="Rider"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person377" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person377" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the first gate in the king's private road; it is called the king's arms, but I have no sign up; it is next door to the duke's hospital.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is that from Bloody-bridge ?</p>
               <p>C. Rider. It is half a mile nearer London: on the 17th of September between seven and eight o'clock, came the deceased into my house; his coat and shirt were torn, and he in a vey bloody condition; I said what is the matter with you? he said I am my lord Harrington's cook; I have been robbed within two hundred yards of this house by two men in brownish cloaths; that he had wounded one of them in four or five places, but did not mention what parts of the body; that he had fired one pistol, and they two; that they got his knife away from him, and he got it again; he did not talk much.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was he when he said this?</p>
               <p>C. Rider. It was either as we were going to the hospital, or in my house; he said also that he lost seven guineas or seven and a half, and his watch. There were five men drinking a bottle of wine in the house; I said, gentlemen turn out.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175312050019"></xptr> I helped them to some pistols, a blunderbuss and a highland durk, and they went out; the deceased wanted a surgeon to dress his wounds. I went with him to the Duke's hospital, and the first we saw was Mr. West.</p>
               <p>Council for the crown. He is a quaker, and we cannot call him in,</p>
               <p>Rider. A small time after in came Mr. Cleator, another surgeon, then I left them together, and went out to see after the five men, and had four more joined me; we went up the road with two candles, the other five had a lanthorn and candle, at about 445 yards from my house, towards Bloody Bridge, (I measured it) we found three pistols, a whip and two keys, two pieces of a sheaf of a knife, each piece about six inches long, about as broad as two fingers, and a long needle.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you there when he was removed from the hospital to his own house?</p>
               <p>Rider. I was, his house was in Brown's Court, near Grosvenor-Square. He was carried in a coach, and he cried out as the coach sway'd, I was in it, and hollowed out to the coachman to drive gently. He was taken out of the coach at Grosvenor's Gate, and carried home in a chair. He was show'd the things that were found, and owned one of the pistols, the whip and the keys; and he said he had a needle in his sheaf, but I do not know whether he was shewn that and the pieces of the sheaf. I went the next morning as soon as it was light, and called the surgeon's man up, and he call'd one of the surgeons. We went up the road, and found blood; a man that joined us there, had found the deceased's hat in a gravel pit.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531205-47-person378">
                  Thomas 
                  Bragg 
               <interp inst="t17531205-47-person378" type="surname" value="Bragg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person378" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person378" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Coach and Horses in Dover-street, I was at a house called the King's Arms, in the King's Road, a little after seven of the clock, on the 17th of September, when the wounded person came in with both his hands holding his belly, his coat torn off one shoulder, and his shirt torn from the other, in a bloody condition, and no hat on. Mr. Rider said, what is the matter with you? he said he had been robbed by two men, about 200 yards up the road. Said Rider, gentlemen, turn out, and see if you can find the highwaymen, he reached me down a gun. The man said to Mr. Rider, for God's sake let me go to some surgeon, for I am very much wounded, and I believe I have wounded one of the men as much as they have done me. I went out first up the road, and lay down, imagining I should hear the man groan that was wounded, but heard nothing. I saw a horse standing with a bridle and saddle, and holsters, but no pistols. I brought him back, and met the others with a lanthorn, with which they were going to look for the thief or pistols, or what they could find in the road. I carried the horse to the deceased, he bid me take him to the Catherine-Wheel Yard, which I did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531205-47-person379">
                  William 
                  Philips 
               <interp inst="t17531205-47-person379" type="surname" value="Philips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person379" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person379" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at Mr. Rider's on the 17th of September in the evening, between seven and eight o'clock, the deceased came in all in a gore of blood, holding up his belly, and said he had been robbed by two men, two or three hundred yards from that house, and that he wounded one of them, he thought mortally, so that he could not get off; then Mr. Rider said, gentlemen, turn out.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531205-47-person380">
                  Wm 
                  Cleator 
               <interp inst="t17531205-47-person380" type="surname" value="Cleator"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person380" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person380" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am one of the surgeons belonging to the Duke's Hospital, on Monday the 17th of September, between seven and eight o'clock, the deceased came into our hospital wounded and very bloody. I asked him pretty fully about the affair as I was dressing him, when he gave me this account: He said, he was riding pretty briskly, and coming to the gate, a man immediately whipped out and catched hold on the bridle of his horse, on this he saw another man get out of the ditch, who came and took him by his left arm; then he took a pistol from his holster, and fired at one of them, but missed him. Immediately each returned the fire with small pocket pistols; they cried, down with him; they pulled him to the ground, just as he had seized the second pistol, but had not time to fire it; one of them forced it from his hand, and began to beat him with the thick end of it, (he had received a violent blow on the mouth, and four of his teeth were beat so that they stood inclining into his mouth; he had likewise a contus'd wound on his head, both which I thought might be done with the pistol) then he said, he thought of his cooking knife as he lay on his back, drew it out, and stabbed one of them, and made the best defence he could, saying, he was sure he had stabbed him, the blood immediately came flowing upon him; but they soon took the knife from him, that he catched fast hold on the blade of the knife, and regained it again, and stabbed him in another place, (he had received a cut in the joint of one finger very deep) but said, before he could make a third stab, it was catched<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175312050020"></xptr> from him again; then he catched it again with both hands, and also regained it, (his fingers were cut on both hands) then he stabbed him the third time; after which it was taken from him, and he regained it no more. Thus by his account he had given one of the men three stabs, I think he named the breast and belly, where he had given two of the wounds, and that there would be no difficulty in knowing them again by their marks; he said the man he wounded retired at a distance, and the other staid jumping on him; the other called to him and said, d - n him, I believe he has done for me, stamp his guts out, d - n him, a dog, murder him; and as he was lying on his back, the other man got on him, and jumped on him; and after they had continued that scene of cruelty some time, they left him, and he recovered himself, and got to Mr. Rider's. The deceased asked me in what condition I took him to be. At that time I could not discover that wound in the belly to be mortal. I told him I hoped he might do well: his principal complaint was of his bowels, occasioned by the jumping on him. When I went to see him the next morning, I then saw he was past all hopes of recovery: At that time I asked him some questions relating to his being hurt : He answered as before; and also told me over night, and in the morning, there is one of them I have not wounded with my knife, but I got his hand at my mouth, and bit either his finger or thumb.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did he die?</p>
               <p>Cleator. He died that day, being the Tuesday, about two in the afternoon : I opened his body before the coroner, and found the wound on the left side the stomach had penetrated the abdomen, and penetrated one of the small guts through and through.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say any thing about what sort of cloaths the two men had on?</p>
               <p>Cleator. He said they had on darkish brown-coloured cloaths.</p>
               <p>Edrop again. After we came home from Petersham; my lord desired somebody would go to the cook to see how he did, I went, this was on Tuesday about twelve o'clock, at which time he was bathing in a warm tub of water. I asked him how he did; he said, very poorly indeed. I said, I hear you drew your knife; he answered, I did, and wounded one of them with it in several places, (naming the thigh, the side of the belly and breast) and that he had bit one of them by the thumb or finger. When I came home I gave my lord an account of what he said to me. Soon after which one of the surgeons came and acquainted my lord that he was dead.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the prisoner's wounds?</p>
               <p>Edrop. I did after he was taken, which was on the 19th, the day after the cook died. He was carried before Justice Fielding, and when there would own to no other wound than one on his breast. A surgeon examined it. The Justice said, Have you no other wounds about you? He said, No, I said, you have one on the side of your belly: He said, I have a scratch there; that was looked into, and found to be a wound. I saw it, but did not much observe it. I asked him again, Have you any other wounds about you? He said, No, I said, you have, either on your thigh or groin. He had his regimental breeches on, almost new, but had no cut or place made through them by which to receive a wound. The Justice ordered him to be searched, and a wound was found upon his groin. The Justice asked him, if he had his regimentals on when he was wounded; He said, he had. The Justice asked him where he was when he was wounded; He said, in Broad St. Giles's: one time he said it was in a sort of a fray, at another time he said there were some russians fell upon him. Lattey (who died since in Newgate) was examined by the said Justice before the prisoner was brought in; there was a bite on the thumb, but the surgeon was very careful in saying whether it was a bite or not: I took it to be from a bite.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My words were about the wounds. I had no wound mortal but one on my breast.</p>
               <p>Edrop. Justice Fielding asked him how he came to deny all the wounds but that on his breast. He said, the others did not pain him so much.</p>
               <p>Cha. Krause. I am turned of fourteen years of age, and am son to the deceased. My father set out from Petersham the 17th of September for London: He always goes the king's road, and rode with his great knife in his pocket, and a brace of pistols before him.</p>
         
               <p>In a few Days will be published Part II.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17531205-47">
                  <interp inst="t17531205-47" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17531205-47" type="year" value="1753"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17531205-47" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17531205"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17531205-47" type="date" value="17531205"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175312050021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 5th, Thursday the 6th, Friday the 7th, Saturday the 8th, and Monday the 10th, of DECEMBER.</p>
                  <p>In the 27th Year of His MAJESTY's Reign. NUMBER I. PART II. for the Year 1753. BEING THE First SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of the Right Hon. 
                  <persName id="t17531205-47-person381">
                     Thomas 
                     Rawlinson 
                  <interp inst="t17531205-47-person381" type="surname" value="Rawlinson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17531205-47-person381" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17531205-47-person381" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Esq; LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by M. Cooper, at the Globe in Pater-noster Row. 1753.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-Pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175312050022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>Kings Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery held for the City of London, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Court. DEscribe that long knife.</p>
               <p>Krause. [He produced one the fellow to it, the blade strait, with a sharp point, and about ten inches long. He is shewn the sheath in two pieces.] This was my father's sheath. On Monday night my mother told me my father had been robbed, and almost murdered; I went up to see him. He said he was very bad, and wounded in several places of his body, that he was coming galloping along by Bloody Bridge, but for fear of any accident there had stopt galloping and was coming a gentle pace; that two men came from each side the way, like devils, upon him, who seized him and pull'd him from his horse; that he fired and they fired; that they got him down and stamp'd upon him; that he wounded one of them in several places with his knife, and felt his blood come upon him as he lay. He mention'd one wound in the breast, and another in the groin, or thereabouts; that he bit one of them in the hand and thumb, but whether it was the same he could not tell; and that the men were both in dark-coloured cloaths.</p>

               <p>Mrs. Krause. I am widow to the deceased. I was sent for to the infirmary; he was there lying upon a bed, and they said he had been robb'd and wounded, but not dangerously. He told me he was very bad, and he believed a dead man; he cried out much of his bowels being in pain, and said he had wounded one of the men that robbed him very much, and if they searched after him he believed he could not get away, for he found his blood come very hot upon him; he named the places where he had wounded him, by the breast, belly, groin and thigh, which he did with his knife; that the man forced it from him, that he got it again, and the other got it again two or three times. He said it was dark, but they appeared to him to be both in dark-colour'd cloaths, and for ought he knew they were about of a size; he also said, about an hour before he died, if the men are taken, remember the bite about the thumb, and the hand. He never ceased vomiting from the time he was brought in till a little before he died, and often said in the night before, I am a dead man, my pain is so great I cannot bear it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531205-47-person382">
                  John 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17531205-47-person382" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person382" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person382" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a surgeon, and live in Great Wild-street. On a Tuesday about the middle of September I attended the prisoner, but know not the day of the month, though I know he was taken up the next day. His wife, as she call'd herself, came to me and said, he was mortally wounded, and begg'd I'd come and dress him. I went with her about seven in the evening to a house in Parker's-lane; he was up, sitting in a chair, with a pair of blue breeches on, in a very low condition, with three very large wounds, which I supposed to have been mortal; one was under his right breast, another at the bottom of his belly,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175312050023"></xptr> another on the back part of that. He did not shew me any more; he only shew'd me one on his breast, but accidentally by turning up his shirt, I saw that large wound on the lower part of his belly. By his behaviour I judged he had received them in some bad works.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you apprehend they were made with?</p>
               <p>Wright. I apprehended they were made with a knife. [Then he is shewn a knife fellow to that of the deceased.] I verily believe them to have been done with the same sort of a blade as this. I asked him which way he got them, but he prevaricated in his story; he said he had been in a bad sray with some comrades, and some of them had wounded him with a scimitar. I told him they were more likely to have been done with a knife, and dressing his wounds told him they seemed to be mortal, bidding him (as he was a soldier) get into the hospital provided for such; but his wife cried, and said, No, don't let him go to the hospital, for I will very honestly pay you, and if he goes in there his pay will cease, and I shall be destitute of necessaries.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you where he got these wounds?</p>
               <p>Wright. No, he did not; but at another time he said he was assassinated privately by a person, but did not say where. Upon asking him how I should be paid, he said, he'd send to a neighbour, who would be security for him. When I went the next morning he and his wife also were gone.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531205-47-person383">
                  Robert 
                  Adare 
               <interp inst="t17531205-47-person383" type="surname" value="Adare"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person383" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person383" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a surgeon, and being desired by the Duke of Newcastle, on the nineteenth of September, to go to New Prison, to look at a soldier there that was wounded, and take what care I could of him, that he might be brought to justice, I went to him, (the prisoner) and found one wound about three inches under his right arm-pit, which had penetrated the breast and wounded the lungs; it seemed to have been made by a cutting instrument about an inch and a half in breadth. He is shewn the fellow to the knife shewn before. This would make just such a wound. There was another wound about four inches above the left hip bone, which came out again, being about five inches in length, by the loins; it went quite through him, and seemed to have been made by the very same instrument. I asked him, if he had any other wounds, and he shewed me a sore on his right leg, saying, he had no other. Being asked the next morning, if I had seen any wound on his thigh, I said, no; returning to him, I desired him to pull down his breeches, and there saw a small wound on the upper part of the thigh near the groin; that also was made by the point of such an instrument as has been now shewn me. I attended him till he was cured.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you how he came by them wounds?</p>
               <p>Adare. He said they were done in a fray at St. Gyles's, with a cuttoe.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think the wounds could be given with such an instrument?</p>
               <p>Adare. It must be 5 inches from the point, not broader than an inch and a half, I am sure this knife would make directly the wounds I saw upon him; cuttoes are generally broader than this knife, and I should think in passing through him must have made a broader wound.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Lattey?</p>
               <p>Adare. I did at the same time, he had two wounds, one a little above the joint of the thumb, and another a little below, they seem'd to be a little jagged, there was a black contus'd spot on the inward part of the thumb, seemed likely to have been made with a tooth; they might be done by a bruise against a post, but I am rather inclinable to think them done by a bite.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531205-47-person384">
                  William 
                  Crosby 
               <interp inst="t17531205-47-person384" type="surname" value="Crosby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person384" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person384" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner sent for me on the 18th of September between 8 and 9 at night, to dress his wounds; I did so, there were four of them, one on his breast, one on his loins, one on his groin, and one on his shin.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this knife?</p>
               <p>Crosby. The wounds might have been given with such a streight tool as this, but it did not seem to be by an instrument quite so broad as this; the prisoner told me he got them in a fray in the street; he had been dress'd before he came to me.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175312050024"></xptr>Q. Was you acquainted with him before?</p>
               <p>Crosby. No, I never knew him before in my life, it was through my acquaintance with Lattey that he came to me; he came first to me to dress the prisoner, who was in my apartment that night, and went away the next morning. We went to the house of Kennedy, and there found him up two pair of stairs in a closet in an empty room, with his shoes in his hand; he was charg'd with this fact, but he said he knew nothing of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531205-47-person385">
                  John 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17531205-47-person385" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person385" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person385" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the taking of the prisoner at Kennedy's house; when he came down stairs, I said Hambleton, how came you by these wounds? he said three men fell upon him in broad St. Gyles's. I went with him to justice Fielding's, and the justice ask'd him many questions on his 2d. examination, and ask'd him what cloaths he had on when he received these wounds, he said he had on his regimentals; he was ask'd after his brown cloaths, he said he had sold them to maintain himself in prison; the justice ask'd him to whom, and he said he could not tell.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531205-47-person386">
                  William 
                  Carey 
               <interp inst="t17531205-47-person386" type="surname" value="Carey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person386" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person386" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am corporal in the same regiment to which the prisoner belongs, I was at the apprehending him, and went in the coach with him to the justice, and I ask'd him in the coach how he came by his wounds, he said three men fell upon him in St. Gyles's, who abus'd and wounded him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531205-47-person387">
                  Thomas 
                  Ash 
               <interp inst="t17531205-47-person387" type="surname" value="Ash"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person387" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person387" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a soldier, about one o' clock on Monday the 17th of September, Hambleton came to my room and put on colour'd cloaths and took off his regimentals; he went away in a blue waistecoat and black britches, and a dark brown coat.</p>
               <p>Q. What colour are your regimental britches?</p>
               <p>Ash. They are blue. I mounted guard the next day, and his regimentals were in my room, I saw them at 7 in the morning when I went out.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he come to your house after this?</p>
               <p>Ash. No, he never did. I met Lattey on the stairs that morning, he ask'd me if I had seen Hambleton, I said, no, for Hambleton should have mounted guard on the Tuesday morning but he did not come.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531205-47-person388">
                  Margaret 
                  Ash 
               <interp inst="t17531205-47-person388" type="surname" value="Ash"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person388" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person388" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the last evidence, the prisoner left his regimentals at our house, and put on brownish coloured cloaths upon the 17th of September; the regimentals continued at my house till next morning, when I deliver'd them to Lattey, who said he came for them.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you see them over night?</p>
               <p>M. Ash. I saw them at 8 o'clock.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531205-47-person389">
                  John 
                  Hassan 
               <interp inst="t17531205-47-person389" type="surname" value="Hassan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person389" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person389" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Wednesday I believe the 19th of September, I with others went to search after the prisoner, Lattey had brought word down that the prisoner had lain twelve hours in his blood, and desired he might be brought to the hospital; we found him in the house of Kennedy near Brooks-market, he then had a light colour'd coat on, and we found his regimentals at the house of O Neal in Parker's-Lane, where Lattey had left them. They were produced in court, but could not be sworn to as the identical cloaths of the prisoner, the regimentals being all of a sort. We went to justice Fielding's, and ask'd him what cloaths he had on on Monday night, he said his regimentals.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see his wounds?</p>
               <p>Haston. I saw two wounds he had.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531205-47-person390">
                  Stephen 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17531205-47-person390" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person390" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person390" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am sergeant to the same regiment to which the prisoner belongs, I saw him on the 17th of September last in the Strand, between one and three o'clock in the afternoon dress'd in a dark brown coat and blew waistecoat.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know Lattey?</p>
               <p>Smith. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see him and the prisoner together?</p>
               <p>Smith. I never did but once.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531205-47-person391">
                  William 
                  Norden 
               <interp inst="t17531205-47-person391" type="surname" value="Norden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person391" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person391" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have seen the prisoner several times. On Monday the 17th of September, I was at 
               <persName id="t17531205-47-person392">
                  John Wright 
                  Newark 
               <interp inst="t17531205-47-person392" type="surname" value="Newark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person392" type="given" value="John Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person392" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's house, near Bloody-bridge in the five fields going to Chelsea, there were three soldiers there in colour'd cloaths, and I believe the prisoner was one of them; one of them was in grey and the other two in brown.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was this?</p>
               <p>Norden. I went in there about two and staid till about six, I took the prisoner to be one of them in a brown coat, and I think it was a surtout.</p>
               <p>Q. To Mrs. Ash, was that brown coat the prisoner put on a surtout-coat ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175312050025"></xptr>Mrs. Ash. I don't think it was?</p>
               <p>Q. To Smith. Was that coat you saw him in in the Strand a surtout coat?</p>
               <p>Smith. It was a plain brown coat, not a surtout.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531205-47-person393">
                  Alexander 
                  Kennedy 
               <interp inst="t17531205-47-person393" type="surname" value="Kennedy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person393" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person393" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Tuesday evening, the 18th of September, I met Lattey, who was a particular acquaintance of mine in the street, he desired me to come to the sign of the Mogul and he'd treat me, I went and did my business and return'd there to him; he told me, that his friend Hambleton was wounded, and I went to see him at the house of O Neal, in Parkers-lane along with Lattey, where I saw his wounds dress'd at which I was shock'd. I ask'd him how he got them, he said, he being got in liquor, had been in bad company fighting with two or three men, and that a woman was the cause of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he say it was?</p>
               <p>Kennedy. I think he said it was about St. Gyles's.</p>
               <p>Q. Who dress'd his wounds then?</p>
               <p>Kennedy. Crosby did; and after he was dress'd, Crosby said that that bed was not proper for him to lie in, and offer'd him a bed at his house, which he accepted off; I saw him there. After that he came to my house and was taken there, but I was not at home.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of any intimacy between Lattey and the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Kennedy. Lattey I knew from a boy, and I ask'd him to come and dine with me, he said, if he did, he should bring a friend with him, which he did, and it was the prisoner; this was on the Sunday before the prisoner was taken; I also that same afternoon drank with them at a house in St. Gyles's.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>When I was wounded, I was disguised in liquor in St. Gyles's. Some where I cannot tell where a woman pickt me up in the street; as I staid talking to her, there came up three men, one of them said, what do you do with my wife? he struck at me, and I at him, I not being able to knock a man down, but some how or other he fell, and one of the others drew a cuttoe and made several passes at me, this was about eleven o'clock at night, please to examine my corporal as to my character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531205-47-person394">
                  William 
                  Carey 
               <interp inst="t17531205-47-person394" type="surname" value="Carey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person394" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person394" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about five years, his character has been but indifferent of late.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Please to examine 
               <persName id="t17531205-47-person395">
                  Stephen 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17531205-47-person395" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person395" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person395" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531205-47-person396">
                  Stephen 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17531205-47-person396" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person396" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person396" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a sergeant in the same regiment that the prisoner belongs to, but not the same company; but can't say any thing to his character one way or other.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Please to ask Ash my character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531205-47-person397">
                  Thomas 
                  Ash 
               <interp inst="t17531205-47-person397" type="surname" value="Ash"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person397" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-person397" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am of the same company the prisoner is off, and know nothing amiss of him but by hearsay.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17531205-47-verdict230" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-verdict230" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty of the murder and robery
            </rs>, <rs id="t17531205-47-punish231" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17531205-47-punish231" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531205-47-defend370 t17531205-47-punish231"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>This being on the Friday, he received sentence immediately to be executed on the Monday following, and his body to be defected and anatomized.</p>
               <p>See him tried twice last sessions, No 487.</p>
            </div1>
