<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17590228-20">
               <interp inst="t17590228-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590228-20" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590228-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17590228"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590228-20" type="date" value="17590228"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17590228-20-off152-c215" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590228-20-defend258 t17590228-20-off152 t17590228-20-verdict156"></join>
         
               <p>136. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17590228-20-defend258" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     More 
                  <interp inst="t17590228-20-defend258" type="surname" value="More"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590228-20-defend258" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590228-20-defend258" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17590228-20-deflabel151" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590228-20-defend258 t17590228-20-deflabel151"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17590228-20-off152" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590228-20-off152" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590228-20-off152" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing ten pints of brandy, value 10 s. and ten pints of shrub, value 10 s. two eighteen shilling pieces, and ten guineas
            </rs>, the goods and money of 
               
                  <persName id="t17590228-20-victim260" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17590228-20-victim260" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590228-20-victim260" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590228-20-victim260" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590228-20-off152 t17590228-20-victim260"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17590228-20-cd153" type="crimeDate">Feb. 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590228-20-off152 t17590228-20-cd153"></join>. *</p>
               <p>John Smith. I <rs id="t17590228-20-viclabel154" type="occupation">keep a public-house</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590228-20-victim260 t17590228-20-viclabel154"></join> in <placeName id="t17590228-20-crimeloc155">Bloomsbury, the sign of the Castle</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17590228-20-crimeloc155" type="placeName" value="Bloomsbury, the sign of the Castle"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17590228-20-crimeloc155" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590228-20-off152 t17590228-20-crimeloc155"></join>; the prisoner was my servant.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had she lived with you?</p>
               <p>Smith. About three quarters of a year; on the eighteenth of February I miss'd ten guineas and two eighteen shilling pieces.</p>
               <p>Q. From where did you miss it?</p>
               <p>Smith. From out of a corner-cupboa rd in the bar?</p>
               <p>Q. Are you a married man?</p>
               <p>Smith. I am.</p>
               <p>Q. Whose business was it to keep the bar?</p>
               <p>Smith. My wife kept it sometimes and sometimes I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the prisoner ever use to go into the bar?</p>
               <p>Smith. Yes, sometimes.</p>
               <p>Q. Has she ever received money there?</p>
               <p>Smith. Sometimes she has.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the cupboard door lock'd?</p>
               <p>Smith. It was.</p>
               <p>Q. When it was lock'd, who kept the key?</p>
               <p>Smith. Either my wife or I, sometimes I left it in the lock.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you use to trust the prisoner with the key?</p>
               <p>Smith. Sometimes I have gave her the key to fetch things out for my wife; we had two keys, and one of them was lost about two months ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever find it again?</p>
               <p>Smith. No, never: at the time of losing it I did not suspect the prisoner to have got it; but I have lost a great many times brandy and shrub from a closet going up stairs, and from the bar, that I have reason to think she had got the key, since, she has confessed she took the liquor away in bottles to a neighbour's house.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell what quantity of liquor you lost?</p>
               <p>Smith. I lost about two gallons of shrub; brandy I cannot tell what I lost of that.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever get any of it again?</p>
               <p>Smith. No, never.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner in your service when you miss'd the money?</p>
               <p>Smith. She was: I took her before justice Welch, there she confess'd she took the money.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was this after you miss'd it?</p>
               <p>Smith. It was on the Tuesday after.</p>
               <p>Q. What day of the week was it that you miss'd it?</p>
               <p>Smith. I miss'd it one the Sunday.</p>
               <p>Q. What where her words in confessing it?</p>
               <p>Smith. She said she took twelve guineas; she did not know that two of them where 18 s. pieces, but took them to be guineas.</p>
               <p>Q. What are the people names where she said she carried the liquor?</p>
               <p>Smith. The woman is named 
               <persName id="t17590228-20-person261">
                  Honour 
                  Whitcome 
               <interp inst="t17590228-20-person261" type="surname" value="Whitcome"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590228-20-person261" type="given" value="Honour"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590228-20-person261" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and she own'd she gave her the money too; she is indicted as accessary but is not in custody.</p>
               <p>Q. What is she?</p>
               <p>Smith. She keeps a chandler's shop within three or four doors of me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you make any search there ?</p>
               <p>Smith. We did, and found two bottles in her house that night; one had had shrub, and another brandy in it; but they were empty.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590228-20-person262">
                  Thomas 
                  Fayram 
               <interp inst="t17590228-20-person262" type="surname" value="Fayram"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590228-20-person262" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590228-20-person262" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was before the Justice of the Peace, and heard the girl confess she robb'd her master of about twelve guineas and a great quantity of brandy and shrub.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590228-20-person263">
                  Thomas 
                  Kemp 
               <interp inst="t17590228-20-person263" type="surname" value="Kemp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590228-20-person263" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590228-20-person263" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was along with Mr Smith at the taking up the girl; he took her out of a neighbour's house and had her into his own house; she would not confess the taking the liquor or money; the constable took her before Mr Welch, there she confessed to the taking two guineas at one time, and about six weeks before that time two guineas more; and about a month after that time, or thereabouts, she said she took a nine shilling and six-penny piece; (she does<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175902280033"></xptr> not know money I believe) or she said it must be a guinea or an eighteen shilling piece, that made five, this was before Mr Smith miss'd his ten guineas and two eighteen shillings pieces; she would not confess to the taking any more that night; that night Mr Welch sent for 
               <persName id="t17590228-20-person264">
                  Honour 
                  Whitcome 
               <interp inst="t17590228-20-person264" type="surname" value="Whitcome"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590228-20-person264" type="given" value="Honour"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590228-20-person264" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , as the girl at the bar had told Mr Welch that she perswaded her to take the money from her master, and that she and another woman a companion of her's perswaded her to take liquor; the next day the girl was examined again there; then she own'd she took twelve guineas of her master's money, which he had mentioned to have lost; she said, she took it on the Sunday morning; she own'd to the taking four of them at first and at last own'd to the whole.</p>

               <p>Q. to prosecutor. You said the first time you miss'd your money was on the eighteenth of February, did you not?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you use to have so much money at a time in your bar?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I had sometimes twenty or thirty guineas at a time there; she at that time left eleven half guineas, one guinea, and a 27 s. piece.</p>
               <p>Q. How much should you have had then in all?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I should have had eleven guineas, a 27 s. piece, and two 18 s. pieces.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you take it that the money was taken away at different times?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I never miss'd any but that time; which was as I said before, ten guineas and two 18 s. pieces.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you suppose she took it all at one time ?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Yes; without she took any on the Saturday night before; they were taken away between the Saturday night and Sunday morning.</p>
               <p>Q. What time had you seen it last before you miss'd it?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I had look'd at it on the Saturday morning the seventeenth the money was all there then; and I miss'd it on Sunday morning between ten and eleven.</p>
               <p>Q. to Kemp. What became of 
               <persName id="t17590228-20-person265">
                  Honour 
                  Whitcome 
               <interp inst="t17590228-20-person265" type="surname" value="Whitcome"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590228-20-person265" type="given" value="Honour"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590228-20-person265" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ?</p>
               <p>Kemp. On the Tuesday night the constable was desired to take her in custody, and bring her again the next morning; then Mrs Whitcome was along with her before Mr Welch; they were taken from there to a public-house, and there Mr Thomas, the constable, took five guineas of Mrs Whitcome's brother to let go home for the night, and the brother was to see her forth-coming on the next morning; this was to prevent her going to the round-house, she having a young child; the constable took pity of that, and thought he could depend on seeing her in the morning, she being a housekeeper in the neighbourhood.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is the constable?</p>
               <p>Kemp. He is very ill in bed.</p>
               <p>The Attorney for the prosecution. We have indicted the constable for this misdemeanour; for the next morning the woman had made her escape.</p>
               <p>Court. You have done right.</p>
               <p>Kemp. The prisoner declared before justice Welch, that Mrs Whitcome was the person that desired her to rob her master, and she was to buy her a new gown, but never did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590228-20-person266">
                  Edward 
                  Morgan 
               <interp inst="t17590228-20-person266" type="surname" value="Morgan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590228-20-person266" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590228-20-person266" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was present when the girl at the bar was taken and carried before the justice; there she confess'd she had robb'd her master several times; that she had taken brandy and shrub and carried them to Mrs Whitcome's.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she mention particulars ?</p>
               <p>Morgan. She said she had taken two guineas at one time, and two at another, and an 18 s. piece, which she did not know what it was.</p>
               <p>The prisoner said nothing in her defence.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17590228-20-verdict156" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590228-20-verdict156" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17590228-20-punish157" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590228-20-punish157" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590228-20-defend258 t17590228-20-punish157"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
