<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17550116-27">
               <interp inst="t17550116-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550116-27" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550116-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550116-27" type="date" value="17550116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550116-27-off142-c254" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-27-defend308 t17550116-27-off142 t17550116-27-verdict143"></join>
         
               <p>78. (M. 1.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17550116-27-defend308" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Lovell 
                  <interp inst="t17550116-27-defend308" type="surname" value="Lovell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-defend308" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-defend308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17550116-27-off142" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-off142" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-off142" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing a bay mare, value 4 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               <persName id="t17550116-27-victim309" type="victimName">
                  Samuel 
                  Elkins 
               <interp inst="t17550116-27-victim309" type="surname" value="Elkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-victim309" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-victim309" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-27-off142 t17550116-27-victim309"></join>
                  </persName>
             . ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-27-person310">
                  Thomas 
                  Burchell 
               <interp inst="t17550116-27-person310" type="surname" value="Burchell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-person310" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-person310" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lost a bay mare out of my fields about the 16th or 17th of November, she was the property of a nephew of mine, 
               <persName id="t17550116-27-person311">
                  Samuel 
                  Elkins 
               <interp inst="t17550116-27-person311" type="surname" value="Elkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-person311" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-person311" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I never could hear of her till I found 
               <persName id="t17550116-27-person312">
                  William 
                  Bullock 
               <interp inst="t17550116-27-person312" type="surname" value="Bullock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-person312" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-person312" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             on her back, riding thro' Kentish-town; I stopped him, and took him before justice Fielding, he said he bought her at Dover fair, he told us believed he could find the man he bought her of. I and a neighbour of mine went with him to Canterbury, there the mare fell sick, so I could go no farther; the rest of the witnesses will give you a farther account.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-27-person313">
                  William 
                  Bullock 
               <interp inst="t17550116-27-person313" type="surname" value="Bullock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-person313" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-person313" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I deal in earthen-ware; I was at Dover fair, I had there almost made an end of selling my goods on the 23d of November. I heard of a mare to be sold, I wanted one to ride home into Staffordshire, to a place called Hadley-green, I went and looked at her, and bought her on the 25th at night, at the King's head at Dover of the prisoner at the bar for four pounds, it is the mare Mr. Burchell has swore to be his nephew's. I took her to Deal market, and from thence back again to Dover, from thence to Sandwich fair, then to Rochester fair, then I had sold all my goods, and came to London, and staid here about two days, and riding through Kentish-town by Mr. Burchell's door, on her, going to Staffordshire, he owned the mare, and took me and her to justice Fielding's, this was a fortnight ago last Tuesday; I knew I had good evidence of my buying her, and I thought I could find the man. Mr. Burchell, his neighbour, and I set out, the mare fell ill at Canterbury, but Mr. Harrison and I went on to Dover, there we heard the prisoner was gone over to France; we staid two or three days to wait for his return, which he did, and was taken by a friend of mine, named Tulip, who keeps the Blue-anchor there, whom I had told it to at Canterbury, and who also knew of my buying the mare of him; he was brought to London, and before justice Fielding he owned he bought the mare in Smithfield, and that he sold her to me for 4 l.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-27-person314">
                  John 
                  Gibbs 
               <interp inst="t17550116-27-person314" type="surname" value="Gibbs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-person314" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-person314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Dover; I saw Mr. Bullock pay four pounds to the prisoner at the bar for the mare he is now trying for; it was at Dover, Bullock insisted upon six-pence back for good luck.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-27-person315">
                  Walter 
                  Harrison 
               <interp inst="t17550116-27-person315" type="surname" value="Harrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-person315" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-person315" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Kentish-town; I was standing at my door and saw Mr. Bullock ride by on this mare, I went and informed Mr. Burchell, Mr. Burchell went and brought him and the mare back, he said he bought her at Dover for four pounds, and described the prisoner as the man he bought her of. I went with him and Mr. Burchell to see for the prisoner; Mr. Burchell's mare fell sick at Canterbury, Bullock and I went on to Dover after he had told Mr. Tulip the mare he bought of the prisoner was stole; Tulip knew the prisoner, and also the buying the mare of him, and left him an indemnification if he should see and apprehend the prisoner; we could not meet with him at Dover, we came back, and Mr. Tulip and the constable brought the prisoner to justice Fielding's the Sunday following.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175501160031"></xptr>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I bought that mare of a gentleman's servant-like in Smithfield on the 18th of November, on a Monday, and paid for her at the George-inn there, and from thence I rode to Canterbury. I keep fairs with gingerbread, she being a little strained in the footlock, and finding her full weak, I sold her to Mr. Bullock, the person said he was just come out of the country and had no occasion for her, this was not on a market-day, one 
               <persName id="t17550116-27-person316">
                  Robert 
                  Conner 
               <interp inst="t17550116-27-person316" type="surname" value="Conner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-person316" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-person316" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             who lives next door to the Plough in Drury-lane, that deals in hard-ware, and one 
               <persName id="t17550116-27-person317">
                  Joseph 
                  Biggs 
               <interp inst="t17550116-27-person317" type="surname" value="Biggs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-person317" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-person317" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             were by at the time and saw me buy and pay for her.</p>
               <p>They were called, but no such persons appeared.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-27-person318">
                  Robert 
                  Swain 
               <interp inst="t17550116-27-person318" type="surname" value="Swain"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-person318" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-person318" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was formerly my servant; while with me he behaved himself honestly. I never heard any ill of his character before this unhappy affair.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he live with you?</p>
               <p>R. Swain. He came the 4th of June, 1748, and continued till the 5th of July, 1749.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen him lately?</p>
               <p>R. Swain. It may be a twelve-month ago since I saw him before this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-27-person319">
                  Stephen 
                  Simonds 
               <interp inst="t17550116-27-person319" type="surname" value="Simonds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-person319" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-person319" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him twelve or fourteen years; he lived four years with the earl of Arran; he was a baker in the country, and a chairman in town; I know nothing ill of him; his character has been very good; I have not seen him, I believe, these eight or nine months before.</p>
               <p>John Green. I have known him about fourteen or fifteen years; I never heard any thing ill of him before this affair. I had seen him about four or five months ago.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-27-person320">
                  Thomas 
                  Slayter 
               <interp inst="t17550116-27-person320" type="surname" value="Slayter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-person320" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-person320" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him from his infancy; I never heard any thing ill of him in my life before this; I believe it is six months ago since I saw him before.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17550116-27-verdict143" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-verdict143" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17550116-27-punish144" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550116-27-punish144" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-27-defend308 t17550116-27-punish144"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
