<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17521206-7">
               <interp inst="t17521206-7" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521206-7" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521206-7" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17521206"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521206-7" type="date" value="17521206"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17521206-7-off26-c57" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-7-defend67 t17521206-7-off26 t17521206-7-verdict29"></join>
         
               <p>7. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17521206-7-defend67" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Chapman 
                  <interp inst="t17521206-7-defend67" type="surname" value="Chapman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-7-defend67" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-7-defend67" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , widow, was indicted for that <rs id="t17521206-7-off26" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17521206-7-off26" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-7-off26" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               she, in a certain court called Dudley Court, in an open place near the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17521206-7-victim69" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Mears 
                        <interp inst="t17521206-7-victim69" type="surname" value="Mears"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17521206-7-victim69" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17521206-7-victim69" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-7-off26 t17521206-7-victim69"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, one purse value one penny, one guinea and thirteen shillings in money from his person did steal
            </rs>, <rs id="t17521206-7-cd27" type="crimeDate">October 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-7-off26 t17521206-7-cd27"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521206-7-person70">
                  James 
                  Mears 
               <interp inst="t17521206-7-person70" type="surname" value="Mears"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-7-person70" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-7-person70" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Lock-and-Key in Hog-Lane, and coming home between twelve and one in the morning on the 29th of October, I went into an alehouse in <placeName id="t17521206-7-crimeloc28">Dudley-Court</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17521206-7-crimeloc28" type="placeName" value="Dudley-Court"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17521206-7-crimeloc28" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-7-off26 t17521206-7-crimeloc28"></join>, and had three pints of beer, where I saw the prisoner and several others, (about five or six in number). Being lame on one hand, I was obliged to undo my purse with my teeth, the prisoner, who went out before me, jumped upon me and clasped me about the neck, da - ng my eyes and limbs, and said I should go along with her. She immediately put her hand in my pocket, and forcibly took out my purse, in which was a guinea and thirteen shillings. I met no body; the prisoner had a little girl with her, but no body else was near me.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you stay after you had paid your reckoning ?</p>
               <p>Mears. I went immediately after. I secured her, and she was sent to the Roundhouse, where the constable searched her cloaths.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your employment ?</p>
               <p>Mears. I deal in horses, and have a stable near Denmark-Street.</p>
               <p>Q. How came your lameness?</p>
               <p>Mears. It came with a cut on my nuckle, which has been opened five or six times.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521206-7-person71">
                  John 
                  Harrop 
               <interp inst="t17521206-7-person71" type="surname" value="Harrop"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-7-person71" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-7-person71" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in St. Giles's High-Street. In the morning of the 29th of October I heard t he prosecutor had been robbed, and the thief put into the Roundhouse. As I went to church I made water in the Church-yard against the Roundhouse. There I saw the purse lying on the ground, and took it up. (Produced in court and deposed to by the prosecutor as his property, which he lost with his money ). The Roundhouse window faces the place where it lay.</p>
               <p>Q. from the prisoner. Ask the prosecutor if he did not give his wife a 36 s. piece in the watch-house after I was there.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I did, but that was loose in my pocket.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>Mr. Mears desired me to drink a pint or two with him, I did and went out, he came out after me, and told me, if I'd go down the alley he'd give me a shilling, which I took, and, knowing that he had a wife and family, would not be concerned with him, so I ran away with the shilling; then he cried out I had robbed him to be revenged of me.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521206-7-person72">
                  James 
                  Milbourne 
               <interp inst="t17521206-7-person72" type="surname" value="Milbourne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-7-person72" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-7-person72" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Watchmaker, and live just by Hicks's Hall. I knew Mears before, having seen him in Smithfield buying and selling horses; I saw him yesterday at Hicks's-Hall, I ask'd him what his business was; he said, I am come to tuck a bitch up that pox'd me seven years ago; as to the prisoner I know nothing of her.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175212060005"></xptr>Prosecutor. I declare I never spoke to that man yesterday.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17521206-7-verdict29" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17521206-7-verdict29" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
