<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17581206-29">
               <interp inst="t17581206-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581206-29" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581206-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17581206"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581206-29" type="date" value="17581206"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17581206-29-off159-c237" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-29-defend286 t17581206-29-off159 t17581206-29-verdict162"></join>
         
               <p>33. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17581206-29-defend286" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Draper 
                  <interp inst="t17581206-29-defend286" type="surname" value="Draper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-defend286" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-defend286" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17581206-29-off159" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-off159" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-off159" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 4 pounds weight of horse-hair, value 8 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17581206-29-victim288" type="victimName">
                     George 
                     Grisewood 
                  <interp inst="t17581206-29-victim288" type="surname" value="Grisewood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-victim288" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-victim288" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               <persName id="t17581206-29-victim289" type="victimName">
                  John 
                  Warrington 
               <interp inst="t17581206-29-victim289" type="surname" value="Warrington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-victim289" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-victim289" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , <rs id="t17581206-29-cd160" type="crimeDate">Sept. 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-29-off159 t17581206-29-cd160"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-29-person290">
                  George 
                  Grisewood 
               <interp inst="t17581206-29-person290" type="surname" value="Grisewood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person290" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person290" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr 
               <persName id="t17581206-29-person291">
                  John 
                  Warrington 
               <interp inst="t17581206-29-person291" type="surname" value="Warrington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person291" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person291" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and I had some horses that were employ'd in the King's service; they were at grass, at Mr Stapp's at <placeName id="t17581206-29-crimeloc161">Stoke-Newington</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17581206-29-crimeloc161" type="placeName" value="Stoke-Newington"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17581206-29-crimeloc161" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-29-off159 t17581206-29-crimeloc161"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. How many were there of them?</p>
               <p>Grisewood. There were fifty or sixty of them; there were seven of them had their manes and tails cut off.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-29-person292">
                  William 
                  Stapp 
               <interp inst="t17581206-29-person292" type="surname" value="Stapp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person292" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person292" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The horses were at grass with me; there were five grey and two black ones, had their manes and tails cut off; I know not who cut them off; but in the field where the horses where, we found a pocket-book, in which were some letters directed to 
               <persName id="t17581206-29-person293">
                  John 
                  Draper 
               <interp inst="t17581206-29-person293" type="surname" value="Draper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person293" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person293" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Fleet-street; we got a search-warrant and search'd his house, and found about the quantity of horse-hair, as we think was cut from horses.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of letters were they?</p>
               <p>Stapp. They were letters that had been open'd and read; we found the prisoner by the directions of them letters, near Temple-bar, Fleet-street.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at the execution of the search-warrant?</p>
               <p>Stapp. I was: we found about two or three pounds of grey horse-hair, tied up in bundles and seem'd very fresh, just as if immediately cut off; there were some black a smaller quantity; we took the prisoner before the gentlemen at Guild-Hall; his defence there, was, that he had had that hair by him there years; it smelt greasey of the horse and oily, as if fresh cut off.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Is the prisoner a house-keeper?</p>
               <p>Stapp. He is: and a peruke-maker.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find other hair besides that?</p>
               <p>Stapp. We found very little besides this.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find no human hair?</p>
               <p>Stapp. Very little.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the letters shown to him?</p>
               <p>Stapp. I do not know what he said to them: but he own'd the pocket-book.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he say he lost it</p>
               <p>Stapp. He said he went to his father's at Totenham-High-Cross, for some apples, and going along, lost his b: but where this was found there was no path.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the prisoner's father ?</p>
               <p>Stapp. I do: he belongs to the turnpike at Stamford-hill.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it not the nearest way to go over your grounds to his father's house.</p>
               <p>Stapp. No: it is out of the way to his father's, go which way you will.</p>
               <p>Q. Do not people go cross your fields some times?</p>
               <p>Stapp. Some times people will, tho' they have no right for so doing.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-29-person294">
                  John 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17581206-29-person294" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person294" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person294" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I found this pocket-book in the fields where my master's horses were; produced in court.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-29-person295">
                  John 
                  Cook 
               <interp inst="t17581206-29-person295" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person295" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person295" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the searching the prisoner's house. Some white and black horse-hair produced. This we found there.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you? Cook. I am constable.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he say he came by it?</p>
               <p>Cook. He said he brought it of a Scotch pedlar, and had had it by him two or three years.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-29-person296">
                  William 
                  Holonby 
               <interp inst="t17581206-29-person296" type="surname" value="Holonby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person296" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person296" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the prisoner's examination the second time, which was on the 28th of September; the horses were brought to Guild-hall, and the sitting Aldermen desired some hair might be cut off to compare with the other hairs, which I did. I have had it in my custody ever since. Producing it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-29-person297">
                  William 
                  Redman 
               <interp inst="t17581206-29-person297" type="surname" value="Redman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person297" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person297" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a peruke-maker. I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175812060033"></xptr> was prosecutors, to come to examine this hair, which I did, and gave it as my opinion, that the greatest part of the hair were just cut off, and had it's natural sweat and moisture about it. 'It is tied about with Barbers thread, part of it is manufactured: some of it has been washed: some of it has the radical moisture, or sweat of the horse now. I don't apprehend it can have remain'd in the state it is now, so long as the prisoner talks of. We find by experience it always will dry.</p>
               <p>Q. Compare this other small parcel that was cut off at Guild-hall, with the others?</p>
               <p>Redman. (he takes them in his hand ): It is impossible to give judgment of this, for hair will come so near: we find the nearer the shoulder it is the strongest, and nearer the head the softest, the out side of the mane in general is lightest and softest, that is the upper and under, provided that is grizzly.</p>
               <p>Q. to Stapp. When was the hair missed?</p>
               <p>Stapp. It was miss'd the 21st of September, and the search made the 26th of September.</p>
               <p>Q. to Redman. Has there been time enough since the 21st of September, to manufacture that which is manufactured, to be in the state it is in?</p>
               <p>Redman. Yes: there has. He might have manufactured the whole, and a great deal more.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you say, that which you say has it's radical moisture in it, that may have been in the state it is in for twelve months?</p>
               <p>Redman. I cannot say how long: no man can be certain. I very much query whether it could: for in lying, the radical moisture will dry into powder and fly off.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-29-person298">
                  John 
                  Graham 
               <interp inst="t17581206-29-person298" type="surname" value="Graham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person298" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person298" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Peruke-maker; I have seen this hair. (He takes it in his hand). I believe most of it is fresh cut off.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think it has been cut off the horses three years?</p>
               <p>Graham. No: nor one year neither; here is the natural moisture upon it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence. On Monday the 18th of September, I had been at my father's at Tottenham-High-Cross; they have a very large orchard, and were complaining they could not get people to gather the fruit; they desired the first leisure time I had, I would come and help them. I did, but then I went by Islington; but the afternoon proving showery, we did not gather much fruit: that afternoon I got an accident, by falling from a pear-tree; my mother insisted on my staying all night; I came home to town the next morning, the day proving fine again, and I was very little wanted at home, as my business is chiefly among the gentlemen of the Law, and they were many of them out. I went on the Friday again, the day being fair, I went to cross these fields, but I found it very wet; I went to go up lordship-lane by Newington, and it was so bad I was oblig'd to take to those fields where these horses were; I remember seeing a great number of them, and whether by pulling out my hankerchief I know not, but my book was dropp'd; there was a usual path, and people have frequent intercourse through that field; I have often gone that way, there are 4 gates to those fields, and I think I went the nearest way to Stamford-hill; I was in bed at my father's house at the time the hair was cut off, and it will be proved, that I had this hair in my house some time before.</p>
               <p>Q. to Stapp. Was the pocket-book wet or dry when it was found?</p>
               <p>Stapp. It was very dry: it was a fine day and found about 4 in the afternoon.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember any rain before that?</p>
               <p>Stapp. I do not remember any rain for two days before. The book was found clear out of any path.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-29-person299">
                  Richard 
                  Stanbury 
               <interp inst="t17581206-29-person299" type="surname" value="Stanbury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person299" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person299" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was journeyman to the prisoner above nine months and a week, I remember this hair extremely well, (looking at it.) it is of my tying up.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has it been in your master's house?</p>
               <p>Stanbury. I remember it being in the house for better than two years, I believe all of it. (there were some picked out with the radical moisture in it), he takes it in his hand.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you say as to that in your hand?</p>
               <p>Stanbury. I really think all this has been in the house better than two years.</p>
               <p>Q. How came it not to be manufactured ?</p>
               <p>Stanbury. Because it is not fit for use.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175812060034"></xptr>Q. When did you come to live with the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Stanbury. I came to him about a week before last Lord Mayor's-day was 12 months.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character.</p>
               <p>Stanbury. He always had the character of a very honest and just man in his dealings, and a very sober man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-29-person300">
                  William 
                  Morris 
               <interp inst="t17581206-29-person300" type="surname" value="Morris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person300" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person300" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw this hair before in Guildhall; I had not seen it for three years before, since I was apprentice.</p>
               <p>Q. Will you swear you saw this hair in the house three years ago?</p>
               <p>Morris. I know the prisoner bought a parcel of hair of 
               <persName id="t17581206-29-person301">
                  James 
                  Hope 
               <interp inst="t17581206-29-person301" type="surname" value="Hope"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person301" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person301" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and there were some such hair as this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-29-person302">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Heckles 
               <interp inst="t17581206-29-person302" type="surname" value="Heckles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person302" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person302" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I work for the prisoner in picking the hair; I remember I desired my master not to have all the hair pick'd, because it would not pay cost; I believe he had this hair between two and three years.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-29-person303">
                  Thomas 
                  Shoarn 
               <interp inst="t17581206-29-person303" type="surname" value="Shoarn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person303" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person303" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw such hair as this between two and three years ago, in the custody of Mr Draper, he offer'd it to sell to me. This is fit only for brush-makers.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure this is the same?</p>
               <p>Shoarn. I can't say it is?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-29-person304">
                  Samuel 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17581206-29-person304" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person304" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I liv'd with Mr Draper about 15 months; I came to him in January 1757, and staid 'till November following, he had then a great deal ofhair by him, and I really believe this is some of the same hair.</p>
               <p>Mr Berry. I have known the prisoner about three years, I never heard but that he bears a very honest character; as to this affair, I know nothing of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-29-person305">
                  Samuel 
                  Closs 
               <interp inst="t17581206-29-person305" type="surname" value="Closs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person305" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person305" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner 15 years, he and I were fellow-apprentices together, he is a man of credit and reputation.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-29-person306">
                  John 
                  Symonds 
               <interp inst="t17581206-29-person306" type="surname" value="Symonds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person306" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about a year and a quarter, he has the character of a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-29-person307">
                  William 
                  How 
               <interp inst="t17581206-29-person307" type="surname" value="How"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person307" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person307" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him three years I never heard any dishonesty of him before.</p>
               <p>Mr Rayment. I have known him four or five years, he is a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-29-person308">
                  Matthew 
                  Roak 
               <interp inst="t17581206-29-person308" type="surname" value="Roak"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person308" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-person308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was tenant to me, a very honest man.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>Roak. I was a Butcher, but now I am a Grave-digger.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17581206-29-verdict162" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581206-29-verdict162" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
