<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17591205-11">
               <interp inst="t17591205-11" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591205-11" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591205-11" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17591205"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591205-11" type="date" value="17591205"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17591205-11-off56-c80" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-11-defend100 t17591205-11-off56 t17591205-11-verdict60"></join>
         
               <p>12. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17591205-11-defend100" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Matthews 
                  <interp inst="t17591205-11-defend100" type="surname" value="Matthews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-11-defend100" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-11-defend100" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17591205-11-off56" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17591205-11-off56" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-11-off56" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing six guineas, the money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17591205-11-victim102" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Macquistin 
                        <interp inst="t17591205-11-victim102" type="surname" value="Macquistin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17591205-11-victim102" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17591205-11-victim102" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-11-off56 t17591205-11-victim102"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling house of the said John
            </rs>, <rs id="t17591205-11-cd57" type="crimeDate">November 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-11-off56 t17591205-11-cd57"></join>.* </p> 
               <p>John Macquistin. I am a <rs id="t17591205-11-viclabel58" type="occupation">turner</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-11-victim102 t17591205-11-viclabel58"></join>, and live in <placeName id="t17591205-11-crimeloc59">Newgate-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17591205-11-crimeloc59" type="placeName" value="Newgate-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17591205-11-crimeloc59" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-11-off56 t17591205-11-crimeloc59"></join>. About a fortnight before I took the prisoner up, which was on the 5th of November last, I was suspicious of somebody in my house robing me, having lost 5 or 6 guineas out of a bag lock'd up in my own chamber, which is up two pair of stairs; but as to the money in the bag I was not quite certain of the sum, only I supposed myself deficient 5 or 6 guineas. I thought it necessary to come to a certainty, so I put exactly 18 guineas and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175912050007"></xptr> a 36 s. piece into the same bag, lock'd it up in the same drawer, and let it lie there a week, and when I went to look at it, there were but 14 guineas and the 36 s. piece, but I found the drawer lock'd as usual. After that I thought I must take some method to know the money again, so I put in 15 guineas, 2 half guineas, 2 36 s. pieces, and 2 moidores, to the amount in all of 22 guineas; I put it down on a piece of paper, and marked each piece with a small cross on the standard side, and determined to look at it 2 or 3 times a day. The money was all safe on the Sunday night. The prisoner came to work, as a journeyman, on Monday morning, and went away in the evening. I had look'd. and found my money right in the morning, and also in the afternoon, but at going to bed at night there were only 20 guineas; two were missing, and the drawer lock'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you put this money to the other, or by itself?</p>
               <p>Macquistin. I put the 22 guineas there, and took the other money away. On missing the 2 guineas, I challenged my maid with it, who declared herself innocent; then I suspected the prisoner, so went with a constable to his lodgings, and charged him, but he denied it. The constable searched him, and found 2 guineas upon him which were my property, and of my own marking, as the others were [the two guineas produced, and inspected by the court and the jury.] I have some of the others in my pocket to compare, if the court pleases.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he confess any thing?</p>
               <p>Macquistin. I don't know he spoke a word all the way he went to the compter, he never confess'd any thing.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Where have the two guineas been since that time ?</p>
               <p>Macquistin. After he was committed the alderman order'd me to take them.</p>
               <p>Council. I should have thought them to have been order'd into an indifferent person's hands.</p>
               <p>Macquistin. They were order'd into mine.</p>
               <p>Q. Is the constable here?</p>
               <p>Macquistin. He is.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not the prisoner your apprentice?</p>
               <p>Macquistin. He had been.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he serv'd his time out?</p>
               <p>Macquistin. He had 22 Months to serve when I had him discharg'd from me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not there a quarrel between you and him?</p>
               <p>Macquistin. If you urge me to do it, I shall tell the truth.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray speak out the whole matter?</p>
               <p>Macquistin. Then the reason why I discharg'd him was, about a month before, he went out in the hight and left the door open, and I was alarmed by my door being open in the night.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he rob'd you of any thing?</p>
               <p>Macquistin. No, he had not as I know of; but I thought that as he had got this method of opening the door and going out, I was not safe in my person or property, so I was determined to get rid of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he ever go out and leave your door open at any other time?</p>
               <p>Macquistin. I know of no other time than that.</p>
               <p>Q. Do'nt you think it possible that a person in going out might accidentally in pulling the door after him leave it open?</p>
               <p>Macquistin. He might, but I think he had no reason for going out of my shop.</p>
               <p>Council. This shews you had a great dislike to him from this single instance, which might be purely accidental.</p>
               <p>Macquistin. Supposing I had been rob'd, who should I suspect but the person who went out of my house?</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a character did you give him before the alderman when you was there?</p>
               <p>Macquistin. The alderman was not there, his clerk was. I told him that the prisoner had gone out of my house and left the door open, and I could not think myself safe in my own house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not say you thought the prisoner to be a very honest man?</p>
               <p>Macquistin. I did say, I did not know that he rob'd me.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a place was this money taken out of?</p>
               <p>Macquistin. From out of a drawer of a double chest upon chest; I always lock it, and put the key into a buroe and lock it up there.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the lock broke?</p>
               <p>Macquistin. No, it was not.</p>
               <p>Q. When you went to enquire for the prisoner, did he offer to secrete himself?</p>
               <p>Macquistin. He was thunderstruck; it was near twelve o'clock at night when I went to him. I laid hold of his collar directly.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you see before you saw the prisoner in that house?</p>
               <p>Macquistin. He was the very first person I saw; I called out and asked if Will was at home, that being his name. The mother (as I thought) called, and said he was. I have heard since it was somebody<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175912050008"></xptr> else that lodges in the house, not his mother. I told her he must come to work in the morning, I had a job to do; then he appeared, and I laid hold of him.</p>
               <p>Samuel Lane. I am a constable. I searched the prisoner, and found two guineas and six pence upon him. I said to his master, here are two guineas, do you know this money. He looked on them, and said here is my mark on both of them, and I will swear to them as part of my money, taken out of my drawer.</p>
               <p>Q. did you look at the marks?</p>
               <p>Lane. I did, and saw them; these are the two guineas here produced.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the prisoner confess any thing?</p>
               <p>Lane. No; I did not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I kick'd a piece of paper before me, and took it up; there were two guineas in it, which I put into my pocket: this was in my master's house.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17591205-11-verdict60" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17591205-11-verdict60" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-11-verdict60" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder40s"></interp>
               Guilty, 39 s.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17591205-11-punish61" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17591205-11-punish61" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-11-punish61" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-11-defend100 t17591205-11-punish61"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
