<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17581025-5">
               <interp inst="t17581025-5" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581025-5" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581025-5" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17581025"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581025-5" type="date" value="17581025"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17581025-5-off23-c54" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581025-5-defend63 t17581025-5-off23 t17581025-5-verdict27"></join>
         
               <p>328. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17581025-5-defend63" type="defendantName">
                     Edward 
                     Thackerill 
                  <interp inst="t17581025-5-defend63" type="surname" value="Thackerill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-5-defend63" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-5-defend63" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17581025-5-off23" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581025-5-off23" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-5-off23" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one hundred weight of tea, value 30 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17581025-5-victim65" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Walker 
                        <interp inst="t17581025-5-victim65" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17581025-5-victim65" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17581025-5-victim65" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581025-5-off23 t17581025-5-victim65"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling-house of the said John
            </rs>, <rs id="t17581025-5-cd24" type="crimeDate">Sept. 20</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581025-5-off23 t17581025-5-cd24"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581025-5-person66">
                  John 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17581025-5-person66" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-5-person66" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-5-person66" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . <rs id="t17581025-5-viclabel25" type="occupation">I deal in the tea-trade</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581025-5-victim65 t17581025-5-viclabel25"></join>, and live in Friday-street, the prisoner was my <rs id="t17581025-5-deflabel26" type="occupation">porter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581025-5-defend63 t17581025-5-deflabel26"></join>, and also did business in my shop in selling of tea.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you charge him with?</p>
               <p>Walker. With stealing a hundred weight of tea.</p>
               <p>Q. What reason have you for so charging him?</p>
               <p>Walker. When the officer came to take stock, the prisoner, in order to make it answer to the exciseman's books, put weights into the canisters, to supply the weight he had taken away.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know this?</p>
               <p>Walker. I know it by his own confession, I took stock along with the officer, the first time of weighing it, it weighed six hundred and eighteen pound and three quarters. This was in the morning, and after breakfast, finding a canister wanted eight pounds of what it had weighed before, I ordered it all to be weighed over again, and then it weighed no more than four hundred and sixty five pounds; all this was before the exciseman was gone out of the shop.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this tea under the prisoner's care ?</p>
               <p>Walker. It was, I sent him after this to fetch a chest of tea home, he went away and did not return; I sent a letter to him at Edmonton, his wife came to me to enquire what the matter was. I told her I had some suspicion her husband had robbed me, and desired her to go home and bring him to town; he came, then I desired to know of him how he came, to rob me, and to tell me the truth, saying he could have no opportunity of taking away any between the two times the tea was weighed; then he told me he had put weights into the canisters to make it answer to the exciseman's books, and that he had taken them out again before the second time of weighing it. I desired to know what he had done with it; he told me he had sold it at several times to such and such people, half a pound, and a pound at a time, for six-pence or a shilling. I asked him how long he had gone on in this way, he said he had practised it ever since the year fifty one or fifty two, and that every time the officer came to weigh, he kept putting in weights till it amounted to an hundred weight and odd.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to send him for tea after you missed such a quantity ?</p>
               <p>Walker. I knew he could not open that chest in the street, and if he ran away, I knew where to find him. I took him before my Lord Mayor, I told the same there as here.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the value of the tea you charge him with?</p>
               <p>Walker. I have put it at the lowest value in the indictment.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>My master promised me very faithfully, if I would tell him who I sold it to, he would forgive me every thing, and I did tell him who I sold it to, and the peoples names.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17581025-5-verdict27" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581025-5-verdict27" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17581025-5-punish28" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581025-5-punish28" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581025-5-defend63 t17581025-5-punish28"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
