<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510116-52">
               <interp inst="t17510116-52" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510116-52" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510116-52" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510116-52" type="date" value="17510116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510116-52-off245-c376" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-52-defend476 t17510116-52-off245 t17510116-52-verdict248"></join>
         
               <p>159. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17510116-52-defend476" type="defendantName">
                     Hannah 
                     Spires 
                  <interp inst="t17510116-52-defend476" type="surname" value="Spires"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-52-defend476" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-52-defend476" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17510116-52-deflabel244" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-52-defend476 t17510116-52-deflabel244"></join>, was indicted on the coroner's inquisition, for the <rs id="t17510116-52-off245" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510116-52-off245" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-52-off245" type="offenceSubcategory" value="infanticide"></interp>
               murder of her bastard child
            </rs>, <rs id="t17510116-52-cd246" type="crimeDate">Dec. 9</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-52-off245 t17510116-52-cd246"></join>* </p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-52-person477">
                  Susannah 
                  Cooney 
               <interp inst="t17510116-52-person477" type="surname" value="Cooney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-52-person477" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-52-person477" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner lived <rs id="t17510116-52-deflabel247" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-52-defend476 t17510116-52-deflabel247"></join> with me. On the 8th of last month, about 8 o' clock in the morning, I heard the prisoner groan; she had complained of the tooth-ach before; I thought she had it again; she lay in the yard upon the stones: I went to her she said she was very bad; I asked her, if she was with child? She said no; I desired her to get up, she would not; said I if you will not go into the kitchen, go up into the one pair of stairs room and lie down on that bed; she did. I sent the girl up to her to see if she would have any breakfast, she said she could not eat any thing. After dinner I went up to her, and said, she must have something to eat or she would be worse; I made her some panado and carried it up: after that I sent the girl up, who gave her some more; and in the evening between 6 and 7 o'clock my husband and I went to a neighbour's house; when we came back, I sent the girl up to know if she would not come down; she sent word she would not come down that night; I went up, and when I came there I saw something I did not like. I thought to myself there must be a child born, I took up a corner of the bed, and under that was a child. I called her murdering slut, or something like it ; she made no answer, I drove her down stairs to her own bed, which was in the kitchen.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you had children?</p>
               <p>S. Cooney. Yes, I have. This child seemed to be at its full growth, but I did not examine its nails, my lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Had she made any provision for it?</p>
               <p>S. Cooney. She did say she had things at her mother's for it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did there appear any wounds or marks on the body?</p>
               <p>S. Cooney. No, there did not, my lord, or any settling of blood.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-52-person478">
                  John 
                  Cooney 
               <interp inst="t17510116-52-person478" type="surname" value="Cooney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-52-person478" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-52-person478" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirmed the testimony of his wife.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-52-person479">
                  Sarah 
                  Bull 
               <interp inst="t17510116-52-person479" type="surname" value="Bull"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-52-person479" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-52-person479" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live servant in this family. After my master and mistress were gone out, in the evening I went up to see how she did, and carried her some panado, she drank it; when my mistress came home she went up and made her come down stairs; then my mistress ordered me to bring a candle, and there was a child wrapped up in two cloths, one round the head, the other round the body.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-52-person480">
                  Mary 
                  Rogers 
               <interp inst="t17510116-52-person480" type="surname" value="Rogers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-52-person480" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-52-person480" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a midwife. About half an hour after 10 that evening I was called out of my bed to this house; there sat the prisoner in a chair by the fire; I went to look at the child; there were all things together that should come into the world. It is my opinion the child was stagnated in the birth for want of help. When I came to clean it, there were no marks of violence upon it; the child was at its full growth, nails and every thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-52-person481">
                  James 
                  Atkinson 
               <interp inst="t17510116-52-person481" type="surname" value="Atkinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-52-person481" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-52-person481" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an apothecary. The child was carried to Shoreditch workhouse; there I viewed the body, I found no marks of violence upon it; I apprehend the child might be suffocated either in the birth or afterwards; but I am apt to think it was born alive, because there were settlings of blood interspersed all about the body.</p>
               <p>Q. Could it breath and yet be suffocated in the birth?</p>
               <p>Atkinson. Yes, my lord, it might.</p>
               <p>Eliz. Spires. The prisoner is my husband's daughter; she had some childbed linen at my house in her box; she had been at my house about a week before. I took the things out of the box. They were produced in court.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510116-52-verdict248" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510116-52-verdict248" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
