<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17531024-25">
               <interp inst="t17531024-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531024-25" type="year" value="1753"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531024-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17531024"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531024-25" type="date" value="17531024"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17531024-25-off105-c123" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-25-defend166 t17531024-25-off105 t17531024-25-verdict108"></join>
         
               <p>467. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17531024-25-defend166" type="defendantName">
                     George 
                     Darwent 
                  <interp inst="t17531024-25-defend166" type="surname" value="Darwent"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-25-defend166" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-25-defend166" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for that he <rs id="t17531024-25-off105" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17531024-25-off105" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-25-off105" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               on the King's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17531024-25-victim168" type="victimName">
                           Joseph 
                           Howard 
                        <interp inst="t17531024-25-victim168" type="surname" value="Howard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17531024-25-victim168" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17531024-25-victim168" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-25-off105 t17531024-25-victim168"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, one hat, val. 7 s. and one peruke, val. 5 s. the property of the said Joseph, did steal, take and carry away,
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17531024-25-cd106" type="crimeDate">October 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-25-off105 t17531024-25-cd106"></join>.* </p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-25-person169">
                  Joseph 
                  Howard 
               <interp inst="t17531024-25-person169" type="surname" value="Howard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-25-person169" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-25-person169" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Throgmorton-street, on Wednesday the 3d of October, about half an hour after 11 at night, I had supp'd with my father; there was a lady there, which I and my brother went to see home, and in my return, I met the prisoner at the bar in <placeName id="t17531024-25-crimeloc107">Parliament-street , Westminster</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17531024-25-crimeloc107" type="placeName" value="Parliament-street , Westminster"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17531024-25-crimeloc107" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-25-off105 t17531024-25-crimeloc107"></join>; he was stooping upon the ground, I said, friend, go along before me, I love to see my enemies before me, for I do not like you at all. He went on before, and when he had got about 200 yards, he then turn'd about, and said, now d - n your eyes I will do for you, upon which I struck him with my fist, he staggered from me, I then knock'd him down with my stick, he got up, and knock'd me down with his fist, I then called to my brother, and said, if you don't fight now I shall be kill'd, for this man is too much for me; he came, and struck him with his stick; he then thought we were too powerful for him, so he<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175310240010"></xptr> run away, and took my hat and wig with him. He dropp'd the wig about twenty yards off, and took my hat to Privy-garden-gate; I followed him, and took him hold on the collar, and there was a Plaisterer's man coming along, and a watchman, so we took him, and carry'd him to Justice Lediard, he was not at home, we then took him to St. Martin's round-house, there he charged the watch with me, as well as I did with him. I sent for a Gentleman, who said he would be answerable for my appearance the next day. We went the next day before the Justice, there the Prisoner said, there was two gentlemen fighting, and he found the hat, and was coming to bring it to me.</p>
               <p>Q. During the time you say he had the better of you, did he attempt to pick your pocket ?</p>
               <p>Howard. No, he did not, neither did he ask me for any money.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he appear to you to be drunk?</p>
               <p>Howard. I did not mind, but he was sober when he came to St. Martin's round-house.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in liquor?</p>
               <p>Howard. No, I was as sober as I am now.</p>
               <p>Q. From the Prisoner. Did you mention any thing of your wig before Justice Fielding ?</p>
               <p>Howard. I did, I mention'd my wig as well as my hat.</p>
               <p>Cross Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you speak to the prisoner first, or he to you ?</p>
               <p>Howard. I spoke to him first, and bid him go about his business.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he first attack you?</p>
               <p>Howard. He did, and said, d - n his eyes, he would do for me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-25-person170">
                  Charles 
                  Howard 
               <interp inst="t17531024-25-person170" type="surname" value="Howard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-25-person170" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-25-person170" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was with my brother when we met the prisoner, he was stooping down, when we went to pass him, he would not let us, neither one way or the other, but did not say a word to us ; I saw another man behind us; I said to my brother, there is an ill-looking fellow behind, I have a notion they want to rob us, I saw the fellow no more. My brother then said to the prisoner, what do you want, do you want to rob us? the prisoner then said, d - n you, come a little further, and I'll tell you what I want, we had both sticks in our hands, my brother told him to go on before, or he would knock him down. He went on about 150 yards towards Charing-Cross, then he went up against the well, and as we went by he started out, and said, d - n my eyes and limbs, I'll do for you, then my brother struck him with his stick, and knock'd him down, he then got up, and threw my brother down, and put his knees upon his belly, my brother cried out; I struck him several times on the head with my stick, he then got up, and took my brother's hat and wig, he dropp'd the wig upon the ground, just as he ran away with the hat, he carried the hat as far as Privy-garden-wall, there he dropp'd it, and there we found it we came up, and took him by the collar, and called out to the watch, the watch came, we charged them with him, and he charged them with us; we carried him to the round-house, there he damn'd us for scoundrels, and said, we had robb'd him of 2 s and 2 d. or 2 s. and 4 d. I cannot say which, I was with him before Justice Fielding, the Justice ask'd him if he was drunk, and he said he was not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-25-person171">
                  John 
                  Abby 
               <interp inst="t17531024-25-person171" type="surname" value="Abby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-25-person171" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-25-person171" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Plaisterer, I was coming along at that time, and heard a squabble, man come running by with a hat in his hand, and ran in at Privy-garden-gate, he turn'd himself round, and dropp'd it down beside him upon the ground, he did not offer to run away. When the prosecutor came up, he told him there was his hat, I went with them to the round house, where they searched his pocket and found a clasp knife, I went with them the next day before justice Fielding, there the prisoner said, he did not remember taking the hat, but said he thought there was a mob, and that he was drunk.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I never had the hat in my hand 'till I took it up to give it into his hand.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Sir 
               <persName id="t17531024-25-person172">
                  William 
                  Wiseman 
               <interp inst="t17531024-25-person172" type="surname" value="Wiseman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-25-person172" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-25-person172" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am lieutenant to the company the prisoner belongs to, I have known him these five years, he always behaved as well as any soldier in the regiment, and was never suspected of any such thing in his life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-25-person173">
                  John 
                  Thornton 
               <interp inst="t17531024-25-person173" type="surname" value="Thornton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-25-person173" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-25-person173" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am ensign in the company, I have known the prisoner six years, he always behaved himself extremely well.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-25-person174">
                  Alexander 
                  Hog 
               <interp inst="t17531024-25-person174" type="surname" value="Hog"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-25-person174" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-25-person174" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am serjeant to the company, and serjeant-major to the regiment, I have known the prisoner almost eight years, he always behaved<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175310240011"></xptr> himself as well as the best man in the regiment ; he never, neglected any duty, nor came drunk or dirty to the regiment; he has received his pay of me these six years, and was always esteemed a very honest just man, there is not a man in the world has a better character than the prisoner, neither do I believe he would be guilty of such a thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-25-person175">
                  William 
                  Car 
               <interp inst="t17531024-25-person175" type="surname" value="Car"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-25-person175" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-25-person175" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner has lodged with me a twelvemonth last year, I think him to be as honest a man as ever I had in my house in my life, I never had the fellow of him, he has lain where there has been money and things of value, and never wrong'd me of a farthing. I lik'd him so well that I was going to bargain with him for another year, I would never desire a better.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17531024-25-verdict108" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17531024-25-verdict108" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
