<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17500912-74">
               <interp inst="t17500912-74" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500912-74" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500912-74" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17500912"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500912-74" type="date" value="17500912"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500912-74-off316-c425" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-74-defend580 t17500912-74-off316 t17500912-74-verdict317"></join>
         
               <p>597. 
               <persName id="t17500912-74-defend580" type="defendantName">
                  William 
                  Escote 
               <interp inst="t17500912-74-defend580" type="surname" value="Escote"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-defend580" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-defend580" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17500912-74-off316" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-off316" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-off316" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               being accessary to a felony in receiving two hundred hempen sacks, val. 4 l. knowing them to be stolen
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175009120035"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-74-person581">
                  Edward 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17500912-74-person581" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-person581" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-person581" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Clerk to Mr. 
               
                  <persName id="t17500912-74-victim583" type="victimName">
                     George 
                     Amyand 
                  <interp inst="t17500912-74-victim583" type="surname" value="Amyand"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-victim583" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-victim583" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-74-off316 t17500912-74-victim583"></join>
                  </persName>
               
            . On the 20th of January, I gave directions to 
               <persName id="t17500912-74-person584">
                  John 
                  Staples 
               <interp inst="t17500912-74-person584" type="surname" value="Staples"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-person584" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-person584" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to land forty one bundles of hempen sacks at Bear Key, four thousand and odd in number. It being too late to land them, we concluded to let them abide in the vessel all night. I saw them in it as I stood on the shore at the Key about seven o'clock in the evening. In each bundle the top sack was mark'd with a V upon it. Each sack was worth five pence half penny. The next day, according to our computation, there were two hundred wanting, two bundles being gone; they were the property of Mr. Amyand.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-74-person585">
                  John 
                  Staples 
               <interp inst="t17500912-74-person585" type="surname" value="Staples"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-person585" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-person585" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I received the aforesaid order to bring up forty one bundles of sacks from on board Captain 
               <persName id="t17500912-74-person586">
                  Woodroff
               <interp inst="t17500912-74-person586" type="given" value="Woodroff"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-person586" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to Bear Key, which I did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-74-person587">
                  Philip 
                  Brann 
               <interp inst="t17500912-74-person587" type="surname" value="Brann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-person587" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-person587" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Staples. I went on board the ship Warren, and took in forty one bundles of sacks marked with a V. I brought them to Bear-Key. I made my lighter fast, and went away about my master's business, and came back to my lighter between four and five in the morning, I found there were two bundles missing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-74-person588">
                  James 
                  Penprise 
               <interp inst="t17500912-74-person588" type="surname" value="Penprise"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-person588" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-person588" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Some time about February last, 
               <persName id="t17500912-74-person589">
                  Joseph 
                  Watson 
               <interp inst="t17500912-74-person589" type="surname" value="Watson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-person589" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-person589" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and I took two bundles of sacks from a lighter at Bear-Key, and carried them down to my house at Shadwell. About two or three days after I heard they were advertised ; and about a fortnight after that I was at Camphor's house drinking with the prisoner Watson, Camphor, and 
               <persName id="t17500912-74-person590">
                  James 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17500912-74-person590" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-person590" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-person590" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I said to Escote, I had got some sacks, and I did not know what to do with them, for they are advertis'd. He said, can I see them? Yes, said I, I have got two of them here. Watson went and fetch'd two. Escote looked on them. Said I, I wish they were in the Thames again. He ask'd how many there were of them. Said I, I have not told them; but in the advertisement, there are two or three hundred. Said the prisoner, what shall I give you for them? Said I, give me what you will. We said, he should have them for a guinea. Said he, I will give it, but you shall spend a crown at 
               <persName id="t17500912-74-person591">
                  James 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17500912-74-person591" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-person591" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-person591" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's house. We agreed to it. ( Johnson is since run away ) Then he took up a sack, and said, I'll show you how to get the mark out. He laid it down on Camphor's table, and ripp'd it down where it is sow'd, with his knife, then cut off at the top about half a yard, just below the mark. The rest of the sacks were at my house. So he and 
               <persName id="t17500912-74-person592">
                  James 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17500912-74-person592" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-person592" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-person592" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came, as agreed upon, about 9 o'clock at night and fetch'd them away. We did not receive the money till about a month after; and then we spent five shillings. I have known the prisoner two or three years, and have dealt with him very considerably for about a year. When he paid us, he said, there wanted some of two hundred, but he did not mind that.</p>
               <p>Camphor. Some time towards the latter end of February, Watson, Penprise, and the prisoner were at my house about nine o'clock in the morning. I went to draw them a tankard of beer, and gave it into Watson's hand. He bid me drink to him, I did. He said I might sit down. Escote said he must not stay for he was going towards Limehouse. They were talking to him about some sacks. He asked them what sort of sacks they were. They said they would suit him in his business, as he is a tobacconist. They fetch'd a couple of them, he said, he could find some use or other for them. They told him they had two large bundles of them. They said the advertisement mentioned two or three hundred. I fetched the advertisement, and shewed it the prisoner. They told him, they would leave the price to him. He said, he chose they should be satisfied. They agreed for a guinea, and the money was to be paid at 
               <persName id="t17500912-74-person593">
                  James 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17500912-74-person593" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-person593" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-person593" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's house, on the other side of the water, and then they were to spend a crown. The two sacks had red marks. I can't now tell the letter, they all said the marks should be taken out. I saw the mark upon the price after it was cut off, but I being backwards and forwards, did not see who cut it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-74-person594">
                  George 
                  Edmonds 
               <interp inst="t17500912-74-person594" type="surname" value="Edmonds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-person594" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-person594" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I took Penprise and Camphor. The name of Penprise was mentioned to Escote. He said, he did not know him or Watson either. But when Penprise was produced before him, he said he did know him, but never had any dealings with him. Said Penprise, you have forgot the parcel of tobacco you bought of me one Sunday morning. The prisoner seem'd speechless.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>When I was taken up, and brought before Justice Hammond, they asked me, if I knew Penprise, I said I did not till I saw him. I never had any dealings with him in my life. Camphor said, it was the day after the goods were advertised, that I bought the sacks ; Penprise says, it was about a fortnight or three weeks after; and as Watson was concerned with him, and is known to be a pawnbroker, if I had bought them, no one is to be blam'd for buying a cheap bargain of a pawnbroker.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500912-74-verdict317" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-verdict317" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500912-74-punish318" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500912-74-punish318" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-74-defend580 t17500912-74-punish318"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
