<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17580913-65">
               <interp inst="t17580913-65" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-65" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-65" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580913"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-65" type="date" value="17580913"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580913-65-off319-c493" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-65-defend611 t17580913-65-off319 t17580913-65-verdict322"></join>
         
               <p>321. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17580913-65-defend611" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Forguerson 
                  <interp inst="t17580913-65-defend611" type="surname" value="Forguerson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-65-defend611" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-65-defend611" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17580913-65-off319" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580913-65-off319" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-65-off319" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one solitaire set with diamonds, and an emerald in the middle, value 300 l.
            </rs> the property of <rs id="t17580913-65-viclabel320" type="occupation">lady 
                  
                     <persName id="t17580913-65-victim613" type="victimName">
                        Barbara 
                        Aston 
                     <interp inst="t17580913-65-victim613" type="surname" value="Aston"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580913-65-victim613" type="given" value="Barbara"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580913-65-victim613" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-65-off319 t17580913-65-victim613"></join>
                     </persName>
                   
               , widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-65-victim613 t17580913-65-viclabel320"></join>, <rs id="t17580913-65-cd321" type="crimeDate">April 15,  1754</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-65-off319 t17580913-65-cd321"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-65-person614">
                  John 
                  Shepherd 
               <interp inst="t17580913-65-person614" type="surname" value="Shepherd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-65-person614" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-65-person614" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live over against St. Clement's church, and keep a turner's and toy shop; on the 15th of April, 1754, there came a man in a brown livery, he offer'd a solitaire set round with diamonds to me, he said he did not know the value of it, but said it were diamonds: I had a gentleman in my house that was a jeweller, I carried it up to him, he said they was diamonds; I told the prisoner it was of great value, and I must stop it till he gave a good account how he came by it: he said a washerwoman found it in Grosvenor square, and gave it to him, and that he would bring the woman to me; he did not come, so I advertised it on the 22d of the same month; I advertised it three times in all, in the daily advertiser. Mr. Fielding, Mr. Welch, and Mr. Stuart came to my house about November the 4th, they ask'd to see the diamonds, I shewed them to them, they sealed them up and left them with me, and Mr. Fielding desired I would call upon him, and he would give me farther directions; I did: he told me to carry them to my lady Aston, saying they were hers. I delivered them to my lady and had a receipt of her. (The solitaire produc'd.) This is the same. I cannot swear that the prisoner is the man that brought it.</p>
               <p>Mr. Stuart. I had this solitaire from my lady Aston about 3 weeks or a month ago, she is not in town now. The prisoner lived servant with my lady Ashton in 1754, and he wore such a livery as Mr. Shepherd has mentioned. I was with him before justice Fielding, and heard him confess that he found the solitare on the carpet of my lady's house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-65-person615">
                  Mary 
                  Hencock 
               <interp inst="t17580913-65-person615" type="surname" value="Hencock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-65-person615" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-65-person615" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lived servant with my lady Astton at the time the prisoner did, he went away in May 1754, I know nothing of the solitaire.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I have lived in Staffordshire since I left my lady's service; I know nothing of what is laid to my charge.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17580913-65-verdict322" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580913-65-verdict322" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
