<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17551204-29">
               <interp inst="t17551204-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551204-29" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551204-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17551204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551204-29" type="date" value="17551204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17551204-29-off151-c218" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-29-defend266 t17551204-29-off151 t17551204-29-verdict156"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17551204-29-off151-c219" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-29-defend268 t17551204-29-off151 t17551204-29-verdict156"></join>
         
               <p>35, 36. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17551204-29-defend266" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Baynham 
                  <interp inst="t17551204-29-defend266" type="surname" value="Baynham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-defend266" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-defend266" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17551204-29-defend268" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Clifton 
                  <interp inst="t17551204-29-defend268" type="surname" value="Clifton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-defend268" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-defend268" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17551204-29-deflabel150" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-29-defend268 t17551204-29-deflabel150"></join>, were indicted, <rs id="t17551204-29-off151" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-off151" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-off151" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               the first for ravishing 
                     
                        <persName id="t17551204-29-victim270" type="victimName">
                           Elizabeth 
                           Broadben 
                        <interp inst="t17551204-29-victim270" type="surname" value="Broadben"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17551204-29-victim270" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17551204-29-victim270" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-29-off151 t17551204-29-victim270"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17551204-29-viclabel152" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-29-victim270 t17551204-29-viclabel152"></join>; and the other for being present, aiding, assisting, comforting, and abetting the said John to commit the said rape
            </rs>, <rs id="t17551204-29-cd153" type="crimeDate">July 6</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-29-off151 t17551204-29-cd153"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>The Witnesses were examined apart.</p>
               <p>Elizabeth Broadben I am fourteen years of age. 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person271">
                  Sarah 
                  Clifton 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person271" type="surname" value="Clifton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person271" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person271" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was <rs id="t17551204-29-deflabel154" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-29-defend268 t17551204-29-deflabel154"></join> at our house, the house of Mr. Wisinthorp; he works Dresden work. There are nine children of us work for him. On the 6th of July our master's child was dead, and 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person272">
                  Sarah 
                  Clifton 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person272" type="surname" value="Clifton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person272" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person272" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said it would look pretty in flowers; so I and 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person273">
                  Rachel 
                  Hannet 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person273" type="surname" value="Hannet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person273" type="given" value="Rachel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person273" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             went to Hannet's mother to get some; I was coming down St. Clement's-lane and heard 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person274">
                  Sarah 
                  Clifton 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person274" type="surname" value="Clifton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person274" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person274" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             laugh, but I did not see her; I saw a fellow apprentice's skirt of her gown in a house, so I went in there; I saw 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person275">
                  Sarah 
                  Clifton 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person275" type="surname" value="Clifton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person275" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person275" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , she asked us if we were a dry; she gave us some strong beer, after that she called for some gin. I drank some; I never tasted any before. She had brought the other apprentice and master's daughter there; she bid them go home.</p>
               <p>Q. How much gin did you drink there?</p>
               <p>E. Broadben. A middling glass, and Hannet did the same. She asked us to go to a friend's house; we said, where; she said, just up the street; we went with her, and the other two went home. We went up <placeName id="t17551204-29-crimeloc155">Clare-market</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17551204-29-crimeloc155" type="placeName" value="Clare-market"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17551204-29-crimeloc155" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-29-off151 t17551204-29-crimeloc155"></join>, and she took us to a publick house; she had hold of our two hands; she took us up stairs, and she called out John, or Thomas, bring a pot of beer. We did not stay a moment below, when we came up there was a man in the room.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there a bed in the room?</p>
               <p>E. Broadben. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. What man was in the room?</p>
               <p>E. Broadben. The man at the bar. She took and locked the door, and put the key in her pocket; after the pot of beer was brought up she bid us both to undress ourselves.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you undress yourselves?</p>
               <p>Broadben. We asked her for why; and I said, I would not; then, she said, she would undress us for us. She took hold on me, and pulled off my things.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you assist her in pulling them off?</p>
               <p>Broadben. No, they were pulled off against my will; and after that she undressed 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person276">
                  Rachel 
                  Hannet 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person276" type="surname" value="Hannet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person276" type="given" value="Rachel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person276" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I cried out while she was undressing me, she first put her hand, then a handkerchief before my mouth, and tied it round my head; she pulled me on the bed, and the prisoner was on the other side. The cloaths were thrown up, then she put me in the bed; then he came into bed.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175512040019"></xptr>Q. Was he undressed?</p>
               <p>Broadben. I did not mind that he was undressing himself, but he was naked when he came into bed.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he do when he was in bed ?</p>
               <p>Broadben. He said, don't you be frightned, my dear, I am not going to hurt you; he got upon me, and she was at the foot of the bed, and pulled my legs. I kept my legs as close as I could; she pulled my legs open, and held them open.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say any thing to you?</p>

               <p>Broadben. She bid me open my legs, and I would not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she speak to him?</p>
               <p>Broadben. No, I did not hear her.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the man do?</p>
               <p>Broadben. He put his private parts upon me at first.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he do more?</p>
               <p>Broadben. Then he put his hands upon my private parts; he put his fingers into my private parts.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he put his private parts into you?</p>
               <p>Broadben. Yes, he did afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure of that?</p>
               <p>Broadben. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any thing come from him?</p>
               <p>Broadben. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find any thing particular?</p>
               <p>Broadben. He made water upon me.</p>
               <p>Q. How far did his private parts go into yours?</p>
               <p>Broadben. Very far, as I thought.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the woman hold your legs all the time?</p>
               <p>Broadben. Yes, Sir, she did, at the foot of the bed, and I could not get loose.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you make any resistance in order to hinder him?</p>
               <p>Broadben. Sir, I strove as hard I could.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he lie upon you?</p>
               <p>Broadben. I can't say how long; I thought it was very long.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the other girl?</p>
               <p>Broadben. She was in the room by the window.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the man hurt you?</p>
               <p>Broadben. He hurt me very much.</p>
               <p>Q. You say you drank some beer and gin, was you fuddled ?</p>
               <p>Broadben. It made me a little giddy.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner say any thing to you when you drank it?</p>
               <p>Broadben. She asked me if I liked it; I said no.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the handkerchief tied round your head all the time?</p>
               <p>Broadben. It was, but not tight.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you cry out ?</p>
               <p>Broadben. I cried out sadly. She said before at undressing me, if I cried out any more, she would kill me almost; then I did not cry.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he get out of bed from you?</p>
               <p>Broadben. He did not; but when he had done I got out as soon I could.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say any thing to you at the time?</p>
               <p>Broadben. He asked me if I liked it; I said no. He asked me if I would come again; I said if he would let me go I would. She let my legs go. When I got out of bed, I dressed myself, and asked to go home; 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person277">
                  Sarah 
                  Clifton 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person277" type="surname" value="Clifton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person277" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person277" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             would not let me go; she said she was going home, and bid me stay till she went.</p>
               <p>Q. At what time was it he asked you if you would come again?</p>
               <p>Broadben. At the time he was on me. After I was out, 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person278">
                  Rachel 
                  Hannet 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person278" type="surname" value="Hannet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person278" type="given" value="Rachel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person278" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was pushed into bed. After that they had some beer, and asked me to drink. I said I wanted to be at home, and we all three went home together; this was on a Sunday.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see your master?</p>
               <p>Broadben. He let us in. He asked us where we had been; we said we had been no where but at the girl's mother's.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to say so?</p>
               <p>Broadben. Because Clifton said to us coming down the lane, if you ever mention this to any body I will kill you. He asked us whether any body had stopped us on the road; we said no body; he said, he'd ask her mother.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you come home?</p>
               <p>Broadben. It was at candlelight.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you acquaint any body with this?</p>
               <p>Broadben. Our master complained we were naughty girls for cutting his thread; and he took notice of our whispering in the kitchen with 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person279">
                  Sarah 
                  Clifton 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person279" type="surname" value="Clifton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person279" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person279" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and going so often to the necessary house, and he enquired what was the matter; this he did many times, and we said nothing. There was a handkerchief missing, and master desired 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person280">
                  Sarah 
                  Clifton 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person280" type="surname" value="Clifton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person280" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person280" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to stand at the door and watch to see who had it. Clifton wanted all the girls to lay it upon one girl. There came a gentleman, a relation of Clifton's, to enquire about it. Then we told our master we would tell him, but we were afraid; he said nobody will hurt you. We said we were afraid, for it was somebody in the house. Then he said, whoever they were they should not stay in the house a minute, if we would tell the truth. Then we both named Clifton, and told some of it; we told him about our being at the house with the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175512040020"></xptr> prisoner Clifton; after some time we told the whole; but it was by degrees.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen the prisoner Baynham since that?</p>
               <p>Broadben. Yes, I did twice. 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person281">
                  Sarah 
                  Clifton 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person281" type="surname" value="Clifton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person281" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person281" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sent me for some china to the Three Compasses, where she had borrowed it, then I saw the prisoner in a room; this was about three weeks after.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any body in that room with him?</p>
               <p>Broadben. No.</p>
               <p>Q Did he kiss you, or offer to play with you?</p>
               <p>Broadben. No. He said don't you remember I was with you above stairs; and as I was once going for some beer (as I used commonly to go of the errand.) it was dark, I met him; he asked me if I knew him (there was a lamp? ) I look'd up to his face, and said I do. Then he asked me how 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person282">
                  Sarah 
                  Clifton 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person282" type="surname" value="Clifton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person282" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person282" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             did, and desired I would bid her bring the other two girls that she had promised to bring.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is this Three Compasses?</p>
               <p>Broadben. In Little-Wild-Street.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to know the house?</p>
               <p>Broadben. Because Clifton took me to that house once before.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever seen the prisoner before the time you say he used you ill?</p>
               <p>Broadben. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. What colour were the bed curtains?</p>
               <p>Broadben. By candle-light they were green.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you stay at Putney ?</p>
               <p>Broadben. Till about half an hour after four.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you describe the man first ?</p>
               <p>Broadben. I described a tall man pitted with the small-pox, his hair tied with a ribbon, and it curl'd on each side.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he dressed?</p>
               <p>Broadben. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. Who brought up the beer?</p>
               <p>Broadben. I was in bed when the last came up; it was brought up by a fat, lusty, shortish woman; Clifton said it was Mrs. Harrison; I did not see her face.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the other girl when you was in bed?</p>
               <p>Broadben. She was sitting by the window, I believe.</p>
               <p>Q. Was her mouth tied with a handkerchief ?</p>
               <p>Broadben. No, it was not till afterwards; but I saw Sarah Clifton put her hands before her mouth when she was undressing her.</p>
               <p>Q. Had not that girl an opportunity to cry out?</p>
               <p>Broadben. She said she was affrighted, seeing how I was used.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to charge Clifton before the justice with a rape, when you went about a robbery?</p>
               <p>Broadben. I had told my master it before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-29-person283">
                  Rachel 
                  Hannet 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person283" type="surname" value="Hannet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person283" type="given" value="Rachel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person283" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am turn'd of 14 years of age; my mother keeps a school at Putney. I and 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person284">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Broadben 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person284" type="surname" value="Broadben"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person284" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person284" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             were sent to her in July last, for a nosegay to bury my master's child with; and we returned the same evening. When we came into the lane that leads to my master's house, I heard 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person285">
                  Sarah 
                  Clifton 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person285" type="surname" value="Clifton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person285" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person285" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             laugh; and 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person286">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Broadben 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person286" type="surname" value="Broadben"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person286" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person286" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             saw the sleeve of one of my fellow-apprentices in a house; so we went in (there was my master's daughter along with them) We staid there I believe above halfan hour, and all came out of the house together. (the name of the other apprentice is 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person287">
                  Ann 
                  Forbis 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person287" type="surname" value="Forbis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person287" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person287" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) Clifton sent my master's daughter and her home; and then asked me and Broadben to go to a friend of hers. We went with her to the Three Compasses in Little-Wild-Street, and up stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you see up stairs?</p>
               <p>Hannet. There we saw 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person288">
                  John 
                  Baynham 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person288" type="surname" value="Baynham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person288" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person288" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and three girls. Clifton shut the door, and I believe lock'd it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the three girls?</p>
               <p>Hannet. No, I did not. Clifton began to undress us.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were these three girls then?</p>
               <p>Hannet. They were in the room.</p>
               <p>Q. In what part of the room?</p>
               <p>Hannet. They continued in the window.</p>
               <p>Q. How old were they?</p>
               <p>Hannet. I can't tell the age of them; one was as big as me, the other as big as 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person289">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Broadben 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person289" type="surname" value="Broadben"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person289" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person289" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the other less; I was talking to these girls when Clifton was undressing Broadben; she undressed her to her shift.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Broadben make any resistance?</p>
               <p>Hannet. She cried out; but she did not leave off undressing her; she did it by force. Then she took and put Broadben by the bedside, and took and undressed me. After she had undressed me she put Broadben into bed.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the man in the room at the time of your first coming in?</p>
               <p>Hannet. He was undressing himself.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was he when she was pushed into bed?</p>
               <p>Hannet. He was then in the bed.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you when she was in the bed?</p>
         
               <p>The Second Part of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17551204-29">
                  <interp inst="t17551204-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17551204-29" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17551204-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17551204"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17551204-29" type="date" value="17551204"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175512040021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON, And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Thursday the 4th, Friday the 5th, Saturday the 6th, Monday the 8th, Tuesday the 9th, and Wednesday the 10th of DECEMBER.</p>
                  <p>In the Twenty-ninth Year of His MAJESTY'S Reign. NUMBER I. PART II. for the YEAR 1756. Being the First SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of The Right Honble SLINGSBY BETHELL, Esq; LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by J. ROBINSON, at the Golden-Lion, in Ludgate-Street, 1755.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175512040022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery held for the City of LONDON, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Hannet. I WAS sitting by the bedside, crying.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any body at the feet of the bed?</p>
               <p>Hannet. I did not mind; I was looking at 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person290">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Broadben 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person290" type="surname" value="Broadben"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person290" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person290" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. What did you see ?</p>
               <p>Hannet. I saw the man get upon her ?</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear him speak to her?</p>
               <p>Hannet. He whispered.</p>
               <p>Q. What was Clifton doing at the time?</p>
               <p>Hannet. She was holding Broadben's legs with both her hands (and open'd them) when he got upon her.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did Clifton stand at that time?</p>
               <p>Hannet. At the side of the bed.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the cloaths on her then, or was she naked?</p>
               <p>Hannet. The cloaths were not upon her; she was in her shift, and he in his shirt.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was the window from you?</p>
               <p>Hannet. That was by the fire-side; so was the bed.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were the three girls the time they were in bed ?</p>
               <p>Hannet. They sat in the window.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Broadben cry out when she was in bed?</p>
               <p>Hannet. She did.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any thing on her face ?</p>
               <p>Hannet. 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person291">
                  Sarah 
                  Clifton 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person291" type="surname" value="Clifton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person291" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person291" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             put her hand to her mouth first, and after that she put a handkerchief, and tied it behind.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was she in bed with the man?</p>
               <p>Hannet. I can't tell. I believe about an hour. When she came out of bed 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person292">
                  Sarah 
                  Clifton 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person292" type="surname" value="Clifton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person292" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person292" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             push'd me into the bed.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Clifton and you both on one side of the bed?</p>
               <p>Hannet. No. I was on the other side.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the three girls do at this time?</p>
               <p>Hannet. They were laughing.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any beer in that room ?</p>
               <p>Hannet. When 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person293">
                  Sarah 
                  Clifton 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person293" type="surname" value="Clifton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person293" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person293" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             went up, she said John bring a pot of beer directly. A man brought up one. After that there was another pot of beer brought up.</p>
               <p>Q. Who brought that up?</p>
               <p>Hannet. A fattish sort of a woman.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you stay in the room ?</p>
               <p>Hannet. I can't tell justly.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think you might be there an hour and half?</p>
               <p>Hannet. I believe longer.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you go there ?</p>
               <p>Hannet. When we went there it was duskish.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you go away?</p>
               <p>Hannet. When we went away the candles were lighted up.</p>
               <p>Q. What o'clock was it when you went home to your master's house?</p>
               <p>Hannet. I believe it was past ten, but I can't be sure.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you all three go home together?</p>
               <p>Hannet. We did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Clifton say any thing in going home?</p>
               <p>Hannet. She threatened to murder us (if we told) as we were going along.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that the reason why you did not speak of it?</p>
               <p>Hannet. It was.</p>
               <p>Q. Who open'd the door to you?</p>
               <p>Hannet. My master did, I believe, but am not sure.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say any thing to you after you got home?</p>
               <p>Hannet. He bid us come to him; and ask'd us where we had been, and what made us stay so long.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you tell him?</p>
               <p>Hannet. I told him a lye. I told him we came late from my mothers.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175512040023"></xptr>Q. Was you not in some confusion when you came home?</p>
               <p>Hannet. I was in a little.</p>
               <p>Q. How came this affair to come to your master's knowledge?</p>
               <p>Hannet. I told him. He found his substance cut to pieces and wasted; and miss'd things. And on making enquiry amongst us [there was a great noise about things being missing] we were obliged to tell.</p>
               <p>Q. How came this report of your being used ill at the Three Compasses to come out?</p>
               <p>Hannet. Because we used always to be sighing and crying; and he asked us about his things which he miss'd; and I told him that Sarah Clifton had got his things. So he went before justice Cox, and I believe the justice found the rape out.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember any thing of the rape being talked of before you was at justice Cox's?</p>
               <p>Hannet. I gave my master a little account of it; he examined me a good deal, and said he would forgive me if I would tell the truth; and I said I would tell him the whole truth about the things, and a little more.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you mean by that little more?</p>
               <p>Hannet. Then I told him something about this affair.</p>
               <p>Q. What was Sarah Clifton carried before the justice for?</p>
               <p>Hannet. She was carried there upon suspicion of a robbery. My master had turned her out at one in the morning, and would not have prosecuted her; but when she was out, I told him something about the rape.</p>
               <p>Council. So then the whole came out by degrees ?</p>
               <p>Hannet. It did.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What are the names of the three girls that were in the room?</p>
               <p>Hannet. I can't tell their names. I can only tell their Christian names, one was Polly, the other Betty, and the other Jenny.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do they live?</p>
               <p>Hannet. I don't know where they live.</p>
               <p>Q. How were they dress'd?</p>
               <p>Hannet. They were dressed fine.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to know their names ?</p>
               <p>Hannet. I went up to them; talk'd to them; ask'd them their names, and they told me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they enquire about Broadben?</p>
               <p>Hannet. They did not much enquire about her; she was in bed.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this a fore-room or a back room?</p>
               <p>Hannet. It was a fore-room.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you go up stairs ?</p>
               <p>Hannet. Clifton went up first, and we followed her.</p>
               <p>Q. Were you close to her, or farther behind ?</p>
               <p>Hannet. We were close to her.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you hold of her, or she of you ?</p>
               <p>Hannet. I don't know which now.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober ?</p>
               <p>Hannet. I was a little giddy.</p>
               <p>Q. Describe the dress of the three girls.</p>
               <p>Hannet. One was dressed in a silk gown.</p>
               <p>Q. What was her name ?</p>
               <p>Hannet. That was Polly; she was dressed best.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the man a wig or his own hair?</p>
               <p>Hannet. I saw him put a cap on. When we first came out I said it was his own hair.</p>
               <p>Q. What else did you say then ?</p>
               <p>Hannet. I said it was tied behind.</p>
               <p>Q. What colour was the cap he put on?</p>
               <p>Hannet. It was a white cap.</p>

               <p>Broadben having said nothing about three girls being in the room, she was sent for in, and Hannet put out of court.</p>
               <p>Council for the Prisoner, to Broadben. How many pair of stairs did you go up at the Three Compasses ?</p>
               <p>Broadben. We went up only one pair.</p>
               <p>C. for Prisoner. When you went up into the room, who did you see there?</p>
               <p>Broadben. There were two or three girls.</p>
               <p>C. for Prisoner. Where was 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person294">
                  Sarah 
                  Clifton 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person294" type="surname" value="Clifton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person294" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person294" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             standing when she open'd your legs?</p>
               <p>Broadben. She was at the feet of the bed.</p>
               <p>C. for Prisoner. How long were you in the room?</p>
               <p>Broadben. I can't tell how long; it was very long as I thought.</p>
               <p>C. for Prisoner. Where were these three girls when you was in bed?</p>
               <p>Broadben. They were sitting up in the window.</p>
               <p>C. for Prisoner. What hour was it when you got home to your master's?</p>
               <p>Broadben. I can't tell the hour.</p>
               <p>C. for Prisoner. What time was it when you came to the Three Compasses?</p>
               <p>Broadben. It was duskish then; and it had been raining?</p>
               <p>Council for the Crown. Was it a back or a fore-room, can you tell?</p>
               <p>Broadben. I can't tell; I did not look at the window.</p>
               <p>C. for Crown. What were the girls names ?</p>
               <p>Broadben. I never saw them before or after.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175512040024"></xptr>C. for Crown. How were they dressed ?</p>
               <p>Broadben. They were dressed very tight and neat.</p>
               <p>C. for Crown. Were you cover'd or uncover'd when you was on the bed?</p>
               <p>Broadben. We were cover'd with the bed cloaths all the time.</p>
               <p>Council for Crown. Where was 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person295">
                  Rachel 
                  Hannet 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person295" type="surname" value="Hannet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person295" type="given" value="Rachel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person295" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Broadben. The girls call'd her; and ask'd her if she should like to be their sister, and to come and live with them.</p>
               <p>C. for Crown. Were the curtains of the bed open or close?</p>
               <p>Broadben. They were not draw'd very close.</p>
               <p>C. for Crown. Had the prisoner his hat on when he went to bed?</p>
               <p>Broadben. No, he had a cap.</p>
               <p>C. for Crown. Did he pull a wig off?</p>
               <p>Broadben. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>C. for Crown. Where was 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person296">
                  Rachel 
                  Hannet 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person296" type="surname" value="Hannet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person296" type="given" value="Rachel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person296" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             when you was put in bed?</p>
               <p>Broadben. She was by the side of the bed.</p>
               <p>C. for the Crown. Where was she when Clifton held your legs?</p>
               <p>Broadben. I believe she was by the window.</p>
               <p>C. for Prisoner. Had you any conversation with the girls when you got up?</p>
               <p>Broadben. No, I had not. They asked me if I should like to be their sister, and to be as finely dressed as they were. I answered them but once; I was affrighted.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-29-person297">
                  Charles 
                  Washingthorp 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person297" type="surname" value="Washingthorp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person297" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person297" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person298">
                  Sarah 
                  Clifton 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person298" type="surname" value="Clifton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person298" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person298" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             lived with me as a servant; and looked over the children, to manage them. We had a little disturbance at our house about some goods that were missing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the two girls Broadben and Hannet belong to you?</p>
               <p>Washingthorp. Yes, they are apprentices. I have nine young girls in all. I found Clifton did not behave herself so well as she should; she begun to get drunk, and behaved very insolently. I gave her warning. After that, I found the girls behaved themselves naughty; instead of minding their work they would tear their work in pieces, and spoil a good deal of thread. They were lazy. When I found out the girl that did the mischief, I gave her correction. The things that were missing from day to day, the girl that cut the thread took upon herself. They told me there was a gang about the house that received the things. I enquired farther. I asked these two girls how they came to do these things; and by moving their Consciences, I began to discover it. But they would not tell me, till I had promised them the prisoner should not be any more in the house. Then they told me that she set them on to take the things away for her, because her time was almost out; and that she bid them provoke me as much as possible, that I might use them ill; and she would set up a cook's shop, and they might run away, and come and be with her, and they should have fine cloaths and live in pleasure. They told me part of this affair at my house, and made a more full discovery at justice Cox's.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the two girls agree in their story ?</p>
               <p>Washingthorp. They did exactly.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they tell you what was their indocement to cut the thread?</p>
               <p>Washingthorp. Only to plague me, and to cause me to use them ill, and then they would run away.</p>
               <p>Q. Does your work require young girls to do it ?</p>
               <p>Washingthorp. It does a great many.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business ?</p>
               <p>Washingthorp. It is Dre work. I went to justice Cox, being a foreigner, and desired his assistance. He sent his clerk, and he examined the girls; and they made the same discovery to him they have mentioned here. When the clerk found the thing so bad, he would have them before the justice. They were carried there, and he examined the woman and committed her.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to find out the man at the bar?</p>
               <p>Washingthorp. By the description the girls gave of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the girls searched by the direction of the justice?</p>
               <p>Washingthorp. They were, by a woman.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Washingthorp. It was several days before last sessions.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a man did the two girls describe ?</p>
               <p>Washingthorp. They described a tall man pitted with the small pox, in his own hair.</p>
               <p>Q. to E. Broadben. Was you abused by the man at the bar?</p>
               <p>Broadben. I was very much.</p>
               <p>Q. How abused?</p>
               <p>Broadben. In my private parts.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you very sure no man ever had laid with you before that time you mention.</p>
               <p>Broadben. I am very sure no man ever did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-29-person299">
                  Susannah 
                  Sanders 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person299" type="surname" value="Sanders"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person299" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person299" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I happened to go with a friend of mine to justice Cox's; I can't charge my memory with the day; there was another person called upon to examine these two girls Broadben and Hannet. I said to the clerk when he had sent them up stairs,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175512040025"></xptr> may I go up; he said yes. I went up, and the woman and I examined them; we both gave our opinion before justice Cox that the children had been pressed upon by a man. There was a great relaxation.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by being pressed upon?</p>
               <p>Sanders. I mean I apprehend a man had lain with them, especially Rachel Hannet; the other was not so much hurt as she was, but she appeared to have been lain with. I apprehend a man had forced both their bodies.</p>
               <p>Baynham's defence.</p>
               <p>A few days before I was taken up I went into the Three Compasses; the people of the house were talking of the affair of these two girls. I asked the landlord of the house who the man was; the landlord said, They will as soon swear to you as any one else if you wear your own hair. After that a man came into the house, and asked for a watchmaker with his own hair tied behind. Mrs. Harrison said there was a lawyer came about it. I went down to Brooks market, and found the man that he came to enquire for; I said don't come into the neighbourhood; he said, never you mind it for I do not. Then we came in there together; then the lawyer, named Mr. Tew, came in again and asked for Baynham; I said, my name is Baynham; he said he should be glad if I would stay, and clear myself, till he came in again, for you are (says he) of the same name, tho' I don't believe you are the same person. Then he came again, and brought with him Elizabeth Broadben, and she said I was the man. Then Rachel Hannet came, and it was half an hour before she would say it was any body; and if Broadben had not spoke first, I believe she would never have said it was me. Then I was taken away to the justice.</p>
               <p>Clifton's defence.</p>
               <p>I never was at the Three Compasses with the a girls together in my life, neither was I ever up stairs in that house.</p>
               <p>Q. to E. Broadben. What sort of a woman was it that brought up the beer?</p>
               <p>Broadben. It was a fattish sort of a woman.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you recollect her face?</p>
               <p>Broadben. No, I could not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-29-person300">
                  John 
                  Harrison 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person300" type="surname" value="Harrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person300" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person300" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I kept the Three Compasses in Little Wild-street till last Good Friday. I remember the 6th of July we had no company in our one pair of stairs room.</p>
               <p>Q. What day of the week was it?</p>
               <p>Harrison. It was on a Sunday. I was at home all that day, and had the key of that room door in my pocket all the afternoon, and was never out of the house.</p>
               <p>Q. How many are there of your family?</p>
               <p>Harrison. Only my wife, myself, and a maid.</p>
               <p>Q. Who else of you was at home that afternoon?</p>
               <p>Harrison. The maid; my wife went out.</p>
               <p>Q. How many rooms have you on a floor?</p>
               <p>Harrison. We had but two on a floor.</p>
               <p>Q. Have they both beds in them up one pair of stairs ?</p>
               <p>Harrison. Only one has a bed; and that is backwards; the other is a club room.</p>
               <p>Q. What colour is that bed furniture?</p>
               <p>Harrison. It is blue.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was your wife gone?</p>
               <p>Harrison. She was gone to a christening at Christ-Church. She stood godmother.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you company below that day?</p>
               <p>Harrison. There might be company drinking below. I remember my wife was obliged to walk it home. It rain'd very hard, and she could not get a coach.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a woman is your maid?</p>
               <p>Harrison. She is a tall and thin.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know both the prisoners at the bar?</p>
               <p>Harrison. I do. I have known Clifton some years. The man I have known since I came to that house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Clifton at your house that day?</p>
               <p>Harrison. No. I did not. I saw Baynham in the morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the girls in your house that day?</p>
               <p>Harrison. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see three other girls in your house, some of them finely dress'd, that day ?</p>
               <p>Harrison. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you live in that house now ?</p>
               <p>Harrison. No. I have left it.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to leave it?</p>
               <p>Harrison. The custom did not answer.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you live in it ?</p>
               <p>Harrison. Very near three quarters of a year. I am not in business now. I am a lodger.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you get your living now ?</p>
               <p>Harrison. I have not been out of business long. My goods were seized upon.</p>
               <p>Q. You are not a prisoner, are you ?</p>
               <p>Harrison. No, I am not.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at the two girls. Do you know them?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175512040026"></xptr>Harrison. No, I do not. I never saw them in my house till Mr. Tew the attorney came with them; he brought them to me, and told, me what they had said; and said if the thing was done in my house, I must know them; he told me they said it was done by a tall man with his hair tied behind. After that the prisoner came in and said you may as well say it was me. Mr. Tew gave the girl a little bit of a tug. Yes, said she, that is the man.</p>
               <p>Q. Before Mr. Tew came there, did not you advise him to get out of the way?</p>
               <p>Harrison. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner wear a wig or his own hair then ?</p>
               <p>Harrison. He wore a sort of a brown wig.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you account for that odd expression of his in saying (you may as well say it is me?)</p>
               <p>Harrison. He did say so.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never give him advice to go out of the way?</p>
               <p>Harrison. I was sure it was not done in my house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you say to him some time before, Mr. Tew had been at your house, and had enquired for one Baynham, and said he was described to be a man in his own hair, that was charged with a rape?</p>
               <p>Harrison. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether or not you did not lend Clifton some china, and the girl Broadben came and fetched it?</p>
               <p>Harrison. They never ask'd me for any china, and I never lent them any.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-29-person301">
                  Frances 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person301" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person301" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person301" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 6th of July last I lived with Mr. Harrison at the Three Compasses in Little-Wild-Street.</p>
               <p>Q. What day of the week was it?</p>
               <p>Jones. It was on a Sunday.</p>
               <p>Q. What company had you up one pair of stairs that day?</p>
               <p>Jones. We had none up stairs at all.</p>
               <p>Q. How are your master's rooms situated?</p>
               <p>Jones. The room the girls swear to was lock'd that day. There was no body that day in that room.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear them give their evidence?</p>
               <p>Jones. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was your mistress that day?</p>
               <p>Jones. She was gone to a christening.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did she return home?</p>
               <p>Jones. She return'd home after twelve at night. It was a very wet night.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know these two girls?</p>
               <p>Jones. No, I do not. I never saw but one, and I can't swear to her.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember a circumstance of borrowing some china?</p>
               <p>Jones. I do; but I don't know which girl it was; neither do I remember seeing her there but that once.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it usual to keep that room lock'd up?</p>
               <p>Jones. It always was, and I always kept the key. If any body had been there, I must have known it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not your master use to keep it?</p>
               <p>Jon es. No, he never did. He only keeps the key of his own room.</p>
               <p>Q. Is his own room a one pair of stairs room ?</p>
               <p>Jones. It is the fore room.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there a bed in that fore room?</p>
               <p>Jones. Yes, but my mistress had that key out with her, in her pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see any young girls there, or women of the town?</p>
               <p>Jones. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. If there were seven people up stairs in any of the rooms at any time, whether you must not know of it?</p>
               <p>Jones. I can't swear to that; this Mrs. Clifton was never up those stairs, to the best of my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What religion are you of?</p>
               <p>Jones. I belong to the church.</p>
               <p>Council. What church, the church of Rome?</p>
               <p>Jones. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Does Mr. Harrison belong to that church?</p>
               <p>Jones. Yes, he does.</p>
               <p>Q. Does his wife?</p>
               <p>Jones. They all do.</p>
               <p>Q. Is there a bed in the fore room?</p>
               <p>Jones. No, there never was.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you live there?</p>
               <p>Jones. I lived there thirteen weeks.</p>
               <p>Q. What colour is the furniture of the bed?</p>
               <p>Jones. Blue.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you go to live there?</p>
               <p>Jones. I think I went there in June, and have been come away almost a quarter of a year.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-29-person302">
                  James 
                  Lancester 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person302" type="surname" value="Lancester"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person302" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person302" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . According to the register of the child's age which was baptised at Christ-Church, by the hospital, it was the 6th of July Mrs. Harrison was godmother and I godfather; the child was baptised about five o'clock; we got there about four, and went away about eleven. It rained very hard; and it was near twelve when she got home.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there another godfather?</p>
               <p>Lancester. There was. His name is 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person303">
                  Thomas
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175512040027"></xptr> Carter<interp inst="t17551204-29-person303" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person303" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; he is cook at a tavern, and his master will not let him come.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to remember it was the 6th of July?</p>
               <p>Lancester. The mother to the child searched the register, and told me so.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Harrison. On the 6th of July last I was at the baptising of Mr. Carpenter's child at Christ-Church, in the city. I stood godmother.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does Mr. Carpenter live?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Harrison. I can't say the name of the street. I went from home a little after three o'clock, and did not return till about twelve at night.</p>
               <p>Q. Who were godfathers with you?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Harrison. I can't say I know their names; one was such a name as Glanister, but he is here.</p>
               <p>Q. Who keeps the key of the one pair of stairs room that has a bed in it?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Harrison. My husband had it that day; I always leave it with him when I go out.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you very often go out?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Harrison. I never do, but when I go to church; then I go one Sunday, and my husband the other.</p>
               <p>Q. What church do you go to?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Harrison. I go to chapel.</p>
               <p>Q. What, a popish or a protestant chapel?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Harrison. A protestant chapel. I am a protestant.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is it?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Harrison. It is in Great Queen-street.</p>
               <p>Q. Is your husband a protestant?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Harrison. Yes, he is.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person304">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Broadben 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person304" type="surname" value="Broadben"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person304" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person304" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Look at this woman, do you know her?</p>
               <p>E. Broadben. I do, this is the woman that I fetch'd the china from.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Harrison. Do you know this girl?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Harrison. I do. 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person305">
                  Sarah 
                  Clifton 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person305" type="surname" value="Clifton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person305" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person305" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             brought this girl to me once; after that she sent her to borrow half a dozen china cups and saucers, and I had them back again.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your husband at home any time when that girl came to your house?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Harrison. I don't know that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-29-person306">
                  James 
                  Dalton 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person306" type="surname" value="Dalton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person306" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a barber and perriwig-maker. I have shaved Baynham from last April.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you dress his hair?</p>

               <p>Dalton. No. I never saw his hair an inch long since I knew him. He has wore that wig ever since last Christmas, which he has on now; and since I first knew him it is above a year.</p>
               <p>Q. What trade is he?</p>
               <p>Dalton. He is a taylor.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Dalton. I live in Great Wild-Street.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never cut Baynham's hair ?</p>
               <p>Dalton. No, I never did. I have shaved his head.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to remember that?</p>
               <p>Dalton. Because I used to see him every day.</p>
               <p>Q. How often did you use to shave him?</p>
               <p>Dalton. Once a fortnight.</p>
               <p>Q. What religion are you of?</p>
               <p>Dalton. I am a 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person307">
                  Roman 
                  Catholick 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person307" type="surname" value="Catholick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person307" type="given" value="Roman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person307" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>To Baynham's character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-29-person308">
                  Thomas 
                  Fryer 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person308" type="surname" value="Fryer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person308" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Baynham thirteen years. I know he has wore a wig these five years. He lodged seven years and more in my house, in Lincoln's-Inn-Fields. I sold him a wig five years ago.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Fryer. He is a sober man, and bears a very good character.</p>
               <p>Mr. Tringfellow. I am a stay maker, and live in Little Wild-Street.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever employ Baynham?</p>
               <p>Tringfellow. No, never; he lodged with me.</p>
               <p>Q. How long?</p>
               <p>Tringfellow. Not quite a fortnight. He just came to my house before this unhappy accident.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known him?</p>
               <p>Tringfellow. I remember him better than two years. I never saw any thing of him but what was very well, as to his behaviour; he kept regular hours. I never heard him swear an oath, or speak an immodest word in discourse.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see him wear his own hair ?</p>
               <p>Tringfellow. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. What religion are you of?</p>
               <p>Tringfellow. I am a 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person309">
                  Roman 
                  Catholick 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person309" type="surname" value="Catholick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person309" type="given" value="Roman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person309" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-29-person310">
                  Walter 
                  Lack 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person310" type="surname" value="Lack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person310" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person310" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about three quarters of a year.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Lack. It is very good for what ever I knew.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>Lack. I am a taylor.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever employ'd him?</p>
               <p>Lack. Never above two days.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175512040028"></xptr>To Clifton's Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-29-person311">
                  Edward 
                  Swan 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person311" type="surname" value="Swan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person311" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person311" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Clifton about 6 or 7 months. She used the White-Hart as she went to market. I never heard an ill character of her in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-29-person312">
                  Sarah 
                  Hasllniest 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person312" type="surname" value="Hasllniest"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person312" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person312" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in St. Clement's-Lane, and have known her 3 or 4 months. I never heard any ill of her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-29-person313">
                  James 
                  Clayton 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person313" type="surname" value="Clayton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person313" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person313" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her 10 years. She lived cook to general O'Farrel, and had a very great trust upon her in the care of his house. I used, at that time, to carry the general, being his chairman. I never heard any thing to the contrary, but that she was a very honest woman. After that she kept an eating house in the Hay-Market, where I frequently used to call and dine.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen her lately?</p>
               <p>Clayton. What she has been for this year past I can give no account of.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-29-person314">
                  Peter 
                  Joanah 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person314" type="surname" value="Joanah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person314" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew her when she lived in the Hay Market. She lived in very good character there.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you live?</p>
               <p>Joanah. I then lived over against her.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Harrison again. I lived with her aunt in Shropshire; there began our first acquaintance. I never heard a bad character of her till this affair; and I have been acquainted with her 30 years.</p>
               <p>For Baynham.</p>
               <p>Hen. Baynham. I have known Baynham these 10 years; and, ever since I knew him, he bore an extraordinary good character. I remember, on the 6th of July I saw him at one Chapman's, in Dean-street, who let him blood that day, between 11 and 12 o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Baynham. I live in Little-Wild-Street.</p>
               <p>Q. What was he let blood for?</p>
               <p>Baynham. He said he was very sleepy, and had and itching in his blood. He came home with me to my lodgings; I asked him to dine with me: he said he must go a little way. He went, and returned about 1, and never was out of my lodgings till 9 at night. I lodge at the house of Mr. Gray, a brewer.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your religion ?</p>
               <p>Baynham. I am of the church of Rome.</p>
               <p>For the Crown.</p>
               <p>Hen. Raminger. I was at the taking 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person315">
                  John 
                  Baynham 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person315" type="surname" value="Baynham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person315" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person315" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I carried Eliz. Broadben, and the other girl, one after the other, to the Three Compasses, in Little-Wild-Street. First I carried Broadben: I told her, I should bring her to Mr. Harinson's house; and there were a great many people there, and bid her take a great deal of care, whom she pitched upon; because that man she pitched upon would be hanged.</p>
               <p>Q. How many people might be there?</p>
               <p>Raminger. There were, I believe, 14 men and women. I believe there were 10 men. The child looked round, and pitched upon the prisoner Baynham immediately, and said, This is the man.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body touch the girl, at the time, to give her Information ?</p>
               <p>Raminger. I did not see any body touch her; I took particular care of that. Afterwards I desired one of their company to go along with me, to see that I did not temper that child; so we went and fetched the other child. I told her the same I had done the other. We brought her there. She went into the room, and, I believe, she was 3 or 4 minutes, and looked about, but would not speak. We pressed her to say, whether the man was in company or not. In the mean time there came an attorney in. He went between the prisoner and the girl, I thought, to baffle the thing. We turned him on one side, to let the child have fair play. Then I asked the girl, whether the man was in company, or not. She said, Yes. I said, Which is the man? Point him out. She would not. I said, Where is the man? She said, He stands by the fire. The prisoner had got up from the table, and put himself between two, and stood by the fire. I said, There stand three or four by the fire. Is it he with the pint mug in his hand? She said, No. I said, Which is the man? Is it this? meaning the prisoner. She said, Yes, that is the man.</p>
               <p>Q. Who took the two girls into the house?</p>
               <p>Raminger. The attorney took the biggest, and I the least, which was Hannet. They took us up stairs, and shewed us a back room, and said, This is the room. One of them said, Here lies a mat, which I tumbled over. They said, The bed did not stand this way. We looked about, and said, The room may be altered. There lay curtains in the window; when they were taken down we did not know. At going up there is a long entry, and the turnings make it very difficult to find out which is the fore room.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the Door open when you went up ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175512040029"></xptr>Raminger. It was.</p>
               <p>Q. to Broadben. Look at this woman (pointing to Mrs. Harrison) is this she that carried the beer up to you?</p>
               <p>Broadben. I did not see her face.</p>
               <p>( Hannet was asked, and answered the same.)</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner's council. Who carries on this prosecution?</p>
               <p>Raminger. It is not me.</p>
               <p>Council for the prosecution. I'll tell you whom it is: it is Mr. 
               <persName id="t17551204-29-person316">
                  Charles 
                  Washingthorp 
               <interp inst="t17551204-29-person316" type="surname" value="Washingthorp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person316" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-person316" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17551204-29-verdict156" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17551204-29-verdict156" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The Day after the trial the two girls denied all they had sworn, and said, Their master had debauched them, and put them upon swearing as they did; upon which he was committed to Newgate.</p>
            </div1>
