<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510703-10">
               <interp inst="t17510703-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510703-10" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510703-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510703"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510703-10" type="date" value="17510703"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510703-10-off45-c74" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-10-defend94 t17510703-10-off45 t17510703-10-verdict49"></join>
         
               <p>418. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17510703-10-defend94" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Glascow 
                  <interp inst="t17510703-10-defend94" type="surname" value="Glascow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-defend94" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-defend94" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for that <rs id="t17510703-10-off45" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-off45" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-off45" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he, in a certain foot way, or open plain, near the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17510703-10-victim96" type="victimName">
                           Joseph 
                           Weeden 
                        <interp inst="t17510703-10-victim96" type="surname" value="Weeden"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510703-10-victim96" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510703-10-victim96" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-10-off45 t17510703-10-victim96"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, one gold ring, value 10 s. one pair of silver shoe buckles, value 5 s. one siber tobacco stopper, value 5 s. one penknife, value 3 d. one guinea, and 8 d. in money number'd, from his person did steal, take, and carry away
            </rs>, <rs id="t17510703-10-cd46" type="crimeDate">May 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-10-off45 t17510703-10-cd46"></join>. *</p>
               <p>Joseph Weeden. On the 22d of May last, as my wife and I were going to <placeName id="t17510703-10-crimeloc47">Old Ford</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17510703-10-crimeloc47" type="placeName" value="Old Ford"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510703-10-crimeloc47" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-10-off45 t17510703-10-crimeloc47"></join>, between <placeName id="t17510703-10-crimeloc48">Bednal Green</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17510703-10-crimeloc48" type="placeName" value="Bednal Green"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510703-10-crimeloc48" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-10-off45 t17510703-10-crimeloc48"></join> and there we passed by two men lying on a bank; we went about 2 or 300 yards on; we heard somebody coming after us, my wife was very much affrighted; as they approached within half the breadth of the court, I turned about; they swore with dreadful imprecations they would rip us up if we made any resistance; the prisoner stopped right before my wife, and the other against me. The other person had trowses on, he shoved his hand into his pocket, and pulled out a butcher's knife; my wife said, for God's sake Mr. Weeden deliver what you have; I gave him a guinea, about eight pennyworth of halfpence, a silver tobacco stopper with a cork screw in it, and a brass handled penknife; then he saw I had on a large pair of silver buckles, he stooped down and took them out, and likewise took an enamelled gold ring from my finger; the prisoner said to my wife, d - n you, your ring, madam ; he tore it off her finger, and the blood followed it, and likewise pulled up her coats to examine if she had silver buckles in her shoes, and examined her if she had any money: after this they bid us keep strait forward, and if we made the least noise in the world they would be after us in a minute. On the Friday following I advertised them, describing the prisoner, he having a remarkable nose, and the things also; and on the same day I was seat for to the sign of the India Warehouse in Fenchurch-street, and by 
               <persName id="t17510703-10-person97">
                  William 
                  John 
               <interp inst="t17510703-10-person97" type="surname" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person97" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person97" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's directions my journeyman and I went beyond Whitechapel church, where the prisoner lodged at a twopenny lodging-house; Mr. Johns and my man went into the house, we went away, and by and by the prisoner came out into the street; Mr. Johns said, there he is, we passed over the way to him; Mr. Johns knowing him, spoke to him, saying, When did you see such a one; we kept walking on almost to the sign of the Crown tavern all four of us, and another person that is not here; I asked him, as we went along, if he had never seen me before; he said no; I asked him if he did not see me on Wednesday in the afternoon betwixt Bednal Green and Old Ford; he said no; Mr. Johns stopping with another person he met with in the street, on a sudden the prisoner turned through the posts and ran back again as hard as he could; John Street and the person that is not here ran after him, calling out, stop thief, and about 2 or 300 yards off he was laid hold on by a person whom we found after was a headborough, who, as soon as I came up, told me he was a peace officer; then I gave him charge of him; he was taken to the sign of the Tewkesbury Church; I dispatched my apprentice away for my wife, though I then knew him, but I thought my wife might know him better than I, because he rifled her; when she came he was turned into a room with about 20 or 30 persons, she knew him upon first fight, and said to him, you are the man that robb'd me of my ring ; we took him before Sir 
               <persName id="t17510703-10-person98">
                  Samuel 
                  Gore 
               <interp inst="t17510703-10-person98" type="surname" value="Gore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person98" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person98" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; my wife and I both swore to him; there he was asked how he got his<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175107030006"></xptr> bread, he could give no account then; he was asked why he ran away; he said he owed a man a sum of money, and he apprehended we were bailiffs; he could give no account where he was that afternoon; he sent for persons to his character, but nobody appeared.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Weeden. On Wednesday, the second of May last, my husband and I went from East Cheap, where we live, to Old Ford, and when we got beyond Bednal Green, we saw the prisoner at the bar lying on the grass. She confirmed the testimony of her husband, and was positive the prisoner was the person that rifled her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-10-person99">
                  William 
                  Johns 
               <interp inst="t17510703-10-person99" type="surname" value="Johns"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person99" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person99" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the India Warehouse in Fenchurch street, an alehouse; a young man was with me reading the paper, and reading Mr. Weeden's, advertisement, said to me, he saw it before it was printed; I read it, and by the description of the man, said, I believe I know him; so he went for the prosecutor as before mentioned, and apprehended him; the prisoner had been : my house before. He confirmed that of the prosecutor and his wife being positive as to the prisoner being one of the persons that robbed them. John Street confirmed that of the taking him, and his mistress finding out the prisoner upon first fight.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>On the 22d of May in the morning I went down to the Keys as usual to work at delivering ships, there being no work, I came home again between 10 and 11 o'clock; my wife is a silk-winder, she was gone home with her work; I went to Black-wall, and came back again between one and two; then I went over to a neighbour's house, where was my wife, I said, Sally, are you coming home? there I sat and drank tea till about six o'clock, then I went home to my own apartment; then two young women came over and staid till between eight and nine, I went to bed about nine o'clock; the day that I was taken they came and asked for me, my wife came and said to me, they want one 
               <persName id="t17510703-10-person100">
                  Jonathan 
                  Elwood 
               <interp inst="t17510703-10-person100" type="surname" value="Elwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person100" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person100" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I said, they may find him at the India warehouse; I was in bed, but got up and ran down; when Mr. Johns saw me he said, have you seen any thing of 
               <persName id="t17510703-10-person101">
                  Jonathan 
                  Elwood 
               <interp inst="t17510703-10-person101" type="surname" value="Elwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person101" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person101" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ? I owed a man in East-Smithfield a sum of money, and I had spent about an hundred pounds, that man threatened to arrest me: when I went with this man into Whitechapel he said, young man, don't you know me; I said, no; said he, I think I have some reason to know you; said I, what is the reason? said he, you robbed me last Wednesday night: going along, Mr. Johns stopped, I thought I was going to be arrested, I saw a person, and said to him, do you know them people ? saying, I fear they are going to arrest me, so I ran away: as soon as they called out, stop thief, I stopped: when we went before the justice my prosecutor would not swear to me; his wife swore she was robbed in the second field from Bednal Green; he said she was mistaken, saying, it was half way down the lane: please to ask him that.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. She did not know the ground so well as I.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you, or did you not swear before the justice?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I did kiss the book, my lord, but I sent for my wife, because I thought she could give a more particular account than I, and that I told Sir 
               <persName id="t17510703-10-person102">
                  Samuel 
                  Gore 
               <interp inst="t17510703-10-person102" type="surname" value="Gore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person102" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person102" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-10-person103">
                  Mary 
                  Philips 
               <interp inst="t17510703-10-person103" type="surname" value="Philips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person103" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person103" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner nine months, he was at our house in the morning the 22d of May about 11 o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. By what do you know it was the 22d of May?</p>
               <p>M. Philips. I always turn my glass as the clock strikes, for I work by the hour.</p>
               <p>Q. The question is, how do you know the prisoner was at your house the 22d of May? by what circumstance?</p>
               <p>M. Philips. It was the Wednesday before the holydays, and his wife came over to me to borrow a basket to go home with her work, she brought it home a little after one, a little after two he came and asked his wife if she was going home, she said, we are going to drink tea; he asked if he might stay and drink tea too, I said, and welcome, he said, by that time we had done tea, it might be a little after five o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Who were with you at that time?</p>
               <p>M. Philips. There were my daughter and I, and they two.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there nobody else?</p>
               <p>M. Philips. No, there was nobody else.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you all this time drinking of tea?</p>
               <p>M. Philips. I was in hasle to go to work, and said to my daughter, we stay a pretty while over our tea, our sitting so long made me grudge the time, but we were not all this time drinking tea, we were some time making a fire.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did the prisoner stay at your house?</p>
               <p>M. Philips. He was there till past six o'clock.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-10-person104">
                  Anne 
                  Philips 
               <interp inst="t17510703-10-person104" type="surname" value="Philips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person104" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person104" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was at our house on the 22d of May.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know it was the 22d of May?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-10-person105">
                  Anne 
                  Philips 
               <interp inst="t17510703-10-person105" type="surname" value="Philips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person105" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person105" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My mother told me so.</p>
               <p>Q. How came she to tell you so?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175107030007"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-10-person106">
                  Anne 
                  Philips 
               <interp inst="t17510703-10-person106" type="surname" value="Philips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person106" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person106" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was asking her the day of the month then.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the occasion of your asking her?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-10-person107">
                  Anne 
                  Philips 
               <interp inst="t17510703-10-person107" type="surname" value="Philips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person107" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person107" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I don't know the occasion of asking her.</p>
               <p>Q. What day of the week was it?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-10-person108">
                  Anne 
                  Philips 
               <interp inst="t17510703-10-person108" type="surname" value="Philips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person108" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person108" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I don't know that.</p>
               <p>Q. Who drank tea with you this 22d of May you talk of?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-10-person109">
                  Anne 
                  Philips 
               <interp inst="t17510703-10-person109" type="surname" value="Philips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person109" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person109" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My mother and sister, and that young man and his wife.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did the Prisoner and his wife stay?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-10-person110">
                  Anne 
                  Philips 
               <interp inst="t17510703-10-person110" type="surname" value="Philips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person110" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person110" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . They staid till half an hour after six o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your sister there before you drank tea or after?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-10-person111">
                  Anne 
                  Philips 
               <interp inst="t17510703-10-person111" type="surname" value="Philips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person111" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person111" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She came in before we began.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you been acquainted with the prisoner?</p>


               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-10-person112">
                  Anne 
                  Philips 
               <interp inst="t17510703-10-person112" type="surname" value="Philips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person112" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-person112" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About nine months.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510703-10-verdict49" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-verdict49" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>
               </p> 
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510703-10-punish50" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510703-10-punish50" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-10-defend94 t17510703-10-punish50"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
