<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17541204-18">
               <interp inst="t17541204-18" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541204-18" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541204-18" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17541204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541204-18" type="date" value="17541204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17541204-18-off88-c161" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541204-18-defend198 t17541204-18-off88 t17541204-18-verdict92"></join>
         
               <p>22. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17541204-18-defend198" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Taylor 
                  <interp inst="t17541204-18-defend198" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-18-defend198" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-18-defend198" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17541204-18-deflabel87" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541204-18-defend198 t17541204-18-deflabel87"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17541204-18-off88" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17541204-18-off88" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-18-off88" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one thirty-six-shilling piece, and thirteen guineas, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17541204-18-victim200" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Lay 
                        <interp inst="t17541204-18-victim200" type="surname" value="Lay"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17541204-18-victim200" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17541204-18-victim200" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541204-18-off88 t17541204-18-victim200"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling-house
            </rs> of the said William, <rs id="t17541204-18-cd89" type="crimeDate">Nov. 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541204-18-off88 t17541204-18-cd89"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541204-18-person201">
                  William 
                  Lay 
               <interp inst="t17541204-18-person201" type="surname" value="Lay"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-18-person201" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-18-person201" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17541204-18-crimeloc90">King's-court, Russel-street, Covent-garden</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17541204-18-crimeloc90" type="placeName" value="King's-court, Russel-street, Covent-garden"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17541204-18-crimeloc90" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541204-18-off88 t17541204-18-crimeloc90"></join>; I am a <rs id="t17541204-18-viclabel91" type="occupation">taylor</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541204-18-victim200 t17541204-18-viclabel91"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you a house-keeper there?</p>
               <p>W. Lay. I am. On the 27th of November last I missed thirteen guineas, and a thirtysix-shilling piece, from out of a box at my bed's head.</p>
               <p>Q. Why do you charge the prisoner?</p>
               <p>W. Lay. She was my servant; my wife had occasion to go out between eleven and twelve o'clock, and left the prisoner in charge of the house; and when I came home at night, the prisoner was absconded, and I missed the money mentioned out of the box.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the box locked.</p>
               <p>W. Lay. It was not a lock box, it was a large tobacco-box, put into my wife's pocket, and put at the bed's head; the prisoner had packed up all her things, and left the key under the door. I sent in quest of her, and she was taken in St. James's-park by 
               <persName id="t17541204-18-person202">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Blackman 
               <interp inst="t17541204-18-person202" type="surname" value="Blackman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-18-person202" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-18-person202" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; she had two gold rings found upon her, for which I suppose she had changed the thirty-six-shilling piece.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541204-18-person203">
                  Grace 
                  Burt 
               <interp inst="t17541204-18-person203" type="surname" value="Burt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-18-person203" type="given" value="Grace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-18-person203" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When this woman was taken and brought into the prosecutor's entry, Mrs. Lay came down stairs, and said to her, How could you serve me so? Give me my money. She said she had none. I said, take her up stairs, and make her strip herself. Then the prisoner put her hand into her pocket, and dropped twelve guineas and a half, and two gold rings.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see them fall from her?</p>
               <p>G. Burt, I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the money wrapt up, or loose?</p>
               <p>G. Burt. It was loose.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any other people by at the same time?</p>
               <p>G. Burt. There were three or four more people in the entry when it fell.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541204-18-person204">
                  Peter 
                  Goadby 
               <interp inst="t17541204-18-person204" type="surname" value="Goadby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-18-person204" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-18-person204" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a pastry-cook in Russel-street, Covent-garden; on the 27th of November Mrs. Blackman called me out of my shop to assist her in taking a person that had robbed somebody. The prisoner ran a good deal, but I overtook her at going into an alehouse near an alley; Mrs. Blackman came up to me, and said, that is<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175412040017"></xptr> the woman, and that she had robbed Mr. Lay of some money; I think she mentioned about twelve guineas. We took her there; when she came to the foot of the stairs, she took out the money from her pocket I believe, and slung it down; I heard it chink, and saw the witnesses take it up; they said there were twelve guineas and a half of it, and two gold rings; I saw one ring.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any money fall to the ground?</p>
               <p>P. Goadby. I saw some fall.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain it did not come from any body else?</p>
               <p>P. Goadby. I am sure it did not; and I saw her hand betwixt her petticoat at the time.</p>
               <p>Q. Has she confessed any thing?</p>
               <p>P. Goady. No, she has not; but said she hoped Mr. Lay would be favourable to her.</p>
               <p>Q. Favourable what for?</p>
               <p>P. Goadby. I don't know for that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541204-18-person205">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Blackman 
               <interp inst="t17541204-18-person205" type="surname" value="Blackman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-18-person205" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-18-person205" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Lay desired me to go after the prisoner at the bar; I went as far as Pimlico, to the duke's hospital; I could not find her there; but at last I found her at a centrybox at the end of the stable-yard; then I asked her to come along with me; she said she was not afraid to go along with me, for she had stole nothing; I said, I did not know of any thing that had been lost.</p>

               <p>Q. What did you say you wanted her to go along with you for?</p>
               <p>E. Blackman. I persuaded her to come home to go to washing, and said I was to help her iron. When we came into Pall-Mall, she went into a house; I said, I did not want to drink any thing. She went backward into the yard, and looked about for a door to get out at. I followed her, there was no door; then she desired me to go and fetch the soldier from the centry-box, saying, he was a poor man, and would be glad to drink. I said I would not. Then we went to go on; she endeavoured to get away, and jumped over the kennel; I took hold on her, and broke her petticoat-string: when we came to the end of the Mews, she would go no farther till she drank; we went into a house, and did drink; she went into the yard there; then we came on to Russel-street, there we staid to hear women sing; there she staid, I could not get her along. Then I left her, and went to the pastry cook, and desired he would come with me, and take a woman; in the mean time, she ran up Jackson's-alley, and we found her going in an alley near that alley. Then we had her to Mr. Lay's house, after which I went away, and saw no more of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541204-18-person206">
                  Judith 
                  Welch 
               <interp inst="t17541204-18-person206" type="surname" value="Welch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-18-person206" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-18-person206" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the prosecutor's entry, and saw the prisoner drop the money; I picked up eleven guineas and a half, and a gold ring and a little boy that stood by picked up one guinea, and a gold ring.</p>
               <p>Q. to Blackman. Did you see her change any gold at any place ?</p>
               <p>E. Blackman. She paid for the liquor in halfpence.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I am ignorant and innocent of all they accuse me with, I never wronged him of a farthing or farthing's worth in my life. I have been a hard-working woman all my life-time; the money was my money, I saved it abroad. My husband went abroad in the time of the rebellion, and it was his hard fate to be killed at the battle of Val; I entered to be a nurse at the city of Maestricht, and I saved this to keep me in my old age. I always kept in secret to myself; I knew fifteen-pence and a bit of victuals would not keep me in habit; if they had been so full of money, they would not have sent me on the Monday to pawn a silver spoon for 1 s. 6 d.</p>
               <p>To her character.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Coulton. I have known the prisoner a good many years to be a hard-working body; I knew her abroad. I am matron of the hospital to the third regiment of guards; I have trusted her with all I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she reckoned to be worth money?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Coulton. I never asked her what money she had; she was worth money abroad after her husband was killed.</p>
               <p>Q. to Burt. In what circumstances is Mr. Lay?</p>
               <p>G. Burt. He lives well.</p>
               <p>P. Goadby. He is in middling circumstances, and bears a good character.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17541204-18-verdict92" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17541204-18-verdict92" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
