<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17531024-20">
               <interp inst="t17531024-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531024-20" type="year" value="1753"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531024-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17531024"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531024-20" type="date" value="17531024"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17531024-20-off85-c93" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-20-defend127 t17531024-20-off85 t17531024-20-verdict87"></join>
         
               <p>462. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17531024-20-defend127" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Gray 
                  <interp inst="t17531024-20-defend127" type="surname" value="Gray"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-20-defend127" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-20-defend127" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17531024-20-off85" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17531024-20-off85" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-20-off85" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing one silk handkerchief, val. 1 s. 6 d. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17531024-20-victim129" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           McPhearson 
                        <interp inst="t17531024-20-victim129" type="surname" value="McPhearson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17531024-20-victim129" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17531024-20-victim129" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-20-off85 t17531024-20-victim129"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17531024-20-cd86" type="crimeDate">Oct. 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-20-off85 t17531024-20-cd86"></join>.*</p>
               <p>John McPhearson. I live in Philadelphia in Pensylvania, and at present lodge near the Hermitage ; on the 22d of this Instant, about twelve of the clock, I was upon 'Change, and hearing a noise went to see what was the matter, I heard the people call out a pickpocket, and saw some people engaged with the prisoner at the bar. I believe he had many of his friends there, it was as much as the people could do to hold him. I got hold on him and received several blows; however we at last tied his hands, and then some gentlemen proposed searching him. I was one that searched his pockets, and saw, among many others, a handkerchief come out of his pocket, which I thought was my own, I felt and found mine gone, then I look'd at that handkerchief and found it was mine; it is a silk India handkerchief of the best sort.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you seen it before?</p>
               <p>McPhearson. I had seen it the day before.</p>
               <p>Q. Where had you been that day you lost it?</p>
               <p>McPhearson. I had been chiefly that day on 'Change; then I tied my handkerchief about his neck, and took him before a magistrate.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-20-person130">
                  James 
                  McCulloch 
               <interp inst="t17531024-20-person130" type="surname" value="McCulloch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-20-person130" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-20-person130" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Monday last, about two o'clock, I was on 'Change, and seeing a mob, I ran towards the people. I heard the people say, take the fellow and duck him, so I laid hold on him, and received a blow from some by-stander that drew blood on both my hands; he was searched and ten or twelve handkerchiefs I believe were taken out of his pocket. The gentlemen got hold on them, one said this is mine, another this is mine, and took them and went their way. When they talk'd of ducking the prisoner, he desired they would save his life, for this was the first fact he had committed. This he spoke on the open 'Change.</p>
               <p>The prisoner had nothing to say, nor call'd any witness.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17531024-20-verdict87" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17531024-20-verdict87" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acq
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
