<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570420-48">
               <interp inst="t17570420-48" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570420-48" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570420-48" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570420"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570420-48" type="date" value="17570420"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570420-48-off258-c471" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-48-defend561 t17570420-48-off258 t17570420-48-verdict261"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570420-48-off258-c472" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-48-defend563 t17570420-48-off258 t17570420-48-verdict261"></join>
         
               <p>197, 198. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17570420-48-defend561" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Maclary 
                  <interp inst="t17570420-48-defend561" type="surname" value="Maclary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-48-defend561" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-48-defend561" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17570420-48-defend563" type="defendantName">
                     Michael 
                     Sullivan 
                  <interp inst="t17570420-48-defend563" type="surname" value="Sullivan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-48-defend563" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-48-defend563" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             were indicted, for <rs id="t17570420-48-off258" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570420-48-off258" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-48-off258" type="offenceSubcategory" value="seducingAllegiance"></interp>
               that they being subjects to the crown of Great-Britain, on the <rs id="t17570420-48-cd259" type="crimeDate">1st of June, in the 28th year of his present majesty</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-48-off258 t17570420-48-cd259"></join>, did unlawfully and feloniously procure 
                     
                        <persName id="t17570420-48-victim565" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Maxwell 
                        <interp inst="t17570420-48-victim565" type="surname" value="Maxwell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570420-48-victim565" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570420-48-victim565" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-48-off258 t17570420-48-victim565"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   to inlist and enter himself to serve the king of Purssia, he being a foreign prince, as a soldier, without leave and licence from our lord the king, under the sign manual, &amp;c. and that they did afterwards retain him, with an intent to cause him to inlist and enter himself to serve a foreign prince. to wit, the king of Prussia, without leave or licence. It was also laid, for that they, on the first of June, did procure 
                     <persName id="t17570420-48-person566">
                        William 
                        Maxwell 
                     <interp inst="t17570420-48-person566" type="surname" value="Maxwell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570420-48-person566" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570420-48-person566" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   to embark on board a certain ship, in order to inlist and serve the king of Prussia as a soldier
            </rs>.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-48-person567">
                  William 
                  Maxwell 
               <interp inst="t17570420-48-person567" type="surname" value="Maxwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-48-person567" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-48-person567" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am now a <rs id="t17570420-48-viclabel260" type="occupation">soldier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-48-victim565 t17570420-48-viclabel260"></join> in my lord 
               <persName id="t17570420-48-person568">
                  Robert 
                  Manners 
               <interp inst="t17570420-48-person568" type="surname" value="Manners"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-48-person568" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-48-person568" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's regiment; the first acquaintance I had with the prisoners was in the year 1754. in April. I accidentally happened to come in company with Sullivan at the White Bear in Princes-street, Clare-market. After having been in his company often till the middle of May, I did not see him till March 1755. Then he call'd at the same house, inquiring for me They directed him to me at the Sugar Loaf, Great Queen street, Lincoln's-Inn-Fields. Then he told me there was a countryman of mine, born in the same town that I was, would be glad to drink a tankard of beer with me, and brought 
               <persName id="t17570420-48-person569">
                  John 
                  Maclary 
               <interp inst="t17570420-48-person569" type="surname" value="Maclary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-48-person569" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-48-person569" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             with him. About the 25th of May, 1755, he desir'd me to come to the house of one Saunders, at the Black Lion, White Hart Yard, Drury lane, to dine<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200072"></xptr> with him on a Sunday. I went, and we dined together, when he told me he had something particular to say to me, saying he was going to the Hermitage stairs to see for a ship to go to Holland, to merchandise in velvets and laces, and said they two were partners, and as I was a taylor I must needs be a judge of these things, and I should go along with them as a servant. I went with him to Wapping, and on our return to Mr. Saunders's we went into a house in Doctor's Commons where Maclary told me he would give me ten guineas per month, which I agreed to; this was on the first of June, and about two or three days after we all three went on board captain Huter's ship, and went down to Gravesend, then to Rotterdam in Holland. They both told me they did not design to go any farther than Rotterdam, where they should compleat their affair. We got to Rotterdam about the ninth or tenth of June. From thence we went for the city of Hamburgh, and said at a place call'd Alno. From thence to a countryman's house that lives by the side of the river that goes up to Hamburgh, where we staid all night. When we got to Hamburgh they pretended the same there, and that they must go five or six miles to an inland town, where they could suit themselves. We went in a carrivan to a place call'd Lersey in Brandenbourg, and put up at an Inn. After we had din'd and drank two or three iriss of punch, Maclary ask'd Sullivan if he had the pattern measure (which I understood afterwards was my measure ) and said he would go and speak with his master. He went out a while, and came back again, and then desir'd I'd go along with him, and likewise said he'd go and buy a horse for the man that drove the carrivan, for his was tir'd. I went along with him. When I came to the place, it seem'd like and inn yard; at the entrance of the passage we went into a little parlour on the right hand side going in. I was not there above five or six minutes before there came an officer, who look'd very hard at me. I said what does he look so hard at me for, I don't like him. They told me he was the general of the town, and we must have a pass before we could proceed, (I found that to be my passport to the regiment that I was to go to join) the officer went immediately to writing, and soon both the prisoners absconded. I could not understand what the officer said, he spoke all in German. When they had been out some time, I began to be very uneasy. When the officer had wrote what he had to do, I took it up and look'd at it. I only saw their two names, and my name. I thought it was a passport to pass us through the country. After that the officer made motions to me to go along with him. I went along with him thro' a passage, he signified to me to pull off my shoes (there was a standard) I did, and was measur'd. I had no manner of notion that they were going to sell me for a soldier, or rather a slave for life. When I was measur'd he took me into a room on the opposite side the passage, where I was oblig'd to pull off my coat, waistcoat and shirt; they view'd my carcate, as if I had been a horse for sale; then they oblig'd me to pull off my shoes, stockings and breeches, and turn'd me into the room where I was at first. Then the officer call'd for wine in great plenty, and I drank two little tumblers full. I thought I was in a strange company, and a strange country, so I refused drinking any more, and turn'd very uneasy. They saw my counternance alter, and directly sent a man that could speak English. I told him I was very glad to see him, or any that was master of the language, because I had been left by two men that were good companions, or rather guardians, for an hour and a half, and I thought it hard usage to leave me so long in strange company. He desir'd me to sit down and make myself easy. I did for a little while. He asked me to drink a glass of wine, I did, then he said to me young man, how should you like to be a soldier in this country. I said it was never my intension in my own country, and much less here, if I serve any it shall be my own native prince. He replied he was afraid I must. I looking very hard at the man, must I, said I, - yes indeed you must; for these two men that brought you here have made a property of you and sold you. I did not know how to contain myself, but said I could not believe that, if he was to swear it. He went out, and in about a quarter of an hour's time he brought in the two prisoners. I said to them, Gentlemen, what are you going to sell me out of my native country, was this your intention when you brought me out of my country. They said yes it was, and you need not think much at it, for when you come to be incorporated into the company, you will find a great many young fellows that we have sold as well as you. I strove to make my escape out of the room, when one laid hold of one sleeve, and another the other, and in the skuffle pull'd off my coat. I got into the middle of the street, and said the first man that attempted to lay hold on me I'd be the death of him. Then there came a dozen or more of grenadiers with their bayorets fix'd, who laid hold of me, and carried me into the guard house, and a centry was let over me with<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200073"></xptr> drawn swords. In that manner I sat or lay the whole night. The next morning about three I was taken away, my two hands tied cross each othe r, and thrown into a waggon, and rode all day towards Stathene in Pomerania, where I was brought before the prince they had sold me to, the prince of Bevern. Then I found there were no less than seven men sold there before me by there two men, and two others that were concerned with them. I refused to put on my regimentals or swear to the colours, till I was obliged by stripes. I served a year and four months. After that a war broke out between her Imperial majesty and the king of Prussia. On the first of October, we had a great battle at a place call Powositz. which held from seven in the morning till three in the afternoon; seven days after the battle I had the good fortune with a young man, now in court, named 
               <persName id="t17570420-48-person570">
                  John 
                  Gleed 
               <interp inst="t17570420-48-person570" type="surname" value="Gleed"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-48-person570" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-48-person570" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , that was in that action, to be sent upon a foraging party, consisting of 12 men and an officer; there we made our escape, thirty of us escaped from that place. I believe I had upwards of a thousand miles to march to Ollend; there were three of us Englishmen as they call'd us, one was Irish, one English and I was Scotch We got to Dover the 29th of Nov. where we were obliged to inlist into my lord Manners's regiment, where I now am. When I came to London, I went to several houses which I knew the prisoners frequented, and found it all to no purpose. At last I went to the house of Mr. Saunders, at the Black Lion. White Hart Yard. I asked him if he had seen them lately, he said he had not. I said you are ignorant of the injury these men have done me, and told him how they had serv'd me. Then he told me where he thought I might find Sullivan, and I went and found him accordingly.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you know whether they had any thing for you where they left you?</p>

               <p>Maxwell. John Maclary told me that very day I was told, laughing, he believ'd he should get about 20 guineas for me.</p>

               <p>Q. Where was Sullivan at that time?</p>

               <p>Maxwell. He was by then.</p>

               <p>Q. from Sullivan. Did not you receive some money from me?</p>

               <p>Maxwell. I never received any from Sullivan, only one shilling at Mr. Saunders's house, and sixpence at Hamburgh.</p>

               <p>Q. from Sullivan. Did not I buy you some cloaths?</p>

               <p>Maxwell. No, you did not.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-48-person571">
                  Roger 
                  Saunders 
               <interp inst="t17570420-48-person571" type="surname" value="Saunders"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-48-person571" type="given" value="Roger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-48-person571" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Black Lion alehouse in White Hart Yard; the two prisoners used my house about two years ago along with Maxwell; the prisoners pretended to deal to Holland, they used to drop in, and sometimes lodge there, and away again. Maxwell lay there about two or three nights. After they were gone from my house about three weeks, I received a letter from Maclary from Holland, which I have look'd for, but cannot find; it mention'd he had an opportunity of going over sooner than he expected. About three months after that they came to my house again, and the first question my wife asked them was, what have you done with the young man that went along with you?</p>

               <p>Q. Was you present?</p>

               <p>Saunders. I was. Said Maclary, he likes the country very well, and is very well settled there. I never saw Maxwell after that till some time in January last, about the latter end of which month he came and told me the hardship he had undergone after he went from my house.</p>



               <p>Q. Did he tell you the same he has here?</p>

               <p>Saunders. He did; I believe I have heard him tell it ten times, and he never varied. He desired my assistance to find out the two prisoners. I said, I did not in the least doubt finding them. While we were speaking one Mr. Scot told us where to find Sullivan, which was at the Rising-Sun, near Lincoln's-Inn fields, by the duke of Newcastle's. I went there and found him; he was a helper in the house. I said I was glad to see him, and ordered him to draw a pint of purl, which he did. While I was drinking it I said, pray when did you see Mr. Maclary. He gave me directions where to find him. Then I went to Maxwell, and we went to a house somewhere in East-Smithfield, by the Maypole; there we met with Maclary, who seem'd not to know Maxwell. We took him in hold and carried him before justice Wright, and he committed him. Then we went and took Sullivan, and he seem'd to make as if he did not know Maxwell too. He was committed also.</p>

               <p>Q. Who paid the expence at your house?</p>

               <p>Saunders. I did not look to Maxwell for any thing; they paid me. Maclary oweth me money now.</p>

               <p>Maclary's Defence.</p>

               <p>Maxwell dined there one Sunday, and paid sixpence for his dinner; we never inlisted him, or gave him any money. At the time of our acquaintance with him, he went to Holland, on his own account, as business was very slack here. If we did do it, the king of Prussia is in alliance with us, and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200074"></xptr> we did not think there would be any harm in assisting him with men.</p>

               <p>Both <rs id="t17570420-48-verdict261" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570420-48-verdict261" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17570420-48-punish262" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570420-48-punish262" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-48-defend561 t17570420-48-punish262"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-48-defend563 t17570420-48-punish262"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>

               <p>There was another indictment against Maclary for an offence of the same nature, in procuring 
               <persName id="t17570420-48-person572">
                  John 
                  Gleed 
               <interp inst="t17570420-48-person572" type="surname" value="Gleed"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-48-person572" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-48-person572" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to enter himself into the king of Prussia's service as a soldier; but, being capitally convicted, he was not tried upon that.</p>
            </div1>
