<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17541204-22">
               <interp inst="t17541204-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541204-22" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541204-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17541204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541204-22" type="date" value="17541204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17541204-22-off109-c189" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541204-22-defend231 t17541204-22-off109 t17541204-22-verdict111"></join>
         
               <p>26. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17541204-22-defend231" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Henry 
                     Govers 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17541204-22-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541204-22-defend231 t17541204-22-alias-1"></join>Debosier</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-defend231" type="surname" value="Govers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-defend231" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-defend231" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17541204-22-off109" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-off109" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-off109" type="offenceSubcategory" value="fraud"></interp>
               defrauding 
                     
                        <persName id="t17541204-22-victim234" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Addis 
                        <interp inst="t17541204-22-victim234" type="surname" value="Addis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17541204-22-victim234" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17541204-22-victim234" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541204-22-off109 t17541204-22-victim234"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   of three gold watches, value 91 l. by certain false tokens and pretences.
            </rs> +</p>
               <p>William Addis. I am a <rs id="t17541204-22-viclabel110" type="occupation">watch maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541204-22-victim234 t17541204-22-viclabel110"></join>, and have had the misfortune to be acquainted with 
               <persName id="t17541204-22-person235">
                  Henry 
                  Govers 
               <interp inst="t17541204-22-person235" type="surname" value="Govers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-person235" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-person235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , otherwise Debosier. The first time I saw<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175412040019"></xptr> him was on the 14th of July. Mr. 
               <persName id="t17541204-22-person236">
                  John 
                  Tureen 
               <interp inst="t17541204-22-person236" type="surname" value="Tureen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-person236" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-person236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             called upon me, and acquainted me he had recommended me to a Spanish merchant, that was just arrived from Spain. On the 13th of July he brought two gold enameled cases, for me to make two watch-movements into them. The next day, which was the 14th, Mr. Govers came with Mr. Tureen, who told me he was a Spanish merchant; that he not only had commissions from Spain, but from several other parts of Europe beside; that he had general commissions for watches and jewels. I gave him no credit at all then; he said he was in hopes I had put in hand the two movements for the cases.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he speak to you in English?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. No, he did not at that time; he spoke French to Mr. Tureen, and Mr. Tureen English to me.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the next time you saw him?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. It was on the of July; he and Mr. Tureen came to, he spoke French to Mr. Tureen, and Mr. Tureen, could not stay, so he left, then Mr. Govers went back into the parlour, in English, but I could understand him; he told me he had commissions from Spain for a gold repeater, and a plain gold watch, called and jeweled, which watches he must absolutely send away by the packet the next day. I kept a workman up the best part of the night to finish them, and finished them the next day by twelve o'clock; I not knowing him, insisted upon some security for these watches before I delivered them; he gave me his own note, payable to Mr. Lefebure at two months for 65 l. upon which I gave him the watches. The note was signed by 
               <persName id="t17541204-22-person237">
                  Henry 
                  Govers 
               <interp inst="t17541204-22-person237" type="surname" value="Govers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-person237" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-person237" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             payable to Mr. Lefebure, and indorsed by Lefebure to me.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you deliver them?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. I delivered them on the 20th of July last, at which time he told me he was going to be married to a lady of great fortune, and that Mr. Renea, a taylor, in Leicester-fields, was making the cloaths for the wedding. On the 26th of the same month he came to me, and told me a friend of his that came with him from abroad, who was then forty miles from London, wrote to him and desired him to buy him a horizontal gold watch, upon which pretence I let him have a gold watch, value 26 l.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say what price must it be?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. No, he did not say what price his friend did fix for to it.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any other security for the payment of that watch but his pretence of being a Spanish Merchant.</p>
               <p>W. Addis. No, none at all; that watch he was to return me again in a fortnight's time, or the money. Every time he was in my company he used often to talk of a lady that he was going to be married to; on the 24th of August he came to me again, and waited from twelve to seven at night, for two other movements, value 11 l. The fortnight was then expended for the 26 l. which he was to pay, or return the watch, that was the time I intended to demand the money of him, the time being expired, he waiting in my parlour for these two movements; I being obliged to go out among my workmen to get these movements finished. I intended to have brought an officer to have arrested him for 26 l. and likewise to have better security for the 65 l. but before I left him he pulled out several letters from his pocket, saying, I have commissions from Spain for four or five thousand pounds in watches and jewels.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he shew any letters ?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. He shewed me two, and said they were from his correspondent in Spain, with the commission; at that time he pretended he was a Spanish merchant, as he always did; upon these pretences, and at the same time his pulling out six gold watch cases, un, telling me he would bring them with six more for me to make movements to go into them, occasioned me to alter my resolution of arresting him, and I also let him have the two other watches, value 11 l. into enamelled cases that I had of him before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he deliver those six cases to you then?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you call the movements, watches, without the cases?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. We do.</p>
               <p>Q. How soon did you hear of those two watches that he had of you on the 20th of July, one of 45 l. the other 20 l.</p>
               <p>W. Addis. The week after we missed him, it was near the latter end of August. I was informed they were both pledged with one Mr. Watson, a pawnbroker, at the corner of Piccadilly.</p>
               <p>Q. What day did you hear of his absconding?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. On the Wednesday after the 24th of August we made all the inquiry we could, sending<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175412040020"></xptr> messengers to divers parts of England, where it was likely to find him. I heard he intended to go to Calais. I went with two gentlemen to Watson's, there I found the two watches, and gave him 31 l. 10 s. for them, the same money he said they were laid in for.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon whose information did you go there?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. I went there upon the information of Mr. Tureen.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you got the other watch?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. I have got them all again; I found the other watch at Mr. Dallin's and Warren's; they keep a register-office. That is the watch, value 26l. deposited for 14l. (all three produced in court).</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner taken before a justice of the peace?</p>
               <p>W. Addis, I was with him before justice Fielding; I charged him before the justice with taking these goods in the manner I have given my evidence here.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say in his defence?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. He said, he would make no reply till he came to a proper place.</p>
               <p>Cross-examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you been acquainted with Mr. Tureen.</p>
               <p>W. Addis. About three months.</p>
               <p>Q. What is he?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. He is a broker to the watch jewelers, that is, to deal between the jewelers and finishers, and he is a jeweler besides.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you deal in?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. I deal in jewels and plate.</p>
               <p>Q. How many customers had Mr. Tureen recommended to you before this?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. Never a one. I have a very good opinion of Mr. Tureen; he told me he believed Govers to be a rich man, and that he was a Spanish merchant, as he declared himself to be.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he had known him before?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. He said he had known him in France.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he was of any trade in France?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. I do not remember he told he was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he give you any account of his family ?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. He did not; I believe Mr. Tureen believed him to be a man of credit, or he would never have been taken in for four or five hundred pounds by him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you he was a man of credit?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. He told me, before I saw Govers, he believed he was a rich man; but not to trust him on his word, but to take all the precaution I could, as of a stranger; he said, he told him he was a merchant, and did not distrust his being such.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath, when M. Tureen applied to you, did not he tell you that Mr. Govers was a man of credit, and you might trust him?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. He did not; he told me he believed he was a Spanish merchant, which he pretended to be; but bid me take necessary precautions of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ask him whether he knew he was a merchant?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. I did, and he said he did not know. The first time he came to me, he said he had met a Spanish merchant at Tom's coffee-house, whom he had recommended to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he come with Mr. Govers the first time he came to you?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. He did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Govers talk to you in English?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. No, Tureen interpreted to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Then you know not what Govers said, but from what Tureen told you?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. The next time he came, was Tureen with him?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. He was; but he left me immediately: then Govers told me he had a commission from Spain for a repeating gold watch, and a plain gold one, capt and jeweled.</p>
               <p>Q. If this man had come a stranger to you, and told you he had been a Spanish merchant, and if he had not been recommended by Tureen, should you have trusted him?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. I should not if he had not shewed me the pretended commissions.</p>
         
               <p>The Second Part of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17541204-22">
                  <interp inst="t17541204-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17541204-22" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17541204-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17541204"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17541204-22" type="date" value="17541204"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175412040021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 4th, Thursday the 5th, Friday the 6th, and Saturday the 7th of DECEMBER.</p>
                  <p>In the Twenty-eighth Year of His MAJESTY's Reign. NUMBER I. PART II. For the YEAR 1755. Being the First SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of THE RIGHT HONOURABLE 
                  <persName id="t17541204-22-person238">
                     STEPHEN THEODORE 
                     JANSSEN 
                  <interp inst="t17541204-22-person238" type="surname" value="JANSSEN"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17541204-22-person238" type="given" value="STEPHEN THEODORE"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17541204-22-person238" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Esq; LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by M. Cooper at the Globe, in Pater-noster Row. 1755.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175412040022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery held for the City of LONDON, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Q. IF he, a stranger, had come to you, and produced a parcel of letters which you did not understand a word of, and said they were commissions from Spain, should you have trusted him with sixty-five pounds?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. I should not, had I not heard he had had dealings with other people.</p>
               <p>Q. Should you have trusted him upon those tokens, without you had heard of him from other people?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. I should not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you paid any part for any of these things?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. I was for the two watches I made first 11 l.</p>
               <p>Q. Who paid you?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. Mr. Tureen paid me. (He is showed the receipt, and acknowledges it).</p>
               <p>Q. Should you have trusted him on these pretences 65 l. unless he had given you a note.</p>
               <p>W. Addis. I should not.</p>
               <p>Q. When were these two movements ordered to be made up.</p>
               <p>W. Addis. They were ordered, and the two cases brought to me on the 14th of July.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he pay you for them before you trusted him with the second order?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. No, it was afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the note given?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. On the 20th of July, payable in two months.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the note ever paid?</p>

               <p>W. Addis. No, it never was.</p>
               <p>Q. Were these two new watches?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. One of them was a gold repeating watch, it was not the worse for wear, though not quite new, but worth more money than I charged.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Tureen come with him the third time ?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. He did.</p>
               <p>Q. I suppose his paying the 11 l. gave you the more faith in him.</p>
               <p>W. Addis. It did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he every time he came into your room say he was a Spanish merchant?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. He was always talking of his commissions.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you conceive of him as a Spanish merchant, when he talked of buying a watch for a friend forty miles off?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not he, before he went abroad, write to Mr. Tureen, or any of his creditors, and desire a meeting of his creditors.</p>
               <p>W. Addis. Where the letter was dated I can't tell; his creditors were all of them waiting for him at Mr. Lefevre's, at which time he was at my house, and had I known it, I should have taken proper care of him.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. This was on the 24th of August; but I was not present at that meeting.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he shew you any names in those commissions?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. He shewed us two letters with names to them.</p>
               <p>Q. What were the names?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. I don't know what names they were; he opened them, and said there were commissions in those letters; I was not capable of reading them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he read them to you?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. He did in broken English, the purport of which was, for several thousand pounds worth of jewels, and three dozen of gold watches.</p>
               <p>Q. Then they might be real letters for aught you know?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. They might.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175412040023"></xptr>Q. Was you at Mr. Fielding's ?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he committed?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. He was, to the Gatehouse.</p>
               <p>Q. At whose suit?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. At several more prosecutors suits besides mine.</p>
               <p>Council for prosecutor. We admit there were twenty of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you all sign the order to carry on the prosecution?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. I sign, I can't say they all do.</p>
               <p>Q. Are there more than five subscribe ?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. There are</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. I first knew the prisoner by the name Govers.</p>
               <p>Q. When was you first acquainted with him?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. Thirty-two years ago in Paris; I was in company with him in England seventeen years ago, when he and I were journeymen; he was a jeweler, and was an apprentice in Germany; after that time I never saw him till the beginning of last June, then I met him at Tom's coffee-house with Mr. Lefevre; I had not seen him for sixteen years before; he invited me, when at the coffee-house, to come and see him at his lodgings; I had heard before his father was reduced, and very poor. I went to Mr. Govers's lodgings on the 12th in Greek-street, Soho; he complained to me his workmen did his work very slowly, and wanted me to recommend a watchmaker to him. Then I said I knew a very good workman; naming Mr. Addis. Then he said, I will give you a couple of watch-cases to have them done, and afterwards I shall give you a couple of dozen of watch-cases, if he will do them quick, because he said he was in a great hurry, having some other goods to send abroad, saying he had four dozen then to do. This was on the 12th of July; he desired me not to forget to go to the watchmaker, and tell him; and I carried the cases on the 13th; then on the 14th he desired me to go with him to the watchmaker's, which I did, to Mr. Addis.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you known Mr. Govers then?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. I had known him about a month.</p>
               <p>Q. In what character did he pass that month?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. He said he was going to be married to a lady of great fortune, and that he was a merchant for Spain and Portugal.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever heard he was a merchant before?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. No, I never had. He told me he had sold things to the king of Poland a twelvemonth before. I was present in his lodgings when he sent for his taylor to be measured for his cloaths, and he told the taylor (this for a ceremony) which induced me to believe he was going to be married. I recommended him, after this, to my acquaintance, under the character of a Spanish merchant, and one going to be married. I was with him when he agreed for the repeating gold watch and the plain one: they were ready made, but there was something to be done to them, and they were not delivered to him that night.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you yourself dealt with him for any thing?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. I have for 330 l. After he had bought these two watches, he gave orders for two other watches to be made.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear any conversation between him and Mr. Addis, he telling him what he was?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. I have heard him tell Mr. Addis he was a Spanish merchant, &amp;c. but I was not with him when the commissions were produced.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Mr. Govers's father?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. I do, but I never had any dealings with him.</p>
               <p>Q. What was his business?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. He was a snuff-box-maker.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he not a jeweller?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. No, he was no jeweller, but he dealt in jewels.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner serve this time with him?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you know the prisoner in London?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. Seventeen years ago; I never saw him from that time till June last.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether he was a jeweller or a merchant can you tell?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. It was to my great surprize to see the prisoner appear as a gentleman here. I have heard his father was very poor when he died.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath can you take upon you to say the prisoner was not a merchant?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. I cannot answer to that; I never heard he was one till he told me so himself; he told me he has been in Constantinople, and all over Europe. I don't know what he has been.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175412040024"></xptr>Q. What do you call yourself ?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. I call myself a jeweler. I have been a merchant for seven years. I have been seven years without working.</p>
               <p>Q. Then if a jeweler does not work, but deals in jewels, he is a merchant?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. Yes sir, I am a jeweler now, and deal too.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you apply yourself to him at Tom's Coffee-house in order to be employed by him?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. No sir, he desired me to come and see him; he was very polite and civil to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you apply to him as an acquaintance of his father's, and hoped you should be employed by them?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. No sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you recommend him to Mr. Addis?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. I did, and said, I hoped he would be a good customer.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that true of false that he was going to be married to a great fortune; will you take upon you to swear he was not going to be married?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. I can't tell such a thing of a foreigner, he made me believe he had paid about three thousand pounds in less than two months time for goods sent abroad.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you swear he had not?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. I can swear nothing; but I think he cannot have done it; I know his goods were in pawn.</p>
               <p>Q. Will you swear all the goods he bought were in pawn?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. No sir; but I wish they were.</p>
               <p>Q. Don't you know of your own knowledge he has made several payments?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. He has, some trifles ?</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you what was done with the goods?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. He said he would send them abroad, but he pawned them directly.</p>
               <p>Q. You say that Mr. Govers told you he has employed workmen to whom he has paid three thousand pounds for work done for him.</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. Yes sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you say he has pawned those goods done by these workmen?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. Part of them.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. I found it out by going about?</p>
               <p>Q. What part?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. Silver plates, watches, and rings.</p>
               <p>Q. How many watches?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. Above a dozen, and above a dozen watch-cases, either he or a man that he had to pawn them for him.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know they were pawned by his orders?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. I know the man that pawned them for him.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know that of your own knowledge?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. He told me so himself, and I went and found the identical goods in the pawnbroker's hands.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you yourself did ever offer any goods to Mr. Govers for sale?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. Several times I did; the more is my misfortune.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever offer him goods that he did not buy?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. No, none but what he has bought, except when we could not agree in the price; but the reason why he did not buy was, that the people wanted ready money that the goods belonged to. When I offered him any other people's goods he would say, I will give you so and so, and a couple of guineas for yourself upon the nail; but the people wanting ready money, was the reason the price did not answer.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you a creditor of Mr. Govers?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. I am; he owes me money.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there a letter sent to desire a meeting of his creditors?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. There was; but he only pretended, he never went abroad at all, I believe.</p>
               <p>Q. Whose goods were the silver plates ?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. They were Mr. Tamphire's.</p>
               <p>Q. Whose the watch-cases?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. They were Mr. Ferron's, and the watches Mr. Addis's.</p>
               <p>Q. At the time of the advertisement had you any notion that he had deceived any body by false tokens?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. Yes, to be sure, I looked upon him to be a great defrauder.</p>
               <p>Q. In what manner was he brought to justice?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. He was discovered by a letter.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you first see him afterwards?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. Mr. Rennie brought him to an officer's house in the Strand; I saw him coming out of the house.</p>
               <p>Council for prosecution. You make these two distinctions, he that works in jewels, you call a jeweler, but he that deals in jewels unmanufactured as mere merchandize, you call a merchant?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175412040025"></xptr>Mr. Tureen. Yes I do; this I call a merchant jeweler, a diamond merchant gets people to work for him, and sends them abroad.</p>
               <p>Council for prosecution. Do you believe now that was a pretence that he was going to be married?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tureen. I believe that was only a pretence in order to defraud the people?</p>
               <p>Council for prosecution to Mr. Addis. Look at that paper. Do you know that hand-writing, have you seen the prisoner write?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. Yes, I have several times. ( He looks at it) I am sure this is his hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Council for defendant. Where did you see him last ?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. I saw him before justice Fielding.</p>
               <p>Q. Don't you know that his rooms were broke open by Mr. Fielding's order?</p>
               <p>W. Addis. I don't know that.</p>
               <p>Mr. Robinson. (He looks at the two letters.) I know Govers's hand-writing, and I believe them to be his hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you swear to it?</p>
               <p>Mr. Robinson. I can.</p>
               <p>Council for defendant. Did you not promise to forgive that man if he would let you into the secret of making snuff?</p>
               <p>Mr. Robinson. I never thought of such a thing.</p>
               <p>Council for defendant. Did you know any thing of these advertisements?</p>
               <p>Mr. Robinson. (He looks at them.) On the 24th of August last, this man, instead of paying me a note that became due, ran away. When he had so done, he wrote a letter, and it came to us on Sunday, and there you'll if find he says expresly, I have ordered the person that I have left this letter with not to give if you till Sunday, that I may have time to make my escape. The gentlemen on the Sunday night got together, and did not know what to do, and Mr. Lefevre went post to Calais, and there he intercepted a letter that was wrote to Madame de La Chapelle. In this letter we found out many proceedings but when this advertisement was made out, I was out of town, and did not know of its being put in. We were first informed there were upwards of two thousand pounds in goods he had bespoke in hardware, quantities of lace, and other things that were looked out to be sent in to him on the Monday morning, but he ran away on the Saturday, therefore this advertisement was put in the paper in order to take him, but I find we are blamed for advertising this large sum.</p>
               <p>Council for defendant. Don't you know it was proposed in that letter to his creditors to pay them as far as it would go?</p>
               <p>Mr. Robinson. No, it is no such thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541204-22-person239">
                  Thomas 
                  Leretondale 
               <interp inst="t17541204-22-person239" type="surname" value="Leretondale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-person239" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-person239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I understand the French language.</p>
               <p>Council. Look at this letter.</p>
               <p>T. Leretondale. I have seen it before.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you made any translation of it?</p>
               <p>T. Leretondale. I have it here in writing. ( He delivers it to the clerk of the arraigns. It is read.)</p>
               <p>'' A thunderstroke which has just crushed me to '' pieces, obliges me to provide immediately for '' the security of my person; it is not that I am '' doubtful of the goodness of your intentions '' towards me, although I have the misfortune to '' owe you sufficient considerably to disorder your '' affairs; yet I flatter myself that you will lend '' your assistance to facilitate the means for paying '' you, in granting me sufficient time to enable me '' to settle my affairs. But there are others, who, '' perhaps, may seek my destruction, and who '' in destroying either my reputation, or otherwise, '' would, by endeavouring to seize on my '' person, deprive me of all the means to enable '' me to satisfy them so long as I live. I therefore '' beseech you to take upon you to call a '' meeting of Messrs. Addis, Tureen, Robinson, '' Tribe, La Basle, Ferron, Rennie, my silversmith '' for large plate, in order to give me '' a letter of licence for three years; I offer to '' pay down, on the signing of it, the first year's '' interest, at the rate of 5 l. per cent. by the '' year, the interest of the second year at the end '' of two years from this time; and in the third '' year your principal in full.</p>
               <p>'' I ask it as a favour of you, as well as of all '' the rest of the gentlemen, not to examine into '' the wrongs that I may have committed by '' dissimulation, and my bad behaviour; I '' thought it was necessary to enable myself to '' continue my commerce, and that I could no '' longer do so, but with ready money, and that '' I must consequently use the precaution of keeping '' by me sufficient effects to enable me to pay '' you in ready money for what other dealings I '' might have with you for the future, if you '' should grant my request.</p>
               <p>'' I hope neither you, nor those gentlemen, if '' they will but regard their own interest, will '' divulge to the world my affair, because I tell '' you frankly that I will not appear. If you '' don't grant me the time in good form, I shall<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175412040026"></xptr> '' take care, even at Calais, to conceal myself '' so secure, that I will confer with nobody, not '' even with any one of you should you come '' there; and that in case you should think that '' in pursuing me to France, or elsewhere, you '' would compel me to do what is impossible, '' that you would be paid; I have the honour '' to assure you the contrary, and that you would '' put me to the hard necessity, against my inclination, '' to conceal, myself from every body '' living, and will consequently lose all your dues, '' instead of which, by a speedy determination to '' give me my liberty, and preserve my reputation, '' I shall instantly return and present myself '' before you, that you may be witnesses of '' my good conduct, and of the care and pains '' I shall take to fulfil my new engagements that '' I shall contract with you. Be persuaded that '' I shall give you, as well as those gentlemen, '' always the preference in my dealings for ready '' money, having no further hopes of any credit. '' You know my affairs require my residence '' in England, therefore don't compel me '' to forsake them. It is impossible for me to '' propose terms more for your advantage at present, '' I know my strength, and I can do no better, '' and I will not fall into the necessity of asking '' you further favours, than those for yours and '' my interest, which is to determine speedily, '' what you intend to do. I shall wait at Calais, '' time sufficient for your answer, hoping you'll '' write by Monday se'nnight, the 26th of August, '' beyond which time I must tell you, that '' I shall provide for my greatest safety.</p>

               <p>'' I reserve the particularizing my losses, my '' misfortunes, until I may, with safety, come '' among you, you will then clearly see I can do '' no otherwise; I hope that all this considered for '' yours and my interest, you will send me without '' delay a favourable answer that will enable '' me at all times to be</p>
               <p>'' your sincere servant, '' 
               <persName id="t17541204-22-person240">
                  Henry 
                  Govers 
               <interp inst="t17541204-22-person240" type="surname" value="Govers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-person240" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-person240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .''</p>
               <p>'' N. B. If I have the misfortune not to hear, '' from you by the return of the post, '' I must tell you I shall pursue my '' journey.</p>
               <p>'' You will, without doubt, be surprized that '' you received my letter but to-morrow; Sunday '' I left it with a person with orders not to give '' it you before that day, that I might have time '' to make off. I shall repeat my humble request '' to send me your answer by the return '' of the post of next Monday, directed to 
               <persName id="t17541204-22-person241">
                  H. 
               <interp inst="t17541204-22-person241" type="given" value="H."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-person241" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            '' Govers, at Mr. La'Sambier's in Golden-head '' street, at Calais.''</p>
               <p>London, Saturday, 24 Aug. at 7 o'clock at night. For Mr. 
               <persName id="t17541204-22-person242">
                  Louis 
                  Lefevre 
               <interp inst="t17541204-22-person242" type="surname" value="Lefevre"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-person242" type="given" value="Louis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-person242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>L. Lefevre. I set out from home on Monday the 26th of August, and got to Calais on the Tuesday about twelve or one. I went to the governor there, he directed me, to go to the king's attorney, which I did; I found the prisoner was not come there, the next day I found a gentlewoman who passed for Mrs. Govers. I examined her whether she had any goods of mine. She had nothing but her own cloaths. I asked her if she knew the prisoner, she said no; the post-man came in while I was searching her, and these and two letters I have in my hand which he brought in, one inclosed in the other; I know them to be the hand-writing of Govers. She said I used her very ill, but I told her what I did was by the authority I had from the king's attorney.</p>
               <p>Q. to the translator. Look at this, (the inclosed letter) have you a translation of it?</p>
               <p>Translator. I have here a true translation. (He delivered it to the clerk of the arraigns.)</p>
               <p>Council for prosecution to Leretondale. Is this a true translation?</p>
               <p>Leretondale. It is; I have examined it. (It is read.)</p>
               <p>London, Aug. 26, 1754.</p>
               <p>'' Will fortune never tire herself in persecuting '' me? Persidious and cruel as she is, I defy her, '' if she does but esteem her whom Ladore.</p>
               <p>'' The amiable qualifications of thy soul, dear '' and tender friend, which have inspired mine '' with a flame as lively as it is delicate, assure '' me, that if the capricious and barbarous don't '' do justice to your read, ment so much as she '' ought, at least she'll respect your virtue. I '' went home so soon as I left you; I surmised '' that my motions were observed; I kept myself '' upon my guard, and well I did; for my presence '' of mind urged me to take all necessary '' precautions; I sent a trusty person to my lodgings '' to get intelligence, and he was told several '' persons had been to inquire for me, one '' after another, who seemed very anxious and '' uneasy. I took a coach, and drew up the '' shutters, and was drove in and about my own '' neighbourhood, where I perceived I was watched '' by several persons who surrounded my lodgings, '' in expectation of seeing me go in or out;<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175412040027"></xptr> '' I therefore resolved to leave behind me my '' linen, my cloaths, my sword, and other effects, '' which I wanted to fetch away, thinking it rather '' better to leave them to chance, than risque my '' being surprised. I ordered the coach to drive me '' to the Post-office, to take post-horses; but there '' I perceived two persons who, upon Change had '' that day presented me with some notes for payment, '' just become due. What could I do? They '' perhaps might have planted somebody upon the '' roads to stop my journey; I then ordered the '' coachman to drive me to the further end of the '' city, and I left my coach, and went and took '' water, and got into a tilt-boat, and wandered '' about upon the Thames till night drew on: '' chance, which governs every thing, threw in '' my way the friend to whom you will direct my '' letters; upon seeing the regard he had to my '' welfare, I trusted him with my secret, and we '' immediately resolved to walk about without the '' city a part of the night, then return into the '' city and take a coach, and again go upon the '' water, and then walk again, and then went '' into a tavern, and lay at a bagnio, from '' whence I actually write to you, my dear friend.</p>
               <p>'' But what! adorable Beaujour, methinks I '' hear you sigh. My tender heart informs me '' yours suffers, and that your charming eyes '' drop tears on account of my fate. No, no, '' I mistake; my love informs me that is not the '' principal cause of their grief; it is because I '' am so unfortunate as not to be near enough to '' wipe them. Come, my sweet angel, let us '' take courage, and expect every thing from '' time and our intimacy.</p>
               <p>'' Stay at Mr. La'Sambier's until the storm is '' over, or a little calmed; I endeavour to give '' them the change (that is, to baffle them).</p>
               <p>'' I wrote to Mr. La'Sambier on the cover of '' this, that you are to arrive, if you are not already, '' at Calais, that he should give you this '' letter, that some letters are to come there for '' me, that I desire him to put them into your '' hands, in the name of 
               <persName id="t17541204-22-person243">
                  Henry 
                  Govers 
               <interp inst="t17541204-22-person243" type="surname" value="Govers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-person243" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-person243" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and '' you will send them to me, directed as follows, '' To Mr. Beaujour, at Mr. Rennie's, against the '' White-horse, in King-street, Golden-square, '' London.</p>
               <p>'' N. B. Well understood that you will put '' them under love above-mentioned, take great '' care to recommend discretion to Mr. La'Sambier; '' tell him I am somebody for whom you interest '' yourself; that I have had misfortunes, that I '' am obliged to take measures with my creditors; '' that if any one writes to him, or any one in '' Calais inquires of him if I am there, and '' where I am, let him answer simply that I '' thought proper to secure myself at Calais until '' other orders. Be punctual in writing to me, '' don't lose one post, I'll do the same; let what '' will happen, I repeat it to you once more, '' stay at Calais until matters are decided in one '' shape or other; rely upon my love, that will '' last as long as I live; it is Beaujour who swears '' to you; thy soul shall be my surety; rest contented, '' preserve those days in which mine are '' attached. Adieu, dear and tender friend; to '' God I recommend you; I mean the god of '' love, until it is possible for me to come and prove, '' in your arms, the vivacity of my sentiments.</p>
               <p>'' It is owing to the managing my affairs '' as I have, that my creditors believe that I '' have baffled their vigilance, and am got to '' Calais. I mention to Mr. La'Sambier that I '' shall arrive forthwith; it is being fearful of his '' indiscretion that makes me so cautious.''</p>
               <p>Council for prosecution. Read the other. ( It is read.)</p>
               <p>London, the 24th Aug. 1734.</p>
               <p>'' Sir,</p>
               <p>'' I have the honour to inform you, that '' Madame de La'Chapelle is set off from here today '' for Calais. I beseech you to be so good '' as to give the inclosed into her own hands, and '' to none else; it is a letter in which she is '' interested.</p>
               <p>'' I hope you would willingly do me the favour '' to receive the letters which may come '' for me directed to you, and to give them to '' Madame de La'Chapelle, who will pay you the '' postage, in case she be arrived in your city '' before me.</p>
               <p>'' I will do my best to prove to you that I am '' worthy to be,</p>
               <p>'' Sir,</p>
               <p>'' Your most humble servant, '' 
               <persName id="t17541204-22-person244">
                  Henry 
                  Govers 
               <interp inst="t17541204-22-person244" type="surname" value="Govers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-person244" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-person244" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .''</p>
               <p>To Mr. La'Sambier, in Golden-head-street, at Calais.</p>
               <p>Q. to Lefevre. How long have you known the defendant?</p>
               <p>L. Lefevre. I knew him in France from a child; he was a neighbour of mine: he came to me about the beginning of May last, and told me, he was sent by a company, and that he was to deal<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175412040028"></xptr> very largely in several branches, of trade for Spain and Portugal, and that he had a great sum of money in Spain.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he lodge in London?</p>
               <p>L. Lefevre. He did lodge by the Tower. He told me he had correspondents very large; he looked over goods with me, a watch set with diamonds, rings, and other things, to the value of 100 l. He said he would sell some in Spain, and some in Portugal, and try which would do best. (Here he was going to give an account how he defrauded, him and of what; but the council for the defendant let him know he was trying for another fact, and that what charge he had against him was not in that indictment.)</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the defendant's father?</p>
               <p>L. Lefevre. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. What was he?</p>
               <p>L. Lefevre. A merchant and snuff-box-maker.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see the defendant at home with his father?</p>
               <p>L. Lefevre. I have, he was in a frock then.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him when he was in England some time ago?</p>
               <p>L. Lefevre. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. What was his business then?</p>
               <p>L. Lefevre. I don't know that; he did something in the jeweling and trinket way.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has he been in England this last time?</p>
               <p>L. Lefevre. The first of my knowing of him was in the beginning of May last.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go to him, or he come to you?</p>
               <p>L. Lefevre. He came to me where I live in Bow-street, and told me he came here for very large dealings.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you believe him?</p>
               <p>L. Lefevre. I so far believed him, that I gave him some credit, and recommended him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you ever paid for any goods you sold him?</p>
               <p>L. Lefevre. He gave me a little money to shew me he had some.</p>
               <p>Q. How much was that little?</p>
               <p>L. Lefevre. He paid me 22 l. out of 500 l.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know he had any more money about him at that time?</p>
               <p>L. Lefevre. No, I don't know that, he told me if I wanted a hundred pounds, or more, he would let me have it; but when he had got as much as he could, he went off. I had so good an opinion of him, that when he said he had a great order for plate, I took him to Mr. Stampair the silversmith.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever ask him for money?</p>
               <p>L. Lefevre. I did sometimes, and he would always have some excuse, but I did not really suspect him to be a thief, till I found it out.</p>
               <p>Q. As to the Letter that was sent to you about meeting his creditors to compromise matters as well as you could, what prevented that taking effect, that you would not have compassion on the gentleman ?</p>
               <p>L. Lefevre. Because he does not speak like a gentleman on a tradesman neither in that letters</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you hear he was at Calais?</p>
               <p>L. Lefevre. I did, but he was not there.</p>
               <p>Q. Don't you think if you would have had compassion on him, he would have come back, had you compounded his debts by the letter he wrote?</p>
               <p>L. Lefevre. If he had given good security for what he offered, we might have done it.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know he never was at Calais?</p>
               <p>L. Lefevre. By all circumstances that appear.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he not surrender ?</p>
               <p>L. Lefevre. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541204-22-person245">
                  Jeremiah 
                  Watson 
               <interp inst="t17541204-22-person245" type="surname" value="Watson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-person245" type="given" value="Jeremiah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-person245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a pawnbroker, and live in Coventry-street, St. James's.</p>
               <p>Council. Look at these two watches ( a plain gold watch and a gold repeater ).</p>
               <p>J. Watson. On the 20th of July last, these two watches were pawned with me for thirty guineas; in the name of Jarmes. I never saw the defendant in my life; they were redeemed by order of Jarmes. I think they are the same.</p>
               <p>C. to Addis. Look at these and see if you know them.</p>
               <p>W. Addis. These are the two watches Govers had of me I saw them in the custody of Mr. Watson, I gave the pawnbroker a receipt for his indemnification.</p>
               <p>J. Watson. I remember you now, I have your receipt at home.</p>
               <p>Q. to Watson. What is the value of the two watches ?</p>
               <p>J. Watson. I cannot take upon me to set a value upon another man's goods; I believe I could sell them for forty guineas, and no more.</p>
               <p>Q. Would you give forty guineas for them?</p>
               <p>J. Watson. I would at this time. (The jury being some of them watch-number, looked at them, and deceased they were well worth the money the defendant was to pay for them ).</p>
               <p>Mr. Delven. I keep a Public-registers-office.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175412040029"></xptr>Q. Look at this other watch, did you ever see it before ?</p>
               <p>Mr. Delvin. This was pawned to me for 14 l. in the name of Jarmes, and it was rede emed by Mr. 
               <persName id="t17541204-22-person246">
                  John 
                  Stamper 
               <interp inst="t17541204-22-person246" type="surname" value="Stamper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-person246" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-person246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17541204-22-person247">
                  William 
                  Addis 
               <interp inst="t17541204-22-person247" type="surname" value="Addis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-person247" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and another, on the 26th of August.</p>
               <p>Q. What would you have given for it?</p>
               <p>Mr. Delven. I would have given 20 l. for it.</p>
               <p>Mr. Rennie. I had been acquainted with Govers from about the latter-end of last June; then I became acquainted with him at the prince of Orange's head in the Hay-market. (He is shewed a letter) About two days before he wrote this letter, he applied to me, and told me, he had met with a fatal stroke from abroad, and had sustained great losses; and said, he was afraid if his creditors should know it, they would trouble him; and asked my advice, saying, he had some notes to pay quickly, and he was incapable of paying them. I advised him to write to his creditors, and keep out of the way till he heard from them. He said he was fearful of staying in England. I told him, if his writing did not succeed, then to go to France. He said, he believed he should not be able to pay them in less than two or three years. When he told me that, then I advised him to go to France. He said he would; but he staid in town on Saturday, Sunday, Monday, and Tuesday.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that?</p>
               <p>Mr. Rennie. Because I saw him. I was present when he wrote this letter in London to his creditor; I take it to be on a Saturday that he wrote it; I really believe he went to go out of England; he went to the coast of Sussex to embark, because he heard his creditors were gone to Dover. I took him to be an honest man.</p>
               <p>Q. In what language did you and he discourse?</p>
               <p>Mr. Rennie. In French; he can talk English, and but a little.</p>
               <p>Q. How came he to be taken?</p>
               <p>Mr. Rennie. I went to a gentleman's seat in Hertfordshire, and the next day coming home, I met Mr. Tribe, one of his creditors, in Tyburn-road, who informed me he was gone off; and Govers sent Mr. Gibeard and Mr. Paris to me, before I had been at home two hours, for me to come to him in James-street, in the Hay-market. This was on the 7th of September; one of them called him to me at the door; then he took me by the hand, and said he was come to England upon seeing his name advertised in the papers, and he would have satisfaction for the affront put upon him. I told him I was very glad to see him come back, for that I myself had been calumniated about having a letter directed to me, and also about having had talk with him. I asked him if he really came to surrender to his creditors, or whether he was the honest man he had told him he was? He said, Yes; and that he had no other than fair dealings with his creditors, and he was not afraid of them, and asked me how he must go on. I told him, if he had a mind to shew himself, as he pretended, that in following my advice he would complete his design, and I advised him to come along with me to an officer's house, and give me leave to go and call his creditors that minute, without going into any other house. Then I went to Mr. Randle's in the Strand, a sheriff's officer, and told Mrs. Randle, there was a gentleman wanted a lodging, and I did not know but he might stay some time with her; that he was come to surrender, and desired her to let him have a good room. He willingly went with me, and called for a glass of wine; at my opening the door, he saw two gentlemen, one of them I knew; I asked him if he knew either of them? He said, he did one; and said he was fearful of being seen by that Man. I asked him for what? He told me, that by that man's intelligence he might be betrayed for the 200 l. mentioned in the papers, and make his affairs worse. I said that was very well thought of then I took him to my own house, and told Mrs. Randle I would bring him on the day following. He said at my house that night; the next day I sent a messenger to Mr. Deval, a friend of the creditor's, to let him know I had something to tell him. My servant returned, and said he was not at home. I went afterwards to Mr. Gosset, where I met Mr. Lefevre, and told him I should be able to bring the Defendant and his creditors face to face. He seemed to rejoice at it, and asked a farther meeting that evening at a coffee-house in King-street. I went in the evening, and told him I was in hopes I should shew him to him the very next day, and desired him to get writs to arrest him; then I thought I should have no farther concern in it. That very evening, which was on a Sunday, the 8th, I took the defendant to Mr. Randle's house again; there I sat and drank a glass of wine with him, and left him there, and went home; and as I was drinking a dish of tea on the Monday Morning, came a note to me, which I shewed to Mr. Deval; he begged of me to call on him before I went to his creditors; I went to him, he then asked me, if I had seen any of them? I said, no.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175412040030"></xptr> but I would go. I went to Mr. Lefevre; he had got a writ in his pocket; I took him to Randle's house, and left him there, and went about my business, and when I returned, the defendant was in custody of a constable, and going before a justice.</p>

               <p>Q. What was your opinion of him as to his honesty?</p>
               <p>Mr. Rennie. I knew no harm or good of him. I did not know he had dealt for a shilling till the day before he went away; now the common cry is against him.</p>
               <p>Cross-examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon the whole of what you say, as to the conduct of the defendant, whether it did not appear to you that he did it with an intent to satisfy his creditors?</p>
               <p>Mr. Rennie. He said he came with intent to face them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he go voluntarily with you to the officer's house ?</p>
               <p>Mr. Rennie. He did.</p>
               <p>Q. From the time that you first saw him after his return, to the time you surrendered him, might not he have made his escape ?</p>
               <p>Mr. Rennie. For what I know he might; I had no warrant, or gave any charge concerning him where I left him.</p>
               <p>Q. to Lefevre. What did the defendant say to you in the officer's house?</p>
               <p>Mr. Lefevre. He said to me, in the officer's house, if he had met me upon the road, he would have blown my brains out.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tax you with putting the advertisement in the papers?</p>
               <p>Mr. Lefevre. No, he did not; I was abroad then.</p>
               <p>For the defendant.</p>
               <p>Claud. Delacombe. (he spoke by Mr. Lamash an interpreter ) I am a captain in the Imperial service; I have been in England since March last; I know the defendant.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Mr. Roberts, a merchant, in Brussels ?</p>
               <p>C. Delacombe. I did; but not as a merchant at Brussels. He was a merchant; I was acquainted with him when I was with the defendant; I know the defendant had given goods to his hands.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know whether Mr. Roberts had any money of the defendant's in his hands?</p>
               <p>C. Delacombe. I don't know that; I have heard them talk very much about trade.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know that they traded together?</p>
               <p>C. Delacombe. I do not know; but I rather say yes than no. As I was one day at the custom-house, there was one Mr. Showler and Govers together; I heard Showler say to Govers, that Roberts was run away with some goods belonging to him; and Govers said, with a loud voice, I believe he has run away with too much from me: that he had four or five thousand guilders of his in his hands, and he feared he should lose them but don't know when it was he failed.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you hear this talk?</p>
               <p>C. Delacombe. At the latter-end of last August.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Govers a trader, or not ?</p>
               <p>C. Delacombe. He passed for a trader while I was at Brussels.</p>
               <p>Mr. Openham. I knew the defendant at Frank-fort in Germany about five of six years ago. I saw him at Lipswick, at the great fair there; I have seen him transact business in wine-houses; I have dealt with him myself in jewels, watches, and tweezer-cases. My father and his were particular acquaintance together at Paris; his father was a jeweler; he was the greatest dealer in France. I knew the defendant at the Change, and at Tom's coffee-house; he told me he had got some coloured stones to dispose of, and he sold them to a person whom I recommended him to. I had so good an opinion of him, that I offered to be his ball body for body. I can swear myself worth four or five hundred pounds.</p>
               <p>Mr. Paris (he being also a foreigner, spoke by Lamash the interpreter ) I have known the defendant twelve or fourteen years; I found him about four months and a half ago in England. I think he followed the trade of his father, he told me so in England. To my own knowledge he always paid his way very well at Paris, or where he went.</p>
               <p>Cross-examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live;</p>
               <p>Mr. Paris. In Northumberland-court, Charing-cross.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>Mr. Paris. I am a doctor and chymist.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is your shop?</p>
               <p>Mr. Paris. I have none; I belong to Dr. Ward.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17541204-22-verdict111" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-verdict111" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17541204-22-punish112" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-punish112" type="punishmentCategory" value="noPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-22-punish112" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="sentenceRespited"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541204-22-defend231 t17541204-22-punish112"></join>
               
                     <note>[No punishment. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
