<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17580913-39">
               <interp inst="t17580913-39" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-39" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-39" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580913"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-39" type="date" value="17580913"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580913-39-off204-c297" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-39-defend373 t17580913-39-off204 t17580913-39-verdict209"></join>
         
               <p>296. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17580913-39-defend373" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Baker 
                  <interp inst="t17580913-39-defend373" type="surname" value="Baker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-39-defend373" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-39-defend373" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17580913-39-off204" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580913-39-off204" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-39-off204" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing five gold-rings, value 30 s. one pinchbeck metal snuff-box, value 5 s. one silver watch, value 3 l. ten pieces of silver, value 18 d. one silver cup, one silver punch ladle, one silver pap-boat, seven silver tea-spoons, three silver table-spoons, one pair of silver studds, one pair of silver buttons, two guineas one half-guinea, 44 s. and one penny in money numbered, the goods and money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17580913-39-victim375" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Jones 
                        <interp inst="t17580913-39-victim375" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580913-39-victim375" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580913-39-victim375" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-39-off204 t17580913-39-victim375"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling house of the said John
            </rs>, <rs id="t17580913-39-cd205" type="crimeDate">September 4</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-39-off204 t17580913-39-cd205"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-39-person376">
                  John 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17580913-39-person376" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-39-person376" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-39-person376" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . <rs id="t17580913-39-viclabel206" type="occupation">I keep the Swan at <placeName id="t17580913-39-crimeloc207">Hampton-wick</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-39-crimeloc207" type="placeName" value="Hampton-wick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-39-crimeloc207" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-39-off204 t17580913-39-crimeloc207"></join>
                  </rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-39-victim375 t17580913-39-viclabel206"></join>, the prisoner lives there.</p>
               <p>Q. What business does he follow?</p>
               <p>Jones. <rs id="t17580913-39-deflabel208" type="occupation">He did follow the business of collar-making</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-39-defend373 t17580913-39-deflabel208"></join>, but I don't know that he follows any now. I lost out of a drawer in the room where I lie, which is one pair of stairs high, the goods mentioned in the indictment, there were four locks broke.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you seen the things last?</p>
               <p>Jones. On Monday morning, the 4th of September, then I put some money out of my pocket into one of the drawers, I think it was two guineas and a half, and there was just a guinea and a half more in silver.</p>
               <p>Q. Mention the goods you lost?</p>
               <p>Jones. Five gold-rings, a pinchbeck snuff-box, a silver watch, a great many small pieces of silver, a silver cup, that will hold about three quarters of a pint, a punch-ladle, a silver boat, seven silver tea-spoons, three table-spoons, a pair of studds, and a button or two; these were in the upper drawer.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the drawer lock'd?</p>
               <p>Jones. I lock'd it after I had put the money in on Monday morning, between 7 and 8 o'clock, and I had the key in my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you miss these things?</p>
               <p>Jones. I missed them on the Tuesday, being the next day, a person came to me for change for a guinea, and I went to unlock the drawer as usual, and found the bolt did not move readily; then I found it had been broke open; there were a great many writings, leases, notes of hand, and agreements, to the amount of 150 l. were all taken away.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175809130033"></xptr>Q. What marks did you observe upon the drawer?</p>
               <p>Jones. The were four drawers broke, and upon one of the little drawers there appeared the mark as if done with a knife, and one of them is split very much by wrenching of it. Mr. Goodchild and Mr. Rowlls tried the prisoner's knife to the mark of the drawer, and they seemed to agree; the mark was just by the lock, where a knife had been put in to force the bolt down, so that it had made a dent in the upper part of the drawer, the dent was very plain.</p>
               <p>Q. Does any body lie near that room?</p>
               <p>Jones. My maid and my little girl lie in a room on the same floor.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to suspect the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Jones. I came to London, to Mr. Fielding, to have the things advertised, and when I returned my writings and papers were found, as they told me, under ground in the prisoner's garden, in a canister; then I got a search-warrant from Mr. Rowlls, and went with the constable to search the prisoner's house, the first we found were the silver cup and spoons, and some small pieces of silver, the punch-ladle, watch, pap-boat, five gold rings concealed under ground close by the pales in the prisoner's garden. (Produced in court and deposed to.)</p>
               <p>Q. Does the prisoner keep any lodgers?</p>
               <p>Jones. No, he does not as I know of.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a garden is the prisoner's?</p>
               <p>Jones. It is a very small garden, all grown over with weeds, it has not been dug up for a year for what I know; but the ground where the things were found appeared to have been fresh dug up.</p>
               <p>Q. How deep in the ground were they?</p>
               <p>Jones. They were not very deep. Upon seeing ing the ground broke was the reason we dug for them.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it an inclosed or an open garden?</p>
               <p>Jones. One side of the garden is but very indifferent for fence, they are pales and some broke down.</p>
               <p>Q. What does it lie too.</p>
               <p>Jones. I think Mr. Dalton's garden and that lie close together.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it bounded by other gardens?</p>
               <p>Jones. There are little houses with little gardens that lie backwards of the houses, and at the back of the prisoner's garden is a meadow.</p>
               <p>Q. Is there any gate that opens out of the garden into the meadow?</p>
               <p>Jones. I think there is, but I am not sure; I never was in it before.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is that garden from your house?</p>
               <p>Jones. It is about 140 yards, or thereabouts; I got a warrant and took the prisoner up; the justices met at my house, and he was examined there, he denied the fact, and said he knew nothing of the matter.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he used to come to your house?</p>
               <p>Jones. Yes, he frequently came, as much as any of the neighbours.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he in your house on Monday the 4th of September?</p>
               <p>Jones. He was in the evening drinking with one Pearson betwixt 6 and 7 o'clock, he was drinking also with Mr. Gill and Mr. Newman, but he went out, and was gone about twenty minutes or half an hour, and came again.</p>
               <p>Q. What room were they drinking in?</p>
               <p>Jones. They were in the public room, the fore room on the ground floor, he staid but a little time before he went out.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he stay after he returned again?</p>
               <p>Jones. He staid but a little time.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is the stair-case from where he was drinking?</p>
               <p>Jones. It is just by.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any body up stairs at the time he was gone?</p>
               <p>Jones. No, not as I remember.</p>
               <p>Q. Could he, during the time he was absent, have gone up stairs and have taken the things out without any body seeing of him?</p>
               <p>Jones. I imagine he could.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were your people at this time?</p>
               <p>Jones. Some in the back kitchen, and some in the cellar.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he when he left the company go away with a candle in his hand?</p>
               <p>Jones. I cannot say whether he did or not.</p>
               <p>Q. How many people had you in the room at that time?</p>
               <p>Jones. He was drinking with three people, and there were people coming in backwards and forwards.</p>
               <p>Q. How many might come in the time he was drinking in that room?</p>
               <p>Jones. Not a great many.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175809130034"></xptr>Q. Do you imagine the prisoner knew the situation of the room up stairs?</p>
               <p>Jones. Without doubt, he knew all my rooms.</p>

               <p>Q. Was he ever up in that room where you kept these things?</p>
               <p>Jones. On the Sunday before he came to our house, pretending he wanted a button to be put on his collar, and wanted the maid to do it; he went into the back-kitchen where my maid was, and said nothing to her about it, but ran up stairs into my back-room.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him?</p>
               <p>Jones. No, but my little boy did, and told me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he, when before the justice, say any thing about going up that Sunday?</p>
               <p>Jones. Yes, he said he went to see for the maid, to put a button on his shirt, and owned he went into my room, where the things were taken from, to see for her; there is the prisoner's knife, it was taken out of his pocket by the constable, this fitted the mark of the drawers.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was at the finding the things besides you?</p>
               <p>Jones. the constable was.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Then you say the garden is a little open on one side.</p>
               <p>Jones. It is.</p>
               <p>Q. Could not a person come out of the meadow into the prisoner's garden?</p>
               <p>Jones. I believe they might; but they could not get into the meadow without coming over the Thames.</p>
               <p>Q. Could not people come into that garden through Mr. Dalton's garden?</p>
               <p>Jones. They might.</p>
               <p>Q. Could they not also come into the prisoner's garden through Mr. Pyke's garden?</p>
               <p>Jones. I believe they might.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-39-person377">
                  Philip 
                  Yernel 
               <interp inst="t17580913-39-person377" type="surname" value="Yernel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-39-person377" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-39-person377" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Tuesday morning, the 5th of Sept. a little before 6 o'clock, I was in my master Mr. Pyke's garden, the sence joyns to the prisoner's garden, the sence is about breast high; I saw the prisoner come out of his garden and he went down in the meadow, about 20 yards distance to an elder-bush, and take from thence a white bundle and conceal it under his coat, and then return to his own garden.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you speak to him?</p>
               <p>Yernel. I did, I gave him the time of the morning, and he the same to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him do any thing in his own garden?</p>
               <p>Yernel. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him go into his own house?</p>
               <p>Yernel. No, I did not; I took it he went to his own house.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of bundle was it?</p>
               <p>Yernel. I thought it was about the bulk of 4 or 5 shirts tied together, I had but a glimpse of it.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was it?</p>
               <p>Yernel. About 14 or 16 inches long; he clap'd it under his frock.</p>
               <p>Q. What was you doing?</p>
               <p>Yernel. I was at digging up things for my master, there was this white pillowbear ( taking one in his hand) found in the ground, wrapp'd about the plate.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you say that was the bundle you saw the prisoner with?</p>
               <p>Yernel. I cannot.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-39-person378">
                  John 
                  Bulling 
               <interp inst="t17580913-39-person378" type="surname" value="Bulling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-39-person378" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-39-person378" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I remember that Tuesday morning the prisoner at the bar borrowed a spade of me; I had borrowed Mr. Pyke's spade, and he came in Mr. Pyke's name to me for it, and said, he had asked Mr. Pyke, and he had given him liberty to have it; I let him have it.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was this?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-39-person379">
                  John 
                  Bulling 
               <interp inst="t17580913-39-person379" type="surname" value="Bulling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-39-person379" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-39-person379" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . It was about three quarters of an hour after seven.</p>
               <p>Q. How far do you live from the prisoner's garden?</p>
               <p>Bulling. It is about an 150 yards distance.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see what the prisoner did with the spade?</p>
               <p>Bulling. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he return it again?</p>
               <p>Bulling. No, not to me; but to Mr. Pyke.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ask him what he was going to do with the spade?</p>
               <p>Bulling. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say?</p>
               <p>Bulling. To the best of my knowledge he said he was going to dig either a stump or a post up.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a garden is the prisoner's?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175809130035"></xptr>Bulling. It is common to any body; there are three tenants, and the prisoner is the middle tenant. Dalton, that is on one side, has liberty to go to the pump and vault; and the other on the other side the same: and at the bottom of the garden there used to be a fence, and a gate; but now there is an open place, that a cart may drive through, where barge-men may come in from out of the meadow; I am subpenaed on both sides.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-39-person380">
                  Thomas 
                  Longhurst 
               <interp inst="t17580913-39-person380" type="surname" value="Longhurst"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-39-person380" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-39-person380" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Tuesday, the 5th of September, between 12 and 1 o'clock, I heard Mr. Jones had been robb'd; I went to him and asked him about it; he told me, he was robb'd; I went and saw there was a place that sceme I to have been lately dug up in the prisoner's garden, I dug there and found a large tin canister, with several writings in it, which proved to be the property of Mr. Jones. (Produced in court.)</p>
               <p>Jones. The writings are my property, and were missing when the plate and money were.</p>
               <p>Q. Is the canister your property ?</p>
               <p>Jones. No, it does not belong to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Does any of the witnesses know whose property the canister is?</p>
               <p>They all answer they do not, and that they never saw it in the prisoner's custody.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17580913-39-verdict209" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580913-39-verdict209" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
