<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17561020-45">
               <interp inst="t17561020-45" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561020-45" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561020-45" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17561020"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561020-45" type="date" value="17561020"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17561020-45-off212-c254" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561020-45-defend332 t17561020-45-off212 t17561020-45-verdict215"></join>
         
               <p>446. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17561020-45-defend332" type="defendantName">
                     Jane 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17561020-45-defend332" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-45-defend332" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-45-defend332" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17561020-45-deflabel211" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561020-45-defend332 t17561020-45-deflabel211"></join>, we indicted for <rs id="t17561020-45-off212" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561020-45-off212" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-45-off212" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pettyLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one linen handkerchief, value twopence
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17561020-45-victim334" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Colverwell 
                  <interp inst="t17561020-45-victim334" type="surname" value="Colverwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-45-victim334" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-45-victim334" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561020-45-off212 t17561020-45-victim334"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17561020-45-cd213" type="crimeDate">October 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561020-45-off212 t17561020-45-cd213"></join> ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561020-45-person335">
                  Thomas 
                  Colverwell 
               <interp inst="t17561020-45-person335" type="surname" value="Colverwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-45-person335" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561020-45-person335" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming along <placeName id="t17561020-45-crimeloc214">Bishopsgate-Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17561020-45-crimeloc214" type="placeName" value="Bishopsgate-Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17561020-45-crimeloc214" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561020-45-off212 t17561020-45-crimeloc214"></join>, between eight and nine o'clock at night, on the 10th of this month. A gentleman named Lotelia came up to me, and asked me if I told not lost any thing out of my pocket. Upon searching I missed my handkerchief.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a handkerchief was it?</p>
               <p>Colverwell. It was a linen one (producing it.) The prisoner at the bar was just behind me. He stop'd her I search'd her and found my handkerchief, and nine others, and a snuff box in her apron. I carried her to the watchhouse. She owned a man took them, and she received them of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any body with her?</p>
               <p>Colverwell. There was a man, but he made his escape from us.</p>
               <p>Jacob Lotelia. I was coming home last Sunday in the evening a little after eight o'clock. Near Bishopsgate, I saw the prisoner and one Soloman (that I had long suspected or picking of pockets ) walking together. I passed them, and wa between them and Mr. Colverwell. He had two gentlewomen with him. I thought the prisoner and Soloman intended to pick his pocket. I live in Lis I turned down to go thither afterwards,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175610200030"></xptr> out of curiosity, I turned again to see whether they pick'd his pocket or not. I past the prosecutor, and then I observed his handkerchief did not hang with the corner out of his pocket, as it did just before. I said, Sir, I believe you have lost your handkerchief. He felt, and said he had. Then I laid hold on Soloman, and the prosecutor the prisoner. Soloman threaten'd to knock me down, and he got from me, and ran away. At first he said he did not belong to her, and she said the same; but when he was gone, and she was stop'd, she said, stop him, stop him, he does belong to me. We searched her, and found an iron snuffbox, and nine handkerchiefs upon her. The prosecutor owned one of them as soon as he saw it, and described a mark upon it, which we afterwards saw.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was taking a walk over More-Fields and met this young man Soloman. He ask'd me if I'd go and drink some beer. I said, I did not care if I did; and after that, as I was walking up Bishopsgate-Street, the prosecutor and two gentlewomen came by me. After that the evidence here said, that man and I had pick'd the prosecutor's pocket of his handkerchief. The young fellow had a tustle with the gentleman. He bid me hold up my lap, which I did, and he flung these things into it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17561020-45-verdict215" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561020-45-verdict215" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
