<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17500711-42">
               <interp inst="t17500711-42" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-42" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-42" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17500711"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-42" type="date" value="17500711"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500711-42-off191-c293" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-42-defend376 t17500711-42-off191 t17500711-42-verdict194"></join>
         
               <p>466. 
               
                  <persName id="t17500711-42-defend376" type="defendantName">
                     Peter 
                     Cordell 
                  <interp inst="t17500711-42-defend376" type="surname" value="Cordell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-42-defend376" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-42-defend376" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17500711-42-off191" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500711-42-off191" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-42-off191" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one silver pint mug, value 30 s.
            </rs> the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17500711-42-victim378" type="victimName">
                     Benjamin 
                     Wood 
                  <interp inst="t17500711-42-victim378" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-42-victim378" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-42-victim378" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-42-off191 t17500711-42-victim378"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17500711-42-cd192" type="crimeDate">June 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-42-off191 t17500711-42-cd192"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-42-person379">
                  Benj 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17500711-42-person379" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-42-person379" type="given" value="Benj"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-42-person379" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . <rs id="t17500711-42-viclabel193" type="occupation">I keep an inn</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-42-victim378 t17500711-42-viclabel193"></join>. The prisoner came into my house when I was putting my harness upon the horses. He said he wanted to go to Islington; I said if he would give me a small treat, I'd carry him there; so he gave me some rumboe; we had two sixpenny-pots more at the Green Dragon at Islington; there he said he would not stay, he'd go home on foot; he left me, and came to my house; when I came home, he was in the yard, he went in to drink with me; then my Spouse said she had lost a silver pint mug, and ask'd him if he had not play'd some trick with it, and desired he'd not frighten her; he said he knew nothing of it, so I search'd the house to see if I could find it; we went into the parlour, my wife sat on one side of him and I on the other, my wife found it in his side-pocket, he had been drinking much, and said how he came by it he did not know, and may be he did not. After this, he said he'd do something to me, if I made him out a thief. I carried him before a justice that same night; he was very much affrighted, and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175007110027"></xptr> declar'd he did not know how he came to do it. I have known him two or three years, he has used my house; I never found any thing amiss in him before. He used generally to drink out of that mug.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body play tricks with the prisoner, and slip it into his pocket?</p>
               <p>Wood. He had it in his pocket before I came home, my wife having missed it before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-42-person380">
                  Anne 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17500711-42-person380" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-42-person380" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-42-person380" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My husband and the prisoner went out together. Some time after this the prisoner came home by himself; I asked him if any thing was the matter ? he said no. He called for half a pint of cyder, the drawer fetch'd it; there was nobody in the house but him. A gentleman came in, I went to call the hostler; no hostler being to be found, the drawer went out to take the horse; after that he went to take a tankard to draw some beer, and missed the pint mug. I searched every where that I imagined it could be; I was very angry with the maid, she said the prisoner was last at the cupboard-door. I desired, if the prisoner had play'd any tricks, he would not surprize me about it: when my husband came home, we sat of each side the prisoner. I took up his clothes, and felt it thro' his coat. Our drawer had been drinking out of it, and had put it into the cupboard. I hope the court will be merciful to him, he was in liquor, and it surely is the first fact.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-42-person381">
                  Sarah 
                  Gifford 
               <interp inst="t17500711-42-person381" type="surname" value="Gifford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-42-person381" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-42-person381" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to the prosecutor. I was at the back door, a gentleman came with his horse, the hostler could not be found; my mistress went out, and the drawer followed her; she bid me go into the house; when I went in the prisoner was in the bar, and seeing me, shut the cupboard-door; then he came out of the bar and shut that too.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-42-person382">
                  John 
                  Tompson 
               <interp inst="t17500711-42-person382" type="surname" value="Tompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-42-person382" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-42-person382" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an officer. On the 21st of June Mr. Wood came to my house, and desired I would go with him to his; accordingly I did, and he gave me charge of the prisoner, who confessed the mug was in his pocket, but asserted that he did not know how it came there; he said he did not take it with an intent to steal it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence. I had drank pretty freely at the prosecutor's house, and he told me we had drank brandy and beer at several places where we went; when I was coming on foot from Islington I could hardly walk; the man at the turnpike saw and spoke to me, but I did not remember the next day, when I was committed to prison, what he said to me, I was so much in liquor. I have drank out of the same mug 50 times.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I believe he has.</p>
               <p>To his Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-42-person383">
                  William 
                  Mosely 
               <interp inst="t17500711-42-person383" type="surname" value="Mosely"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-42-person383" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-42-person383" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner 14 or 15 years, I never heard any thing ill of him before, and am sorry to hear it now. I have recommended him often, and he has always done well.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-42-person384">
                  Thomas 
                  Witherley 
               <interp inst="t17500711-42-person384" type="surname" value="Witherley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-42-person384" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-42-person384" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have employed the prisoner for these twelve months past. I am a writing stationer. He is a scrivener. He has behaved always very diligently with me. I have intrusted him with deeds of consequence; he was always very honest to me; I really believe him to be an honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-42-person385">
                  Samuel 
                  James 
               <interp inst="t17500711-42-person385" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-42-person385" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-42-person385" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him upwards of 12 years; I always thought him a good companion, and a very honest man; I knew nothing to the contrary till this affair happened.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-42-person386">
                  John 
                  Baxter 
               <interp inst="t17500711-42-person386" type="surname" value="Baxter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-42-person386" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-42-person386" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him five years, and never heard ill of him before this.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500711-42-verdict194" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500711-42-verdict194" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
