<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17500530-21">
               <interp inst="t17500530-21" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500530-21" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500530-21" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17500530"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500530-21" type="date" value="17500530"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500530-21-off98-c113" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500530-21-defend151 t17500530-21-off98 t17500530-21-verdict100"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500530-21-off98-c114" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500530-21-defend153 t17500530-21-off98 t17500530-21-verdict101"></join>
         
               <p>389, 390. 
               
                  <persName id="t17500530-21-defend151" type="defendantName">
                     Jeremiah 
                     Knapp 
                  <interp inst="t17500530-21-defend151" type="surname" value="Knapp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-21-defend151" type="given" value="Jeremiah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-21-defend151" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17500530-21-defend153" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Clancey 
                  <interp inst="t17500530-21-defend153" type="surname" value="Clancey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-21-defend153" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-21-defend153" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for the <rs id="t17500530-21-off98" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500530-21-off98" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-21-off98" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17500530-21-victim155" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Heart 
                        <interp inst="t17500530-21-victim155" type="surname" value="Heart"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500530-21-victim155" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500530-21-victim155" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500530-21-off98 t17500530-21-victim155"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17500530-21-cd99" type="crimeDate">May the 5th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500530-21-off98 t17500530-21-cd99"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500530-21-person156">
                  Thomas 
                  Buckmore 
               <interp inst="t17500530-21-person156" type="surname" value="Buckmore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-21-person156" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-21-person156" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable. The deceased was brought by a watchman to the watch-house in Catherine-street, near the tower, about half an hour after twelve at night, between the 4th and 5th of May. I ask'd him who it was that did him this mischief. He answer'd, he did not know the names of the men, but there were two, the one a foreigner, the other a sailor; that the sailor<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175005300012"></xptr> knock'd him down with a stick, and the other, the man of the house, cut him with a sword. He died last Friday. The people in the neighbourhood heard a noise in Knapp's house, which by their directions we went and surrounded, and took the two prisoners to the watch-house. Knapp was taken the next morning before the deceased, who look'd at him about half a minute, and then said he was the man that cut him with a swore, but that he had chang'd his cloaths, for before he had on regimentals. The deceased was really in his senses at this time, tho' at times he had a few ghts, as once he had about two o'clock; and he told me before he should know the man if he could see him. The prisoners were brought in separately ; but I did not hear him say any thing to Clancey, I being not there when he was brought in. They were also separately examin'd before Justice Goodman, where they confess'd the abuses they had done to the deceased. Clancey was first examined; he own'd he struck him a blow once with a stick; the Justice ask'd him who it was that cut the man in the manner he was; he reply'd it was Mr. Knapp; and when Knapp was examin'd, he own'd he cut the man, but 'twas in his own defence. - On his cross examination, he said Knapp's house was about 300 yards from the watch-house; and that it was impossible to hear the noise made there to the watch-house; that, when he went by Knapp's door about eleven o'clock, all was very still then; and that the deceased had slumbered a little between the time he was brought there, and Knapp's being brought in.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500530-21-person157">
                  Joseph 
                  Page 
               <interp inst="t17500530-21-person157" type="surname" value="Page"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-21-person157" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-21-person157" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming down the Ditch side about four o'clock in the morning of the 5th of May, and going by Knapp's door, I saw the headborough sitting there, who said he wanted my assistance, for that there had been a man murder'd. When the house was surrounded, somebody burst the door open. I went in, and found Knapp just getting out of bed. We took him, and carry'd him to the deceased. I held the prisoner before him, and said, young man, is this the man that has cut you? He lifted up his eyes and look'd hard at him, and said he was the man, but that he had chang'd his cloaths, for before he had on soldier's cloaths. About a minute or two after, he was asked again, and he answered as before, and added, that there was another man concerned with him who had a white waistcoat on, and a pair of clean trowsers. Clancey was then very soon brought in, and the deceas'd said that was the other person, adding, that he knock'd him down with a stick, and, after he had got up, and was running down the hill, Knapp follow'd him about 100 yards with a cutlass, and after he gave him a cut or two, the deceased begg'd for mercy, saying, for the Lord's sake don't kill me, struggling from him at the same time about 10 yards farther; but Knapp follow'd him, and said d - n you, I'll sla you by G - d; but as for Clancey, he never follow'd him. The deceased made no declaration how the quarrel began, but said he never was within the door, but was knock'd down at the door. [He shew'd the cap the deceased had on at the time, a thick worsted cap with three cuts in it about two inches long each.] Knapp declared he cut him so long till the cutlass flew in two.</p>
               <p>On his cross-examination he said he had this conversation with the deceased a little after seven in the morning; that he believed the constable was not there; and that the deceased was pretty saint, but very sensible.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500530-21-person158">
                  Charles 
                  Maclane 
               <interp inst="t17500530-21-person158" type="surname" value="Maclane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-21-person158" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-21-person158" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I belong to the second regiment of guards, and on the 5th of May between eleven and twelve o'clock was upon guard in the tower, about 100 yards from Knapp's door, whence I heard a great disturbance, and there came out a man, and said, are you come to rob my house? another man said, knock'd him down; to me it seem'd like a quarrel. The man however was knock'd down, but he recovered and ran about 40 yards, follow'd by another man with a hanger or sword in his hand, who knock'd him down, and after that struck him four or five blows. I call'd out, and said I would fire on him, if he did not let the man alone, but could not get to them because the ditch was between us. He left the deceas'd there, who strove to get up, but could not. The man that did it had on a soldier's coat, but I cannot be positive as to the prisoners, it being too far off to see; but when a watchman came, I call'd to him to take the man up that was cut.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500530-21-person159">
                  Margaret 
                  Gray 
               <interp inst="t17500530-21-person159" type="surname" value="Gray"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-21-person159" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-21-person159" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live within four doors of Knapp's house, and had been in bed and asleep, but between eleven and twelve o'clock the 4th of May, I heard a great noise of fighting with sticks, and something struck as tho' against a stone. This was upon Tower-hill, at what distance from Knapp's house I cannot positively say, but believe 'twas about 20 yards. I heard the century call and tell them he'd fire, and then some persons, I believe above two, ran away towards Knapp's door.</p>
               <p>Q. When was that fighting with sticks?</p>
               <p>M. Gray. Before I got out of bed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500530-21-person160">
                  Thomas 
                  Heyley 
               <interp inst="t17500530-21-person160" type="surname" value="Heyley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-21-person160" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-21-person160" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming by about four o'clock, and was charg'd by the watchman to assist. When we went into Knapp's house, he was<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175005300013"></xptr> in bed. We staid till he got up, and then went with him to the watch-house. We ask'd the man whether he knew the prisoner ; he said, he did, and that he was the very man. They left me in the house, to take care of it. I took Clancey, who was up stairs under a bed.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500530-21-person161">
                  Henry 
                  Dobson 
               <interp inst="t17500530-21-person161" type="surname" value="Dobson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-21-person161" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-21-person161" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a surgeon. On Saturday the 5th of May, the deceased was brought to the London hospital. We found a large wound on the right side of his head on the upper part; it reached almost down to his ear; he had another wound under the right ear, and one on the left side of his head, beginning at the upper part thereof, and reaching down about two inches and a half, but that on the right side was the most mortal. He died May the 26th, and, by the directions of the surgeons, was opened, and 'twas the judgment of them all that these wounds were the occasion of his death. On the 5th of May I enquir'd of him how this accident happen'd. He said, as he was along with a ship-mate of his, going a-cross Tower-hill, they saw a crowd of people at a door, and upon enquiry what the matter was, a soldier and sailor came out; that the soldier, whom he took for a foreigner, drew his hanger, and swore he would kill him, and accordingly gave him two or three cuts on the head; that he was knock'd down several times by them, and that he made the best of his way from them, but was so closely follow'd by them that he could not escape, for at Tower-ditch the soldier overtook him, and cut him again two or three times. The soldier, who was century in the Tower heard the disturbance, and call'd out, saying he would fire upon them, which made them desist. The deceased lay in his blood upon the ground, whence he was taken and carried to the watch-house. When he gave me this account, he was quite in his senses; and there were some bruises in his arms, and the wounds were made by some cutting instrument.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he give you any account how the quarrel arose?</p>
               <p>Dobson. He never told me what first occasioned the mob.</p>
               <p>Knapp's defence.</p>
               <p>I am a High German, and live upon Tower-hill. I heard a great noise that night in the street, but never went out of my house till the constable came next morning and took me out.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you forgot what you said before the Justice?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I don't know what I said there. Some people gave me brandy before I went there, and I was very much in liquor.</p>
               <p>Clancey's Defence.</p>
               <p>I'll tell the truth. There were three men came and knock'd at Knapp's door between twelve and one o'clock, when Knapp, who was much in liquor, went and ask'd what they wanted, adding, that it was an unseasonable time of the night to let any body in; but they insisted upon coming in, or they would break the door open. I then went out at the back door, and saw they were no watchmen. I ask'd them if they were going to rob the house, when one of them knock'd me down twice; and I, in my own defence, gave him one blow with my fist, but no more. The other prisoner said, gentlemen, go away from my house, and don't make any more noise about my door ; upon which two of them run, but the deceas'd stay'd behind, crying shame on the others for running, and throwing stones at Knapp and me; which made Knapp say, must my house be broke open by those three villains ? However, this man went away at last, and stood at the end of the lane. Knapp follow'd him, but what was done afterwards I can't tell. I was the first that went in, and Knapp came in afterwards.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500530-21-person162">
                  William 
                  Osborne 
               <interp inst="t17500530-21-person162" type="surname" value="Osborne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-21-person162" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-21-person162" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went in the infirmary to the deceased about a week before his death, who told me the same as the other witnesses have said, that he was coming by the door and saw a mob, that he stopp'd amongst the people, and that a soldier and a sailor came out, one of whom knock'd him down, and the other cut him. I let Knapp the house where he lives, and never knew ill of him.</p>
               <p>Knapp guilty of <rs id="t17500530-21-verdict100" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500530-21-verdict100" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-21-verdict100" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               manslaughter
            </rs>, and Clancey <rs id="t17500530-21-verdict101" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500530-21-verdict101" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500530-21-punish102" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500530-21-punish102" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500530-21-punish102" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500530-21-defend151 t17500530-21-punish102"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
