<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17520514-8">
               <interp inst="t17520514-8" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520514-8" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520514-8" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520514"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520514-8" type="date" value="17520514"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520514-8-off36-c45" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-8-defend57 t17520514-8-off36 t17520514-8-verdict38"></join>
         
               <p>288. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17520514-8-defend57" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Turner 
                  <interp inst="t17520514-8-defend57" type="surname" value="Turner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-8-defend57" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-8-defend57" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17520514-8-off36" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520514-8-off36" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-8-off36" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one yard of muslin, value 12 d, one yard of lawn, value 12 d. five yards of cotton cloth called nankeen, value 12 d.
            </rs> the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17520514-8-victim59" type="victimName">
                     Edward 
                     Eyres 
                  <interp inst="t17520514-8-victim59" type="surname" value="Eyres"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-8-victim59" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-8-victim59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-8-off36 t17520514-8-victim59"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17520514-8-cd37" type="crimeDate">April 14</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-8-off36 t17520514-8-cd37"></join>.* </p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-8-person60">
                  John 
                  Pennel 
               <interp inst="t17520514-8-person60" type="surname" value="Pennel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-8-person60" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-8-person60" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Wych-street, and am a brush-maker ; one Mrs. Worster, that lodges at my house, was at an Alehouse over the way, the prisoner came and asked for her, I sent him to her: she came over in about half an hour, with a piece of lawn in her hand, and desired my mother would lend her four shillings, to pay the prisoner for it: my mother said she had not so much, but in about half an hour she should have it: we suspected it was not honestly come by. In the mean time I went to Mr. Eyres in York-street, Covent-garden, to know if they missed such things.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to go there?</p>
               <p>Pennel. Mrs. Worster had before this acquainted me, that the prisoner was servant to Mr. Eyres.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take the lawn with you?</p>
               <p>Pennel. No, my Lord, she carried it with<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175205140007"></xptr> her to the alehouse again. I asked Mr. Eyres, whether he allowed his servants to carry out things? he said, no. Then I told him, I tho't he had been robb'd, and told of the affair, he sent two of his servants with me: then I went and told the woman, if she would bring the lawn, she might have the money, she came over, and brought Turner up stairs into her room, and then came down with the lawn in her hand: my mother deliver'd the lawn to the two men; they said it could not be honestly come by, for it must cost more than was asked for it. Then they went up to the prisoner, and asked him how he came by it? he said he would give Mr. Eyres an account of that, we took him there. He told Mr. Eyres, that he took it out of the shop-window. Mr. Eyres asked him, if he had taken any thing else? he said, no: we search'd his pockets, and found a piece of muslin, and a piece of nankeen ; then he said, he took them all out of the shop.</p>
               <p>Mr. Willeton produc'd about a yard of lawn.</p>
               <p>Q. to Pennel. Is this the lawn you speak of?</p>
               <p>Pennel. It is; here is a mark upon it, that I made, to know it by again.</p>
               <p>Q. to Willeton. Is this Mr. Eyres's property?</p>
               <p>Willeton. We have so many pieces, that I can't swear it is his property. About the 14th of April, this Evidence Pennel, came to Mr. Eyres's, and asked master if he allowed his servant Turner to carry out goods, as mentioned before, telling him the case? Mr. Eyres sent me and another fellow-servant to his house with him: after having staid about half an hour, we were taken up stairs to Turner; he had agreed to sell the lawn for 4 s. 6 d. I asked him how he came by it? he made me no direct answer, and seemed a good deal in liquor. I desired him to go back, and give Mr. Eyres an account, he did, and told Mr. Eyres, he had the lawn out of the shop. His pockets appearing pretty bulky, he was ask'd what he had there? we search'd them, and there found a piece of nankeen, and a remnant of muslin, (Produced in court) he was asked, where he had them? he said, from out of Mr. Eyres's Shop.</p>
               <p>Q. What was he at Mr. Eyres's?</p>
               <p>Willeton. He was employed as a porter 6 or 7 years. The day after his confinement he endeavoured to cut his throat, and has done it in such a manner, that he speaks with much difficulty to be understood.</p>
               <p>Q. to the prisoner. Do you hear and understand what is deposed against you?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. to Willeton. Had you any suspicion of the prisoner before this affair ?</p>
               <p>Willeton. No, my Lord, till this affair we never suspected him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-8-person61">
                  Henry 
                  Bostone 
               <interp inst="t17520514-8-person61" type="surname" value="Bostone"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-8-person61" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-8-person61" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Eyres. On Tuesday, the 14th of April, I took this piece of nankeen, and remnant of muslin, out of the prisoner's pocket, and also heard him confess, either to the lawn, or the whole, I can't justly say ; also, that it or they were Mr. Eyres's property, and that he took them out of his shop</p>
               <p>The Prisoner in his defence said, he had nothing to say, but referr'd himself to the two last witnesses for a character; who both said, they could not charge him with any thing of this nature, before this fact.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520514-8-verdict38" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520514-8-verdict38" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
