<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17591205-33">
               <interp inst="t17591205-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591205-33" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591205-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17591205"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591205-33" type="date" value="17591205"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17591205-33-off167-c263" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-33-defend329 t17591205-33-off167 t17591205-33-verdict171"></join>
         
               <p>37. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17591205-33-defend329" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Page 
                  <interp inst="t17591205-33-defend329" type="surname" value="Page"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-33-defend329" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-33-defend329" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17591205-33-off167" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17591205-33-off167" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-33-off167" type="offenceSubcategory" value="fraud"></interp>
               obtaining goods by false pretences. with intent to defraud 
                     
                        <persName id="t17591205-33-victim331" type="victimName">
                           Joseph 
                           Gayland 
                        <interp inst="t17591205-33-victim331" type="surname" value="Gayland"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17591205-33-victim331" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17591205-33-victim331" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   and 
                     
                        <persName id="t17591205-33-victim333" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Barber 
                        <interp inst="t17591205-33-victim333" type="surname" value="Barber"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17591205-33-victim333" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17591205-33-victim333" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , to the value of 34 l. 19 s.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17591205-33-cd168" type="crimeDate">June 14</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-33-off167 t17591205-33-cd168"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-33-person334">
                  Edward 
                  Dukes 
               <interp inst="t17591205-33-person334" type="surname" value="Dukes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-33-person334" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-33-person334" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live servant with Mess. Gayland and Barber, in <placeName id="t17591205-33-crimeloc169">Thames-Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17591205-33-crimeloc169" type="placeName" value="Thames-Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17591205-33-crimeloc169" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-33-off167 t17591205-33-crimeloc169"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. What are they?</p>
               <p>Dukes. They are <rs id="t17591205-33-viclabel170" type="occupation">wholesale grocers</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-33-victim331 t17591205-33-viclabel170"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-33-victim333 t17591205-33-viclabel170"></join>; the prisoner at the bar came to our shop on the 14th of June last, inquired for Mr. Barber, and asked how he did. I told him Mr. Barber was in the country. He said he wanted a hogshead of sugar, and accordingly I sold him one. Then I said, you are a stranger to me, therefore my masters will expect the money for it, please to walk into the compting-house, and leave me a direction where you live; he left me a direction, and told me if I came with the sugar in a cart, he should be at home about four o'clock inthe afternoon, and would give me the money; accordingly I went, but when I came there he was not at home.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was his house?</p>
               <p>Dukes. It was in East-Smithfield.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you find at his house?</p>
               <p>Dukes. His wife; I asked her what time she expected him home; she said she could not tell, but she expected him home soon. We put the hogshead of sugar into the shop, and I waited there upwards of an hour; I came away, and the next morning I went again, but saw nothing of the prisoner; on the Monday following he sent me a letter (producing one.)</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know it to be his hand-writing?</p>
               <p>Dukes. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>Court. Then it cannot be read.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner say he was acquainted with Mr. Barber?</p>
               <p>Dukes. He told me he knew Mr. Barber very well.</p>
               <p>Q. Would you have let him have had the sugar,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175912050030"></xptr> if you had not heard him say he was acquainted with Mr Barber ?</p>
               <p>Dukes. I do not believe I should.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the sugar ever paid for?</p>
               <p>Dukes. No.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was it that he came?</p>
               <p>Dukes. It was about ten or eleven o'clock in the forenoon.</p>
               <p>Q. You say he said he knew Mr. Barber, did you ask him who he was?</p>
               <p>Dukes. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you?</p>
               <p>Dukes. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he write his name in your compting-house?</p>
               <p>Dukes. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he give a right direction, for the sugar to be sent by the carman?</p>
               <p>Dukes. Yes, and he said he would pay me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go to the prisoner on the Monday after ?</p>
               <p>Dukes. I went to his house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find him in his shop?</p>
               <p>Dukes. No.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see him?</p>
               <p>Dukes. I saw him on the Wednesday following.</p>
               <p>Q. Where?</p>
               <p>Dukes. He was in his shop then.</p>
               <p>Q. What passed at that time?</p>
               <p>Dukes. I asked him for the money, and he told me he should call upon Mr. Barber and Mr. Gayland.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he not at that time offer you some money?</p>
               <p>Dukes. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he not offer to pay you fifteen or sixteen guineas, in part of that debt ?</p>
               <p>Dukes. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not he at any other time?</p>
               <p>Dukes. No, I asked his wife for part of the money, if he could not give me the whole, and said if he did not like the sugar, I would take it back again, and he should be at no expence for the cartage.</p>
               <p>Q. What answer did she make?</p>
               <p>Dukes. She told she could say nothing to it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there never an offer made you to pay you in part?</p>
               <p>Dukes. No, never; I asked him and his wife to pay me.</p>
               <p>Q. What day was that?</p>
               <p>Dukes. That was on the Wednesday.</p>
               <p>Q. What answer did he give you?</p>
               <p>Dukes. He said he had not quite money enough, but he was going out, and should get a little more; that I should have some the next day, and he would call and pay my master.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ask for the whole, or part then?</p>
               <p>Dukes. I asked for the whole thirty-four pounds and upwards.</p>
               <p>Q. If he had offered you any in part, should you have taken it?</p>
               <p>Dukes. I should.</p>
               <p>Q. If he had offered you five pounds, would you have taken it?</p>
               <p>Dukes. I should; I would not have refused to have taken any part of the money.</p>
               <p>Mr. Barber. I never saw the prisoner before I saw him at the bar, to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Have these goods over been paid for?</p>
               <p>Barber. No.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Mr. Macmurdow, at the corner of Ludgate Street ?</p>
               <p>Barber. Yes, I do.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known him?</p>
               <p>Barber. I have known him some years.</p>
               <p>Q. Have not you dealt with him?</p>
               <p>Barber. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you often been at his house?</p>
               <p>Barber. I have.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mr. Macmurdow. I have known the prisoner at the bar some years.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Macmurdow. I live in St. Paul's Church Yard.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business ?</p>
               <p>Macmurdow. I am a grocer.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did the prisoner live?</p>
               <p>Macmurdow. He kept a grocer's shop in East-Smithfield.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he not once your servant ?</p>
               <p>Macmurdow. He was, in part of the years 1752 and 1753.</p>
               <p>Q. During that time was you acquainted with Mr. Barber?</p>
               <p>Macmurdow. I was; I had at that time pretty large dealings with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner at the bar use to go down to Mr. Barber's on any business for your account in that time?</p>
               <p>Macmurdow. He might for what I know.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you had any dealings with the prisoner at the bar since he has lived in East-Smithfield ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175912050031"></xptr>Macmurdow. I have served him with some goods, such as teas and such things, and he always paid for them as I sent them.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. If a person comes to your servant, and promise to pay him for goods, and gets them, and does not pay for them what do you think of that?</p>
               <p>Macmurdow. I should think my servant should take care and have the money before he delivers the goods.</p>
               <p>Q. If a man gains credit with your servant at your shop, by pretending to be acquainted with you, and your servant delivers him goods upon promise of payment of ready money, and he does not pay at all, do you think that an honest man ?</p>
               <p>Macmurdow. I should think my servant must be really persuaded that he is an acquaintance of mine before he would deliver them.</p>
               <p>Council. That is not an answer.</p>
               <p>Macmurdow. A man may be a rogue in pretending to do it, but I should think my servant a very great fool to deliver goods upon such a contract, without taking the money.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever authorise the prisoner at the bar to make use of your name, in getting any credit from any of your customers where you have dealt, to get goods?</p>
               <p>Macmurdow. No; I do not know that ever I gave him the use of my name for any thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Suppose a man should buy goods, and not keep his payments, should you think that an honest man?</p>
               <p>Macmurdow. There is many an honest man that cannot make good his payments at all times.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-33-person335">
                  Sarah 
                  Osborn 
               <interp inst="t17591205-33-person335" type="surname" value="Osborn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-33-person335" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-33-person335" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was servant to Mr. Page in June last.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he live then ?</p>
               <p>S. Osborn. In East Smithfield.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he keep a publick shop?</p>
               <p>S. Osborn. He did.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember Mr. Dukes's coming there in June?</p>
               <p>S. Osborn. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. What day?</p>
               <p>S. Osborn. It was on the 18th of June.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he come for?</p>
               <p>S. Osborn. He came to my master the prisoner, for money for a hogshead of sugar.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know it was the 18th?</p>
               <p>S. Osborn. That very morning I had been at the King's-Bench, for a rule for my master.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know it was a rule?</p>
               <p>S. Osborn. Because I had never seen such a thing before, I opened and look'd into it.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by a rule?</p>
               <p>S. Osborn. A rule of court I believe.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your master in prison then?</p>
               <p>S. Osborn. No, he was not.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a thing was that rule?</p>
               <p>S. Osborn. It was a piece of paper.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to call it a rule?</p>
               <p>S. Osborn. I think they call it a rule, and I remember it was on the 18th of June.</p>
               <p>Q. What day of the week was it?</p>
               <p>S. Osborn. It was on a Monday, and after I came from bringing the rule my master had a friend drinking a pot of beer with him, when this Mr. Dukes came in, and my master asked him if he would drink.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your master confined at home then?</p>
               <p>S. Osborn. No, he was not.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to go for a rule?</p>
               <p>S. Osborn. I do not know any farther.</p>
               <p>Q. Who sent you for the rule?</p>
               <p>S. Osborn. My master did.</p>
               <p>Council for the prisoner. I own by this he must have been a prisoner. I find upon the return of the habeas it appears he was committed by Sir 
               <persName id="t17591205-33-person336">
                  Michael 
                  Forster 
               <interp inst="t17591205-33-person336" type="surname" value="Forster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-33-person336" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-33-person336" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to the King's Bench on the 16th of June.</p>
               <p>Q. What did Mr. Dukes say when your master asked him to drink?</p>
               <p>S. Osborn. He said, he did not care if he did.</p>
               <p>Q. What was it you heard pass between your master and Mr. Dukes about paying any money?</p>
               <p>S. Osborn. He asked my master for money for a hogshead of sugar; my master reply'd, he could not pay him then, by reason he had just paid the king his duty.</p>
               <p>Q. Duty upon what?</p>
               <p>S. Osborn. Upon soap; my master made soap. He said if he would take what he had in part, which was about 15 or 16 guineas, he would give it him, and would in a few days pay him the rest.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any money produced?</p>
               <p>S. Osborn. No.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Dukes. Did you deliver this bill of parcels at the time you delivered the goods? ( producing one.)</p>
               <p>Dukes (taking it in his hand.) Yes, I did.</p>
               <p>It is read to this purport.</p>
               <p>"LONDON, June 14, 1759.</p>
               <p>"Mr. 
               <persName id="t17591205-33-person337">
                  Thomas 
                  Page 
               <interp inst="t17591205-33-person337" type="surname" value="Page"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-33-person337" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-33-person337" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             bought of Gayland and</p>
               <p>"Barber 
               <persName id="t17591205-33-person338">
                  Jamaica
               <interp inst="t17591205-33-person338" type="given" value="Jamaica"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-33-person338" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sugar a cask, quantity 1512 lb.</p>
               <p>"weight - 34 l. 19 s. 1 d.</p>
               <p>"Deducted 114 lb for tare."</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17591205-33-verdict171" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17591205-33-verdict171" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17591205-33-punish172" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17591205-33-punish172" type="punishmentCategory" value="imprison"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-33-defend329 t17591205-33-punish172"></join>
               
                     <note>[Imprisonment. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
