<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17501205-58">
               <interp inst="t17501205-58" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501205-58" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501205-58" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17501205"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501205-58" type="date" value="17501205"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17501205-58-off288-c342" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501205-58-defend460 t17501205-58-off288 t17501205-58-verdict290"></join>
         
               <p>70. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17501205-58-defend460" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Floyd 
                  <interp inst="t17501205-58-defend460" type="surname" value="Floyd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-defend460" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-defend460" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17501205-58-off288" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-off288" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-off288" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               forging and publishing a certain receipt for money; part printed, and part written, with an intent to defraud
            </rs>, <rs id="t17501205-58-cd289" type="crimeDate">March 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501205-58-off288 t17501205-58-cd289"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-58-person461">
                  George 
                  Dear 
               <interp inst="t17501205-58-person461" type="surname" value="Dear"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person461" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person461" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the parish of St. George's, Wapping; I am a perriwig maker; I have been acquainted with the prisoner two or three years; I employ'd him as a broker, to buy and sell stocks; he once sold out about 250 l. of mine; he advised me to make use of my money, to lend upon East-India warrants, because then I should receive five per cent, which the stocks did not bear; I employ'd him to sell it out; then I desir'd him to lend it on East-India warrants, which he had before recommended to me; this was sold out in March last; I saw him in about two days, and he then told me, he had lent my money upon these warrants. When I came again, he brought me one of these receipts, No. 782; this is not the first he brought; the first he brought me, I since deliver'd back again, for another with more money; the first was in the same nature as this, for 103 l. that was on the 18th of March, but this I had the 21st of March, he brought this for the security of 156 l. 18 s. 7 d.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you accept that as the only security, or did he give you any other?</p>
               <p>Dear. He gave me his own note with it, at the same time; to the best of my memory, it was drawn in my presence; I understood it he had a receipt of Mr. Constable; the prisoner acted as a middle man between us; he told me he had a note of Mr. Constable's, but I did not ask him for that, at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Would you have lent this money on his note, without having this, which you at that time took to be a warrant?</p>
               <p>Dear. No, I would not, sir.</p>
               <p>Q. When was it dated?</p>
               <p>Dear. It was dated March 21, 1749.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you make application to Mr. Floyd. in order to be satisfied, as to the reality of that instrument he had pledg'd with you?</p>
               <p>Dear. Some time afterwards, I believe about three months, I ask'd to see the goods; I expected to see them in the East-India company's ware-house; he told me, it was not customary to see the goods; that they were under two keys, the company had one, and the government the other: so I was satisfied at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know Mr. Constable?</p>
               <p>Dear. No, I did not. I receiv'd the first quarter's money when it became due; and the next I receiv'd was of the prisoner, in the month of August; I made farther enquiry of a gentleman, to whom I was recommended : he satisfied me so far that he thought they were good, but he said, if any one of the parties should die, I might be troubled to get my money. I had ask'd the prisoner several times after Mr. Constable, in order to see him, to be satisfied about it, whether he had had my money; but he did not tell me where he liv'd. I wanted him to call my money home at the expiration of six months; I demanded principal and interest on the 21st of Sept. He told me he had seen Mr. Constable and told him of it, and had appointed a time of payment : it being prompt time at the India-House, he said, he could not pay just then. I apply'd to the prisoner after this again, then he brought me a guinea, he said Mr. Constable sent it to buy me a pair of gloves, and told me, he would come down to my house. I refus'd to take it, he lost it on the table; after this I saw him again, and ask'd where Mr. Constable liv'd; he said, near St. George's church Southwark ; I desir'd him to go<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175012050025"></xptr> to him along with me, this was on the 15th of Nov. he told me, he was to go out about business in the morning with a gentleman; then I desir'd him to set a time next morning; he said, he could not go, but at last agreed. I call'd upon him that morning, and found him at home in the Minories, between 9 and 10 o'clock. Then I claim'd his promise to go with me; he said, he was oblig'd to go out about business ; I importun'd him much, he said, he could not. Then I ask'd him to give me directions where he liv'd, for I was resolv'd to go myself. He told me he liv'd near St. George's church in the Borough, but said, he had forgot the street: he told me I might enquire at the Grayhound Inn there, and there I should have a full direction. I went immediately ; when I came there, the master of the house was out, and the woman did not know any such Man. She said she knew the prisoner. I was about an hour and half enquiring about there, at length I found where he liv'd, by enquiring at a publick house, where the servant maid told me she had liv'd with Mr. Constable. I found by her he liv'd on the back of Guy's Hospital. I went and found his house, and his servant told me he was at the King's-Head coffee-house, Swithens Alley. I went thither, and there I found him and told him my business; he desired to see this receipt, before that I thought they were warrants; he looked upon them and immediately said they were false. I ask'd him if he had had any dealings with the prisoner in the Tea way; he said he never had in his life.</p>
               <p>Q. Who drew the Promissory Note?</p>
               <p>Dear. The Prisoner at the Bar.</p>
               <p>Q. Is the hand Writing in the receipt and that it is filled up with the same?</p>
               <p>Dear. I cannot tell whether it is the same or not. Mr. Constable desired me to go and take the Persons up, or I should lose all my Money. I went with the receipt to Mr. Oswell an attorney, and he went with me to the East India House; there I saw Mr. Holbrook, he is the Warehouse keepper. I desired him to go and check this receipt; we found the goods were weighed, Mr. Holbrook deliver'd the receipt to Mr. Oswell, and Mr. Oswell to me.</p>
               <p>Cross Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure that is the same receipt you received of the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Dear. I am sure it is, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has it been out of your hands?</p>
               <p>Dear. Ever since the 16 of Nov. [it is read, and is to this purport.] No. 782 received 21st of March 1749, of Mr. 
               <persName id="t17501205-58-person462">
                  Joseph 
                  Constable 
               <interp inst="t17501205-58-person462" type="surname" value="Constable"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person462" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person462" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the sum of 167 l. 16 s. 7 d. for Lynn, folio 138, No. 716, 745, 746, 3 Chests Bohea Tea, &amp;c. sold him by the East India Company at their sale, 1749, September, for whose use I say receiv'd,</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-58-person463">
                  Wm 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17501205-58-person463" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person463" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person463" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17501205-58-person464">
                  E. 
               <interp inst="t17501205-58-person464" type="given" value="E."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person464" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            164 W. B.</p>
               <p>James Whitehall.</p>
               <p>The Note to this purport.</p>
               <p>London March 21, 1749. Borrowed of Mr. 
               <persName id="t17501205-58-person465">
                  George 
                  Dear 
               <interp inst="t17501205-58-person465" type="surname" value="Dear"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person465" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person465" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 156 l. 18 s. 7 d. for the security of which I have deposited in his hand a receipt Bohea Tea. No. 716, 745, 746. and I promise to pay to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17501205-58-person466">
                  George 
                  Dear 
               <interp inst="t17501205-58-person466" type="surname" value="Dear"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person466" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person466" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the said Sum of 156 l. 18 s. 7 d. with Interest, 
               <persName id="t17501205-58-person467">
                  Wm 
                  Floyd 
               <interp inst="t17501205-58-person467" type="surname" value="Floyd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person467" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person467" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Counsel. That W. B. was set by Mr. Alderman Baker, when he examined it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-58-person468">
                  Simon 
                  Holbrook 
               <interp inst="t17501205-58-person468" type="surname" value="Holbrook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person468" type="given" value="Simon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person468" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Warehouse-keeper to the East India Company, Mr. Dear came to me on Saturday the 17th of Nov. and brought this receipt, and Mr. Oswell's Clerk was along with him, he asked me whether it was good, he said the Goods lay in Lime-street Warehouse, I went along with him there, I examined the Books, and found the Goods were delivered the 8th of Feb. 49, to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17501205-58-person469">
                  Samuel 
                  Torin 
               <interp inst="t17501205-58-person469" type="surname" value="Torin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person469" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person469" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have the original Warrant here; our method is, the Warrant is first given to the Buyer, and we have the receipt in our Office; then when any part of the goods are delivered we keep the warrant and deliver up the receipt. The warrant was produced in Court. The company could not have had this warrant, had not the goods been delivered up to Mr. Torin; [it is read, the contents to this purport.] You are desired to deliver to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17501205-58-person470">
                  Robert 
                  Sedgwick 
               <interp inst="t17501205-58-person470" type="surname" value="Sedgwick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person470" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person470" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , for Mr. 
               <persName id="t17501205-58-person471">
                  Samuel 
                  Torin 
               <interp inst="t17501205-58-person471" type="surname" value="Torin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person471" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person471" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the following goods for Lynn, folio 138. No. 716, 745, 746, 3 Chests of Bohea Tea, weight 938 1/2 at 3 s. 5 d. sold him by the united East India Company, in the Sep. sale 49, he having paid for the same, 149 l. 10 s. 1 d. after the discount &amp;c.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-58-person472">
                  William 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17501205-58-person472" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person472" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person472" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-58-person473">
                  James 
                  Whitehall 
               <interp inst="t17501205-58-person473" type="surname" value="Whitehall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person473" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person473" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>[This is the warrant that was in the Company's Custody for these 3 Lotts]</p>
               <p>Mr. Torin. This is the real warrant, it is my hand writing; the Indorsement, and the receipt below are my Clerk's writing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-58-person474">
                  Joseph 
                  Constable 
               <interp inst="t17501205-58-person474" type="surname" value="Constable"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person474" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person474" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he is shew'd the forg'd receipt.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you in Sept. sale 49. buy the goods mentioned in that receipt?</p>
               <p>Constable. I did not, sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you deliver that receipt now in your hand to the prisoner at the bar?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175012050026"></xptr>Constable. No, sir, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you imploy him to borrow on it?</p>
               <p>Constable. No, sir, no person would lend any thing on it. Mr. Dear brought it to me at the Coffee-house, in Nov. that was the first time I ever saw it, he wanted to know of me whether I sold these goods mentioned, or whether it was a genuine warrant, I told him I never sold Mr. Floyd any such goods.</p>
               <p>Cross Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know one Venter?</p>
               <p>Constable. Yes I do, sir.</p>

               <p>Q. Where is he now?</p>
               <p>Constable. I don't know, he is gone off.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you not heard since he is gone off, some ill practices of his ?</p>
               <p>Constable. I have been informed he was suspected of forging the company's warrants.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any thing, do you know, between the prisoner and Venter?</p>
               <p>Constable. I never saw them together.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever buy goods for Venter?</p>
               <p>Constable. I did at the Michaelmas sale ; I cannot tell what sort, or who they were delivered to. They were weighed in my name.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever seen Venter write?</p>
               <p>Constable. I have [he is shew'd the false receipt.] I do not think it any thing like his writing.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think any man that is a Broker would take any of these receipts for the security of money?</p>
               <p>Constable. A man that is a Broker knows better, he must know it is no security at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Would he not suppose it was a true receipt?</p>
               <p>Constable. The receipt never is delivered till part of the goods are delivered, if part of the goods are delivered they write that upon it, then it is good for the residue, that is all.</p>
               <p>Q. Suppose a man has a true receipt with nothing more upon it, would it be of any use to any man living?</p>
               <p>Constable. I would not lend one shilling upon it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-58-person475">
                  William 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17501205-58-person475" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person475" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person475" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , [the receipt is put into his hand.]</p>
               <p>Q. Is that 
               <persName id="t17501205-58-person476">
                  William 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17501205-58-person476" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person476" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person476" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             on it your hand writing?</p>
               <p>Webb. No, it is not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-58-person477">
                  James 
                  Whiteball 
               <interp inst="t17501205-58-person477" type="surname" value="Whiteball"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person477" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person477" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am assistant to Mr. Webb, he is one of the joint Treasurers, [it is put into his hand.]</p>
               <p>Q. Is the name 
               <persName id="t17501205-58-person478">
                  James 
                  Whitehall 
               <interp inst="t17501205-58-person478" type="surname" value="Whitehall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person478" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person478" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             on it, your hand writing?</p>
               <p>Whitehall. It is not, sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know there was a sale of goods in Sept. 49, were there any goods in these particular numbers?</p>
               <p>Whitehall. There were 3 Chests of Bohea Tea sold at that time, of these numbers.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that?</p>
               <p>Whitehall. I know it by the original warrant.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hall. I am Clerk in the accomptants office. there was a sale of goods in the Year 49, I attended that sale.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember what Lot 716, 745, and 746, were?</p>
               <p>Hall, I can tell if I had the book, [the book was put into his hand.] I wrote it down as the cryer confirms it, by crying as loud as he can, such a person's name, at such a price, after the Auctioneer has called it, [he opens the book.] here is an account of the Cargo of the Ship Lynn, here is Lot 716, 745 and 746, 3 Chests of Bohea Tea, the weight of the whole 1000 and 9 pounds, the price too in the book is 3 s. 5 d. per pound, this is not the neat weight, this is what we call the water side weight.</p>
               <p>Q. Who were the three chests sold to?</p>
               <p>Hall. They were sold to 
               <persName id="t17501205-58-person479">
                  Robert 
                  Sedgwick 
               <interp inst="t17501205-58-person479" type="surname" value="Sedgwick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person479" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person479" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-58-person480">
                  Simon 
                  Holbrook 
               <interp inst="t17501205-58-person480" type="surname" value="Holbrook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person480" type="given" value="Simon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person480" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The goods belonging to this receipt were in Limestreet warehouse, they are sold and delivered.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see them delivered?</p>
               <p>Holbrook. No, Sir, I did not.</p>
               <p>Mr. Mordant. Here is Mr. Sedgwick's order for weighing these three chests of bohea tea, No. 716, 745, and 746.</p>
               <p>Q. When were they weighed?</p>
               <p>Mordant. They were weighed on the 9th of January.</p>
               <p>Q. Who weighed them?</p>
               <p>Mordant. I weighed them, the neat weight is nine hundred thirty eight pounds and half, at 3 s. 5 d. per pound, here is the weighing note of my own signing, they were part of the Lion's cargoe.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I do declare I did borrow the money of Mr. Venter, and at the same time thought the receipt was as good as India bonds, or other security; I carried them to Mr. Dear, and made no manner of doubt in giving him my note as an indemnity; I have always attended publick in my business, and was in Sept. with Mr. Chancey, who, at that time, asked me how I should act was he in my case, that he might not be charged with an officer at that time; I told him, was he in my case and I in his, he should deposit something in my hands, and I accordingly gave him two warrants; by the account I gave him he thought me to be an honest man, and advised me to do the most I could to detect the villain that had imposed upon me ; I did<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175012050027"></xptr> try all manner of arts and schemes to take him. After I had been with Mr. Chancey near a month, I voluntarily went to him again at the East India house, and attended him there in order to have the liberty of selling my goods. Mr. Dear is mistaken in saying I did the business for Mr. Constable; I did not tell him that till the 21st of September, at which time I knew Mr. Venter was gone, for which reason I made use of Mr. Constable's name in order to get time to take Venter up, and to pay the money, which I expected I must do out of my own fortune.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mr. Chancey. Mr. Venter had made use of a receipt that appeared to be a forgery when it was made; Mr. Floyd was then absent from England; I was uneasy about these false warrants and receipts ; when the prisoner was brought to me I examined him how he came by a receipt which was forged, and produced against him; he told me he had it of one Venter, with much the same he has now declared; I thought him innocent, but told him I could not let him go without some security for his appearance ; he did deposit two warrants with me for teas to the amount of about 120 l. I did not chuse to do this of my own head, so I sent for a friend to talk the thing over, and it did appear to me he was not guilty. Some time after this he said he had an opportunity of disposing of the teas, and applied for liberty so to do; he was before the committee and told his story there, who gave him leave to go about his business upon condition he deposited the warrants. This is the fact as near as I can relate, but this does not relate to the affair now before the jury.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-58-person481">
                  Herman 
                  Barker 
               <interp inst="t17501205-58-person481" type="surname" value="Barker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person481" type="given" value="Herman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person481" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner did apply to me to look after Venter the latter end of this summer ; he said he lived opposite the Fleet prison, and was a grocer; I went to the house at the corner of Fleet lane and enquired out his character; the prisoner said he had bought some notes of him, and that he thought they were forged, so wanted to bring him to justice. I repeated my enquiry on Sunday following, but could not find him; Floyd came to me afterwards, but I told him I could not go any more; he asked me if I knew where to find a person that would, and I proposed to him one Williamson.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Barker. I am a Vintner, and live at the Salutation Tavern in Nicholas street.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was it when you made this enquiry?</p>
               <p>Barker. I take it to be in August.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever find Venter?</p>
               <p>Barker. No, I never saw him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go to his house?</p>
               <p>Barker. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know he was gone off then?</p>
               <p>Barker. No, I did not, sir.</p>
               <p>- Williamson. I was applied to by the last evidence to make enquiry after Venter about six or seven weeks ago.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-58-person482">
                  Theophilus 
                  Hearsay 
               <interp inst="t17501205-58-person482" type="surname" value="Hearsay"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person482" type="given" value="Theophilus"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person482" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner pretty near a twelvemonth, and have trusted him with 2000 l. value at a time, with which he might have run away; I waited above half an hour in Bartholomew lane till he brought it me.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Hedrsay. It was on the 18th of October; I always thought he was an honest man, even after this I have trusted him to go to the Bank to fetch money; once it was either 40 or 50 l.</p>
               <p>William Sands. I have known him about a year and half, and have trusted him with a great deal of money (2 or 300 l. at a time) his general character is very good.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-58-person483">
                  John 
                  Lee 
               <interp inst="t17501205-58-person483" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person483" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person483" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner from the year 1747; I frequently employed him, and look upon him to be a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-58-person484">
                  George 
                  Gorman 
               <interp inst="t17501205-58-person484" type="surname" value="Gorman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person484" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person484" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner two or three years, and he has a general good character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-58-person485">
                  John 
                  Briggs 
               <interp inst="t17501205-58-person485" type="surname" value="Briggs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person485" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-person485" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him three or four years, and have had dealings with him; he always paid me honestly, and I never heard any thing to his discredit till this.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17501205-58-verdict290" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501205-58-verdict290" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
