<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17550116-6">
               <interp inst="t17550116-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550116-6" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550116-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550116-6" type="date" value="17550116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550116-6-off27-c77" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-6-defend85 t17550116-6-off27 t17550116-6-verdict32"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550116-6-off33-c77" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-6-defend85 t17550116-6-off33 t17550116-6-verdict32"></join>
         
               <p>50. (M. 2.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17550116-6-defend85" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Ash 
                  <interp inst="t17550116-6-defend85" type="surname" value="Ash"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-6-defend85" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-6-defend85" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for <rs id="t17550116-6-off27" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550116-6-off27" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-6-off27" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he on the king's highway, on 
                     <persName id="t17550116-6-victim86" type="victimName">
                        Mary, <rs id="t17550116-6-viclabel28" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-6-victim86 t17550116-6-viclabel28"></join> of 
                           <persName id="t17550116-6-person87" type="victimName">
                              
                                 <persName id="t17550116-6-victim88" type="victimName">
                                    James 
                                    Whitchurch 
                                 <interp inst="t17550116-6-victim88" type="surname" value="Whitchurch"></interp>
                              <interp inst="t17550116-6-victim88" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                              <interp inst="t17550116-6-victim88" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                           </persName>
                               
                           <interp inst="t17550116-6-person87" type="surname" value="Whitchurch"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17550116-6-person87" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17550116-6-person87" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        </persName>
                        
                        <interp inst="t17550116-6-victim86" type="surname" value="Whitchurch"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550116-6-victim86" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550116-6-victim86" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , <rs id="t17550116-6-viclabel29" type="occupation">Esquire</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-6-person87 t17550116-6-viclabel29"></join>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-6-victim88 t17550116-6-viclabel29"></join>, did make an assault, putting her in fear of her life, and taking from her person, one silk purse, value 6 d. and five shillings in money, numbered, the property of the said James
            </rs>, &amp;c. <rs id="t17550116-6-cd30" type="crimeDate">Nov. 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-6-off27 t17550116-6-cd30"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-6-off33 t17550116-6-cd30"></join>.*</p>
               <p>Mary Whitchurch. On the 23d of November I had been from Twickenham to Bushy-park in a chariot, my lady Ferrers was with me; we returned from thence about one o'clock, and met two men on horseback in <placeName id="t17550116-6-crimeloc31">Teddington</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17550116-6-crimeloc31" type="placeName" value="Teddington"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550116-6-crimeloc31" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-6-off27 t17550116-6-crimeloc31"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-6-off33 t17550116-6-crimeloc31"></join> parish, immediately the chariot stopped as they came up to us, one of the men came on my side, and said, Make haste.</p>
               <p>Q. Which side did you sit on?</p>
               <p>M. Whitchurch. I sat on the left-hand side, he spoke to me; I did not then see a pistol, but afterwards I did. I immediately gave him a silk purse with only a little silver in it; after this, I saw a man on the other side, I put the glass down which was up on that side, and my lady gave that man a handful of silver, he had a large pistol in his hand, which he put into the chariot, I desired him to take it out, which he did immediately, and desired I would not be affrighted; when they had taken the money they immediately went away.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175501160006"></xptr>Q. Had they any thing on their faces ?</p>
               <p>M. Whitchurch. No, my lord, they had not.</p>
               <p>Q. Look upon the prisoner, do you know him?</p>
               <p>M. Whitchurch. I can't take upon me to say he was one of them; I think he seems to be a desperate sort of a person, but I looked but little upon them, fearing they should use us ill for it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-6-person89">
                  William 
                  Parprit 
               <interp inst="t17550116-6-person89" type="surname" value="Parprit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-6-person89" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-6-person89" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am footman to Mr. Whitchurch, and was behind the chariot on the 23d of November, there was my lady Ferrers with my lady at that time in it. I believe it was about twelve o'clock when we set out; we went to Bushey-park for an airing, in our return in the parish of Teddington, the prisoner and another person, each on horseback, came up and bid us stop, the prisoner came on my lady Ferrer's side, he put a pistol into the chariot and demanded her money, I saw my lady Ferrers put her hand out and give him something; the person on the other side desired my lady not to be affrighted, saying he would not hurt them; that person had a short pistol; as soon as they had got the money they rode off.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any knowledge of the prisoner before this?</p>
               <p>W. Parprit. No, I had not, but I took particular notice of them both.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to recollect the day?</p>
               <p>W. Parprit. I took particular notice of it in the almanack, because I thought it might happen that the persons might be taken.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was this ?</p>
               <p>W. Parprit. It was about a quarter of an hour before two o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. How was the prisoner dressed?</p>
               <p>W. Parprit. He was dressed in mourning, or a sort of dark grey; he appeared like a Gentleman's servant.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take much notice of the other?</p>
               <p>W. Parprit. I did, he was in a light-coloured coat and plate buttons.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to take such particular notice of them?</p>
               <p>W. Parprit. Because I could not help it, being behind the chariot.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any others besides the two you speak of ?</p>
               <p>W. Parprit. No, there were not.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever seen the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>W. Parprit. I cannot say whether I have or not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at the taking of him?</p>
               <p>W. Parprit. I know nothing of the taking him, he was brought to justice Cox's for me and farmer Emmerton to look at.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutrix. On which side was he that bid you not be affrighted ?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. They both did.</p>
               <p>William Norden. There was an information came to justice Fielding that there were two young gentlemen highwaymen about Twickenham, Teddington, and those parts; the day after this robbery was committed, Mr. Fielding dispatched me and another to see if we could meet with them; we got descriptions of them at Teddington, and was there told that they were born there, and both their names; the other they told us was named 
               <persName id="t17550116-6-person90">
                  Thomas 
                  Holdernoss 
               <interp inst="t17550116-6-person90" type="surname" value="Holdernoss"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-6-person90" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-6-person90" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; we could not find them; after that justice Cox sent for me, he said he know the people that did the robberies, and one of them had a warrant granted against him for a bastard child, and that a woman had given information where he was; I went according to direction, and there found the prisoner. I asked him if his name was 
               <persName id="t17550116-6-person91">
                  Thomas 
                  Ash 
               <interp inst="t17550116-6-person91" type="surname" value="Ash"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-6-person91" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-6-person91" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he said, yes then I said, I have a warrant against you; and took him and put him in a room and locked him up, and went after Holderness, but could not meet with him. I took the prisoner before justice Cox, the footman was sent for, who knew him directly, he cried, and confessed before the justice this robbery, and two or three others.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he confess this robbery ?</p>
               <p>W. Norden. He said he robbed a chariot just by Teddington.</p>
               <p>Q. How came he to confess it ?</p>
               <p>W. Norden. Mr. Cox knew him before, and said to him, ah, Tom, I am sorry for you; then he confessed directly, and said Holderness drew him in to go a robbing, in order to get money to pay for a bastard child.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business? Are not you a thief-catcher?</p>
               <p>W. Norden. I think it a very honest employment. I dare say, if you was robbed, you would employ me.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you acknowledge you follow that profession?</p>
               <p>W. Norden. Yes, Sir, I am very often sent for<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175501160007"></xptr> by people of great credit, on such occasions, when they have been robbed.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I can give a very particular account where I was that day that the crime was committed which is laid to my charge. I breakfasted with my brother, and from thence went to the Tower, and was there about two; there I drank a pint of beer, and had a welsh-rabbit, and staid till five in that house; from thence I went to Mr. Short's in the Tower, to see a fellow-servant there; I drank tea, and came home after that.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-6-person92">
                  John 
                  Ruff 
               <interp inst="t17550116-6-person92" type="surname" value="Ruff"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-6-person92" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-6-person92" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a drawer at an alehouse in the Tower; on the Saturday before St. Andrew's day, the prisoner, whom I know very well, came to our house, and sent for 
               <persName id="t17550116-6-person93">
                  Margaret 
                  Plaistow 
               <interp inst="t17550116-6-person93" type="surname" value="Plaistow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-6-person93" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-6-person93" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a servant maid, that lives in the Tower, an acquaintance of his. He came about half an hour after two at noon; she came and staid with him about ten minutes; he both eat and drank at our house; he had a pint of beer, a halfpennyworth of tobacco, and smoked a pipe, and had a welsh-rabbit; my mistress got up from her dinner to make it. He staid there till very near five; we were going to light up candles when he went away.</p>
               <p>Q. What time do you frequently dine?</p>
               <p>J. Ruff. We always dine exactly at two; we never are ten minutes under or over.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you recollect it to be the Saturday before St. Andrew's day.</p>
               <p>J. Ruff. My wife lives fellow servant with me, and we have a great many Scotchmen use our house, and she got a hurt on St. Andrew's day, and was delivered of a child that same night.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-6-person94">
                  Margaret 
                  Plastow 
               <interp inst="t17550116-6-person94" type="surname" value="Plastow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-6-person94" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-6-person94" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner sent for me on the 23d of November last to the Stone-kitchen, an alehouse in the Tower so called.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to remember that day?</p>
               <p>M. Plastow. My fellow-servant, when I got up, said he would give me a dish of tea in the afternoon, it being his birth-day. I went to the prisoner I believe a quarter after two, I staid there I believe five minutes; I told him I must not stay, for the dinner was not gone up stairs; but I should be glad to see him in the afternoon to drink tea; and between four and five I went there to him again, and he came up with me, and he and my fellow-servant, 
               <persName id="t17550116-6-person95">
                  Francis 
                  Platt 
               <interp inst="t17550116-6-person95" type="surname" value="Platt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-6-person95" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-6-person95" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , drank tea together at my master's house; he staid there with us till between eight and nine.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-6-person96">
                  Francis 
                  Platt 
               <interp inst="t17550116-6-person96" type="surname" value="Platt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-6-person96" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-6-person96" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 23d of November the prisoner came to our house.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you particularly fix upon that day?</p>
               <p>F. Platt. It being my birth-day, he came with my fellow-servant, and staid till some time after eight at night.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he boots and spurs on, or a whip in his hand.</p>
               <p>F. Platt. No, he had neither of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he look as if he had been on a hard journey.</p>
               <p>F. Platt. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he dressed ?</p>
               <p>F. Platt. He had on a white coat.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of buttons?</p>
               <p>F. Platt. I can't tell that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-6-person97">
                  Thomas 
                  Ludby 
               <interp inst="t17550116-6-person97" type="surname" value="Ludby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-6-person97" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-6-person97" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner three years and upwards; he lived servant with my father very near two years, during which time he always behaved very faithful. He had a great trust committed to his care; I never heard any ill of him before this time.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17550116-6-verdict32" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550116-6-verdict32" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a second time indicted, for <rs id="t17550116-6-off33" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550116-6-off33" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-6-off33" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he together with 
                     <persName id="t17550116-6-person98">
                        William 
                        Holderness 
                     <interp inst="t17550116-6-person98" type="surname" value="Holderness"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550116-6-person98" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550116-6-person98" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , not yet taken, upon the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17550116-6-victim100" type="victimName">
                           Edward 
                           Emerton 
                        <interp inst="t17550116-6-victim100" type="surname" value="Emerton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550116-6-victim100" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550116-6-victim100" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear, and danger of his life, and taking from his person 15 s. in money, numbered
            </rs>, <rs id="t17550116-6-cd34" type="crimeDate">Novemb. 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-6-off27 t17550116-6-cd34"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-6-off33 t17550116-6-cd34"></join>.* </p> 
               <p>Edward Emerton deposed, that he had his servant were with his waggon on <placeName id="t17550116-6-crimeloc35">Hampton-common</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17550116-6-crimeloc35" type="placeName" value="Hampton-common"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550116-6-crimeloc35" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-6-off27 t17550116-6-crimeloc35"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-6-off33 t17550116-6-crimeloc35"></join>, stopt by two men on horseback, and they took from him 15 s. which he had just taken for a load of straw; but both he and his servant, Christopher Bignal, who was with him at the time, were so affrighted, that they could only say it was by two men, and had neither of them any knowledge whether the prisoner was one of them.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17550116-6-verdict36" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550116-6-verdict36" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
