<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17520625-54">
               <interp inst="t17520625-54" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520625-54" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520625-54" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520625"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520625-54" type="date" value="17520625"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520625-54-off236-c394" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520625-54-defend490 t17520625-54-off236 t17520625-54-verdict239"></join>
         
               <p>388. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17520625-54-defend490" type="defendantName">
                     David 
                     Murry 
                  <interp inst="t17520625-54-defend490" type="surname" value="Murry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-54-defend490" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-54-defend490" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17520625-54-off236" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520625-54-off236" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-54-off236" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one wooden box, value 2 s. three linen shirts, three linen stocks, three pair of worsted stockings
            </rs>, the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17520625-54-victim492" type="victimName">
                     Edward 
                     Stafford 
                  <interp inst="t17520625-54-victim492" type="surname" value="Stafford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-54-victim492" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-54-victim492" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520625-54-off236 t17520625-54-victim492"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17520625-54-cd237" type="crimeDate">June 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520625-54-off236 t17520625-54-cd237"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-54-person493">
                  Edward 
                  Stafford 
               <interp inst="t17520625-54-person493" type="surname" value="Stafford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-54-person493" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-54-person493" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My brother seat the things mentioned in the indictment for me by the carrier's waggon from Gloucestershire, to the Saracen's-Head on Snow-Hill; I went there and saw the box; I left a direction for it to be carried to <placeName id="t17520625-54-crimeloc238">York Buildings</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17520625-54-crimeloc238" type="placeName" value="York Buildings"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520625-54-crimeloc238" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520625-54-off236 t17520625-54-crimeloc238"></join> for me, but I never received it.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know what was in it?</p>
               <p>Stafford. I only know by a letter which I received from my brother.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-54-person494">
                  John 
                  Kirby 
               <interp inst="t17520625-54-person494" type="surname" value="Kirby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-54-person494" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-54-person494" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The waggon comes from Stratford-upon-Avon. Mr. Stafford came to inquire for the box and produced a letter; I shewed him the box, it was almost a yard long, and directed to him; I employed Holmes as a porter to carry it where he lives, having a pretty deal of business at that time to do myself.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-54-person495">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Holmes 
               <interp inst="t17520625-54-person495" type="surname" value="Holmes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-54-person495" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-54-person495" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a ticket porter; I was trusted to carry the box; the 12th instant I set out from Snow-Hill about nine o'clock; there was the name Stafford on the bottom of it, directed to the Three Balls in Buckingham-street for him. I went to Tottenham-Court-Road with another parcel; coming with that box along Monmouth-street, so down Drury lane, then into Russel-Court, across Covent Garden, I had the box on my knot; I asked for Buckingham-street; a man passed by me with white stockings on and said, this is the street, pointing to King-street, as I know since.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>Holmes. It was then about a quarter after ten o'clock; then I asked for Mr. Stafford's; the man said, that is the gentleman's house, and that is his servant standing at the door; I went up to the house, it was the prisoner that stood in the passage at the door; said he, d - n it, where have you been all this while? are you not come from the Saracen's-Head on<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175206250034"></xptr> Snow-Hill with this box? I told him, yes: he made me believe he put his hand in his pocket to pay me, and then said, I have no halfpence, my master is at the Shakespear's-head tavern in Covent-Garden, he'll make you drink. I left the box upon a bulk at the door, and the prisoner clapped his arm upon it and said, I might take it with me. I went to the Shakespear's-head and inquired; the gentleman at the tavern said to me, young man, there is no such man here, go and look after your box, you are defrauded out of it. I have many such persons sent here. I went back again, and the box was gone off the bulk where I set it and the prisoner taken I was telling people how I had been served; the prisoner came up again and said, what's the matter here? I looked at him and said, you are the person that robbed me of my box. This was about eleven o'clock, it was quite a light night; he had a black stock on, and I also took notice of his face. I seized him as he was going in at the door; I found he lodged there; I carried him to the Roundhouse.</p>
               <p>Q. from the prisoner. Was you not much in liquor?</p>
               <p>Holmes. No, I was not, I was sober.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he the same cloaths on when you saw him the last time as he had before?</p>
               <p>Holmes. He had, my lord.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>As to the charge against me, I am intirely innocent. As I was coming home to my lodgings I saw a mob of people and the porter amongst them; so I went up and asked him what was the matter? he said he had lost a box, and that he had left it with a footman on the bulk while he went to the gentleman, which was gone when he came back; there were several people laughing at him, telling him he was a drunken fellow. He charged seveveral others with it; I blamed him for his ignorance ; then he seized and charged me.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>- Holloway. I am a watchman in King-street Covent-Garden; I took the prisoner to the watch-house.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the evidence (Holmes) fuddled or sober ?</p>
               <p>Holloway. He was in liquor very much. When I first saw him he was standing against the wall without the box; he said, watchman, they have stole a long box from me; I went half the length of the street and came back again; then he said a man had told him he was a gentleman's servant that owned the box; the prisoner was going into his own lodgings. The evidence said he delivered it to a man dressed in livery and white stockings; as the prisoner was going into his own door he said, this is the man. I never saw the prisoner before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520625-54-person496">
                  John 
                  West 
               <interp inst="t17520625-54-person496" type="surname" value="West"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-54-person496" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520625-54-person496" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in that street; as I was going home the prosecutor was making a noise about a box; I said to him, what is the matter, friend? he answered, the man that took the box away was dressed in footman's cloaths, and had white stockings on; said I, where was you directed to? he said to Buckingham-street; I told him, this is King street, so he was going to fight with me; then I thought he was drunk. When we were before the justice on the second examination, the justice ordered me and the prisoner to change cloaths, we did, and I was brought up instead of the prisoner; the justice asked him if I was the man; he swore to me twice. When he found he was mistaken, he then swore to the buckles in my shoes.</p>
               <p>Q. What business are you?</p>
               <p>West. My father is a perukemaker.</p>
               <p>Holmes. Justice Fielding's clerk can tell to the contrary of what this evidence has said; I did not say he was the man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520625-54-verdict239" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520625-54-verdict239" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
