<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560915-28">
               <interp inst="t17560915-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-28" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560915"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-28" type="date" value="17560915"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560915-28-off149-c164" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-28-defend218 t17560915-28-off149 t17560915-28-verdict153"></join>
         
               <p>355. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17560915-28-defend218" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17560915-28-defend218" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-28-defend218" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-28-defend218" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17560915-28-off149" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560915-28-off149" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-28-off149" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one silver tankard, value 6 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17560915-28-victim220" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Taber 
                        <interp inst="t17560915-28-victim220" type="surname" value="Taber"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560915-28-victim220" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560915-28-victim220" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-28-off149 t17560915-28-victim220"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling house of the said John
            </rs>, <rs id="t17560915-28-cd150" type="crimeDate">June 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-28-off149 t17560915-28-cd150"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-28-person221">
                  John 
                  Taber 
               <interp inst="t17560915-28-person221" type="surname" value="Taber"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-28-person221" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-28-person221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . <rs id="t17560915-28-viclabel151" type="occupation">I keep a publick house</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-28-victim220 t17560915-28-viclabel151"></join>, <placeName id="t17560915-28-crimeloc152">the Fox and Anchor in Charterhouse-Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17560915-28-crimeloc152" type="placeName" value="the Fox and Anchor in Charterhouse-Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17560915-28-crimeloc152" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-28-off149 t17560915-28-crimeloc152"></join>. On the 2d of June about ten at night my wife was in the passage, and the maid was coming out of the parlour. She said to my wife, did you see two gentlemen that I draw'd a tankard of beer for? My wife said, she had not seen any body; and she'd be hang'd if the tankard was not stoln. I ask'd the maid how she came to draw in a tankard to two strangers ? She said, she had seen one (that is, the prisoner at the bar) three or four times before; and she believed he lived in the neighbourhood. Missing my tankard, I advertised it in the Publick-Advertiser, two guineas reward; but have not seen it since. About seven weeks ago there came two men to my house, and asked me if I had lost a tankard? I said, I had; and had not found it since. They wanted me to describe the men I suspected. I call'd the maid, and she described one of the men. She said, the other held down his face. They said, there was such a man in Bridewell, committed by my Lord-mayor for picking a pocket. I and the maid went along with them, but kept these two men out, and desired the girl going along to be exceeding careful who she pitch'd upon. Going in she said, the prisoner at the bar was the man that call'd for the tankard of beer, and also for a pint of twopenny to put into it; and when she came up, they and the tankard were gone ( he was in his waistcoat.) I desired he'd put his coat on. She said; there was no occasion, for she was positive. I took him before Mr. Fielding, and there she swore to him. All he said was, he never was at my house in his life time. They did not pay their reckoning.</p>
               <p>Q. Were not there other people in your house at the time?</p>
               <p>Taber. There were five people from Buckinghamshire that deal in lace; and one Kelsey, a soldier, that was tried here yesterday.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-28-person222">
                  Ann 
                  Bagley 
               <interp inst="t17560915-28-person222" type="surname" value="Bagley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-28-person222" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-28-person222" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have seen the prisoner several times come into master Taber's house, and I always draw'd him a tankard of beer. He used to bring two or three people with him. I draw'd him a tankard of beer on the 2d of June, at past ten at night, in a silver tankard, and delivered it to him. They were sitting in a box over against each other; and there were some lace men at the farther end of the room, and a soldier sat opposite to them (they were sitting near the street window.) They sent me down for a pint of twopenny, and I brought it up; but they were both gone, tankard and all.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was Kelsey?</p>
               <p>A. Bagley. He was sitting in his place when they were gone. I went after this to Bridewell, and saw the prisoner in his waistcoat beating hemp. I knew him as well in his waistcoat as in his coat.</p>
               <p>Q. How soon after you was in Bridewell did you pitch upon the prisoner?</p>
               <p>A. Bagley. I pitch'd upon him immediately.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the coat that he put on the same as he had on at your house?</p>
               <p>A. Bagley. The very same.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I never was in the prosecutor's house in my life. The coat I have now on, I bought a great while since the time they say the tankard was stoln. There was nobody by when the girl pitch'd upon me.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-28-person223">
                  Walter 
                  Buckland 
               <interp inst="t17560915-28-person223" type="surname" value="Buckland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-28-person223" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-28-person223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a salesman and taylor in Long-Lane. The coat he has on, I sold him about eight or nine weeks ago.</p>
               <p>Q. to A. Bagley. Of what colour was the coat he had on?</p>
               <p>A. Bagley. It was white. Such as he has on now.</p>
               <p>Buckland. He had no coat of the colour of this in the beginning of June. He is a very honest young fellow.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-28-person224">
                  John 
                  Trusty 
               <interp inst="t17560915-28-person224" type="surname" value="Trusty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-28-person224" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-28-person224" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a shoe-maker. I have known the prisoner eight or nine years; he always had a good character. He is a needle maker.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175609150014"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-28-person225">
                  Stephen 
                  Trusty 
               <interp inst="t17560915-28-person225" type="surname" value="Trusty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-28-person225" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-28-person225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him twenty years and upwards. He is a very honest young fellow.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-28-person226">
                  Sarah 
                  Fuller 
               <interp inst="t17560915-28-person226" type="surname" value="Fuller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-28-person226" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-28-person226" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him ever since he was born. He always behaved very just and honest.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-28-person227">
                  Mary 
                  Brooks 
               <interp inst="t17560915-28-person227" type="surname" value="Brooks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-28-person227" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-28-person227" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him ever since he was born. He is a very honest young fellow.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-28-person228">
                  John 
                  Macklin 
               <interp inst="t17560915-28-person228" type="surname" value="Macklin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-28-person228" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-28-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him fourteen years; he is a very honest sober young man. I serv'd my time to his father.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17560915-28-verdict153" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560915-28-verdict153" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
