<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560714-32">
               <interp inst="t17560714-32" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560714-32" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560714-32" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560714"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560714-32" type="date" value="17560714"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560714-32-off170-c274" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560714-32-defend328 t17560714-32-off170 t17560714-32-verdict175"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560714-32-off170-c275" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560714-32-defend330 t17560714-32-off170 t17560714-32-verdict175"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560714-32-off170-c276" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560714-32-defend332 t17560714-32-off170 t17560714-32-verdict175"></join>
         
               <p>316, 317, 318. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17560714-32-defend328" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Blackman 
                  <interp inst="t17560714-32-defend328" type="surname" value="Blackman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-32-defend328" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-32-defend328" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17560714-32-defend330" type="defendantName">
                     George 
                     Pilman 
                  <interp inst="t17560714-32-defend330" type="surname" value="Pilman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-32-defend330" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-32-defend330" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , and  
               
                  <persName id="t17560714-32-defend332" type="defendantName">
                     George 
                     Sunderland 
                  <interp inst="t17560714-32-defend332" type="surname" value="Sunderland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-32-defend332" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-32-defend332" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17560714-32-off170" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560714-32-off170" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-32-off170" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 4 piece of linen cloth. each containing 24 yards, value 5 l. 11 s. the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17560714-32-victim334" type="victimName">
                           Joseph 
                           Downs 
                        <interp inst="t17560714-32-victim334" type="surname" value="Downs"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560714-32-victim334" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560714-32-victim334" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560714-32-off170 t17560714-32-victim334"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , on a certain wharf, on a navigable river, to wit, the river Thames
            </rs>, <rs id="t17560714-32-cd171" type="crimeDate">June 20</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560714-32-off170 t17560714-32-cd171"></join> ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560714-32-person335">
                  Joseph 
                  Downs 
               <interp inst="t17560714-32-person335" type="surname" value="Downs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-32-person335" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-32-person335" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . <rs id="t17560714-32-viclabel172" type="occupation">I keep a wharf</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560714-32-victim334 t17560714-32-viclabel172"></join> by <placeName id="t17560714-32-crimeloc173">Queen-Hithe</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17560714-32-crimeloc173" type="placeName" value="Queen-Hithe"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17560714-32-crimeloc173" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560714-32-off170 t17560714-32-crimeloc173"></join>, call'd <placeName id="t17560714-32-crimeloc174">Currier's and Downs's wharf</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17560714-32-crimeloc174" type="placeName" value="Currier's and Downs's wharf"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17560714-32-crimeloc174" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560714-32-off170 t17560714-32-crimeloc174"></join>. On the 9th of June we had some goods for Bristol, and some in a chest that came from Mr. Amian, on Lawrence-Poultney Hill On the 19th of June the barge lay at my wharf; I was call'd up on Sunday morning the 20th of June; my servant told me I had been rob'd. I went and found the chest broke open, and saw some of the bargemen I ask'd them who had been their watchmen to night. They said we. I sent my boy away to Mrs. Mahone, and my clerk to Mr. Amian, Mr. Shailer who I master of the barge came. I got a search warrant to search the barge that lay off my wharf.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you miss?</p>
               <p>Downs. Out of 150 pieces of cloth in the chest, I missed four pieces. On searching the barge, the bargemen came on board. We found nothing in the barge. The same day about twelve o'clock Sunderland went from on board his barge with one of the bargemen in it, in a sculler, to Pepper Alley. When I came to take in the goods out of the barge, Shailer call'd out to the men, hire you Pepper Alley man, which gave me suspicion; so I went to Pepper-Alley, and ask'd at the sanding place if they saw any of the men (meaning the prisoners at the bar) land there. A man said, he remember'd seeing such men land there; and described Pitman as well as any painter could paint him, and said they had some bundles of cloth under their arms. Then I got a warrant, and took the prisoners up</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever find the goods again?</p>
               <p>Downs. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. How can you fix a charge upon these persons ?</p>
               <p>Downs. Because the barge lay at my wharf, and they being watchmen, had any body else came they must have seen them.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Are the goods your property?</p>
               <p>Downs. I have got a bill and receipt that I paid for them; as they lay on my wharf I was to make them good.</p>
               <p>Q. How was this chest fastened ?</p>
               <p>Downs. It was a Hamburgh chest, nailed very strong, and corded.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560714-32-person336">
                  John 
                  Dupice 
               <interp inst="t17560714-32-person336" type="surname" value="Dupice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-32-person336" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-32-person336" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant at the Bear at the Bridge-foot. I was weeping my master's yard between seven and eight o'clock on a Sunday morning, when blackman and Pitman came thro' the yard, and I swept it into one of their shoes; he turn'd about and damn'd me, and as he turn'd about I saw three pieces of linen under his coat.</p>
               <p>Q. Which was that?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175607140038"></xptr>Dupree. That was Blackman.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you follow them ?</p>
               <p>Dupree. No, I did not. The prosecutor came and enquired if I saw such people, and I described them. When they were taken up Blackman desired having any piece of cloth at all, or being out of his master's barge at the time.</p>
               <p>Q. What said Pitman ?</p>
               <p>Dupree. He said he was asleep under the tilt; after he said he was walking about, and that he never went through our yard that morning.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What size was this linen ?</p>
               <p>Dupree. I did not see the length of it, I took it to be two feet wide.</p>
               <p>Q. to Downs. What is the width of the linen you missed ?</p>
               <p>Downs. I suppose they are three quarters wide dowlas.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560714-32-person337">
                  William 
                  Wallis 
               <interp inst="t17560714-32-person337" type="surname" value="Wallis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-32-person337" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-32-person337" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am clerk to Mr. Downs. On the 20th of last month our maid came to our window, and said we had been robbed. I went down on the wharf, and found the chest broke open. I asked one of the bargemen who were watchmen that night; he said, what is that to me. Then I went and inform'd my master of it.</p>
               <p>Q. How near the wharf did their barge lie?</p>
               <p>Wallis. It lay so near that they could get out of their barge upon our wharf. I should think they must know something about it, because nobody could come over the barge without their knowledge. I remember I heard the barge-master call out to these men, and say, hollow, you Pepper-Alley man.</p>
               <p>Q. Were these men alone at the time?</p>
               <p>Wallis. No, there were several barge men on board the barge then.</p>
               <p>Q. What is Pepper Alley?</p>
               <p>Wallis. It is a place where they buy second hand cloaths and things.</p>
               <p>Q. How was the chest broke?</p>
               <p>Wallis. It was open'd with something like a crow. and the cord was cut.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the mark of a crow?</p>
               <p>Wallis. I did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560714-32-person338">
                  Thomas 
                  Sturit 
               <interp inst="t17560714-32-person338" type="surname" value="Sturit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-32-person338" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-32-person338" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a cooper by trade: I told the prosecutor I'd do all in my power to assist him. There prisoners were taken up on suspicion. I went with the other evidence to make all the enquiry I could. We went to Pepper-Alley, but could hear nothing of the linen. Then we went to the bear at the Bridge foot; where the master told us he heard his servant say there were two men went thro' there, who made their way to Tooley-Street, with some bundles under their arms; we also made enquiry in Rosemary-Lane, but could find nothing of them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560714-32-person339">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Craggs 
               <interp inst="t17560714-32-person339" type="surname" value="Craggs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-32-person339" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-32-person339" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know Sunderland, he lodged in my house. I remember on Sunday the 20th of June he was at home; I believe in the morning betwixt nine and ten. Then he went out, and did not return till bed time.</p>
               <p>Q. What happened at his going out ?</p>
               <p>E. Craggs. He brought with him a steak, which I dressed for his breakfast. He eat it, and went out directly.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Did you hear Sunderland say any thing before the alderman ?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Sunderland said there he had nothing to do with it; that he went out of the house where he lodged on the Sunday morning between eight and nine: and Mrs. Craggs said he went out very early, returned again, and had a beef sleak for his breakfast.</p>
               <p>Q. to E. Craggs. Did he go out twice that morning?</p>
               <p>E. Craggs. He went out in the morning, and brought a steak in his hand, and I dressed it.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did he go out first?</p>
               <p>E. Craggs. I can't tell what time he went out; when I was in bed I heard him, but cannot tell the time.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Mention what he said before the alderman ?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. He said he went from home between eight and nine o'clock to Mrs. Mahone's, and went on board a barge, and was not at home till betwixt ten and eleven at night, when he went immediately to bed.</p>
               <p>Blackman's defence.</p>
               <p>I don't know any thing of it; I never heard any body go upon the wharf, neither was there myself; and as for my going thro' the Brown-Bear yard I never saw the place. I never was out of my barge till six o'clock in the morning, when I went to Mrs. Mahone's house, and had two pots of beer.</p>
               <p>Pitman's defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing at all of what I am charged with.</p>
               <p>For the prisoners.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560714-32-person340">
                  Francis 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17560714-32-person340" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-32-person340" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-32-person340" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Pitman seven or eight years. I never heard any thing amiss of him, but that he is an honest industrious man.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Blackman?</p>

               <p>Harris. I don't know so much of him as I do of the other: He always bore an honest character as far as ever I heard.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175607140039"></xptr>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Harris. I am abaker.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Sunderland?</p>
               <p>Harris. I have known him twenty years. I don't know any harm of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560714-32-person341">
                  Joseph 
                  Shailer 
               <interp inst="t17560714-32-person341" type="surname" value="Shailer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-32-person341" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-32-person341" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know Blackman and Pitman.</p>
               <p>Q. What is their general character?</p>
               <p>Shailer. Their general character is very honest: I never knew them accused of any thing before a justice in my life before. Pitman lived with me before he was able to work.</p>
               <p>Q. By whom do you imagine the chest was broke open, considering the situation of your barge ?</p>
               <p>Shailer. Some body got at it, but which way God knows, for I know not. They might have went over the lighters that lay near the wharf: They lay nearer the wharf than my barge.</p>
               <p>Q. Might not some of your men get upon the wharf?</p>
               <p>Shailer. I don't know how they could get there: I don't imagine any thing at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Who were your watchmen that night?</p>
               <p>Shailer. 
               <persName id="t17560714-32-person342">
                  William 
                  Blackman 
               <interp inst="t17560714-32-person342" type="surname" value="Blackman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-32-person342" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-32-person342" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17560714-32-person343">
                  George 
                  Pitman 
               <interp inst="t17560714-32-person343" type="surname" value="Pitman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-32-person343" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-32-person343" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; and they were both in the barge when I got up the next morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you sleep?</p>
               <p>Shailer. I slept at Mrs. Mahone's. I never lie on board the barge, without the barge is on the road.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you leave them over-night?</p>
               <p>Shailer. At ten o'clock I left them on board the barge.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you not things of value on board your barge?</p>
               <p>Shailer. I have; I never lost any thing by them.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. This man declared himself he went on board the barge at four, and the men were walking on board her. The men declared their master call'd to them from under the tilt, when they were asleep.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. It was at Guild Hall, before Mr. alderman Bridgen.</p>
               <p>All three <rs id="t17560714-32-verdict175" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560714-32-verdict175" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
