<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17590425-2">
               <interp inst="t17590425-2" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590425-2" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590425-2" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17590425"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590425-2" type="date" value="17590425"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17590425-2-off7-c33" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590425-2-defend36 t17590425-2-off7 t17590425-2-verdict11"></join>
         
               <p>145. (M). 
               
                  <persName id="t17590425-2-defend36" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Burch 
                  <interp inst="t17590425-2-defend36" type="surname" value="Burch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-2-defend36" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-2-defend36" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17590425-2-off7" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590425-2-off7" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-2-off7" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing two oil-stones, value 7 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17590425-2-victim38" type="victimName">
                     Edward 
                     Parker 
                  <interp inst="t17590425-2-victim38" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-2-victim38" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-2-victim38" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590425-2-off7 t17590425-2-victim38"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17590425-2-cd8" type="crimeDate">July 28, 1757</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590425-2-off7 t17590425-2-cd8"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175904250003"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17590425-2-person39">
                  Edward 
                  Parker 
               <interp inst="t17590425-2-person39" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-2-person39" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-2-person39" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I employed Mr. Pain, a master Carpenter, last March it was two years ago, to do up my house: he had several journeymen employed at it: I lost two oil-stones, at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the use of oil-stones? </p>
               <p>Parker. They are to set a keen edge upon tools after they are ground.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever get them again?</p>
               <p>Parker. I have one of them again the prisoner brought it and delivered it to my wife.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of the other?</p>
               <p>Parker. He has since confessed he threw that away in the fields. An oil-stone produced. This is that which he brought again, it is my property.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear him at any time say any thing as to these oil-stones; did he acknowledge or deny taking them?</p>
               <p>Parker. I took him up with a warrant; he said he took them, but thought them to be of no value.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the value of them?</p>
               <p>Parker. I do not imagine them to be worth any thing like what they are valued at in the indictment, they are not the things I imagined them to be.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Have not you often declared, that the stones were of so little value, that you was sorry you had brought on this thing?</p>
               <p>Parker. I have; I did it with intent to find out other things that I lost about the same time.</p>
               <p>Q. What opinion had you of the prisoner when he work'd at your house?</p>
               <p>Parker. I had a very good opinion of him 'till I lost many things; and by the discovery of one, thought I should find out the rest.</p>
               <p>Q. From that good opinion you had of him whether you have not supported him since he has been in goal?</p>
               <p>Parker. I have in some measure.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you imagine he only took these stones as considering them to be trifling things?</p>
               <p>Parker. I believe he took them as thinking they might be of use to him, and none to me.</p>
               <p>Mr. Pain. I was doing the jobb for Mr. Parker, at his house in <placeName id="t17590425-2-crimeloc9">Totenham-Court Road</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17590425-2-crimeloc9" type="placeName" value="Totenham-Court Road"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17590425-2-crimeloc9" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590425-2-off7 t17590425-2-crimeloc9"></join>: I am a master Carpenter: the prisoner was one of my <rs id="t17590425-2-deflabel10" type="occupation">journeymen</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590425-2-defend36 t17590425-2-deflabel10"></join> amongst many others that worked there; we were raising the house a story higher; after the jobb was done, Mr Parker and his wife made great complaints to me, that my men had robbed them of many things, and particularly these oil-stones, which they had taken from out of a drawer. I knowing the use of these stones, and that some of them are very valuable, I made inquiry about them, and suspected the prisoner. I asked him to see his oil-stone; he said, he had never an oil-stone in the world but one; I asked him to produce that, then he said, it was at his lodgings in Shoe-lane; I bid him fetch it; he came and brought me a stone, but not this that is here produced, it was one of mine which I had lost: by catching him in that lie, I said, I believe you are guilty of taking Mr. Parker's. So if you do not tell me the truth I'll send for a constable, and send you away; upon that he cried, and said, he had one piece of Mr. Parker's, and he would go and fetch it, which he did (this is the same) I asked him if he had never another; he said no, that was all he had.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say where he had this stone?</p>
               <p>Mr. Pain. He said, he had it from Mr Parker's house; I perswaded him to carry it again; accordingly he said he would, and went from me with it; and I find since he did carry it. As soon as he came back again, I paid him what was due to him, and turned him away.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had he worked for you?</p>
               <p>Pain. He had worked for me about eighteen months.</p>
               <p>Q. How had he behaved in that time?</p>
               <p>Pain. He had behaved honestly as far as I know.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the value of this stone?</p>
               <p>Pain. He takes it in his hand. (It was broke in two pieces.) This is an out-side slabb, and he having broke it in flitting of it, it is but of little use.</p>
               <p>Q. Wouldy on employ him again was he at liberty?</p>
               <p>Pain. No, I would not: I have great reason not to employ him.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175904250004"></xptr>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>This stone was found in pulling down the house, and there were others had pieces of stone as well as I: as soon as I heard it was a stone of consequence, I went and carried it to Mrs Parker, and told her, I had found a stone, that I was informed was of value to you, so I have brought it again.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590425-2-person40">
                  John 
                  Somes 
               <interp inst="t17590425-2-person40" type="surname" value="Somes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-2-person40" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-2-person40" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner two years: I was foreman: he worked under me.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Somes. He always behaved extreamly well, every body respected and caressed him; he was very industrious, and had the character of an honest man.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you known him lately?</p>
               <p>Somes. I have down to this time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590425-2-person41">
                  George 
                  Castle 
               <interp inst="t17590425-2-person41" type="surname" value="Castle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-2-person41" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-2-person41" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner two years; he once worked under me, where I was a foreman.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Castle. He was always sober, descrete, honest, and a good servant to his master, at the time I had the care of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he work with you?</p>
               <p>Castle. It was at a jobb at Mr Taylor's two years ago.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he work with you there?</p>
               <p>Castle. About three months: I had not my health, so was forced to leave the jobb.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590425-2-person42">
                  James 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17590425-2-person42" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-2-person42" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-2-person42" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about five months.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a character has he bore in the world?</p>
               <p>Wood. He worked for me between four and five months, and was with me at the time he was taken up; I have no reason to think but that he was honest, industrious, and sober.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590425-2-person43">
                  John 
                  Harrington 
               <interp inst="t17590425-2-person43" type="surname" value="Harrington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-2-person43" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590425-2-person43" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner worked for me eight weeks as a journeyman Carpenter.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known him?</p>
               <p>Harrington. I have known him ever since the 28th of October last.</p>
               <p>Q. How has he behaved since you have known him?</p>
               <p>Harrington. He was very diligent and sober, and never lost any time; I have trusted him in every room in my house with the doors open, and was he at liberty I would trust him again, as I did before.</p>
               <p>Q. to Parker. The offence is laid to be committed on the 28th of July last was twelve months, how come you not to take him up sooner?</p>
               <p>Parker. I never saw him in all that time.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is it since you took him up?</p>
               <p>Parker. It is about seven weeks ago.</p>
               <p>Q. If you had found him before that time, should you have taken him up?</p>
               <p>Parker. I should not have troubled myself much about it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17590425-2-verdict11" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590425-2-verdict11" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
