<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570114-31">
               <interp inst="t17570114-31" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570114-31" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570114-31" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570114"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570114-31" type="date" value="17570114"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570114-31-off173-c212" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570114-31-defend265 t17570114-31-off173 t17570114-31-verdict176"></join>
         
               <p>88. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17570114-31-defend265" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Barnard 
                  <interp inst="t17570114-31-defend265" type="surname" value="Barnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570114-31-defend265" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570114-31-defend265" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17570114-31-off173" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570114-31-off173" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570114-31-off173" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing four loaves of bread, value 2 s.
            </rs>  the property of 
               <persName id="t17570114-31-victim266" type="victimName">
                  John 
                  Willey 
               <interp inst="t17570114-31-victim266" type="surname" value="Willey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570114-31-victim266" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570114-31-victim266" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570114-31-off173 t17570114-31-victim266"></join>
                  </persName>
             , <rs id="t17570114-31-cd174" type="crimeDate">Jan. 11</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570114-31-off173 t17570114-31-cd174"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570114-31-person267">
                  John 
                  Willey 
               <interp inst="t17570114-31-person267" type="surname" value="Willey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570114-31-person267" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570114-31-person267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17570114-31-viclabel175" type="occupation">baker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570114-31-victim266 t17570114-31-viclabel175"></join>, and live in Cloth-Fair. I can only say the bread was mine. I was present on the prisoner's examination, but he did not own it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570114-31-person268">
                  George 
                  Lisle 
               <interp inst="t17570114-31-person268" type="surname" value="Lisle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570114-31-person268" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570114-31-person268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to the prosecutor, and I pitch'd my basket in the street.</p>
               <p>Q. What street ?</p>
               <p>Lisle. I don't know the name of the street. I am a stranger in London. There were in the basket seven quartern loaves, one half peck, and one threepenny loaf. I had taken one quartern loaf out of the basket, to go and serve a customer, and when I was coming back to my basket I saw the prisoner taking bread out of it. He went away with it, and I went after him.</p>
               <p>Q. What bread had he got?</p>
               <p>Lisle. He had got four loaves of bread upon him.</p>
               <p>Q. What loaves ?</p>
               <p>Lisle. Quartern loaves. I brought him back.</p>

               <p>Q. Who did the loaves belong to?</p>
               <p>Lisle. They belong'd to my master the prosecutor. The prisoner talked a great deal to me, and would said have had me gone over to a publick house, to drink with him.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do with the loaves ?</p>
               <p>Lisle. He threw them into the backet. I was not willing to go, but he drag'd me into the alehouse by force; where he told me he had been a master baker some time ago. He wanted me to excuse him, and let him go, and he would give me money.</p>
               <p>Q. What were the words he made use of?</p>
               <p>Lisle. He did not mention what he would give me money for, but I look'd upon it, it was to excuse him. When he found I would not excuse him he began to quarrel with me, and struck me in the face. The people turned us both out of the house. When he came into the street he made his way from me. I called out to people to hold him, and a man took hold of him, and held him by the coat till I came. Then I held him, and sent for a constable.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. The thing was done in Monkwell-Street.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I went out about ten in the morning to come to Dr. Ward, having an ulcer in my bladder. I I got there about a quarter after ten, and found three old women at the door. They said he would not be there till about twelve. I had a little boy along with me, so I thought I would go and shew him St. Paul's. Going along Cheapside I met an acquaintance, named 
               <persName id="t17570114-31-person269">
                  John 
                  Nichols 
               <interp inst="t17570114-31-person269" type="surname" value="Nichols"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570114-31-person269" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570114-31-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He asked me to drink. He took me to a house and gave me a pint of purl. It was the same alehouse where the witness and I were. He said to me, you say you are a going to St. Paul's, will you take three or four loaves with you for me to Temple-Bar, and said he'd bring some rolls on the morrow morning for breakfast. I went and took the loaves. Presently came the young man, and said they were his. I was affrighted out of my wits. Then he and I went to the alehouse together, and the gentleman told him I had been at that house before along with a young man.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175701140035"></xptr>Q. to Lisle. Do you know any thing of the prisoner having been there, as he says?</p>
               <p>Lisle. I know nothing of his being there with any body. The people of the house said he came in there, and asked if the baker was there that belong'd to the basket in the street. My basket was just by.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I did not ask that Nichols where he lived. I have sent many people after him.</p>
               <p>Lisle. He had a boy walking along with him, whom he called his son, that had go, a half peck and two quartern one from out of my basket.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570114-31-person270">
                  Mary 
                  Hewps 
               <interp inst="t17570114-31-person270" type="surname" value="Hewps"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570114-31-person270" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570114-31-person270" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner a great many years. He is a baker.</p>
               <p>Q. How many years have you known him?</p>
               <p>M. Hewps. Above ten years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>M. Hewps. I never heard any thing amiss of him in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. Does he keep a shop now?</p>
               <p>M. Hewps No, he does not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he ever?</p>
               <p>M. Hewps. He did live in Redcross Street, in the Park, on the other side of the water, in Castle-Street.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is that ago?</p>
               <p>M. Hewps. I believe it is above seven years ago since he left off business.</p>
               <p>Q. What has he been since?</p>
               <p>M. Hewps. A journeyman.</p>
               <p>Mr. Baker. I knew him about ten years ago, but I have not seen him lately. He kept a baker's shop in Castle-Street, in the Park, Southwark. He was of pretty good reputation then. He has been a journeyman baker since, but after he left the baker's shop he kept a publick house.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570114-31-verdict176" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570114-31-verdict176" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570114-31-verdict176" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder1s"></interp>
               Guilty 10 d.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570114-31-punish177" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570114-31-punish177" type="punishmentCategory" value="corporal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570114-31-punish177" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="publicWhipping"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570114-31-defend265 t17570114-31-punish177"></join>
               
                     <note>[Whipping. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
