<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17580222-13">
               <interp inst="t17580222-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580222-13" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580222-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580222"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580222-13" type="date" value="17580222"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580222-13-off69-c106" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580222-13-defend125 t17580222-13-off69 t17580222-13-verdict72"></join>
         
               <p>117. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17580222-13-defend125" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Humphreys 
                  <interp inst="t17580222-13-defend125" type="surname" value="Humphreys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-13-defend125" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-13-defend125" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17580222-13-off69" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580222-13-off69" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-13-off69" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               that he on the <placeName id="t17580222-13-crimeloc70">25th of January</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-13-crimeloc70" type="placeName" value="25th of January"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-13-crimeloc70" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580222-13-off69 t17580222-13-crimeloc70"></join>, between the hours of one and two in the night of the same day, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17580222-13-victim127" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Wade 
                        <interp inst="t17580222-13-victim127" type="surname" value="Wade"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580222-13-victim127" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580222-13-victim127" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580222-13-off69 t17580222-13-victim127"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , did burglariously break and enter, with intent the goods of the said John to steal
            </rs>, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580222-13-person128">
                  John 
                  Wade 
               <interp inst="t17580222-13-person128" type="surname" value="Wade"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-13-person128" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-13-person128" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , junior. I live with my father at <placeName id="t17580222-13-crimeloc71">Mile-End</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17580222-13-crimeloc71" type="placeName" value="Mile-End"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17580222-13-crimeloc71" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580222-13-off69 t17580222-13-crimeloc71"></join>; betwixt the 25th and 26th of January, at about one in the morning, I heard a little noise, like the tinkling of a hammer; I came down from my bed (as I lie over the stable) and found the coach-house broke open. I said hallo I saw the prisoner come out of the coach-house, and run down the garden. He got upon a hot bed, with intent to get over the wall, but his feet<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175802220010"></xptr> struck in it, so that he was obliged to roll over. I got over as soon as he, and laid hold on him. He said he would kill me, and struck me with this hammer (producing one) then I threw him, but he got up again. I threw him three times, in which time he had struck me two blows with the hammer on my head, but by the assistance of the moon I saw it and catch'd his arm, so that it only stun'd me a little. At last I got the hammer out of his hand, and said you have given me two or three blows, I'll give you two or three. So I gave him two or three hearty ones, which settled him. Then I call'd Nathan, a Jew, whose window was near us. He came with a sword to my assistance, and his wife call'd the watch, who came and took him to the watch house. I had fastened that door over night, and I found it with the lock broke, and the door forced.</p>
               <p>Q. Did this coach-house belong to the dwelling house?</p>
               <p>Wade. It is at the bottom of my father's garden. There are goods, such as beds and houshold goods in it, but it is twenty yards from the dwelling house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580222-13-person129">
                  John 
                  Wade 
               <interp inst="t17580222-13-person129" type="surname" value="Wade"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-13-person129" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-13-person129" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the elder. It is my house that was broke open. I lock'd one lock myself over night, which I found broke open, the heads of the nails were eat off, they remained in the lock, and the points of them remained in the door to the coach house; it was an iron plate lock, with a hasp. There was another lock broke besides that; the stable and the coach-house join, there is a door out of one into the other, and they reach from one end of the garden to within twenty yards of the dwelling-house, in the same inclosure.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the coach-house and all let you on one lease?</p>
               <p>Wade. I have them all on one lease.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever let the coach-house distinct from the dwelling house.</p>
               <p>Wade. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580222-13-person130">
                  Nathan 
                  Nathan 
               <interp inst="t17580222-13-person130" type="surname" value="Nathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-13-person130" type="given" value="Nathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-13-person130" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Thursday was a month as I was in bed I heard somebody call very weakly, Nathan, Nathan, Nathan, in the back place, which is our burying ground; I am a Jew, and have the care of it; this was between one and two at night.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does your house stand?</p>
               <p>Nathan. It stands just by Mr. Wade's garden. I stept out of bed, and from a little back window I saw two men struggling in our burying ground, about six or eight yards from the wall under my window. I said what is the matter. Mr. Wade said for God's sake come down, or I shall be kill'd, for I have got a thief. My wife hearing it, call'd out thieves, murder, &amp;c. to alarm the neighbourhood. I ran down stairs, and took a sword, with nothing but my great coat on. There I found Mr. Wade, junior, upon the prisoner; he was all bloody on his forehead, with the hammer in his hand. I said to the prisoner, if you offer to stir, I'll run you through. There came in a watchman and Mr. Child. Then I said to the prisoner, how came you to come here to surprise people at this time of the night. He said I was coming to take that which was not my own.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Mr. Wade by at that time?</p>
               <p>Nathan. I believe he was not at that time, he was gone to dress himself. We took the prisoner to the watch-house, and after that to justice Bury, but he would not acknowledge any thing. As we were coming back from the justice's, he said he lay under a hay stack, and it was very damp, and he got over the wall to see for some barn or place where he might lie; but there is a shed in our place, in which he could have got to lie, without going over that wall, which is seven feet high.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580222-13-person131">
                  Eve 
                  Nathan 
               <interp inst="t17580222-13-person131" type="surname" value="Nathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-13-person131" type="given" value="Eve"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-13-person131" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the last evidence. I said to the prisoner, you wicked man, how could you come here to frighten people at night. He said I was coming to take that which was not my own.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580222-13-person132">
                  Joseph 
                  Child 
               <interp inst="t17580222-13-person132" type="surname" value="Child"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-13-person132" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-13-person132" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was the first person that went there after Nathan's wife had call'd out for assistance. There I saw the prisoner lying, and 
               <persName id="t17580222-13-person133">
                  John 
                  Wade 
               <interp inst="t17580222-13-person133" type="surname" value="Wade"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-13-person133" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-13-person133" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             upon him without breeches, stockings or shoes on. The prisoner's shoes were off, which I suppose he lost by the struggling. I took him up, and asked him, as we were going along, what made him be there, he said, I am like a great many more, I wanted to take that which was none of my own. I led him to the watch-house.</p>
               <p>Mr. Ireland. I saw the prisoner as he was lying on his back, in the Jews burying place. Mr. Child was lifting him up, and 
               <persName id="t17580222-13-person134">
                  John 
                  Wade 
               <interp inst="t17580222-13-person134" type="surname" value="Wade"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-13-person134" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-13-person134" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was prodigiously beat and bloody.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was going to see for work, but I got fuddled, and lay under a hay cock, and going to get into the road again, I saw a place covered, so got over there for shelter. I never was within the place. That hammer belongs to a plough.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175802220011"></xptr>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580222-13-person135">
                  Nicholas 
                  Leonard 
               <interp inst="t17580222-13-person135" type="surname" value="Leonard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-13-person135" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-13-person135" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner six or seven years; it is that time ago since he lodged in the same room I did. He bore an honest character then, but I know nothing of him since.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17580222-13-verdict72" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580222-13-verdict72" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17580222-13-punish73" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580222-13-punish73" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580222-13-defend125 t17580222-13-punish73"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
