<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560915-37">
               <interp inst="t17560915-37" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-37" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-37" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560915"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-37" type="date" value="17560915"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560915-37-off193-c207" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-37-defend280 t17560915-37-off193 t17560915-37-verdict195"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560915-37-off193-c208" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-37-defend281 t17560915-37-off193 t17560915-37-verdict195"></join>
         
               <p>366, 367. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17560915-37-defend280" type="defendantName">
                     Catherine 
                     King 
                  <interp inst="t17560915-37-defend280" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-37-defend280" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-37-defend280" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               <persName id="t17560915-37-defend281" type="defendantName">
                  Mary 
                  Collings 
               <interp inst="t17560915-37-defend281" type="surname" value="Collings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-37-defend281" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-37-defend281" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , <rs id="t17560915-37-deflabel192" type="occupation">spinsters</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-37-defend280 t17560915-37-deflabel192"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-37-defend281 t17560915-37-deflabel192"></join>, were <rs id="t17560915-37-off193" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560915-37-off193" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-37-off193" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               indicted for stealing one hat, value 2 s. and one gold ring, value 9 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17560915-37-victim283" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Haste 
                        <interp inst="t17560915-37-victim283" type="surname" value="Haste"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560915-37-victim283" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560915-37-victim283" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-37-off193 t17560915-37-victim283"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17560915-37-cd194" type="crimeDate">Aug. 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-37-off193 t17560915-37-cd194"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-37-person284">
                  James 
                  Haste 
               <interp inst="t17560915-37-person284" type="surname" value="Haste"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-37-person284" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-37-person284" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the parish of Bethnal-Green. I can't say any thing against either of the prisoners at the bar, for I was so much in liquor I don't know I was in their company. On the 7th of August I lost a hat and some money (I don't know how much) and a plain gold ring from off my finger.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever seen your hat or ring since?</p>
               <p>Hasle. They are now in the constable's hands.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-37-person285">
                  Daniel 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17560915-37-person285" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-37-person285" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-37-person285" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable in Shadwell parish There being a great outcry between twelve and one o'clock, on the 7th of August at night, I went to see what was the matter, and Mr. Clark gave me charge of the prisoner Collings for a robbery. I took her to the watch-house, and after a little time the prisoner King was brought in by some other person. The prosecutor was there, and I asked him if he knew either of the prisoners.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he drunk or sober?</p>
               <p>Jones. At first he did not seem to be in liquor. He told me he was sure they were the two persons that had rob'd him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you in what manner they rob'd him?</p>
               <p>Jones. No, he did not. He said he had lost a hat and ring, and some money, and charged me with both of them. I asked him more than once whether he was sure the prisoners were the persons that rob'd him, and he said he was.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoners say?</p>
               <p>Jones. Collings denied the fact. King said she found the hat.</p>

               <p>Q. Where was the hat found?</p>
               <p>Jones. I don't know, I did not see it that night, nor the ring neither. I searched King, but found nothing upon her. [The hat and ring were then produced in court.]</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. Do you know whose property these are ?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. They are mine, and what I lost that night.</p>
               <p>Mr. Clark. About a quarter of an hour under or over twelve o'clock at night, August the 7th, Collings came into my house, and wanted two penny-worth of bread and cheese. I said, you shall have nothing here. She then wanted me to change a piece of money. I saw it was only a counter, so would have nothing to do with it. The prosecutor was at the door; she ran out to him, put her hand into his pocket, took out a six pence, and gave it me to change. The other prisoner was there; they took him one under one arm, and the other under the other, and drag'd him along. He drop'd on his knees, and I saw King take his hat from off his head.</p>
               <p>Q. Is this hat here produced the same?</p>
               <p>Clerk. I can't say it is. I observed King had him fast by the hand, tho' I did not see the ring taken from him; but he missed it directly.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-37-person286">
                  Mary 
                  Buckle 
               <interp inst="t17560915-37-person286" type="surname" value="Buckle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-37-person286" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-37-person286" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep shop for my uncle, who is a pawnbroker. King brought me the hat and ring here produced; she pawn'd the hat for 2 s. and the ring for 9 s.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she come alone?</p>
               <p>M. Buckle. I believe Collings came along with her; there was a woman with her, very much like her.</p>
               <p>King's defence.</p>
               <p>When I first came in company with the prosecutor, he had never a hat on; after we parted I kick'd against a hat, and took it up; and going a little way farther, my shoes being bad, I trod on that ring and hurt my foot, and stoop'd and took it up. This other young woman knows nothing of the matter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-37-person287">
                  Lucy 
                  Martin 
               <interp inst="t17560915-37-person287" type="surname" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-37-person287" type="given" value="Lucy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-37-person287" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Collings these three or four years; she lived servant with me, and had a very good character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-37-person288">
                  Mary 
                  Parker 
               <interp inst="t17560915-37-person288" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-37-person288" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-37-person288" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Collings between ten and eleven years; she was always a very honest sober girl. She has been often trusted in my house, and I never heard she was so much as suspected before.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17560915-37-verdict195" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560915-37-verdict195" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
