<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17581025-7">
               <interp inst="t17581025-7" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581025-7" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581025-7" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17581025"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581025-7" type="date" value="17581025"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17581025-7-off33-c60" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581025-7-defend72 t17581025-7-off33 t17581025-7-verdict37"></join>
         
               <p>330. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17581025-7-defend72" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Davis 
                  <interp inst="t17581025-7-defend72" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-7-defend72" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-7-defend72" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17581025-7-off33" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581025-7-off33" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-7-off33" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one silk and stuff gown, value 1 l. 3 s. one pair of stays, value 10 s. one satin hat, value 5 s. one linen cap, value 5 s. one linen apron, value 2 s. one pair of sleeves, value 1 s. one pair of stockings, value 1 s. one fan, value 1 s. and two yards of ribon, value 6 d.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17581025-7-victim74" type="victimName">
                     Sarah 
                     More 
                  <interp inst="t17581025-7-victim74" type="surname" value="More"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-7-victim74" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-7-victim74" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581025-7-off33 t17581025-7-victim74"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17581025-7-viclabel34" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581025-7-victim74 t17581025-7-viclabel34"></join>, <rs id="t17581025-7-cd35" type="crimeDate">June 6</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581025-7-off33 t17581025-7-cd35"></join>.*</p>
               <p>Sarah More. On the 6th of June I had ordered the prisoner at the bar to fetch my box from the waggon with the things mentioned in the indictment in it; ( naming them,) I gave him a shilling for fetching them, and when I went to his house for them the box was broke open and the things mentioned were taken out.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. She ordered me to bring the things to my own apartment.</p>
               <p>S. More. I told him in case it was too late at night when he returned he might keep them at his house till morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he bring them to your house?</p>
               <p>S. More. He did not, so I went to his house the next morning, there I found my box uncorded and the lid broke open.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it locked before?</p>
               <p>S. More. It was, and I had the key in my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner at home?</p>
               <p>S. More. No, I saw a little girl first, then his wife came in.</p>
               <p>Q. How was it broke?</p>
               <p>S. More. The lock was not broke, but the hinges were.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after this was it that you took out a warrant against the prisoner?</p>
               <p>S. More. It was about a month after.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the reason you did not take it before?</p>
               <p>S. More. I was ill and could not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it upon the account of your illness that you did not?</p>
               <p>S. More. It really was.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you take the prisoner up?</p>
               <p>S. More. I took him up on the first of July, I waited for the waggoner coming up.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you charge the prisoner with this fact at taking him up?</p>
               <p>S. More. I did, and said if he would bring me my things that were missing nothing should come on it.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Mr. Wade ?</p>
               <p>S. More. I do, he is one of the prisoner's bondsmen, they came and offered me the money for the things after the bill was preferred.</p>
               <p>Q. Who came with him?</p>
               <p>S. More. Mr. Banister did.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you with the prisoner before the justice?</p>
               <p>S. More. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. What was said there?</p>
               <p>S. More. The prisoner said he would die before he would confess, and he would never pay me for them neither.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581025-7-person75">
                  Mary 
                  More 
               <interp inst="t17581025-7-person75" type="surname" value="More"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-7-person75" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-7-person75" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am mother to the prosecutrix, I saw her put all the things into the box, and after that I corded it fast and safe and sent it by the carrier.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the things she mentioned in the box ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175810250008"></xptr>M. More. They were.</p>
               <p>Q. From whence did you send them?</p>
               <p>M. More. From out of Staffordshire: I had been not well and her master gave her leave to come down to see me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581025-7-person76">
                  John 
                  Waley 
               <interp inst="t17581025-7-person76" type="surname" value="Waley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-7-person76" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-7-person76" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the person that drove the waggon, I delivered the box to the prisoner at the bar in the same condition as I received it in the country, it was fastened tight with a cord.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>As I received it of the waggoner so I delivered it.</p>
               <p>Q. to Waley. Are you sure you delivered it corded to the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Waley. I am sure I delivered it locked and corded fast to him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. It was about nine at night when I received it, and she was in bed when I brought it, and would not come down, so I took it home.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Burk Wade. The young woman seemed inclinable to make it up; the justice said there is no evidence to convict the prisoner, and I believe I shall discharge him on the Wednesday, we went away, then I asked her how she could swear against the man, she said she would not swear for the world that he had her things.</p>
               <p>Q. What concern had you in it?</p>
               <p>Wade. I am a neighbour, and have known the prisoner between four and five years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is he?</p>
               <p>Wade. He is <rs id="t17581025-7-deflabel36" type="occupation">a labourer belonging to the water works at Chelsea</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581025-7-defend72 t17581025-7-deflabel36"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Wade. He has an exceeding good character, we thought him an honest man, and I am one of his bail.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutrix. Was the box empty when you found it?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No it was not, there were other things in it.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there no more in value left, than there were missing?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. There were.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there more in weight left, than taken away ?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. There were.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you locked the box ?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. I did, before I came from my mother's house, and my mother corded it, and there was not a bit of cord upon it at the prisoner's house,</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. I did, and thought him an honest man or I had not sent him for my box.</p>
               <p>Q. What induced you to think he took them out?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. The waggoner told me he delivered the box out of the waggon to him safe.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you search the prisoner's house?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. No I did not, they told me I could not take a search warrant out for them.</p>
               <p>Q. Describe the condition the box was in when you first saw it at the prisoner's.</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. It was broke in several places on the top and sides, I have not had it mended, it is in the same condition now.</p>
               <p>Q. to Waley. How long was the waggon coming to London?</p>
               <p>Waley. It was five days.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the box in the waggon all the time?</p>
               <p>Waley. It was.</p>
               <p>Q. Could any body come at it in the waggon?</p>
               <p>Waley. No they could not without removing other things.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you swear that at the time it was delivered to the prisoner, that the hinges and lock were as safe as when delivered to you?</p>
               <p>Waley. It was all the very same, locked and corded fast and the things safe.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure of it?</p>
               <p>Waley. I am quite sure, I delivered it to him with my own hands.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after you received the box of the prosecutrix's mother before you put it into the waggon?</p>
               <p>Waley. I put it in directly as I received it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did it stay in the yard any time?</p>
               <p>Waley. No it did not.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did the waggon stay at London before you took the box out?</p>
               <p>Waley. I believe the waggon stood in the inn-yard with it in about two hours; the waggon was not unloaded till the next morning, there was only the box taken out, which I delivered to the prisoner with my own hands.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175810250009"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17581025-7-person77">
                  Joseph 
                  Banister 
               <interp inst="t17581025-7-person77" type="surname" value="Banister"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-7-person77" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-7-person77" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about eight years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Banister. I believe he is as honest a labouring man as any in the kingdom, he was always willing to oblige any man, I never heard any thing amiss of him in my life.</p>
               <p>Mr. Brent. I have known him ever since September 1756.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Brent, I never knew any other than that of a very honest industrious man; I belong to the water works, I know nothing of his general character, only of his behaviour with us, I pay him his wages, I never heard of any dishonesty by him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581025-7-person78">
                  Thomas 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17581025-7-person78" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-7-person78" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-7-person78" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have worked with the prisoner two years and a half.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known him?</p>
               <p>Clark. I have known him five years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character?</p>
               <p>Clark. I never knew any thing of him but that of an honest man, he earns twelve shillings a week, and that is very good bread, I am frequently with him.</p>
               <p>Mr. Carey. I have known him two years and a half.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Carey. It is as good as most mens, I never heard any ill of him in my life, he is an honest pains taking man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581025-7-person79">
                  Richard 
                  Beech 
               <interp inst="t17581025-7-person79" type="surname" value="Beech"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-7-person79" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-7-person79" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I have known him upwards of two years, he is a very honest pains taking man.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner to Waley. Were there not passengers in your waggon when you came to town?</p>
               <p>Waley. There were two, but they were very sufficient people.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17581025-7-verdict37" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581025-7-verdict37" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17581025-7-punish38" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581025-7-punish38" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581025-7-defend72 t17581025-7-punish38"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
