<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17511204-39">
               <interp inst="t17511204-39" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511204-39" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511204-39" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17511204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511204-39" type="date" value="17511204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17511204-39-off224-c308" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511204-39-defend391 t17511204-39-off224 t17511204-39-verdict228"></join>
         
               <p>48. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17511204-39-defend391" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Brown 
                  <interp inst="t17511204-39-defend391" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-39-defend391" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-39-defend391" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17511204-39-off224" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17511204-39-off224" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-39-off224" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing twenty-one shillings in money numbered
            </rs>, the money of 
               
                  <persName id="t17511204-39-victim393" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Hawkins 
                  <interp inst="t17511204-39-victim393" type="surname" value="Hawkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-39-victim393" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-39-victim393" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511204-39-off224 t17511204-39-victim393"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17511204-39-cd225" type="crimeDate">October 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511204-39-off224 t17511204-39-cd225"></join>. +.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Hawkins. I am wife to William. We <rs id="t17511204-39-viclabel226" type="occupation">keep <placeName id="t17511204-39-crimeloc227">the Goat in Eagle-court in the Strand</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-39-crimeloc227" type="placeName" value="the Goat in Eagle-court in the Strand"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-39-crimeloc227" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511204-39-off224 t17511204-39-crimeloc227"></join>
                  </rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511204-39-victim393 t17511204-39-viclabel226"></join>. The prisoner came into my house on the 22d of October, he had a pot of beer and paid for it. He asked for a bit of bread as my family were eating. I asked him to eat a bit of meat, he did, he staid from 3 in the afternoon till 12. There were 3 or 4 people with him at first, I imagined by his manner of proceeding he knew them all. About 12 he asked me who I had in the house? saying he had a charge of money about him and must lie there all night. I told him that his bed was a shilling. He asked for change for what he called a Shina, that was a 36 s. piece. I said I had but a guinea, said he, what have I had? said I, so much; he said his money was in the waistband of his breeches, I turned my face from him while he went to take it out. He said give me the silver, I did 21 shillings and held my hand for his money. He took up a knife and said if I stirred he'd do me a mischief.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever seen him before?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Hawkins. I never saw him before that time. He talked to me as if he had known me a long time. He said he wanted to go to the play, I lent him half a guinea. He talked so much goodness I thought he was much better than many of us christians.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>Coming by this woman's house about 5 o'clock, I was called in by her. She said she know'd me. She wanted me to drink pint of beer. She got a girl in white gown, she groped and felt at me. The woman ask me if I please go up stairs and have fire. Said she what signifies starving in this company<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175112040025"></xptr> in a large room. We'll go where is a bed, we went up, she brought up 2 bowls of punch, after that the girl asked me go to the play. I went with her to it and back again, she ask me if I would go to supper, tell me what will have. I said some pork stakes. She said she could get some mutton chops. She would not let me keep the Mans company below, but be with this girl up stairs, thinking I had great deal money. She decoyed me still to stay and sleep there. She said what time will you get up, you are as safe as in queen's house, it will be but half a crown for your bed, and a girl to lie with you all night. I finding it was bad house would not stay. She would hang me for a farthing, Look into her character, my Lord, see what a character she has got. I have serv'd my king and country great many years.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutrix. Were there other company in your house at that time?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. There was no men in my house but what were in a garret in bed</p>
               <p>Q. Did he go to the play that night?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. He did, with a woman that come in with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you keep a licensed house?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. I do. I have kept it 3 years.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511204-39-person394">
                  John 
                  Lavers 
               <interp inst="t17511204-39-person394" type="surname" value="Lavers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-39-person394" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-39-person394" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am beadle of the parish. The prosecutrix keeps a very bad house. There are a great many loose, idle people use it. I have seen them when I go my rounds with the constable. It is looked upon in the neighbourhood to be a bad house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see that black there. (Note, the prisoner was a black).</p>
               <p>Lavers. No, not to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17511204-39-verdict228" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17511204-39-verdict228" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
