<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570914-6">
               <interp inst="t17570914-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-6" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570914"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-6" type="date" value="17570914"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570914-6-off36-c64" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-6-defend73 t17570914-6-off36 t17570914-6-verdict39"></join>
         
               <p>303. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17570914-6-defend73" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Martha 
                     Dobbin 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17570914-6-alias-2" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-6-defend73 t17570914-6-alias-2"></join>Carter</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-6-defend73" type="surname" value="Dobbin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-6-defend73" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-6-defend73" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17570914-6-deflabel35" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-6-defend73 t17570914-6-deflabel35"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17570914-6-off36" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570914-6-off36" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-6-off36" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing five linen sheets, value 30 s. one pair of silver buckles, value 12 s.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175709140005"></xptr> one silver watch with two silver seals, value 3 l. two linen sheets, five pair of thread stockings, one pair of worstead stockings, one pair of shag breeches, one pair of buckskin breeches, and one copper pot, the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17570914-6-victim76" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Saunders 
                        <interp inst="t17570914-6-victim76" type="surname" value="Saunders"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570914-6-victim76" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570914-6-victim76" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-6-off36 t17570914-6-victim76"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling-house of the said William
            </rs>, <rs id="t17570914-6-cd37" type="crimeDate">May 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-6-off36 t17570914-6-cd37"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-6-person77">
                  William 
                  Saunders 
               <interp inst="t17570914-6-person77" type="surname" value="Saunders"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-6-person77" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-6-person77" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17570914-6-crimeloc38">Gilbert-street, Bloomsbury</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17570914-6-crimeloc38" type="placeName" value="Gilbert-street, Bloomsbury"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17570914-6-crimeloc38" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-6-off36 t17570914-6-crimeloc38"></join>. I had all the goods mention'd in the indictment, except the copper pot, on Sunday night, and I missed them the Tuesday morning after, being the 3d of May; they were all kept in a chest of drawers and the copper pot was in the kitchen.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to suspect the prisoner ?</p>
               <p>Saunders. I had a bill upon my door to lett a room. The prisoner came and ask'd me if I had a lodging I said, if she would call the next week it. She came the next week, and my little boy and I were both ill in bed, who said we should be lost for want of somebody to take care of us; I said, I had nobody that I could trust, so I let her come into the house to look after us.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you know her before ?</p>
               <p>Saunders. I never saw her before she came to enquire after the lodging.</p>
               <p>Q. What was you to pay her per week?</p>
               <p>Saunders. I paid her half a crown per week.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was you sick?</p>
               <p>Saunders. Between a month and five weeks. In the time she was with me I lost four shirts, mark'd W. F. one mark'd 
               <persName id="t17570914-6-person78">
                  George 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17570914-6-person78" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-6-person78" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-6-person78" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , two of my little boy's, a shift of my little girl's, a pair of silver buckles, mark'd W. F. a watch-with two silver seals, a pair of sheets, a pair of cotton stockings, five pair of thread stockings, a pair of shag breeches, a pair of buckskin breeches, and a copper pot. I had wound my watch up and put it in my pocket, and my breeches under my head, on the Monday night, and in the morning my breeches were gone. Then I looked about and missed the other things. She was gone and I never saw her since, till Tuesday was se'n-night.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she in the house when you went to bed over night?</p>
               <p>Saunders. She was in the room after I was in bed. I had taken a sweat that night.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she lodge in your house?</p>
               <p>Saunders. No; she used to go to her lodgings abroad. She had set up with us six nights, when we were very ill, and used to lock us in and put the key under the door. About two days after I found the shag breeches at Mr. 
               <persName id="t17570914-6-person79">
                  Robert 
                  Hull 
               <interp inst="t17570914-6-person79" type="surname" value="Hull"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-6-person79" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-6-person79" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's house, and a shirt at a house the corner of Lumber-Court, near the Seven-Dials. I found the copper pot and one silver seal. ( Produced in court, and deposed to) I getting intelligence of the prisoner's being at the house of one Dobson, got a warrant and went there, where the people told me she was gone in the country that morning; but on the Tuesday after the constable took her, when she began to blaspheme and make a great noise, but I had found all these things but the seal before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she confess any thing?</p>
               <p>Saunders. No, she did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-6-person80">
                  Robert 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17570914-6-person80" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-6-person80" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-6-person80" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a publick house in Gray's-Inn-Lane; the prisoner gave me this seal to keep some time in June, and said she was going into the country.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-6-person81">
                  Mary 
                  Ansel 
               <interp inst="t17570914-6-person81" type="surname" value="Ansel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-6-person81" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-6-person81" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner pawn'd this copper pot with me on the 21st of May, in the evening.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-6-person82">
                  Robert 
                  Hull 
               <interp inst="t17570914-6-person82" type="surname" value="Hull"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-6-person82" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-6-person82" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner brought these breeches to me; the prosecutor came and described them, and I deliver'd them to him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I went to take a lodging of the prosecutor, and he did not chuse to take me in as a lodger, but as a housekeeper and companion; he and his child being sick, I pawn'd my linen gown to support them. After that he brings home his lawful wife, dressed in green. The child met me in the street and said, my mamma is come home, so I did not think proper to go to the house again. I never received a halfpenny of him, but one single shilling for the child and me to take pleasure in a walk to Hampstead. I went to Covent Garden and met with an acquaintance of mine, who ask'd me how I liked my old man. I told him I was afraid his wife would send me to Bridewell, and was come away. I had that seal above five years.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. What are you?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I am a cobler, and live under the Blue-Lion, at the corner of Gray's-Inn passage.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-6-person83">
                  Catherine 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17570914-6-person83" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-6-person83" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-6-person83" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner three years; I never heard she bore a bad character, only what I have heard about this affair.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see her last?</p>
               <p>C. Evans. I had not seen her for five months last past.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-6-person84">
                  Michael 
                  Connel 
               <interp inst="t17570914-6-person84" type="surname" value="Connel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-6-person84" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-6-person84" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Leadenhall-Market, and have known the prisoner some years; I know no ill of her, except this affair.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175709140006"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-6-person85">
                  John 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17570914-6-person85" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-6-person85" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-6-person85" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her two years. She has a very good character. I will speak as much as she deserves: I know no ill of her, till this affair.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570914-6-verdict39" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570914-6-verdict39" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
