<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17561208-10">
               <interp inst="t17561208-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561208-10" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561208-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17561208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561208-10" type="date" value="17561208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17561208-10-off51-c69" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-10-defend86 t17561208-10-off51 t17561208-10-verdict54"></join>
         
               <p>10. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17561208-10-defend86" type="defendantName">
                     Daniel 
                     Jones 
                  <interp inst="t17561208-10-defend86" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-10-defend86" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-10-defend86" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17561208-10-off51" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561208-10-off51" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-10-off51" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 21 pair of thread stockings, val. 4 s. and 4 pair of cotton ditto
            </rs>, the goods of 
               <persName id="t17561208-10-victim87" type="victimName">
                  
                     <persName id="t17561208-10-person88" type="victimName">
                        William 
                        Wooley 
                     <interp inst="t17561208-10-person88" type="surname" value="Wooley"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17561208-10-person88" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17561208-10-person88" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-10-off51 t17561208-10-person88"></join>
                     </persName>
                   and Co.<interp inst="t17561208-10-victim87" type="surname" value="Wooley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-10-victim87" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-10-victim87" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-10-off51 t17561208-10-victim87"></join>
                  </persName>
             
                  <rs id="t17561208-10-cd52" type="crimeDate">Nov. 4</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-10-off51 t17561208-10-cd52"></join>.* </p> 
               <p>Mr. Edlington. The prisoner at the bar served us in the capacity of a <rs id="t17561208-10-deflabel53" type="occupation">porter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-10-defend86 t17561208-10-deflabel53"></join>, during which time we had much reason to suspect his fidelity; in the month of May he left us, and after he was gone, Mr. Wooley, my father, refused him his box, saying he would see the inside of it before it went away; he said he had not got the key about him at this and the other time when he came, but he would bring it. This past on for 4 months. Mr. Wooley was disatisfied, so he went to my Lord-mayor, and got a warrant and broke it open, and in it we found 21 pair of thread stockings, and 4 pair of cotton ones, and sundry other things, our property.</p>
               <p>Q. Who are your partners?</p>
               <p>Edlington. Wooley and Hopkins.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain as to the goods?</p>
               <p>Edlington. I am, they were of our own manufacturing.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175612080008"></xptr>Q. When was the box broke open ?</p>
               <p>Edlington. On the 4th of November.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561208-10-person89">
                  James 
                  Compton 
               <interp inst="t17561208-10-person89" type="surname" value="Compton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-10-person89" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-10-person89" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was sent for about the begining of November last to Mr. Wooley's in Cheapside; there was a search warrant given to me, and I was order'd to break a box open, which they said belong'd to the prisoner; I broke it open, and found in it these stockings ( producing 25 pair ) a pair of muffatees and a piece for breeches. After that I went and took the prisoner, and carried him before my Lord-mayor, and he was committed.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say for himself ?</p>
               <p>Compton. He said he was very sorry, and if his master would forgive him, he'd never do the like again; it was the first time he ever did so.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>The box lying in that house, some body might have a spite against me, and put them in; I never put such things in.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mr. Townsend. My master Mr. Butler wanting a footman, the prisoner came to offer himself as such. I lik'd the appearance of the lad very well, and hired him for a footman (all but his character.) I went to Mr. Wooley's house for his character; one of the partners in the shop gave me a very good one of him. I asked the man in the shop if he thought him an honest man, who replied he was. I hired him, and he lived with us from the 26th of May to the 12th of Nov following, during which time he justly fulfill'd his trust. I have twice sent him out to change bank notes, one a 20 l. and the other a 30 l. he brought the change to me; once I sent him with our plate to the silversmith to have it weigh'd, when the plate act commenced; he brought it safe. During the time he lived with us, we don't know we lost the value of a halfpenny in any thing. He behav'd very well. Part of the time he was with us we were in the country at my lord Arran's, where was a great quantity of plate; we lost nothing there.</p>
               <p>John Hall. I was with the prisoner at my lord Arran's in the country, where was great quantity of liquor; he behav'd with a great deal of sobriety and order. I do not remember I ever heard him swear an oath, he gain'd the esteem of every person for a sober diligent servant, I believe no body, during that time, either heard him swear or saw him in liquor.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17561208-10-verdict54" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561208-10-verdict54" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17561208-10-punish55" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561208-10-punish55" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-10-defend86 t17561208-10-punish55"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
