<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560714-24">
               <interp inst="t17560714-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560714-24" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560714-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560714"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560714-24" type="date" value="17560714"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560714-24-off125-c139" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560714-24-defend178 t17560714-24-off125 t17560714-24-verdict128"></join>
         
               <p>306. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17560714-24-defend178" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Burket 
                  <interp inst="t17560714-24-defend178" type="surname" value="Burket"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-24-defend178" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-24-defend178" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17560714-24-deflabel124" type="occupation">single woman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560714-24-defend178 t17560714-24-deflabel124"></join>, was indicted for the <rs id="t17560714-24-off125" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560714-24-off125" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-24-off125" type="offenceSubcategory" value="infanticide"></interp>
               murder of her female bastard child
            </rs>. She stood likewise charged on the coroner's inquest for the said murder, <rs id="t17560714-24-cd126" type="crimeDate">June 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560714-24-off125 t17560714-24-cd126"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560714-24-person179">
                  Thomas 
                  Buckle 
               <interp inst="t17560714-24-person179" type="surname" value="Buckle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-24-person179" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-24-person179" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the same house where the prisoner did.</p>
               <p>Q. Whose house is that?</p>
               <p>Buckle. One Mr. Bailey's; and she was <rs id="t17560714-24-deflabel127" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560714-24-defend178 t17560714-24-deflabel127"></join> to Mr. Bow, a singer in the play-house, who lodges in the same house. She was suspected by us all to be with child, but she denied it to he, mistress, and every one of us. One time I went up stairs with a bushel of coals for her. She said she was short breath'd, and could not go up four or five pair of stairs. She call'd me up into her own garret, to fetch her up two pails of water. I ask'd her what was the matter with her. She said she was short breath'd. I said, you are certainly with child. She said, no, she was not. I said, you surely are as much as ever my wife was; and with a great many words she own'd that she was with child, and that one Mr. Jones a taylor was the father of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is this Jones ?</p>
               <p>Buckle. He is a master taylor in York-Street, Covent-Garden. She had lived there before she came to live with Mr Low. I endeavour'd to persuade her to swear the child to Mr. Jones. She said she would not.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of a child being born?</p>
               <p>Buckle. I was at the taking a child out of Mr. Bailey's vault, and I help'd to wash it.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know this was her child?</p>
               <p>Buckle. I took her out of her mistress's room and carried her to the watch house, and said to her, how could you be so cruel to throw this child down the vault? She said, I do not deny the child's being mine, but I beg you'll take no farther notice.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you when you had this conversation ?</p>
               <p>Buckle. This was as we were going along.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body else hear it?</p>
               <p>Buckle. No.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you ?</p>
               <p>Buckle. I am a soldier, but am also a weekly servant to Mr. Bailey.</p>
               <p>Q. When the child was taken out of the vault, how did it appear?</p>
               <p>Buckle. It seem'd to be full grown, as far as I could judge, in all shapes.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any wounds upon it?</p>
               <p>Buckle. No, none at all: But I did not take much notice of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560714-24-person180">
                  Mary 
                  Hewit 
               <interp inst="t17560714-24-person180" type="surname" value="Hewit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-24-person180" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-24-person180" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mrs. Bailey. I went to the prisoner on a Sunday in the forenoon, and ask'd her what she had done with her child.</p>
               <p>Q. What day of the month was that?</p>
               <p>M. Hewit. I can't tell the day of the month. She did not resolve me then, but cry'd. I went in the afternoon, and ask'd her again, when she told me she had put it into a clout, and flung it down the necessary.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any thing of the child when it was born?</p>
               <p>M. Hewit. No, I did not. She ask'd me to lie with her that night, but I did not, it did not suit; I had lain with her several nights before. As I declined it, she ask'd my fellow servant.</p>

               <p>Q. What was your reason for declining it?</p>
               <p>M. Hewit. Because I was to get up soon the next morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the child after it was taken out out of the vault ?</p>
               <p>M. Hewit. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. How did it appear?</p>
               <p>M. Hewit. I did not see any bruises.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say about it?</p>
               <p>M. Hewit. She told me it was born deed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560714-24-person181">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Winter 
               <interp inst="t17560714-24-person181" type="surname" value="Winter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-24-person181" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-24-person181" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was sent for on the 22d of June before the justice, and ordered to search the prisoner. She was at the Round-house. I found she had had a child a few days before. I desired she might be put into a bed and taken care of. Accordingly she was. The coroner and jury ordered me to get the child cleaned, and bring it to them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any marks of violence upon it?</p>
               <p>E. Winter. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did it appear to be full grown ?</p>
               <p>E. Winter. It did; it was two foot all but one inch long; and as fine a girl as ever I set my eyes on.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any conversation with the prisoner about it?</p>
               <p>E. Winter. No, none at all. We were strangers to each other.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175607140015"></xptr>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>My child was still born.</p>

               <p>Q. to M. Hewit. Was there any preparation made for the child?</p>
               <p>M. Hewit. Here is some linen that I took out of the box (producing a shirt, a cap, a forehead cloth, a long stay, and a roller.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you by them?</p>
               <p>M. Hewit. Justice Fielding ordered the box to be brought to his house, and bid me search it. I did so, and found these things in it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she ever tell you she was with child?</p>
               <p>M. Hewit. No, she never did. I had told her she was with child.</p>
               <p>Q. What answer did she make?</p>
               <p>M. Hewit. She never denied or own'd it to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Had she ever said any thing to you about this linen before?</p>
               <p>M. Hewit. No, she had not; she said she had things in the box, when the justice asked her if she had made any preparation.</p>
               <p>Q. Who fetch'd the box?</p>
               <p>M. Hewit. The justice order'd Buckle to fetch it, which he did.</p>
               <p>Q. to Buckle. Was you sent to fetch the box by the justice ?</p>
               <p>Buckle. I was, and 
               <persName id="t17560714-24-person182">
                  Mary 
                  Hewit 
               <interp inst="t17560714-24-person182" type="surname" value="Hewit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-24-person182" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-24-person182" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             went with me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you open the box?</p>
               <p>Buckle. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever ask the prisoner if she had made any preparation for her child?</p>
               <p>Buckle. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she ever say to you that she had made any?</p>
               <p>Buckle. No.</p>
               <p>To her Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560714-24-person183">
                  Ann 
                  Arnold 
               <interp inst="t17560714-24-person183" type="surname" value="Arnold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-24-person183" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-24-person183" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was sent to my house from out of the country, and I got her this unhappy place.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she give you any account of having any linen prepared for the child?</p>
               <p>A. Arnold. No, she did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her character?</p>
               <p>A. Arnold. She has a very honest character.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known her?</p>
               <p>A. Arnold. I have known her ever since she came out of the country, which is about 20 months.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560714-24-person184">
                  Mary 
                  Weinwright 
               <interp inst="t17560714-24-person184" type="surname" value="Weinwright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-24-person184" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-24-person184" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the prisoner; and never heard any ill of her in my life. She always behaved very well, and never denied her being with child to me. She used to come on errands to me from her mistress, sometimes twice or thrice a day, for butten and cream, and what was wanting.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of her preparing linen for the child?</p>
               <p>M. Weinwright. No, I do not; I never asked her that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560714-24-person185">
                  Ann 
                  List 
               <interp inst="t17560714-24-person185" type="surname" value="List"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-24-person185" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560714-24-person185" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . One day I asked the prisoner how long she had to go, and she told me about a month; she never denied her being with child in the least to me.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known her?</p>
               <p>A. List. About four months, ever since she has been with Mr. Low. I often asked her about her lying in; she never denied it to me. I took her to be a married woman by her behaviour.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she brought to bed near the time she said ?</p>
               <p>A. List. It was about the time.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her character?</p>
               <p>A. List. I took her to be a very sober person.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17560714-24-verdict128" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560714-24-verdict128" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
