<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17531024-70">
               <interp inst="t17531024-70" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531024-70" type="year" value="1753"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531024-70" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17531024"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531024-70" type="date" value="17531024"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17531024-70-off313-c359" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-70-defend479 t17531024-70-off313 t17531024-70-verdict316"></join>
         
               <p>519. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17531024-70-defend479" type="defendantName">
                  Job 
                  Horniblew 
               <interp inst="t17531024-70-defend479" type="surname" value="Horniblew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-70-defend479" type="given" value="Job"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-70-defend479" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for that he, together with 
               <persName id="t17531024-70-person480">
                  Dennis 
                  Neal 
               <interp inst="t17531024-70-person480" type="surname" value="Neal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-70-person480" type="given" value="Dennis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-70-person480" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17531024-70-off313" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17531024-70-off313" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-70-off313" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               in a certain field, or open place, near the King's highway; on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17531024-70-victim482" type="victimName">
                           Joseph 
                           Rixton 
                        <interp inst="t17531024-70-victim482" type="surname" value="Rixton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17531024-70-victim482" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17531024-70-victim482" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-70-off313 t17531024-70-victim482"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and stealing from him one steel tobacco-box, value 6 d. one clasp knife, one iron key, and 4 s. and 6 d. in money number'd
            </rs>, <rs id="t17531024-70-cd314" type="crimeDate">September 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-70-off313 t17531024-70-cd314"></join>.</p>
               <p>J. Rixton. I am a <rs id="t17531024-70-viclabel315" type="occupation">shoe-maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-70-victim482 t17531024-70-viclabel315"></join>, and live in St. Paul's Church-yard; on the 17th of September, very near 8 o'clock, coming from the Boo, a little beyond the Foundling-Hospital, I had got almost to the end of the field ; I heard a ask what a clock it was, it was very, (I saw nobody then,) I said I could not tell, immediately a man came up and clapped a pistol to<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175310240036"></xptr> my belly, and said, your money; I said you are welcome to have it: he took what I had, which was about four or five shillings, then he said, your watch; there were two other men with him, he ordered one of them to put his hand, into my left hand pocket, they were standing on that side me; I said, there is nothing but keys, they took them out, the man before me, said to the man, give them him again, which I thought they had done; but when I got home I missed one, they took out also a pair of spectacles, a penknife, and a tobacco-box; I could not see them, to discern who they were, they seem'd to be middle-siz'd men.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-70-person483">
                  Joseph 
                  Randolph 
               <interp inst="t17531024-70-person483" type="surname" value="Randolph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-70-person483" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-70-person483" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner at the bar, Dennis Neal, and I -</p>
               <p>Q. Where is 
               <persName id="t17531024-70-person484">
                  Dennis 
                  Neal 
               <interp inst="t17531024-70-person484" type="surname" value="Neal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-70-person484" type="given" value="Dennis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-70-person484" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Randolph. He is now confin'd in Winchester-Goal ; we were going towards the Foundling-hospital, Dennis said, if I like this man I'll stop him, he did, holding a pistol to him, the man was the prosecutor, he said, I must have your money, he took from him 5 s. and 6 d. and some half-pence, a tobacco-box, I took out some keys out of his left hand pocket, and delivered them to Neal, he gave the prosecutor them again; I took a penknife out of his right hand pocket, the prisoner stood close by with a pistol in his hand; Neal put the money in his pocket, and said, the tobacco-box would do instead of a pistol to put to peoples heads; then we went to Highgate, and spent some of the money.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-70-person485">
                  William 
                  Norden 
               <interp inst="t17531024-70-person485" type="surname" value="Norden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-70-person485" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-70-person485" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Friday was fortnight I had an information against Bowyer, for several robberies; we heard he used to lie in Chick-lane, we went and searched the house, and found the evidence and prisoner in bed together; we knew they had been guilty of many bad things, we saw a watch hanging by them, and there were boots and spurs; we turned the pillows over, and found two brace of pistols loaded in their pillowcases, then we searched further and found Bowyer ; we brought them all three to Clerkenwell-Bridewell, there Randolph wanted to be admitted an evidence; we took him to justice Fielding, who took his confession, this was the very first robbery he mentioned, I found the tobacco-box and penknife on Randolph; (produced in court, and the box deposed to by the prosecutor,) who said, one knife might be like another, and would not sware to that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-70-person486">
                  William 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17531024-70-person486" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-70-person486" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-70-person486" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was with Norden in taking the prisoner, and he confirm'd his account.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>They found us in bed with these things about us, the evidence against us was in trouble last sessions.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17531024-70-verdict316" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17531024-70-verdict316" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17531024-70-punish317" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17531024-70-punish317" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-70-defend479 t17531024-70-punish317"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>See the prisoner an evidence last sessions, No. 396, and sessions before, 359, by the name of Joseph.</p>
            </div1>
