<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17580113-25">
               <interp inst="t17580113-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580113-25" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580113-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580113"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580113-25" type="date" value="17580113"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580113-25-off151-c231" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-25-defend276 t17580113-25-off151 t17580113-25-verdict156"></join>
         
               <p>86. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17580113-25-defend276" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Percival 
                  <interp inst="t17580113-25-defend276" type="surname" value="Percival"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-25-defend276" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-25-defend276" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17580113-25-off151" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580113-25-off151" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-25-off151" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one canvas bag, value 6 d. and sixty pounds weight of pimento, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17580113-25-victim278" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Cutter 
                        <interp inst="t17580113-25-victim278" type="surname" value="Cutter"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580113-25-victim278" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580113-25-victim278" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-25-off151 t17580113-25-victim278"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in a certain vessel lying on a navigable river, called the river Thames
            </rs>, <rs id="t17580113-25-cd152" type="crimeDate">January 4</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-25-off151 t17580113-25-cd152"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-25-person279">
                  Andrew 
                  Morrison 
               <interp inst="t17580113-25-person279" type="surname" value="Morrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-25-person279" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-25-person279" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a waterman, and ply a common wherry. There was a ship lay <placeName id="t17580113-25-crimeloc153">between Union-Stairs and Bell-Dock</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17580113-25-crimeloc153" type="placeName" value="between Union-Stairs and Bell-Dock"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17580113-25-crimeloc153" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-25-off151 t17580113-25-crimeloc153"></join> ( I don't know her name, nor the captain's neither) to which I carried the prisoner as a fare, about noon, but don't know the day. He desired me to stay, and I staid about ten minutes.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175801130029"></xptr>Q. Where was the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Morrison. He was on board. He threw something into my boat, but I don't know what it was.</p>
               <p>Q. What was it like?</p>
               <p>Morrison. It was in a bag.</p>
               <p>Q. How big?</p>
               <p>Morrison. About as big as a large pillow.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he come on board you after that?</p>
               <p>Morrison. No.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do with it?</p>
               <p>Morrison. I threw it over board.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you do so?</p>
               <p>Morrison. Because I was afraid of the custom-house officers, for fear I should lose my boat, it not being my own. I suspected it to have been something that was run.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do after that?</p>
               <p>Morrison. I went away directly.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-25-person280">
                  Thomas 
                  Gouge 
               <interp inst="t17580113-25-person280" type="surname" value="Gouge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-25-person280" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-25-person280" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a waterman that attend upon ships. I was going on shore with a man, about twelve o'clock, that day, and saw 
               <persName id="t17580113-25-person281">
                  Andrew 
                  Morrison 
               <interp inst="t17580113-25-person281" type="surname" value="Morrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-25-person281" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-25-person281" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in his boat at the ship's head named Ranger. I asked him what he did there He said he was waiting for a fare. I said I believed he was waiting for no good, for I had a suspicion he was going to rob the ship.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Gouge. He is a <rs id="t17580113-25-deflabel154" type="occupation">soldier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-25-defend276 t17580113-25-deflabel154"></join>, but he was employed on board the ship as <rs id="t17580113-25-deflabel155" type="occupation">a lumper, whose business is to put the casks out of the ship, at 6 d. a cask</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-25-defend276 t17580113-25-deflabel155"></join>; they were unloading the ship. I saw a bag in the head of the wherry that Morrison was in. He saw me, and had not time to row with his wherry head foremost, fearing I should catch him; but he rowed stern foremost. I rowed as fast as I could towards the ship. They called from the ship and said, Mr. Gouge row after that man, he has a bag of pimento in his boat</p>
               <p>Q. What is pimento?</p>
               <p>Gouge. It is West-India all spice. When I came up to Morrison he threw the bag over board. I saw it would swim, so I row'd by it after him; but when I found he would not run away I shoved back, took up the bag, and ask'd him the meaning of throwing it over board. He said he did not do any such thing. I took him, and carried him on board the ship with the bag, and told him if he would tell who gave it him, he should have his liberty. He said he would. Then he went and charged the prisoner at the bar with it. Then we took the prisoner up, and had him before a magistrate, but he denied it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-25-person282">
                  William 
                  Cutter 
               <interp inst="t17580113-25-person282" type="surname" value="Cutter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-25-person282" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-25-person282" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am master of that ship, and most of the goods, at that time, were my property, so I appear as prosecutor; but know nothing of the taking of it.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the prisoner employed about in that ship ?</p>
               <p>Cutter. I employ a master lumper, and he finds a gang of men to work out the goods from the ship.</p>
               <p>Q. to Morrison. Did you know the prisoner before that day?</p>
               <p>Morrison. I have several times before carried him on board, and brought him on shore, from that and several other ships.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known him?</p>
               <p>Morrison. I have known him about three quarters of a year; I have drank with him, and know him very well.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you close by the ship when you threw the bag over-board.</p>
               <p>Morrison. No, I was not.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you row your boat?</p>
               <p>Morrison. I row'd her stern foremost.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was at work in the hold of that ship, and two men along with me. I knew nothing of this affair, till I heard all the officers in an uproar; but this old Morrison knowing me, he, to clear himself, made use of my name.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. What is the value of that pimento?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. It is worth about thirty-eight shillings.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-25-person283">
                  Matthew 
                  Salmon 
               <interp inst="t17580113-25-person283" type="surname" value="Salmon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-25-person283" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-25-person283" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a sergeant in the third regiment of foot-guards, and the prisoner belongs to the company which I do.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has he been in that regiment?</p>
               <p>Salmon. He has been in it about five years.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know him before he was in the regiment?</p>
               <p>Salmon. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. How has he behaved?</p>
               <p>Salmon. Very well, none better. I was very much surprised to hear this of him, for he could have been trusted by any officer with any thing they have. He is a well behaved young man, and has been at work most commonly; he always appear'd clean under arms.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175801130030"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-25-person284">
                  John 
                  Andrews 
               <interp inst="t17580113-25-person284" type="surname" value="Andrews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-25-person284" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-25-person284" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am also a sergeant in the same company that the prisoner belongs to, and have known him five years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Andrews. He has an exceeding good character.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his pay?</p>
               <p>Andrews. Their pay is four shillings a week, and it takes up one of it to repair them, so that they have three shillings a man to live on; but as he is a working fellow, and gets six or eight shillings to it, it is of great service to him.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17580113-25-verdict156" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580113-25-verdict156" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
