<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17520914-37">
               <interp inst="t17520914-37" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520914-37" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520914-37" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520914"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520914-37" type="date" value="17520914"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520914-37-off180-c247" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-37-defend317 t17520914-37-off180 t17520914-37-verdict183"></join>
         
               <p>443. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17520914-37-defend317" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Huits 
                  <interp inst="t17520914-37-defend317" type="surname" value="Huits"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-37-defend317" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-37-defend317" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17520914-37-off180" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520914-37-off180" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-37-off180" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing two brass candlesticks, val. 2 s.
            </rs> the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17520914-37-victim319" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Humphrys 
                  <interp inst="t17520914-37-victim319" type="surname" value="Humphrys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-37-victim319" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-37-victim319" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-37-off180 t17520914-37-victim319"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17520914-37-cd181" type="crimeDate">Aug. 31</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-37-off180 t17520914-37-cd181"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520914-37-person320">
                  John 
                  Humphrys 
               <interp inst="t17520914-37-person320" type="surname" value="Humphrys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-37-person320" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-37-person320" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <rs id="t17520914-37-cd182" type="crimeDate">Holbourn</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-37-off180 t17520914-37-cd182"></join>, above the bars, this day 7 night about 6 o'clock I came home, there was the prisoner sitting in my room, my wife was there. I asked him his business, he said he was come to buy my goods, and said my wife spoke to him about selling them; I told him I did not want to sell them, and desired him to go out of the room. Then he said there was a broker to come who would buy them. I desired him to go about his business, I went down to my landlady, then there came a broker and two porters through the passage and went up stairs, I followed them up; the broker said I am come to buy your goods. I said I am not going to sell them; the broker took his leave of me, saying, he hoped there was no harm done, and went away. The prisoner insisted upon staying there, and buying my goods, I told him if he'd not go I would make him, then he went away. Two days after we missed a pair of brass candlesticks, and by inquiring I found them at a broker's facing St. Andrew's Church, on Thursday last.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you seen them before?</p>
               <p>Humphrys. I believe they were on the mantle-piece in my room the day that the prisoner was there?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520914-37-person321">
                  Ann 
                  Winter 
               <interp inst="t17520914-37-person321" type="surname" value="Winter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-37-person321" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-37-person321" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Holborn, facing St. Andrew's Church, I bought these two candlesticks of the prisoner at the bar last Monday, about six in the evening, I have seen him about a dozen times before.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I keep a house myself, I have many sufficient people to appear for me, they are not here, but if I had known I would have brought them, I can bring them tomorrow, or I can go and fetch one or two now.</p>
               <p>Q. to Winter. How did he behave when he sold you the things?</p>
               <p>A. Winter. Very sensibly. He came and said, here is a bargain for you; I looked at them and asked the price; he said upon the word of an honest man I gave twenty pence for them, and I will have two shillings of you if you have them. I have bought things of him two or three times before, he always behaved very sensibly.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520914-37-verdict183" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520914-37-verdict183" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
