<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17591205-23">
               <interp inst="t17591205-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591205-23" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591205-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17591205"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591205-23" type="date" value="17591205"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17591205-23-off116-c143" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-23-defend185 t17591205-23-off116 t17591205-23-verdict120"></join>
         
               <p>25. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17591205-23-defend185" type="defendantName">
                     Samuel 
                     Fuller 
                  <interp inst="t17591205-23-defend185" type="surname" value="Fuller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-23-defend185" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-23-defend185" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17591205-23-off116" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17591205-23-off116" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-23-off116" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he, on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17591205-23-victim187" type="victimName">
                           Joseph 
                           Stevens 
                        <interp inst="t17591205-23-victim187" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17591205-23-victim187" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17591205-23-victim187" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-23-off116 t17591205-23-victim187"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and taking from his person five guineas, one half guinea, one 36 s. piece, and one silk purse, value 1 s. his property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17591205-23-cd117" type="crimeDate">Nov. 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-23-off116 t17591205-23-cd117"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-23-person188">
                  Joseph 
                  Stevens 
               <interp inst="t17591205-23-person188" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-23-person188" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-23-person188" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Daget's Court, Brokers-Row, Morefields. On the 14th of Nov. at night, I was in Broad-Street, at the Rose and Crown, the house of Mr. Barber. I went away it might be past twelve at night; the prisoner is a <rs id="t17591205-23-deflabel118" type="occupation">watchman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-23-defend185 t17591205-23-deflabel118"></join>, and was called to take care of me home.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in liquor?</p>
               <p>Stevens. I was a little in liquor, yet I could have gone home by myself, but my friend called the watchman to go with me. As I was in <placeName id="t17591205-23-crimeloc119">Bedlam-Passage going out of Broad-Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17591205-23-crimeloc119" type="placeName" value="Bedlam-Passage going out of Broad-Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17591205-23-crimeloc119" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-23-off116 t17591205-23-crimeloc119"></join>, I apprehend I was knock'd down.</p>
               <p>Q. Who knock'd you down?</p>
               <p>Stevens. The prisoner at the bar, I believe; I know I was knock'd down.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any body else near you?</p>
               <p>Stevens. No, only the prisoner and I together.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you be certain who knock'd you down?</p>
               <p>Stevens. I am very certain it was the prisoner, I knew him again four or five days after, tho' he was not in his watchman's dress.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he dress'd when he went along with you?</p>
               <p>Stevens. He was in a watchman's dress, and had a great coat on.</p>
               <p>Q. What was you knock'd down with?</p>
               <p>Stevens. I was knock'd down with a large staff or stick, I was struck on my left cheek and my nose, which made me incapable of going out for two or three days.</p>
               <p>Q. What happened to you after you was knock'd down?</p>
               <p>Stevens. He took me home notwithstanding. I was to give him six pence. I had a shilling or two in my other pocket loose, so I gave him a shilling, and he was to have brought me six-pence the next morning, but he never did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you lose any thing?</p>
               <p>Stevens. I had five guineas and a half and a 36 s. piece in my pocket, but do not know who took it out of my pocket, it was in a green purse in my side pocket; I am morally certain he knock'd me down.</p>
               <p>Q When did you miss your money?</p>
               <p>Stevens. I missed it the next morning; the first thing I did was to look for my money.</p>
               <p>Q. Cannot you be certain who was the man that took the money out of your pocket, as well as who knock'd you down?</p>
               <p>Stevens. I cannot say that; I can only say I had the money in my pocket when the prisoner took care of me. When I was knock'd down I was stunn'd with the blow and fall together, and not sensible of what might be done to me; when I missed my money I was sensible of my being knock'd down, and that there was nobody but the prisoner near me; then I sent to Mr. Barber, in order to find out the watchman, and he found him on the Monday following about three o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. What day of the week was you knock'd down?</p>
               <p>Stevens. On the Wednesday evening.</p>
               <p>Q. What account did your friend Mr. Barber give you, when you sent to him?</p>
               <p>Stevens. He said he could not tell where he lived, but by enquiring of Mr. Tudman, the beadle of the ward, he found him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he not to be found upon his stand?</p>
               <p>Stevens. No, the prisoner absented himself from his duty, so Mr. Tudman sent for him to pay him for his watching, and appointed me to be there. I knew him assoon as I saw him; he was secured and taken to the compter that night, and next morning carried before my lord-mayor. I was present, and charged him with knocking me down, alledging that my money was taken from me. He owned he went home with me, but not that he had knock'd me down, or took my money. At the time that I charged the constable he denied that he had ever seen me in his life, or ever went any where with me. He also offered to make it up with me, and offered to give me so much a week; I have, witness here that heard him.</p>

         
               <p>Note, The Second Part of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17591205-23">
                  <interp inst="t17591205-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17591205-23" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17591205-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17591205"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17591205-23" type="date" value="17591205"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175912050017"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON, And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 5th, Thursday the 6th, and Friday the 7th, of DECEMBER, In the Thirty-third Year of His MAJESTY'S Reign.</p>
                  <p>NUMBER I. PART II. for the YEAR 1760. Being the First SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of The Right Honble Sir 
                  <persName id="t17591205-23-person189">
                     THOMAS 
                     CHITTY 
                  <interp inst="t17591205-23-person189" type="surname" value="CHITTY"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17591205-23-person189" type="given" value="THOMAS"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17591205-23-person189" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Knt. LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by G. KEARSLY (Successor to the late Mr. Robinson) at the Golden-Lion, in Ludgate-Street, 1759.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175912050018"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, and Oyer and Terminer, for the City of LONDON, and at the General 
                  <persName id="t17591205-23-person190">
                     Sessions
                  <interp inst="t17591205-23-person190" type="given" value="Sessions"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17591205-23-person190" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                     </persName>
                of Gaol Delivery of Newgate, holden for the said City of LONDON, and County of MIDDLESEX, at Justice-Hall in the Old-Bailey, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Q. DID not you examine your pocket at the time you gave him the shilling?</p>
               <p>Stevens. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you not to charge him that night?</p>
               <p>Stevens. I did not know that I should have occasion to charge him with robbing me, not knowing then that I had been rob'd.</p>
               <p>Court. You had sense enough to give him a shilling, and desired him to bring you six pence the next morning.</p>
               <p>Stevens. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you at that time recollect he was the man that knock'd you down?</p>
               <p>Stevens. I am sure he is the man that knock'd me down.</p>
               <p>Q. Then why did you not charge him that night?</p>
               <p>Stevens. Very early in the morning I recollected I had been knock'd down. The prisoner said I fell;</p>
               <p>Q. What company had you been in at the house where you came from?</p>
               <p>Stevens. I had nobody but Mr. Barber, and his wife with me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you get in liquor with this man and his wife, or where did you get in?</p>
               <p>Stevens. I had been in company before at the sign of the Mansion-house, opposite the Mansion-house; but I had been there but half an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you made fuddled?</p>
               <p>Stevens. It was by what I drank at Mr. Barber's, I drank but part of a tankard of beer before. I was very well when I came in.</p>
               <p>Court. It is very odd that a man should be knock'd down by another, and reward that man that knock'd him down with a shilling; and again it is as odd that the same man should go home with him afterwards. What company was you in at the Mansion-house?</p>
               <p>Stevens. I was only with my fellow servant. I travel for Mr. Maltby, who is a linen draper.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you produce your money that evening before your fellow-servant?</p>
               <p>Stevens. No. I am sure I had it when I went into Mr. Barber's house.</p>
               <p>Q. Where had you been before you went to drink with your fellow servant?</p>
               <p>Stevens. I went immediately from my business at Mr. Maltby's.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-23-person191">
                  Abraham 
                  Renew 
               <interp inst="t17591205-23-person191" type="surname" value="Renew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-23-person191" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-23-person191" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watchman. 
               <persName id="t17591205-23-person192">
                  Samuel 
                  Fuller 
               <interp inst="t17591205-23-person192" type="surname" value="Fuller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-23-person192" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-23-person192" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the prisoner at the bar, was with me that night, I am upon the same stand in Broad-Street with him; he is a spare man, so was put with me that night. I know that night he was absent from his stand for about two hours and a half, or three hours; when he came back, I asked him where he had been; he said he had been at Mr. Barber's, and had been with a job; I asked him what job; he said he had been along with a gentleman home. He said first of all the gentleman thought of going in a coach, but he thought afterwards he was capable of going home without a coach, so discharged the coach, and took him with him. He was afterwards taken in custody at Mr. Tudman's, and I and another watchman were charged with him.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you miss the prisoner from his stand that night?</p>
               <p>Renew. I missed him about ten o'clock, and he came to me again after one; when we were charged with him we took him to Mr. Barber's, and there the gentleman said he had better own it, but he denied it; at last he made a proposition, that if Mr. Stevens would take so much money down, he would give him a note to pay him so much a week till all was paid.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175912050019"></xptr>Q. What said the prosecutor to that?</p>
               <p>Renew. He would not make it up, and the constable said he could not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he there charged with knocking the prosecutor down?</p>
               <p>Renew. He was; Mr. Stevens charged him with it. At first he said he never knew the man, nor never went home with him, and afterwards, before my Lord-mayor, he own'd it.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Whether my Lord mayor would admit the prosecutor to take his oath about who knock'd him down?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. My Lord-mayor made no difficulty only in this, that as I was in liquor it was dangerous to grant me my oath as to my being certain of his robbing me; I told his Lordship, I was sure he knock'd me down.</p>
               <p>Mr. Woodward. The first time of my seeing the prisoner was in the constable's custody, charged with knocking the prosecutor down and the robbery. I told him myself I thought his case look'd dangerous, and advised him to make an end of the affair rather than go before my Lord-mayor, for then it would be too late; so after some time he called me out.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>Woodward. At Mr. Barber's; the constable was against his going out, but I told him I would take care of him; when we came out, he asked me if I thought Mr. Stevens would make it up; I told him I knew nothing of that, but thought his case was dangerous; he said, I have not all the money by me, but I will pay part of it down, and I'll pay him the other part weekly, tho' I am innocent too; these were his words, and I told him I thought he was both a knave and a fool. The prosecutor never accepted of his proposal, tho' the prisoner urged the thing several times, saying he would pay part down, and give a note for the payment of the rest.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be there?</p>
               <p>Woodward. I am an acquaintance of Mr. Stevens, and he desired I would go with him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-23-person193">
                  John 
                  Barber 
               <interp inst="t17591205-23-person193" type="surname" value="Barber"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-23-person193" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-23-person193" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a publick house; Mr. Stevens was at my house on the 15th of November last.</p>
               <p>Q. What condition was he in when he first came into your house?</p>
               <p>Barber. He was in liquor, but I did not observe it till he went to get up to go away.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you, or do you not know whether he was in liquor when he first came into your house?</p>
               <p>Barber. Then he was in liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he when he went out of your house?</p>
               <p>Barber. In liquor to be sure.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he more in liquor when he went out than at coming in?</p>
               <p>Barber. He was, so I thought it necessary to take care of him when he went home, and delivered him to the prisoner, desiring him to see the gentleman safe home; the prisoner undertook it, and I saw them go past Broad-street church.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is his home from your house?</p>
               <p>Barber. I believe about four or five hundred yards; it is in Daget's-Court, the farther end of Broad Street Buildings.</p>
               <p>Q. After this did the prosecutor ever acquaint you that he had been knocked down and rob'd?</p>
               <p>Barber. He did the next day, which was on the Thursday.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say to you?</p>
               <p>Barber. He told me he had been knocked down and rob'd of his money, and asked me whether I knew the watchman that went home with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you who he believed the person was that knocked him down and robbed him?</p>
               <p>Barber. He said he believed it was the watchman that I sent home with him. I did not know the prisoner's name, so I inquired among the watchmen and found him out. There was one Berry, a watchman, that was opposite our door at the time, who was to have fetch'd a coach for Mr. Stevens to go home in, but the prisoner, being a younger man, out-ran him, and got the coach. Then Mr. Stevens would not be persuaded to go in it, but said he would walk home. When I found he would not go in the coach, I desired the prisoner (he being a watchman belonging to the ward) to take care of him, and see him home, thinking there was no danger. He took his lanthorn and staff with him, and I saw Mr. Stevens walk very well as I stood at my door.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. What did he give the coachman?</p>
               <p>Barber. He gave him a shilling, but would not go with him.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. What did my Lord mayor do in regard to giving him his oath?</p>
               <p>Barber. My Lord-mayor was a little tender as to that, till he heard the prisoner wanted to make it up with Mr. Stevens; then I believe it made him think the prisoner was guilty.</p>
               <p>Q. What hour of the night was it when he went out of your house?</p>
               <p>Barber. The watchman was going one o'clock when he was first called, and I believe it was better than half an hour after when they set out.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175912050020"></xptr>Q. to Renew. What time did the prisoner return to his stand?</p>
               <p>Renew. It was pretty near two o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. to Barber. What time did Mr. Stevens come to your house?</p>
               <p>Barber. I believe he came in about half an hour after eleven o'clock on the Wednesday night, and went away on Thursday morning as I have mentioned.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I went home with Mr. Stevens, but I do not know any thing of what he says.</p>
               <p>To his Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-23-person194">
                  John 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17591205-23-person194" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-23-person194" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-23-person194" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about two years; he has work'd for me as an out door porter, and has been very honest as far as I know. I have trusted him to receive small sums of money for me, about four, five, or six pounds; I always looked upon him to be a very honest fellow.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-23-person195">
                  John 
                  Grimes 
               <interp inst="t17591205-23-person195" type="surname" value="Grimes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-23-person195" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-23-person195" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I believe I have known him four or five years; he has carried out meat for me, and done business for me as a porter when I wanted him: I never heard any complaint of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he ever take money for you?</p>
               <p>Grimes. No, not as I remember.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Was there any mark on your head from this blow?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. There were upon my cheek and nose for five or six days.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17591205-23-verdict120" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17591205-23-verdict120" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
