<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560603-15">
               <interp inst="t17560603-15" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560603-15" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560603-15" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560603"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560603-15" type="date" value="17560603"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560603-15-off80-c116" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560603-15-defend139 t17560603-15-off80 t17560603-15-verdict83"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560603-15-off80-c117" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560603-15-defend141 t17560603-15-off80 t17560603-15-verdict83"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560603-15-off80-c118" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560603-15-defend143 t17560603-15-off80 t17560603-15-verdict83"></join>
         
               <p>253, 254, 255. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17560603-15-defend139" type="defendantName">
                  Samuel 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17560603-15-defend139" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-defend139" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-defend139" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , 
               
                  <persName id="t17560603-15-defend141" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Perry 
                  <interp inst="t17560603-15-defend141" type="surname" value="Perry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-defend141" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-defend141" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17560603-15-defend143" type="defendantName">
                     Samuel 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17560603-15-defend143" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-defend143" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-defend143" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17560603-15-off80" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-off80" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-off80" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that they on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17560603-15-victim145" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Ridge 
                        <interp inst="t17560603-15-victim145" type="surname" value="Ridge"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560603-15-victim145" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560603-15-victim145" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560603-15-off80 t17560603-15-victim145"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , on the king's highway, did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and stealing from his person one hat, value 3 shillings, and 2 shillings in money number'd
            </rs>, <rs id="t17560603-15-cd81" type="crimeDate">May 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560603-15-off80 t17560603-15-cd81"></join>. </p> 
               <p>Thomas Ridge. On the 16th of May, as I was going to Fulham with my wife in a chaise, I came round by a place called <placeName id="t17560603-15-crimeloc82">Walham-Green</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17560603-15-crimeloc82" type="placeName" value="Walham-Green"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17560603-15-crimeloc82" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560603-15-off80 t17560603-15-crimeloc82"></join>, and call'd at the Red-Lion. I set out from thence at about a quarter before ten at night, and walk'd the chaise gently along. There is a little bit of a rising ground, where a bye lane goes up to some fields. I put my horse into a little trot, at which time there came the three prisoners seemingly from behind the chaise, running along on the left hand the chaise. 
               <persName id="t17560603-15-person146">
                  Samuel 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17560603-15-person146" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-person146" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-person146" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             crossed the road, and took hold of my horse's bridle. He was then as now in his regimental cloaths. Said he, where are you going so fast? I said, I am not in a hurry at all; gentlemen, what do you want? They swore they wanted money. I said, gentlemen, I have got none. They swore I had. I said again, I had not. This we repeated three or four times. Said Lewis, have not you got three or four shillings in your pocket? I said to my wife, if you have any give it to them, for I went out with only a trifle in my pocket. She said, she had none. Then I said, gentlemen, I have two shillings (which is all I have about me) and if you will let the horse go, you are welcome to that. Then Lewis, who was on my left hand, said, give it to that man (meaning Perry) which I did. Lewis came round to the other side, and search'd my breeches all round, and pull'd a hanger almost out of his bosom. He felt a little wrinkle in my breeches, and swore there was something. I said, I had no more. My hat fell off my head, and I was going to put it on again, but he took it, and they all three ran away together. Then I came on through the turnpike, and so to the Cross-Keys, where I saw two or three of my men. I said to them, you must go along with me, I have been robb'd between Chelsea and Walham-Green, by two soldiers belonging to the guards, and another man in colour'd cloaths. We went to seek after them, and call'd in at some publick houses, and at last found them not above two or three hundred yards from the place where they rob'd me. When I came near them, I said these are the men. They had got some women with them, one of whom went off, and three of them came with them.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was this after you was rob'd?</p>
               <p>Ridge. We took them within an hour after.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Ridge. I keep a farrier's shop, and coaches for the road at Chelsea.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What house did you find them at?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175606030012"></xptr>Ridge. We found them at no house at all, we found them betwixt Mr. Osgood's brew-house and the creek.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see them at the Hare and Hounds ?</p>
               <p>Ridge. No, never in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. Might not there be other soldiers upon the road as well as the prisoners?</p>
               <p>Ridge. There might, but I took particular notice of them.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was you rob'd?</p>
               <p>Ridge. A little before ten o'clock.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560603-15-person147">
                  Mary 
                  Ridge 
               <interp inst="t17560603-15-person147" type="surname" value="Ridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-person147" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-person147" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the prosecutor, and was with him in the chaise; there came two soldiers and a man in colour'd cloaths; one soldier laid hold of the horse's bridle, and another went up to the chaise. My husband said, what do you want? they said, money. He said, he had none; but told me if I had any to give it them I said I had none. Then he gave them two shillings I believe. I was extreamly frighted, I don't know the men at all. They took away my husband's hat.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560603-15-person148">
                  Henry 
                  Warrin 
               <interp inst="t17560603-15-person148" type="surname" value="Warrin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-person148" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-person148" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to the prosecutor. Master came to a publick house joining to our yard, to me and two or three of my fellow servants, and said he had been rob'd. Of what, and where, said I? he said by Little-Chelsea. I went and got a cutlass, and the other men came out with mops and staves; and we went to look after the thieves along the King's-Road, and call'd in at two alehouses, but found nobody. At last we saw the three prisoners and some women. We went by them, and master said, they are the men that rob'd me.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>Warrin. The prisoners were standing against Mr. Osgood's wall. He was not for taking them, fearing they had fire arms. We went into a house, the sign of the Plough, and ask'd if there were any body there. There was a carpenter that lives at Walham-Green, who went with us, and the landlord lent us a pistol. We loaded it, and also a blunderbuss that one of our men had. Then we went and took the prisoners, who made no resistance. There were three women with them, I believe there was one more, who made off. When we had put the prisoners into the cage, we met a soldier's wife, who said she was going to them. I went and felt about her, but found nothing. She said she would swear against me. As I had Perry by the collar, master said, when you had robbed me you ran away; one of the others said; no, we did not run at all.</p>

               <p>Q. Were they searched ?</p>
               <p>Warrin. No otherwise than about the out side of their cloaths for fire arms. We did not search in their pockets.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is the place where you went from to the Hare and Hounds ?</p>
               <p>Warrin. We were not so far as that?</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the man that keeps that house?</p>
               <p>Warrin. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he an honest man?</p>
               <p>Warrin. He is reputed as such. I can't say I know much of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560603-15-person149">
                  David 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17560603-15-person149" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-person149" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-person149" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Cross Keys. On the 16th of May, at ten at night, Mr. Ridge came into my house and said he had been rob'd, and call'd his man Harry, and said we'll go in pursuit of them; we went all up the King's Road and enquired, and turn'd down to Little-Chelsea; at last we found and secured the three prisoners at the bar.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you search them?</p>
               <p>Davis. No farther then round their cloaths.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Did you ever meet with your hat again?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No, I never did. We had a suspicion that the woman who went off, carried the hat and hanger away.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find any hanger upon them?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No, we did not.</p>
               <p>Lewis's defence.</p>
               <p>Perry enlisted for a soldier on the 14th of May last; he came to me, and desired I'd give him my company to Walham Green, to see some of his country women that came up year after year to work in the gardens. We went together, with the other prisoner, and got there about three o'clock, and sat and rested ourselves; then we went and took a walk. He went a little before us, and found the girls. We went into Fulham fields. and return'd again to the house, where we rested ourselves (the Hare and Hounds) about six o'clock, and staid till nine. Then the landlady came to the door, and said my husband is not very well, and beg'd that we would not stay late. We said we would not. We drank three or four full pots of beer, and after that the maid desired us to go. There was but a small quantity of beer in the pot, and I drank it. This was about half an hour after ten. Then we and the three girls went away. They never were out of our company from six o'clock to the time we were taken up. There came five men by us with mops and pitch-forks in their hands. I began to laugh at Perry, because he<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175606030013"></xptr> had got plam cloaths on, thinking they were a press-gang. One of them said to me, my friend; will you go and be a penny? I said I am just come from a publick house. Then he said, good night to you. I said the same to him. He had not been gone above five or six minutes, before there came ten or a dozen men with pistols and blunderbusses, and said there had been a robbery committed, and we must be the men that did it. We made no resistance, but went along with them.</p>
               <p>Perry's defence.</p>
               <p>I enlisted the 14th of May last, and came to the other two prisoners on the 16th, and desired their company to Walham Green, having heard my country women were coming up for their summer's work. We went in at the Hare and Hounds, to rest ourselves, till about four o'clock. Then I went and fetch'd my country women, and we went into the fields, returned about six, and staid till nine. Then the woman of the house came and told us her husband was very ill and desired we would not stay late. We said we would not. She lock'd up the door at nine, but we staid till half an hour after ten. Then she call'd to the servant girl, and order'd her to turn us out. We had but a little beer in the pot, we drank it, and went out, and the three girls with us; they went with us about a mile. We were standing to take our leave of them, when five men came up, four passed us, and the other staid and desired us to be a penny with him at the next house. My comrade said he had beer enough. He had not been gone above five or six minutes before there came ten or a dozen men, and said that a man had been rob'd that night, and took us; they search'd us, but found nothing upon us; the girls were never out of our company all the time.</p>
               <p>Smith's defence.</p>
               <p>Perry enlisted himself for a soldier on the 14th of May. After that, he ask'd us to take a walk with him to Walham-Green, for he wanted to know how his friends did. We got there about three o'clock, and about four we went all out together. Perry hearing where his country women were, he went and fetch'd them. Then we took a walk into the fields for about an hour or better. We came back about six, and had two or three pots of beer. It might be nine o'clock, when Mrs. Carne came and said, her husband was ill, and desir'd we would go. We said we would when we had had another pot. She lock'd the door, and about half an hour after ten we went away. The girls went with us about half a mile. While we were standing under a wall five men came by, four of whom stared very hard at us. The last, who had a pitch-fork in his hand pressed upon us very hard to go and be a penny with him We told him we had not used to stay out so late, but that was a night by chance, as we had met with some of our country-women. He bid us a good night, and in about five or six minutes afterwards there came ten or a dozen men, who took and search'd every one of us.</p>
               <p>For the prisoners.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560603-15-person150">
                  Stephen 
                  Carne 
               <interp inst="t17560603-15-person150" type="surname" value="Carne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-person150" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-person150" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Hare and Hounds near Walham-Green. I remember the day the prisoners were taken. They came to my house between three and four o'clock, and ask'd after some young women that came up every summer to work in the gardens, who not being at my house, they went out to look for them about four o'clock, and came back between six and seven with three young women. I went to bed at nine, so can't ascertain the time they went away.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is your house?</p>
               <p>Carne. It is opposite the Swan, just as you enter Walham-Green.</p>
               <p>Q. Is your's a good clock?</p>
               <p>Carne. It is and went right then, and has done ever since.</p>
               <p>Q. Had any of these men any arms did you see?</p>
               <p>Carne. No, I saw none.</p>
               <p>Q. Were their coats buttoned or unbuttoned ?</p>
               <p>Carne. I saw their coats unbuttoned.</p>
               <p>Q. How did they behave them selves at your house?</p>
               <p>Carne. Very discreetly.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560603-15-person151">
                  Frances 
                  Carne 
               <interp inst="t17560603-15-person151" type="surname" value="Carne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-person151" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-person151" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the last evidence. I remember the three prisoners at the bar being at my house the day they were taken up.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did they come there ?</p>
               <p>F. Carne. They came between three and four o'clock in the afternoon. They staid about half an hour, and went out and return'd about six or seven, with three young women. They staid in my house till about half an hour after ten.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be so certain as to time?</p>
               <p>F. Carne. I look'd at the clock when I went to carry up my husband's wine, and I ordered the maid to unlock the door; she did, and let them out at that time, and the three young women with them.</p>
               <p>Q. From the time they came in betwixt six and seven, to half an hour after ten, did they go out of your house ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175606030014"></xptr>F. Carne. No, they did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any sword or daggers they had ?</p>
               <p>F. Carne. No, I did not, and if there had been any I should have seen them, for their coats were unbuttoned.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see a hat brought in besides what they wore?</p>
               <p>F. Carne. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Is your's an eight day clock?</p>
               <p>F. Carne. It is, and a very good one, and goes very right.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560603-15-person152">
                  Sarah 
                  Stevenson 
               <interp inst="t17560603-15-person152" type="surname" value="Stevenson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-person152" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-person152" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I came from Worcestershire, the prisoners are my countrymen. Perry took me, 
               <persName id="t17560603-15-person153">
                  Sarah 
                  Southel 
               <interp inst="t17560603-15-person153" type="surname" value="Southel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-person153" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-person153" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17560603-15-person154">
                  Mary 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17560603-15-person154" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-person154" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-person154" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , to the other two at the Hare and Hounds; we staid a while, went out, and came in again between six and seven o'clock; we were never out of their company that night till half an hour after ten, when the gentlemen took us up on suspicion of this robbery.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you there twice that day with them?</p>
               <p>S. Stevenson. I was. I went in first between three and four.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560603-15-person155">
                  Sarah 
                  Southel 
               <interp inst="t17560603-15-person155" type="surname" value="Southel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-person155" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-person155" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17560603-15-person156">
                  Mary 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17560603-15-person156" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-person156" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-person156" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed just the same.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560603-15-person157">
                  Thomas 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17560603-15-person157" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-person157" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-person157" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Amos Sidway, and 
               <persName id="t17560603-15-person158">
                  John 
                  Sidway 
               <interp inst="t17560603-15-person158" type="surname" value="Sidway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-person158" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-person158" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , deposed the three prisoners were by trade all blacksmiths, industrious hard working men, of good character.</p>
               <p>Serjeant Stevens and Serjeant Parton deposed' they behaved well as soldiers, and were industrious men.</p>
               <p>All three <rs id="t17560603-15-verdict83" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560603-15-verdict83" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
