<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17520514-28">
               <interp inst="t17520514-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520514-28" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520514-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520514"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520514-28" type="date" value="17520514"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520514-28-off145-c207" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-28-defend253 t17520514-28-off145 t17520514-28-verdict149"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520514-28-off150-c207" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-28-defend253 t17520514-28-off150 t17520514-28-verdict149"></join>
         
               <p>314. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17520514-28-defend253" type="defendantName">
                     Nathan 
                     Levi 
                  <interp inst="t17520514-28-defend253" type="surname" value="Levi"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-defend253" type="given" value="Nathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-defend253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for that <rs id="t17520514-28-off145" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-off145" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-off145" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               he on the <rs id="t17520514-28-cd146" type="crimeDate">29th of Dec</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-28-off145 t17520514-28-cd146"></join>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-28-off150 t17520514-28-cd146"></join>. about the hour of two in the night, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17520514-28-victim255" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Martyfla 
                        <interp inst="t17520514-28-victim255" type="surname" value="Martyfla"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520514-28-victim255" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520514-28-victim255" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did break and enter, one wooden drawer, value 2 d. one silver stock-buckle, one pair of silver knee buckles, set with Bristol stones, one china cup, one china saucer, one mahogany tobacco dish, and 30 shillings in money numbered, in the dwelling-house of the said John did steal
            </rs>, &amp;c ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-28-person256">
                  John 
                  Martyfla 
               <interp inst="t17520514-28-person256" type="surname" value="Martyfla"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person256" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person256" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17520514-28-crimeloc147">Chatherine-wheel-alley , Whitechapel</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17520514-28-crimeloc147" type="placeName" value="Chatherine-wheel-alley , Whitechapel"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520514-28-crimeloc147" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-28-off145 t17520514-28-crimeloc147"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-28-off150 t17520514-28-crimeloc147"></join>, and <rs id="t17520514-28-viclabel148" type="occupation">keep a publick-house</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-28-victim255 t17520514-28-viclabel148"></join>, which was broke open either the first or second Sunday before Christmas: I fastened the doors myself, and went to-bed between twelve and one on the Saturday night; the street-door was fastened with two bolts on the inside, there was a little window in the middle of the door, which was fastened with an oaken pin: The girl got up between six and seven in the morning, and found the street-door open. She came and told me, and I went down and found it so: The wicket was cut so as to get in a knife between that and the door, and the pin cut in two; after that was open it was easy to get in a hand, and unbolt the door. The inside door was fastened on the inside with two bolts; on the inside door there had been a pane of glass in that broke, and I had nail'd a piece of board on it, which board was pulled off, after which they might easily open that door. We found a six-pence in silver in a little room by the bar. We missed 4 s. 6 d. of the girl's box money; in a cupboard in the little room there were about 26 shillings in half-pence, a silver three-pence, and a pair of sleeve buttons, in a till, which was also missing, till and all.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any thing of them afterwards;</p>
               <p>Martyfla. I did, about a fortnight ago a watchman came and asked me if I had been robb'd: I said I was, and told him of what. I went with him at his desire to the Compter, and from thence to Guild-hall ; there was 
               <persName id="t17520514-28-person257">
                  Philip 
                  Abraham 
               <interp inst="t17520514-28-person257" type="surname" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person257" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person257" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who told me he had broke the doors open; he was committed. We found the till, or drawer, in Marlborough-court,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175205140029"></xptr> in a necessary-house, by his directions; he said, he put it in on Wednesday last in the afternoon.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you heard the prisoner say any thing about it ?</p>
               <p>Martyfla. No, my Lord, he always denied it.</p>
               <p>Philip Abraham I, and the prisoner, and one 
               <persName id="t17520514-28-person258">
                  Jack 
                  Robertson 
               <interp inst="t17520514-28-person258" type="surname" value="Robertson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person258" type="given" value="Jack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person258" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , made an agreement to break this house open on Christmas evening; being hindered that night by people walking backwards and forwards, we went the next Saturday from Marlborough-court, where Robertson and I lived, to Levi's house, and told him we were going to the same house we were at on the Christmas evening.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did the prisoner live?</p>
               <p>Abraham. He liv'd in Gravel-lane. Houndsditch, we went to the prosecutor's house, between two and three on the Sunday morning. Robertson bid Levi stand at the corner of Catherine-wheel Alley, and me go to the corner of the other alley, to watch if any body came, which we did, then Robertson went to the prosecutor's house. We staid so about a quarter of an hour, when Levi saw a watchman coming up the alley, then he cough'd, which was the signal we were to give each other, to take notice somebody was coming. Then Robertson was coming towards me; but turning his head he saw the watchman go down a little alley, and then went back to the door again. In about a quarter of an hour after this Robertson had the doors open, and gave a whistle: Then Levi and I came up to the house, Robertson had the drawer on his head in the street, by the door. He said now we'll go home; Levi said, stay a little longer, I'll go in and see if there is any thing else. He went in and staid about three or four minutes, and came out, and brought a china cup and saucer. Then we all three went home.</p>
               <p>Q. How was the wicket when you went up?</p>
               <p>Abraham. It was open and the door too.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you ever in that house before?</p>
               <p>Abraham. No, never except that Saturday night we had a pot of beer there. Robertson and Levi knew the house, for they lived in the same alley. When we got to our house in Marlborough-court, Petticoat-lane, said Levi, what shall we do with the drawer? then he himself said, in answer to his own question, we'll take the money out, and throw it down into the house of office. This we thought proper, because we did not care our wives should know of it. Then we went all three of us to the house of office. Robertson and I took the money out, and put it into Levi's hat. There were twenty-six shillings in halfpence, we found in it a tobacco dish, a stock buckle, and a pair of silver buttons. Then Robertson threw the tobacco dish and drawer down the house of office, then we went into the house, and Levi the money and put it into the closet. We went to bed directly and slept till seven or eight o'clock, and then we shar'd the money 8 s. 8 d. each We sold the stock buckle and buttons to a fellow that travell'd the country, a Jew; we had 10 d. each for them.</p>
               <p>Q. What was his name ?</p>
               <p>Abraham. I don't know his name.</p>
               <p>Q. When was you taken up?</p>
               <p>Abraham. It was about six months after, I believe, I went and made myself a voluntary evidence : It was upon a quarrel on a Tuesday night, about three weeks ago. I and Robertson were drinking a pint of beer at the Three Pidgeons, about a month ago, one 
               <persName id="t17520514-28-person259">
                  Dick 
                  Hutton 
               <interp inst="t17520514-28-person259" type="surname" value="Hutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person259" type="given" value="Dick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person259" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came and enquired after me, he call'd me on one side, and said he had got some things to sell; I said I would not do any thing more that way. Robertson ask'd what it was, I told him, He said to Dick, I believe I can sell it. Then he was to come next morning to produce it. I observed they wanted to sting Dick out of his stuff, and I would not let them. This was the quarrel, so Levi and Robertson sent people to take me up on the Thursday night before, and I got away. Then I went and made my information to 
               <persName id="t17520514-28-person260">
                  Henry 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17520514-28-person260" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person260" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person260" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a constable.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-28-person261">
                  Jane 
                  Ellison 
               <interp inst="t17520514-28-person261" type="surname" value="Ellison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person261" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person261" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to the prosecutor, I came down stairs, I believe, about seven o'clock on that morning, and found three doors open. She confirmed the account given by her master.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-28-person262">
                  Henry 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17520514-28-person262" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person262" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person262" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable, I was officer of the night the last of April: The prisoner and evidence were brought to me by three watchmen ; the evidence said, they had been concerned in robberies, together with one Robertson, in breaking a house in Catherine-wheel-alley, Whitechapel, and another in Sugar-loaf-court. The prisoner entirely denied being concerned in any such things.</p>
               <p>A watchman. On the 30th of April, between eleven and twelve at night, I was in Harrow-alley; The evidence call'd stop thief, he was the first man that came up to me. I saw Levi standing, I asked the evidence if that was he; he said it was. The prisoner came readily along with me, he made no resistance at all, I carried him to the constable.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175205140030"></xptr>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I am as innocent as the child unborn. This is nothing but out of spight: The evidence was tossing up half-pence, my dog was near him, and he gave the dog a kick, so I took and lick'd him, and upon that he began this.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-28-person263">
                  Joseph 
                  Collet 
               <interp inst="t17520514-28-person263" type="surname" value="Collet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person263" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person263" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable: On the 29th of April, about ten or eleven o'clock, there was the evidence and prisoner in Houndsditch: The evidence said the prisoner had been up one pair of stairs in his house, and that he had assaulted him, and had drawn a knife upon him, and threatened to kill him. I had Levi searched and found no knife upon him, Levi was so drunk he could hardly speak or stand. The evidence said, he hop'd I'd send Levi to the Compter. I asked what was the grounds of the quarrel, or if he ever drank with the man: He said, no. I asked, if he knew the man, he said no. After that, he said he knew his name. I told him I could not send him to the Compter for this; but if he'd get a warrant I'd serve it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-28-person264">
                  Sophia 
                  Ross 
               <interp inst="t17520514-28-person264" type="surname" value="Ross"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person264" type="given" value="Sophia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person264" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mrs. Decoster at Totteridge.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you a Jew?</p>
               <p>S. Ross. No, I am not. The prisoner has been four or five times at our house, within a year or two; he came the first Sunday after Christmas, I think, but cannot be positive as to the day of the month, I and my fellow-servant dined out that day at Mr. King's; he staid all night and breakfasted with his aunt, the cook, next morning.</p>
               <p>Rose Joseph. I am aunt to the prisoner at the bar, and live at Mr. Decoster's at Totteridge ; he came to me, and lay all night. I can't tell the day of the month, to the best of my knowledge it was the first Sunday after Christmas. This I know, that very day my fellow-servants dined at Mr. King's.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day did he come?</p>
               <p>R. Joseph. He came about two o'clock.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-28-person265">
                  William 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17520514-28-person265" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person265" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person265" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Porteridge, and am Parish clerk, Mr. Decoster's Servants came and dined with me on Sunday the 29th of Dec.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you recollect it ?</p>
               <p>King. Because I know the Friday before I dined at my Lord Chief Justice Levi's with his tradesmen, and they having no hog meat at Mr. Decoster's, I thought it might be something of a rarity to the servants to dine with me, and am very positive as to the day.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520514-28-verdict149" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-verdict149" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>(L.) He was a second time indicted, for that <rs id="t17520514-28-off150" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-off150" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-off150" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               he on the <rs id="t17520514-28-cd151" type="crimeDate">31st of March</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-28-off145 t17520514-28-cd151"></join>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-28-off150 t17520514-28-cd151"></join>, about the hour of three in the night, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17520514-28-victim267" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Whiteman 
                        <interp inst="t17520514-28-victim267" type="surname" value="Whiteman"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520514-28-victim267" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520514-28-victim267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did break and enter, and stealing out thence one silver pint mug, one silver table spoon, one silver pepper box, one silver strainer, one pair of silver shoe buckles, one pair of silver knee buckles, one tea chest, one man's hat, three yards of holland, eight linnen caps, 7 linnen handkerchiefs, two cloth cloaks, two linnen aprons, the goods of the said Thomas in his dwelling-house
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-28-person268">
                  Thomas 
                  Whiteman 
               <interp inst="t17520514-28-person268" type="surname" value="Whiteman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person268" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17520514-28-crimeloc152">Sugar-loaf-court</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17520514-28-crimeloc152" type="placeName" value="Sugar-loaf-court"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520514-28-crimeloc152" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-28-off145 t17520514-28-crimeloc152"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-28-off150 t17520514-28-crimeloc152"></join>; on the first of April I came down stairs, between five and six in the morning, I found the sash window shoved up, which was fast over night, and missed the goods mentioned in the indictment. I was sent for to the Compter, and there the evidence, 
               <persName id="t17520514-28-person269">
                  Philip 
                  Abraham 
               <interp inst="t17520514-28-person269" type="surname" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person269" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , own'd that he, the prisoner, and another person, broke the house, and took the things. I had none of the goods again, but a shirt not quite made, which was pawn'd; he said the plate was sold for 4 s. 6 d. per ounce, and gone abroad, and the other things were sold in Rag-fair.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner acknowledge any thing about it?</p>
               <p>Whiteman. No, he always denied it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-28-person270">
                  Philip 
                  Abraham 
               <interp inst="t17520514-28-person270" type="surname" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person270" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person270" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17520514-28-person271">
                  Jack 
                  Robertson 
               <interp inst="t17520514-28-person271" type="surname" value="Robertson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person271" type="given" value="Jack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person271" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the prisoner and I went on Easter Tuesday, about three o'clock in the morning, to the prosecutor's house in Sugar-loaf-court, in Leadenhall street; Levi stood at the corner of Fenchurch-Buildings, and I at the corner of Leadenhall-street, and Robertson went and broke the window-shutter, and went in at the window, and took the things. Here he mentioned them all by name; but his evidence being unconfirmed by any witness of credit, the prisoner was <rs id="t17520514-28-verdict153" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-verdict153" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>For 
               <persName id="t17520514-28-person272">
                  Philip 
                  Abraham 
               <interp inst="t17520514-28-person272" type="surname" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person272" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-28-person272" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , see No. 182. in Cockayne's mayoralty.</p>
            </div1>
