<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17520514-25">
               <interp inst="t17520514-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520514-25" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520514-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520514"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520514-25" type="date" value="17520514"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520514-25-off128-c190" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-25-defend231 t17520514-25-off128 t17520514-25-verdict133"></join>
         
               <p>311. 
               
                  <persName id="t17520514-25-defend231" type="defendantName">
                     Johan Frederick 
                     Renisonce 
                  <interp inst="t17520514-25-defend231" type="surname" value="Renisonce"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-25-defend231" type="given" value="Johan Frederick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-25-defend231" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17520514-25-off128" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520514-25-off128" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-25-off128" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               stealing six yards of silver lace
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17520514-25-victim233" type="victimName">
                     Charles 
                     Pierce 
                  <interp inst="t17520514-25-victim233" type="surname" value="Pierce"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-25-victim233" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-25-victim233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-25-off128 t17520514-25-victim233"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17520514-25-cd129" type="crimeDate">April 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-25-off128 t17520514-25-cd129"></join>.*</p>
               <p>Charles Pierce. I am a <rs id="t17520514-25-viclabel130" type="occupation">Taylor</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-25-victim233 t17520514-25-viclabel130"></join>, I live in <placeName id="t17520514-25-crimeloc131">Castle-street , Leicester-fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17520514-25-crimeloc131" type="placeName" value="Castle-street , Leicester-fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520514-25-crimeloc131" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-25-off128 t17520514-25-crimeloc131"></join>: On the 17th of April last, I had an order to make a laced suit of cloaths against the next day at two o'clock: the prisoner was my <rs id="t17520514-25-deflabel132" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-25-defend231 t17520514-25-deflabel132"></join>, and the lace in his custody, which was forty yards and upwards, as he was obliged to work all night; when he had finished the cloaths he returned me two yards and a half of the lace; I mistrusted he could not have put so much lace into the cloaths, so I took and measured it; I found six yards and upwards wanting: I was g'd to go to Birmingham, so could not take him up till I returned again, which I did last Saturday, after which I went to his lodgings, and there I found about a yard and three quarters of the lace, he then owned that, and said, he had no more of it. We carried him before Justice Lediard, he was committed for further examination; after that he confessed he had intrusted a man, one Langford, to sell the lace ; when we came to take him up, he said he knew nothing of it. We went again, and searched his lodgings, and in all found six yards.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you prescribe what quantity of lace should be put into that suit of cloaths?</p>
               <p>Peirce. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had the prisoner worked for you?</p>
               <p>Peirce. He had worked for me upwards of 12 months.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he industrious, or was he a lazy fellow?</p>
               <p>Peirce. He was always industrious and very willing to work.</p>
               <p>Q. Can't some taylor's finish a suit of cloaths with more, and some with less lace ?</p>
               <p>Peirce. No, not in this suit of cloaths they could not.</p>
               <p>Q. Why so?</p>
               <p>Peirce. Because this was to be put on quite strait.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he not the care of business for you, and might have had an opportunity of cheating you in your absence ?</p>
               <p>Peirce. No, Sir, he could not, he had plain cloaths to make and it was not in his power to cheat me in them, because I cut them out myself.</p>
               <p>Q. Has there not been some quarrels of late amongst the masters and journeymen taylors?</p>
               <p>Peirce. What of that ?</p>
               <p>Q. Have not you declared, that you and some others met together in order to ruin this man?</p>
               <p>Peirce. No, Sir, never in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you not been a contributor against this man as a journeyman Taylor.</p>
               <p>Peirce. He never was prosecuted before.</p>
               <p>Q. Has not the prisoner laced and trimmed many gentlemen's cloaths for you, in the time he has worked for you?</p>
               <p>Peirce. That he has, sir.</p>

               <p>Q. How came you not to suspect him before?</p>
               <p>Peirce. Because there was not so much lace wanting.</p>
               <p>Q. How near can you guess to in a suit of cloaths ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175205140027"></xptr>Peirce. I can guess within three quarters of a yard of lace.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-25-person234">
                  William 
                  Cuthburd 
               <interp inst="t17520514-25-person234" type="surname" value="Cuthburd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-25-person234" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-25-person234" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Peirce: I delivered into the prisoner's custody 40 yards of silver lace on Friday in the evening, to get the cloaths done against the next day, and upon the measurement of the cloaths there were upwards of six yards missing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-25-person235">
                  Daniel 
                  Carne 
               <interp inst="t17520514-25-person235" type="surname" value="Carne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-25-person235" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-25-person235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am high constable of Westminster: Mr. Peirce desired me to come and take the prisoner up, he sent for him down stairs and charged me with him; the prisoner then said, he never did defraud his master in his life-time; and said, he had got a quarter of a yard of the lace at home, which he would go and fetch; so I went with him: we took him before Justice Lediard, he denied it still, he was committed for farther examination, after which I went to him, then he said, he had delivered it to Mr. Langford, and as I understood, in order for sale. Mr. Lediard granted a warrant in order to search: Mr. Langford denied knowing any thing of the matter, but upon bringing the prisoner out of the Gatehouse in order to contront him, who told him he had put it into his cupboard (they lodged together) I went and found it as the prisoner had said, it was set upon a silk waistcoat the prisoner was making for himself. Produced in court.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I took the silver lace along with me home, through a mistake, it was among some paper patterns, I put them into my trunk, and we were so much in a hurry every day, I could not spare time to go to look for it; I put it on that crimson waistcoat for myself to see how it would look.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-25-person236">
                  John 
                  Mangoe 
               <interp inst="t17520514-25-person236" type="surname" value="Mangoe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-25-person236" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-25-person236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner several years; he worked with one Mr. Neal five years; I went to him and desired he would appear for his character, he begged to be excused, and said, several of the Master-Taylors had been with him on this affair, and said, the whole trade was determined to hang him, as an example to others.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you ?</p>
               <p>Mangoe. I am a master Staymaker.</p>
               <p>- Bushman. I have known him about three years, he is a very honest, sober, careful man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-25-person237">
                  Jacob 
                  Sower 
               <interp inst="t17520514-25-person237" type="surname" value="Sower"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-25-person237" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-25-person237" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him nine years; I have travelled with him from Germany into Italy ; he was always reckon'd an honest industrious man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-25-person238">
                  John 
                  Langford 
               <interp inst="t17520514-25-person238" type="surname" value="Langford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-25-person238" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-25-person238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Taylor; I have known the prisoner above four years, I never knew any ill of him, he and I have lodged together for some time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-25-person239">
                  John 
                  Angard 
               <interp inst="t17520514-25-person239" type="surname" value="Angard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-25-person239" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-25-person239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him for some years, I esteem him an honest man.</p>
               <p>- White. I have known him two years, he is a very honest sober man, I have worked for him, he paid me very honestly.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p> 
               <p>White. I am a Peruke-maker.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520514-25-verdict133" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520514-25-verdict133" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-25-verdict133" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder1s"></interp>
               Guilty 10 d.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520514-25-punish134" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520514-25-punish134" type="punishmentCategory" value="corporal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-25-punish134" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="whipping"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-25-defend231 t17520514-25-punish134"></join>
               
                     <note>[Whipping. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
