<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17530718-45">
               <interp inst="t17530718-45" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530718-45" type="year" value="1753"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530718-45" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17530718"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530718-45" type="date" value="17530718"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17530718-45-off235-c322" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-45-defend403 t17530718-45-off235 t17530718-45-verdict240"></join>
         
               <p>363. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17530718-45-defend403" type="defendantName">
                     David 
                     Jones 
                  <interp inst="t17530718-45-defend403" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-45-defend403" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-45-defend403" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indictment that <rs id="t17530718-45-off235" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530718-45-off235" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-45-off235" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               he on the <rs id="t17530718-45-cd236" type="crimeDate">23d of April, 1751</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-45-off235 t17530718-45-cd236"></join>, between the hours of one and two in the night of the same day the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17530718-45-victim405" type="victimName">
                           David 
                           Paul 
                        <interp inst="t17530718-45-victim405" type="surname" value="Paul"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530718-45-victim405" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530718-45-victim405" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-45-off235 t17530718-45-victim405"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did break and enter,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175307180036"></xptr>60 china cups, val. 20 s. 4 china saucers, one Bow china tea pot, one earthen tea-pot, two pickle dishes made of earthen ware, five fish-plates made of earthen ware, one earthen fish strainer, one shew glass, and other things did steal, take, and carry away
            </rs>. +</p>
               <p>This robbery was committed in company with 
               <persName id="t17530718-45-person406">
                  William 
                  Hatton 
               <interp inst="t17530718-45-person406" type="surname" value="Hatton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-45-person406" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-45-person406" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , oherwise Forrester. See his Trial No. 374, in alderman Cockayne's mayoralty.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-45-person407">
                  David 
                  Paul 
               <interp inst="t17530718-45-person407" type="surname" value="Paul"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-45-person407" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-45-person407" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live <placeName id="t17530718-45-crimeloc237">joining to the Swan brewhouse gate, White-chape</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17530718-45-crimeloc237" type="placeName" value="joining to the Swan brewhouse gate, White-chape"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17530718-45-crimeloc237" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-45-off235 t17530718-45-crimeloc237"></join>l, I am a <rs id="t17530718-45-viclabel238" type="occupation">taylor</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-45-victim405 t17530718-45-viclabel238"></join> by trade, but <rs id="t17530718-45-viclabel239" type="occupation">my wife keeps an earthen ware and china shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-45-victim405 t17530718-45-viclabel239"></join>, which she has kept about eight years. On the 23d of April , 1751, the watchman called me up between one and two o'clock, and when I came down the shutters were all broke to pieces, one pane of glass was broke, and one shutter lay in the middle of the channel, I shut the shop up myself, and am sure it was shut up fast. The bolt and keys were so the next morning. I missed the things mentioned in the indictment, (he produces a Bow china tea-pot ) and this tea-pot was one that I lost at that time. There was a woman came and gave information, whom I stopp'd and carried before Sir 
               <persName id="t17530718-45-person408">
                  Samuel 
                  Gower 
               <interp inst="t17530718-45-person408" type="surname" value="Gower"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-45-person408" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-45-person408" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I cannot swear that the prisoner did it.</p>
               <p>Q. How large was the pane of glass that was broke?</p>
               <p>Paul. I believe it would let me in.</p>
               <p>Q. from the prisoner. Do you know any thing of me?</p>
               <p>Paul. No, I know nothing of him, but I believe he is the man by circumstances.</p>
               <p>Elizabeth Hall. I have known the prisoner at the bar these two years.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know Hatton and Hall?</p>
               <p>Hall. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know any thing of the china ?</p>
               <p>Hall. Yes, Hatten, Hall, and Jones brought a bag, like a coal sack, with earthen ware and china in it, in April, 1751, they brought the goods to one Mrs. Titchbourne's in the Back Lane.</p>
               <p>Q. What were the particular things ?</p>
               <p>Hall. There was five earthen fish plates, two brown stone plates, and a great many tea cups and saucers, and a great many broke.</p>
               <p>Q. When they brought these things to this place, how did they say they came by them?</p>
               <p>Hall. George Hall said he broke open a house in White-chapel, the prisoner at the bar gave me six-pence to carry the china to one Mrs. Roach's in Gravel-Lane, Bishopsgate-street.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner say where he had them?</p>
               <p>Hall. No, he said nothing to me where he had them.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner there when Hall said he broke open the house in White-chapel?</p>
               <p>Hall. Yes, he was, they were all three together.</p>
               <p>Q. How did they say they got into the house?</p>
               <p>Hall. They said they broke the window shutter.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of that tea-pot.</p>
               <p>Hall. Yes, this tea pot had never a lid when they brought it.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know this is the pot?</p>
               <p>Hall. I know it by the roughness of the spout, one 
               <persName id="t17530718-45-person409">
                  Sarah 
                  Merrit 
               <interp inst="t17530718-45-person409" type="surname" value="Merrit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-45-person409" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-45-person409" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and I carried them, and had sixpence a-piece.</p>
               <p>Q. from the prisoner to Hall. Did I ever give you any money?</p>
               <p>Hall. He himself gave it me, it was a crooked six-pence, before he gave me things to carry.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-45-person410">
                  Sarah 
                  Merrit 
               <interp inst="t17530718-45-person410" type="surname" value="Merrit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-45-person410" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-45-person410" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew Hatton and Hall, and the prisoner at the bar, I have known them four or five years; but the other two I knew but about two or three months by seeing them about the place where they liv'd.</p>
               <p>Q. How long ago is that?</p>
               <p>Merrit. I don't know, I think, as near as I can guess, last April was two years, I saw them both in company together, and the prisoner with them.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon what occasion did you see them all three?</p>
               <p>Merrit. They were in a publick house drinking when I came in, and asked me to sit down and drink: We had not been long there before 
               <persName id="t17530718-45-person411">
                  David 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17530718-45-person411" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-45-person411" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-45-person411" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came in, they asked him if he had been picking pockets; he said, d - n your blood, yes. Then I heard them make a bargain to go out together, and Elizabeth Hall asked me to lay with her, which I did; about two or three in the morning somebody knock'd at the door, there were 
               <persName id="t17530718-45-person412">
                  David 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17530718-45-person412" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-45-person412" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-45-person412" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Hatton and Hall, Jones had got the bag with the china in it, and Hall had got a bag of pumps. In the morning, as soon as ever we were up, they asked me and Elizabeth Hall to carry them into Gravel Lane, Hall ask'd if I would go, I said I could carry nothing on my head, so I got a person to carry for me, and went with them. Jones went for Minous and Scampy, two Jews, with whom they bargained to sell these things, I heard George Hall say, he asked twenty-seven shillings, and Scampy and Minous bid them but twenty-three, so they could not agree: Then they carried the things into Rag-Fair, where they heard that this<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175307180037"></xptr> Forrester was going to make himself an evidence, and directly George Hall sent me to 
               <persName id="t17530718-45-person413">
                  James 
                  Brabrook 
               <interp inst="t17530718-45-person413" type="surname" value="Brabrook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-45-person413" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-45-person413" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to come and take them up.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-45-person414">
                  Abraham 
                  Miers 
               <interp inst="t17530718-45-person414" type="surname" value="Miers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-45-person414" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-45-person414" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew Hatton, Hall, and the prisoner at the bar; I have known the prisoner about 14 years, and Hatton and Hall about two years and a half: the china was brought to one Mrs. Roach's house to be sold to me and the Jews, they ask'd thirty-six shillings, and there was 22 bid, they parted for a crown, but don't know what became of them afterwards, this was about two years ago last April.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear Jones, Hall and Hatton say from whence they had these goods.</p>
               <p>Miers. No, I never asked them where they had them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-45-person415">
                  Miers
               <interp inst="t17530718-45-person415" type="given" value="Miers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-45-person415" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was only taken by these thief-takers to come and swear my life away for the reward, nothing else, <rs id="t17530718-45-verdict240" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530718-45-verdict240" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acq. but detained to be tried on another indictment
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
