<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17511016-3">
               <interp inst="t17511016-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511016-3" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511016-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17511016"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511016-3" type="date" value="17511016"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17511016-3-off11-c37" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-3-defend41 t17511016-3-off11 t17511016-3-verdict14"></join>
         
               <p>546. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17511016-3-defend41" type="defendantName">
                     Samuel 
                     Bacon 
                  <interp inst="t17511016-3-defend41" type="surname" value="Bacon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-defend41" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-defend41" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17511016-3-off11" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-off11" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-off11" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               robbing 
                     
                        <persName id="t17511016-3-victim43" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Bretley 
                        <interp inst="t17511016-3-victim43" type="surname" value="Bretley"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17511016-3-victim43" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17511016-3-victim43" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-3-off11 t17511016-3-victim43"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the King's highway of a gold watch, value 8 l. and two shillings in money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17511016-3-cd12" type="crimeDate">Oct. 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-3-off11 t17511016-3-cd12"></join>. +.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-3-person44">
                  John 
                  Bretley 
               <interp inst="t17511016-3-person44" type="surname" value="Bretley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-person44" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-person44" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Sunday morning last, about nine o'clock, I was going from my own house on <placeName id="t17511016-3-crimeloc13">Muswell-hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17511016-3-crimeloc13" type="placeName" value="Muswell-hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17511016-3-crimeloc13" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-3-off11 t17511016-3-crimeloc13"></join> to the house of Mr. Masterman, which is about three or four hundred yards from my house, and about half way I was met by the prisoner at the bar; he was on a brown mare, with a dark muzzle, and I was in my slippers, under which I had a pair of wooden clogs; and he asked me if that was the road to Highgate; I replied, there was no turning, and that he could not miss his way; I then went on, and he towards High-gate. When I was got within about forty or fifty yards of Mr. Masterman's house, I heard something behind me; I looked back and saw, I think, the same man, with a mask on his face, and a pistol in his hand, about four or five yards behind me. I mistrusting his errand, put my hand under my coat to push in my watch chain, which, with two large seals, hung visibly to be seen. He said, Give me your watch, or I will shoot you; I said I had none, or would not, or such like words. He replied, I saw your watch when I met you, therefore I know you have a watch; and added, I am an unhappy man, drove to it by necessity; I am a gentleman, and a man of honour, and drove to the utmost distress, or I should not use you in this manner; - I insist upon it, or I will shoot you through the head. I did not immediately give it him, but wanted him to put his pistol within my reach, that I might have an opportunity to lay hold on it ; then he put his hat towards me for my watch, and I put it into the hat. He then insisted upon my money; said I, I have but little, and it will not do you much service; to which he replied, don't conceal any; I answer'd, if you don't believe me, search me; which if he had, I designed to have secured him, but he would not, so I gave him two shillings into his hat. He then went off, and turning his horse about, when he was got about five or six yards, said, You shall have your watch again, if you advertise it, for the value of the gold, and then rode very fast off towards Highgate ; and I seeing Mr. Masterman, or his servant, called out for him to get me a horse, telling him that I had been robbed. I saw the prisoner ride by my house, and ran to see whether he turned towards Pinchley-common. I then mounted a horse, took a handle of a rake in my hand, and pursued, and Mr. Masterman's servant mounted another horse, and overtook me at Highgate; there we inquired, and was directed wrong, but found our mistake, and turned again. We never saw the prisoner till we got to the Spaniard at Hampstead. I had described him to the servant. I saw the prisoner turning by Mr. Arnold's corner, so I cut cross through the gravel pits, to meet him at North-end. We also called out as we rode; and when we came to North-end we saw him in the bottom. By this time the people were a little alarmed, and about two miles beyond there he quitted his horse, and took to the fields. My horse was almost knocked up, so I jumped upon the horse the prisoner had quitted. The prisoner had hid himself in a hedge, and before I got to him, he was by some persons dragged out. We took him before 
               <persName id="t17511016-3-person45">
                  Hammond 
                  Cross 
               <interp inst="t17511016-3-person45" type="surname" value="Cross"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-person45" type="given" value="Hammond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-person45" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; and he was committed.</p>
               <p>[He produced a wizard, which was found where the prisoner quitted his horse.]</p>
               <p>On his cross-examination beyond. When the prisoner asked the way to Highgate, he looked pretty<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175110160004"></xptr> hard at the prisoner ; that he lost fight of the prisoner for about two miles riding; that he found nothing upon the prisoner, but that the prisoner shewed him a hole in his pocket, when he asked him where his watch was, and said he had lost it out of that hole as he rode; that when his mittimus was made out, the prisoner desired to speak with him in another room; that he there begged his pardon, and that he did not appear to be in liquor. That when he came to North-end he saw a man, which he took to be the prisoner, riding extreme hard; that he did not see him quit his mare; that he was certain the man that robbed him was upon that mare which he himself afterwards mounted; that she then seemed, when he found her, to have been rode very hard, and spurred a good deal.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-3-person46">
                  George 
                  Griffice 
               <interp inst="t17511016-3-person46" type="surname" value="Griffice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-person46" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-person46" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Masterman. Mr. Bretley called out to me, to know if my master had any horses in the stable, saying he had been robbed; I said there were two. He then pointed out, saying, there goes the man, but I did not see him. I saddled two horses, he mounted one, and I the other, and pursued him to High-gate, where a man informed us he had turned to the left hand; upon which I rode round the two roads that go to London, and met several persons, who said there was no such man gone that way; then I went to the turnpike, and there I was told that no such person had pass'd through there; we turned again to the left, went to the Spaniards, and enquired there, and was told that there was such a man gone by some little time before. When we had got about two hundred yards from thence, I saw a man riding full speed, and calling to Mr. Bretley, I informed him, that I believed, by his description, there was the man that robbed him.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he describe the person who robbed him?</p>
               <p>Griffice. He described him as having a thin face, and riding a dark bay mare with a brown muzzle. I saw the man turn at the corner of a house, and take down the great road; for I was in view of him about a mile riding in the road, being rather better mounted than Mr. Bretley. I called out to a gentleman to stop him, informing him that he was a highwayman; then the prisoner turned out of the road, and rode to a hedge, quitted his mare, and jumped over it. There were a great crowd of people got about his mate, and I saw Mr. Bretley get on the mare; for my horse refused to go over the hedge, or I had taken the prisoner in the first field. When I had got up to him, there was a man or two had got hold of him; then Mr. Bretley came up, and after he had tied the prisoner's thumbs, he asked him where his watch was; he said he had it not. We got him into the road, mounted him with a man behind him, and carried him to the Justice's.</p>
               <p>Q. from the prisoner. Did you see me dismount my mare, or did she throw me?</p>
               <p>Griffice. He was on full speed, and in such a case no man can give evidence of that. According to the description Mr. Bretley gave me, the prisoner is the man that robbed him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-3-person47">
                  James 
                  Grubb 
               <interp inst="t17511016-3-person47" type="surname" value="Grubb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-person47" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-person47" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming to Mr. Bretley's house the same time he was robbed, and about forty yards from Mr. Bretley's gate I met the prisoner on the same brown mare, which Mr. Bretley rode afterwards; he was whipping and spurring all the way he went, and I expected she would throw him every minute. This was just after the robbery was committed; the prisoner was going towards Highgate, but there was no mask on his face then. I took particular notice of his clothes and his mare, but I did not so much mind his face. I followed Mr. Bretley, and saw the prisoner, when they had got him into the road, after taken. I saw the mare, and can swear it is the same mare I saw before, and that the prisoner had on the same sort of clothes. The mare was a dark bay with a brown muzzle.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-3-person48">
                  William 
                  Harison 
               <interp inst="t17511016-3-person48" type="surname" value="Harison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-person48" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-person48" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was with one Eldridge upon the Green, and there was the cry, Stop a highway-man! I saw the prisoner on horseback turn to the Green, who rode at a great rate. We pursued him, being about fifty pole from him when he turned out of the road. When we came up to him, we found him crept into a ditch covered pretty much with bushes. I did not see him when he quitted the mare, but I can swear the prisoner is the man I saw riding, and the mare I believe to be the same, but I did not so much mind her.</p>
               <p>Eldridge confirmed what the last evidence said, with this addition, That the prisoner was found in a ditch in the second field.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-3-person49">
                  Daniel 
                  Harison 
               <interp inst="t17511016-3-person49" type="surname" value="Harison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-person49" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-person49" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . As I was coming from Ditton to town, I saw the prisoner come riding down the hill very fast, whipping his horse, and as I rode up the hill they said it was a highwayman, and desired I would turn back again. I was pretty well mounted, so I rode back, and got ground of him every minute. I saw some people coming along, I called out to them a highwayman, stop him, &amp;c. he turned round upon Golder's Green, jumped off his horse, and went through a hedge, and ran over the fields. The hedge was difficult, and I could not jump my horse over, but I went<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175110160005"></xptr> down a little lower, got over, and went down the field; he then got over the stile, and went into the second field; I likewise jumped my horse over the stile, by the assistance of a man to force him, but the prisoner was then out of sight. Presently I heard a man say there he is, and I saw him pulled out of the hedge. I am certain he is the same man I saw whipping and riding, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>The prisoner called 
               <persName id="t17511016-3-person50">
                  Benjamin 
                  Sidney 
               <interp inst="t17511016-3-person50" type="surname" value="Sidney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-person50" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-person50" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a watchmaker, to whom he was apprentice, and had served upwards of five years, to give him a character; who, upon his cross-examination, acknowledged he had once made an elopement from his service, and at times would stay out till eleven or twelve o'clock at night.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-3-person51">
                  Evan 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17511016-3-person51" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-person51" type="given" value="Evan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-person51" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17511016-3-person52">
                  Richard 
                  Brooks 
               <interp inst="t17511016-3-person52" type="surname" value="Brooks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-person52" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-person52" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17511016-3-person53">
                  George 
                  Hager 
               <interp inst="t17511016-3-person53" type="surname" value="Hager"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-person53" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-person53" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17511016-3-person54">
                  Thomas 
                  Linley 
               <interp inst="t17511016-3-person54" type="surname" value="Linley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-person54" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-person54" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Harwood Lassiter, 
               <persName id="t17511016-3-person55">
                  Thomas 
                  Going 
               <interp inst="t17511016-3-person55" type="surname" value="Going"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-person55" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-person55" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17511016-3-person56">
                  Henry 
                  Newhouse 
               <interp inst="t17511016-3-person56" type="surname" value="Newhouse"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-person56" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-person56" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , had all known him for some years, and never heard any thing ill of him before this affair.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17511016-3-verdict14" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-verdict14" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17511016-3-punish15" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17511016-3-punish15" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-3-defend41 t17511016-3-punish15"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
