<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17500912-72">
               <interp inst="t17500912-72" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500912-72" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500912-72" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17500912"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500912-72" type="date" value="17500912"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500912-72-off306-c398" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-72-defend545 t17500912-72-off306 t17500912-72-verdict311"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500912-72-off306-c399" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-72-defend547 t17500912-72-off306 t17500912-72-verdict311"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500912-72-off306-c400" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-72-defend549 t17500912-72-off306 t17500912-72-verdict311"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500912-72-off306-c401" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-72-defend551 t17500912-72-off306 t17500912-72-verdict311"></join>
         
               <p>591, 592, 593, 594. 
               
                  <persName id="t17500912-72-defend545" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Masterson 
                  <interp inst="t17500912-72-defend545" type="surname" value="Masterson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-defend545" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-defend545" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17500912-72-defend547" type="defendantName">
                     Jane 
                     Poor 
                  <interp inst="t17500912-72-defend547" type="surname" value="Poor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-defend547" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-defend547" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17500912-72-defend549" type="defendantName">
                     Margaret 
                     Cavenhau 
                  <interp inst="t17500912-72-defend549" type="surname" value="Cavenhau"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-defend549" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-defend549" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17500912-72-defend551" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Cole 
                  <interp inst="t17500912-72-defend551" type="surname" value="Cole"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-defend551" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-defend551" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17500912-72-off306" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-off306" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-off306" type="offenceSubcategory" value="housebreaking"></interp>
               breaking and entering the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17500912-72-victim553" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Woolfall 
                        <interp inst="t17500912-72-victim553" type="surname" value="Woolfall"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500912-72-victim553" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500912-72-victim553" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                     
                  , one cloth rockeloe, one pair of cloth breeches, value 6 s one cloth waistcoat trim'd with gold, 10 pound weight of thread, the goods of the said Thomas; two pair of stays, a camblet gown, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17500912-72-victim555" type="victimName">
                           Esther 
                           Woolfall 
                        <interp inst="t17500912-72-victim555" type="surname" value="Woolfall"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500912-72-victim555" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500912-72-victim555" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                     
                   ; one velvet mantelet, one silk hood, one gauze handkerchief, one yard of velvet, two tortoiseshel snuff boxes, one silver girdle-buckle, three silver spoons, one gold ring with crystal stones, three pair of sheets, six shifts, and other things, the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17500912-72-victim557" type="victimName">
                           George 
                           Johnson 
                        <interp inst="t17500912-72-victim557" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500912-72-victim557" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500912-72-victim557" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                     
                  , in the dwelling house of the said 
                     <persName id="t17500912-72-person558">
                        Thomas 
                        Woolfall 
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-person558" type="surname" value="Woolfall"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500912-72-person558" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500912-72-person558" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17500912-72-cd307" type="crimeDate">July 26</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-72-off306 t17500912-72-cd307"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-72-person559">
                  Thomas 
                  Woolfall 
               <interp inst="t17500912-72-person559" type="surname" value="Woolfall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-person559" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-person559" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17500912-72-crimeloc308">Peter-street, at the corner between that and Hide-street, Bloomsbury</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17500912-72-crimeloc308" type="placeName" value="Peter-street, at the corner between that and Hide-street, Bloomsbury"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17500912-72-crimeloc308" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-72-off306 t17500912-72-crimeloc308"></join>. In the night, betwixt the 25th and 26th of July, my house was broke open. There was an iron bolt belonging to the window broke in two pieces, and a pane of glass broke; it was the kitchin window on the ground floor. The watchman came into the house between two and three o'clock and awaken'd us.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he here?</p>
               <p>Woolfall. No, he is not, my lord. We found two doors open. We have two doors in Peter-street, and one in Hide-street; one in each street was open. There was a box taken away out of the room where I work (I am a <rs id="t17500912-72-viclabel309" type="occupation">taylor</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-72-victim553 t17500912-72-viclabel309"></join>). In the box where a rockeloe, 10 pound weight of thread, a waistcoat trim'd with gold, a burdet gown, a quilted coat, a pair of stays, two cloth cloaks, a linen gown, a cotton gown, a silk gown unfinished. I saw the box the day before in its place. I lost also two rolls of flannel. About three or four days after I had an information by a woman now in court. I got a search warrant and searched Cavenhau's house, in Drury lane, there I found the rockeloe. I found my flannel, and some thread, and I found the breeches, but they were not in the house, they were found on a person's back. There were a brown gown found in the house upon a maid's back, Cavenhau said, they were brought in by a lodger.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-72-person560">
                  Mary 
                  Russel 
               <interp inst="t17500912-72-person560" type="surname" value="Russel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-person560" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-person560" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Mr. Woolfall's, I am his wife's shop-woman, she <rs id="t17500912-72-viclabel310" type="occupation">keeps a toy-shop, and is a haberdasher of small wares</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-72-victim555 t17500912-72-viclabel310"></join>, and did so before he married her. Betwixt the 25th and 26th of July the watch were coming up stairs; I was apprehensive of some disorder in the house, and came down; I found the house had been broke open, the shutter at the kitchin window was pull'd open, the bult broken in two pieces, and a pane of glass broken; there was a box lost from off the shop-board, containing several things of value. I keep the books, and have an account of what was in it (She mentions them as in the Indictment). The box was lock'd, Mr. Woolfall kept the key. She was shewn the bundles of thread found. We had some such thread as this, but I cannot swear to it. She is show'd some flannel. That I cannot swear to; we lost some such. On searching Cavenhau's house there were found some thread, some flannel, and a rockeloe, but I cannot positively swear to either.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-72-person561">
                  William 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17500912-72-person561" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-person561" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-person561" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at justice Fielding's the first of August, there was 
               <persName id="t17500912-72-person562">
                  Thomas 
                  Axford 
               <interp inst="t17500912-72-person562" type="surname" value="Axford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-person562" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-person562" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the constable, who is not here now, he demanded me to go and help search the house of Cavenhau. We went there, and up one pair of stairs in a front room we found these things. I took an inventory of them all. There were this last witness, the prosecutor, and another young woman before the justice. This witness then said, she could swear to the things. Then we went to St. Andrew's street, to the three Coffins near the seven Dials, to Masterson's lodgings, we laid hold of him, and in searching him we found a pistol in his bosom. He lodged up one pair of stairs; we went and opened a box, and found in it some more flannel, and four pound of thread. The young woman came up, and said, I'll swear that is my box. She took a key she had got and opened it directly.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175009120034"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-72-person563">
                  Mary 
                  Russel 
               <interp inst="t17500912-72-person563" type="surname" value="Russel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-person563" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-person563" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I cannot swear to the box, it is like ours.</p>
               <p>Q. to the prosecutor. Is that your box? It was produced in court.</p>
               <p>Woolfall. It is like my box that I lost, but I will not swear to it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-72-person564">
                  William 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17500912-72-person564" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-person564" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-person564" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When he was shew'd these things before justice Fielding, he said, the things were his, and he would swear to them, although he will not now</p>
               <p>Esther Woolfall. I am servant to the prosecutor. I remember the house was broke open between the 25th and 26th of July. I shut that window up over night, that was broke open, the bolt was whole then, and the pane of glass was whole. She would swear to none of the goods, but she allow'd she had the key that open'd the box; but said, one key might be like another, &amp;c. We found a gown at Cavenhau's. It was produced in court, she would not swear to it, but said, it is like that of mine which I lost, but the lining is alter'd if it is mine.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-72-person565">
                  George 
                  Beecher 
               <interp inst="t17500912-72-person565" type="surname" value="Beecher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-person565" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-person565" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming by. I am a constable in that division. I was only an assistant, I had not the warrant. They desired me to step into this Cavenhau's house, Mr. Woolfall was there. We went by the direction of one 
               <persName id="t17500912-72-person566">
                  Ann 
                  Gervey 
               <interp inst="t17500912-72-person566" type="surname" value="Gervey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-person566" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-person566" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . she I found had been before justice Fielding. We went and in her house we found a pistol and a dark lanthorn; the prisoner, Cavenhau, seemed to be much affrighted.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-72-person567">
                  Elias 
                  Ridler 
               <interp inst="t17500912-72-person567" type="surname" value="Ridler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-person567" type="given" value="Elias"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-person567" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable, they brought the warrant to me. The young woman, 
               <persName id="t17500912-72-person568">
                  Esther 
                  Woolfall 
               <interp inst="t17500912-72-person568" type="surname" value="Woolfall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-person568" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-person568" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , said, take hold of his gown, as it was on one of the prisoner's back, saying, it is my gown, I'll swear to it, by the two small bits of camblet on the shoulder. Then we went to Masterson's, and found a pistol upon him, a dark lanthorn, a frame clock-spring saw, ripping chisels, and other things.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-72-person569">
                  Ann 
                  Gervey 
               <interp inst="t17500912-72-person569" type="surname" value="Gervey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-person569" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-person569" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 25th of July, 
               <persName id="t17500912-72-person570">
                  Thomas 
                  Masterson 
               <interp inst="t17500912-72-person570" type="surname" value="Masterson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-person570" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-person570" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the barber, came to Cavenhau's back door about twelve o'clock, I lodged there then, and am chare-woman there; my boy went and let him in. I heard his voice, which I know very well, but did not see him. He went up stairs and staid some time, then he went down stairs again. The boy ran down before him to let him out ; he said to the boy, what do you want you dog? go back. So we waited, and about a quarter of an hour after 
               <persName id="t17500912-72-person571">
                  William 
                  Cavenhau 
               <interp inst="t17500912-72-person571" type="surname" value="Cavenhau"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-person571" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-person571" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and he came down and lock'd the door after them, and took the key with them. I could hear them speak to one another, and I know it was them, for nobody else were in the house but them. I know not when they came in again, it was about eleven o'clock the next day before they got up. In the closet I saw a large roll of flannel and a rockeloe, they were not there before. I saw two rolls of thread, which lay upon the table between the two windows. I saw also three spoons, and a long black hood, Mrs Cavenhau said, she had them to sell. She employed Mrs. Cook to sell them for her. She carried them out and brought Mrs. Cavenhau 50 s. Mrs. Cavenhau said that was better than nothing. I saw some gowns, none of these things were in the house before they went out. Masterson, the prisoner, gave my son a pair of breeches. Mrs. Cavenhau asked him. If he had an old pair, he order'd my son to come on Sunday morning. Mr. Woolfall swore to the breeches, and put my boy in Bridwell.</p>
               <p>The Constable. - Please you, my lord, the prosecutor swore to the goods before the justice, although he will not here.</p>
               <p>Q. to the prosecutor. Pray what is the meaning of it, that you should be so ready to swear to these things before the justice, and do not care to do it now?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. One thing may be like another.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not swear positively before the justice?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Yes, my lord, I did.</p>
               <p>The constable said the shop-woman, and maid servant, swore likewise, before the justice. They being asked concerning that, said they did, but would not swear to them now.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-72-person572">
                  John 
                  Gervey 
               <interp inst="t17500912-72-person572" type="surname" value="Gervey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-person572" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-person572" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Cavenhau's house, he and Masterson used to be backwards and forwards there. Mrs. Cavenhau asked Masterson, if he had an old pair of breeches to give to me, he ordered me to come for a pair on Sunday morning. I went, he gave me these breeches, that have been produced in court. I brought them home, Mr. Woolfall swore to them, and I have been in Bridewell ever since.</p>
               <p>All <rs id="t17500912-72-verdict311" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500912-72-verdict311" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
