<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17590912-3">
               <interp inst="t17590912-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590912-3" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590912-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17590912"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590912-3" type="date" value="17590912"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17590912-3-off29-c63" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-3-defend71 t17590912-3-off29 t17590912-3-verdict32"></join>
         
               <p>247. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17590912-3-defend71" type="defendantName">
                     Edward 
                     Dixon 
                  <interp inst="t17590912-3-defend71" type="surname" value="Dixon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-3-defend71" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-3-defend71" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17590912-3-off29" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590912-3-off29" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-3-off29" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing three guineas, one half guinea, and 10 s. and 9 d. in money, one pair of worstedstockings, value 2 s. and one linnen shirt, value 5 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17590912-3-victim73" type="victimName">
                           Joseph 
                           Haselham 
                        <interp inst="t17590912-3-victim73" type="surname" value="Haselham"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590912-3-victim73" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590912-3-victim73" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-3-off29 t17590912-3-victim73"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17590912-3-cd30" type="crimeDate">Sept. 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-3-off29 t17590912-3-cd30"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590912-3-person74">
                  Joseph 
                  Haselham 
               <interp inst="t17590912-3-person74" type="surname" value="Haselham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-3-person74" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-3-person74" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the George in St Giles's: the prisoner and I were together at the Castle and Falcon on the 8th of September, between six and seven in the evening.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is that?</p>
               <p>Haselham. In <placeName id="t17590912-3-crimeloc31">St Giles's parish in Holborn</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17590912-3-crimeloc31" type="placeName" value="St Giles's parish in Holborn"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17590912-3-crimeloc31" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-3-off29 t17590912-3-crimeloc31"></join>. We had been there about half an hour. We had been drinking at the George about three hours, that is in Broad St Giles's, just before.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you, after you had been drinking so long there, to go to the Castle and Falcon?</p>
               <p>Haselham. I was a little in liquor. There were four of us; we had been all together; there were serjeant Coles, he belongs to the Guildhall subscription; he is now out of town. I believe we were all four together at the Castle and Falcon about half an hour. I laid my head on the table and fell asleep; they were all there then but the serjeant, he was gone out. I believe I slept about an hour. When I awaked I found myself alone. When I went to sleep I had 4 l. 5 s. and 9 d. about me; three guineas and a half in gold, the rest in silver, and 3 d. in half-pence. He left 18 d. in my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. How much silver?</p>
               <p>Haselham. I can't tell justly how much silver, having changed a guinea just before. We paid 8 d. each, but the serjeant, at the Castle and Falcon, but do not know how much I spent at the George. I lost a pair stockings, which were afterwards found in the prisoner's pocket: they were taken out of my right-side pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you awake?</p>
               <p>Haselham. I believe about half an hour after seven.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to suspect the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Haselham. Because a person that is here told me, he saw him take my things out of my pocket, upon which I took him up, and charg'd him with it. I took him before the justice, there he denied it. The stockings were found in his pocket when I first took him up. The shirt was found at his cousin's in Gray's-Inn-Lane. I was at the finding of it. We went there by the direction of a man that was with<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175909120008"></xptr> him when he left it to be washed, but he is not here. A shirt and stockings produced in court and depos'd to.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you take the prisoner up?</p>
               <p>Haselham. We took him up on the Sunday, at the George in St Giles's.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. What did the landlady of the house say to you when you miss'd the money?</p>
               <p>Haselham. She said, the prisoner had taken it.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Whether or not the landlady did not say she heard me say, that I, as a friend of your's, took it by way of security?</p>
               <p>Haselham. She did say so; but before the justice he denied it, and said, he knew no more of it than he did of his dying day.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever get your money again?</p>
               <p>Haselham. Yes; he confessed the fact in the Round-House, and returned four guineas and a half.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. What did you do with the four guineas and a half?</p>
               <p>Haselham. The Justice ordered it into the hands of the Serjeant.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. There is ten shillings and threepence due to me out of the money.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. There is that due to him; he could not give him exact the money, not having change, the ten shillings and three-pence is his property.</p>
               <p>Q. If it had been in your power when that four guineas and a half were delivered to the Serjeant, you would not have prosecuted, would you?</p>
               <p>Haselham. No, I would not have hurt the man.</p>
               <p>Thomas Green. I was in the room when the prosecutor fell asleep: I saw the prisoner put his hand in his right-side pocket in a very private manner. I was within about four yards of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any thing in his hand when he withdrew it?</p>
               <p>Green. No, I did not. After that I saw him put his hand in his left-hand pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you one of that company?</p>
               <p>Green. No, I am servant in the house: the prisoner and prosecutor were drunk, but the prisoner was the soberest I think of the two.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17590912-3-verdict32" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590912-3-verdict32" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
