<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17540911-41">
               <interp inst="t17540911-41" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-41" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-41" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-41" type="date" value="17540911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540911-41-off221-c332" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-41-defend403 t17540911-41-off221 t17540911-41-verdict224"></join>
         
               <p>456. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17540911-41-defend403" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Incle 
                  <interp inst="t17540911-41-defend403" type="surname" value="Incle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-41-defend403" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-41-defend403" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17540911-41-off221" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540911-41-off221" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-41-off221" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               that he on the <rs id="t17540911-41-cd222" type="crimeDate">21st of May</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-41-off221 t17540911-41-cd222"></join>, about the hour of one in the night, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17540911-41-victim405" type="victimName">
                           Sarah 
                           Parr 
                        <interp inst="t17540911-41-victim405" type="surname" value="Parr"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540911-41-victim405" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540911-41-victim405" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-41-off221 t17540911-41-victim405"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , widow, did break and enter, and steal out thence two glass bottles full of brandy, value 2 s. one glass bottle full of geneva, and one glass bottle called geneva bitters
            </rs>, the goods of the said Sarah ++.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-41-person406">
                  Sarah 
                  Parr 
               <interp inst="t17540911-41-person406" type="surname" value="Parr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-41-person406" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-41-person406" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at <placeName id="t17540911-41-crimeloc223">Islington</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17540911-41-crimeloc223" type="placeName" value="Islington"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17540911-41-crimeloc223" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-41-off221 t17540911-41-crimeloc223"></join>. On the 21st of May, between the hours of one and two in the morning, I was in bed with my daughter in a parlour, my little dog barked, I heard something padding, presently I heard a violent wrench, I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175409110037"></xptr> called and said, You villains, are you going to rob me? After this they were still, then I heard a second noise, that was a pane of glass taking out at the window. I had four glass bottles stood on a table under that window when I went to bed. I heard them rattle, and called out a second time, What, you villains, are you still there? I am coming this minute. Then I laid still a little longer, and heard another noise, when I jump'd out of bed; and as I passed through the second room to tell another person, I heard them run away; then I went back and sat down in the parlour till I thought all was safe; I then opened the door that looked into the room where the bottles stood, and saw the window shutter was down; then r shut the door again, and fastened it, and sat down till I heard the watchman come by; I called him, and then went into the room and missed the four bottles. There was a bottle of cherry brandy, another of other brandy, one of geneva, and another of geneva bitters, all gone. The watchman told me he had seen three men over-against his stand drinking out of a bottle, but he knew none of them. About five weeks after, a man came and asked me if I was not robb'd about ten days before Whitsontide, and said he had got six fellows in Tothill-fields bridewell, and one of them is admitted evidence, he had confessed two robberies, and one of them was robbing me of four bottles of liquor, and desired me to come to Justice Fielding's; I went, the prisoner and evidence were there, but I knew nothing of them, for I saw no body.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-41-person407">
                  James 
                  Weeden 
               <interp inst="t17540911-41-person407" type="surname" value="Weeden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-41-person407" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-41-person407" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner, 
               <persName id="t17540911-41-person408">
                  John 
                  Simms 
               <interp inst="t17540911-41-person408" type="surname" value="Simms"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-41-person408" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-41-person408" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and I are night-men; we went all three together one day to the prosecutrix's house about 2 o'clock to see how the house stood; knowing her to be a widow woman that keeps a publick house we thought there were no men to oppose us; we concluded to break the house as near the bar as we could. We went from the Castle in Leicester-street, by Lickapont-street, the house we used, and got to her house about eleven at night, we thought it too soon to attack it, so we went to Holloway; we got to a farm-house, and thought to break that open, but it was too fast for us, so we went into a place and took a game cock and hen, and killed them. Coming back we met an elderly woman just by Islington church, Simms knocked her down and took from her one shilling and ten pence farthing, and an apron, which we sold for a shilling; then we came to Mrs. Parr's house, I pull'd three or four times at the window shutter, it would not come out, at last it did; after that the prisoner broke the glass, we took out 4 bottles of spirituous liquors, I took out one of them, and Simms three; then we broke the sash of the window, with an intent to get in, but some of the glass fell, and the prosecutrix struck a light and call'd out Thieves. We had a pistol and cutlass with us. There was a soldier in the house, we agreed the first man we saw to shoot or cut down, believing there was but one man at most, but the woman made such a noise we were forced to go away, knowing the watchman was very nigh; we went through the church-yard, and took a bottle of cherry brandy, and drank to the watchman, and bid him good night. We got to Leicester-street about 3 o'clock.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I am a hard working man, I am innocent of the fact.</p>
               <p>Several persons appeared to his character, who all gave him a very good one.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540911-41-verdict224" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540911-41-verdict224" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
