<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17530718-42">
               <interp inst="t17530718-42" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530718-42" type="year" value="1753"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530718-42" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17530718"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530718-42" type="date" value="17530718"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17530718-42-off222-c306" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-42-defend380 t17530718-42-off222 t17530718-42-verdict226"></join>
         
               <p>360. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17530718-42-defend380" type="defendantName">
                     Stephen 
                     Rosbow 
                  <interp inst="t17530718-42-defend380" type="surname" value="Rosbow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-42-defend380" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-42-defend380" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17530718-42-off222" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530718-42-off222" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-42-off222" type="offenceSubcategory" value="shoplifting"></interp>
               stealing one guinea, the money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17530718-42-victim382" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Mace 
                        <interp inst="t17530718-42-victim382" type="surname" value="Mace"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530718-42-victim382" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530718-42-victim382" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-42-off222 t17530718-42-victim382"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the shop of the said John
            </rs>, <rs id="t17530718-42-cd223" type="crimeDate">May 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-42-off222 t17530718-42-cd223"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-42-person383">
                  John 
                  Mace 
               <interp inst="t17530718-42-person383" type="surname" value="Mace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-42-person383" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-42-person383" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I <rs id="t17530718-42-viclabel224" type="occupation">keep a snuff-shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-42-victim382 t17530718-42-viclabel224"></join>, in <placeName id="t17530718-42-crimeloc225">Marybone-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17530718-42-crimeloc225" type="placeName" value="Marybone-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17530718-42-crimeloc225" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-42-off222 t17530718-42-crimeloc225"></join>. On the 30th of May last. I was out of town, and when I came home my wife told me she had had two men in the shop that had stole a guinea; I enquir'd after the prisoner at the bar, and the other man that came in with him, to know their names and places of abode, I enquir'd at several places, at last my wife said, she heard the prisoner went by the name of Dragon, and I enquir'd of several people that knew him, but they knew not where he liv'd, but we found the man that was with him and took him up, he said, he knew nothing of it. On the 4th of June we took up the prisoner and carry'd him before the justice, he talk'd in French, and the justice's boy was his interpreter, he said the prisoner confess'd he had the guinea, but took it out of a mistake.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was this after you lost it?</p>
               <p>Mace. I lost it on the 30th of May, and this was on the 4th June.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any confession taken?</p>
               <p>Mace. I cannot say, the prisoner sent several times to offer me the guinea ; and there is a gentleman now in court I believe, that came from the prisoner to my wife, and said, I had better give him 20 guineas and let him go, for he would not be in my coat for 100 l.</p>
               <p>Q. from the prisoner. Did not you take up another person and swear against him for defrauding you of this guinea?</p>
               <p>Mace. We took up another man first, but afterwards with his information we took up the prisoner, and on his confession we discharg'd the other.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-42-person384">
                  Jane 
                  Mace 
               <interp inst="t17530718-42-person384" type="surname" value="Mace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-42-person384" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-42-person384" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner and another man came into our shop on the 30th of May, and ask'd for a pound of tobacco. I weigh'd it, and he threw down a guinea and desir'd change, I took it up and look'd at it on the other side of the counter, and he stood about the middle ; then I laid it down by me, thinking I had change in my pocket, I had not enough, but went into the back room, and brought him change, and put it down on the counter, (he had folded up the tobacco and was putting it into his pocket just as I came out of the back room ) I never saw the guinea afterwards, there was a woman in the shop that came for a pennyworth of snuff, I did not look for the guinea her fact, the two men went out and the guinea was go.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you did not put the guinea in your pocket ?</p>
               <p>Mace. I am sure I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was it before you must it?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175307180035"></xptr>Mace. In a minute or less, I only serv'd the snuff since, and there was nobody had been there but the prisoner and his companion, and the woman that came for the snuff.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you sweep the shop, it might have dropt down ?</p>
               <p>Mace. No, I am very sensible that it was far enough on the counter that it could not fall.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the prisoner then?</p>
               <p>Mace. He was at a distance off ; when we was before the justice, the interpreter told me he confess'd he took the guinea, and his companion said he had it.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was that companion?</p>
               <p>Mace. I know nothing at all of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was this interpreter?</p>
               <p>Mace. The justice's boy. The prisoner sent the interpreter that is here, whose name is Delaport, to me, and said, we had better go and give the prisoner 20 guineas and let him go about his business.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Trevill. I went into the shop for snuff, and saw the prisoner, after he had handled the tobacco, throw down a guinea, and ask'd for change; th e gentlewoman took the guinea and look'd at it, and the man that was with the prisoner said I believe it is good, she said it was. She had not silver enough in her pocket, so she left the guinea, and went in to get change. While she was gone the prisoner at the bar put his hand over and took the guinea, and then he laid it down again near the other person that was with him, who looked at it, but I did not see him lay it down, nor take it away, for I never saw the guinea afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Then you saw the guinea in the other man's hand after it was in the prisoner's ?</p>
               <p>Trevill. Yes, I did, but did not see him lay it down again, nor take it away. When the prisoner was before the justice, the interpreter said that this man took the guinea.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure he said this man, or the other man took it?</p>
               <p>Trevill. No, he said it was this man, for he repeated it in English.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17530718-42-verdict226" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530718-42-verdict226" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
