<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17531024-41">
               <interp inst="t17531024-41" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531024-41" type="year" value="1753"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531024-41" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17531024"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531024-41" type="date" value="17531024"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17531024-41-off184-c219" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-41-defend292 t17531024-41-off184 t17531024-41-verdict187"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17531024-41-off188-c219" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-41-defend292 t17531024-41-off188 t17531024-41-verdict187"></join>
         
               <p>487. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17531024-41-defend292" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Hambleton 
                  <interp inst="t17531024-41-defend292" type="surname" value="Hambleton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-41-defend292" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-41-defend292" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for that he, together with 
               <persName id="t17531024-41-person293">
                  Allen 
                  Lattey 
               <interp inst="t17531024-41-person293" type="surname" value="Lattey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-41-person293" type="given" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-41-person293" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17531024-41-off184" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17531024-41-off184" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-41-off184" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               on the King's highway on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17531024-41-victim295" type="victimName">
                           Joseph 
                           Trow 
                        <interp inst="t17531024-41-victim295" type="surname" value="Trow"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17531024-41-victim295" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17531024-41-victim295" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and stealing from him six gold rings, val. 46 s. one pair of silver shoe buckles, one half guinea, and 5 s. in money number'd
            </rs>, <rs id="t17531024-41-cd185" type="crimeDate">Sept. 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-41-off184 t17531024-41-cd185"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-41-off188 t17531024-41-cd185"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>The prosecutor depos'd, he was coming towards London, <placeName id="t17531024-41-crimeloc186">between Bloody-bridge and the Turnpike, which is between Chelsea and the Park</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17531024-41-crimeloc186" type="placeName" value="between Bloody-bridge and the Turnpike, which is between Chelsea and the Park"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17531024-41-crimeloc186" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-41-off184 t17531024-41-crimeloc186"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-41-off188 t17531024-41-crimeloc186"></join>, in a chaise alone, on the 2d of September; he was met by two men, stopped and robb'd, but could not swear positively to the prisoner. A pair of buckles were produc'd, which were found in Lattey's pocket when he was taken, which the prosecutor could swear to, he also could swear Lattey was one, but he being very ill could not take his trial then, the prisoner was <rs id="t17531024-41-verdict187" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17531024-41-verdict187" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a second time indicted for that he, together with 
               <persName id="t17531024-41-person296">
                  Allen 
                  Lattey 
               <interp inst="t17531024-41-person296" type="surname" value="Lattey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-41-person296" type="given" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-41-person296" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17531024-41-off188" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17531024-41-off188" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-41-off188" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               on the King's highway on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17531024-41-victim298" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Wheeler 
                        <interp inst="t17531024-41-victim298" type="surname" value="Wheeler"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17531024-41-victim298" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17531024-41-victim298" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and stealing from him one silver watch, val. 3 l. one pair of silver buckles, val. 8 s.
            </rs> the goods of the said Robert, <rs id="t17531024-41-cd189" type="crimeDate">Sept. 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-41-off184 t17531024-41-cd189"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-41-off188 t17531024-41-cd189"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-41-person299">
                  Robert 
                  Wheeler 
               <interp inst="t17531024-41-person299" type="surname" value="Wheeler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-41-person299" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-41-person299" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I do not know the prisoner: on the 16th of September I was robb'd near the one mile stone going to Hampstead, between eight and nine o'clock, of a silver watch and a pair of buckles by two men on foot; they stopped my horse, I saw one of them on my right side had a pistol, one of them said, d - n you, deliver: they took my watch and buckles, and also my<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175310240024"></xptr> money, which I have not laid in the indictment; the tallest of them, at my going away, gave me a shilling, and said I was a brave fellow. It was so very dark, that I could neither distinguish their faces or cloaths. I advertised the watch, and on the 18th I saw it at a pawnbroker's again, I saw my buckles in 
               <persName id="t17531024-41-person300">
                  Charles 
                  Weyland 
               <interp inst="t17531024-41-person300" type="surname" value="Weyland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-41-person300" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-41-person300" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's hands, the Turnkey of New-prison.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-41-person301">
                  Joseph 
                  Watson 
               <interp inst="t17531024-41-person301" type="surname" value="Watson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-41-person301" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-41-person301" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a pawnbroker, I received this watch (producing one which the prosecutor deposed to) from 
               <persName id="t17531024-41-person302">
                  John 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17531024-41-person302" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-41-person302" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-41-person302" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , otherwise Lattey, and one Kennedy was with him, I lent him two guineas on it.</p>
               <p>- Kennedy. I know the prisoner, and have been acquainted with him about a month, I am a cooper: 
               <persName id="t17531024-41-person303">
                  Allen 
                  Lattey 
               <interp inst="t17531024-41-person303" type="surname" value="Lattey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-41-person303" type="given" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-41-person303" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I knew from a boy, but had not seen him since I left the regiment, I was a serjeant. I met with him in London about a month ago, and being told who he was, for being grown I did not know him, I invited him to my house to dine; he came and brought the prisoner with him, the Sunday before he was taken up, and they went away in the evening about five or six o'clock. The next morning Lattey came to me at my work between ten and eleven o'clock, he sat in the shop, and said he wanted to raise money, and he must pawn his watch.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any body with him?</p>
               <p>Kennedy. No. I went with him to Mr. Watson, there he pawn'd it; on the Friday night I saw the prisoner, I believe it was in Parker's-lane at a private house, I am not acquainted in that part of the town. I was going along, and Lattey passed by me himself ; he said, he was going to a publick-house, (pointing to one) and wanted me to drink. I went on to do my business, and then went there to him, where we had two tankards of beer; there was another person with him, which he said was a surgeon, whose name is Crosby ; he said, Hambleton is very bad and not likely to live, and that is his surgeon: I went along with them to see him, where he was lying in Parker's-lane; I spoke to him, but he made me little or no answer being very weak.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any discourse with him about that watch, or the robbery?</p>
               <p>Kennedy No, never. The surgeon took the prisoner to his own house, in an Alley near Drury-lane: the next day I went down to Mr. Watson's, he having sent to me, to let me know the watch was not honestly come by, and was advertised ; while I was gone with him, in endeavouring to take up Lattey, I was informed the prisoner was gone from the surgeon's to my house, where he was taken.</p>
               <p>Q Don't you know he was found in your house concealed in a closet up two pair of stairs.</p>
               <p>Kennedy. I was told so, but that is not my apartment.</p>
               <p>Q to Watson. Did you sead for the prisoner that time?</p>

               <p>Watson. I did, having seen it advertised I sent for him to tell him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-41-person304">
                  Charles 
                  Wheeler 
               <interp inst="t17531024-41-person304" type="surname" value="Wheeler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-41-person304" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-41-person304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Lattey and Hambleton were committed, upon suspicion of the murder of my lord Harrington's Cook, to New prison, where I am Turnkey, (he produces a pair of silver buckles which were deposed to by the prosecutor to be taken out of his shoes when he was stopp'd) these buckles I found in the pocket of Lattey, who I find is since dead in Newgate; Lattey cleaned them as his own, and Hambleton desired I'd return them to him, saying, they were Lattey's property.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I am quite innocent of the affair.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17531024-41-verdict190" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17531024-41-verdict190" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was detained to take his trial next sessions for the murder of my lord Harrington's Cook.</p>
            </div1>
