<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17541023-38">
               <interp inst="t17541023-38" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541023-38" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541023-38" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17541023"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541023-38" type="date" value="17541023"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17541023-38-off186-c188" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-38-defend253 t17541023-38-off186 t17541023-38-verdict190"></join>
         
               <p>502. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17541023-38-defend253" type="defendantName">
                  Thomas 
                  Rolf 
               <interp inst="t17541023-38-defend253" type="surname" value="Rolf"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-defend253" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-defend253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted, for <rs id="t17541023-38-off186" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-off186" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-off186" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he, in a certain field, or open place, near the King's highway, on 
                     <persName id="t17541023-38-victim254" type="victimName">
                        Mary, <rs id="t17541023-38-viclabel187" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-38-victim254 t17541023-38-viclabel187"></join> of 
                           <persName id="t17541023-38-person255" type="victimName">
                              
                                 <persName id="t17541023-38-victim256" type="victimName">
                                    Thomas 
                                    Turton 
                                 <interp inst="t17541023-38-victim256" type="surname" value="Turton"></interp>
                              <interp inst="t17541023-38-victim256" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                              <interp inst="t17541023-38-victim256" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                           </persName>
                               
                           <interp inst="t17541023-38-person255" type="surname" value="Turton"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17541023-38-person255" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17541023-38-person255" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        </persName>
                        
                        <interp inst="t17541023-38-victim254" type="surname" value="Turton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17541023-38-victim254" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17541023-38-victim254" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , did make an assault, putting her in corporal fear and danger of her life, and stealing from her person 5 s. in money
            </rs>, the money of the said Thomas, <rs id="t17541023-38-cd188" type="crimeDate">Oct. 10. </rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-38-off186 t17541023-38-cd188"></join>*</p> 
               <p>Mary Turton. Last Wednesday was se'nnight, about 2 o'clock in the afternoon, I was going from London to Newington; being in a field beyond <placeName id="t17541023-38-crimeloc189">Newington green</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17541023-38-crimeloc189" type="placeName" value="Newington green"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17541023-38-crimeloc189" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-38-off186 t17541023-38-crimeloc189"></join>, in a minute's time I saw a pistol put to my breast, I had not seen the man before. He said, your money, madam, your money. I hesitated a little time, I did not know whether he designed to rob me or not. Then he said your money, madam, and your purse. I said I have no purse; I took out what silver I had, and gave it into his hand; I believe there might be about 8 s. of it. Then he said I have taken up this trade for want, and am in great stress, and have been all about to enquire for work and can get none. He then went away; so when I thought myself clear of him, I called to a man and a boy, whom I saw in another field, and said I had been robbed by a man, and pointed which way he was gone.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the man that robbed you when you pointed ?</p>
               <p>M. Turton. No, I did not. After they understood me, I saw them run the way that I pointed. I told them that I was going to Newington, and desired if they took him to bring him to me. I went on and met other people, and sent them after them. I had not been at Newington, at the house of Mr. Carter, a boarding school, above three quarters of an hour before they brought a man to me, I went out to him and said, you villain, you robbed me; he made me no answer as I remember, there was a great croud about him. I desired the gentleman to let me go into the parlour, which he did and shut the door, and saw no more of him at that time. Then they sent for the constable and secured him, and I took coach and came home. The next morning I went to justice Fielding's, and the man was brought there, but could not then swear to his face, but swore I thought him to be the man. I looked at the pistol when I was robbed, and not at the man's face. I told the people the man that had robbed me was in a dark coat, and the man they brought had a dark coat, and he answered the description.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you now say you believe, or are you sure this is the man?</p>
               <p>M. Turton. I believe that is the man.</p>
               <p>Q. Is this the man they brought to you?</p>
               <p>M. Turton. The very same man.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say at the justice's, when charged with it?</p>
               <p>M. Turton. He denied it.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Did you see a mask on the man's face?</p>
               <p>M. Turton. No, I saw none.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. She says it was about two o'clock in the afternoon, I hope the person's face might be perfectly seen, and what sort of buttons were to the man's coat?</p>
               <p>M. Turton. I can't describe them.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. What waistcoat and breeches?</p>
               <p>M. Turton. I don't know</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Whether the person's hat was flapped or cocked?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175410230023"></xptr>M. Turton. I think it was flapped.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. She said before the justice she thought it was a tinderbox pistol.</p>
               <p>M. Turton. No. I said I looked earnestly on the pistol, and was not sure at first whether it was a tinderbox or not, but I saw afterwards it was no tinderbox.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you alone?</p>
               <p>M. Turton. No, my daughter, a girl about 14 years of age, was with me, and she was very much frightened as well as myself</p>
               <p>Joseph Saunders. Last Wednesday was se'nnight, about two in the afternoon, I saw a man along with the prosecutrix, in a field behind Newington green, I was in the next field spreading of dung. I saw him also go from her.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was you from her at that time?</p>
               <p>Saunders. About 100 yards.</p>
               <p>Q Were they any time together?</p>
               <p>Saunders. They were together but a very little time.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe what they were doing?</p>
               <p>Saunders. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him before he came to her?</p>
               <p>Saunders. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any other but they two together?</p>
               <p>Saunders. There was the gentlewoman's daughter. After the man was gone she called to me and said that man has robbed me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the man when she called to you ?</p>
               <p>Saunders. Yes, he was in fight then.</p>
               <p>Q. How far might they be distant from each other at the time she called ?</p>
               <p>Saunders. About 60 yards.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure he was then in fight ?</p>
               <p>Saunders. I am sure he was. I ran after him about a mile and a half, and never lost sight of him till he was taken. I called out for assistance, and a soldier whose name is Hewit, ran and took him.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was he taken?</p>
               <p>Saunders. We took him between Canbury house and Newington green.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you alone when the gentlewoman call'd to you ?</p>
               <p>Saunders. No, my brother, a little boy, was with me.</p>
               <p>Q. How old is he?</p>
               <p>Saunders. He is about 10 years of age.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was you to the prisoner when he was taken?</p>
               <p>Saunders. I believe I was about 60 yards at the time. We then carried him to Newington town to the gentlewoman. Upon her seeing him, she said this is the man that frightned me, and said he had a pistol in his pocket. We searched him, and the took a pistol out of his pocket. Produced in court. There was no flint in it or charge, there was only a piece of paper put down the barrel.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say upon this ?</p>
               <p>Saunders. He said he did it for need. that he had got a wife and two children, and his wife way to lie down again, and that he had been about to get work and could get done.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he mention what his trade was?</p>
               <p>Saunders. He said he was a taylor.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure this is the person which you saw with the gentlewoman ?</p>
               <p>Saunders. I am sure he is.</p>
               <p>Q. What colour was his coat ?</p>
               <p>Saunders. He had a brown coat on.</p>
               <p>Q. What buttons?</p>
               <p>Saunders. Yellow buttons.</p>
               <p>Q. Was his hat cocked or not?</p>
               <p>Saunders. It was cocked all round, but when we took him he flapped it. I went with him to justice Fielding's, the prosecutrix was there. The justice asked him what he carried that pistol for, he said for fear any body should molest him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find any gunpowder or ball upon him?</p>
               <p>Saunders. I don't know that there was either.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutrix. Did you speak to this witness soon after you was robbed?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. As soon as I thought myself safe from the person that robbed me I called. This was one of the people at work in the field. I also saw more people coming.</p>
               <p>Q. What was this witness at work at?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. I saw some heaps of dung near him, I think he was spreading them about.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he come near you?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. No, he d id not, but he ran towards the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. At the time you called to him, did you see the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. No, I did not, but I pointed the way he was gone. I saw the man at work in the field a little before I was robbed, and while he was robbing me.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember his making use of that expression, of doing it for want, at the time he was brought back to you?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. To be sure he said something, but I was in such confusion, I can't upon my oath mention what words he said; I believe he made use of words to that effect.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175410230024"></xptr>Q. from prisoner. Did you never lose sight of me ?</p>
               <p>Saunders. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Did not you say you lost sight of the man to the soldier, or you had taken him sooner?</p>
               <p>Saunders. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Are the fields all open from the place the woman was, to the place where the prisoner was taken?</p>
               <p>Saunders. No, we took him in a lane.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541023-38-person257">
                  Richard 
                  Hewit 
               <interp inst="t17541023-38-person257" type="surname" value="Hewit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-person257" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-person257" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going from the Thatched-house, Islington, last Wednesday was se'nnight, between 2 and 3 o'clock towards Newington-green, by the river side I saw 3 men running, one was at some distance before the other two, they cried, stop him, stop him. I thought at first they had been only playing of tricks; when they came up almost to me, they told me that man had robbed two gentlewomen; then I pursued him, and caught him, and held him till Saunders came up; then I asked him where the gentlewomen were gone, he said to Newington, or Newington green. Then we took the prisoner to Mr. Carter's, and the gentlewoman came out to him into the yard, and said, this is the rogue that robbed me, and said he has a pistol in his pocket, without a flint in it. I searched his pocket, and found one without a flint in it, with a bit of paper put down the barrel, and no charge.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say?</p>
               <p>Hewit. He seemed to be very sorry, and said he did it out of want.</p>
               <p>Q. Did what?</p>
               <p>Hewit. Why, did the robbery.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you what trade he was?</p>
               <p>Hewit. He did, he said he was a taylor, and that he had been enquiring about for work at several places that day, and could not get any.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you search him for any thing else, besides the pistol?</p>
               <p>Hewit. No, we did not, I can't tell whether he had any money in his pocket or not,</p>
               <p>Q. What coloured clothes had he on?</p>
               <p>Hewit. He had a brownish coat, with yellow buttons, and his hat cock'd up all round. As I had hold of him in the yard he desired I'd let him go and speak to the gentlewoman, to try to get off. I went in with him, he told the gentlewoman he was sorry for what he had done, and he would do any thing that lay in his power to make her amends. She said she could not say any thing to him till the morrow. She was prodigiously frightned. He was taken away by the constable, and the next day carried before justice Fielding. The justice asked him how he came to carry pistols? he said, that was in his own defence, fearing any body should molest him.</p>
               <p>Q Did he say he was in debt?</p>
               <p>Hewit. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541023-38-person258">
                  John 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17541023-38-person258" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-person258" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-person258" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Wednesday was 7 night, betwixt two and three o'clock in the afternoon, I was going to Newington, and saw Saunders pursuing the prisoner; the prisoner had passed me. Saunders said he had robbed two ladies of some money, upon which I ran after him, and got before him to stop him; the soldier was just upon him, and laid hold of his collar. We took him to Newington, to the house where the gentlewoman was, she came out and said that was the man. I saw the pistol taken out of his pocket. The prisoner seemed very still a little time, after that he said he did it for want; that he had no work to do, and could get none, and was obliged to do it. He said he was a taylor. They sent for a constable and took him to New-prison, and the next day before justice Fielding, but I was not at the justice's the first time, I was on his second examination.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541023-38-person259">
                  Elisha 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17541023-38-person259" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-person259" type="given" value="Elisha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-person259" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am beadle of the parish, and had just been with a person to New-prison, as I met them bringing the prisoner there, which happened to be the same day he was taken. I said I had heard he had got 15 s. from the people he had robbed; upon which the prisoner said he had got but eleven. He pulled out eight shillings and sixpence, and a half crown, and said he had never a farthing when he came from home, and said, here is all I have got, and delivered it into the turnkey's hands. Then I asked him how he came by the pistol; he said he gave five shillings and six-pence for it in Holbourn; and confessed he took from the prosecutrix and her daughter eleven shillings.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutrix. Was your daughter robbed at the time?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. She was, of half a crown, and a six-pence. I am not certain how much money I had in my pocket, it was about 4 s. and the rest of my money was in six-pences. I swear rather under than over.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you believe you had in your pocket to the amount of 8 s. 6 d?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. Yes, my lord. I do believe I had.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he take all you had?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. By accident there was six-pence left behind.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175410230025"></xptr>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>On the 16th of Oct. about 9 o'clock in the morning. I set out from home to seek for work: I am a taylor; the first place I called at was at Mr. Eaton's at Islington, finding no work there I went on to Newington, and called at Mr. Dickson's, in Church-street : the next I called at was Mr. Myers's, in the same street : the next was at Mr. Griffith's, in Church street; not meeting with work there I went on to Tottenham High-Cross; from thence to Edmonton. Meeting with no work, I from thence returned back for home. Coming up Church-street again, keeping straight along by the river side, I saw two or three men come running towards me from out of the fields on my left hand; I did not know what their intent might be, I ran from them, and they pursued me: After that I met a man, and went on about two fields farther, and then I saw another man coming cross the fields towards Newington-green; that man crossed over one of the bridges on the right hand into the fields, I kept straight along. These men still pursued me. By that time I got cross another field they got pretty near me; they called, stop him, stop him. There were two men coming along, one of them was a soldier. I turned from the river to the left hand down a lane, and before I had got twenty yards down it, a man crossed the fields and jumped down from a bank upon me, and said, d - n you, I have catched you, you have robbed two gentlewomen in such a place. I, in running, was not able to speak, or say any thing in my own defence. The man went to strike at me, I held up my arm and desired him not to use him ill. Then the other came and said he is my prisoner, and catched me by my collar. Then Saunders came up to us, and the others inquired of me where the gentlewoman was to be found that had been robbed: Saunders said at Newington. Then they took me along the river side, going along Saunders said I lost sight of him a good while, or else I had not let him run so far as he did. When I came to Newington town, I untied my hat, because I would not be exposed to the public. Then they took me to several places to inquire for this gentlewoman, and at last they found her. Then she said, that is the man that robbed me, and he put a pistol to my breast and wanted my money. There were about 30 or 40 people about me. Somebody there produced a pistol directly, and said they took it out of my pocket. I never had any occasion to use any such thing. After that they charged the constable with me, and took me to New-Prison, and put me into a little room, where there were many irons hanging about, which was a great shock to me, that had done no ill in my life before. The turnkey said, if you have any money about you, I'd advise you to give it to me, and you shall have it safe again from my hands. I was much obliged to the man, thinking he would save the money for me. When the constable came the turnkey pulled the money out of his pocket, which I gave him, and said, young man, there is the 11 s. you gave me last night, and gave it to the constable. I was taken before justice Fielding, there the gentlewoman was examined concerning what had happened; she told him it was a man in a darkish coat that did the robbery, she did not swear to me.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541023-38-person260">
                  John 
                  Darby 
               <interp inst="t17541023-38-person260" type="surname" value="Darby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-person260" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-person260" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was an apprentice to me, and served above 6 years, during which time he behaved very well and careful in his business. He used to write for me, and take my accounts in general. I have trusted him with money several times, and goods to a great value.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is it since he left your service?</p>
               <p>Darby. It is between 5 and 6 years. He married my servant maid the time he was my apprentice, and had half a year to serve, upon which I gave him up his indentures. Since this I have often heard he behaved very well, and endeavoured to maintain his family.</p>
               <p>Q What has his character been of late?</p>
               <p>Darby. In general it was very good. He endeavoured to work when he could get it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541023-38-person261">
                  Jonathan 
                  Judson 
               <interp inst="t17541023-38-person261" type="surname" value="Judson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-person261" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-person261" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a woollen-draper. I knew the prisoner when he was an apprentice, he used to be sent to my shop often for goods; he behaved well, and was a very sober lad.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you known him of late?</p>
               <p>Judson. No, I have not; but I never heard any ill of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541023-38-person262">
                  William 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17541023-38-person262" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-person262" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-person262" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I believe I have known him about 10 years down to this time. I was foreman to his master where he was an apprentice, and have since employed him myself.</p>
               <p>Q. How lately?</p>
               <p>Thompson. Within this month, or thereabouts.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Thompson. He has a very good character. I never heard any thing to the contrary.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541023-38-person263">
                  John 
                  Priestman 
               <interp inst="t17541023-38-person263" type="surname" value="Priestman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-person263" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-person263" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about a year and a half. I employed him about 6 months regularly. He went from me a little above a year ago.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175410230026"></xptr>Q. Have you known any thing of him since?</p>
               <p>Priestman. I can't say I have heard much of him. As to the time he worked for me I employed him a good deal in writing, he kept my books; I believed him to be very honest in his principles; I had a very good character of him from the people where he lodged. I told him I could not wholly employ him to keep my accounts, but I heard of a person that wanted a clerk, and said I'd be bound for him as far as 50 l.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541023-38-person264">
                  John 
                  Dolphin 
               <interp inst="t17541023-38-person264" type="surname" value="Dolphin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-person264" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-person264" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him 12 years, he had ready furnished lodgings at my house about 2 years ago. He used to come home directly after he had done work, and had a very good character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541023-38-person265">
                  Jacob 
                  Lewin 
               <interp inst="t17541023-38-person265" type="surname" value="Lewin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-person265" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-person265" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have been very intimate with him these 5 or 6 years. He worked hard for his family, to bring them up decently, and always bore an excellent character. I have seen him at work within these six weeks.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541023-38-person266">
                  Thomas 
                  Griffice 
               <interp inst="t17541023-38-person266" type="surname" value="Griffice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-person266" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-person266" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Newington, and am a taylor. The morning this robbery was committed he was at my house to seek for work: when he found I could not employ him he leaned on my shop-board, and seemed very uneasy.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541023-38-person267">
                  George 
                  Myers 
               <interp inst="t17541023-38-person267" type="surname" value="Myers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-person267" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-person267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Stoke Newington, and am a taylor. I never saw the prisoner before he was taken, but my people told me he had been at my house that morning to seek for work.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541023-38-person268">
                  John 
                  Dickson 
               <interp inst="t17541023-38-person268" type="surname" value="Dickson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-person268" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-person268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was at my house the day the robbery was committed (at Newington) to ask for work, he had an answer from my wife and daughter, but I did not see him till after he was taken.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541023-38-person269">
                  Matthias 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17541023-38-person269" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-person269" type="given" value="Matthias"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a taylor, the prisoner served me in the capacity of a clerk, he came about the beginning of last Dec. and served me till the latter end of March. I believe, during the time he was with me, 400 l. went through his hands. I then did really believe him to be as honest a man as any. He had a great deal of liberty to have robbed me of a hundred pounds. There were very few weeks but he laid out 20 l. for me.</p>
               <p>Q. What family has he?</p>
               <p>Walker. He has a wife and 2 small children, and she is ready to lie down again.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17541023-38-verdict190" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-verdict190" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17541023-38-punish191" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17541023-38-punish191" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-38-defend253 t17541023-38-punish191"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
