<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560915-62">
               <interp inst="t17560915-62" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-62" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-62" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560915"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-62" type="date" value="17560915"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560915-62-off308-c358" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-62-defend477 t17560915-62-off308 t17560915-62-verdict311"></join>
         
               <p>396. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17560915-62-defend477" type="defendantName">
                  Esther, <rs id="t17560915-62-deflabel307" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-62-defend477 t17560915-62-deflabel307"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17560915-62-person478">
                        Michael 
                        Fury 
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person478" type="surname" value="Fury"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560915-62-person478" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560915-62-person478" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17560915-62-alias-6" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-62-defend477 t17560915-62-alias-6"></join>Hall</rs>, otherwise <rs id="t17560915-62-alias-7" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-62-defend477 t17560915-62-alias-7"></join>Morris</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-defend477" type="surname" value="Fury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-defend477" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-defend477" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , widow, was indicted for <rs id="t17560915-62-off308" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-off308" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-off308" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               that she in company with 
                     <persName id="t17560915-62-person479">
                        Michael 
                        Fury 
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person479" type="surname" value="Fury"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560915-62-person479" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560915-62-person479" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , did steal one stuff gown, three tablecloths, one bible, one linen shirt, one ironing cloth, one cloth coat, one cloth waistcoat, one velvet hood, one white pilgrim  one straw hat, three pieces of holland, one apron, and one hundred guineas, the goods and money of 
                     <persName id="t17560915-62-victim480" type="victimName">
                        Richard 
                        Lane 
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-victim480" type="surname" value="Lane"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560915-62-victim480" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560915-62-victim480" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-62-off308 t17560915-62-victim480"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , in his dwelling-house
            </rs>, <rs id="t17560915-62-cd309" type="crimeDate">July the 19th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-62-off308 t17560915-62-cd309"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>Richard-Lane. I live in <placeName id="t17560915-62-crimeloc310">Balsover Street, Marybone parish</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17560915-62-crimeloc310" type="placeName" value="Balsover Street, Marybone parish"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17560915-62-crimeloc310" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-62-off308 t17560915-62-crimeloc310"></join>. The prisoner lived with me. I took her in act of charity, till she could get a place to lodge in, and dispose of some of her things. On the 19th of July in the morning I went out, having given her the keys of my things. I left her and the child at home. I came home between twelve and one; and found the door last, and was told she was gone pack and package, with boxes and things. I got a gentleman's servant to go in at the sash, who opened the door for me. I found all the things ship'd and gone; a box, chest, and trunk from one pair of stairs. Then I went up another pair, and found the drawers had been opened, and things pull'd and mangled about. I missed a pair of stays of my wife's, and an old pair of the prisoner's left in their room.</p>
               <p>Q. What other goods did you miss?</p>
               <p>Lane. A piece of stuff to make a gown, and another piece to make a waistcoat; a silk embroider'd apron, two or three tablecloths, a bible, an ironing cloth, a cloth coat, a cloth waistcoat, a velvet hood, a velvet pilgrim, a scraw hat, a linen and cotton gown, a tea chest, and other things, and a hundred guineas from out of a cupboard below stairs; I saw the money in the morning before I went out. She knew I used to put it there. She took the little boy with her that I left in the house. He is about eight years old. It was his black coat she took, and put him on an old coat and hat. I advertised her and the little boy, with two guinea reward. After which I had word brought she was at Islington, and I found her and the little boy at the constable's house there, on the 23d of July (two gowns, an embroider'd apron, a printed piece, for a waistcoat, a qu bible, a waistcoat, an ironing cloth, five tablecloths, and two pocket aprons, (produced in court, and deposed to.) This waistcoat I had given the little boy, and he had it on when I went out that day. It is her child, but I have kept it a long time, ever since it was born.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to keep it?</p>
               <p>Lane. She was pleased to say it was mine.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had she been at your house?</p>
               <p>Lane. She was backwards and forwards for nine years.</p>
               <p>Q. Is your wife alive ?</p>
               <p>Lane. She has been dead about sixteen weeks. She died the 20th of May.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure these things were in the house that morning ?</p>
               <p>Lane. They were.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you counted the hundred guineas?</p>
               <p>Lane. I did it about a week before.</p>
               <p>Q. If there were such an intimacy between you as you speak of, did not you tell her there were a hundred guineas in that place?</p>
               <p>Lane. No, I did not. We were at variance a great while. I had kept her so long, that I was almost tired of hers. I had done this and the other for her, that I was almost suifeiced with her.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you leave in the house with her and the boy?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175609150039"></xptr>Lane. Nobody.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to charge 
               <persName id="t17560915-62-person481">
                  Michael 
                  Fury 
               <interp inst="t17560915-62-person481" type="surname" value="Fury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person481" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person481" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             with these things?</p>
               <p>Lane. Because I was informed he shew'd the coachman the way to the Bell-Inn, in Friday-Street, with the things.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she swear that was your child before a justice of the peace?</p>
               <p>Lane. Yes, she did.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did she lie in?</p>
               <p>Lane. In my house.</p>
               <p>Q. After the child was born, did you not provide a wet nurse's place for her, and say you was her uncle?</p>
               <p>Lane. Yes, I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you recommend her?</p>
               <p>Lane. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you did not give her the things mentioned in the indictment ?</p>
               <p>Lane. No, not I.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she at your house the time of your wife's illness?</p>
               <p>Lane. She was; but neither my wife nor I gave her a halfpenny worth of the things.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you give her the care and trust of your house ?</p>
               <p>Lane. She was in the care of it. I had no other person in the house to take care of it but she. I have had one maid and another maid, but she would not let them stay.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you give her the keys of all, after your wife's decease ?</p>
               <p>Lane. I gave her the key of nothing, except the tea chest.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you arrest her for a debt after she was taken up?</p>
               <p>Lane. Yes, I did; for meat, drink and lodging.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it for meat, drink and lodging for the child?</p>
               <p>Lane. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she not taken up for a felony?</p>
               <p>Lane. She was, and I charged her with it directly.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to take her to the bailiff's house after you had charged her with a felony?</p>
               <p>Lane. We did not know but she would let us have some of the goods.</p>
               <p>Q. When you went to Islington, did not you arrest her upon an action?</p>
               <p>Lane. Yes. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. After you found you could get no money of her, did not you go and get her taken into custody for a felony?</p>
               <p>Lane. Yes.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-62-person482">
                  John 
                  Jackson 
               <interp inst="t17560915-62-person482" type="surname" value="Jackson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person482" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person482" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a hackney-coachman. I was call'd from Brook-Street by a young man, to the corner of Holles-Street; there were the prisoner at the bar and a chairman, and I went and fetched some boxes and a trunk to the coach, and after they were in the coach, she and her child got in, and I carried them to the Bell in Friday Street by the young man's direction, and she paid me.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know that young man who directed you?</p>
               <p>Jackson. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-62-person483">
                  Isaac 
                  Welden 
               <interp inst="t17560915-62-person483" type="surname" value="Welden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person483" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person483" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was call'd as a porter from my stand, in Bond Street, and help'd to carry the boxes and chest to the coach; there was a woman and a boy. I never saw her before or since, this may be the woman for what I know.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-62-person484">
                  James 
                  Kelsey 
               <interp inst="t17560915-62-person484" type="surname" value="Kelsey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person484" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person484" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an apprentice to the trunk-maker, at the corner of St. Paul's Church Yard. A man whom I heard call'd by the name of 
               <persName id="t17560915-62-person485">
                  Michael 
                  Fury 
               <interp inst="t17560915-62-person485" type="surname" value="Fury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person485" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person485" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came to our shop and bought a trunk, and I went and carried it to the inn. There was he and the woman at the bar to the best of my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Kelsey. I believe it may be better than 2 months ago. The gentleman ask'd me if I had any thing that would take a lock of a painted chest, so I went and fetched a hammer and chissel, and took it off. The man said I must pack up the things, and the woman said, who should pack them up but myself; there were a great many things in the chest, such as cloaths, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-62-person486">
                  Walter 
                  Murrel 
               <interp inst="t17560915-62-person486" type="surname" value="Murrel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person486" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person486" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable at Islington, and took the prisoner at the Wagon and Horses there, by virtue of an advertisement, and 
               <persName id="t17560915-62-person487">
                  Mary 
                  Murphy 
               <interp inst="t17560915-62-person487" type="surname" value="Murphy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person487" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person487" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's information, on the 22d of last month. I asking her after the chest and things which were advertised she produced them, and I took them to my house. The next morning I waited on Mr. Lane, and he went to Mr. Powel, in Gray's-Inn-Lane, who arrested her, and took her out of my hands to his own house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-62-person488">
                  Mary 
                  Murphy 
               <interp inst="t17560915-62-person488" type="surname" value="Murphy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person488" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person488" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I carried the trunk and box for the prisoner; she brought them to my house at Islington.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-62-person489">
                  Joseph 
                  Bergery 
               <interp inst="t17560915-62-person489" type="surname" value="Bergery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person489" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person489" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am chamberlain at the Bell-Inn in Friday-Street. This coachman came to our inn with a woman and child, and some boxes, but I don't know the woman.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I took nothing but what was my own; he beat me three days running, and I was in danger of my life.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175609150040"></xptr>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-62-person490">
                  Mary 
                  Dimment 
               <interp inst="t17560915-62-person490" type="surname" value="Dimment"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person490" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person490" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who had known her three or four years, 
               <persName id="t17560915-62-person491">
                  Ann 
                  Woodstock 
               <interp inst="t17560915-62-person491" type="surname" value="Woodstock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person491" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person491" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             seven, 
               <persName id="t17560915-62-person492">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Clarkson 
               <interp inst="t17560915-62-person492" type="surname" value="Clarkson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person492" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person492" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             seven, 
               <persName id="t17560915-62-person493">
                  Thomas 
                  Shelbourn 
               <interp inst="t17560915-62-person493" type="surname" value="Shelbourn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person493" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person493" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             three or four, and 
               <persName id="t17560915-62-person494">
                  Robert 
                  Scot 
               <interp inst="t17560915-62-person494" type="surname" value="Scot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person494" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-person494" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             about one year, all gave her a good character.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17560915-62-verdict311" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560915-62-verdict311" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
