<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570914-37">
               <interp inst="t17570914-37" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-37" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-37" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570914"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-37" type="date" value="17570914"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570914-37-off248-c369" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-37-defend450 t17570914-37-off248 t17570914-37-verdict251"></join>
         
               <p>345. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17570914-37-defend450" type="defendantName">
                     Catherine 
                     Nowland 
                  <interp inst="t17570914-37-defend450" type="surname" value="Nowland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-37-defend450" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-37-defend450" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17570914-37-deflabel247" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-37-defend450 t17570914-37-deflabel247"></join>, was indicted for that <rs id="t17570914-37-off248" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570914-37-off248" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-37-off248" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               she, on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17570914-37-victim452" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Trevor 
                        <interp inst="t17570914-37-victim452" type="surname" value="Trevor"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570914-37-victim452" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570914-37-victim452" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-37-off248 t17570914-37-victim452"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and taking from his person one 36 s. piece, and 8 s. 6 d. in money numbered, his property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17570914-37-cd249" type="crimeDate">August 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-37-off248 t17570914-37-cd249"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-37-person453">
                  Thomas 
                  Trevor 
               <interp inst="t17570914-37-person453" type="surname" value="Trevor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-37-person453" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-37-person453" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to a gentleman in Crown Court, Westminster. On Wednesday the 24th of August I was going to the Bolt and Tun in Fleet-street, to send a 36 s. piece by the coachman to my mother in the country; and going down <placeName id="t17570914-37-crimeloc250">Wych street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17570914-37-crimeloc250" type="placeName" value="Wych street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17570914-37-crimeloc250" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-37-off248 t17570914-37-crimeloc250"></join> I met a man in the middle of the street, I run against him, he d - n'd my eyes, and said can't you see your way.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the night was it?</p>
               <p>Trevor. The clock at the New Church in the Strand had just struck eleven. He gave me a push as I past him, and gave a sort of a hem; then up came a man and woman together.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they follow or meet you?</p>
               <p>Trevor. They met me, the man stop'd me and bid me stand. She took hold of my collar, it was the prisoner at the bar. I push'd my fist to her breast to get rid of her. She had on a long cardinal, there was a lamp just by. She said d - n his eyes, knock his brains out, he has struck me on the breast. Then I received three blows with a great stick, one on my head, another on my shoulder, and the other on the side of my neck.</p>
               <p>Q. Who gave you them?</p>
               <p>Trevor. The man that stood fronting me. He was a well set man in a light colour'd coat; the other man came behind me, and held me fast by my two arms, I cannot describe him; he swore if I made any resistance he'd knock my brains out. I had a pair of leather breeches on, and my money was in the right hand pocket; the prisoner put her hand in my pocket, and took out a 36 s. piece, half a crown, and 6 s. in silver; they rifled every pocket, then spoke broad Irish for her to go off.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you an Irishman?</p>
               <p>Trevor. No.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did they keep you there?</p>
               <p>Trevor. About three or four minutes. They swore if I made any resistance, or call'd out, or followed them, they'd knock my brains out, so I return'd back again; there was never a watchman came near me. The next day I went to send a letter down to my mother, to let her know what had happened, and that I could not send the money down as I intended. Going along the Butcher-Row about nine at night, I saw the woman at the bar coming along with the same hat and cardinal on, and a man on the other side of the way, they were falling out. She said she had given him the 36 s. piece, which she had of a man the night before, and had got no more money to give him. I followed her till she came to the cook's shop, I got along side her and laid hold of her hat, and look'd in her face. She d - n'd my eyes, and ask'd<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175709140044"></xptr> me what business I had to meddle with her hat; the man, seeing me, ran away. I took hold of the woman, and carried her to justice Fielding.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was you to them when you heard her say those words?</p>
               <p>Trevor. I was walking after them some time before she said the words.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she speak very loud ?</p>
               <p>Trevor. No, not very loud. They were quarreling and d - ning one another. They spoke so loud that people that took any notice might have heard them.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What part of Wych Street;</p>
               <p>Trevor. About the middle of the street.</p>
               <p>Q. How long before the woman came up was it that you ran against the man?</p>
               <p>Trevor. It was about a minute before that.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was you got from the place ?</p>
               <p>Trevor. I was got about ten yards nearer Temple Bar.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you meet somebody in the street?</p>
               <p>Trevor. No, I did not meet one man, nor watchman in the street.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the man lay hold of you before the woman came up?</p>
               <p>Trevor. He did. He laid hold on the breast of my coat, and stood before me.</p>
               <p>Q. How near to a lamp was you?</p>
               <p>Trevor. It was within three or four yards of a lamp, it was before me. The man was on the right side of me, and the woman on the left. She had a red cardinal and muffatees, and a black hat flap'd. The light of the lamp came clear between them both. I look'd her very hard in the face, she stood upright, and held up her face.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did the man hold you?</p>
               <p>Trevor. I believe for the value of five minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. How long were they in committing the robbery ?</p>
               <p>Trevor. I believe they were about ten minutes committing it and keeping me there.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there no doors open?</p>
               <p>Trevor. No, there were not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you call out when they said they'd knock your brains out?</p>
               <p>Trevor. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you go to a justice of the peace to make information?</p>
               <p>Trevor. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the shops open at the time you took the prisoner ?</p>
               <p>Trevor. They were all open. She was very much in liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. What was it you heard them say?</p>
               <p>Trevor. When he ask'd her for money she d - n'd him, and said, she gave him the six and thirty piece she took the night before.</p>
               <p>Q. How was she dress'd ?</p>
               <p>Trevor. She was in the same dress as before, the same muffatees, cardinal, hat, and no stays on.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know she had no stays on when you was rob'd.</p>
               <p>Trevor. Because I struck her on the breast, and the cardinal flew back, and all her breast was open.</p>
               <p>Q. Which hand did you strike her with?</p>
               <p>Trevor. With my right hand, but had not much use of my hand, being held behind.</p>
               <p>Q. Where abouts did you strike her?</p>
               <p>Trevor. A little above her breasts. She had a little white handkerchief that flew on one side.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you get her to justice Fielding's?</p>
               <p>Trevor. In a coach, as soon as I had taken her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell the justice the same as now?</p>
               <p>Trevor. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether since her being committed you have not had conversation with any body, about what reward you shall get?</p>
               <p>Trevor. No, I have not. I want no reward.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I never saw that man till last Thursday was three weeks. He met me just by Clare Court, Clare Market; there was a little boy with me, we were going to the market. He stop'd me, and wanted to kiss me, and put his hands under my cloaths. I bid him get away, and said I was not for his purpose. Then a parcel of little boys got about me, and mob'd me. Then he told the people I had rob'd him. He got me into Bow-street, and after that to the Round-house, and I charged him as I was coming cross Covent Garden. I asked what sort of a man was my prosecutor, they shew'd me this man, and said he charg'd me with robbing him of a 36 s. piece, and half a crown. I wanted to send home for the people that were with me the night before, but they would not grant it.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-37-person454">
                  John 
                  Hussey 
               <interp inst="t17570914-37-person454" type="surname" value="Hussey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-37-person454" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-37-person454" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 24th of August last, to the best of my knowledge, the prisoner call'd upon me at Mr. Wilson's chambers, in Lincoln's Inn. She was with me about three or four in the afternoon,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175709140045"></xptr> she dined with me there, and told me she was going to the sign of the Fox and Goose in Drury Lane, and desir'd I would meet her there about nine or ten o'clock. I went there about half an hour after nine, and she was there at the time.</p>
               <p>Q. Who keeps that house?</p>
               <p>Hussey. One Carlisle. I staid there with her till twelve o'clock. She was in company with me all the time in that house. I am sure she was not out of the house ten minutes together in that time.</p>
               <p>Q. What makes you certain of the day?</p>
               <p>Hussey. What makes me certain of it is this, because the day following I was told she was taken up the day before.</p>
               <p>Q. What day of the week was it that you heard it?</p>
               <p>Hussey. To the best of my knowledge it was on a Saturday.</p>
               <p>Q. What day of the month ?</p>
               <p>Hussey. It might be about the 26th day of the month.</p>
               <p>Court. That was after she was committed.</p>
               <p>Hussey. I am not sure of the day of the month. I minuted down the time, fearing I should be call'd upon. I was told that an accident had happen'd to Mrs. Newland, being charg'd picking a man's pocket of a piece of gold and half a crown.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her general character?</p>
               <p>Hussey. I never heard any thing that was had of her, as to being guilty of theft or any thing of that kind.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Hussey. I live at Mr. Wilson, No. 16 near the pump; I am his clerk.</p>
               <p>Q. Which Wilson?</p>
               <p>Hussey. Mr. William Wilson, an eminent attorney.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is your master now ?</p>
               <p>Hussey. He is in Yorkshire.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you bring women to dine in your chambers ?</p>
               <p>Hussey. I am to tell the truth, and it is true, it happened so, I had a great many briefs to draw up then.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you been clerk to Mr. Wilson?</p>
               <p>Hussey. About four.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-37-person455">
                  Michael 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17570914-37-person455" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-37-person455" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-37-person455" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner fourteen.</p>
               <p>Q. What character ?</p>
               <p>Brown. thing laid to her charge to be very honest as to any thing.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570914-37-verdict251" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570914-37-verdict251" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
