<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17500228-63">
               <interp inst="t17500228-63" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500228-63" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500228-63" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17500228"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500228-63" type="date" value="17500228"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500228-63-off270-c324" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500228-63-defend459 t17500228-63-off270 t17500228-63-verdict272"></join>
         
               <p>264. 
               
                  <persName id="t17500228-63-defend459" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Thorp 
                  <interp inst="t17500228-63-defend459" type="surname" value="Thorp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500228-63-defend459" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500228-63-defend459" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for that <rs id="t17500228-63-off270" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500228-63-off270" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500228-63-off270" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he in a certain field, or open place, near the king's highway, upon 
                     
                        <persName id="t17500228-63-victim461" type="victimName">
                           Daniel 
                           Brown 
                        <interp inst="t17500228-63-victim461" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500228-63-victim461" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500228-63-victim461" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500228-63-off270 t17500228-63-victim461"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear, and danger of his life, one silver watch, value 40 s. from his person did steal, take, and carry away
            </rs>, <rs id="t17500228-63-cd271" type="crimeDate">Nov. 21, 1748</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500228-63-off270 t17500228-63-cd271"></join>.</p>


               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500228-63-person462">
                  Daniel 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17500228-63-person462" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500228-63-person462" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500228-63-person462" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Nov. 21, 1748. I had been out towards Holloway a shooting, it being a hard frost; returning home about a quarter of an hour after six; I then lived in Cold-Bath-Fields, it<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175002280018"></xptr> being a very moon-light night, I saw three men in the next field to the Cold Bath, between Cold Bath and Merlin's Cave, as great a distance from me as about the length of the Old Bailey, the prisoner was one of them. When they came along side me, the prisoner came out from the rest, and said D - n you, stand; and d - n your eyes if you move, I'll blow your brains out. He took out my silver watch, and what silver I had, about seven or eight shillings. The other men never touched me. He put his hand into my other pocket, and took out some half-pence, and other trifling things, and returned them me again. I was told, by describing him, such a man had been seen at the Ship; I think the landlord's name was Glover in Chick-lane. I went there the next day with an acquaintance, when the prisoner and about four or five men came in about four in the afternoon. The prisoner sat down next to me; I was very much surprized, he swore and cursed in a terrible manner. They got shaking halfpence in a hat, and a quarrel arose, whether it was pretended I cannot say. The prisoner bad me get up and second him; I told him I was not for fighting. Then there were more of them came in, about 10 or 12 in all. I staid there about half an hour; some pretended to be going home, some one way and some another, and they all dispersed. I asked the landlord who this man was, and he begged of me not to speak till his wife was gone out, saying she was going to market. After that he told me his name was 
               <persName id="t17500228-63-person463">
                  John 
                  Thorp 
               <interp inst="t17500228-63-person463" type="surname" value="Thorp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500228-63-person463" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500228-63-person463" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , otherwise Donecey. After that I took several people with me at several times, but the landlord told me they had absconded his house ever since. In last January I saw the prisoner's name mentioned as apprehended at St. Alban's; I had some business at my father's at Barnet, so I went to St. Alban's goal, and upon the first sight I knew the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500228-63-verdict272" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500228-63-verdict272" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17500228-63-punish273" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500228-63-punish273" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500228-63-defend459 t17500228-63-punish273"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
