<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17580113-24">
               <interp inst="t17580113-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580113-24" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580113-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580113"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580113-24" type="date" value="17580113"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580113-24-off145-c222" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-24-defend265 t17580113-24-off145 t17580113-24-verdict150"></join>
         
               <p>85. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17580113-24-defend265" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Bradley 
                  <interp inst="t17580113-24-defend265" type="surname" value="Bradley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-24-defend265" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-24-defend265" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17580113-24-off145" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580113-24-off145" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-24-off145" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing ten half guineas
            </rs>, the money of 
               
                  <persName id="t17580113-24-victim267" type="victimName">
                     James 
                     Malows 
                  <interp inst="t17580113-24-victim267" type="surname" value="Malows"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-24-victim267" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-24-victim267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-24-off145 t17580113-24-victim267"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17580113-24-cd146" type="crimeDate">December 25</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-24-off145 t17580113-24-cd146"></join>. +</p>
               <p>Mr. Wilkerson. I am foreman to Mr. Malows, <rs id="t17580113-24-viclabel147" type="occupation">a mason</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-24-victim267 t17580113-24-viclabel147"></join>, in St. James's. On the Saturday night, being Christmas Eve, I paid the workmen, in King-Street, at the Blue Boar's Head.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Wilkerson. He was one of our workmen, and I paid him there with the rest. When I had paid them I had sixteen half guineas left. I had three or four half crowns, and some halfpence, which I put in a bag to the half guineas, and took them home that night.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Wilkerson. I live in the same street where Mr. Malows does. On the Sunday morning I took them down to <placeName id="t17580113-24-crimeloc148">Westminster</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17580113-24-crimeloc148" type="placeName" value="Westminster"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17580113-24-crimeloc148" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-24-off145 t17580113-24-crimeloc148"></join>, and lock'd them up there in a desk in the compting-house, in <placeName id="t17580113-24-crimeloc149">Channel-Row</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17580113-24-crimeloc149" type="placeName" value="Channel-Row"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17580113-24-crimeloc149" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-24-off145 t17580113-24-crimeloc149"></join>, and saw all was safe. On the Tuesday morning I was coming down, when one of our men met me, and told me the compting house had been broke open. When I came there I found the desk open, and that there were ten half guineas missing out of the bag. 
               <persName id="t17580113-24-person268">
                  William 
                  Atkins 
               <interp inst="t17580113-24-person268" type="surname" value="Atkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-24-person268" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-24-person268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             having some suspicion of the prisoner, he went over the water to inquire after him.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon what was his suspicion grounded?</p>
               <p>Wilkerson. Because he had got some new shoes and stockings, and had the morning before borrowed six-pence of him.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-24-person269">
                  William 
                  Atkins 
               <interp inst="t17580113-24-person269" type="surname" value="Atkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-24-person269" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-24-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a workman belonging to Mr. Malows. I went to work on the Tuesday after Christmas Day, about six, went to breakfast at eight, and then heard that the compting-house was broke open. I found a tool that the compting-house window was broke open with. ( Producing a stone mason's chissel) This is it; it lay between two Portland stones near the window.</p>

               <p>Q. How was it broke?</p>
               <p>Atkins. There was a board nailed up, and a piece of a saw plate, that was worn out, over it; that plate was taken off, and the board opened.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know who that chissel belongs to?</p>
               <p>Atkins. I do. I went and ask'd the men in the shop whose tool it was. They said it was Bradley's, who came that morning to work about nine o'clock. I shew'd him the tool, and said to him, is this your tool? He said, yes. I told him it had a hand in breaking my master's compting house open.</p>
               <p>Q. What answer did he make?</p>
               <p>Atkins. He said he wished it might be found out.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-24-person270">
                  William 
                  Weatherstone 
               <interp inst="t17580113-24-person270" type="surname" value="Weatherstone"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-24-person270" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-24-person270" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Crown alehouse, at the foot of Westminster-Bridge, on the Surry side. On Monday the 26th of December last, betwixt the hours of ten and eleven, the prisoner came into my house, and call'd for a pint of beer. He put his hand into his pocket and pull'd out about eight or ten half guineas. I asked him how he came to carry so much money in his pocket ?<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175801130028"></xptr> He said, as he was coming over Westminster-Bridge he kick'd something before him (which was in a bit of paper.) He pick'd it up, and it was these half guineas. As such money is useful to me to give change for larger gold, which I do every Saturday. in order for the payment of the men that work in Mr. Morris's yard, I gave him four guineas for eight of them. He said the same when he came before the justice.</p>
               <p>Q. to Wilkerson. Was all the money taken that was put in the desk?</p>
               <p>Wilkerson. There were 50 l. in all, in the compting-house, but not in the same drawer; this lay by itself: there was nothing missing but these half guineas.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner ever in the compting-house?</p>
               <p>Wilkerson. No; but I have seen him come and make water by it.</p>
               <p>Q. How near the compting-house did he use to work?</p>
               <p>Wilkerson. About 100 yards distance.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had he work'd with you?</p>
               <p>Wilkerson. About three months.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you find the men tools, or do they find them themselves?</p>
               <p>Wilkerson. They find their own tools themselves, and they have their own marks upon them.</p>
               <p>Q. What mark has this chissel ?</p>
               <p>Wilkerson. There is a mark so as to know it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>Going over Westminster-Bridge that Monday night I saw a piece of paper, and kicked it before me; I took it up, and in it I found these half guineas. I went into Mr. Weatherstone's house, and called for a pint of beer, who seeing the money in my hand, ask'd me how I came by it. I told him I found it. He asked me to let him have some for guineas, because Mr. Morris's men were paid at his house every Saturday, and he was troubled sometimes to get money for change.</p>
               <p>Q. to Weatherstone. Did he pull out the money loose, or was it in any thing?</p>
               <p>Weatherstone. They were all loose.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-24-person271">
                  John 
                  Breenhaw 
               <interp inst="t17580113-24-person271" type="surname" value="Breenhaw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-24-person271" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-24-person271" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a carpenter and joiner, and have known the prisoner almost twenty years; I knew him when he was an apprentice in Derbyshire: he is a stone-mason.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has he been in London?</p>
               <p>Breenhaw. I can't tell.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Breenhaw. I always heard he was an honest young man, and he served his time duly and truly.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you been in London?</p>
               <p>Breenhaw. I have been in London above twelve months.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you live in London now?</p>
               <p>Breenhaw. I saw him frequently last year.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you related to him?</p>
               <p>Breenhaw. No, I am not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-24-person272">
                  John 
                  Breenhaw 
               <interp inst="t17580113-24-person272" type="surname" value="Breenhaw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-24-person272" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-24-person272" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , junior. I have known this man sixteen years perfectly well; I knew him in Derbyshire. He came out of the country nine or ten years ago, and I have known him in London all the time, except about six months when he was in the country. I have work'd with him at several gentlemen's houses.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>Breenhaw. I am a cabinet-maker and joiner.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you work with him in London, or in the country?</p>
               <p>Breenhaw. In the country.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Breenhaw. That of a very honest, industrious, sober man; I never heard any body give him a bad character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-24-person273">
                  Francis 
                  Soutard 
               <interp inst="t17580113-24-person273" type="surname" value="Soutard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-24-person273" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-24-person273" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner seventeen or eighteen years.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Soutard. I live at Kensington, and am a gardener. I knew him in Derbyshire when he was apprentice to one 
               <persName id="t17580113-24-person274">
                  Henry 
                  Stewardson 
               <interp inst="t17580113-24-person274" type="surname" value="Stewardson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-24-person274" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-24-person274" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Soutard. He always had as good a character as any young man in all the country.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17580113-24-verdict150" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580113-24-verdict150" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
