<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560225-40">
               <interp inst="t17560225-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560225-40" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560225-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560225"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560225-40" type="date" value="17560225"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560225-40-off228-c300" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-40-defend375 t17560225-40-off228 t17560225-40-verdict230"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560225-40-off228-c301" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-40-defend376 t17560225-40-off228 t17560225-40-verdict230"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560225-40-off228-c302" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-40-defend378 t17560225-40-off228 t17560225-40-verdict230"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560225-40-off228-c303" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-40-defend379 t17560225-40-off228 t17560225-40-verdict230"></join>
         
               <p>152, 153, 154, 155. (L) 
               <persName id="t17560225-40-defend375" type="defendantName">
                  Mary 
                  Mac Cullen 
               <interp inst="t17560225-40-defend375" type="surname" value="Mac Cullen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-40-defend375" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-40-defend375" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . <rs id="t17560225-40-deflabel226" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-40-defend375 t17560225-40-deflabel226"></join>. 
               <persName id="t17560225-40-defend376" type="defendantName">
                  Ruth 
                  Skelton 
               <interp inst="t17560225-40-defend376" type="surname" value="Skelton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-40-defend376" type="given" value="Ruth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-40-defend376" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , 
               
                  <persName id="t17560225-40-defend378" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Robertson 
                  <interp inst="t17560225-40-defend378" type="surname" value="Robertson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-40-defend378" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-40-defend378" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               <persName id="t17560225-40-defend379" type="defendantName">
                  Catherine 
                  Hughes 
               <interp inst="t17560225-40-defend379" type="surname" value="Hughes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-40-defend379" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-40-defend379" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , <rs id="t17560225-40-deflabel227" type="occupation">spinsters</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-40-defend376 t17560225-40-deflabel227"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-40-defend378 t17560225-40-deflabel227"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-40-defend379 t17560225-40-deflabel227"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17560225-40-off228" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560225-40-off228" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-40-off228" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch, value 3 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17560225-40-victim381" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Parnhill 
                        <interp inst="t17560225-40-victim381" type="surname" value="Parnhill"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560225-40-victim381" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560225-40-victim381" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-40-off228 t17560225-40-victim381"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17560225-40-cd229" type="crimeDate">February 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-40-off228 t17560225-40-cd229"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-40-person382">
                  John 
                  Parnhill 
               <interp inst="t17560225-40-person382" type="surname" value="Parnhill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-40-person382" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-40-person382" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Two of the prisoners at the bar pick'd me up in Holbourn last Monday about four o'clock, at the bottom of the hill.</p>
               <p>Q. Which two were they?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. 
               <persName id="t17560225-40-person383">
                  Ruth 
                  Skelton 
               <interp inst="t17560225-40-person383" type="surname" value="Skelton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-40-person383" type="given" value="Ruth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-40-person383" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17560225-40-person384">
                  Catherine 
                  Hughes 
               <interp inst="t17560225-40-person384" type="surname" value="Hughes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-40-person384" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-40-person384" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , they asked me to give them some beer. We went to the Red-Lion in Shoe-lane, where we had 3 or 4 pints of egg hot.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you call egg hot ?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. It is gin, ale and eggs.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you stay there?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. Till about 7 o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. I was a little in liquor when I went in there.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you go from thence?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. After that we went to Cheapside; there they call'd a coach; we got in it, and they order'd the coachman to drive to the Magpye, in Whitechapel.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you drink there?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. We did. We had three pots of porter there; and staid I believe about an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you go when you left that place?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. They order'd the coachman to go to the Brown-Bear, in East-Smithfield. There we had some pork steaks and beer.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not you fuddled by this time?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. No, but I was a little merry. Then the other two prisoners join'd us company; from thence we all five agreed to go to the Red-Lion, in Bishopsgate-street. After we came there, we had some beer; and after that some mull'd wine; and staid drinking till about twelve at night. Then they began to make a quarreling in the house. The woman of the house then said get you out all together; I don't like you; you shall not lie here; get about your business. Then they all four got into the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175602250032"></xptr> coach; and I said to the coachman, I'll give you a shilling to carry them home, or where they have a mind to go; and I said I'd stay there and lay by myself all night. Then they said, come, my dear, or some such words, come into the coach with us. So by their persuasions I did get into the coach. I had my watch in my pocket then.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know you had it?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. I took particular notice, and put the string within side my breeches.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not you pretty much fuddled by this time ?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. No, I was not; I was pretty middling. I had not been in the coach above five minutes, when my watch was gone.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you feel it go?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. I did not miss it immediately.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to miss it?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. The coachman said he would have his money before-hand; and came down from off the box to me for 2 s. This was after I had been in the coach about five minutes. I went to put my hand to my pocket, and missed my watch.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was he going to drive to?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. I don't know that; God knows. I missed my watch. I said I am rob'd, I am rob'd; the watchman came immediately up, and we carried them to the watch-house, and from thence we went all five to the compter; the next morning we went to Guildhall before Mr. alderman Cockayne, who committed them all to Newgate, and bound me over to prosecute.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you your watch again ?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. No, never.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the women search'd?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. No, they were not.</p>
               <p>Q. Which of them sat nearest you in the coach?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. I can't tell, indeed.</p>
               <p>Q. Can't you tell which sat nearest to you?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. They were all four together.</p>
               <p>Court. But you must sit next to one of them.</p>
               <p>Parnhill. My Lord, I got in the middle of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell which took the watch?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. It was gone amongst them.</p>
               <p>Skelton. You have known me fourteen years. You know when you came out of the Red-Lion, you insisted upon getting into the coach, but the coachman would not let you, and then you went to fighting.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. I am an ironmonger and chapman.</p>
               <p>Skelton. That is, he cries about the street to buy old iron and lead.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know all the four prisoners?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. I do, I know them by sight.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known them ?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. God bless you, I don't know how long I have known them. I have seen them go up and down the streets to buy old cloaths.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever been in their company before ?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. I have with two of them, drinking sometimes.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you acquainted with any of them before?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. No. What do you mean by acquainted? I don't understand that. I have been drinking with them.</p>
               <p>Q. With how many have you been drinking?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. With the little one and the great one.</p>
               <p>Court. Name their names?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. That is, Skelton and Hughes.</p>
               <p>Q. How many times might you have drank with them?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. I can't say, several times.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the One-Tun, in Field-Lane?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you met with 
               <persName id="t17560225-40-person385">
                  Ruth 
                  Skelton 
               <interp inst="t17560225-40-person385" type="surname" value="Skelton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-40-person385" type="given" value="Ruth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-40-person385" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17560225-40-person386">
                  Catharine 
                  Hughes 
               <interp inst="t17560225-40-person386" type="surname" value="Hughes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-40-person386" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-40-person386" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in the One -Tun, or in the street?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. They were in the street; I came out, and they ask'd me to give them some beer; then I said we will go to the Red-Lion, in Shoe-Lane.</p>
               <p>Q. Had they been at the One-Tun with you?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. No, they had not.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you drink at the One-Tun ?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. Only some porter with my sister.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you go to the 
               <persName id="t17560225-40-person387">
                  Ben 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17560225-40-person387" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-40-person387" type="given" value="Ben"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-40-person387" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's head?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. That I can't remember now.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you go to the Shepherd and Dog in Whitechapel?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you drink in all these places where you went?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. Yes, I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you, or did you not pull your cloaths off to fight the coachman?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. Yes, I did, at the Red-Lion door.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you not a tustle together ?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. No, we had not indeed.</p>
               <p>Q. How long before you miss'd your watch, did you see it ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175602250033"></xptr>Parnhill. I saw it about five minutes before.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure of that ?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. I pull'd it out to see what hour it was, at the coach door; and put it in my fob again.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this after you had strip'd to fight?</p>
               <p>Parnhill. It was.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-40-person388">
                  Francis 
                  Yates 
               <interp inst="t17560225-40-person388" type="surname" value="Yates"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-40-person388" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-40-person388" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had just been home with my coach; and calling at the Red-Lion in Bishopsgate-Street, saw this man, and the four women at the bar, at the Red-Lion door. I believe they had a bottle of mull'd whis; and staid there the value of an hour. The prosecutor changed a guinea to pay for it; he took his watch out at the same time he took the guinea out, to see what a clock it was. He gave the coachman a shilling for bringing them there. Three of these women agreed to lie by themselves in one bed; and to the least of the women, which is Skelton, he gave a shilling to lie with him.</p>
               <p>Q. What is this Red-Lion?</p>
               <p>Yates. It is an inn.</p>
               <p>Q. Do they let such people lay together there?</p>
               <p>Yates. I can't say, but there may be such people lie there. After this they began to make words, and the gentlewoman said neither of them should lie there, and turn'd them out. Then the man gave the coachman a shilling to drive the women home somewhere. The coachman said he'd have 2 s. The man went to get into the coach; the coachman said he should pay first; he said he would not pay first, and pull'd off his hat and wig to fight. I knowing the coachman, said to him, don't hit him, for he is fuddled; so he did not. Then he put on his hat and wig again. Then the women call'd him to come into the coach, and said come my dear, and call'd him by his name. One of them said to him, have you got your watch and your handkerchief? I said to the watchman, let us see whether the man has got his watch, or not; he came with his light, and I saw the prosecutor pull his watch out.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the watch?</p>
               <p>Yates. I did, and saw him pull out his silk handkerchief from his right-hand pocket; after they had much intreated him, he got into the coach; but he had not been in the coach above four minutes, before the coachman would have his money; he went to put his hand in his pocket, and could not find his watch; he said it was gone.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the watch afterwards ?</p>

               <p>Yates. No, I never saw it after this. I can't tell who had it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not the prosecutor very much fuddled ?</p>
               <p>Yates. The man was not in a drunken condition, but he was a little in liquor.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he accuse any of these four women with having his watch?</p>
               <p>Yates. He did none in particular; he said they had it betwixt them. Then he came out of the coach, and charged the watch with them.</p>
               <p>Q. Were any of them search'd?</p>
               <p>Yates. No, none of them; tho' one of the good women did pull her gown off.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-40-person389">
                  John 
                  Freeman 
               <interp inst="t17560225-40-person389" type="surname" value="Freeman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-40-person389" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-40-person389" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watchman at the end of Widegate-Alley. I heard a great noise at half an hour after 12 o'clock. I went to the Red Lion door, and there were the prisoners and prosecutor.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the prosecutor's watch?</p>
               <p>Freeman. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the night was it when you saw it?</p>
               <p>Freeman. At almost one o'clock, it was just before he got into the coach. The four women were in the coach, and said to the man, my dear, have you got your silk handkerchief? He put his hand in his coat-pocket and pull'd it out, so likewise he did his watch, and put it into his sobb, and turn'd the ribband withinside his breeches, and stept into the coach; and he had not been there five minutes before he came out, and said he had been rob'd, and gave me charge of the four prisoners.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the watch after that ?</p>
               <p>Freeman. No, I never saw it since/.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the women search'd?</p>
               <p>Freeman. No, one of them offer'd to be search'd, but the others said, nobody should search them.</p>
               <p>M'Cullen's defence.</p>
               <p>I am as innocent as the child unborn.</p>
               <p>Skelton's defence.</p>
               <p>I never saw the watch.</p>
               <p>Robertson's defence.</p>
               <p>I can have a hundred people to my character. This woman ( putting her hand on Skelton ) lay with the old rogue all night in the Compter.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175602250034"></xptr>Hughes's defence.</p>
               <p>I never saw the watch.</p>
               <p>All four <rs id="t17560225-40-verdict230" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560225-40-verdict230" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
