<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570713-29">
               <interp inst="t17570713-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570713-29" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570713-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570713"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570713-29" type="date" value="17570713"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570713-29-off136-c217" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570713-29-defend267 t17570713-29-off136 t17570713-29-verdict139"></join>
         
               <p>275. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17570713-29-defend267" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Wales 
                  <interp inst="t17570713-29-defend267" type="surname" value="Wales"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-29-defend267" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-29-defend267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17570713-29-off136" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570713-29-off136" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-29-off136" type="offenceSubcategory" value="sodomy"></interp>
               that he being moved by the instigation of the devil, not regarding the order of nature, on the <rs id="t17570713-29-cd137" type="crimeDate">24th of April</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570713-29-off136 t17570713-29-cd137"></join>, 1757, with force and arms, in the parish of Fulham, in Middlesex, on a certain beast, call'd a mare, then and there being, wickedly and feloniously did lay his hands, and did carnally know<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175707130025"></xptr> and that detestable crime call'd buggery did commit and perpetrate
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570713-29-person268">
                  Peter 
                  Garry 
               <interp inst="t17570713-29-person268" type="surname" value="Garry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-29-person268" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-29-person268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 24th of April last I rode on my mare to Parsons Green.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Garry. I live in Long-Acre. I expected to meet a friend or two from London at <placeName id="t17570713-29-crimeloc138">Parsons-Green</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17570713-29-crimeloc138" type="placeName" value="Parsons-Green"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17570713-29-crimeloc138" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570713-29-off136 t17570713-29-crimeloc138"></join>, but they not being come when I got there, I put up at the Peterborough-Arms, facing Peterborough House, then put my mare into the stable, and order'd her bitt to be taken out of her mouth, and her girth slack'd, and that she should have some hay. Then I left the stable, and went into the house, and call'd for a bottle of Yorkshire ale and a paper of tobacco, to enjoy myself till my friends came.</p>
               <p>Q. Had they appointed to meet you there?</p>
               <p>Garry. No, they had not, but they frequently go there, and one of them came before I went away; and having no company before they came, I fill'd a glass of ale, and lighted my pipe, and began to smoke; then I walk'd towards the stable door, to see if my mare was feeding, the prisoner was in the stable (the first time I ever saw him) along with the hostler; my mare did not feed, and I said she is very warm, and will feed by and by; then I came out of the stable, and left the prisoner and hostler there, and return'd to the house, which is some little distance from the stable. I drank another glass of my ale, and my company not being come I walk'd down to the stable again, and found the stable door shut; not thinking proper to disturb the horses, I passed the door, but there being a window that shuts up with a wooden shutter, which was latch'd up with a piece of leather, I look'd therefrom into the stable, and saw my mare and a man's head about her. I wonder'd what the man was doing, and thrust my head further into the window, and saw the prisoner at the bar in the act of beastiality with my mare, standing upon something that he had put cross the stall, about a foot and half high. I was surprized and shock'd thereat; and seeing Mr. Campbell smoaking a pipe at the house door, who was a stranger to me, I went up to him, and desired him to step with me to the stable, and told him the occasion, and he went with me, and observed the prisoner's actions in the stable from the window; then Mr. Campbell went away, and brought two other men from a greater distance from the stable than he was when I went to him.</p>
               <p>Q. How far might Mr. Campbell be from that window when you went to him?</p>
               <p>Garry. He was about twenty-five yards distance; the other two witnesses came back along with Mr. Campbell, and saw the prisoner in the action I first saw him in; but some noise being made, he was alarm'd and turn'd his head about, and saw us all at the window, and then he withdrew from the mare.</p>
               <p>Q. How near were you all to the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Garry. I could have reach'd him with my hand whip, and struck him cross the back; and being a good deal incensed against him, I went into the stable and horse-whip'd him all the while he kept doing up his breeches, they being quite down when I first went in. He kept crying out. What do you horse-whip me for, I have been doing nothing but putting the cloth over your man ? I said you had no occasion to have put your breeches down for that, I believe you have been doing that which will bring you to an unfortunate end.</p>
               <p>Q. How wide is the stall?</p>
               <p>Garry. I suppose about six foot wide. The thing he stood upon was either a piece of deal, or pitchfork, or broom, or something of that sort. I believe I should have neglected prosecuting the prisoner, had he not been very insolent, for when I was got to my pipe again, the prisoner being postilion to a post chaise that had brought down some gentry, as he was putting his horses to the chaise, he turn'd back, and seeing me at the door he held up his hand or whip, and said, I'll do for you for horse-whipping of me; whereupon, seeing him so very outrageous, I laid hold of him, and said public justice should be done on him, and then with some assistance he was carried before a justice of the peace at Fulham, who committed him to New-Prison; my mare is since dead.</p>
               <p>Mr. Campbell. Whilst I was sitting on a bench in the yard at the Peterborough-Arms, Mr. Garry, a person I had never seen before, came to me, seemingly in some confusion, and pull'd me by the arm, and said pray step this way. I said where, he still beg'd I'd go with him, and I went accordingly, and when we were got about half way to the stable, he said you'll see something that will surprize you, there is a little fellow buggering my mare in the stable. I went up to the stable window, and found what he had said to me was true, and was very much shock'd thereat; I then ran and beg'd of Mr. Sayer and Mr. Bedford to come back to the stable window with me, telling them what I had seen; accordingly they forthwith came, and found the prisoner much in the position as I had left him in, I was gone above a minute.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he stand upon?</p>
               <p>Campbell. I can't say that, but as we look'd in<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175707130026"></xptr> at the window, my hat made a little noise against the window shutter, and thereupon the prisoner turn'd his head about and look'd at us, and drop'd down behind the mare. Then Mr. Garry went in and horse whip'd the prisoner, after which I went into the house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe the prisoner's breeches to be down?</p>
               <p>Campbell. I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570713-29-person269">
                  John 
                  Sayer 
               <interp inst="t17570713-29-person269" type="surname" value="Sayer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-29-person269" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-29-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was drinking at the Peterborough Arms on Parsons Green, on Sunday the 24th of April. Mr. Campbell came to me and Mr. Bedford, and desired us to step with him to the stable window, which we did, and there saw the prisoner in beastiality with a mare; there being four of us we made the window dark, or else by somebody rushing against the window shutter the prisoner was disturb'd, and drop'd down from the mare; on which I said to Mr. Garry, Sir, go in and horse-whip him, for I think he deserves it very much, and here is a pond near, which he ought to be drag'd thro'; thereupon I went into the stable with Mr. Garry, and saw the p risoner's breeches quite down, and he endeavoured to put them up all the time Mr. Garry was horse whipping of him, but when the prisoner came out to put his horse to, he began to use Mr. Garry with ill manners, and call'd him names; then Mr. Garry went up to him, and said he should be prosecuted. He laid hold of him, and we assisted to secure the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. What had I in my hand?</p>
               <p>Sayer. Nothing as I know of.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570713-29-person270">
                  John 
                  Bedford 
               <interp inst="t17570713-29-person270" type="surname" value="Bedford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-29-person270" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-29-person270" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When Mr. Campbell came to call me, and told me I should see something not common, I went, and there were four of us at the window together, which darken'd it, but there-from we saw the prisoner behaving in a very improper manner, and something rushing against the window, he turn'd his head about and observed us, and then drop'd down from the mare, and endeavoured to pull the cloth that was upon the mare over her back. Mr. Garry went in and horse whip'd him, and the prisoner seemed to be bustling as if he was putting his breeches up at the time he was horse-whipped.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. What did you see in my hand?</p>
               <p>Bedford. I did not see you had any thing in your hand.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was making water between my horse and the gentleman's mare, and she had shaken the cloth off her. I took and threw it over her again, and he presently came into the stable, and fell a strikeing of me, I had the bridle in my hand at the time; there was nothing in the stable but a broom, a fork and a shovel.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570713-29-person271">
                  Joseph 
                  Goad 
               <interp inst="t17570713-29-person271" type="surname" value="Goad"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-29-person271" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-29-person271" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner had a pair of horses in that stable, and the mare stood in a stall between them. I had the care of the horses in the stable. I went out of the stable after the mare was there, and left the prisoner, and was not in the stable for an hour after.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. This is the man that was in the stable with the prisoner the first time I went to the stable.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. What time did you put your mare in the stable?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. About half an hour after three. She had been in the stable about an hour and a half before the prisoner was secured.</p>
               <p>To his Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570713-29-person272">
                  Simon 
                  Prish 
               <interp inst="t17570713-29-person272" type="surname" value="Prish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-29-person272" type="given" value="Simon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-29-person272" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner is upwards of sixteen years of age, and has lived in several noblemen's families. I believe he is the first of his family that ever was within side a prison. I ask'd Mr. Bedford in this court yard if he saw any thing of this affair, he said yes. Then I ask'd him what, and he said, he did not come till all was over.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570713-29-verdict139" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570713-29-verdict139" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17570713-29-punish140" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570713-29-punish140" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570713-29-defend267 t17570713-29-punish140"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
