<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17531205-65">
               <interp inst="t17531205-65" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531205-65" type="year" value="1753"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531205-65" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17531205"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531205-65" type="date" value="17531205"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17531205-65-off315-c399" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531205-65-defend525 t17531205-65-off315 t17531205-65-verdict317"></join>
         
               <p>76. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17531205-65-defend525" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Bell 
                  <interp inst="t17531205-65-defend525" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-65-defend525" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-65-defend525" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for that <rs id="t17531205-65-off315" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17531205-65-off315" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-65-off315" type="offenceSubcategory" value="coiningOffences"></interp>
               he, not being employed in or for the mint in the tower of London, or elsewhere, had in his custody a press for coinage, contrived and resembling the presses for coinage in the tower of London, and this without any lawful authority
            </rs>, <rs id="t17531205-65-cd316" type="crimeDate">July 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531205-65-off315 t17531205-65-cd316"></join>.*</p> 
               <p>John Sandall. I am porter of the mint, and have been about nineteen years.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you often see the coiners at work?</p>
               <p>Sandall. I do often. On the 26th of July last I found some tools for coining at the house of Mrs. Bilson in Winchester-street. I had taken Mr. Bell the day before at one Mr. Elgar's, who was engraving a pair of dyes for him to make Lewidores; in searching the cellar which they told me was Mr. Bell's property, there I found a press fixed upon a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175312050035"></xptr> block, as ours are in the mint, for coining. Every thing was fixed, but two springs, that lay ready to fix; it is of the very same kind as ours are, and to be pull'd in the same manner.</p>
               <p>Q. Could it be used for coining?</p>
               <p>Sandall. As I take it, it could; it only wanted the dyes to be fixed; they are made fast by four skrews. They are to be done in a very little time, the w orkmen shifting them as they see occasion; so that in the same manner sixpences, shillings, or a guinea, may be struck with that press. We have larger for crown pieces.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find any thing else?</p>
               <p>Sandall. There stood by the press what is called a stake, to flat or beat any thing upon; there were also a hammer and a ladle to melt rosin with, but what the use of that was I don't know. Up in the garret, which they said was the prisoner's garret, I found a stove new built to a chimney with brick work, that would run down gold or silver without any blowing; there was likewise a table fix'd, with a wheel to turn with a foot, and a pair of sheers, with some tongs to take the crucibles out of the fire; there were two windows to the room. There was another table with some drawers on the other side the room, where I found a little long ladle to cast gold or silver in; in one of the drawers, or upon the table, was a file, and a touchstone, as I suppose, with two pair of tongs to grasp the crucibles two small crucibles to melt any thing in, either gold or silver, and a brass instrument, the use unknown to me then, (the workmen who made it will tell the use of it) with an iron flask, or case, to cast in. In his escrutore, or bureau, which was in his bedchamber, as they called it, I found about 38 pieces of coin of different metals, and a pair of dyes to strike them with in a beaufet, or corner cupboard.</p>
               <p>Q. What are they called?</p>
               <p>Sandall. They are called deux-sols pieces; it is a French two-pence. Some of them were brass, some copper, whitened, and all representing the same French money. On the 28th I went with Mr. Cook, the solicitor of the mint, to look over the prisoner's writings; in the drawers there was a piece of metal weighing about six-pennyweight, which, upon the trial of it, proved gold, worse than standard five carats two grains; I had it tried by our assay-master, and was worth about 2 l. 18 s. by the shape of it it was cast in that little ladle which I found in the room where the fire-place was; it seemed to be part of a larger piece cut or broke off. I went with Mr. Bell before Justice Fielding, and he was committed, on the 26th; the 27th he was sent for to be re-examined, when he owned that all these things I have mention'd belonged to him. This was before Mr. 
               <persName id="t17531205-65-person526">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17531205-65-person526" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-65-person526" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-65-person526" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the blind gentleman.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say all?</p>
               <p>Sandall. I can't say he said the word all; but the press and things which were found in that house were mentioned.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he own the press?</p>
               <p>Sandall. He said the press was his press, and the other were his things.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say the place where they were found was his lodgings?</p>
               <p>Sandall. He did.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether at the mint the same press is made use of both for shillings and guineas?</p>
               <p>Sandall. Yes, it is; it is only shifting the dye.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What are those two springs that were not put in?</p>
               <p>Sandall. I know not the name; they are iron or steel springs.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the use of them?</p>
               <p>Sandall. As the fly is pull'd round, they are to help the fly to play up.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see a press used in the mint for coinage without those springs?</p>
               <p>Sandall. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. If a press is unfinished, do you call that a press?</p>
               <p>Sandall. I should take this to be a press; there were the springs ready to fix; it was finished, and they might be put in as soon as the question might be asked.</p>
               <p>Q. Can the skrew of the press be taken out and soon put in again?</p>
               <p>Sandall. No, Sir.</p>

               <p>Q. Suppose you see a watch without the pendulum, would you call that a watch?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175312050036"></xptr>Sandall. I never saw a pendulum.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you work the press in the condition you saw it?</p>
               <p>Sandall. No, because the springs were not fixed; but the moniers know better than I do.</p>
               <p>Q. How many presses did you ever see beside those in the mint and this?</p>
               <p>Sandall. I have seen one in the hands of a tradesman, who engraves dyes, and makes buttons and such things.</p>
               <p>Q. Are those presses that are made for watch keys, cane heads, and such things, made in the same method as those in the tower?</p>
               <p>Sandall. I never saw any of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Could this be made use of in making metal buttons?</p>
               <p>Sandall. It might.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you do halfpence and farthings in the same press?</p>
               <p>Sandall. We do; it is only changing the dye; it does not require so strong a weight to coin a shilling, or sixpence, as it does to coin a halfpenny, I suppose.</p>
               <p>Q. Could this press be made to coin a shilling?</p>
               <p>Sandall. I am sure it would coin a shilling, or deux sols piece.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever seen the head of a cane taken off?</p>
               <p>Sandall. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Is there not rosin in it?</p>
               <p>Sandall. There is.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner say what use he made of these things?</p>
               <p>Sandall. He told the justice they were to make medals and coin.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he express what coin?</p>
               <p>Sandall. No, he did not; he used the word coin.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not the word deux-sols-piece mention'd?</p>
               <p>Sandall. I don't remember that it was. I believe he said it was not intended to make any coin of this kingdom; he said they were to go to Canada, and that he was employed by a certain gentleman, whom he refused to name, and he was to have forty pounds every month.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he mention any thing else beside medals and coin?</p>
               <p>Sandall. I believe he mention'd buttons, medals and coin.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Did not I tell you where you might find the press?</p>
               <p>Sandall. He did; he said he had a press in his house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531205-65-person527">
                  William 
                  Hankins 
               <interp inst="t17531205-65-person527" type="surname" value="Hankins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-65-person527" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-65-person527" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am one of the moniers in the mint.</p>
               <p>Q. What is a monier?</p>
               <p>W. Hankins. That is one that makes the money. I saw the press that Mr. Sandall found in Winchester-street, it is a proper press for coinage.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the springs in it?</p>
               <p>W. Hankins. No, they were not when brought to the Tower.</p>
               <p>Q. How long time does it take to fix them in?</p>
               <p>W. Hankins. They are put in in a minute.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it like those you use in the Tower?</p>
               <p>W. Hankins. It is just such a one as we use for sixpences, shillings, half-guineas and guineas.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you make use of this in coining money the same as with those at the Tower ?</p>
               <p>W. Hankins. We could, but not so expeditiously as with our own.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the use of the springs?</p>
               <p>W. Hankins. The use is to lift up the box after the piece is struck.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How many other presses have you ever seen besides those in the Tower?</p>
               <p>W. Hankins. I never saw any in my life besides this and those in the Mint.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you have coined guineas with this press if the springs were not in?</p>
               <p>W. Hankins. We could, may be one in an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any leather on the fly of this press ?</p>
               <p>W. Hankins. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Are there not leathers on the fly of your presses when they are worked?</p>
               <p>W. Hankins. There are.</p>
               <p>Q. Is this as big a press as yours in the Mint?</p>
               <p>W. Hankins. No, it is not as some are; it is about the middle size.</p>
               <p>Q. Could this be used to coin any base mettle, either halfpence, farthings, or deux sols pieces?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175312050037"></xptr>W. Hankins. Yes, it might.</p>
               <p>Q. Would this coin a medal?</p>
               <p>W. Hankins. It would.</p>
               <p>Q. Could the press be worked without the leather?</p>
               <p>W. Hankins. We could strike a single piece.</p>
               <p>Council for Crown.</p>
               <p>To Mr. Sandall. Did you see any leather when you found the press?</p>
               <p>Sandall. I believe I saw none; there was the iron fixed to the press to pull with, there was a piece of cord fixed to one end, and a cord will do as well as leather.</p>
               <p>Q. to Hankins. Is it necessary to have the leathers on when it is not working?</p>
               <p>Hankins. When it is not worked neither cord nor leather is necessary, but when they work it they put them on; we can strike some money with only the push of it without a man standing to pull it.</p>
               <p>Q. What money is that?</p>
               <p>Hankins. Pennies.</p>
               <p>Q. Is a press the same without the leathers?</p>
               <p>Hankins. The press is the same without them.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the fly fixed?</p>
               <p>Hankins. It was, ready for work.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531205-65-person528">
                  William 
                  Vanderesck 
               <interp inst="t17531205-65-person528" type="surname" value="Vanderesck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-65-person528" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-65-person528" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am one of the moniers.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen the press Mr. Sandall found in Winchester-street?</p>
               <p>W. Vanderesck. I have; it appears to me to be a proper press for coinage; I cannot say I examined it thoroughly, but it is proper for any piece not bigger than a shilling or a guinea, it is not big enough for crowns or half-crowns.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the springs on when you saw it?</p>
               <p>W. Vanderesck. No they were not.</p>
               <p>Q. Can it be used without the springs?</p>
               <p>W. Vanderesck. It may be one piece or so, without the springs.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see such a press in tradesmen's hands?</p>
               <p>W. Vanderesck. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Robert M' Gill. I know the prisoner Mr. Bell; I live at Woolwich; he came to me there, and asked me if I could help him to a smith that could make a press for striking of medals; this was in June last; I said I could; so we went so a tavern; he asked me when I should be at London; I said the next day, to see the review in Hide-park.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>R. M' Gill. I am a smith; he desired me to come to his house, which I did; then I took him to Puddle-dock-hill, to a man I think named Wood; Mr. Bell told him that he wanted a press to strike some pieces of the same size with some that he shewed him.</p>
               <p>What sort of pieces?</p>
               <p>R. M' Gill. They were copper pieces whitened, and a yellow piece about the bigness of a guinea; it had an impression on both sides; two round O's on one side, and the head of a man on the other. He is shewed a yellow piece. They are such as this; the man said he could make one of that size for about twenty pounds; but they could not agree; so I asked him if he could direct us to see one any where; he said he had made one for forty pounds for one Mr. Yeo in Covent-garden, and he believed he would shew it me.</p>
               <p>Q. What is that Mr. Yeo?</p>
               <p>M' Gill. I have heard he is an engraver for the Mint in the Tower. Mr. Yeo strikes large medals, such as they make presents of at the universities, bigger than a crown piece. I went and told my brother, that if Mr. Bell had one made, I would get him the job; so took my brother to Mr. Yeo's, and told him that a gentleman wanted a press made, and desired he would let him look at it; he showed us the press and all about it; then I went and carried Mr. Bell there, and he saw it; Mr. Yeo shewed him a great many pieces he had struck with it. Mr. Bell pulled his piece out of his pocket, and told him he would have some such cut; Mr. Yeo said he could not do it without acquainting the master of the Mint. Mr. Bell said he did not care who knew of it; so we parted; I went and saw the presses in the Tower after this. My brother and Mr. Bell met next day, and bargained to make a press; I think he was to give my brother twenty-five pounds.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Bell come to you in a publick manner?</p>
               <p>M' Gill. He did; he did not whisper, or in-join<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175312050038"></xptr> me to keep it a secret. We went in at a publick house, and talked about it the next day; he made no secret of it.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say he wanted it for?</p>
               <p>M' Gill. He said he would do buttons, cane-heads, nails, and watches.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you think there was any harm in what you were about?</p>
               <p>M' Gill. No, I did not think there was.</p>
               <p>Council for Crown.</p>
               <p>Did you ever see any cane heads of his striking?</p>
               <p>M' Gill. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Or metal buttons?</p>
               <p>M' Gill. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Bell say he wanted a press for striking small coin as well as medals?</p>
               <p>M' Gill. I cannot say that; I think he said he wanted a press to strike those things he shewed.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you take that yellow piece to be gold or brass?</p>
               <p>M' Gill. It appears to me to be gold. He told me there was a settlement at Canada, near Nova-Scotia; and he was to make some medals for that place.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he mean by medals?</p>
               <p>M' Gill. I think he said medals.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner's council. Are you sure that this piece you have been shewn is the very same piece he shewed to Yeo?</p>
               <p>M' Gill. It is like it; but I never read the inscription round it.</p>
               <p>Q. What is Mr. Bell's trade?</p>
               <p>M' Gill. He was brought up a gentleman as far as I know.</p>
               <p>Council for Crown.</p>
               <p>Had you ever been in his company before he came to you at Woolwich ?</p>
               <p>M' Gill. I had; but we were not very much acquainted.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he a button-maker?</p>
               <p>M' Gill. No, not as I know of.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he a cane-head maker?</p>
               <p>M' Gill. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he a dealer in brass?</p>
               <p>M' Gill. I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Nenien M' Gill. My brother the left witness</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>N. M' Gill. It was in June, on the same day that the review was in Hide-park; he shewed me a piece of coin, and a pair of dyes made to it; I did not then know what it was; they call it a Louis-d'or. He is shewn the yellow piece of coin. It was such a piece as this.</p>
               <p>Q. to Sandall. Look at that piece; where had you it?</p>
               <p>Sandall. This is the same piece that the dyes were to have been engraven by, and I have the dyes here.</p>
               <p>N. M' Gill. Bell said it was to make such pieces as those. I went to Mr. Yeo's in Covent-garden to see that press; after that I went to the Tower two or three times to see them. When the press was made I carried it home; I was to have ten guineas advance, and have got about 7. Afterwards Mr. Bell said that as soon as it was ready he was to work it.</p>
               <p>Q. Who advised you to go to the Tower?</p>
               <p>N. M' Gill. My brother; he had seen them before.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you carry it home ?</p>
               <p>N. M' Gill. I cannot tell the day. I forged a pair of dyes by his direction, and carried them to the engraver; but they were never made.</p>
               <p>Mr. Sandall produced a pair of dyes not finished.</p>
               <p>N. M' Gill. These are them which I forged by Mr. Bell's orders; the Louis-d'ors were given to me by him, in order for the size of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of any gold being melted?</p>
               <p>N. M' Gill. Yes, there was some gold melted by order of Mr. Bell, to be struck by those dyes; but we made no trial, they not being finished.</p>
               <p>Q. What gold did you melt?</p>
               <p>N. M' Gill. Mr. Bell and I together melted thirty-six shilling pieces.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any order given to work this secretly?</p>
               <p>N. M' Gill. There was none; he said he did not care who saw it; only in case any body should see it and take the trade out of his hands, then he should he a loser by it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he mean the Louis-d'or? that<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175312050039"></xptr> found out one Mr. Elgar an engraver; Mr. Bell ordered me to get the dyes engraved as the other. I went with my fellow-servant to Mr. Elgar, and we agreed for a guinea and a half; then my fellow-servant took me to a flatter's, where the gold was to be rolled; I took it there by Mr. Bell's order.</p>
               <p>Q. What was that to make?</p>
               <p>N. M' Gill. It was to make such pieces as these, meaning the yellow pieces produced.</p>
               <p>Q. to Sandall. Describe the nature of making guineas, and from what.</p>
               <p>Sandall. It is necessary we should have the gold flatted out of the bar, to be worked to the size that the piece of money is to be of.</p>
               <p>Council for Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Did you ever see a press like this in the custody of a tradesman?</p>
               <p>Sandall. I saw a press something like this in the hands of an engraver, who engraves dyes to strike buttons with; but I did not examine it.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531205-65-person529">
                  John 
                  Daubin 
               <interp inst="t17531205-65-person529" type="surname" value="Daubin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-65-person529" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-65-person529" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about eleven months; he sent some Birmingham ware to me, consisting of snuffers, corkscrews. &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Daubin. It was in June.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they of his own making?</p>
               <p>Daubin. I don't know that they were: there was one cane head, I cannot say what it was made of, whether gold or pinchbeck.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell who made it?</p>
               <p>Daubin. No, I cannot, indeed.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell whether he made it?</p>
               <p>Daubin. I don't know, it is concluded Birmingham ware.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Daubin. About eleven months ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever know he was any trade?</p>
               <p>Daubin. I never knew he was.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen him many times since you first knew him?</p>
               <p>Daubin. Very often, I have been at his lodgings.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any press?</p>
               <p>Daubin. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q Bell, when he dealt with you, as a person that was setting up to make Birmingham goods?</p>
               <p>Daubin. That I did, and understood that he was to go on with Birmingham ware, to make snuff-boxes, or any thing of that ware.</p>
               <p>Q. What were your reasons for it?</p>
               <p>Daubin. Because he told me so.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any other reasons beside that ?</p>
               <p>Daubin. No, I have not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531205-65-person530">
                  Mary 
                  Daubin 
               <interp inst="t17531205-65-person530" type="surname" value="Daubin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-65-person530" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-65-person530" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the last witness, I know the prisoner, and have known him about eleven months.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of any trade he was carrying on?</p>
               <p>M. Daubin. I bought some things of him in the Birmingha m way, as snuffers, a corkscrew, and buckles; he shewed me a sample of some cane heads.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell any otherwise than what he told you, that he made them?</p>
               <p>M. Daubin. I do not know.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531205-65-person531">
                  Henry 
                  Phillips 
               <interp inst="t17531205-65-person531" type="surname" value="Phillips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-65-person531" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531205-65-person531" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I work in watch chains and buttons.</p>
               <p>Q. How are they made?</p>
               <p>Phillips. In different kinds.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see any press used for that purpose ?</p>
               <p>Phillips. Yes, I have, but I never had one.</p>
               <p>Q. What are they used for?</p>
               <p>Phillips. In the jewelling way, and for buttons.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of presses are they?</p>
               <p>Phillips. They seem to be the same as those in the Tower, to the best of my knowledge, though I have not seen them in the Tower for 20 years.</p>
               <p>Calverley Pinkney. I have seen all the various presses that are used in the mint; and have also seen several in tradesmen's shops they are the same sort with those in the mint.</p>
               <p>Q. What trades are they commonly used for?</p>
               <p>Pinkney. They are us'd for striking the bows for watch keys, and for watch chains, and for the metal pieces for the dial plates of watches, for cane heads, buttons, and divers other things.</p>
               <p>Q. Does the press make only a flat impression?</p>
               <p>Pinkney. There are dyes prepared of divers forts, there is two of them, the one concave and the other convex, and the swiftness of the to the impression,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175312050040"></xptr> and the spring gives the rebound; the quicker the blow the neater the impression; and it requires a press of the same force with those in the Tower to make the work neat.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Will the presses you have seen coin money?</p>
               <p>Pinkney. According to their size they will coin all sorts of money.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17531205-65-verdict317" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17531205-65-verdict317" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>By consent of the Attorney-General, and the Counsels for the prisoner, the <rs id="t17531205-65-punish318" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17531205-65-punish318" type="punishmentCategory" value="noPunish"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531205-65-defend525 t17531205-65-punish318"></join>
               judgment was respited till after the opinion of the twelve Judges
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
