<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17540911-24">
               <interp inst="t17540911-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-24" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-24" type="date" value="17540911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540911-24-off135-c187" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-24-defend229 t17540911-24-off135 t17540911-24-verdict139"></join>
         
               <p>438. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17540911-24-defend229" type="defendantName">
                  Jer.
                   Main
               <interp inst="t17540911-24-defend229" type="surname" value="Main"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-24-defend229" type="given" value="Jer."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-24-defend229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17540911-24-off135" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540911-24-off135" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-24-off135" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he, in a certain passage, near the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17540911-24-victim231" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Foster 
                        <interp inst="t17540911-24-victim231" type="surname" value="Foster"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540911-24-victim231" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540911-24-victim231" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17540911-24-viclabel136" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-24-victim231 t17540911-24-viclabel136"></join>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-24-victim233 t17540911-24-viclabel136"></join>, did make an assault, putting her in corporal fear and danger of her life, two calicoe window-curtains, value 2 s. the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17540911-24-victim233" type="victimName">
                           Matth.ew 
                           Crush 
                        <interp inst="t17540911-24-victim233" type="surname" value="Crush"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540911-24-victim233" type="given" value="Matth.ew"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540911-24-victim233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , and one linnen handkerchief, value 6 d. and 3 d. in money, the property of the said Mary, did steal, take and carry away
            </rs>, <rs id="t17540911-24-cd137" type="crimeDate">August 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-24-off135 t17540911-24-cd137"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-24-person234">
                  Mary 
                  Foster 
               <interp inst="t17540911-24-person234" type="surname" value="Foster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-24-person234" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-24-person234" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 17th of August last, between 6 and 7 o'clock in the morning, I was on the marsh wall, by the mill, at <placeName id="t17540911-24-crimeloc138">Poplar</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17540911-24-crimeloc138" type="placeName" value="Poplar"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17540911-24-crimeloc138" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-24-off135 t17540911-24-crimeloc138"></join>, walking along I was alone.</p>
               <p>Q. What place is it? Is it a lone place, or among houses ?</p>
               <p>Foster. There are no houses, it is an open field. I had two calicoe curtains in my hand belonging to Mr. Crush; the prisoner met me and stopped me. I was going over the water. He told me I could not get a boat there. He took me in his arms, and carried me into the rushes, betwixt the river Thames and the bank, without saying another<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175409110016"></xptr> word to me; there he used me in a very indecent manner.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you continue there?</p>
               <p>Foster. I believe about half an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you both come out of the rushes together ?</p>
               <p>Foster. We did, and went to Mr. Crush's house, about a mile from the place.</p>
               <p>Q. How far did he walk with you before he took any thing from you?</p>
               <p>Foster. About ten yards. He asked me for my bundle, and said he'd carry it for me. He threw me into a ditch at getting over a stile, my bundle fell out of my hand, and he picked it up. After that I asked him for it; he said he would carry it, for he was afraid it would tire me.</p>
               <p>Q. How soon did you ask him for it after he picked it up?</p>
               <p>Foster. It might be about ten minutes after he picked it up. When I got him to Mr. Crush's I bid him come in, and he would not, but went to the door, and offered to pull me out, and then ran up an alley.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you meet with any body betwixt the rushes and Mr. Crush's house?</p>
               <p>Foster. No we did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you get to Mr. Crush's ?</p>
               <p>Foster. It was about half an hour after eight. As soon as I got into the house, I made complaint in what manner he had used me, and that he had got the curtains, my handkerchief, and 3 d. in money.</p>
               <p>Q. How came he by the money?</p>
               <p>Foster. He asked me for my money, and I refused him. He asked me again, and I gave him three pence.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Foster. This was just after he took me out of the ditch; my handkerchief was tied round the curtains. They went and took him with my Bundle.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever seen him before?</p>
               <p>Foster. No, never to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any pistol he had ?</p>
               <p>Foster. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he strike you?</p>
               <p>Foster. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you say to him when he took the things ?</p>
               <p>Foster. I said I'd treat him if he'd go into the town. I did it to take care of myself. He said he thought it would look odd for me to treat him.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Foster. I live servant with Mr. Crush's sister in East-Lane, Greenwich. I had never been of that side of the water before.</p>
               <p>Q. In what manner did he throw you into the ditch?</p>
               <p>Foster. When he came to the stile, he fell into the ditch and pulled me in after him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a wet or dry ditch ?</p>

               <p>Foster. It was a very muddy ditch, and we were both very dirty.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he fuddled ?</p>
               <p>Foster. Really I can't tell, for I never saw him before.</p>
               <p>Q. from the prisoner. Did not you see the miller as we went by?</p>
               <p>Foster. There was the miller at his gate; the prisoner said to him, Hallow.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you call to the miller to assist you?</p>
               <p>Foster. I did not. I thought he might be as bad as the other, and I was willing to get the prisoner to Mr. Crush's house.</p>
               <p>Q. from the prisoner. Did I not ask you to go in at the first publick house to drink?</p>
               <p>Foster. He asked me to go in at several alehouses, but I would not. I said, I would go to the farthest end of the street before I would drink.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is the street?</p>
               <p>Foster. It is a pretty long street. He came singing and whistling along the street.</p>
               <p>Q. Is Mr. Crush's house at the end of the street?</p>
               <p>Foster. No, it is past the middle of the street.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-24-person235">
                  Matthew 
                  Crush 
               <interp inst="t17540911-24-person235" type="surname" value="Crush"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-24-person235" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-24-person235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 7th of August this girl was sent from her mistress, my sister, for two callicoe curtains. She came to my house between five and six in the afternoon. I keep the sign of the three Foxes in Narrow-street, Ratcliff. My wife made her sit down and eat some bread and butter, and drink a dish of tea; after that she went away, the way she has here mentioned, for Greenwich, with the curtains. She came back to my house crying between eight and nine, and said she had been stop'd and used ill. I asked where the man was that stop'd her. She said he was gone up the street. A person looking out at a window, said he was gone up the court. I took a man with me; it being no thoroughfare; I found the prisoner betwixt a shed and a necessary house at the upper end of the court. We seized him and took the things from him. He said he did not design to run away with them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say she had been robbed?</p>
               <p>Crush. No, she did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you understand by her complaint ?</p>
               <p>Crush. I understood she had been used very ill, but not in the way of robbery.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175409110017"></xptr>Q. Did you know the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Crush. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say any thing about her losing the curtains or 3 d?</p>
               <p>Crush. No, she did not to me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-24-person236">
                  James 
                  Hone 
               <interp inst="t17540911-24-person236" type="surname" value="Hone"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-24-person236" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-24-person236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the door; I heard a man had got the girl's bundle; I went up the court with Mr. Crush, there we found the prisoner with it under his arm. He had but very little to say for himself.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear him say how he came by the bundle?</p>
               <p>Hone. No, I did not. The girl said, he threw her into the ditch, and she dropped the bundle and he took it up. And that he had asked her for it twice before, and she would not give it him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>When this girl came over the stile, she said, she was a-dry. I said, I had no money till I came to town. She said, she had got some half-pence, and half a crown. She gave me 3 d. to go to a publick house, and when we came to a publick house, she would not go in with me, and I returned her her 3 d. again.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutrix. Did he return you your 3 d. again?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. He did, in Mr. Crush's house, after he was taken and brought in, and I had ask'd him for it.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-24-person237">
                  Thomas 
                  Gibson 
               <interp inst="t17540911-24-person237" type="surname" value="Gibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-24-person237" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-24-person237" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a taylor, and have known the prisoner about 18 months; he worked with me about 6 months, he behaved well then.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is that ago?</p>
               <p>Gibson. About a year or ten months.</p>
               <p>Q. How has he behaved since?</p>
               <p>Gibson. I know nothing of him since?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-24-person238">
                  Sarah 
                  Powers 
               <interp inst="t17540911-24-person238" type="surname" value="Powers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-24-person238" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-24-person238" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I did keep the Foxes, the house now Mr. Crush has. The same night this man was taken, I was there, the girl came into a box, and asked a man to come in and drink a pint of beer, seemingly in a civil manner; no man coming in, the girl said, the man had got her bundle; she was ask'd what man; she said, she did did not know, but he was a taylor. Mr. Crush and other people went out and up the court, and brought the prisoner in. The girl declared before the justice, the man did not take the bundle from her, but as he was helping her over the stile, they both fell down, and he took up the bundle, she ask'd him fol it, and he told her he'd carry it, fearing it should tire her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear her say she consented to his carrying it?</p>
               <p>S. Powers. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say he would not give it her?</p>
               <p>S. Powers. No, she did not, and she said, he said he'd take her to a lodging. She answered, which way will you get a lodging? he said, he'd pawn his coat; she said, no, how sadly you'll look without a coat, we had better pawn the bundle. First of all she said they were down in the rushes, and she spit; he said, d - n you, do you spit at me; she said, no, but she was very dry, and wish'd he'd go and get some beer; he said, he had no money, have you any? She said 3 d. he said, give it me, and I'll go and get some beer; she gave it him; he asked her to go in at several alehouses going along; she said, no, she would go to the end of the street if it was ever so far.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is Mr. Crush's house from the end of the street?</p>
               <p>S. Powers. It is pretty near the end of the street.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is it from the rushes to Mr. Crush's house?</p>
               <p>S. Powers. It is about a mile distant.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-24-person239">
                  James 
                  Hosier 
               <interp inst="t17540911-24-person239" type="surname" value="Hosier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-24-person239" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-24-person239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a master taylor in Panton-Square, St. James's, the prisoner has work'd for me several times off and on; any hour he was with me he might have deprived me of a good many things; I believe him to be an honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-24-person240">
                  Peter 
                  Vyan 
               <interp inst="t17540911-24-person240" type="surname" value="Vyan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-24-person240" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-24-person240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a master taylor in St. James's, I have known him 3 or 4 years, he work'd with me from the 24th of May to the 15th of June last; I never found any thing of him but that of an honest man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540911-24-verdict139" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540911-24-verdict139" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
