<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17590711-25">
               <interp inst="t17590711-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590711-25" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590711-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17590711"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590711-25" type="date" value="17590711"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17590711-25-off146-c174" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590711-25-defend220 t17590711-25-off146 t17590711-25-verdict148"></join>
         
               <p>238. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17590711-25-defend220" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Price 
                  <interp inst="t17590711-25-defend220" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-25-defend220" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-25-defend220" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17590711-25-off146" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590711-25-off146" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-25-off146" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               the wilful murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17590711-25-victim222" type="victimName">
                           Alexander 
                           Miller 
                        <interp inst="t17590711-25-victim222" type="surname" value="Miller"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590711-25-victim222" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590711-25-victim222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590711-25-off146 t17590711-25-victim222"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17590711-25-cd147" type="crimeDate">July 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590711-25-off146 t17590711-25-cd147"></join>. He stood likewise charged on the Coroner's Inquisition for manslaughter. ++</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590711-25-person223">
                  Edmund 
                  Camper 
               <interp inst="t17590711-25-person223" type="surname" value="Camper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-25-person223" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-25-person223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a Publick-house. Last Saturday between nine and ten o'clock, the prisoner and the deceased, and another man, came to my house to drink a tankard or two of beer; they staid in the yard some time. I got Miller to assist me to do a little jobb, and gave him a full pot of beer, and they were a penny or three-half-pence each towards some more: then said this Miller to the prisoner, I'll give you a touch at sticks for a full pot of beer. Said the prisoner, I never could play with a stick, but I'll play with you at your game, and after that you shall with me at mine. They went out into the yard and found two sticks, and went to fighting with them; the deceased broke his stick over the prisoner's head; after that they dropped their sticks and went to fighting with their fists. Miller came up to Price and took hold of him and tore his shirt; then Price resented it, and seemed to be very angry, and said, he had rather he had torn so much of his skin; then they went to fighting, and Miller the deceased ran his head into Price's breast; presently Price took the same opportunity and served him the same sauce; by running his head under Miller's chin, and he dropped down dead directly, never spoke nor never moved afterwards.</p>

               <p>Q. How near was you to them when they were fighting?</p>
               <p>Camper. I was but a very little way from them.</p>
               <p>Q. How did the prisoner behave after this?</p>
               <p>Camper. He lifted the deceased's head up against a few ropes that lay there, and fell a-crying. He then came to me and said, he believed the man was dead; there was some water that the prisoner sprinkled in the deceased's face; the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907110026"></xptr> prisoner came and surrendered himself to me, and never made any attempt to get away.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590711-25-person224">
                  Richard 
                  Rowland 
               <interp inst="t17590711-25-person224" type="surname" value="Rowland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-25-person224" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-25-person224" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was along with the prisoner and deceased drinking at this time: the deceased gave the prisoner a challenge first for five shillings: at first it was proposed to fight with sticks: the prisoner said, Elick, I don't want to quarrel. The deceased started up soon after and pulled out six-pence and said, now I'll lick you with a stick: he threw his money on the table. Then the prisoner said, I don't value six-pence, come out at the door, if you lick me I shall hit you again; then the deceased ran into the yard and got a stick; the prisoner followed him; then they went to fighting with two sticks; they broke their sticks and took hold of one another, and went to work with their fists. The deceased made a blow at the prisoner with his head; then the prisoner came right in plump upon him, and there it ended.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>The deceased challenged to fight me for five shillings, either with a stick or fists. I said, I am no man for sticks; I don't fight with a stick; then he pulled out a six-pence and said, he would fight me for six-pence. I said, I did not want any quarrel. Please to ask these witnesses my character.</p>
               <p>Q. to Camper. How long have you known the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Camper. I have known him about three years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his disposition of mind as to being quarrelsome?</p>
               <p>Camper. I never saw the man quarrelsome in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he used your house much?</p>
               <p>Camper. He has used my house about three years, and worked for me.</p>
               <p>Q. to Rowland. How long have you known the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Rowland. I have known him much about the same time.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a temper has he?</p>
               <p>Rowland. I never saw no ill of him.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17590711-25-verdict148" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590711-25-verdict148" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-25-verdict148" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17590711-25-punish149" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590711-25-punish149" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-25-punish149" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590711-25-defend220 t17590711-25-punish149"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
