<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17531024-15">
               <interp inst="t17531024-15" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531024-15" type="year" value="1753"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531024-15" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17531024"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531024-15" type="date" value="17531024"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17531024-15-off62-c73" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-15-defend98 t17531024-15-off62 t17531024-15-verdict66"></join>
         
               <p>456. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17531024-15-defend98" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Darby 
                  <interp inst="t17531024-15-defend98" type="surname" value="Darby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-15-defend98" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-15-defend98" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , widow, was indicted for <rs id="t17531024-15-off62" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17531024-15-off62" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-15-off62" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one silver tankard, val. 6 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17531024-15-victim100" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Jeffereys 
                        <interp inst="t17531024-15-victim100" type="surname" value="Jeffereys"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17531024-15-victim100" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17531024-15-victim100" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-15-off62 t17531024-15-victim100"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling-house of the said Robert
            </rs>, <rs id="t17531024-15-cd63" type="crimeDate">Sept. 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-15-off62 t17531024-15-cd63"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-15-person101">
                  Robert 
                  Jeffereys 
               <interp inst="t17531024-15-person101" type="surname" value="Jeffereys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-15-person101" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-15-person101" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17531024-15-crimeloc64">Hemlock-court, Temple Bar</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17531024-15-crimeloc64" type="placeName" value="Hemlock-court, Temple Bar"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17531024-15-crimeloc64" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-15-off62 t17531024-15-crimeloc64"></join>, and <rs id="t17531024-15-viclabel65" type="occupation">keep a publick-house</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-15-victim100 t17531024-15-viclabel65"></join>, the prisoner and another young woman used to meet a young man sometimes at my house: on the 29th of September, about four in the afternoon, there were only two gentlemen at my house, and the prisoner, who call'd for a three half-penny glass of brandy, and said she expected she should be at my house again at seven in the evening; after she was gone I missed a silver tankard from out of that room where she was.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you seen that tankard lost ?</p>
               <p>Jeffereys. I am positive it was in the room at one o'clock that afternoon.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did she come to your house?</p>
               <p>Jeffereys. She came between twelve and one, and staid till three. I suspected the prisoner, but did not know where to find her; on Sunday was se'nnight the other young woman came that used to meet her, I kept her till she told me where to find the prisoner, which she said was at her mother's in Magpye-alley, Fetter-lane. I went and enquired for her, they denied her, but as the young woman had told me she was then at home, I insisted on seeing her, and went up stairs and found her concealed amongst some curtains to a turn-up bed. I asked her why she hid herself, she said she heard my voice and was afraid of me. She desired to talk with me by myself, so I went with her into her own room, where she said she hoped I would be merciful unto her; I said I would as much as I could. Then she said the tankard was at a pawnbroker's in Cursiter-street. I took her before alderman Bethell at Guild-hall, who granted a search-warrant to search the pawnbroker's house. We went there, and she asked for the tankard she had pawned in the name of 
               <persName id="t17531024-15-person102">
                  Sarah 
                  Robertson 
               <interp inst="t17531024-15-person102" type="surname" value="Robertson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-15-person102" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-15-person102" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , (the name she went by) and it was produced. Produced in court and deposed to.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-15-person103">
                  Thomas 
                  Marsh 
               <interp inst="t17531024-15-person103" type="surname" value="Marsh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-15-person103" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-15-person103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a pawnbroker, the prisoner and a gentleman came together, and I delivered a tankard to them, but I am not sure this is the tankard, I believe it is it. The tankard I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175310240006"></xptr> delivered I had of the prisoner at the bar; she had other things out at the same time, which was Sept. 29.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I advertised this tankard several times between the 29th of Sept. and the time I met with it again, and describ'd it.</p>
               <p>Q. to Marsh. Did you not read the advertisement while you had it in your custody?</p>
               <p>Marsh. Indeed I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Don't you usually read the advertisements in the papers.</p>
               <p>Marsh. I generally do, but I don't remember seeing this advertisement.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you lend her upon it?</p>
               <p>Marsh. I lent her four guineas and a half upon it.</p>
               <p>Q. Don't you remember the letters on the handle ?</p>
               <p>Marsh. I believe this is the tankard here produc'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the weight of it?</p>
               <p>Marsh. It weigh'd twenty-one ounces and odd penny weights.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. This weighs twenty-one ounces fifteen penny weights.</p>
               <p>The prisoner had nothing to say.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mr. Martingale. I knew the prisoner's father and her from a child; she was well brought up, but debauched by her father's apprentice, who is a very bad man, and I think necessity was the cause of her committing this action.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17531024-15-verdict66" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17531024-15-verdict66" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-15-verdict66" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder40s"></interp>
               Guilty 39  s.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17531024-15-punish67" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17531024-15-punish67" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-15-punish67" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-15-defend98 t17531024-15-punish67"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
