<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17530221-43">
               <interp inst="t17530221-43" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530221-43" type="year" value="1753"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530221-43" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17530221"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530221-43" type="date" value="17530221"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17530221-43-off209-c272" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530221-43-defend348 t17530221-43-off209 t17530221-43-verdict213"></join>
         
               <p>153. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17530221-43-defend348" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Edward 
                     McManning 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17530221-43-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530221-43-defend348 t17530221-43-alias-3"></join>Howard</rs>, otherwise <rs id="t17530221-43-alias-4" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530221-43-defend348 t17530221-43-alias-4"></join>James Farrel</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-defend348" type="surname" value="McManning"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-defend348" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-defend348" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for that <rs id="t17530221-43-off209" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-off209" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-off209" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               he, on the <rs id="t17530221-43-cd210" type="crimeDate">8th of February</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530221-43-off209 t17530221-43-cd210"></join>, about the hour of eight in the night, the dwelling house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17530221-43-victim351" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Showery 
                        <interp inst="t17530221-43-victim351" type="surname" value="Showery"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530221-43-victim351" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530221-43-victim351" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530221-43-off209 t17530221-43-victim351"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17530221-43-viclabel211" type="occupation">Esq;</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530221-43-victim351 t17530221-43-viclabel211"></join>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530221-43-victim354 t17530221-43-viclabel211"></join> did break and enter, one velvet coat, value 8 l. one pair of velvet breeches, one cloth coat with gold lace, one other coat with metal buttons gilt with gold, one coat, one surtout coat, one frock, one waistcoat, one cloth frock, one gold brocaded waistcoat, one silk waistcoat, one other silk waistcoat, one worsted waistcoat, one cloth waistcoat, two pair of silk breeches, one pair of cloth breeches, two pair of worsted breeches, two pair of leather breeches, two pair of silk hose, three pair of worsted hose, two pair of thread ditto, ten linnen shirts, five muslin neckcloths ruffled worked with needle-work, thirty ells of linnen cloth, one pair of sheets, one pillow-bier, two linnen tablecloths, three napkins, one gold laced hat, three other hats, one pair of boots, one pair of shoes, three other pair of shoes, one sword with a gilded hilt, one sword not gilt, one gold ring set with a chrystal stone and two diamond sparks, one silver tobacco box, two silver table-spoons, four silver tea-spoons, the goods of 
                     <persName id="t17530221-43-person352">
                        John 
                        Showery 
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-person352" type="surname" value="Showery"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530221-43-person352" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530221-43-person352" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , Esq; did steal, take, and carry away. 
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>It was laid over again to be the dwelling house of 
               
                  <persName id="t17530221-43-victim354" type="victimName">
                     Joseph 
                     Harris 
                  <interp inst="t17530221-43-victim354" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-victim354" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-victim354" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            .</p>
               <p>And it was laid over again for entering the dwelling house, and breaking his way out. *</p>
               <p>John Showery, Esq; On the 6th of February last I mounted guard at the Horse-Guards, near Buckingham-Gate, where we continued four days; as soon as we had relieved the other guard I walked from them cross the Park home to my lodgings at the house of Mr. Harris in <placeName id="t17530221-43-crimeloc212">Spring-Gardens</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17530221-43-crimeloc212" type="placeName" value="Spring-Gardens"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17530221-43-crimeloc212" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530221-43-off209 t17530221-43-crimeloc212"></join>, and ordered such cloaths to be put up as I had occasion for while upon guard, which 
               <persName id="t17530221-43-person355">
                  Mary 
                  Brackenbury 
               <interp inst="t17530221-43-person355" type="surname" value="Brackenbury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-person355" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-person355" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sent accordingly, and the key of my door as directed (I am a lodger there, but the furniture is my own). This was on the Thursday, and on the Friday following, about seven in the morning, the chamber-keeper's servant at the guard-room came and told me I had been robbed, and there was a soldier came to acquaint me with it, which was Armstrong, a soldier, who gave me two silver table-spoons, a tobacco-box, and a pocket-book, and asked me if they were mine; I told him they were; then he said I had been robbed the last night, and if I made haste he supposed he'd help me to part of the things and the thief, so I immediately took my pistols which lay on the table, put them in my bosom, and went with him to Long-Acre; he said the thief was in a house in Drury-Lane, and it was not proper for me to go in there, but he'd bring him to me. We went in at the Vine; he went for the man; in the mean time I got a constable, and in a short space of time he came in with the prisoner, and one 
               <persName id="t17530221-43-person356">
                  John 
                  Conner 
               <interp inst="t17530221-43-person356" type="surname" value="Conner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-person356" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-person356" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who is here to give evidence; the servant of the house told me they were gone backwards, so I went into the room, and put a pistol to the prisoner's head, and said, he was a dead man if he resisted; the constable took hold of Conner, and the soldier of the prisoner, we took a parcel that then lay on the table before the prisoner, two linnen shirts, one blue-grey surtout coat, and one hat, all my property, and were in my room when I went to mount guard, (produced in court); we took them before justice<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175302210025"></xptr> Fielding; some time before he was ready to examine them, Armstrong said to me, feel in his pocket for a ing, saying, he saw him have one. I took out this ring (produced in court and deposed to) from the fob of his breeches (it had a chrystal and two diamond sparks) then the other witness (Conner) took me aside, and bid me feel for some stockings, and in the lining of his coat we found a pair of silk stockings, my property; then Mr. Fielding was ready. I told him the things which we there produced were my property . Mr. Fielding asked him what he had to say for himself; he said a woman robbed me and gave them to him to sell, but, upon being asked what woman, he gave no answer; then he said to me, captain, as you have most of your things again, what signifies sending me to goal? let me go home; he also said, captain, I wish you'd shoot me through the head, it would give me ease (or words to that effect.) He was put into a coach to go to goal. I lent the constable my pair of pistols to guard him, and desired he would take care of him. Then I went with Armstrong to the house of one Reason at the saleshop near St. Giles's; the soldier had before given me the key of a large box which was there, I took the key and unlocked it, and found several things in it my property. As soon as I saw the things were mine, I locked it again. Before I examined the whole, we put the box and another parcel into a coach, which Mrs. Reason delivered to me, and then went to my lodgings; when I came there I took out one black velvet coat, one brocaded waistcoat, one pair of velvet breeches, one cloth coat with gold lace, one cloth coat with metal buttons double gilt and engraved, one scarlet coat with black trimming, another with blue trimming, a coat and waistcoat made of Wilton stuff lined with brown holland, two red cloth frocks, one stuff frock, one blue silk waistcoat, one black cloth waistcoat . one worsted waistcoat, two pair of silk breeches, and other goods, as mentioned in the indictment. I got all my woollen goods again; then I asked the soldier if he knew of any more, there being some cotton and some thread stockings, and some shirts missing, which I have not got again; he gave me an account of some shirts of which he'll tell the court. Then I examined my buroe, which I found was broke open, the chamber door of the same, and the brass box was gone that received the bolt of the lock.</p>

               <p>Q. Had you seen the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Showery. I had; he was put into the house few days before this robbery was committed, by Mr. Harris, to take care of the goods for him . He had taken the house, but was not as then come into the house. The prisoner had the key of the house.</p>
               <p>Q. How did the lock of your door appear when you observed it ?</p>
               <p>Showery. It appeared as it did when double locked; the bolt was shot out.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530221-43-person357">
                  John 
                  Armstrong 
               <interp inst="t17530221-43-person357" type="surname" value="Armstrong"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-person357" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-person357" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner at the bar goes by the name of Farrol, and on the 8th of this month, between the hours of seven and eight, he came to me at York-Buildings to the Fox, in Villers-street ; he said he wanted to speak with me, so I got up and went with him to the door, and he told me he had got a parcel of cloths to dispose of, and if I would sell them, or recommend him to any body that would buy them of him, he'd handsomely reward me; I told him I knew a woman that dealt in all manner of cloaths, whose name was Reason, and if he'd go there may be she might buy them; then he saw Conner in the same house, who was drinking in another company, he said he wanted to speak with him, so he went in and brought him out, and told him he had got some cloths ready for him to carry, and then was the time for him to go, saying, he'd not detain him. Then we all three went together.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the night was this?</p>
               <p>Armstrong. It was then near eight at night; we went to Spring Gardens; the prisoner took a key out of his pocket and opened a door, but I did not know whose house it was, though I have been in it since, it is the house the prosecutor lives in. We all three went into the house, and he desired us to stay a moment and he'd bring a light, which he did; then he locked the street door, and in the passage was a large bundle tied up either in a table-cloth or a sheet, in a little room where he said he lay; by the passage there was a long bag full of other cloaths; he said to Conner, do you take that in the passage and I this, which they did; then he unlocked the door, so we went out, and he locked the door after him and put the key in his pocket. We went up by the king's Muse by Long-Acre, and so to Reason's house ; he would have had me take the bundle he carried, when we were about half way, but I would not; I told Mrs. Reason we had got a parcel of cloaths to sell, so he threw them down on the floor and said to her, don't be<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175302210026"></xptr> in fear, madam, for what is here are all none, and wanted to sell them all to her. As soon as they were opened, and she saw the regimentals and rich cloathing, she said her husband was not at home, and she would have nothing to say to them, and looked a little affrighted. I took her aside and whispered to her, and said, I thought they must be some officer's cloaths that he had robbed, and desired she would be so good as to lend me a box or chest to lock them up till next morning, and I would see if I could find the officer who had been robbed, and I would see that she should be rewarded for so doing. At first she did not chuse it, but at last she emptied a box full of her own cloaths and lent me the box, and desired I would do as I pleased; so I put in as many as it would hold and locked it, and put the key in my pocket. The rest we left in the long bag, and tied the bag up in the sheet or table cloth; then the prisoner gave me two large silver spoons and a large silver tobacco-box to see if she would buy them, but she would not, so I kept them. We went away, and the prisoner insisted upon having something to make money that night, so he took four shirts away with him, two of which he gave Conner to pawn. I told him I thought I could bring a person in the morning that would buy them all; the prisoner desired I would bring him as soon in the morning as I could to the Plough in Drury-Lane, and so we parted. Then I went to the place where we had the goods from, and enquired of a man near there if he knew any body belonging to the horse-guards near that place; he told me there was one captain Showery that mounted guard such a day at such a place, and that he lived over the way, so I went home to my quarters, and in the morning early enquired of a Sentinel at Buckingham-Gate for captain Showery, who said he was in bed; I desired he would go immediately and tell him he was robbed; he called to a woman, and she went and acquainted the captain, and presently I was admitted into his apartment, I gave him the pocket-book, tobacco-box, and two silver spoons ; he said they were his ; I told him if he would go with me speedily I would endeavour to help him to his cloaths, and the man that took them; so he went with me to Long-Acre . The rest as the captain had before deposed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530221-43-person358">
                  John 
                  Conner 
               <interp inst="t17530221-43-person358" type="surname" value="Conner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-person358" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-person358" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner came to call me and the last witness at the Fox in Viller's-Street, near Hungerford-Market, on the 18th of this month between seven and eight in the evening; he told me he had a parcel of cloaths to dispose of, and if I would carry them he'd pay me generously for my trouble; he said they were at a house in Spring-Gardens, so we both went with him there.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you ever in the house before ?</p>
               <p>Conner. I had, and lay with the prisoner about six nights in that house; I knew there was a lodger above, but did not know whether it was a man or a woman. The prisoner opened the door with a key, then shut the door and went for a light; then he came and locked the door, he shewed me a bundle for me to carry, which lay in the passage, and he was to carry another . We took them and went to the house of Reason. (He had told me they belonged to a woman who was in the verge of the court, and he was to sell them for her.) The prisoner offered to sell them to Mrs. Reason, but she would have nothing to say to them upon seeing the regimentals, and appeared to be much affrighted; he said she need not be afraid, for they were all his own; by the persuasion of Armstrong she lent him a box to lock them up in till the morning, he locked them up and offered her the key, but she would not have any thing to do with it; then he put it into his pocket. The prisoner brought two pair of silk stockings and four shirts, and said he wanted some money that night. As we were coming down Bridge-street by a pawnbroker's, he desired me to take two of the shirts and pawn them; I asked him what name I should carry them in, and he said, in the name of Johnson; I went and pawned them for half a guinea; then the prisoner appointed to meet me at the Plough in Drury-Lane, in the morning before eight. He and I came, and after him came Armstrong; the prisoner was angry with him for staying so long; Armstrong desired us both to go with him to another house in Long-Acre, saying, he had got a man that would buy the things. The prisoner had this bundle with him that was first produced. When we were got to the house and sat down, the captain and constable came and seized the prisoner and me, and carried us before the justice, where the prisoner was searched, and a ring was found in his right fob, and a pair of silk stockings in the lining of his coat.</p>
               <p>Q. from the prisoner . What did you say to Armstrong, when the captain's door was broke open ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175302210027"></xptr>Conner . I knew nothing of it, nor he neither, at the time we went there.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you ever in the captain's room, when you went to lie with the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Conner . No, I was not so far up stairs.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530221-43-person359">
                  Mary 
                  Reason 
               <interp inst="t17530221-43-person359" type="surname" value="Reason"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-person359" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-person359" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I buy and sell old cloaths, I have seen the soldier Armstrong, three or four time before, he and the other witness and prisoner came to my house, about half an hour after eight at night, on the eighth of this month, they brought two bundles of things, and flung them down on the floor, and asked me if I would buy some cloaths, I said I would buy nothing, at that time of night; the prisoner said, mistress you need not be afraid, for they are all my own, then they offer'd me a silver tobacco box and two large silver spoons. I returned them to the soldier, and would not buy any thing; and desired them to take them all away; then the soldier whispered me, and said, the prisoner had robbed some gentleman, and desired I would lend them a box to pack them up, which I refused, and would have not concern with them, and much desired they would take them away; but upon his intreaty I did lend a box; and he put in as many as he could and lock'd it, the rest they put up in a bundle together. He told me he'd fetch them the next day, and bring the gentleman that had been robbed, which he did, and the gentleman took them away, and sent me the box again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530221-43-person360">
                  Lewis 
                  Jackmore 
               <interp inst="t17530221-43-person360" type="surname" value="Jackmore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-person360" type="given" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-person360" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I let this house for Squire Dickson, to capt. 
               <persName id="t17530221-43-person361">
                  Joseph 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17530221-43-person361" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-person361" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-person361" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , on the 3d of November last, for two years; he had the key deliver'd and had the possession of it, I can't say whether he had any goods put into the house.</p>
               <p>Q. to Captain 
               <persName id="t17530221-43-person362">
                  Showrey
               <interp inst="t17530221-43-person362" type="given" value="Showrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-person362" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Do you know whether captain Harris, has put any goods into the house?</p>
               <p>Showrey. Yes, I have seen chairs, tables, a bed, and some pictures.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530221-43-person363">
                  Mary 
                  Brackingborough 
               <interp inst="t17530221-43-person363" type="surname" value="Brackingborough"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-person363" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-person363" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . Captain 
               <persName id="t17530221-43-person364">
                  Showrey
               <interp inst="t17530221-43-person364" type="given" value="Showrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-person364" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             lodged at the house, at Captain 
               <persName id="t17530221-43-person365">
                  Harris
               <interp inst="t17530221-43-person365" type="given" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-person365" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's in Spring-Gardens, he had the two pair of stairs forwards, I remember his sending for some cloaths to the guard, about a fortnight ago, I delivered them out, the man who came for the portmantua, brought directions for me to lock the door and send the key by him, which I did, and I remember some of these things being in the room, when I locked the door.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530221-43-person366">
                  Mary
                   O'Neal
               <interp inst="t17530221-43-person366" type="surname" value="O'Neal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-person366" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-person366" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I was employ'd to clean the house of Mr. Harris, I remember the prisoner being there yesterday was fortnight, the day I came to the house; he came there about eleven o'clock. I had orders he should get a woman to help me clean the house; he brought one to me on the Thursday; but the woman went away and he was on and off. He said it was not worth my while to begin then, he'd help me the next day. We dined together, after which I went and worked at cleaning, till I could see no longer, and then I went to my lodging; he was there, I said to him, go and shut up the windows; he was drying his stockings, and said, it is not for want of stockings that I am drying these, for I can put on fix pair: he took the key and went, and just as the watchman was calling the hour twelve, he came with the key to me, and laid it down on the dresser: I said to him, don't you lie in the house: he said he had a letter from his master, and he was going to Hyde-Park-Corner, to take care of the horses, and he knew where to lie.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell whether captain Showrey's door was lock'd that day?</p>
               <p>M. O'Neal . I did not go up so high.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530221-43-person367">
                  James 
                  Reynolds 
               <interp inst="t17530221-43-person367" type="surname" value="Reynolds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-person367" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-person367" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable of St. Martin's in the Field's, on the 9th of this month, captain Showrey came before nine in the morning, I went with him to the Vine in Long-Acre, the captain gave me one of his pistols, in about ten minutes, we heard they were come in, we went into the room where they were, and took him and Conner, The rest as the captain and Armstrong had before deposed with this addition; that the prisoner said Armstrong and Conner were the persons that broke open the door and eserutore, corner cupboard, and a tea chest belonging to the captain.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask Armstrong what he did with the gold-lace he took off of the captain's hat, and the knot he took off of the sword.</p>
               <p>Armstrong. I never saw a hat with a lace, I saw three plain ones, the prisoner gave me the knot of lace which he took off the sword with-inside the tobacco-box, and said it would make it weight the better, and I returned it to the captain.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>The soldier Armstrong is the man that did the fact.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17530221-43-verdict213" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-verdict213" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17530221-43-punish214" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530221-43-punish214" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530221-43-defend348 t17530221-43-punish214"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
