<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17581025-2">
               <interp inst="t17581025-2" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581025-2" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581025-2" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17581025"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581025-2" type="date" value="17581025"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17581025-2-off6-c41" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581025-2-defend43 t17581025-2-off6 t17581025-2-verdict8"></join>
         
               <p>325. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17581025-2-defend43" type="defendantName">
                     Edward 
                     Able 
                  <interp inst="t17581025-2-defend43" type="surname" value="Able"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-2-defend43" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-2-defend43" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17581025-2-off6" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581025-2-off6" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-2-off6" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing five chairs with matted seats, value 7 s, 6 d.
            </rs> the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17581025-2-victim45" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Hughes 
                  <interp inst="t17581025-2-victim45" type="surname" value="Hughes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-2-victim45" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-2-victim45" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581025-2-off6 t17581025-2-victim45"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17581025-2-cd7" type="crimeDate">September 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581025-2-off6 t17581025-2-cd7"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581025-2-person46">
                  John 
                  Hughes 
               <interp inst="t17581025-2-person46" type="surname" value="Hughes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-2-person46" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-2-person46" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was burnt out of my house on Sunday the 10th of September, and lost many of goods.</p>
               <p>Q. Why do you charge the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Hughes. I did not know that I had been robbed till after the prisoner was taken up, and five chairs stopped at an alehouse on the Surry side of the water above-bridge; then I was informed of it, and went and saw the chairs, and knew them to be my property.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581025-2-person47">
                  William 
                  Richmond 
               <interp inst="t17581025-2-person47" type="surname" value="Richmond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-2-person47" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-2-person47" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I belong to the Hand-in-Hand fire-office; I was told by a neighbour as I was at the Waterman's-arms Bank-side, that the prisoner had brought five chairs from the fire that was then below bridge, I went and saw the chairs at Mr. Richard's house, in his cellar.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does Mr. Richards live?</p>
               <p>Richmond. He keeps the Waterman's-arms Bank-side, I went and saw the chairs; there was the prisoner, I asked him how he came by them, he told me he took them up in the river Thames; I felt of the seats of the chairs, they were every one of them dry. I told the prisoner he had done the wrong thing by bringing them from the premises.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say to that?</p>
               <p>Richmond. He said nothing at all; I went and told justice Clark of it, he ordered him to be kept in the custody of Mr. Richards.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the fire near the water side?</p>
               <p>Richmond. It was close by the water side; the prosecutor came and owned them.</p>
               <p>Mr. Richards. I keep the Waterman's-arms Bank-side, there were five chairs brought into my house by a gentleman unknown to me, and the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. How many of them did the prisoner bring ?</p>
               <p>Mr. Richards. He brought in one or two of them.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say concerning how he came by them?</p>
               <p>Mr. Richards. He said he had taken them upon the river Thames as they were swimming, and that there was a great fire below bridge where he took them up.</p>
               <p>Q. to the prosecutor. In what part of the house did you see those chairs?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I saw them in a one pair of stairs room.</p>
               <p>Q. to Richards. How came the chairs to be removed out of the cellar to that room above?</p>
               <p>Richards. The prisoner was going to take the chairs away on the Monday morning, and as I was ordered by justice Clark not to deliver them to him; I carryed them up stairs, I having a back door to my cellar, at which it is possible he might have got in and taken them away.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is that gentleman you mention, that brought some of them into your house?</p>
               <p>Richards. I do not know any thing of him, it seems he was going by and saw the chairs in the prisoner's possession, and he asked him how he came by them; the prisoner told him he took them up as they were floating on the river; so the gentleman said they ought to be kept in somebody's custody till the right owner came for them; he carried them first to a chandler's shop and the woman would not take them in, so he was directed to my house; he came and said, landlord give these chairs house-room till the right owner comes, here is a waterman says<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175810250004"></xptr> he found them swimming on the river Thames, he insisted upon their being put in some other person's custody, and not in the hands of the prisoner at the bar, thinking he did not come honestly by them.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen the gentleman since?</p>
               <p>Richards. No I have not.</p>
               <p>Q. to Richmond. Did the prisoner say he picked up five chairs?</p>
               <p>Richmond. I mentioned the five chairs to him, and told him he should not have brought them through bridge but have put them on shore near the place where he took them up.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you charge him with stealing them?</p>
               <p>Richmond. I told him I believed he took them from the fire on shore.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say to that ?</p>
               <p>Richmond. He said nothing to that: I told him they were as dry as they were when they were made.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the fire burning at that time?</p>
               <p>Richmond. The fire was burning about five or six hours that Sunday morning.</p>
               <p>Q. to Richards. What time were the chairs brought into your house?</p>
               <p>Richards. They were brought in between the hours of four and five on Sunday Sept. 10.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is it from your house to the place where the fire was?</p>
               <p>Richards. It is better than half a mile distance.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was with my boat below bridge, I happened to see this fire, there were two chairs a floating, a young gentleman desired me to hand them out of the water, I did, presently I saw three more, he desired me to take them up too, I thought they might be his chairs; after that I could not find him, so I brought them to Mr. Richards's house, because the house was all of a hurly-burly, I had not a pipe of tobacco for taking them up.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581025-2-person48">
                  William 
                  Gurney 
               <interp inst="t17581025-2-person48" type="surname" value="Gurney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-2-person48" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-2-person48" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am engineer to the Hand-in-Hand fire-office, I have known the prisoner about twenty five years, he has behaved very well.</p>
               <p>Q. How has he behaved of late ?</p>
               <p>Gurney, I never heard that he robbed any body of the value of a six-pence, he has been at fires with me divers times and always behaved well.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he employed at this fire can you tell?</p>
               <p>Gurney. No he was not, I am lame and could not attend it.</p>
               <p>Mr. Higgins. I heard the prisoner demand the chairs of Richmond before he went to justice Clark, he told Richmond he would carry them to the place where he took them up that they might be given to the right owner.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say whose chairs they were?</p>
               <p>Higgins. No he did not, and I think he never knew whose chairs they were.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17581025-2-verdict8" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581025-2-verdict8" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
