<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17571207-24">
               <interp inst="t17571207-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17571207-24" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17571207-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17571207"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17571207-24" type="date" value="17571207"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17571207-24-off126-c180" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571207-24-defend222 t17571207-24-off126 t17571207-24-verdict128"></join>
         
               <p>29. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17571207-24-defend222" type="defendantName">
                     Samuel 
                     Huggins 
                  <interp inst="t17571207-24-defend222" type="surname" value="Huggins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-24-defend222" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-24-defend222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17571207-24-off126" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17571207-24-off126" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-24-off126" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving the said fat, knowing it to have been stolen
            </rs>, <rs id="t17571207-24-cd127" type="crimeDate">Nov. 28</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571207-24-off126 t17571207-24-cd127"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571207-24-person223">
                  Mary 
                  Bates 
               <interp inst="t17571207-24-person223" type="surname" value="Bates"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-24-person223" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-24-person223" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was sworn and deposed, That Sebisa Hewett was convicted for stealing this fat, and without her evidence she should not be able to convict the prisoner; upon which Hewett was order'd to be branded in the hand, which was done accordingly.</p>
               <p>Sebisa Hewett. I took eighteen pounds of fat, my mistress's property, and went to sell it to a tallow-chandler, at the corner of Bull-Inn Court, but he would not buy it.</p>
               <p>Q. For what reason would he not buy it?</p>
               <p>S. Hewett. Because it stunk so. Then I went to Mr. Huggins's house, and he gave me three halfpence a pound for it, which was four pence halfpenny for three pounds; I carried some twice, and his boy bought and paid me for it; and another time the maid give me three pence for two pounds.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever any discourse with Mr. Huggins abous fat?</p>
               <p>S. Hewett. No, never.</p>
               <p>Q. What was this fat made of?</p>
               <p>S. Hewett. It was the trimmings of hogs and bullocks bladders, fat and skin together.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your mistress's business?</p>
               <p>S. Hewett. She sells bladders to apothecaries and oil shops, and the fat that comes off them she sells to tallow-chandlers.</p>
               <p>Q. Does she make gold-beater's skin?</p>
               <p>S. Hewett. No, she does not.</p>
               <p>Q. Is this all her business?</p>
               <p>S. Hewett. It is.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175712070014"></xptr>Q. Do you imagine Mr. Huggins apprehended you stole it?</p>
               <p>S. Hewett. I only sold him some once; he did not ask me any questions.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he a housekeeper?</p>
               <p>S. Hewett. Yes, and lives in great credit.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571207-24-person224">
                  Mary 
                  Bates 
               <interp inst="t17571207-24-person224" type="surname" value="Bates"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-24-person224" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-24-person224" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I missed my sat last Monday morning, so ask'd the girl when she came home what she had done with it. She was very angry with me. I put on my hat and cloak, and went and found it in the scale, in Mr. Huggins's shop. I asked his servant who he bought it of, and he described the prisoner at the bar. Then Mr. Huggins came into the shop. I asked him to let his servant go with me to my house, to see my servant. He said he should go with me. The boy went with me, and fix'd upon the prisoner as soon as he saw her, and said, to her face, you brought me four pounds in the morning, and four pounds just now. Then I went to Mr. Huggins's shop, and took 
               <persName id="t17571207-24-person225">
                  Esther 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17571207-24-person225" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-24-person225" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-24-person225" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (one that cleans my bladders for me) along with me. I said to him, how could you be so hard hearted to buy this sat? I think he said his shop was his market, but I will not be positive.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you value the sat at?</p>
               <p>M. Bates. At two pence halfpenny per pound.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find the sat in his publick shop?</p>
               <p>M. Bates. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>M. Bates. I deal in bladders of bullocks and hogs.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you deal largely?</p>
               <p>M. Bates. I deal for 400 l. a year. I sell to apothecaries, tobacconists, oil-men, and the like; I don't keep them to eat and drink.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember you said before justice St. Lawrance, that you did not believe he knew that fat was stolen?</p>
               <p>M. Bates. I don't know.</p>
               <p>Q. Will you swear you did not say so?</p>
               <p>M. Bates. I will not swear that. I remember I beg'd of Mr. Huggins to make it up, and said I would be at half the charges.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. This woman came to my shop and said her servant had rob'd her, and had brought some sat to my shop. I said I was very sorry for it, and would send my boy to her house, to see if he could find it out; but the woman was extremely insolent to me and used me very ill.</p>
               <p>M. Bates. When I had the girl before the justice, he said what do you bring her here for. I said, I would forgive her, if Mr. Huggins would; but he would not, and insisted upon her being prosecuted. I could not help prosecuting her, upon his threatening her and me too.</p>
               <p>Q. For what reason did you prosecute her?</p>
               <p>M. Bates. Because he insisted upon it that I should prosecute her.</p>
               <p>Q. to Hewett. Where did Mr. Huggins buy that three pounds of sat of you?</p>
               <p>S. Hewett. In his own shop.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he buy it publickly, or in a secret manner?</p>
               <p>S. Hewett. No, he bought it publickly.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he weigh it in the publick shop?</p>
               <p>S. Hewett. He did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571207-24-person226">
                  Esther 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17571207-24-person226" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-24-person226" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-24-person226" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I clean the bladders for Mrs. Bates, and went with her to Mr. Huggins, where the fat was then in his scale. We desired him to let his servant go with us to see the prisoner. He said he should, and sent him with us; I knew the sat as soon as I saw it.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mr. Kempster. I am a tallow-chandler, and have bought many a hundred weight of this fat when I was apprentice: My master took all they made, and he never gave more than a penny a pound for it, when candles were as dear as they are now. I would not give a penny a pound for it. I have turn'd such out of my shop, and would not take it in at all, it is so nauseous and sinking.</p>
               <p>There were many other witnesses of the trade to give him a character, but the court thinking it needless to examine them, he was honourably <rs id="t17571207-24-verdict128" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17571207-24-verdict128" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>It was ordered to be so inserted as the opinion of the court and the jury.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571207-24-person227">
                  John 
                  Thorp 
               <interp inst="t17571207-24-person227" type="surname" value="Thorp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-24-person227" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-24-person227" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , one of the jury, before the trial came on, told the court Mr. Huggins was his acquaintance, and that he believed him to be as honest a man as any living; and desiring the court he might not be of the jury, that he might not be charged with partiality, 
               <persName id="t17571207-24-person228">
                  George 
                  Carbold 
               <interp inst="t17571207-24-person228" type="surname" value="Carbold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-24-person228" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-24-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was sworn in his stead.</p>
            </div1>
