<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17511016-50">
               <interp inst="t17511016-50" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511016-50" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511016-50" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17511016"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511016-50" type="date" value="17511016"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17511016-50-off230-c281" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-50-defend367 t17511016-50-off230 t17511016-50-verdict232"></join>
         
               <p>603. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17511016-50-defend367" type="defendantName">
                  John 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17511016-50-defend367" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-defend367" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-defend367" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17511016-50-off230" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-off230" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-off230" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one gold ring with diamonds, one silver snuff-box, one tortoise-shell snuff-box, and one laced pair of russles, the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17511016-50-victim369" type="victimName">
                           Charles 
                           Tompson 
                        <interp inst="t17511016-50-victim369" type="surname" value="Tompson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17511016-50-victim369" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17511016-50-victim369" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-50-off230 t17511016-50-victim369"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling-house of the said Charles
            </rs>, <rs id="t17511016-50-cd231" type="crimeDate">August 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-50-off230 t17511016-50-cd231"></join>. || .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-50-person370">
                  Charles 
                  Tompson 
               <interp inst="t17511016-50-person370" type="surname" value="Tompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person370" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person370" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I employed Mr. Wilmote, a master-plaisterer, who sent the prisoner to do some white-washing in my house. After he was gone I missed several things, which before were locked up in the drawers, and found the drawers open.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he any body worked with him?</p>
               <p>Tompson. I cannot say I saw any body else but the prisoner, and a boy to attend him. When I came to enquire the prisoner's character, it gave me more ground for suspicion. I took out a search-warrant, and the constable and I went and searched his house, but found nothing. Upon hearing he was seen with a ring on his finger, described like that I lost, I took him up.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you lose?</p>
               <p>Tompson. I lost a ring with seven rose diamonds, a silver snuff-box, a tortoise-shell snuff-box, some Brussels lace, and a small silver porringer.</p>
               <p>Cross-Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the ring pet ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175110160025"></xptr>Tompson. It was in a mahogany desk buroe.</p>
               <p>Q. Who kept the key of it?</p>
               <p>Tompson. My wife.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it locked when the prisoner came to work?</p>
               <p>Tompson. I cannot say it was.</p>
               <p>Q. What family have you?</p>
               <p>Tompson. I have a servant man, a servant maid, and two sons.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this room, when washing, open to any body of the family?</p>
               <p>Tompson. At that time it was.</p>
               <p>Q. Had not the prisoner a labourer to attend him?</p>
               <p>Tompson. There might be for what I know. I will not say there was not.</p>
               <p>Q. How many rooms had you white-washed?</p>
               <p>Tompson. There were two more rooms beside the room where the things were. He did them all three.</p>
               <p>Q. Were not the rooms left open for him to have access from one to the other upon occasion?</p>
               <p>Tompson. They were.</p>
               <p>Q. When were they finished ?</p>
               <p>Tompson. They were finished the twenty-ninth of August.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you seen the things last?</p>
               <p>Tompson. I had seen the ring on my wife's finger three or four days before.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-50-person371">
                  Mary 
                  Tompson 
               <interp inst="t17511016-50-person371" type="surname" value="Tompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person371" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person371" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had the diamond ring on my finger the 26th of 
               <persName id="t17511016-50-person372">
                  August 
                  There 
               <interp inst="t17511016-50-person372" type="surname" value="There"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person372" type="given" value="August"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person372" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             were seven diamonds of middling water roses. On the 28th I went to my drawers, took up the shagreen case in which my ring was put, and shook it; it rattled. I had my child stood by me; he had been at sea; he asked me what it was; I said a ring.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you open the case?</p>
               <p>M. Tompson. I did not; but it was a case for only a single ring; and as I shook it, I heard it plain. I missed it the second of September. To the best of my knowledge I locked the drawers, but I will not swear that. The prisoner was at work during the time I had the ring upon my finger, and after I put it in the drawer.</p>
               <p>Cross-Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know your ring was not gone at that time you say something rattled?</p>
               <p>M. Tompson. At that time I had the case, but when I missed the ring, I missed the case likewise.</p>
               <p>Q. What water were the diamonds?</p>
               <p>M. Tompson. They were rather of a yellowish cast, not a clear water.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you a judge of that ?</p>
               <p>M. Tompson. I was brought up in the business.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see this ring since?</p>
               <p>M. Tompson. No, Sir, I have not.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>M. Tompson. We keep Will's Coffee-house in Cornhill.</p>
               <p>Q. Had your servants access to these rooms, during the time of white-washing?</p>
               <p>M. Tompson. Yes, Sir, they had.</p>
               <p>Q. What room were the goods in?</p>
               <p>M. Tompson. It was a one pair of stairs room.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the prisoner a labourer to assist him?</p>
               <p>M. Tompson. I believe he had, but I don't think he was ever in that room, for it wanted no scraping, nor no mortar. I believe there was none but the boy attended him in that room.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-50-person373">
                  Henry 
                  Benson 
               <interp inst="t17511016-50-person373" type="surname" value="Benson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person373" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person373" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am of the same trade the prisoner is of. On Sunday, the first of September, the prisoner came to the Coach and Horses at the lower end of St. Martin's Lane, and asked me if I would drink; he called for a pint of beer, and we sat down together. He had a ring on his finger, which I supposed then to be a diamond ring. I never saw a ring on his finger before.</p>
               <p>Q. Describe it.</p>
               <p>Benson. There was one stone in the middle, one of each side, and two between of each side, being seven in all; but the middle stone was the largest. It was a very handsome ring. In the afternoon Mr. Kite and I took a walk. When we got into Duke-street, at the Bricklayers Arms, we saw the prisoner and his wife coming along; we called him in, he came, and we drank three or four full pots of beer together, which Mr. Kite paid for; then the prisoner and I called for an eighteen penny tiff of punch, which we paid betwixt us; there I saw the ring again several times. The prisoner was taken on Saturday the seventh at the pay-table; he said he could produce the ring he had on that Sunday; he produced one, but it looked as much like it, as this candlestick is like the ring, (pointing to a brass candlestick.) There were three stones on it, and so black, I don't know what metal it was. The prosecutor asked me if it was the same ring, I said it was not.</p>
               <p>Cross-Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. How near did you sit to the prisoner at the alehouse?</p>
               <p>Benson. We were so near to each other, that we touched one another.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175110160026"></xptr>Q. Which finger was the ring on?</p>
               <p>Benson. It was on his right hand little finger. I saw it when he went to light his pipe, or take hold on the mug.</p>
               <p>Q. Who told you how many stones there were?</p>
               <p>Benson. I never was told at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you and he any quarrel?</p>
               <p>Benson. No, none at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you speak to the prisoner about the ring ?</p>
               <p>Benson. No, I did not. Mr. Kite and I talked about it after, but not there.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure the ring you saw afterwards was not the ring you saw on the prisoner's finger?</p>
               <p>Benson. I am sure it was not; it was not like it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-50-person374">
                  Richard 
                  Kite 
               <interp inst="t17511016-50-person374" type="surname" value="Kite"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person374" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person374" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Coach and Horses at the bottom of St. Martin's Lane, a publick-house. I remember the prisoner being in company with 
               <persName id="t17511016-50-person375">
                  Henry 
                  Benson 
               <interp inst="t17511016-50-person375" type="surname" value="Benson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person375" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person375" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             on the first of September in the morning; I did not drink with them, being too soon in the morning for me. I did not see the ring in my house. I took a walk, and about three o'clock the same day I was in company with him and Benson at the Bricklayers Arms in Duke-street, Grosvenor-square. We had four tankards of beer, and I paid a shilling for them; then they two called for eighteen pennyworth of punch. I there saw a very handsome ring on the prisoner's right hand finger. I could swear to the make of the ring: there was a large stone in the middle, two at the ends drawed into a point, and two on each side. I have not seen such a one these twenty years; it was a seven stone ring, and there was a great deal of lustre.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was you in company with the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Kite. About three hours.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a diamond ring?</p>
               <p>Kite. I have seen a great many diamond rings, it looked like a diamond ring.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner ?</p>
               <p>Kite. He is sometimes a master-plaisterer, and sometimes a journeyman.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever observe he had a ring on before?</p>
               <p>Kite. No, not to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Cross-Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. How came it you did not see this fine ring in the morning?</p>
               <p>Kite. I did not sit down with them then.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was it, you or Benson, that spoke first about the ring?</p>
               <p>Kite. It was me that first spoke to Benson about it.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was you the prisoner when in Duke-street?</p>
               <p>Kite. I was within a yard of him three hours.</p>
               <p>Q. How came it you did not ask him concerning it?</p>
               <p>Kite. Because it would have been a piece of ill manners.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs. Tompson. What sort of make was the ring you lost?</p>
               <p>M. Tompson. It was old fashion make, some may call it a fancy ring, it was set a little odd; it had seven diamonds ; the middle one not very large, five on the shank; and two opposite. The diamonds are roses, but not set like a rose.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had it been set?</p>
               <p>M. Tompson. Fifteen years at least.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-50-person376">
                  Sarah 
                  Griffin 
               <interp inst="t17511016-50-person376" type="surname" value="Griffin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person376" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person376" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw a ring on the prisoner's finger with seven stones in it, in his own apartment, in company with his wife; it looked very well.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>S. Griffin. It was on a Sunday night about two months ago, I never saw him have such a one on before; I lodged in his house.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know there were seven stones ?</p>
               <p>S. Griffin. I counted them, the middle one was biggest.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you speak to him about it?</p>
               <p>S. Griffin. No, I did not, nor he to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you talked with Mr. Tompson about it?</p>
               <p>S. Griffin. I never saw him before to-day. I had a subpoena brought me last night; it is very likely I might speak of such a thing, but I did not think to have been brought here about it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-50-person377">
                  Mary 
                  Griffin 
               <interp inst="t17511016-50-person377" type="surname" value="Griffin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person377" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person377" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw a tortoiseshell snuff box in the shape of a book; the prisoner's little girl gave it me into my hand, she had it to play with.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mr. Bailey. I am a master bricklayer; the prisoner worked for me last summer was twelvemonth for about three months; he is an honest man as far as I know.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-50-person378">
                  Thomas 
                  Paston 
               <interp inst="t17511016-50-person378" type="surname" value="Paston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person378" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person378" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a master bricklayer. I have known him about four years; he worked for me about two months ago. I never heard a bad character of him before this.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175110160027"></xptr>Mr. Owen. I have known him about three years. I keep a publick house; he has frequented my house several times; I have left him a great many times where there has been plate, China, linen, and other things, which he might have taken away had he been a bad man. I never heard his character was bad till now.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-50-person379">
                  Ishmael 
                  Reves 
               <interp inst="t17511016-50-person379" type="surname" value="Reves"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person379" type="given" value="Ishmael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person379" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him betwixt four and five years. I am a carpenter; we have worked together at several places; I always looked upon him to be an honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-50-person380">
                  Joseph 
                  Bridges 
               <interp inst="t17511016-50-person380" type="surname" value="Bridges"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person380" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person380" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him between four and five years. I am a carpenter and joiner; I have worked with him several times, where he might have stolen those things; I never heard any ill of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-50-person381">
                  James 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17511016-50-person381" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person381" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person381" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him betwixt three and four years; he had a general good character till lately.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-50-person382">
                  William 
                  Peters 
               <interp inst="t17511016-50-person382" type="surname" value="Peters"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person382" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person382" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a tyler. I have known him about three years; he always had a good character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-50-person383">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Jewel 
               <interp inst="t17511016-50-person383" type="surname" value="Jewel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person383" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person383" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him above ten years. I knew him in Bristol; he had the character of an honest man.</p>

               <p>Mr. Pearson. I am an officer belonging to the Marshalsea Court. I have known him by being about the neighbourhood; I never heard any ill of him till this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-50-person384">
                  John 
                  Hays 
               <interp inst="t17511016-50-person384" type="surname" value="Hays"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person384" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-person384" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about a year; he has done business for me; he might have robbed me of several tankards; I never heard a bad character of him in my life.</p>
               <p>Mr. Holt. I have known him between three and four years; he has been often in my house; I never heard a bad character of him, except this thing. These evidences were all asked if they had ever seen him with a diamond ring on his finger, or any other ring. They all answered in the negative.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17511016-50-verdict232" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17511016-50-verdict232" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
