<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17520116-22">
               <interp inst="t17520116-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520116-22" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520116-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520116-22" type="date" value="17520116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520116-22-off123-c203" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520116-22-defend250 t17520116-22-off123 t17520116-22-verdict126"></join>
         
               <p>104. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17520116-22-defend250" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Batleys 
                  <interp inst="t17520116-22-defend250" type="surname" value="Batleys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-22-defend250" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-22-defend250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for that <rs id="t17520116-22-off123" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520116-22-off123" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-22-off123" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               he, on the <rs id="t17520116-22-cd124" type="crimeDate">31st of Decem</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520116-22-off123 t17520116-22-cd124"></join>. about the hour of four in the night, on the same day the dwelling house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17520116-22-victim252" type="victimName">
                           Francis 
                           Taylor 
                        <interp inst="t17520116-22-victim252" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520116-22-victim252" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520116-22-victim252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520116-22-off123 t17520116-22-victim252"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , did break and enter, one hat, value 4 s. one linnen napkin, one table cloath, one knife, the goods of the said Francis, out of the Dwelling house did steal
            </rs>, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520116-22-person253">
                  Francis 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17520116-22-person253" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-22-person253" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-22-person253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the <placeName id="t17520116-22-crimeloc125">Cock in Tottenham court-road</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17520116-22-crimeloc125" type="placeName" value="Cock in Tottenham court-road"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520116-22-crimeloc125" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520116-22-off123 t17520116-22-crimeloc125"></join> ; on the 31st of December between ten and eleven o'clock at night, I shut up the house; the last thing we do, is to look round to see that all things is safe; we did so that night; then we went to bed between four and five in the morning; the bitch in the house made a great barking, I knocked with my shoe, the maid got up, and went down; in about two minutes after I heard murder and thieves called, I jumped out of bed, the servant man and a lodger came down, we searched the house round about and found nothing, we found the yard and cellar doors open; there was a casement that looks into the cellar, out of the yard, had an iron bar cross it, that was broke much, but they could not get it open; we went down into the cellar, and there we found the prisoner, by the side of one of the butts; we searched him and found the hat he had on was my son's; he had a napkin round his neck, and a table cloth round his body, like an apron tucked up, and a case knife in his bosom, all my property; he had a large stick in his hand; the napkin and table cloth were in the kitchen, we had used them just before we went to bed; in the kitchen window there was a pane of glass taken out to put a hand in, to open the window, which stood open; the hat was in a band box, in a one pair of stairs room; the prisoner said he and three more were with him; he said he bid them go away out of the cellar door; and that as he knew the house, he would go away at any time; he had been taken the Monday was a month before in my house and sent to Bridewell, he said he had agreed with some men in Bridewell, a week before, to come and rob this house, he knowing it well; and that he pushed one of them into the casement, and then he crept after; he said he went thro' my entry about nine o'clock, and by the help of a ladder in our yard, took a pane of glass out of my window where<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175201160028"></xptr> I lie, but the inside shutter was shut, so could not proceed any farther ; then they went up a ladder into my hay-loft, and covered themselves with hay ; my man had been about ten o'clock into the loft, to put on his coat which was there, and he buttoned the door with a great button, as big as my fist, and in the morning that was burst open.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520116-22-person254">
                  Mary 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17520116-22-person254" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-22-person254" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-22-person254" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Taylor; I came down stairs betwixt four and five; the bitch made a noise; my master knocked to know whether any of us were up; I went down, and the bitch followed me into the tap room; the prisoner struck me down with a stick; I had a candle in my hand; I saw his face at that time; I said, in the name of God, what do you do here? I cry'd out murder ; I ran up stairs, he followed me, and struck me down again upon the Stairs; then he made down into the cellar; then my master and others went down, and in about half an hour's time, they brought him up stairs; he had this napkin about his neck, and this table-cloth about his body, like a brewer's apron, my master's son's hat on his head, and one of our cafe knives in his bosom; I heard him tell my master, he got in at the kitchen window, and through the entry into the hay-loft, with two others with him, and another came afterwards.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520116-22-person255">
                  William 
                  Helme 
               <interp inst="t17520116-22-person255" type="surname" value="Helme"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-22-person255" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-22-person255" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Taylor; I came down betwixt four and five o'clock; I heard the cry of murder and thieves; the other two men were with me; we searched the taproom and yard, and found nothing; then we went down into the cellar; there we took the prisoner with the things mentioned upon him; I heard him say, he slid in at the cellar window, and two men with him, and went into the hay-loft, and that their intent was to strip the kitchen.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520116-22-person256">
                  John 
                  Haywood 
               <interp inst="t17520116-22-person256" type="surname" value="Haywood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-22-person256" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-22-person256" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable; on New-year's-day I was knocked up out of my bed to come to the prosecutor's: when I came there, they had got the prisoner in one of the boxes in the taproom: I said, what, Will, are you come again? I had carried him to Bridewell before; I thought your time had not been expired; said he, I was turned out yesterday ; said I, you look to have a better hat on than you had on in Bridewell; Mr. Taylor looked at it, and said, it was his son's hat; then the prisoner said, he took it out of a band-box up stairs; then Mr. Taylor began to feel on his apron, and said, what have you got here, this is my table cloth, where did you get it? he said, he had it from out of the kitchen; then he took the napkin from round the prisoner's neck; then the prosecutor asked him, how he could come here again; he said, he and two more men agreed in Bridewell, when they got out, to come and rob the house, and gave an account how they got in, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I went through the entry, and lay on the mow; I was hungry, and did not know what to do, so I went in and got somewhat to eat, and took that knife to eat with; I had had no victuals for five days before.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520116-22-verdict126" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520116-22-verdict126" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17520116-22-punish127" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520116-22-punish127" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520116-22-defend250 t17520116-22-punish127"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
