<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17580113-17">
               <interp inst="t17580113-17" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580113-17" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580113-17" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580113"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580113-17" type="date" value="17580113"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580113-17-off97-c149" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-17-defend179 t17580113-17-off97 t17580113-17-verdict100"></join>
         
               <p>74. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17580113-17-defend179" type="defendantName">
                  Elizabeth, <rs id="t17580113-17-deflabel96" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-17-defend179 t17580113-17-deflabel96"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17580113-17-person180">
                        John
                          Allen
                     <interp inst="t17580113-17-person180" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580113-17-person180" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580113-17-person180" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
                     <interp inst="t17580113-17-defend179" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-17-defend179" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-17-defend179" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for that <rs id="t17580113-17-off97" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580113-17-off97" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-17-off97" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               she, on the <rs id="t17580113-17-cd98" type="crimeDate">20th of November</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-17-off97 t17580113-17-cd98"></join>, about the hour of twelve in the night of the same day, the dwelling house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17580113-17-victim182" type="victimName">
                           Daniel 
                           Field 
                        <interp inst="t17580113-17-victim182" type="surname" value="Field"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580113-17-victim182" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580113-17-victim182" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-17-off97 t17580113-17-victim182"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did break and enter, and two cotton gowns, value 20 s. one crape gown, value 5 s. one linen gown, value 18 d. one callimanco petticoat, value 3 s. two other petticoats, one pair of slays, value 2 s. eight linen caps, six linen handkerchiefs, three linen aprons. and two pieces of cotton, the goods of the said Daniel, did steal in his dwelling house
            </rs>. +</p>
               <p>Mrs. Field. I am wife to the prosecutor, and we live at <placeName id="t17580113-17-crimeloc99">Finchley</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17580113-17-crimeloc99" type="placeName" value="Finchley"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17580113-17-crimeloc99" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-17-off97 t17580113-17-crimeloc99"></join>. We went to bed on the 20th of November last, about nine o'clock at night.</p>
               <p>Q. What servants do you keep ?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Field. We keep none at all. There were a man and his wife lodged in the house, but they went to bed before us.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see all was fast when you went to bed?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Field. The doors were fasten'd as soon as it was dark, lock'd and bolted</p>
               <p>Q. How many doors have you to your house ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175801130016"></xptr>Mrs. Field. We have two; one has two bolts, and the other a lock and a bolt.</p>
               <p>Q. How were the windows fasten'd?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Field. They were fasten'd as usual.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there nobody in your house that night but you and your husband, and the two people ?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Field. Yes, my three children one betwixt six and seven years old, another betwixt eleven and twelve, the other thirteen and three relations that came to see us; but my husband and I went to bed last, and arose together in the morning a little before seven o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any noise in the night?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Field. No, none at all The man that lodges in my house got up before me came to the stair-foot, and ask'd who was up, nobody. He said, I thought you had been washing, for here are the cloaths scattered about upon the floor.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his name?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Field. His name is Hapworth. When we came down, we found the window was broke, under where I lie, and the back door open.</p>
               <p>Q. How was the window broke?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Field. The glass was broke, and the shutter open'd; the key of the door was left over-night on the inside. I missed two cotton gowns, one of which was taken from out of the room I lie in, one bed gown, one quilted petticoat, two under petticoats, and my stays.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not lock your chamber door?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Field. No, we left that open because we would hear the children if they wanted any thing. The other cotton gown and a crape gown, a quilted petticoat and a baize-petticoat, were taken out of a chest in the next room to where I lie. I missed a handbox with 6 handkerchiefs, 8 caps, 4 pair of ruffles, and two pieces of cotton to make frocks of, from out of my room; likewise a pair of shift sleeves with ruffles sewed to them, and 3 colour'd aprons, from out of the room they first broke into, and a shift and a petticoat from out of the passage. I could not tell who to suspect.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner before ?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Field. No, I never saw her before I saw her in New prison with some of my cloaths on her back.</p>
               <p>Q. How was she apprehended ?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Field. She was taken up in Rosemary-Lane, as she was selling some things belonging to Mr. Coleman, who has another indictment against her for breaking his house and stealing things.</p>
               <p>Q. What things of your's had she on?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Field. A gown, petticoat and handkerchief. I charged her with stealing them from me. At first she denied it, and said her husband brought them from Scotland. I went to justice Welch, and gave an account of what I had lost, and what I had seen on the prisoner's back. He sent for her, and going along she denied it, but at last said she would tell all before the justice.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you get any of your things again ?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Field. I had several of them again. Before the justice she said, that herself and two more a man and a woman, broke the window with a penknife, thro' which they all got in, then opened the door, went all up into my room, and saw us asleep in bed, and that she came down and stood at the door, till the others brought away the things.</p>
               <p>Q Did she confess they took all the things mention'd in the indictment?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Field. She did. She said if I did not find them the other woman had them, but she could not tell where she was. I found some of the things again; a cotton gown, a petticoat, and 2 pieces of cotton, at Mr. Towers's, in High-Holbourn, and a shift and quilted petticoat, which the prisoner had sold to one 
               <persName id="t17580113-17-person183">
                  Sophia 
                  Philips 
               <interp inst="t17580113-17-person183" type="surname" value="Philips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-17-person183" type="given" value="Sophia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-17-person183" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in Gray's Inn-Lane; the rest of the things she said were in Catherine's-Lane, where she lodged. There were a crape gown, a bed gown, two petticoats, two caps and a handkerchief, at the house of 
               <persName id="t17580113-17-person184">
                  Margaret 
                  Holt 
               <interp inst="t17580113-17-person184" type="surname" value="Holt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-17-person184" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-17-person184" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . We went to these places by her direction, she going with us ( produced in court, and deposed to.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-17-person185">
                  Daniel 
                  Field 
               <interp inst="t17580113-17-person185" type="surname" value="Field"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-17-person185" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-17-person185" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the prosecutor. I saw the prisoner come to our house the morning before the robbery, to ask charity.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see her before that time?</p>
               <p>Field. No.</p>
               <p>Q. How was the window of your house broke open?</p>
               <p>Field. There was a pane of glass broke, by which means they could put in their hand and open the window, and so get in.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you give any farther account than what your wife has done?</p>
               <p>Field. No, I can not; I heard the prisoner's confession, as my wife has related.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-17-person186">
                  Martha 
                  Towers 
               <interp inst="t17580113-17-person186" type="surname" value="Towers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-17-person186" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-17-person186" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a sale shop, at the Ship and Shears in High-Holbourn. The prisoner at the bar came to my shop about six weeks ago, towards eleven in the forenoon, and I bought a gown, a petticoat, and two pieces of cotton of her.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175801130017"></xptr>Q. Look among these things, and see if you know them ?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-17-person187">
                  Martha 
                  Towers 
               <interp inst="t17580113-17-person187" type="surname" value="Towers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-17-person187" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-17-person187" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . These are the same things ( taking them in her hand) to the best of my knowledge. I bought another flannel petticoat of her, but that I sold again.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you give for them all ?</p>
               <p>M. Towers. To the best of my knowledge I gave 11 s. 3 d. for them.</p>
               <p>Q. What was that petticoat worth that you sold?</p>
               <p>M. Towers. That was worth a shilling.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. The constable and I found some things at the house of 
               <persName id="t17580113-17-person188">
                  Margaret 
                  Holt 
               <interp inst="t17580113-17-person188" type="surname" value="Holt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-17-person188" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-17-person188" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-17-person189">
                  Thomas 
                  Witts 
               <interp inst="t17580113-17-person189" type="surname" value="Witts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-17-person189" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-17-person189" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable. [He produced a gown, two petticoats, a bed gown, two caps, a pair of ruffles, and a handkerchief, which were deposed to by the prosecutor's wife. ]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-17-person190">
                  Charles 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17580113-17-person190" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-17-person190" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-17-person190" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable, I was sent by justice Welch with the prisoner to find out the black quilted petticoat, where she said she had sold it She said she did not know the name of the place, but I followed her. She went to the house of 
               <persName id="t17580113-17-person191">
                  Sophia 
                  Philips 
               <interp inst="t17580113-17-person191" type="surname" value="Philips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-17-person191" type="given" value="Sophia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-17-person191" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and there I found it I heard the prisoner say, there was a man and a woman concern'd with her in breaking the house, and stealing the things.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she saw what were their names ?</p>
               <p>Smith. She said their names were John and 
               <persName id="t17580113-17-person192">
                  Sarah 
                  Cotter 
               <interp inst="t17580113-17-person192" type="surname" value="Cotter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-17-person192" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-17-person192" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I came from Scotland, and have no friends here. My husband is a soldier, and is now at Portsmouth, and was gone a fortnight before I was put in consinement. Cotter and his wife did not come from Scotland with me, I met with them in the house where I lodg'd.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17580113-17-verdict100" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580113-17-verdict100" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17580113-17-punish101" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580113-17-punish101" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-17-defend179 t17580113-17-punish101"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>There was another indictment for a crime of the same nature at Hendon, but being cast upon this, the court did not try her for the other.</p>
            </div1>
