<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17530607-10">
               <interp inst="t17530607-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530607-10" type="year" value="1753"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530607-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17530607"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530607-10" type="date" value="17530607"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17530607-10-off38-c63" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530607-10-defend80 t17530607-10-off38 t17530607-10-verdict40"></join>
         
               <p>270. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17530607-10-defend80" type="defendantName">
                     Edward 
                     Christophers 
                  <interp inst="t17530607-10-defend80" type="surname" value="Christophers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-defend80" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-defend80" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17530607-10-off38" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-off38" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-off38" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one promissory note under the hand of 
                     <persName id="t17530607-10-person81">
                        John 
                        Hays 
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-person81" type="surname" value="Hays"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530607-10-person81" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530607-10-person81" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  . bearing date April 29, 1751, val. 50 l. by which note, 
                     <persName id="t17530607-10-person82">
                        John 
                        Hays 
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-person82" type="surname" value="Hays"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530607-10-person82" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530607-10-person82" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   promised to pay to 
                     <persName id="t17530607-10-person83">
                        Thomas 
                        Garret 
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-person83" type="surname" value="Garret"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530607-10-person83" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530607-10-person83" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , or order, the sum of 50 l. six months after date
            </rs>, <rs id="t17530607-10-cd39" type="crimeDate">July 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530607-10-off38 t17530607-10-cd39"></join>. +.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530607-10-person84">
                  Thomas 
                  Garret 
               <interp inst="t17530607-10-person84" type="surname" value="Garret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-person84" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-person84" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 29th of April, 1751, William Hulls and 
               <persName id="t17530607-10-person85">
                  John 
                  Hays 
               <interp inst="t17530607-10-person85" type="surname" value="Hays"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-person85" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-person85" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came to me with a hood and judgment of one hundred pounds for me to sign to Hays, I said to them I did not owe him any thing; he said if I did not sign it, he would arrest me for 16 pounds, and put me in goal. I consulted with Christophers, the prisoner, what to do; his advice was, that if 
               <persName id="t17530607-10-person86">
                  John 
                  Hays 
               <interp inst="t17530607-10-person86" type="surname" value="Hays"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-person86" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-person86" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             would give me a note for 50 l. I should give him a bond and judgment for 100 l. which I did; then he went down into the country with the bond and judgment to receive the money, but could not get the money, by reason of the mortgage upon my estate.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is this Hays?</p>
               <p>Garret. He keeps the earl of Stair's head in Vine-street. In July following, I lost the note out of my pocket which Hays gave me to pay me, or my order, 50 l. it was given me April 29, 1751, payable 6 months after date; I had it when I went to bed, and saw it, and in the morning missed it: the prisoner at that time lay with me, and nobody else.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever find it again?</p>
               <p>Garret. No, I never did. I went to Hays, and told him I had lost my 50 l. note that he gave me; he said what signifies 50 l. between you and I.</p>
               <p>Ann Boon. The prisoner at the bar lodged at<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175306070006"></xptr> my house in September 51, who told me he had done an ill thing by poor Garret, which was that upon the bond of 100 l. given to Hays from Garret. Hays gave to Garret a promissory note for 50 l. that as Hays could get nothing on the bond in the country, he desired the prisoner to get the note from the prosecutor, and give it to him, which he said he did; that he took it out of his pocket when he was asleep in the night, (as they lay together) and carried it to Hays, and Hays, in his presence, flung it into the fire and destroy'd it; he also said, that he was sorry, for that he had a hand in getting all Garret's estate from him, which was 60 or 70 l. a year.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this conversation?</p>
               <p>A. Boon. It was at my house in Chandos-street in a one pair of stairs room.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any body by at this conversation ?</p>
               <p>A. Boon. There were 
               <persName id="t17530607-10-person87">
                  William 
                  Frost 
               <interp inst="t17530607-10-person87" type="surname" value="Frost"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-person87" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-person87" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17530607-10-person88">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Bohus 
               <interp inst="t17530607-10-person88" type="surname" value="Bohus"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-person88" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-person88" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             at the time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530607-10-person89">
                  William 
                  Frost 
               <interp inst="t17530607-10-person89" type="surname" value="Frost"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-person89" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-person89" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On December, 1751, I heard the prisoner confess to the evidence in her house, that if she would excuse him some little incumbrance (what I can't justly say) he'd open to her the whole scene of villainy; then he owned to the taking this 50 l. note out of Garret's pocket, and delivering it to Hays.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530607-10-person90">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Bohus 
               <interp inst="t17530607-10-person90" type="surname" value="Bohus"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-person90" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-person90" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirmed the above, but could not be certain as to the time, neither the month nor year.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I am as innocent of the affair as the child unborn. Hays and Mrs. Boon have both been at law for the fellow's estate; they wanted me to swear to serve their ends, but I would not, so am now prosecuted out of spight.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mr. Whitewood. I keep a publick house near London-Wall, and know the prisoner and prosecutor, they behaved like brothers, and called each other so. I really believe the prisoner was got among a bad set of people, but believe him to be a very honest man. This very woman (Mrs. Boon) once came to me as the prisoner's friend, about making up an affair of a bastard child that was laid to him, and now she wants to hang him. I have seen the prisoner and prosecutor drinking together often since the time of what they call the robbery, in good friendship.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530607-10-person91">
                  John 
                  Olsinbrook 
               <interp inst="t17530607-10-person91" type="surname" value="Olsinbrook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-person91" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-person91" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the King's-Head facing Cripplegate church, and know the prisoner and prosecutor, and have seen them drinking together at Hays's house in the year 52, and also at my own house divers times, they were like brothers. I never heard Garret charge the prisoner with taking a note or any such thing.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner's general character?</p>
               <p>Olsinbrook. He is an honest man, and I'd trust him with untold gold.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530607-10-person92">
                  William 
                  Lucas 
               <interp inst="t17530607-10-person92" type="surname" value="Lucas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-person92" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-person92" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner near two years, and have seen him and Garret together an hundred times since the year 51 in good friendship.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530607-10-person93">
                  Margaret 
                  Bourne 
               <interp inst="t17530607-10-person93" type="surname" value="Bourne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-person93" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-person93" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about two years, I also know Garret, and have seen them together since the year 51 several times at Hays's, the house where they lodged together I lived servant, and they appeared very friendly.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear them talk about the note ?</p>
               <p>Bourne. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530607-10-person94">
                  Abraham 
                  Greenwood 
               <interp inst="t17530607-10-person94" type="surname" value="Greenwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-person94" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-person94" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am near 16 years of age, and live at Mr. Hays's, and have seen the prisoner and prosecutor together several times since the year 51.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear Garret charge the prisoner with having taken any thing from him?</p>
               <p>Greenwood. No, I never did, they always appeared like brothers.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does Mr. Hays live?</p>
               <p>Greenwood. He lives in Vine-Street, near Round-Court, in the Strand.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530607-10-person95">
                  John 
                  Woodruff 
               <interp inst="t17530607-10-person95" type="surname" value="Woodruff"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-person95" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-person95" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Man-in-the-Moon in Chiswell-street, and have known the prisoner about four years, he lived with me once about 4 or 5 months, and the reason of his leaving me was I had not employment for him; I always took him to be a very honest man, and never heard to the contrary.</p>
               <p>Mr. Wadsworth. I live at Yowel, and the prisoner is my servant. At this time he came very well recommended to me, and has behaved exceeding well. I could trust him with untold gold.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your opinion of him after hearing what has has been said here?</p>
               <p>Wadsworth. I now have the same opinion I had before.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17530607-10-verdict40" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530607-10-verdict40" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
