<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510523-13">
               <interp inst="t17510523-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510523-13" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510523-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510523"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510523-13" type="date" value="17510523"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510523-13-off70-c80" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-13-defend106 t17510523-13-off70 t17510523-13-verdict74"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510523-13-off70-c81" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-13-defend107 t17510523-13-off70 t17510523-13-verdict74"></join>
         
               <p>364, 365. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17510523-13-defend106" type="defendantName">
                     David 
                     Evans 
                  <interp inst="t17510523-13-defend106" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-defend106" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-defend106" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               <persName id="t17510523-13-defend107" type="defendantName">
                  Ann 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17510523-13-defend107" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-defend107" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-defend107" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , <rs id="t17510523-13-deflabel69" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-13-defend107 t17510523-13-deflabel69"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17510523-13-off70" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-off70" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-off70" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one sconce looking glass, value 25 s. one chimney glass, value 14 s.
            </rs> the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17510523-13-victim109" type="victimName">
                     George 
                     May 
                  <interp inst="t17510523-13-victim109" type="surname" value="May"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-victim109" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-victim109" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-13-off70 t17510523-13-victim109"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17510523-13-cd71" type="crimeDate">March 1, 1750</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-13-off70 t17510523-13-cd71"></join>. +</p>
               <p>See No 666, &amp;c. in John Blachford, Esq; mayoralty.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-13-person110">
                  Sarah 
                  May 
               <interp inst="t17510523-13-person110" type="surname" value="May"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-person110" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-person110" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17510523-13-person111">
                  Ann 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17510523-13-person111" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-person111" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-person111" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was my <rs id="t17510523-13-deflabel72" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-13-defend107 t17510523-13-deflabel72"></join>, she came to me Feb. was twelvemonth, and lived with me five or six weeks; while she was with me I lost a diamond ring, sheets, glasses, and many things.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at these glasses, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>S. May. They are my husband's property. I lived at the Lebeck's head in Catharine's-street, going from thence I deposited them in a lumber room in <placeName id="t17510523-13-crimeloc73">Denmark court</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17510523-13-crimeloc73" type="placeName" value="Denmark court"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510523-13-crimeloc73" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-13-off70 t17510523-13-crimeloc73"></join>, where I took three rooms at Mr. Love's; when I came to go into my own house in Catharine-street again I miss'd these glasses.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain they were carried to Mr. Love's?</p>
               <p>S. May. I am certain they were, and Mrs. Jones the prisoner used to lie in the room where they were put. Mrs. Kelso came to me one day to ask me her character, then I had missed the glasses, and told her, I had lost them and other things. She said, if I would go along with her, she would help me to the sight of the glasses.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a house do you keep?</p>
               <p>S. May. I keep a private house.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Mr. Evans ?</p>
               <p>S. May. I never saw him till one time Mrs. Jones told me he was her husband.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember there was a trial against Kelso for these very glasses?</p>
               <p>S. May. Yes, I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not you here at that time?</p>
               <p>S. May. I was, and gave my oath they were my husband's property. If Mr. May had been here he would have had them again.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain you took your oath?</p>
               <p>S. May. I believe I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not you frequently with this woman after you miss'd these glasses?</p>
               <p>S. May. No, sir, I was not.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you keep your goods at Mr. Love's?</p>
               <p>S. May. I kept them there seven months.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any lock to the door where you kept them?</p>
               <p>S. May. No, sir, there was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray tell us the reason you left that house call'd the Lebeck's head ?</p>
               <p>S. May. Because we had money enough to live upon, and it was too much business for me.</p>
               <p>Q. Come tell me, was it, or was it not, for your safety, at the time the bawdy houses were attempted to be pull'd down?</p>
               <p>S. May. No, sir, it was not.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to go there again since?</p>
               <p>S. May. Because the house is our own, I don't sell any thing now.</p>
               <p>Q. Is not there an action brought against Kelso at the court of Common pleas by your husband for these very glasses?</p>
               <p>S. May. I believe there is.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-13-person112">
                  Henry 
                  Kelso 
               <interp inst="t17510523-13-person112" type="surname" value="Kelso"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-person112" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-person112" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Prince's-street, Soho. On the 11th of April was twelve months, 
               <persName id="t17510523-13-person113">
                  Ann 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17510523-13-person113" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-person113" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-person113" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came to me, and asked me if I would buy two glasses she had to dispose of. I said, if she would suffer them to be valued by a proper person I would buy them, saying, I did not understand those sort of goods. These are the two glasses; I have had them a good while in my custody; they have been out of my custody now about a month ; they were fixed up in the lodging room of 
               <persName id="t17510523-13-person114">
                  David 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17510523-13-person114" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-person114" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-person114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17510523-13-person115">
                  Ann 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17510523-13-person115" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-person115" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-person115" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in Great Pultney street. She said, she bought them of a gentleman she had liv'd with, that had kept the Lebeck's head. I got Mr. Ellis who keeps the blanket warehouse, to go and value them; he went with my wife and returned, and told me to the wearer they might be worth 5 l. I gave 
               <persName id="t17510523-13-person116">
                  Ann 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17510523-13-person116" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-person116" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-person116" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             4 l. 17 s. for them; she told me, they were her goods. I knew she had another husband living, and he is so now Evans and she used to say they were married together on the 13th of June, seven years ago, and never denied it till this affair happened.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you there when the glasses were taken away?</p>
               <p>Kelso. I was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Evans present when you bought them?</p>
               <p>Kelso. He was not, nor when they were appraised ; I had the misfortune to be tried for stealing<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175105230008"></xptr> ing these glasses (in this court) by the two prisoners, and had a copy of my indictment granted me; the prisoners were my prosecutors: here is the receipt 
               <persName id="t17510523-13-person117">
                  Ann 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17510523-13-person117" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-person117" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-person117" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave me when I paid for the glasses; they made my man a prisoner to destroy his evidence that wrote it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-13-person118">
                  James 
                  Ellis 
               <interp inst="t17510523-13-person118" type="surname" value="Ellis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-person118" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-person118" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed to going with Mrs. Kelso, and valuing the glasses. The same as in the former trial.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-13-person119">
                  Martha 
                  Kenister 
               <interp inst="t17510523-13-person119" type="surname" value="Kenister"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-person119" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-person119" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was servant to Mr. May, I had lived there two years; I left them last January was twelve months; I remember those glasses very well; I clean'd them every week, sometimes three or four times a week; my mistress bought them at Heywood's bagnio.</p>
               <p>Prisoner Ann Jones's defence.</p>
               <p>The time the bawdy-houses were pulled down in the Strand, Mr. May went to Mr. Love's, No. 5. in Denmark-court; Mr. Love was so careful of the street door, he trusted nobody with the key of it. I was hired to Mrs. May the 20th of December, 1749, and January the 30th following I was discharged.' She hired 
               <persName id="t17510523-13-person120">
                  Ann 
                  Sinclair 
               <interp inst="t17510523-13-person120" type="surname" value="Sinclair"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-person120" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-person120" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and delivered to her an inventory of the goods, and said she missed nothing, and made me a present of five shillings. On the 19th of October last, when Mr. Evans prosecuted Mr. Kelso, Mrs. May was asked in court, if she knew how she was robbed, she said she could not tell. I have been at her house since, she said she never suspected me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-13-person121">
                  Ann 
                  Sinclair 
               <interp inst="t17510523-13-person121" type="surname" value="Sinclair"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-person121" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-person121" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was hired to Mrs. May the 30th of January as a servant, and stay'd with her eleven weeks and some days, and this woman, 
               <persName id="t17510523-13-person122">
                  Ann 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17510523-13-person122" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-person122" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-person122" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , otherwise Ann Jones was with her; Mrs. May wanted her to go with her as her cook, and me to be her bar maid. Her husband asked me, if ever I lived in a bawdy house; said I, I never did; then, said he, if you go with her you must, for she never kept any thing else; then, said I, I hope you'll excuse me, for I don't choose to go in such a way of life; she insisted upon my going and would not discharge me, and said, if I would not, she would swear any thing against me. She always said the prisoner was an extreme good servant, and she would recommend her to any thing in her power. I have seen her in Mrs. May's company early and late; she has sometimes been brought home by the porter so drunk that she could not stand. She sent her to nurse a gentlewoman and gave her a crown.</p>
               <p>John Park. I was buying some pictures in the shop of Mr. Dunning, a broker in Holborn; there was Mr. Evans the prisoner; he said, he was looking upon two glasses in order to buy them; he bought them, and ordered them to be carried home; I think they had gilt frames; one of them was for a chimney. [He looked upon them in court, and said, they were the same, or like them.] I saw him pay the money for them. This was in March was twelve months.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is Mr. Dunning?</p>
               <p>Park. He died about eight or nine months ago.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Park. I have been a broker this 28 years.</p>
               <p>Q. Why do you remember March more than any other month?</p>
               <p>Park. I know my profits and loss for many years past.</p>
               <p>Q. When was you applied to by Mr. Evans to recollect this affair?</p>
               <p>Park. I can tell you no farther.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you the subpoena to attend?</p>
               <p>Park. About two days ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Then cannot you tell when you was first applied to by the prisoner? recollect yourself.</p>
               <p>Park. It was about six months ago.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17510523-13-verdict74" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510523-13-verdict74" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>P. S. Mrs. May did appear in court after the trial of Mr. Kelso was over, and said she and her husband would swear that the glasses were their property, but she was not sworn.</p>
            </div1>
