<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560915-55">
               <interp inst="t17560915-55" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-55" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-55" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560915"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-55" type="date" value="17560915"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560915-55-off273-c314" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-55-defend419 t17560915-55-off273 t17560915-55-verdict277"></join>
         
               <p>387. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17560915-55-defend419" type="defendantName">
                     David 
                     Jones 
                  <interp inst="t17560915-55-defend419" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-55-defend419" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-55-defend419" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for the <rs id="t17560915-55-off273" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560915-55-off273" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-55-off273" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               wilful murder of 
                     <persName id="t17560915-55-victim420" type="victimName">
                        Ann 
                        Hall 
                     <interp inst="t17560915-55-victim420" type="surname" value="Hall"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560915-55-victim420" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560915-55-victim420" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-55-off273 t17560915-55-victim420"></join>
                     </persName>
                   
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17560915-55-viclabel274" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-55-victim420 t17560915-55-viclabel274"></join>. He stood also charged on the coroner's inquest for manslaughter, <rs id="t17560915-55-cd275" type="crimeDate">July 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-55-off273 t17560915-55-cd275"></join>. *</p> 
               <p>Samuel Cutts. On a Saturday in June ( I don't know the exact day of the month) about nine in the evening, as I was coming out of St. James's palace, I met with the prisoner, who asked me to go with him to his lodgings. He and the deceased lived together. He said she had been working hard all<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175609150033"></xptr> day, and he would give her a little beer to refresh her. He accordingly order'd some beer home, and we went into their room. They were very friendly, and had play'd together in the street, as they went along. I took the beer and said, Mrs. Jones, to your good health; she after that drank to his good guard, for being a <rs id="t17560915-55-deflabel276" type="occupation">soldier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-55-defend419 t17560915-55-deflabel276"></join> he was to go upon guard the next day; and he thank'd her. She then said, I will come down to-morrow and see what ' guard you keep, but if I find 
               <persName id="t17560915-55-person421">
                  Welch 
                  Peg 
               <interp inst="t17560915-55-person421" type="surname" value="Peg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-55-person421" type="given" value="Welch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-55-person421" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             there, I ' will either do for her, or she shall do for me; I ' will know who has the most right, if I swing at ' Tyburn for it the next day. 'The prisoner laugh'd, and said, the woman is mad sure, and bid her hold her tongue, saying, we met in friendship, what signifies making this noise and disturbance? She said she would make a noise, for he did not use her as a wife. I said, be so good as to drink, Mrs. Jones, and I will go. He again told her to hold her tongue, and her reply was, I'll expose you. She was sitting down low, either upon a basket of cloaths or in a nursing chair, her head being almost as low as the table, on which stood the quart pot of beer, when (without taking the pot in his hand ) he gave hand a sweep and struck it off the table, and it fell upon her; she stoop'd down, and the beer run from her. I saw blood run from her face; there was a wound made on the side of it. She said she would go down stairs, and have something done to it. He desired her to go to bed. She went down stairs, I followed her, and the prisoner after me; She had it dress'd with some gin, and I went away.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her after that ?</p>
               <p>Cutts. Yes, several times. She came to our house for things to wash after that; I saw her twice afterwards much concern'd in liquor, and once at Kemington about a fortnight after that. She is since dead.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you believe that was the occasion of her death ?</p>
               <p>Cutts. I can't be a judge of that, but I don't think he struck the pot with an intent to hurt her. I look'd upon his intention to be to sling down the beer, that we might go away.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-55-person422">
                  Gertrude 
                  Butherworth 
               <interp inst="t17560915-55-person422" type="surname" value="Butherworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-55-person422" type="given" value="Gertrude"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-55-person422" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner and the deceased lodged with me. I saw the wound after it was given; she complain'd pretty much of her head, so went to the hospital, and had it dress'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know whether the prisoner and deceased lay together the night it was done ?</p>
               <p>G. Butherworth. They did not; she sat upon the stairs all night. But she continued in the lodging, and lay with him when he came home till she went into the hospital.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-55-person423">
                  Sarah 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17560915-55-person423" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-55-person423" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-55-person423" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the wound about three days after it was given; it was a very large wound, on the side of her head; I dressed it twice, and it seem'd to be very dangerous.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-55-person424">
                  John 
                  Hunter 
               <interp inst="t17560915-55-person424" type="surname" value="Hunter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-55-person424" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-55-person424" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I a surgeon, and dressed the deceased's wound after she came into St. George's hospital, which I was told was a fortnight after she received it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it such a wound that you apprehended to be dangerous?</p>
               <p>Hunter. The wound itself was not dangerous. I make no doubt but she might have recover'd, if it had been taken care of at the beginning. I believe she died of it, as I found no other illness on her, but what was occasion'd by that wound.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you open her after she was dead?</p>
               <p>Hunter. I did; it was on the right side of the head. The appearances I imagine were occasion'd by a blow on the part.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17560915-55-verdict277" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560915-55-verdict277" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
