<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17521206-39">
               <interp inst="t17521206-39" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521206-39" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521206-39" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17521206"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521206-39" type="date" value="17521206"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17521206-39-off196-c268" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-39-defend343 t17521206-39-off196 t17521206-39-verdict198"></join>
         
               <p>47. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17521206-39-defend343" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Marshall 
                  <interp inst="t17521206-39-defend343" type="surname" value="Marshall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-39-defend343" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-39-defend343" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17521206-39-off196" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17521206-39-off196" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-39-off196" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing twenty-five pounds weight of loaf sugar, val. 12 s. privately in the warehouse of 
                     <persName id="t17521206-39-victim344" type="victimName">
                        Rice 
                        Price 
                     <interp inst="t17521206-39-victim344" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17521206-39-victim344" type="given" value="Rice"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17521206-39-victim344" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-39-off196 t17521206-39-victim344"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , his property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17521206-39-cd197" type="crimeDate">Nov. 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-39-off196 t17521206-39-cd197"></join> ||</p>
               <p>Rice Price. On the 18th of Nov. last, between the hours of 7 and 8 in the evening; I saw the prisoner coming out of my warehouse, (which is over against my house) with a lump of sugar under his arm; (produc'd in court and deposed to 25 pounds weight and upwards)</p>
               <p>Q. What is the value of it?</p>
               <p>Price. It cost me 14 s. and 3 d. I ran to the door and saw my man coming up out of the cellar ; I asked him if he had had any body with him, he said no: I thought I missed a small loaf of sugar from near the door; I went after the prisoner and took him with it under his arm; my man at that time called out, then the prisoner dropp'd the sugar down.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the warehouse door open or shut?</p>
               <p>Price. They are folding doors, and they were both open; this was on Saturday night; I carried the prisoner before my Lord-Mayor, on the Monday morning; there he pretended he saw the sugar lying on the ground.</p>
               <p>Q. from the Prisoner. Which arm had I it under?</p>
               <p>Price. He had it under his left arm next to the wall.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521206-39-person345">
                  Joseph 
                  Hermatage 
               <interp inst="t17521206-39-person345" type="surname" value="Hermatage"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-39-person345" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-39-person345" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Price, I was down in the warehouse and saw the prisoner come in and take the sugar on the 18th of Nov.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the evening was it?</p>
               <p>Hermatage. It was very near 8 o'clock; when<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175212060027"></xptr> he was gone out I called out stop thief, and ran after him and seiz'd him by the collar behind.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he ever out of your sight ?</p>
               <p>Hermatage. He was not, till I took hold on him.</p>
               <p>Q. from the Prisoner. Had I the sugar when you laid hold on me?</p>
               <p>Hermatage. I laid hold on him just before he dropt it.</p>
               <p>Q. How far from the warehouse door was it that you laid hold on him?</p>
               <p>Hermatage. It was but 3 or 4 yards from the warehouse door.</p>
               <p>Q. Where has the sugar been since?</p>
               <p>Hermatage. It has been seal'd up ever since.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521206-39-person346">
                  Benjamin 
                  Dell 
               <interp inst="t17521206-39-person346" type="surname" value="Dell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-39-person346" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-39-person346" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live next door to the warehouse; I heard the sugar loaf fall, I went to the door and took it up just by the prisoner's feet; when they had seiz'd him, I gave it to the constable when he came.</p>
               <p>Q. Whereabouts did it fall?</p>
               <p>Dell. It fel l upon the stone step near our shop window.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is your shop from the prosecutor's warehouse?</p>
               <p>Dell. There is only an entry between them, about 4 or 5 feet broad.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>Coming down Bow-lane, I saw a man in a white frock 5 or 6 yards before me; I thought I heard something drop; Mr. Price came and laid hold of me, the man just turn'd the corner at the time; he call'd to his man, and sent for a constable; they carried me to the Compter directly.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>William Watkin's. I am a shoemaker; and live in Flying-Horse-Court, Grub-street, I have known the prisoner about six months; I never heard any harm of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521206-39-person347">
                  Susannah 
                  Haines 
               <interp inst="t17521206-39-person347" type="surname" value="Haines"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-39-person347" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-39-person347" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Cross-Key-Court in Grub-street; I am an old cloaths woman; I have nothing to say against the prisoner, or for him; no further than I know him to be a very honest fellow.</p>
               <p>Q. how long have you known him?</p>
               <p>S. Haines. About three years.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17521206-39-verdict198" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17521206-39-verdict198" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-39-verdict198" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder5s"></interp>
               Guilty 4 s. and 10 d.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17521206-39-punish199" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17521206-39-punish199" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-39-defend343 t17521206-39-punish199"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
