<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17590711-18">
               <interp inst="t17590711-18" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590711-18" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590711-18" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17590711"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590711-18" type="date" value="17590711"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17590711-18-off105-c140" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590711-18-defend173 t17590711-18-off105 t17590711-18-verdict110"></join>
         
               <p>232. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17590711-18-defend173" type="defendantName">
                     Edward 
                     Norman 
                  <interp inst="t17590711-18-defend173" type="surname" value="Norman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-18-defend173" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-18-defend173" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for that <rs id="t17590711-18-off105" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590711-18-off105" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-18-off105" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               he, on the King's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17590711-18-victim175" type="victimName">
                           Stephen 
                           Randall 
                        <interp inst="t17590711-18-victim175" type="surname" value="Randall"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590711-18-victim175" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590711-18-victim175" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590711-18-off105 t17590711-18-victim175"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear, and danger of his life, and stealing from his person, one canvas bag, value one penny, one 36 s. piece, and one half guinea
            </rs>, the property of the said Stephen, &amp;c. <rs id="t17590711-18-cd106" type="crimeDate">July 4</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590711-18-off105 t17590711-18-cd106"></join>. + .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590711-18-person176">
                  Stephen 
                  Randall 
               <interp inst="t17590711-18-person176" type="surname" value="Randall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-18-person176" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-18-person176" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was riding <placeName id="t17590711-18-crimeloc107">in the road from Walton-Bridge to Hounslow</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17590711-18-crimeloc107" type="placeName" value="in the road from Walton-Bridge to Hounslow"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17590711-18-crimeloc107" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590711-18-off105 t17590711-18-crimeloc107"></join>, on Wednesday the 4th of July, I met with a man on horseback; he asked me the way to Twickenham. I told him he was in the wrong road, and pointed to him his way. He ask'd me what country I had been in, I said in <placeName id="t17590711-18-crimeloc108">Surry</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17590711-18-crimeloc108" type="placeName" value="Surry"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17590711-18-crimeloc108" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590711-18-off105 t17590711-18-crimeloc108"></join>. He asked me what crops were there, I said very good. He said they were good where he had been. He rode a mile in the road with me. When we came to <placeName id="t17590711-18-crimeloc109">the way that turns down to Twickenham</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17590711-18-crimeloc109" type="placeName" value="the way that turns down to Twickenham"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17590711-18-crimeloc109" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590711-18-off105 t17590711-18-crimeloc109"></join>, I told him to keep that blind road and it would carry him there. He said, the road he was in was a delightful fine road, and he would ride that road a little farther, and went on with me about a quarter of a mile. Then he asked me, what gentleman's seat that was which we saw? I said, the Duke of Argyle's. soon after, as I was talking to him, he clapp'd a pistol to my breast, and said, Your money. I was very much surprized, and desired him to take it away; and said, what I had should be at his service, and directly gave him my bag, in which, I suppose, were a 36 s. piece, a 27 s. piece, and three half guineas; but I am sure there was the money laid in the indictment, and a 6 d. Then he said, Your watch. I said, no watch indeed. He d - d me, and bid me dismount: he unbutton'd my waistcoat, and said, you conceal the watch, d - n you. I said, I have none indeed. Then he said, I must have your bridle; I was so affrighted I could not pull it off; he got from his horse and pulled it off, and drove my horse away with the bridle in his hand. He asked me my name, and place of abode. I told him, my name was Jibbet, and I lived in Bond-street; then he got on his horse, and was going away, and asked me, where I should see him again? I told him, his place should be mine; the Bell at Hounslow, if he pleased. He said that would not do, but if I would meet him on Monday morning by them five trees, pointing to them; if possible he would give me my money again. I said, Sir, if you please to give me my bag; he said, I'll give it you: he looked at it, and said, it was a common canvas bag, and that it would be of service to him; and he would leave my bridle about half a mile up the road. My horse made it's way to the Red Lion at Hounslow. I saw the man ride down to Hanworth; and I saw him, I believe, two miles and a half a-head. I went away to Teddington and sent the hostler for the bridle, and he brought it with the head-stall cut. He was cloathed in black, with spatterdashes buttoned up, and a piece of black crape about his neck. His horse was a brown bay, no white, only his legs. I took a great deal of notice of his horse when he went off. I have seen just such a horse since at Mr Tootings, a Hosier in Oxford road: I can't say it is the same horse, but as much like it as possible. I was before Mr Fielding when the prisoner was there. I believe the prisoner at the bar is the same man.</p>

               <p>Q. Had he any thing to disguise his face?</p>
               <p>Randall. I am very sure he is the man; I know him from a thousand.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907110020"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17590711-18-person177">
                  John 
                  Stokes 
               <interp inst="t17590711-18-person177" type="surname" value="Stokes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-18-person177" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-18-person177" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I took the prisoner on Saturday last, the latter part of the afternoon, at the house where he lodges; he came with a pair of black spatterdashes and a whip in his hand.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to suspect this man?</p>
               <p>Stokes. Mr. Green, where he was a lodger seven weeks, told an acquaintance of mine of an advertisement, and said, he believed he had an highway-man in his house. We went and looked at the horse in the stable, and while we were at Mr Green's house I jumped up and took him. He made no defence at all. I took this canvas bag out of his pocket. Producing one.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. This is the canvas bag which the prisoner took from me, it is a very remarkable one, lined part of the way up.</p>
               <p>Stokes. Here are two pocket-pistols, and a paper of gun-powder, which we took out of his pocket loaded with balls.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. It was much such a pistol as this he held to my breast, it shone very much.</p>
               <p>Stokes. I asked him what he did with those pistols; he said, he carried them for fear of bailiffs. Going to Justice Fielding's he said, Pray gentlemen, if you can't do me good, do me no harm, don't mention the fire-arms.</p>
               <p>Richard Green. The prisoner lodged in my house seven weeks: I live in Fleet-street, opposite the Bolt and Tun-Inn: I am a Pen-Cutter. The prisoner came in on the Monday night (before the Wednesday on which the robbery was committed) and sent for a tankard of beer; drinking it, he said, he was going to dinner with some gentlemen, on one side Brentford the next day. He desired I would recommend him to a house: I told him a friend of mine had one to let. He went and the horse was to be ready for him the next morning. He left my house on Tuesday morning about five o'clock. I don't know what dress he went out with. He returned on Wednesday night between eight and nine: then he was dressed in black, and a black thing about his neck and spatterdashes on. He went out on Thursday morning in black, and came home with those on he has now, a red waistcoat and brown coat.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590711-18-person178">
                  Edward 
                  Porter 
               <interp inst="t17590711-18-person178" type="surname" value="Porter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-18-person178" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-18-person178" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Porter: I was at the taking of the prisoner, and took those pistols out of his pocket.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I am under very unfortunate circumstances; quite a stranger: I properly belong to His Majesty's ship the Royal Anne, Admiral Holbourn. I was born in Ireland, and have served in different stations. I have nobody here to speak for me: some of my friends are now at Portsmouth, and some at Plymouth, so that I cannot clear myself as I would. I was only taken last Saturday. I am only twenty-one years of age. I was in great distress. I really intended to give him his money again.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17590711-18-verdict110" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590711-18-verdict110" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17590711-18-punish111" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590711-18-punish111" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590711-18-defend173 t17590711-18-punish111"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
