<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17511016-11">
               <interp inst="t17511016-11" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511016-11" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511016-11" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17511016"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511016-11" type="date" value="17511016"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17511016-11-off54-c81" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-11-defend98 t17511016-11-off54 t17511016-11-verdict57"></join>
         
               <p>554. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17511016-11-defend98" type="defendantName">
                     Lawrence 
                     Whittum 
                  <interp inst="t17511016-11-defend98" type="surname" value="Whittum"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-11-defend98" type="given" value="Lawrence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-11-defend98" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17511016-11-off54" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17511016-11-off54" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-11-off54" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one silver pint mug, value 30 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17511016-11-victim100" type="victimName">
                     Jane 
                     Newbolt 
                  <interp inst="t17511016-11-victim100" type="surname" value="Newbolt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-11-victim100" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-11-victim100" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-11-off54 t17511016-11-victim100"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17511016-11-cd55" type="crimeDate">Sept. 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-11-off54 t17511016-11-cd55"></join>.*</p>
               <p>Jane Newbolt. I <rs id="t17511016-11-viclabel56" type="occupation">keep a publick house</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-11-victim100 t17511016-11-viclabel56"></join>. The prisoner came into my house with a sheep's heart to broil, he called for a mug of beer, he staid from betwixt one and two to four in the afternoon; after he had drank his pint he had two penny-worth of beer in the same silver pint pot; at last there was nobody in the house but he and me, I was sitting musing, he went out ; my maid being gone out, she came in and said, the man is gone with the silver mug ; she ran out and enquired which way he was gone: in about a quarter of an hour she brought him and the mug squeezed and bent together. Produced in court and sworn to.</p>
               <p>Cross Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he use your house?</p>
               <p>J. Newbolt. I don't know I ever saw him before.</p>
               <p>Q. Had there been nobody in the house the time he was there?</p>
               <p>J. Newbolt. There had been several companies, but they were all gone when the last penny-worth was drawn, then there were none but he, I, and the maid in the house.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was you to the prisoner?</p>
               <p>J. Newbolt. I was sitting in the next box to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure that was the very pint mug the prisoner drank out of?</p>
               <p>J. Newbolt. It is a particular mug, and I am certain it is.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-11-person101">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17511016-11-person101" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-11-person101" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-11-person101" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to the prosecutrix. I drew the prisoner the pennyworth of beer in this mug, he said he waited for somebody, there was nobody at that table but himself; I went out to get in some pots, and when I returned he was gone, and I missed the mug; I ran out and saw him in Column-street, I cried, stop thief, he has stole my mistress's silver mug; he got into a place where was no thorough fare; there was a throng of people, I collared him; he said he had none of the mug; at that time somebody came over the wall, which he stood near to, with the mug in their hand, so I brought him back.</p>
               <p>Cross Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see this mug upon him?</p>
               <p>E. Brown. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there other people in the house the time he was there?</p>
               <p>E. Brown. There was nobody but my mistress, him, and me, when I delivered the mug last to him.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutrix. Did you see the maid deliver the mug to the prisoner at the time she speaks on?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. I did, Sir, and after the maid went out there was nobody in the house but him and me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body come into the house betwixt the time the maid delivered the last pennyworth of beer to him and the time the maid said the mug was missing?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. There was not any body came in.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mr. Walker. I live at the White Hart in Thames-street, and have known the prisoner 15 years, he has had a very good character, he was an hostler, he is now I believe out of place.</p>
               <p>Mr. Prew, one of the jewry. The prisoner lived hostler with me six months and was as good a servant as ever I had.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is this ago?</p>
               <p>Prew. It is almost a year ago.</p>
               <p>Q. to the Prosecutrix. Where is the man that found the tankard?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. He was sworn before the alderman, but I cannot find where he lives.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17511016-11-verdict57" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17511016-11-verdict57" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
