<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17521206-27">
               <interp inst="t17521206-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521206-27" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521206-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17521206"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521206-27" type="date" value="17521206"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17521206-27-off121-c170" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-27-defend216 t17521206-27-off121 t17521206-27-verdict126"></join>
         
               <p>31. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17521206-27-defend216" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Slow 
                  <interp inst="t17521206-27-defend216" type="surname" value="Slow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-27-defend216" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-27-defend216" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for that <rs id="t17521206-27-off121" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17521206-27-off121" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-27-off121" type="offenceSubcategory" value="housebreaking"></interp>
               he on the <rs id="t17521206-27-cd122" type="crimeDate">9th of Nov</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-27-off121 t17521206-27-cd122"></join>. about the hour of three in the afternoon, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17521206-27-victim218" type="victimName">
                           Samuel 
                           Becket 
                        <interp inst="t17521206-27-victim218" type="surname" value="Becket"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17521206-27-victim218" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17521206-27-victim218" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-27-off121 t17521206-27-victim218"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did break and enter, the said Samuel then and there being, one silk purse value 12 d. one canvas bag, one leather pocket, two two-guinea pieces, four guineas, three half guineas, two thirty-six shilling pieces, one moidore, and five pounds in money number'd, the goods and money of the said Samuel in his dwelling-house did steal, take, and carry away
            </rs>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521206-27-person219">
                  Samuel 
                  Becket 
               <interp inst="t17521206-27-person219" type="surname" value="Becket"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-27-person219" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-27-person219" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17521206-27-viclabel123" type="occupation">breeches-maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-27-victim218 t17521206-27-viclabel123"></join> and live in <placeName id="t17521206-27-crimeloc124">Long-lane near Smithfield</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17521206-27-crimeloc124" type="placeName" value="Long-lane near Smithfield"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17521206-27-crimeloc124" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-27-off121 t17521206-27-crimeloc124"></join>; last Lord-Mayor's day, between two and three in the afternoon, my house was broke open; up one pair of stairs, the partition that comes into a closet, which closet opens into my room, was broke through; the prisoners house joins to mine, the hole was broke out of his house; the pannel was broke, two boards split in two about a yard and half in length, and the lath and plaister was broke through, so that a man might with case get through: all was safe and my money in my drawers between eleven and twelve that morning; then I saw my purses and pocket and money in them, in all 20 l. there was two two-guinea pieces, two thirty-six shilling pieces, one moidore, four guineas, three half guineas, six crown pieces, and the rest in silver, which was about 3 l. 10 s. the silver was in the leather pocket, which pocket I had made use of three or four years, it is a particular one; the gold was in a green purse, I saw the gold in it as it lay, it was in my middle drawer in my chamber where I lie, in a chest of drawers: between two and three o'clock I was alone in my house and heard a noise, Mr. Slow's wife was knocking at his door almost a quarter of an hour; the neighbour at the next door to him look'd out and said I believe your husband is not at home; perhaps he is gone out to see my Lord-Mayor's shew; Mrs. Slow said, I know he is in the house; bye and bye he came down and let her in: I went up stairs about four o'clock, and then shut my windows down.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you awake all the time you was at home?</p>
               <p>Becket. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober?</p>
               <p>Becket. I was all the time.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any noise above stairs?</p>
               <p>Becket. No, my Lord, I did not. About two or three months before this, the prisoner at the bar desired<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175212060014"></xptr> to see my apartment, and brought a candle, pretending there was a pannel loose, and he wanted to fasten it: I went up with him: My closet is a longish dark place: He went in, I did not, but I examined it since, and find the pannel fastens on his side and not on mine.</p>
               <p>Q. When was you in the closet last ?</p>
               <p>Becket. About three or four days, or a week before it was broke through.</p>
               <p>Q. After you found the house broke, what did you do?</p>
               <p>Becket. I examined into the affair, and found the prisoner had a man and a woman lodged in his garret, I went and knocked at the door between four and five o'clock, there was the woman lodger, who said she lived there, and the prisoner came from the door at the same time and said, what is the matter? there was also his wife. I said, who had broke their house into mine to-day? the prisoner said I don't know, I have nobody but a man and a woman lodger in my garret. I left him there, and found afterwards he was very flush of money that night, so I fetched a search-warrant the next day, and went to his house, which we searched and found both gold and silver, and after some time the leather pocket which had my silver in.</p>
               <p>Q. What pieces of money were found?</p>
               <p>Becket. Silver and gold between 5 and 6 l. but I cannot swear to any of it.</p>
               <p>Cross Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this the house he lived in where you found that pocket?</p>
               <p>Becket. It was, he has made doors from one to another.</p>
               <p>Q. Whose room is that which was on the backside your closet?</p>
               <p>Becket. He keeps it in his own hands, it is a one pair of stairs room.</p>
               <p>Q. What description did you give of this pocket to persons you talked with?</p>
               <p>Becket. I have said it is a little coarse in the grain, it is not taken off so clean as sometimes leather is, and one side there is a speck or two of the grain upon it, I can pick it out from a hundred.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you say before my lord mayor you knew it because it was stitched with yellow silk?</p>
               <p>Becket. I said there's a place looks as if it was stitched with yellow silk.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you tell any body it was stitched with yellow silk ?</p>
               <p>Becket. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521206-27-person220">
                  William 
                  Newton 
               <interp inst="t17521206-27-person220" type="surname" value="Newton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-27-person220" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-27-person220" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was present when Mr. Becket missed his money, about four o'clock in the afternoon he said he had lost 20 l. he lighted a candle, went up stairs and came down again, saying, my money is gone, and my house is broke out into Slow's: then I went up with him, he opened the closet door, and put down the candle, where I saw a hole big enough for two men to go through in the pannel out of Slow's passage into the prosecutor's closet.</p>
               <p>Q. How was the plaister wall?</p>
               <p>Newton. There was no plaister wall as I saw, only wainscot or boards nailed up against a post. We went to Mr. Slow's house and found his wife, and in a moment he came. We had a notion of a person that lives in the upper part of the house; they were ready to get a candle, then we went up there, and all was secure. When the search-warrant was got I was present at the searching of the house, none but the prisoner was left with me, who walked up and down for about a quarter of an hour, but nothing passed between him and me, There was a rattling of money up stairs, then he left me and went up and came down again, saying, it is very surprizing to me he has not been robbed before now. After that came the officer and Mr. Becket, and searched below, where Mr. Greenwood brought out a linnen bag, and asked Mr. Becket if that was his, he said no. In a minute after that, or less, he brought out that leather pocket and tossed it down, and Mr. Becket said, this is my pocket in which my silver was. After this we went to the Mansion-House to have a hearing before my lord mayor. The prisoner walked up and down, and seemed very uneasy, so I said to him, had not you better make it up with him, it is running a great hazard to go before my lord; he said, I'll do any thing to make Mr. Becket easy; said I, doubtless some of the money is embezzled away, give him the remainder: then he said, suppose I give him a note for the remainder. Presently after he said, if I do my character is blasted, and I may as well he hang'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this conversation?</p>
               <p>Newton. This was in the Mansion-House before we appeared before my lord mayor.</p>
               <p>Cross Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was by at this conversation?</p>
               <p>Newton. There were none by but he and I.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Newton. I live in Wood-Street.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175212060015"></xptr>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Newton. I am a breeches-maker,</p>
               <p>Q. When the pocket was found, did not he call his wife to bring a pair of breeches that it was taken out of?</p>
               <p>Newton. He did desire her to fetch a pair of breeches that a pocket was taken out of, but there was no proof it was that pocket.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521206-27-person221">
                  Richard 
                  Nash 
               <interp inst="t17521206-27-person221" type="surname" value="Nash"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-27-person221" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-27-person221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Becket appeared before Sir 
               <persName id="t17521206-27-person222">
                  George 
                  Champion 
               <interp inst="t17521206-27-person222" type="surname" value="Champion"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-27-person222" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-27-person222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             for a search-warrant, and I, being an officer, went along with him and searched the house of the prisoner; we found between 5 and 6 l. in money, then I came down stairs and looked among some rubbish in an old trunk all rags and very ordinary stuff, there I found a little linnen bag, I was down on my knees, so sent it out by another man, which the prosecutor did not know. After that I looked farther, and found this leather pocket in that trunk, and Mr. Becket directly said he had it many years to keep his money in.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he mention he thought it was done with silk ?</p>
               <p>Nash. He did mention that he thought it was done with silk, but when he came to look at it, he said that the place that he meant was a stain in the grain of the leather: The prisoner said it could not be Mr. Becket's, because it came out of his black breeches; they were fetched down, and no pockets were out of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find any thing else?</p>
               <p>Nash. No, I did not; Slow was in a great quandary.</p>
               <p>Q. Amongst whose things did you find the pocket?</p>
               <p>Nash. Amongst the prisoner's things.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>We went over to Mr. Greenwood's; the prosecutor said, my pocket has got yellow stitches in the middle of it. I said, had it been stitch'd with stuff of any colour? At last Mr. Nash said, here is a crease; then said Mr. Becket, that is the place I meant: I was very much in a flutter, and said I had a pair of breeches which I had lengthened: the next day, when I came to consider better, I found how the thing was, but then I did not.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521206-27-person223">
                  Thomas 
                  Ripshaw 
               <interp inst="t17521206-27-person223" type="surname" value="Ripshaw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-27-person223" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-27-person223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a piece of a Taylor: I remember taking out a pocket for the prisoner out of a pair of breeches on the 14th of March was a Twelvemonth: I carried them home to him: He was angry I did not put it in again: I told him, I thought two pockets would be sufficient to hold his money and mine.</p>
               <p>Q. Should you know that pocket again?</p>
               <p>Ripshaw. No, I don't say that: There is not an honester man in London than he is.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521206-27-person224">
                  John 
                  Seagood 
               <interp inst="t17521206-27-person224" type="surname" value="Seagood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-27-person224" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-27-person224" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I believe I have known the prisoner four or five years: I was with him before my Lord Mayor on Saturday morning; the descriptions the prosecutor gave for knowing the pocket, was by yellow stitches, and the goodness of the pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner's general character?</p>
               <p>Seagood. A very good one; that of an honest man.</p>
               <p>Mr. Langford. I have known him about six years, he worked in my house two years and a half, and I have trusted him with many sums of money.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Langford. I take him to be as honest a man as ever was born down to this time.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is it since he worked in your house?</p>
               <p>Langford. He has been gone from me about two years and a half.</p>
               <p>Mr. Jordan. I have known him these last two years, and look upon him to be as honest a man as any in Christendom; he has had opportunities to defraud me; my apprentices have given him sometimes a corner, or circle too many, and he has brought it back again, saying, your boy has given me this too much. He was always very honest, and is a <rs id="t17521206-27-deflabel125" type="occupation">clock-engraver</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-27-defend216 t17521206-27-deflabel125"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mandevile Sinnersal. I have known him about 10 or 12 years, and always looked upon him to be a very industrious honest man. I have employed him, and believe he never wronged me nor any body else.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17521206-27-verdict126" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17521206-27-verdict126" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-27-verdict126" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               Guilty of felony only
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17521206-27-punish127" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17521206-27-punish127" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-27-punish127" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-27-defend216 t17521206-27-punish127"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
