<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17590228-22">
               <interp inst="t17590228-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590228-22" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590228-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17590228"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590228-22" type="date" value="17590228"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17590228-22-off164-c227" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590228-22-defend274 t17590228-22-off164 t17590228-22-verdict168"></join>
         
               <p>138. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17590228-22-defend274" type="defendantName">
                     Margaret 
                     Elliott 
                  <interp inst="t17590228-22-defend274" type="surname" value="Elliott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590228-22-defend274" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590228-22-defend274" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17590228-22-deflabel163" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590228-22-defend274 t17590228-22-deflabel163"></join>, was indicted, for that <rs id="t17590228-22-off164" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590228-22-off164" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590228-22-off164" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               she, on the <rs id="t17590228-22-cd165" type="crimeDate">20th of February</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590228-22-off164 t17590228-22-cd165"></join>, about 7 in the night, on the same day, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17590228-22-victim276" type="victimName">
                           George Smith 
                           Bradshaw 
                        <interp inst="t17590228-22-victim276" type="surname" value="Bradshaw"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590228-22-victim276" type="given" value="George Smith"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590228-22-victim276" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590228-22-off164 t17590228-22-victim276"></join>
                     </persName>
                     
                   did break and enter, with intent, the goods and chattels of the said George Smith to steal, take, and carry away
            </rs>. *</p>
               <p>George Smith Bradshaw. I live in <placeName id="t17590228-22-crimeloc166">Dean-street Soho</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17590228-22-crimeloc166" type="placeName" value="Dean-street Soho"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17590228-22-crimeloc166" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590228-22-off164 t17590228-22-crimeloc166"></join>; within these 12 months last past, my house has been robb'd 4 or 5 times.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Bradshaw. I am an <rs id="t17590228-22-viclabel167" type="occupation">upholsterer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590228-22-victim276 t17590228-22-viclabel167"></join>; having had a great quantity of goods taken away, I desired my people to be watchful, to see if they could find any body. On the 20th of Feb. they found the prisoner at the bar, and brought her to me.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was it?</p>
               <p>Bradshaw. It was about 7 o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it dark?</p>
               <p>Bradshaw. It was after dark; she was carried before Justice St Laurence and there searched; I was by, and this key (producing a pick-lock key) was found upon her; we have tried it, and it opens my street door.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it the house that you live in ?</p>
               <p>Bradshaw. No, it is a house that I hire.</p>
               <p>Q. Do any of your people lie in it?</p>
               <p>Bradshaw. Yes, two of them do; it is a house that I keep goods in; I did live in that house some years, but now I am remov'd to another house, and keep goods in this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590228-22-person277">
                  George 
                  Hamp 
               <interp inst="t17590228-22-person277" type="surname" value="Hamp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590228-22-person277" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590228-22-person277" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 20th of February, in the evening, about 7 o'clock; I and John Lethany went over to see if things were safe in this house.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Hamp. I am porter to Mr Bradshaw; upon finding the door only single lock'd (which we always double lock'd) we suspected some body was got in, so we searched the house.</p>
               <p>Q. Who had the key of the door?</p>
               <p>Hamp. We had; we got a candle and went in, and in the two pair of stairs room, we found the prisoner at the bar</p>
               <p>Q. Did the goods lie above or below?</p>
               <p>Hamp. There are goods above and below too; the prisoner was lying on her hands and knees, in order to conceal herself, she could not conceal herself behind any goods, there being but a few in that room?</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say for herself?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175902280035"></xptr>Hamp. She said she came in there for lodging; I ask'd her how she got in? she said that the door was open, but we found it single lock'd; we took her from thence to Dean-street, to my master's house.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you before the Justice with her?</p>
               <p>Hamp. I was, and saw that pick-lock key taken from her; she had a coarse apron round her loose, and another check apron under it, tied round her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590228-22-person278">
                  John 
                  Lethany 
               <interp inst="t17590228-22-person278" type="surname" value="Lethany"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590228-22-person278" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590228-22-person278" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was with the last witness; we found the prisoner in the two pair of stairs room, on her hands and knees, with her face towards the boards.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590228-22-person279">
                  Henry 
                  Boswarney 
               <interp inst="t17590228-22-person279" type="surname" value="Boswarney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590228-22-person279" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590228-22-person279" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . We had a suspicion that the prisoner had got a key to open the door.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Boswarney. I belong to Mr Bradshaw; I put the goods into the house, many of which are gone. We searched the prisoner, and at first found nothing but the key of her own room; then I put my hand down her bosom, and there I found this pick-lock key. I went with Mr Bradshaw to the street door, at which she must have gone in, to try if the key would unlock it, and found it would unlock and lock it, which it did very well.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I am a poor woman, my friends are gone from me; I was very weary, and did not know what to do; I went in there, and thought it was an empty house, to lie there all night. I found that key in the street.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17590228-22-verdict168" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590228-22-verdict168" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
