<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17520408-20">
               <interp inst="t17520408-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520408-20" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520408-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520408"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520408-20" type="date" value="17520408"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520408-20-off112-c134" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520408-20-defend172 t17520408-20-off112 t17520408-20-verdict116"></join>
         
               <p>229. 
               <persName id="t17520408-20-defend172" type="defendantName">
                  
                     George 
                     Farmer 
                  . otherwise <rs id="t17520408-20-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520408-20-defend172 t17520408-20-alias-3"></join>Firmer</rs>, <rs id="t17520408-20-deflabel111" type="occupation">Esq;</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520408-20-defend172 t17520408-20-deflabel111"></join> commonly called <rs id="t17520408-20-alias-4" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520408-20-defend172 t17520408-20-alias-4"></join>Lord Lempster</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-20-defend172" type="surname" value="Farmer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-20-defend172" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-20-defend172" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for the <rs id="t17520408-20-off112" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520408-20-off112" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-20-off112" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               murder
            </rs> of 
               
                  <persName id="t17520408-20-victim175" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Gray 
                  <interp inst="t17520408-20-victim175" type="surname" value="Gray"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-20-victim175" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-20-victim175" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520408-20-off112 t17520408-20-victim175"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17520408-20-viclabel113" type="occupation">Esq;</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520408-20-victim175 t17520408-20-viclabel113"></join> &amp;c. <rs id="t17520408-20-cd114" type="crimeDate">Feb 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520408-20-off112 t17520408-20-cd114"></join>. *</p>
               <p>Capt. Collingwood. I am an acquaintance of my Lord Lempster, and was likewise of the unfortunate deceased. On the 23d of February last, I dined with my Lord Lempster, at the Bedford-head, who told me, he had seen Capt. Gray, the deceased, that morning upon guard; I said, I had not seen him but should be very glad to see him; my Lord proposed to go to<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175204080013"></xptr> the Tilt-yard coffee-house to him; I agreed to go. We went about eight in the evening, and there we found the captain alone, and joined company with him in a room above stairs. My Lord had once at a masquerade refused to lend Capt. Gray ten guineas; they had some words after supper, I think about twelve o' clock, between them, about the circumstances of refusing,, &amp;c. I can't tell the particulars; the first affronting words I heard, was Capt. Gray gave my Lord Lempster the lie, which was without any thing amiss, for there had been very good language used before; then upon this my Lord Lempster called him rascal and scoundrel, which Capt. Gray returned with many abusive words. Mr. Gray at last jump'd up and drew his sword; my Lord Lempster had not his sword, upon which he jump'd up and got to it. I ran in between them, and got up to Capt. Gray, and was very busy in keeping them at a distance; there was, no advances made; I insisted upon their sitting down again, and putting up their swords, which they both did, I told them as there was nobody present but me, that I should never divulge any thing that happened, and they were safe in my hands.</p>
               <p>Q. How long might they stay after this quarrel ?</p>
               <p>Capt. Collingwood. I believe they might stay an hour, and they behaved very well to each other, seemingly good friends, and had no quarrel that night.</p>
               <p>Q. Whither, during that interval, they did not go into the passage?</p>
               <p>Capt. Collingwood. Not as I remember, we went all down stairs together; we left Capt. Gray at the coffee-house, and my Lord and I went away together, we parted at Charing-Cross, he went towards his lodging, and I to mine.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hudson. I keep the Tilt-yard coffee-house, I was not in the coffee room when my Lord Lempster and Capt. Collingwood came there, but came in soon after, which was about nine ; they were all three sitting at a table: I paid my respects to the gentlemen, and made them a bowl of punch ; they drank it, and seemed extremely sociable for some time; I cannot tell how the topick came up readily, I know it was something about lending some money. Capt. Gray seemed to harp on it. Capt. Collingwood said, you might have given him a civiller answer; and at such a time when a man is in a hurry at play, the Capt. might have excused him, that it was a hurry, and my Lord had no intention to affront him. Capt. Gray turned his head on one side and said, d - n you. My Ld. Lempster turned and talked to me about some horses, seemingly to evade it: Then my Ld. said, Collingwood, will you go and sup any where? and seemed intirely to evade it, but Capt. Gray at several intervals harp'd upon things. I think he mentioned the Cardigan; said Capt. Collingwood, with all my heart; said Capt. Gray, can't you as well sup here; my Lord said, he had no objection to the house. I went up and got a fire; this was between eleven and twelve: they went up and had some supper and more punch: I waited supper myself, which was over, I believe, about twelve. I was backwards and forwards several times in the room; they called for a pack of cards and play'd; my Lord and Capt. Collingwood play'd, and Capt. Gray sat by; then Capt. Gray came out and went his rounds, and returne d again, after which, I was in my own room a little way off; I heard a noise like showing back of chairs: I then came to their room door, and heard Capt. Gray say, D - n your blood, you scoundrel, come out; you rascal, you coward, you dare not come out. After that, I heard my Lord, who was then sitting in a chair, jump up, and said, No, Gray, I cannot put up with that; he went cross the room: I was cautious of going in, but looked through the key-hole of the door: there was Capt. Collingwood standing with Capt. Gray, he said, I beg you'll desist. My Lord advanced no farther than the table; Capt. Collingwood pacify'd Capt. Gray, and set him down again. I never went into the room at all. Had any thing happened, I could easily have gone in and laid hold on my Lord, his back being towards me: I had the latch in my hand for that purpose. They sat down after this seemingly good friends, and continued together so an hour or more. I did not think it was any more than a little drink, and did not expect it would have come to such a heighth as fighting. After this, they had another bowl of punch, which I made; when they went down stairs I lighted them down ; after this was over, before they went down, my Ld. Lempster, I believe, and Capt. Gray, were in the passage ; the lights in the passage were burnt out that I could not see; Capt. Gray ordered me to shut my room door and go in, which I did: I knew Capt. Gray's voice perfectly well.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175204080014"></xptr>Q. Did more than one person say shut the door ?</p>
               <p>Hudson. There was talking in the passage, but I could not distinguish the voices, there was some whispering like, I can't take upon me to sware my Ld. Lempster was one.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Capt. Collingwood one?</p>
               <p>Hudson. I can't take upon me to sware he was, they drank a bowl of punch after this. I lighted Capt. Gray to the guard room about five o' clock: he came in again the next day about eight and breakfasted; he asked me, where Lord Lempster lived; I said, I did not know; I looked at him pretty-steadfastly, and said, I hope that little dispute is over, and there is no more of that: No, he said, no more : then I told him where he lived: then I taxed him again, and said, I hoped there is nothing at all in that affair; he said no, there is not; I am going to breakfast with him, and the affair is made up, and if I don't go he'll take it amiss.</p>
               <p>Q. to Capt. Collingwood. Do you recollect your being in the passage that night, when the last witness was ordered to shut his door?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520408-20-person176">
                  Robert 
                  Fudge 
               <interp inst="t17520408-20-person176" type="surname" value="Fudge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-20-person176" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-20-person176" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a barber; I used to dress Capt. Gray: I remember on Monday the 24th of February last, about eight in the morning, I was at the Tilt-yard guard-room; there was another officer on guard, he asked Capt. Gray where he was the night before, he said, at the Tilt-yard coffee-house with Lord Lempster and Capt. Collingwood; to the best of my remembrance they talked of indifferent things; nothing of this affair; he did say Lord Lempster had used him ill; but heard no more of that; he told me to go up to his lodgings and bring his mourning cloaths, and be at the Tilt-yard coffee-house by ten o'clock; and a pair of stockings and a plain hat; I asked him, if he would have his mourning sword; he said, no; (at other times I have brought his mourning sword with his mourning cloaths) he gave me orders to bring a yard of black ribband. I was going in at the horse guards as the clock struck ten; he was on the parade, I waited about an hour, when he was relieved: he went towards the coffee-house, as I supposed, to seek after me; I followed him there, and went up stairs and he after me; I dressed him there, he put on mourning cloaths, but not a mourning sword, he bound the ribband about the hilt of a silver mounted sword.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he appear at that time?</p>
               <p>Fudge. I thought he was confused, his countenance did not apper serene, he throwed things about in an odd manner, and called for some brandy and milk.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he used to drink such liquor?</p>
               <p>Fudge. I never saw him, sir. He went out of the coffee house about half an hour after eleven o'clock.</p>
               <p>Eliz. Cross. I live servant with Mrs. Whiy in the Hay-Market. I remember, between eleven and twelve o'clock, Mr. Gray came and asked, if Lord Lempster lodged there, and if he was at home, and also, if his servant was at home; he desired I would go up and tell Lord Lempster his name was Gray; my Lord knocked at the wainscot for his servant and called Robert: I told him his servant was gone out, then my Lord desired I would shew the gentleman up; as I came down stairs I met my Lord's servant: I then walked about my business and said nothing to the gentleman, nor he to me; as I thought my Lord's servant a more proper person to do it than myself. I did not see the gentleman go up stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember you saw my Lord and the gentleman go out that morning?</p>
               <p>E. Cross. I did not see that.</p>
               <p>Q. What time do you think they went out?</p>
               <p>E. Cross. I believe they went out before twelve o'clock.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the gentleman say his name was ?</p>
               <p>E. Cross. He said his name was Gray.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the servant been out of the house.</p>
               <p>E. Cross. He told me he was going out to have a coat mended, and I did not know but he was out till I saw him.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think Lord Lempster heard Mr. Gray's voice.</p>
               <p>E. Cross. I can't tell that. I was up no more than three or four stairs, and answered through the wainscot. My Lord might hear the knock at the door, but Capt. Gray spoke low.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520408-20-person177">
                  William 
                  Powell 
               <interp inst="t17520408-20-person177" type="surname" value="Powell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-20-person177" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-20-person177" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a musician; on the 24th of February last I was in <placeName id="t17520408-20-crimeloc115">Marybone-fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17520408-20-crimeloc115" type="placeName" value="Marybone-fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520408-20-crimeloc115" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520408-20-off112 t17520408-20-crimeloc115"></join>, I saw my Lord Lempster and Capt. Gray walking in the fields, on my left-hand; I did not know them then, they were walking side by side very amicably, I looked at them but a very little while, and continued my walk, they were in<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175204080015"></xptr> the next field to me about the middle of it, (it was a very fine day.)</p>
               <p>Q. How far was that field they were in, from the Hay-market ?</p>
               <p>Powell. I believe it is a mile or better; a very little time after I had seen them, not having walked above three hundred yards, I happened to turn my head by accident, they were engaged with swords, both naked, Capt. Gray had turn'd with his face toward London, Lord Lempster stood in a line as he had walked, I had a side view of them; immediately I cry'd out to them, not to kill one another, I ran towards them, and had got but a very little way, before Capt. Gray dropp'd on his knee, and got up again, and advanced a step or two, and then fell on his face, he never rose more: while Capt. Gray advanc'd in this manner, Lord Lempster stood then upon a retreat, with the point of his sword dropt; when the Captain fell on his face, Lord Lempster look'd upon him a little time, and said, O Lord! O God! What is this! in a mournful voice like surpriz'd, and then went off; I immediately went over the ditch, the deceased was vomiting blood as he lay on his face, I kneeled down by him and turn'd him on his back, I held up his head with my left hand, and asked him how he did, he opened his eyes very wide, and fix'd them, he vomited a torrent of blood, and died instantly; I wiped his mouth, and hop'd he would have spoke, I open'd his waistcoat and pull'd up his shirt, and saw a small wound in his right side, there was a small effusion of blood: Lord Lempster went off hastily; I follow'd him, and came up with him just at the entrance in the town in the street, my Lord came up to me, and told me Capt. Gray had call'd upon him on this occasion, that the Captain was an officer, and so was he, and said, Sir, what could I do? I could not help it, he made me go out with him, or forced me, and I am sorry for it.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any thrust after the Capt. was fallen upon his face?</p>
               <p>Powell. I did not. The Capt. advanced up to my Lord before he fell, and put out his sword: I was a good deal confused : I could not take a minute's observation of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see my Lord return a thrust, after that putting out his sword?</p>
               <p>Powell. No, Sir, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go up to my Lord, or he to you?</p>
               <p>Powell. He stopp'd and came from the other side of the way rather towards me, and entered into talk of this unhappy subject.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520408-20-person178">
                  Thomas 
                  Tompkins 
               <interp inst="t17520408-20-person178" type="surname" value="Tompkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-20-person178" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-20-person178" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Captain had received a wound on his breast, which penetrated between the third and fourth rib, into the cavity; and without doubt was the occasion of his death; it was impossible for him to live.</p>
               <p>Lord Lempster being called upon to tell the court what he had to say, spoke to the following purport.</p>
               <p>Lord Lempster. I have only to say, I am extreamly sorry to be the unhappy occasion of Mr. Gray's death, as he was a gentleman of great honour, and for whom I had great regard, I made use of all the arguments I could, in order to dissuade him from his intentions, that is not to fight, when we went on our way; when we came to the field, he drew first upon me, and I was under a necessity of killing him, in my own defence; for which I am verily sorry, and wish it had never happened.</p>
               <p>The council for the prisoner rested it here, without calling any witnesses.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520408-20-verdict116" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520408-20-verdict116" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-20-verdict116" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520408-20-punish117" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520408-20-punish117" type="punishmentCategory" value="noPunish"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520408-20-defend172 t17520408-20-punish117"></join>
               
                     <note>[No punishment. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
