<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17540424-70">
               <interp inst="t17540424-70" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540424-70" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540424-70" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540424"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540424-70" type="date" value="17540424"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540424-70-off364-c600" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540424-70-defend727 t17540424-70-off364 t17540424-70-verdict367"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540424-70-off364-c601" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540424-70-defend729 t17540424-70-off364 t17540424-70-verdict367"></join>
         
               <p>208. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17540424-70-defend727" type="defendantName">
                     Mark 
                     Curtice 
                  <interp inst="t17540424-70-defend727" type="surname" value="Curtice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-70-defend727" type="given" value="Mark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-70-defend727" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17540424-70-defend729" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Nitchel 
                  <interp inst="t17540424-70-defend729" type="surname" value="Nitchel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-70-defend729" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-70-defend729" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17540424-70-off364" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540424-70-off364" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-70-off364" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one pair of gold sleeve buttons, value 20 s.
            </rs> the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17540424-70-victim731" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Ridge 
                  <interp inst="t17540424-70-victim731" type="surname" value="Ridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-70-victim731" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-70-victim731" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540424-70-off364 t17540424-70-victim731"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17540424-70-cd365" type="crimeDate">March 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540424-70-off364 t17540424-70-cd365"></join>.* </p> 
               <p>Judith Ridge. I live in <placeName id="t17540424-70-crimeloc366">Bridge-street, West-minster</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17540424-70-crimeloc366" type="placeName" value="Bridge-street, West-minster"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17540424-70-crimeloc366" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540424-70-off364 t17540424-70-crimeloc366"></join>. Upon the 27th of March a woman came into our shop and bought a pair of stockings; it was between eight and nine at night; after she had bought them and paid for them, I lighted her down the steps. There were none in the house but I and the maid; I was shutting the door which would hardly catch: the two prisoners pushed in upon me, they beat me, and drove my head through the glass door that goes into the back parlour; I screamed out and the maid came, they knocked her down, and one of them stamped upon her; when they had done that, they came and laid hold on me again and gave me a push against the counter, I hit him with the candlestick and called out murder they bursted open the door into the parlour, and opened the other door, and met my husband coming down stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were they going?</p>
               <p>Ridge. They were going up stairs; in the mean time the maid run for a constable, then he came they shewed a Marshalsea's-court-writ; then the constable said he had no business with it. They brought my husband down and tore his night gown all to tatters, beat him terribly, and tore him about.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they arrest him?</p>
               <p>Ridge. They did: I said, give me leave to send for ba</p>
               <p>Q. Did they shew the writ before the constable came</p>
               <p>Ridge. They did not. I then saw Curture take up a pair of gold buttons and put them in his pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. What buttons were they?</p>
               <p>Ridge. They were what my husband pulled out of his shirt sleeves, they lay upon the table; he put them in his right hand pocket, either coat or waistcoat; I said, you have got my husband's buttons: he said, d - n you, and away he went out; then he came in again, and I said, you have got my husband's buttons; he said then you may search me you b - h.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did the buttons lay?</p>
               <p>Ridge. They lay upon a table, I saw him take them up, and put his hand down to his pocket.</p>
               <p>Cross Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. What reason have you to charge them both?</p>
               <p>Ridge. Because they both beat me and were present.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you know where they both lived?</p>
               <p>Ridge. I did not?</p>
               <p>Q. Did your husband owe any money?</p>
               <p>Ridge. He did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you know they were employed to arrest him?</p>
               <p>Ridge. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Have not you indicted them at Hicks's-hall for a misdemeanour?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175404240059"></xptr>Ridge. Yes, for this very fact.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540424-70-person732">
                  Ann 
                  Young 
               <interp inst="t17540424-70-person732" type="surname" value="Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-70-person732" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-70-person732" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 27th of March, between eight and nine o'clock at night, there was a woman came in and bought a pair of child's stockings; my mistress took the candle and lighted her down the steps; as soon as she had shut the door there came two men who pushed against it and threw her down backwards; they came behind the counter, threw me down and trod upon me: the glass sash-door was locked, they took my mistress by the shoulders and beat her head through it; then they forced open the parlour door. We screamed out murder! I saw my master pull out a pair of gold buttons out of his sleeves and put them down upon a table after the men had been in; he was putting on his shirt to go out with the men.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not this after they had arrested him?</p>
               <p>Young. It was. I heard my master ask the men for the buttons; then one of them went out of the house and staid about five minutes, and came in again.</p>
               <p>Cross-Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you all the time with the prisoners and your mistress?</p>
               <p>Young. No. When they knocked me down I fetched a constable.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of the buttons?</p>
               <p>Young. I don't know.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not one of the two men stoop down and give them to her directly?</p>
               <p>Young. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure those buttons were gold?</p>
               <p>Young. I always took them to be so.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the buttons for both hands, or one?</p>
               <p>Young. They were for each.</p>
               <p>Curtice's Defence.</p>
               <p>On the 27th of March we had got an action against Mr. Ridge, at the suit of Mr. Radish, a linnen-draper in Cheapside; we had been after him two or three days, and finding him very shy, we sent this woman in to buy stockings; we told her to leave the street door open that we might get in; she did so, and we went in and made the arrest; Mr. Ridge desired to put on a clean shirt; we granted it: after that he said he had lost his sleeve button: Mr. Mitchell stooped down and took it up, and said, here it is; it was then in his hand: after this he got a warrant, thinking to redress himself, and swore this felony. I went and surrendered myself up. I never saw the buttons.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17540424-70-verdict367" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540424-70-verdict367" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
