<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17511016-52">
               <interp inst="t17511016-52" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511016-52" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511016-52" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17511016"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511016-52" type="date" value="17511016"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17511016-52-off238-c303" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-52-defend394 t17511016-52-off238 t17511016-52-verdict241"></join>
         
               <p>606. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17511016-52-defend394" type="defendantName">
                     Hugh 
                     Coffee 
                  <interp inst="t17511016-52-defend394" type="surname" value="Coffee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-52-defend394" type="given" value="Hugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-52-defend394" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17511016-52-off238" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17511016-52-off238" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-52-off238" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one hundred pounds in money numbered
            </rs>, the money of 
               
                  <persName id="t17511016-52-victim396" type="victimName">
                     Adolphus 
                     Hemmings 
                  <interp inst="t17511016-52-victim396" type="surname" value="Hemmings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-52-victim396" type="given" value="Adolphus"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-52-victim396" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-52-off238 t17511016-52-victim396"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17511016-52-cd239" type="crimeDate">Sept. 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-52-off238 t17511016-52-cd239"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-52-person397">
                  Adolphus 
                  Hemmings 
               <interp inst="t17511016-52-person397" type="surname" value="Hemmings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-52-person397" type="given" value="Adolphus"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-52-person397" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a German. I met the prisoner in Sydney-alley, about 11 in the morning, on the 6th of last month, near Leicester-fields. I was going to receive a sum of money; he said he had some business in the city; I said I had received the bills; he went with me; I asked him to drink half a pint of wine; I said I wanted the money for these bills. We then being near the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175110160028"></xptr> Bank, as one was a Bank-bill, the other from the South-sea house, for 25 l. he told me I might have cash for both at the Bank. I went and received the money, and then came to the prisoner at the alehouse, where I told him I had received it. I went home to my house in <placeName id="t17511016-52-crimeloc240">Rupert-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17511016-52-crimeloc240" type="placeName" value="Rupert-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17511016-52-crimeloc240" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-52-off238 t17511016-52-crimeloc240"></join>; he lodged then by Leicester-fields; he came to my house afterwards. I gave the money to my wife, and bid her put it into a chest in the dining-room. The 7th I had a bill to pay; I told my wife such a man was coming, and I wanted the money to pay the bill. I sent her up for it, and she staid a little longer than ordinary; so I went up, and was then in the bed chamber, and had the money in a child's stocking. I asked her for what money I wanted, which was 7 l. 14 s. she gave it me, and put the other up; it was all gold in the stocking, the silver was in a news-paper, both which she put into a chest of drawers, I saw her. We both came down stairs between seven and eight o'clock, and I paid the man the bill. The next morning I told my wife I wanted some more money; she said it was in the drawer; so I went up with the keys, and found the drawer open, the upper part whereof was broke; I told my wife, who said she locked the drawer. There was the news-paper and about 30 s. in silver; the stocking and gold were gone; my wife said it was 
               <persName id="t17511016-52-person398">
                  Hugh 
                  Coffee 
               <interp inst="t17511016-52-person398" type="surname" value="Coffee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-52-person398" type="given" value="Hugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-52-person398" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had done it, saying, I saw him last night go out of the house through the entry, and I thought he came for his wife. I went directly to the house where he lodged, where I met him and his wife; I asked him if he had been at my house last night; he said he had not: said I, you was in our passage between eight and nine o'clock; said he, I was at the Rose and Crown from seven till twelve. We went into a publick house (I think it is the Duke's Head ) and had a dram, where I told him I had lost my money. My wife came in, took hold of him, and said, you are the man that robbed me, and I will charge you. We came all four together to my house. He always denied knowing any thing of the money.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever seen it since?</p>
               <p>Hemmings. No, my lord, I have not.</p>
               <p>Q. When had he been at your house last?</p>
               <p>Hemmings. He was in our tap-room that same day about four o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever tell him where your wife put the money?</p>
               <p>Hemmings. No, I never did, but he was well acquainted with my house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-52-person399">
                  Margaret 
                  Hemmingt 
               <interp inst="t17511016-52-person399" type="surname" value="Hemmingt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-52-person399" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-52-person399" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the prosecutor. I saw the prisoner go along our entry about half an hour after I put the money into the drawers. The bill was paid about seven o'clock. then the money was put there; I locked the drawer, and put the key into my pocket. There were above a hundred pounds all in gold.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you when you saw the prisoner in the entry?</p>
               <p>M. Hemmings. I was in my tap-room; he was going out towards the street door from the kitchen between eight and nine o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were the stairs going up to that room where the money was put?</p>
               <p>M. Hemmings. The stairs were just by the cellar door in the entry.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the prisoner been drinking in your house then?</p>
               <p>M. Hemmings. He had not; he did not come into the tap-room.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you speak to him?</p>
               <p>M. Hemmings. I did not; I thought he was looking for his wife; they used very often to come to our house.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there a light in your entry?</p>
               <p>M. Hemmings. There was a lamp in the entry.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure it was he?</p>
               <p>M. Hemmings. I am certain it was the prisoner, I can swear that.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he searched?</p>
               <p>M. Hemmings. He was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any body come down stairs at that time?</p>
               <p>M. Hemmings. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Who were in the publick room at that time?</p>
               <p>M. Hemmings. There were my husband, myself, and some people drinking.</p>
               <p>Q. Is there a door betwixt the tap-room and the entry?</p>
               <p>M. Hemmings. There is, but that was open at that time, and I saw it was him that passed by.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I had wrote a letter and went and left it at the post office; then I went to the Rose and Crown, and staid there till past 11 o'clock at night, and knew nothing of the money being lost till they came the next morning.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17511016-52-verdict241" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17511016-52-verdict241" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
