<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17531024-40">
               <interp inst="t17531024-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531024-40" type="year" value="1753"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531024-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17531024"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17531024-40" type="date" value="17531024"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17531024-40-off179-c208" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-40-defend279 t17531024-40-off179 t17531024-40-verdict183"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17531024-40-off179-c209" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-40-defend281 t17531024-40-off179 t17531024-40-verdict183"></join>
         
               <p>485, 486. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17531024-40-defend279" type="defendantName">
                     Charles 
                     Mahagen 
                  <interp inst="t17531024-40-defend279" type="surname" value="Mahagen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-40-defend279" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-40-defend279" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17531024-40-defend281" type="defendantName">
                     Frances 
                     Mahagen 
                  <interp inst="t17531024-40-defend281" type="surname" value="Mahagen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-40-defend281" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-40-defend281" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , spinster , were indicted, for that they, <rs id="t17531024-40-off179" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17531024-40-off179" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-40-off179" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               in a certain alley, or open place, near the king's highway, on 
                     <persName id="t17531024-40-person282">
                        Richard 
                        Coombe 
                     <interp inst="t17531024-40-person282" type="surname" value="Coombe"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17531024-40-person282" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17531024-40-person282" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and taking from him 11 s. in money numbered
            </rs>, <rs id="t17531024-40-cd180" type="crimeDate">Oct. 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-40-off179 t17531024-40-cd180"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-40-person283">
                  Richard 
                  Coombe 
               <interp inst="t17531024-40-person283" type="surname" value="Coombe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-40-person283" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-40-person283" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the bottom of Clerkenwell-Green, next door to the French-horn ; I am a carpenter and fish-maker, and make for several carpenters : I was going through Black-boy-alley, on Saturday the 13th of this instant October, about seven at night, I had some bills in my pocket to receive money for work done; I saw a man and two women standing together, almost by the little alley at the <placeName id="t17531024-40-crimeloc181">end of Black-boy-alley, near Chick-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17531024-40-crimeloc181" type="placeName" value="end of Black-boy-alley, near Chick-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17531024-40-crimeloc181" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-40-off179 t17531024-40-crimeloc181"></join> ; the two prisoners were two of them; I don't know the third person. I went to go past them, and at the same time I received a violent blow on my mouth, and instantly a basket was put to my face, and my head squeezed up against the wall; I felt a hand in my pocket: when the basket was taken from my face I catched hold of the woman with the basket in her hand, and brought her to the light in Chick-lane, she called out 
               <persName id="t17531024-40-person284">
                  Charles 
                  Charley 
               <interp inst="t17531024-40-person284" type="surname" value="Charley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-40-person284" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-40-person284" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ; I never quitted her till I got her to the light.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it light or dark?</p>
               <p>Coombe. It was dark, there is no lamp where I was robbed : the man prisoner immediately came back upon her crying out, and struck me several blows in the little: entry ; there was much light in Chick-lane, by which I could easily see the prisoners, and believe them to be the same: the man had a cape coat and a red waistcoat, I saw his face; the woman struck me several blows in Chick-lane with her hand, and also with the basket there: they were both on me together: I tried to push them both into the Black Raven alehouse that is opposite Black boy-alley; but the man pushed the woman in and shut me out; I was pushed back down the steps and fell down, I was never down before that: I told my name, and where I was going, and said, I had been robbed of 11 s. and some halfpence, and said, the people that robbed me were in at the Black Raven, and desired assistance, I got assistance, and we went into the house, they were there at our first going, but at last they were push'd out of the house and were taken before I got out of the house; I got hold on the woman, I took hold of one arm, and another man on the other, and we had her to a constable at the Butchers-arms, in Smithfield; after we had been there some time, a man bid me look about to see who I knew ; I saw the man prisoner, and said, he was the man that was in the robbery, and the people secured him : I charged the constable with them both,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175310240019"></xptr> and they charged the constable with me and the man that assisted me in bringing the woman there.</p>
               <p>On his cross examination he did not vary in the least.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-40-person285">
                  Patrick 
                  Murray 
               <interp inst="t17531024-40-person285" type="surname" value="Murray"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-40-person285" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-40-person285" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Peters-Lane, near Hicks's-hall, and am a shoe-maker, I had been about business up the water, and landed at Black-Fryars, on the 13th of October about seven in the evening, and walked up the market, when I came to the bottom of Field-lane, next to Chick-lane, I heard a crying out, so went up to it; but before I got there I heard a man say, I have been robbed, thieves I ran and saw the prosecutor had hold of a woman, either of her arm or skirt of her gown, I saw them scuffle cross the lane, the woman had a basket in her hand with which she struck the prosecutor. The man prisoner was there, and push'd the woman into the Black Raven alehouse, she turn'd about and with the basket struck the prosecutor, or whether she pushed him with the door, as he wanted to follow them in, so that he fell down at the door.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a basket was it?</p>
               <p>Murray. It was made in the form of a boat, or oval, I help'd the man up, and asked him what was the matter; he said, he was robb'd of his money by that man and woman and another person. I said, if any body would assist we'd go in, and see if we could take them; so we went in and the prosecutor pointed to the woman, and said she was one of them; she and the man were both taken in the house, but the people in the house rescued them from us, and they were conveyed to a sort of a back door, where was a stair case, I went backwards and saw them both, and another woman with them, that door goes into an inn-yard. The people turn'd the prosecutor and two or three more out of the house, and was going to turn me out, but I said I would have a pint of beer, and insisted upon being there, and it was then that I went backwards and saw the prisoners. I ran to the street door, and told the people that the prisoners were not gone out; upon which they rush'd in again, and pull'd them out of this place, which was a sort of an entry into the tap room, but they were rescu'd from us a second time, and pushed out at the street door; they made an attempt to run down Black-Boy-Alley, but the woman was taken before she got into it, but by whom I know not. Then she call'd out, Charley ! Charley! then I went to get a constable, and she was taken to the Butcher's-Arms in Smithfield, but the man got off. The woman behaved at the Butcher's-Arms with very indecent language not to be mention'd, and in about an hour's time the man came in, I believe of his own accord. I sa w him, and said to Mr. Coombe, get up, look about. and see if there is not somebody here that you know, immediately he got up, and pointed to Mr. Attonbury's apprentice, who was sent for to him about business, said he, I know that young man. I saw the prisoner was screening himself behind the people, and pushing to get out at the door; as soon as Mr. Coombe saw him, he said, that is the man that was concerned in the robbery, I seized him and delivered him to the constable.</p>
               <p>Cross Examin'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know that third person you saw with the prisoner ?</p>
               <p>Murray. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q Did you hear this woman complain that the prosecutor had used her ill ?</p>
               <p>Murray. She said he wanted to be great with her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-40-person286">
                  Thomas 
                  Kelly 
               <interp inst="t17531024-40-person286" type="surname" value="Kelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-40-person286" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-40-person286" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an iron back maker, on the 13th of this Instant about seven in the evening I was at my father-in-law's door, which is opposite the Crown in Chick-lane, I heard a disturbance in Black-Boy-Alley, and went to see what was the matter, where was Mr. Coombe. who stood against Mr. Doleman's door in Chick-lane at the corner of the alley, and somebody pushed him way from the door, and said, don't make a disturbance here ; then he went down to the next house, and the two prisoners at the bar followed him and collar'd him, and dragg'd him across the lane; the woman struck him several times with a basket over his head and face, and pull'd off his wig, the man held him all the time; then she threw his wig in his face, and said D - n a - n seize you, ye thief, take your wig again. I asked them the meaning why they used the man in that manner; she said he knock'd her sister down in the entry; then she said, Charley, go and fetch a constable, they were then got near the Black Raven door, and Charley endeavoured to get her away, but she would not be persuaded; then he push'd her into the Black Raven, and the prosecutor fell down at the door; he got up again, and said, gentlemen, I am used very ill, my name is Coombe, I am a carpenter, and live in Clerkenwell</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175310240021"></xptr>Green, I have been stopt by a man and two women; the man struck me on the face, and the woman run a basket against my face, they held me fast and robbed me; this was in Black-boy-alley, and that he got hold of one of the women and dragged her into Chick-lane, and that a man and one of the women were now in the house; I, and others went in to secure them; we secured them; but they were twice rescued from us in the house. The rest as the last evidence, with this addition ; that when they were taken before the alderman, the woman said, the prosecutor took hold on her sister's arm and dragged her about, and said, come along you bitch and drink a pot of beer.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-40-person287">
                  Daniel 
                  Fennel 
               <interp inst="t17531024-40-person287" type="surname" value="Fennel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-40-person287" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-40-person287" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Wheelwright. on Saturday was sen'night at night, my partner and I had left off work, and were going to the Crown in Chick-Lane to make our bill in order for the receiving our money. We heard the cry of murder! murder ! I am robbed; I went up to the prosecutor, and said, are your actually robbed ? he said yes, of 11 s. and upwards, then I said, I'll assist you; then he, and I, and another man, went in at the Black Raven; the people of the house shoved us back again after we had got the people, and got them backwards by a staircase and a backdoor; I knowing the backdoor, when I was out of the house, went towards it to see if they were gone out or not; when I came there, the two women and man were shoved out at the foredoor ; I ran and laid hold on the woman, I took her by one hand, and Mr. Coombe by the other, and we carried her to the constable, at the Butchers Arms, in Smithfield : after we had got her there, she swore I had robb'd her, so I was detained; whilst we were there the man came in. The rest as Murray had deposed, with this addition, that after the woman was in the watch-house she denied what she had said about his robbing her, so he was let go.</p>
               <p>Cross Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you hear the woman say, she, or her sister, had been used ill by the prosecutor?</p>
               <p>Fennel. No, I did not hear her say any such word, that they had been either of them abused by any body.</p>
               <p>Mr. Cheene. I am constable; I and my brother constable had them in charge, I never heard the woman make any complaint of any indecency from Coombe.</p>
               <p>The other constable deposed the same.</p>
               <p>Mahagen's Defence.</p>
               <p>We came to London on the 4th of October, from Ireland : I got a room to lodge in at Mr. Reynold's, in Black-boy alley; I was recommended there by the people at the Raven: The prosecutor met me in the alley and knocked my wife down; I went up stairs; they called me down; my wife said, the man was gone ; I saw him running, I ran after him, and said, how came you to knock my wife down? he said, I will go before a justice, or any place; the woman recovered herself, came up and said to me, don't be concerned with him; some people said, why don't you take him into custody; I said, I am a stranger, nobody will assist me, so we let him go; then he went to the others, and they contrived this thing against us.</p>
               <p>The Woman's Defence.</p>
               <p>As I was coming with my sister I had a basket in my hand, the prosecutor knocked my sister down, and put his hands up my coats and down my bosom, and bid the whores come away with him, and said, if we would not, he would knock our brains out.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoners.</p>
               <p>Gibbon Smith. I never saw the prisoners before this thing happened, which was on a Saturday night. I think this day fortnight, near seven o'clock ; I was coming from Cow Cross up Black-boy-alley with my wife, we heard a great noise and a woman calling Charley, Charley; when we got up to it, they were all out of the alley in Chick-lane; there was quarrelling and fighting, a woman beat a man with a basket, and I believe the men had blows; I can't recollect that the prisoners are either of the persons; there was another woman came to a door, and said, for God sake Charley come out, for there is somebody quarrelling with your wife; there was somebody came down stairs, but they were gone out of the alley before we came there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-40-person288">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17531024-40-person288" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-40-person288" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-40-person288" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the last evidence, I was with him at that time, we heard a great noise with two women and a man; I don't know that ever I saw them before; I heard the two women call out Charley, Charley, a man was meddling with the women.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see that ?</p>
               <p>Smith. No, I did not; when they saw my husband and I coming along they went out into Chick-Lane, and my husband shoved me along; there I saw a woman beating a man with this basket. Produced in court as before described.</p>
         
               <p>The Second Part of these PROCEEDINGS will be published in a few days.</p>
         

               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17531024-40">
                  <interp inst="t17531024-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17531024-40" type="year" value="1753"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17531024-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17531024"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17531024-40" type="date" value="17531024"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175310240020"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Goal Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the Goal Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 24th, Thursday the 25th, Friday the 26th, Saturday the 27th, Monday the 29th, and Tuesday the 30th of October,</p>
                  <p>In the 27th Year of His MAJESTY's Reign, BEING THE Eighth SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of the Right Honble Sir CRISP GASCOYNE, Knt. LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>NUMBER VIII. PART II.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by M. COOPER, at the Globe in Pater-noster Row. 1753.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-Pence.]</p>
               </div1>
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17531024-40">
                  <interp inst="t17531024-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17531024-40" type="year" value="1753"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17531024-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17531024"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17531024-40" type="date" value="17531024"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175310240022"></xptr>
THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Goal Delivery held for the City of London, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>	
               <p>Q. HOW came you by that basket ?</p>
               <p>Smith. I pick'd it up after they let it fall, and deliver'd it to the Raven people.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Barton. I have known the prisoner about a week, they lodg'd in Cock-court, Black-Boy-Alley, I know the other woman, they all three lay together when they came to town.</p>
               <p>Q Is the other woman related to them?</p>
               <p>Barton. I don't know whether she is or not; on this day fortnight I was getting some water, I had just put my pail under the cock, I heard a great out-cry, which was two women and a man fighting.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the night was this?</p>
               <p>Barton. It was between seven and eight o'clock. The women call'd out, Charley! Charley! I look'd at them, and thought they were the people that lodg'd next door to me. I call'd the man, and I believe he made no more steps down stairs than one, for he had like to have tumbled over me; he asked me what was the matter, I said, if that is your wife here is a man beating her, she will kill her he stings her about so, I suppose he'll smother her; I believe he was stopped in Chick-lane, but I did not go to see.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-40-person289">
                  Thomas 
                  Reynolds 
               <interp inst="t17531024-40-person289" type="surname" value="Reynolds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-40-person289" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-40-person289" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoners about a week; they lodged at my house.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. That evidence keeps a lodging house for such sort of people in Black-Boy-Alley.</p>
               <p>Reynolds. I did not see the beginning of the quarrel, if the robbery, as is pretended, was after the cry, Charley! Charley! I know it could not be ; for I saw the Alley clear. I was in my own house, and heard the prisoner's wife call Charley. I think three times, the prisoner was then in his own room, he came down to the assistance of his wife ; I saw the prosecutor run away, and the prisoner after him, calling out, Stop him, stop him. I heard the woman say, Charley, Charley, I have been ill used; I think she said she had been knock'd down.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him come down stairs ?</p>
               <p>Reynolds. No, but I heard him: I went to Chick-Lane with a candle in my hand, then they were fighting ; I said to Mr. Mahagen. why can't you charge him? charge him, he said, what is that ? I said, with a constable: the prosecutor never mentioned any thing of a robbery as.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you near him?</p>
               <p>Reynolds. I was as to this man, pointing a man within a yard of him, I returned home: them fighting ; and after that the prisoner came to me, and said, they have taken my away, what can I do?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175310240023"></xptr>Prisoner. She is my wife's sister.</p>
               <p>Reynolds. As for Mr. Kelly, and the other man, they were never in the alley.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that?</p>
               <p>Reynolds. I was there all the while; he charged the man with the robbery, I went to the Butchers-Arms with the man, where there was nothing talked off but hanging of him; they took him into custody: I staid there some time, and then went home.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they charge one another?</p>
               <p>Reynolds. I don't know for that; the prisoner and I had been at the Raven together that day, we went home, and he went up stairs; he had not been out of my house to my knowledge ?</p>
               <p>Q. Had you been out again in the time ?</p>
               <p>Reynolds. I had been up and down the alley several times.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17531024-40-person290">
                  William 
                  Doleman 
               <interp inst="t17531024-40-person290" type="surname" value="Doleman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-40-person290" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17531024-40-person290" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I am a salesman, there was a woman with a basket in her hand quarrelling at my door; she said, he had used her sister ill. I said get all away from my shop window and push'd them away; then I went to my other shop, and saw no more of it.</p>
               <p>Eliz. Wilson. I heard a noise in Chick-lane, a woman cry'd out, and said her sister had been used ill; then a great many people came into my house whom I wanted to get out.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Wilson. I keep the Black Raven.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoners come into your house?</p>
               <p>Wilson. They did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you remove them to another part of the house?</p>
               <p>Wilson. No, I did not, I was in the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you hear these people that came in after them, charge the prisoners with a robbery?</p>
               <p>Wilson. No, I did not; there had been a quarrel, but I cannot tell about what.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you order your door to be shut against some of the witnesses ?</p>
               <p>Wilson. I do not know that my door was shut against any body that night.</p>
               <p>Q. Were not the prisoners searched in your house ?</p>
               <p>Wilson. No, there was nobody searched that I know of.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoners before that night ?</p>
               <p>Wilson. Yes, they had their beer at our house; about a quarter of an hour after the people were all gone out, the man called to know if his sister was there, and I told him she was not.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Tipping. I was sitting at my own door in the alley, and the mob cry'd out Murder, I saw a woman beat a man with a basket, her sister sat down on my step, that woman said the man had used her sister ill, and he knock'd her sister down.</p>
               <p>Q. to Reynolds. What employment do the prisoners follow?</p>
               <p>Reynolds. They <rs id="t17531024-40-deflabel182" type="occupation">sold handkerchiefs , stocks, combs and laces</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-40-defend279 t17531024-40-deflabel182"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17531024-40-defend281 t17531024-40-deflabel182"></join>.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Matthews. One day since this happened I stood at the end of Mutton-lane, and heard the prosecutor and another man talking together about this robbery, the other man asked him if he was sure this was the woman that robb'd him; he said, I don't know, I cannot be positive whether the woman in custody, or the b - h that is run away, robb'd me, but I was robb'd of 11 s.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17531024-40-verdict183" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17531024-40-verdict183" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acq
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
