<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510911-54">
               <interp inst="t17510911-54" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510911-54" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510911-54" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510911-54" type="date" value="17510911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510911-54-off249-c338" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-54-defend439 t17510911-54-off249 t17510911-54-verdict252"></join>
         
               <p>529. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17510911-54-defend439" type="defendantName">
                  Ad
               <interp inst="t17510911-54-defend439" type="given" value="Ad"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-54-defend439" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17510911-54-deflabel248" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-54-defend439 t17510911-54-deflabel248"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17510911-54-off249" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510911-54-off249" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-54-off249" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 20 4 half guineas, the money of 
                     <persName id="t17510911-54-victim440" type="victimName">
                        John 
                        Wilson 
                     <interp inst="t17510911-54-victim440" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510911-54-victim440" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510911-54-victim440" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-54-off249 t17510911-54-victim440"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , in the dwelling-house of the said John
            </rs>, <rs id="t17510911-54-cd250" type="crimeDate">August 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-54-off249 t17510911-54-cd250"></join> ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-54-person441">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17510911-54-person441" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-54-person441" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-54-person441" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in nest-street. <placeName id="t17510911-54-crimeloc251">St. Giles's in the field</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17510911-54-crimeloc251" type="placeName" value="St. Giles's in the field"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510911-54-crimeloc251" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-54-off249 t17510911-54-crimeloc251"></join>. I employed the prisoner to clean two rooms, a one pair and a two pair of stairs room. My money lay in the one pair of stairs, this was in August, but I don't know the day. She had done business for me two or three times before; I paid her, and she was to have come again the next day, but did not. She came to the sign of the Hampshire hog, facing St. Giles's church, about eight or nine days after, drunk, in a coach, and had bought herself new cloaths, silver buckles, and fine things, a pair of tabby stays, a fine black hat, and fine shoes: she sent for me there, and I went to her; she called for a dram, and paid me 3 s. she owed me before ; she had not silver enough about her, but pulled out half a guinea, and asked if I could change it. I took it, gave her change, and looked upon it, knowing her to be poor and miserable before. I told my money the night before I set her to clean my rooms, and remember'd one half guinea to be a Queen Anne's, and that there was a black spot on it by the side of the cross; I was struck with a damp when I looked upon the half guinea I had of her. I ran home directly, thinking she had been robbing me, when I missed my money, the drawer being open, and not a halfpenny in it: I will take my oath this half guinea is mine, producing it in court, for I never had any body went into my room but her; it was a chest of drawers, and I had the key in my pocket, and they were locked. The day I employ'd her, there were in them 20 guineas and four half guineas, pinned up in a little bag, which was to pay for my coals, and she knew that well enough.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you use to leave your chamber door open?</p>
               <p>E. Wilson. I never did in my life, no-body ever went into it but my little boy, my husband and myself.</p>
               <p>Q. How old is your little boy?</p>
               <p>E. Wilson. He is going into the fourteenth year of his age. The drawer must be broke open, for I could not lock it afterwards. My husband never had any money out without first asking me for the key, and I don't believe he has taken a shilling out of that drawer these three or four years. Upon missing my money, we sent after her, and she was taken and put into St. Giles's Round-house by the constable, the 22d of 
               <persName id="t17510911-54-person442">
                  August 
                  Before 
               <interp inst="t17510911-54-person442" type="surname" value="Before"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-54-person442" type="given" value="August"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-54-person442" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             we<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175109110030"></xptr> took her to the justice, she had offered to give us 4 l. 10 s. per year, and would give her note for it whilst the money was repaid, but my husband refused it; when before the Justice, she made the same offer.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she own the taking the money?</p>
               <p>E. Wilson. She did not deny it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you get any of the money again?</p>
               <p>E. Wilson. No, none at all, but the 3 s. she paid me.</p>
               <p>Q. Suppose you had seen this half guinea in the hands of any other person, should you have known it?</p>
               <p>E. Wilson. Yes, I should.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you have sworn to it?</p>
               <p>E. Wilson. Yes, I could.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you have sworn to any of the other money ?</p>
               <p>E. Wilson. There were, I believe, two or three guineas I could swear to; besides, the prisoner never had any thing to hide her nakedness, before she robbed me.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you had this half guinea?</p>
               <p>E. Wilson. I do not know that. I am no scholar.</p>
               <p>Q. Does any other person live in your house but your husband and son?</p>
               <p>E. Wilson. There is an old woman lives up in the garret.</p>
               <p>Q. Had she used to go into your room?</p>
               <p>E. Wilson. She never did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-54-person443">
                  Timothy 
                  Gearey 
               <interp inst="t17510911-54-person443" type="surname" value="Gearey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-54-person443" type="given" value="Timothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-54-person443" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was employed by Mrs. Wilson's son-in-law, 
               <persName id="t17510911-54-person444">
                  Henry 
                  Flannigin 
               <interp inst="t17510911-54-person444" type="surname" value="Flannigin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-54-person444" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-54-person444" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She was taken up the 22d of August, when I was at the Crown and Cannon in St. Giles's. She asked how much was the money. and, as high as I can remember, they told her it was upwards of twenty pounds ; she said she did not believe it was so much; then she wanted to get away, and said if Mr. Wilson came, she was in danger of being hanged. When Mr. Wilson came, she said she had hired herself to the man for 4 l. 10 s. per year in that publick house, and she would give him a note for it till he was paid his money; but she denied that she had it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-54-person445">
                  Henry 
                  Flannigin 
               <interp inst="t17510911-54-person445" type="surname" value="Flannigin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-54-person445" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-54-person445" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was present when the prisoner was taken at the Black Dog in White cross-Street, for stealing twenty two guineas. I said she must go home directly, so I carried her to the Crown and Cannon, and went for Mr. Wilson to come to her, and he returned with me. I heard her say, if they would go and fetch her master, (if he would give his note) she would pay 4 l. 10 s. a year, till the money is paid; his name is Radman; he keeps the Black Dog in White-cross-Street.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she own to the taking the money?</p>
               <p>Flannigin. She said she knew nothing of that. I was with her before the Justice, and she made the same offer there. She was a very miserable creature before, but now she was well dressed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-54-person446">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Carier 
               <interp inst="t17510911-54-person446" type="surname" value="Carier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-54-person446" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-54-person446" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was never in any way of business of getting her livelihood. I have seen her coming home at two or three o'clock in the morning, as I have been going to market. I have lodged in Mr. Wilson's house these six years, and know they will not let any body go into their room, not so much as to make the bed.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you been in that room?</p>
               <p>E. Carier. I have, with either the son or the daughter.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at home, when she was cleaning out the house?</p>
               <p>E. Carier. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you live in the upper or lower part of the house ?</p>
               <p>E. Carier. I live in the lower part.</p>
               <p>Q. to E. Wilson. In what room were the brasses cleaned?</p>
               <p>E. Wilson. They were cleaned in the last evidence's room; then after that they were carried up into the room.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-54-person447">
                  Sarah 
                  Ribons 
               <interp inst="t17510911-54-person447" type="surname" value="Ribons"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-54-person447" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-54-person447" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I cannot tell how long it is ago the prisoner asked me to drink at Mr. Gee's house, but I said I did not chuse to drink. She then asked me to do one favour for her, and that was to go up into Church-street to one O'Brian, and tell him, if any body came to ask any questions, to keep his mind to himself.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-54-person448">
                  William 
                  Gee 
               <interp inst="t17510911-54-person448" type="surname" value="Gee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-54-person448" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-54-person448" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable. On the 23d of August the prisoner was in my custody, who said she would work seven years to make Mr. Wilson satisfaction for the money he had lost, and if I would go with her to her master, she would give a note for 4 l. 10 s.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say 4 l. 10 s. a year, till it was repaid.</p>
               <p>Gee. No, my Lord, only for one year's wages.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-54-person449">
                  John 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17510911-54-person449" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-54-person449" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-54-person449" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I told the money, I think, on the third, fourth, or fifth of August; there were twenty guineas, and four half guineas in a drawer, in the chest of drawers, which was always kept locked.</p>
               <p>Q. Who keeps the key?</p>
               <p>Wilson. Sometimes I do, and sometimes my wife; but she had it most, and if money was to be paid, she generally went up for it.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this money missing?</p>
               <p>Wilson. I believe it was on the 23d of August,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175109110031"></xptr> about ten days after she cleaned the rooms; then she came to change the half guinea at the Hampshire Hog; there was a black spot upon one of the scepters, but it is now scratched off, though I dare say there is a dent there. I can swear to this half guinea, if it was put amongst fifty more, holding it in his hand. [The jury well examined it, but could find nothing upon any of the scepters to distinguish it from another.] She was asked how she came by it, she answered, May be some cull gave it me. She said, if I would let her go where she was going to be hired, her master should give a note for 4 l. 10 s. a year, as long as she stayed there.</p>

               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Wilson wanted me to clean her house, which I did on the third of 
               <persName id="t17510911-54-person450">
                  August 
                  The 
               <interp inst="t17510911-54-person450" type="surname" value="The"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-54-person450" type="given" value="August"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-54-person450" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             first place I cleaned out was the one pair of stairs room. I made the beds, and left the door open, and window open, for the room to dry; then I went up into the two pair of stairs room, and cleaned there. Mrs. Wilson and her son was with me, for she helped me; then I cleaned all the stairs. After that she told me not to do any more that night, but come again the next morning. I went the next morning at seven, and cleaned the brass and pewter; after that she paid me one shilling and sixpence for two days.</p>
               <p>Q. to Eliz. Wilson. Was you with the prisoner all the while?</p>
               <p>E. Wilson. I was only absent about two minutes, to get a little sand, and left the door open; but when I came back, I locked it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the boy with her?</p>
               <p>E. Wilson. He was in the room with her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you, when you lock'd the door, shut up the window?</p>
               <p>E. Wilson. I did not shut that then.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510911-54-verdict252" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510911-54-verdict252" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
