<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17550515-10">
               <interp inst="t17550515-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550515-10" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550515-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550515"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550515-10" type="date" value="17550515"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550515-10-off42-c78" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-10-defend92 t17550515-10-off42 t17550515-10-verdict44"></join>
         
               <p>217. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17550515-10-defend92" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Elisabeth 
                     Pool 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17550515-10-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-10-defend92 t17550515-10-alias-3"></join>Easterby</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-10-defend92" type="surname" value="Pool"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-10-defend92" type="given" value="Elisabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-10-defend92" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17550515-10-deflabel41" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-10-defend92 t17550515-10-deflabel41"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17550515-10-off42" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550515-10-off42" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-10-off42" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one pair of thread hose, value 2 s. 6 d. one silk handkerchief, value 1 s. one pound of soap, half a yard of muslin, one gallon of small-beer, half a bushel of coals, three pounds weight of bread, half a pound of butter, and three pounds of roast mutton
            </rs>, the goods of 
               <persName id="t17550515-10-victim94" type="victimName">
                  Higgens 
                  Peyton 
               <interp inst="t17550515-10-victim94" type="surname" value="Peyton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-10-victim94" type="given" value="Higgens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-10-victim94" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-10-off42 t17550515-10-victim94"></join>
                  </persName>
             , <rs id="t17550515-10-cd43" type="crimeDate">May 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-10-off42 t17550515-10-cd43"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>Higgens Peyton. On this day fortnight I was informed my cook-maid, the prisoner at the bar, used to admit a man in at the fore-parlour window, and after staying there some time, return back the same way; and that she handed out a basket, which he used to take away. I got up the next morning, between three and four o'clock, and opening one of the shutters of the dining-room window, from whence I could see the fore-parlour window, I saw a man in a great coat getting in at it, and after staying about half an hour, returned, and received a basket from the window, but I could not see who gave it. He then unlocked my area-door, and went away with the basket. On the Monday morning I saw him come about five o'clock, and open my area-door, and get in at the window; I had two people in readiness to take him, it was the same man whom I saw on the Saturday morning. After staying in my house some time, I saw him get out again, and a basket was handed to him as before; he went out set down the basket, and locked the area-door; then took up the basket, and was carrying it away; but he had not been a minute from my house, but as soon as I got down, they brought him back; the man confessed he had been in six or seven times, and begged I would forgive him; so did the prisoner. He confessed before Mr. Fielding he had taken away the things that these baskets contained. There were two baskets which I saw opened before Mr. Fielding, there was a cag of small-beer in one basket, in the other there was about half a quartern loaf of bread, about half a pound of butter, and about two pounds and a half of roast mutton, and about half a bushel of coals; these they both confessed they took from me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she confess she was the person that handed out these things?</p>
               <p>Peyton. No, she did not; but said she had committed the fact. Upon the prisoner's delivering the key of her trunk to me, I delivered it to my wife; she will give an account what she found there. After this, I carried the prisoner and the man before my Lord-Mayor, when he was pleased to commit the man to the house of correction, and the prisoner to Newgate; he has since made his escape.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550515-10-person95">
                  Henry 
                  Bodicote 
               <interp inst="t17550515-10-person95" type="surname" value="Bodicote"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-10-person95" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-10-person95" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Monday was se'nnight, between the hours of five and six, I waited at the end of Castle-yard for the man's coming out, that was gone into the prosecutor's house, I did not see him go in or come out, but met him with two baskets, one in each hand; I told him he must go back with me to the house where he brought them from, he did; in the house he owned he had done the same six or seven mornings before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner confess any thing?</p>
               <p>Bodicote. Not in my hearing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550515-10-person96">
                  Edward 
                  Wybourne 
               <interp inst="t17550515-10-person96" type="surname" value="Wybourne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-10-person96" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-10-person96" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard the prisoner say she was sorry for what she had done.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say what she had done?</p>
               <p>Wybourne. Not in my hearing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550515-10-person97">
                  Robert 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17550515-10-person97" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-10-person97" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-10-person97" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Bodicote, he ordered me to go along with him that morning, I saw the man go in at the window, he had but one basket and came out with two; I saw a woman open the window of Mr. Peyton's house, but can't say it was the prisoner. When he came out he had two baskets.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the prisoner convey anything out?</p>
               <p>Carter. I can't say I did.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175505150008"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17550515-10-person98">
                  Deborah 
                  Morley 
               <interp inst="t17550515-10-person98" type="surname" value="Morley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-10-person98" type="given" value="Deborah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-10-person98" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mr. Peyton; I saw the prisoner's box opened, and there was found in it a pair of Mr. Peyton's white thread-stockings, and also a silk handkerchief of my master's, likewise some pieces of soap, I can't tell who those belonged to. (The stockings and hankerchief produced in court.)</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. What is the value of the stockings and handkerchief?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. The stockings cost three shillings and six-pence, and the handkerchief four shillings and six-pence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550515-10-person99">
                  Catherine 
                  Dickerson 
               <interp inst="t17550515-10-person99" type="surname" value="Dickerson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-10-person99" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-10-person99" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mr. Peyton; I saw the prisoner's boxes brought down, upon the opening them, to the best of my knowledge, there were a pair of thread stockings taken out with my master's mark on them; there was also a handkerchief taken out of another small box, and some pieces of soap.</p>
               <p>D. Morley. That box was the prisoner's.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Peyton. I found these pair of stockings and handkerchief in the prisoner's box the 15th of this month, they are mine; I gave her half a dozen pair of stockings last July, but these were bought since that, and marked last September, the stockings cost three shillings, the box was locked in which the stockings were in, but that which the handkerchief was in was not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>My mistress gave me half a dozen pair of stockings, and as to the box which the handkerchief was in, it had no lock upon it.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. My wife did inform me she had given her several pair of stockings some time ago.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17550515-10-verdict44" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550515-10-verdict44" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
