<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570914-41">
               <interp inst="t17570914-41" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-41" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-41" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570914"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-41" type="date" value="17570914"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570914-41-off266-c425" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-41-defend511 t17570914-41-off266 t17570914-41-verdict269"></join>
         
               <p>349. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17570914-41-defend511" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Murray 
                  <interp inst="t17570914-41-defend511" type="surname" value="Murray"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-defend511" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-defend511" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for the <rs id="t17570914-41-off266" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-off266" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-off266" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               wilful murder
            </rs> of 
               
                  <persName id="t17570914-41-victim513" type="victimName">
                     Edward 
                     Clark 
                  <interp inst="t17570914-41-victim513" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-victim513" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-victim513" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-41-off266 t17570914-41-victim513"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            . He likewise stood charged for the said murder on the coroner's inquest, <rs id="t17570914-41-cd267" type="crimeDate">July 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-41-off266 t17570914-41-cd267"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-41-person514">
                  Thomas 
                  Russel 
               <interp inst="t17570914-41-person514" type="surname" value="Russel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person514" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person514" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I can't tell the day of the month, it was on a Sunday morning; as I was coming down the back lane the clock struck six: This was about a quarter of a mile from the prisoner's cellar door, in the back lane. When I came there I heard a noise. There was a man about buying of a shirt of the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Russel. He <rs id="t17570914-41-deflabel268" type="occupation">sells shirts and old shoes, and such things</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-41-defend511 t17570914-41-deflabel268"></join>. Hearing a great noise I stop'd. I heard the man that is dead say, '' If you did not like '' the money that I bid you, you might have bid '' me go about my business, and said, you rogue, '' you have done me an injury, which, I think, I '' shall never get over; you had no occasion to '' use me so ill; here is money if you would have '' taken it.'' There was a sort of a skirmish in the cellar. Clark the deceased made haste up out of the cellar. Murray followed him, and push'd him with his right elbow several times in the stomach and bowels in the street. Clark said he would make him pay for it the next day. As the prisoner was following him I went away, and was absent the best part of half an hour. After that I saw the deceased, about a quarter of a mile from Murray's cellar, heaving up blood. I saw him do it three times.</p>
               <p>Q. In what place was he then ?</p>
               <p>Russel. I can't tell the name of the lane. He turn'd himself round, and I said, God bless me have you received some inward blow? He made me no answer. In a quarter of an hour after that he was dead.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether Clark made any resistance when this elbowing was?</p>
               <p>Russel. No, he made none.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you a coal-heaver?</p>
               <p>Russel. No, I am not. I am a craft.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was there besides you?</p>
               <p>Russel. There were several people, but all strangers to me. I neither knew Murray nor the deceased before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-41-person515">
                  Robert 
                  Burcher 
               <interp inst="t17570914-41-person515" type="surname" value="Burcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person515" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person515" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was taking a walk by on a Sunday morning, and heard a noise in this cellar. I stood at the door, being willing to see what it was. Presently the deceased came up out of the cellar, pretty much in a hurry. The prisoner at the bar followed him, and said, this fellow pretends to buy a shirt, and at the same time comes to steal one, meaning the deceased, and swang his hand about. The deceased said, did you see me offer to<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175709140052"></xptr> lay my hand on any thing. The prisoner answer'd, you dog, if you don't go along, I will beat your head into the channel, making all the tricks and game on the deceased he could, and pelting him with several things.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he throw at him?</p>
               <p>Burcher. I do not know what they were. I think one thing look'd like a piece of bone, and he followed him as far as the Bull and Butcher door, which is about fifty or sixty yards from his cellar door. Murray came and faced him opposite that door, and set another man to laugh at him. I being dry, went in at the Sun and Sword, facing Murray's. While I was drinking my pint of beer the prisoner was taken up, and Clark was dead.</p>
               <p>Q. In how long time was this ?</p>
               <p>Burcher. I believe all this was within half an hour. There were some people that stood by who knew I knew something of it, so they desired me to go before the justice.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was he from the deceased when he threw at him?</p>
               <p>Burcher. About thirty yards distance, following him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any thing hit the deceased.</p>
               <p>Burcher. I did not perceive any thing did. I saw the prisoner offering his elbow to the deceased, but whether his elbow touch'd his body I was not high enough to see.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-41-person516">
                  Robert 
                  Mackloney 
               <interp inst="t17570914-41-person516" type="surname" value="Mackloney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person516" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person516" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was drawing a pint of beer at the Sun and Sword, for a gentleman that was going by on horseback. I heard a noise, and heard Mr. Murray bid the deceased go two or three times, but he would not. Mr. Murray give him a push with his elbow. The deceased gave Mr. Murray several words of ill language, but I do not remember what.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>Mackloney. It was at Mr. Murray's cellar door in the street. He only gave him a push, and said, go away you scoundrel.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-41-person517">
                  Mary 
                  Tompson 
               <interp inst="t17570914-41-person517" type="surname" value="Tompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person517" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person517" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going to drink a pint of beer at the Bull and Butcher, when I saw the prisoner come out of his cellar, and give the deceased a knock on his side with his fist.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it with his fist or elbow?</p>
               <p>M. Tompson. With his fist, which was the first thing I saw. He call'd him Munster man before he struck him. The deceased went away two or three doors beyond the Horns and Horshoe. The prisoner followed him, and gave him a kick with his foot. I know no more, only I saw the deceased after he was dead.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was you to the prisoner when he gave the deceased that blow ?</p>
               <p>M. Tompson. Within three yards of him.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the deceased say ?</p>
               <p>M. Thompson. He said, what are you going to kill me?</p>
               <p>Q. Did he call Murray any names ?</p>
               <p>M. Tompson. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is the Horns and Horshoe from the prisoner's cellar ?</p>
               <p>M. Tompson. It is about as far as cross the Court-yard.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-41-person518">
                  John 
                  Newton 
               <interp inst="t17570914-41-person518" type="surname" value="Newton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person518" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person518" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Bull and Butcher.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is that from the prisoner's cellar ?</p>
               <p>Newton. It is about sixty yards. The deceased came into my house and call'd for a pint of hot, which, I imagine, was after all was over. He came in a stooping posture, with his hands on his breast, saying, he had been used very ill by a man where he had been to buy a shirt. I believe he was not in my house above five minutes, and in about five minutes after a man came in and said, the man that had a pint of hot was d ead. He drank about a gill of the hot, or a little better. Then I went to the prisoner and said, it is a pity you should use any man so ill.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-41-person519">
                  Samuel 
                  Darkin 
               <interp inst="t17570914-41-person519" type="surname" value="Darkin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person519" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person519" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a surgeon, and was call'd in by the parish to inspect the body of the deceased. We open'd him, and found a large quantity of extravasated blood in the thorax, which proceeded from the large artery, leading directly to the heart, being burst, and was sufficient cause for the man's death. It is the greatest artery in the body.</p>
               <p>Q. Which way do you imagine that might come ?</p>
               <p>Darkin. It might be by a blow or a fall, or any external violence on the part. If by a fall, it must be by pitching on a post, or such like thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any bruise on the out-side of the body?</p>
               <p>Darkin. No.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-41-person520">
                  John 
                  Holsford 
               <interp inst="t17570914-41-person520" type="surname" value="Holsford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person520" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person520" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a surgeon. The prisoner employed me to inspect the body of the deceased. We found a large quantity of coagulated blood upon opening the thorax. We removed the blood and examined the lungs, and found them in a sound state. We found the large blood vessel, leading to the heart, was ruptur'd, with which it is impossible for a man to live.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you form any judgement which way that vessel came to be ruptur'd ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175709140053"></xptr>Holsford. It might be by some violent blow just as the vessel was extended by the motion of the body.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Supposing a man was to give a person a push with his elbow, could that burst that vessel ?</p>
               <p>Holsford. Not without great violence.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I never meddled with the man any more than your Lordship, nor never left my own door. The poor man was almost dead when I saw him down in my cellar; to look in his face you would not think he could live half an hour. I think it a sin to strike a man in his health, much more so when he is almost dead. He was hardly able to go up-stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. to Newton. Did you know the deceased before ?</p>
               <p>Newton. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. In what condition was he before, in regard to his health?</p>
               <p>Newton. He was a sickly ailing person.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-41-person521">
                  Edward 
                  Moreton 
               <interp inst="t17570914-41-person521" type="surname" value="Moreton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person521" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person521" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The deceased work'd for me on board a ship, in taking coals out of her. He had work'd the 23d of July, which was the day before he died, and not being well, he did not work his time by an hour.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-41-person522">
                  Daniel 
                  Brian 
               <interp inst="t17570914-41-person522" type="surname" value="Brian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person522" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person522" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The deceased work'd one week along with me on board a ship, call'd the Bee. I am a coal-heaver. There were three of us in the hold together that Saturday, and every one of us were to do our share. He did not work all the day. Between ten and twelve he complained he was not able to do his work as a man ought to do. He could not fill the basket. Then he ask'd us to crane it up, for he could not. When we were coming up out of the hold he fell down, and by and bye he began to spew blood. He said the man had kill'd him that went to help him up out of the hold. He vomited a great deal of blood, about a quart. A man had trod upon him as he was getting out of the hold. I offer'd a crown on deck that he might have the benefit of clergy. I thought he would die in less than half an hour.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-41-person523">
                  John 
                  Garthwate 
               <interp inst="t17570914-41-person523" type="surname" value="Garthwate"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person523" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person523" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at work with the deceased on the Friday or Saturday, I can't say which. He was taken ill about two in the afternoon.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear him complain of any illness in the hold ?</p>
               <p>Garthwate. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you upon deck ?</p>
               <p>Garthwate. No.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you know then?</p>
               <p>Garthwate. I saw him vomit up a pretty large quantity of blood, about two o'clock in the afternoon. He left work about two hours before the rest of us, and was help'd into the boat by some of us.</p>
               <p>Q. How did that vomiting of blood happen?</p>
               <p>Garthwate. I do not know. I did not hear.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-41-person524">
                  John 
                  Boyd 
               <interp inst="t17570914-41-person524" type="surname" value="Boyd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person524" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person524" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew Clark the deceased. He work'd on board the Bee with me on the Saturday before he died. I saw him dropping down, and his head came against the gunnel; whether it was owing to drunkenness I cannot tell, but he was spewing a large quantity of blood upon deck.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he received any hurt that occasioned it?</p>
               <p>Boyd. That I don't know.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-41-person525">
                  Lawrence 
                  Demingh 
               <interp inst="t17570914-41-person525" type="surname" value="Demingh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person525" type="given" value="Lawrence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person525" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew Clark, but don't know whether he is dead or not. I have heard say he is dead, and remember he was ill when at work with me on board the Bee. He could not come upon deck till he was helped up in the basket. He said he was hurt by one in the hold, that he thought to come up the first man, but another man got upon his shoulders, and he was forced to put his hands on his knees. He drop'd backwards on the deck. I had him by the forehead and back part of his head. He vomited much, and was not able to work.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him get into the boat to come away ?</p>
               <p>Demingh. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-41-person526">
                  Mary 
                  Hackney 
               <interp inst="t17570914-41-person526" type="surname" value="Hackney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person526" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person526" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The deceased call'd the Sunday morning, about five o'clock, on which he died, for a pint of beer. I ask'd him how he did. He said he was not well. I said, I think you don't look well. He said he was very ill, that he had a bad fall on board a ship, and had been bleeding upwards and downwards all night; he was then very sick.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-41-person527">
                  Joseph 
                  Moody 
               <interp inst="t17570914-41-person527" type="surname" value="Moody"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person527" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person527" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never saw the deceased before he came into the house and ask'd 
               <persName id="t17570914-41-person528">
                  Mary 
                  Hackney 
               <interp inst="t17570914-41-person528" type="surname" value="Hackney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person528" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person528" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             for a pint of beer. He said he had never been well since he had a fall on board a ship, and all that night had been bleeding upwards and downwards.</p>
               <p>Edward Cashman. I was up that morning between five and six o'clock, and heard Murray and a man scolding in the street. Murray call'd him<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175709140054"></xptr> Munster thief. The man said he was no Munster man, he was a Connor man. Murray call'd him so still. The man walked away, and Murray took a bone and threw after him. The man turn'd about and said, I'll make you pay for that to-morrow. I said to Murray, was that man going to steal a pair of shoes? No, said he, I was only playing the joak with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any struggling between them?</p>
               <p>Cashman. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Michael M'Carty. I live just by Mr. Murray, I heard him and the deceased scolding at one another, but did not see Murray do any thing to him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-41-person529">
                  Mary 
                  Timmings 
               <interp inst="t17570914-41-person529" type="surname" value="Timmings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person529" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-person529" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw Clark that day stand about six doors from Murray's, talking to him. Murray call'd him a Munster man. He said, he was a Connor man. I saw Clark go in at the Bull and Butcher. He had an ague upon him, and look'd like death. I never saw a blow given.</p>
               <p>Mr. White. I have known the prisoner about eleven years.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he a quarrelsome or cruel man?</p>
               <p>White. I keep a publick house. He has been in it many a time, and I never heard him in any quarrel.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570914-41-verdict269" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570914-41-verdict269" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
