<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17571026-23">
               <interp inst="t17571026-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17571026-23" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17571026-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17571026"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17571026-23" type="date" value="17571026"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17571026-23-off119-c201" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571026-23-defend240 t17571026-23-off119 t17571026-23-verdict121"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17571026-23-off119-c202" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571026-23-defend242 t17571026-23-off119 t17571026-23-verdict122"></join>
         
               <p>397, 398. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17571026-23-defend240" type="defendantName">
                     Terence 
                     Shortney 
                  <interp inst="t17571026-23-defend240" type="surname" value="Shortney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-23-defend240" type="given" value="Terence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-23-defend240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17571026-23-defend242" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Frip 
                  <interp inst="t17571026-23-defend242" type="surname" value="Frip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-23-defend242" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-23-defend242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             were indicted for <rs id="t17571026-23-off119" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17571026-23-off119" type="offenceCategory" value="miscellaneous"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-23-off119" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pervertingJustice"></interp>
               publishing a libel in order to prevent justice
            </rs>. ++</p>
               <p>[ See the trial of Capt. Morris, No. I in April Sessions.]</p>
               <p>Wells Egelsham. I am printer of the Public Advertiser. There was an advertisement brought by the prisoner Shortney [He looks on a paper] I know this to be the same, because here is the mark of the business upon it, which we put upon all advertisements.</p>
               <p>Q. What was it brought for?</p>
               <p>Egelsham. To be inserted in the paper.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it published?</p>
               <p>Egelsham. It was, on <rs id="t17571026-23-cd120" type="crimeDate">Tuesday the 19th of April</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571026-23-off119 t17571026-23-cd120"></join> last.</p>
               <p>Q. to Clerk of the Arraigns. Is this the same laid in the indictment?</p>
               <p>Mr. Ford, Clerk of the Arraigns. It is the same.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571026-23-person243">
                  Robert 
                  Spavan 
               <interp inst="t17571026-23-person243" type="surname" value="Spavan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-23-person243" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-23-person243" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . As to this paper I know nothing of it; I did not take it in. I heard Shortney own he was the author of it, and that he brought it in order to be printed in the Public Advertiser.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did he own that to?</p>
               <p>Spavan. He own'd it to me.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Spavan. This was the Thursday after it was published; it was published on the Tuesday before.</p>
               <p>Capt. 
               <persName id="t17571026-23-person244">
                  John 
                  Morris 
               <interp inst="t17571026-23-person244" type="surname" value="Morris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-23-person244" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-23-person244" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This advertisement was produced on my trial. Immediately after the trial the prisoner Shortney confessed he wrote it himself, and left it with the printer.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Capt. Morris. This was when I enter'd into recognizance to prosecute.</p>
               <p>Q. Produce the paper which he said was his own hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Capt. Morris. delivers a paper into Mr. Ford's hand.</p>
               <p>The record of the trial and acquittal of Captain Morris was read in court.</p>
               <p>Then the libel was read and compared with the indictment, viz.</p>
               <p>' To the truly charitable and humane, friends of ' and enemies to the violaters of virtue.</p>
               <p>' An unhappy gentlewoman, whose husband being ' under unavoidable misfortunes, was necessitated ' to be continually on the foot amongst ' her friends endeavouring to extricate him, was ' way-laid by a base and notorious villain, who, ' under pretence of assisting her husband, inveigled ' her into his power, and cruelly used and ravished ' her, for which he stands indicted these seven ' months past, ever since which he has absconded. ' But upon hearing that he was to be out-lawed, ' and that the poor woman was dangerously ill (as ' she has been for four months since this unhappy ' affair) he put the unhappy sufferers to great expences<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175710260030"></xptr> ' in attending several notices of his surrender ' to trial (at times that he was well assured ' that the poor woman was not able to sit up in her ' bed, much less to appear in court to try him) ' which expence, her sickness, and the loss of her ' husband's time, has rendered them objects of ' unutterable compassion. They therefore are indispensibly ' obliged thus most humbly to call upon ' the truly charitable and humane, to enable ' them to bring this vile offender to justice, who, ' from the strength of money, and the powerful ' friends that he ( vile as he is) has to stand by ' him, boasts that he'll get over this prosecution, ' which so loudly calls for the assistance of every ' virtuous lady, tender husband, and truly affectionate ' parent. This (now) unhappy couple, ' having nothing to back them in this melancholy ' prosecution, but the justness of their resentment, ' fear, that it is absolutely necessary for them to ' have proper council at the trial, to minutely examine ' his witnesses (as they are told he has a ' great many prepared) have it not in their present ' abilities to see council (as he too well knows and ' boasts of) unless charitably aided, as above requested; ' upon the strength of which he proposes ' taking his trial next sessions at the Old-Bailey, ' which begins to-morrow, and has given ' notice to the prosecutors, that he will surrender ' in court that day.</p>
               <p>' Donations will be most gratefully acknowledged ' in this paper, or in person by the unhappy ' sufferers, if admitted, and will be received by ' Mr. 
               <persName id="t17571026-23-person245">
                  John 
                  Frip 
               <interp inst="t17571026-23-person245" type="surname" value="Frip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-23-person245" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-23-person245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , apothecary, in Carey-street, opposit ' to the Plough Inn, Lincoln's-Inn, who ' has attended the poor woman in her sickness ' these four months past, and still attends her, and ' who, in compassion to their deplorable situation, ' is pleased to take the trouble upon him.'</p>
               <p>After which it was read and compared with the printed account in the Public Advertiser the 18th and 19th of April last.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>Without troubling the court I submit to the mercy of the court, and hope it will be considered I have suffered by two sits of illness since I have been in Newgate.</p>
               <p>Frip's Defence.</p>
               <p>The prisoner is the sole author of it, what I did was out of charity, he called upon me after he had left it with the printer, and told me he had made use of my name to receive donations for him; I consented to it, not thinking of the consequence.</p>
               <p>Capt. Morris. I n regard to Mr. Frip, I believe he was really innocent, and was lead into it by the prisoner Shortney.</p>
               <p>Q. to Egelsham. Did Mr. Frip come with Shortney when he brought the advertisement?</p>
               <p>Egelsham. He did not; as his name was to it, to receive donations, I went to him and asked him whether he was the author of the advertisement, he told me no. (His wife had said the same to Mr. Spavan before.) Mr. Frip said it was one Shortney that told him he had brought it to our house to be inserted, and after he had left it he called upon him and acquainted him therewith, that he had used his name, and that it was without his knowledge his name was made use of; and he passed it off, thinking it was a good-natured action, and did not trouble himself about it.</p>
               <p>Shortney <rs id="t17571026-23-verdict121" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17571026-23-verdict121" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Frip <rs id="t17571026-23-verdict122" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17571026-23-verdict122" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17571026-23-punish123" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17571026-23-punish123" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-23-punish123" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="fine"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571026-23-defend240 t17571026-23-punish123"></join>
               
                     <note>[Fine. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17571026-23-punish124" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17571026-23-punish124" type="punishmentCategory" value="imprison"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571026-23-defend240 t17571026-23-punish124"></join>
               
                     <note>[Imprisonment. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
