<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17590717-1">
               <interp inst="t17590717-1" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590717-1" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590717-1" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17590717"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590717-1" type="date" value="17590717"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17590717-1-off1-c18" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590717-1-defend19 t17590717-1-off1 t17590717-1-verdict4"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17590717-1-off1-c19" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590717-1-defend21 t17590717-1-off1 t17590717-1-verdict4"></join>
         
               <p>243, 244. 
               
                  <persName id="t17590717-1-defend19" type="defendantName">
                     Samuel 
                     Scrimshaw 
                  <interp inst="t17590717-1-defend19" type="surname" value="Scrimshaw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-defend19" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-defend19" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17590717-1-defend21" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Ross 
                  <interp inst="t17590717-1-defend21" type="surname" value="Ross"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-defend21" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-defend21" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted <rs id="t17590717-1-off1" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-off1" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-off1" type="offenceSubcategory" value="extortion"></interp>
               together with 
                     <persName id="t17590717-1-person22">
                        John 
                        Richardson 
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person22" type="surname" value="Richardson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590717-1-person22" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590717-1-person22" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , not taken, for that they being persons of wicked and corrupt minds and dispositions, without the fear of God before their eyes, and wickedly and maliciously desing, and intending, through the instigation of the Devil, not only unjustly to disturb the peace and happiness of 
                     <persName id="t17590717-1-victim23" type="victimName">
                        Humphry 
                        Morice 
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-victim23" type="surname" value="Morice"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590717-1-victim23" type="given" value="Humphry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590717-1-victim23" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590717-1-off1 t17590717-1-victim23"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , <rs id="t17590717-1-viclabel2" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590717-1-victim23 t17590717-1-viclabel2"></join>; an honest, upright, and worthy leige-subject of our said Lord the King; but also to injure him in his good character and reputation, as in his estate and fortune; and also by wicked and diabolical devices, accusations, and pretences, unjustly to acquire to themselves, a large sum of money from him the said Humphry, to support their useless and profligate ways of life, on the <rs id="t17590717-1-cd3" type="crimeDate">26th of Feb.</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590717-1-off1 t17590717-1-cd3"></join> and upon divers other days and times, with force and arms, at London, did wickedly, unlawfully, and maliciously, combine, conspire, confederate, and agree together, to write divers wicked and scandalous letters to him, with divers horrid, wicked, false, and malicious threats, insinuations, and menaces therein contained, unjustly to defame, and injure his character, and to disturb his peace and happiness, unless he would comply with divers wicked, scandalous, unjust, and oppressive terms, contained in the said letters, to the great damage, injury, and oppression of him the said Humphry; to the great dishonour and scandal of the laws of this kingdom, to the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907170003"></xptr> evil and pernicious example of all others, in the like case offending, and against the peace of our said lord the King, his crown and dignity. With four other counts, varying the nature of the offence
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>After the indictment was opened by Mr Eyre, Mr Serjeant Davy spoke as follows *.</p> 
               <p> *The publisher of this trial thinks it his duty to acquaint the publick, that he had no opportunity of saying Mr. Serjeant Davy's speech before him, for his perusal, before he went the Circuit; and that 'tis now printed from the Short-Hand Writer's notes, with all the care that is possible.</p>
               <p>May it please your Lordship, and you Gentlemen of the Jury. I am Counsel in this case for the prosecution, against the two defendants at the bar.</p>
               <p>This is an indictment consisting of five counts, containing two species of offences. The first four counts are for a conspiracy in the manner mentioned in the indictment.</p>
               <p>The first count for a conspiracy to extort money from Mr Morice, by threatning falsely to accuse him of certain detestable crimes, of which he was innocent.</p>
               <p>The second count for a conspiracy to extort money, by threatning falsely to charge him with having been guilty of sodomitical practices, of which he was wholly innocent.</p>
               <p>The third count for a conspiracy, to write divers wicked, false, and scandalous letters to him, with divers false, horrid, and malicious threats, insinuations, and charges therein, unjustly to defame, and injure him in his character.</p>
               <p>The fourth count, and to which, perhaps, this case will be more particularly applicable, is, that they did agree together, to extort money from Mr Morice; and in order to bring it; about, that they did write divers, wicked, and scandalous letters, with divers, impious, false, and malicious charges, and accusations, therein contained, unjustly to defame, and injure that gentleman in his character.</p>
               <p>These are the counts in this indictment, with respect to the conspiracy.</p>
               <p>There is another general count, for sending threatning letters to Mr Morice, highly reflecting on his character, with intention to extort money from him.</p>
               <p>Gentlemen, these are two different sorts of offences; and with regard to the first, a single person cannot be guilty of it, for no man can conspire with himself alone. There are three different persons in this indictment, two of them only are before you (the third is not taken). Two persons may be guilty of a conspiracy, so that if you should find either of these defendants have agreed with Richardson, or with each other, you may find your verdict accordingly.</p>
               <p>I thought proper to mention this, because this is a case (as all conspiracies are) attended with some difficulty.</p>
               <p>It is necessary you should apply your attention to that general rule of law I have mentioned.</p>
               <p>Conspiracies are things not easily found out; they are not at first so intelligible as could be wished. It becomes my duty, and I hope I shall have no need to make an apology for taking up your time, to relate this matter to you as intelligibly, and clearly, as possible, in order that you may be enabled to apply your attention more properly to the several sorts of evidence, which will be laid before you.</p>
               <p>Gentlemen, in the first place, it is necessary you should be informed who these persons are, Scrimshaw, Richardson, and Ross, for though Richardson is not before the court, yet, if it appears that either Scrimshaw or Ross conspired with him, then that person is as guilty, as if he had conspired with the other.</p>
               <p>These three persons were lately partners in an Office of Intelligence, kept in Fleet-Market, in the City of London, an office where servants were to be informed of masters, and other persons of a variety of other things; amongst which, commissions in the army; and these two articles of business introduced these persons into the guilt they are charged with.</p>
               <p>Scrimshaw was formerly a Hair-Merchant in Covent-Garden, but since a bankrupt.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907170004"></xptr>Richardson was formerly a Linnen-Draper, but since a bankrupt. Likewise,</p>
               <p>Ross was lately a common Soldier.</p>
               <p>These three persons have entered into a partnership together, and kept this Office of Intelligence.</p>
               <p>There is one 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person24">
                  Peter 
                  Parry 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person24" type="surname" value="Parry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person24" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person24" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who will appear before you as a witness. He had occasion to apply to this office in January last, for intelligence of a place to serve as a servant to a hop-merchant. This enquiry, which cost him one shilling, occasioned several meetings between him and the defendants. Parry it seems had made an appointment some time ago to meet Scrimshaw and Richardson, in order to treat upon some business; but was hindered from keeping it, by another engagement that he entered into, of going to the Fountain-Tavern on Ludgate-Hill; and from this occasion, the whole of this conspiracy took it's rise.</p>
               <p>Mr Morice, the gentleman who prosecutes the persons before you, had a servant, one Gosling, who was his groom, and had had some unhappy differences with his wife; in order to their coming to some terms, there was to be a meeting with Gosling and his wife, and some friends, at the Fountain-Tavern; at which Parry, by means of his wife being an acquaintance of Gosling's wife, was there; and Mr Steydall of Maddox-street, a gentleman of known good character, at the request of Gosling, was also at this meeting.</p>
               <p>On this occasion, as frequently is the case, when men and their wives meet to make up breaches, they part less affectionate than they met; it happened so here, - for Gosling's wife, who is not of the most peaceable temper in the world, happened to use some harsh expressions to her husband; and amongst other opprobrious names, called him, in her passion, a Buggerer. Now from that single circumstance all this great scene of conspiracy, which will be laid before you, arises. Parry was there, and heard this, but at that time did not apply it to any purpose. At his next meeting with Scrimshaw and Richardson, which was at the Earl of Warwick in Fleet-Lane, which is in the city of London, (for it is very necessary for you, gentlemen, to consider what was done in the city of London) he was to make his apology for net having met them according to his appointment. - There was another gentleman happen'd to be there; and I am sorry to find he is not in this indictment; his name is Boulton Comson, an Attorney. Parry in making his apology to Scrimshaw, for not coming to his appointment, told the true reason, the meeting of Gosling and his wife; and in conversation told them what had passed between them. Scrimshaw, upon hearing the word Buggerer put his singer up to his nose; and said, something may come of this. - When such low people keep an office of intelligence they are glad to have intelligence of all kinds. - Then said he, do you call upon me, (speaking to Parry) to-morrow, something may be made of this; the next day Parry went, then Scrimshaw made him this infamous proposal, - That as to what had been said the night before, of Gosling's wife accusing her husband of buggery, and observing that he lived with Mr Morice, and that gentlemen, who are tender of their reputation, are the fittest persons to work upon, - said, if this matter is well managed it will be a fortune to us. - It would be a mine, - do you attend to me on this occasion, and we will make a considerable sum of money out of this.</p>
               <p>Several meetings were had, and several proposals made, but they did not hit, and correspond; but at last it was agreed, that Parry was to be the hand through which this business was to be transacted. - Scrimshaw, Richardson, and Ross, had also several meetings, unknown to Parry, and agreed to be the prompters of Parry, to direct him in what manner the scheme should be executed. Scrimshaw first wrote a letter in a disguised hand to Mr Morice, directed it to him in Dover-Street, and put it into the Penny-Post. That letter, it is true, was wrote at a house near the Cockpit, which is not in the city of London.</p>
               <p>But I should have told you, that in order to convict persons of a conspiracy, it is not necessary to prove that any thing was done in consequence of it. For a bare conspiracy to do an unlawful act, is a crime of itself indictable, although nothing further is done in pursuance of it. But whatever happened in any other place, in consequence of this conspiracy in London,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907170005"></xptr> this court hath jurisdiction to inquire into. Accordingly the following letter was sent.</p>
               <p>London, Feb. 27. 1759.</p>
               <p>'Honoured Sir,</p>
               <p>'I Hope you will excuse my taking this liberty</p>
               <p>'(more so as I am a stranger to you) but</p>
               <p>'I happen'd to be at a certain place not long</p>
               <p>'since, where your name was drawn in question</p>
               <p>'upon a subject I am certain was you to</p>
               <p>'know it, you would by no means approve of</p>
               <p>'it (more so, as the party receives so considerable</p>
               <p>'a bounty from your hand, and is</p>
               <p>'maintained by you). If you desire to know</p>
               <p>'the particulars, will make an affidavit of</p>
               <p>'what was mentioned, and will explain other</p>
               <p>'instances to you concerning what I have here</p>
               <p>'mentioned, and must beg my name to be kept</p>
               <p>'a secret. If you think it proper may send</p>
               <p>'me a line directed thus; To R. E. to be</p>
               <p>'left at the Paul's Head, Lawrence-Lane,</p>
               <p>'Cheapside. Or if it will be more agreeable,</p>
               <p>'be pleased to put it in the Daily Advertiser</p>
               <p>'on Saturday or Monday next, and you shall</p>
               <p>'hear farther from me, and all secrecy shall be</p>
               <p>'punctually observed.</p>
               <p>' I am, Sir,</p>
               <p>' Your most obedient,</p>
               <p>'humble servant to command,</p>
               <p>'R. E.'</p>
               <p>'To Humphry Morice, Esq;</p>
               <p>'Member of Parliament, at</p>
               <p>'his house Dover-Street,</p>
               <p>'Westminster.'</p>
               <p>Gentlemen, you see this letter orders the answer to be directed to the Paul's-Head, Lawrence-Lane, London. You observe farther, that this letter gives great hints of something to be told very much to the advantage of Mr Morice, which greatly concerns his character, and which will require the solemnity of an affidavit; you see too, a great secrecy is to be imposed on the very person, whom, if guilty, it concerned only to keep it so. Yet the conspirators are the persons who desire it may be made a secret. Mr Morice ordered a short answer to be sent to this letter;</p>
               <p>'Telling them,</p>
               <p>'if they would be at the Hoop-Tavern in Coventry-Street,</p>
               <p>'Piccadilly, next Sunday evening,</p>
               <p>'exactly at nine o'clock, he should be</p>
               <p>'there, ready to hear the particulars, and that</p>
               <p>'they might depend upon his observing an inviolable</p>
               <p>'secrecy; and if they could not meet</p>
               <p>'at that place to send a line by a porter, with</p>
               <p>'directions for them to ask for Mr Williams.'</p>
               <p>You observe, that Mr Morice, not knowing or guessing what sort of a secret was to be told him, adopted the name of Mr Williams, and you will see the reason for that by and by. - This letter was directed to R. E. at the Paul's-Head, Lawrence-Lane, where Parry found it, and communicated it to Scrimshaw and Comson, who met at Caywood's by Charing-Cross, where Comson prepared a draught for an answer, but Scrimshaw not approving it, altered it, and than copied it, and sent it by a private hand. It was dated March 3, 1759. 12 o'clock, and is as follows:</p>
               <p>'Honoured Sir,</p>
               <p>'YOur's I receiv'd,' here is an acknowledgment of having received the letter sent to Lawrence-Lane, Cheapside; then he proposes some other meeting, and says,</p>
               <p>'if it be agreeable to you, would rather meet you</p>
               <p>'either on Monday or Tuesday night, at the</p>
               <p>'place and time you mentioned; if not, will</p>
               <p>'to-morr ow night, as desired, and shall observe</p>
               <p>'the direction. Therefore I presume to</p>
               <p>'beg the favour of your interest, to intercede</p>
               <p>'for me with some gentlemen, to procure me</p>
               <p>'a place in the Custom-house, Victualling-Office,</p>
               <p>'or in any other station under the government,</p>
               <p>'in any part of England, as I am sensible</p>
               <p>'it is in your power to grant me a favour</p>
               <p>'of this kind, as vacancies of this nature daily</p>
               <p>'happens. Sir, in my asking you this favour,</p>
               <p>'I hope you will not take me (nor look upon</p>
               <p>'me) to be one of those that would offer to</p>
               <p>'impose upon any gentleman, as Sir John</p>
               <p>'Glyne, member for Flint, and 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person25">
                  Samuel 
                  Egerton 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person25" type="surname" value="Egerton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person25" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person25" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ,</p>
               <p>'Esq; member for Cheshire, and others,</p>
               <p>'knows me extremely well, and would do any</p>
               <p>'thing to serve me; but in asking of this nature</p>
               <p>'it is not in their power to serve a friend;<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907170006"></xptr> ' if it is, they do not chuse to make use of ' their interest, if they have any. As I have ' met with great losses, and have been out of ' employment above this two years, and having</p>
               <p>'a wife and child to maintain, has reduced</p>
               <p>'my circumstances very much, which is</p>
               <p>'the sole reason of my petitioning you to be</p>
               <p>'my friend; as it will be doing me a great</p>
               <p>'piece of service, and yourself no diskindness,</p>
               <p>'which shall be for ever acknowledged.' (This is a letter wrote by Scrimshaw in answer to Mr Morice's first letter; he mentions his connections with other persons, as a man of consequence, and then concludes in this manner)</p>
               <p>'(your compliance to the above will be much</p>
               <p>'better bestowed than on them who now receive</p>
               <p>'your bounty, and you may depend I</p>
               <p>'will disclose the whole, and nothing but the</p>
               <p>'truth, as I shall make an affidavit of the</p>
               <p>'same.) Be pleased to send me an answer to</p>
               <p>'the above, directed as before, and let it be</p>
               <p>'there by eight in the morning, if not tonight.</p>
               <p>'Your compliance to the within mentioned,</p>
               <p>'and you may command,</p>
               <p>'Your most obedient servant, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>'P. S. If possible let me have your answer tonight.</p>
               <p>'I should be greatly obliged to</p>
               <p>'you, to inclose in the answer a couple of</p>
               <p>'franks.'</p>
               <p>'To Humphry Morice, Esq;</p>
               <p>'Member of Parliament,</p>
               <p>'Dover-Street, Westminster.'</p>
               <p>They very modestly desire him to inclose a couple of franks, to show they are people of very genteel correspondence. To this Mr Morice caused this short answer to be wrote.</p>
               <p>'IF we do'nt meet this evening I can't hear</p>
               <p>'what you have to say in a great while,</p>
               <p>'being to go out of town to-morrow, so shall</p>
               <p>'expect you at nine o'clock.'</p>
               <p>Mr Morice, from the receipt of the first of these letters, saw very plainly, it was sent with some intent to extort money from him, and determined to prepare for a prosecution against the conspirators, whoever they should be; and therefore he let them proceed farther, before they should fall into the trap which was laid to catch them. - For this end an appointment was made for a meeting at the Hoop-Tavern on Sunday evening, and Mr Morice with his servant went there, but nobody came. Gentlemen, as the present defendants have no counsel, I will make it my duty to point out every circumstance in their favour. Hitherto Scrimshaw only has appeared with Parry, but it will appear that the other defendant Ross, (as well as Richardson, who is not now before the court) were all privy to the whole of this transaction; and though they did not all together confederate, and agree with Parry, yet they confederated and agreed one with another. A few days after this, upon Parry's going again to the Office of Intelligence in the Fleet-Market, Richardson and Ross applied to him. This is the first time they said any thing at all to him. They asked him how the grand affair went on. Now it is impossible they should have known any thing at all about this grand affair if they had had no communication with Scrimshaw: he informed them how the grand affair, as they call'd it, went on; then Richardson, in the presence of Ross and Parry, at the Golden Key, Fleetditch, drew up the following letter, which Parry copied, and sent to Mr Morice, dated the 28th of March.</p>

               <p>'SIR,</p>
               <p>'MY reason for not complying with your</p>
               <p>'repeated desires, of having an interview</p>
               <p>'with me at the Hoop-Tavern, in Coventry-street;</p>
               <p>'as I did not receive your letter 'till the</p>
               <p>'Monday, otherwise would have waited you.</p>
               <p>'There was two other gentlemen of my acquaintance,</p>
               <p>'in the adjoining room, whom</p>
               <p>'will come upon oath, of what passed, as well</p>
               <p>'as myself; you may depend on the greatest</p>
               <p>'honour, and secrecy. I have a relation that</p>
               <p>'has been twenty-three years in the Train of</p>
               <p>'Artillery, in the East-Indies, as Lieutenant,</p>
               <p>'lately come home; and is now Captain-Lieutenant</p>
               <p>'in the same: a gentleman of family</p>
               <p>'and fortune, who is desirous of being</p>
               <p>'promoted to the rank of Captain, in an old<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907170007"></xptr> ' company of Invalids, in Britain, or the adjacent</p>
               <p>'isles; or the Captain of an old regiment</p>
               <p>'of Foot, at home, or abroad. If this</p>
               <p>'is not agreeable to you, would be glad to</p>
               <p>'know what favours you would bestow; as the</p>
               <p>'point, now in-question, takes your honour in</p>
               <p>'the most tender part. I hope, for your own</p>
               <p>'peace, you will not fail in giving me a speedy</p>
               <p>'answer, directed as before.</p>
               <p>' I am,</p>
               <p>'Sir,</p>
               <p>' your most obedient servant,</p>
               <p>'to command, R. E.'</p>
               <p>This letter, gentlemen, was wrote by Richardson, in the presence of Ross; at this time I would explain to you a circumstance that appeared afterwards: the reason for their application for this captain's commission. - These people kept an Office of Intelligence, and it happened that about this time, a gentleman had applied to this office (as these office-keepers have a knowledge of all places, from the Great-Seal to the Hall-Keeper ) where you give them a shilling for intelligence, and have your name entered. - A letter had been sent to the office to be informed, if any such intelligence could be given, with a reward of two hundred pounds if they could get it. Here you see, that if they could have furnished their customer, they could have put the money into their own pockets. To this letter there is a postscript, that the party applying had been twenty-three years in the King's service.</p>
               <p>Mr Morice upon the reception of this letter sent the following answer.</p>
               <p>'AS I am quite in the dark about what</p>
               <p>'you have to tell me, nor can at all</p>
               <p>'guess what it is. I do not know how to</p>
               <p>'promise any thing 'till I hear what you</p>
               <p>'have to say, which I shall be ready to do</p>
               <p>'next Monday, the 2d of April, if you will</p>
               <p>'come to the Hoop-Tavern at five o'clock</p>
               <p>'and ask for Mr Williams. - What you</p>
               <p>'have to say to me let me know that first</p>
               <p>'then it is time to talk of favours.'</p>
               <p>He did not get an answer 'till the 31st of March: but in the mean time here is another circumstance that happened, which w evidently show that there was a connection between the defendants and Richardson.</p>
               <p>Ross and Richardson, immediately after the writing this last letter, in conversation with Parry, asked him, Is this man like to come down? - It is not every body that is like' to be affrighted with these letters. - Is Mr. Morice that kind of man that one might expect will bleed? And then Ross and Richardson to encourage Parry, told him, that they had made inquiry after Mr Morice's character: and gave this account of him, that he was a gentleman of a very great estate, and great interest and that he belonged to the Board of Green Cloth. - All this is true. - But then they added this circumstance, that he had lately paid 1500 l. smart-money on the like occasion. This, gentlemen, was the mere effect of their own wicked imaginations, and made use of to encourage Parry to go on: the next day, which is very material, Scrimshaw came to Parry, and told him the very same story. It is very true, you and I may at different times tell the same story to a third person, without having any communication with one another; but it is impossible you and I should both invent such a lye, and tell it exactly in the same manner, unless we have had some consultation together.</p>
               <p>Things being in this situation, Mr Morice was very desirous to have an interview with these conspirators; and did not discourage them too much, as the surest means of bringing them to justice, and of fixing them beyond all possibility of defence.</p>
               <p>Scrimshaw, on the other hand, looks upon every thing to be in a fair way of success, and takes notice to Parry, that Mr Morice is always desirous of an interview, and therefore hopes that Mr Morice will bleed freely: and that a good deal of money may be made on the occasion. Under this prospect he calls upon Parry to give him the following promissory note.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907170008"></xptr> Dated March 29.</p>
               <p>'I do hereby agree and</p>
               <p>'promise to pay to 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person26">
                  Samuel 
                  Scrimshaw 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person26" type="surname" value="Scrimshaw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person26" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person26" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , or order,</p>
               <p>'one half of the sum I do receive from Humphry</p>
               <p>'Morice, Esq; of Dover-street, Member</p>
               <p>'of Parliament: as witness my hand,</p>
               <p>'
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person27">
                  Peter 
                  Parry 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person27" type="surname" value="Parry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person27" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person27" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .'</p>
               <p>This note, gentlemen, was found in Scrimshaw's pocket at the very time he was taken.</p>
               <p>Parry having shewed Scrimshaw the last answer he got from Mr Morice, Scrimshaw 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person28">
                  drew
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person28" type="given" value="drew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person28" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             an answer to it, but Parry did not send it; and instead of it, he sent another, which he wrote from a draught of Richardson's. Here we bring them all clearly connected together, although Scrimshaw, it must be admitted, was not seen at any one time conferring with them upon this subject, and there was this very clear reason for it. It was necessary they should attend Parry separately, and at different times, in order that, by comparing notes one with another, they might try his fidelity. Rogues cannot always confide in one another. - This letter drawn by Richardson, and copied by Parry, was dated the 31st of March, and I will read it to you.</p>
               <p>'SIR,</p>
               <p>'I Did not know you was so far under the</p>
               <p>'cloud, not to know the full meaning of</p>
               <p>'my letters. And I hope you will now excuse</p>
               <p>'my drawing the whole curtain, but it may</p>
               <p>'fall into other hands before it reaches you: as</p>
               <p>'by what here follows you will be able to</p>
               <p>'unriddle the whole. I myself was present</p>
               <p>'at the whole, likewise two gentlemen of</p>
               <p>'my acquaintance was in the adjoining</p>
               <p>'room, and heard what passed. A certain</p>
               <p>'person was pleased to charge you with sod - I</p>
               <p>'practices, which I think all mankind ought</p>
               <p>'to hold the greatest detestation; and that you</p>
               <p>'now have a * youth training (not far from</p>
               <p> town for that purpose). Now, Sir, if you are</p>
               <p>'willing to comply with the proposal in my last,</p>
               <p>'it will bind an inviolable secrecy. If that is</p>
               <p>'not agreeable, shall be glad to know what</p>
               <p>'you are willing to do. Your answer by the</p>
               <p>'bearer, or to-morrow morning by nine</p>
               <p>'o'clock. And if your proposal be agreeable</p>
               <p>'to the confidence such a subject deserves, you</p>
               <p>'may depend upon the most profound secrecy,</p>
               <p>'and likewise an interview at the place mentioned,</p>
               <p>'as desired. I beg your answer immediately.</p>
               <p>' I am,</p>
               <p>'Sir,</p>
               <p>' Your humble servant, R. E.</p>
               <p>'P. S. As the bearer comes on purpose, I</p>
               <p>'hope you will pay him.</p>
               <p> A child of eight years old, belonging to one of Mr Morice's servants, and educated by that gentleman's charity at Hampstead.</p>
               <p>'Sir, it is a thousand pitties, a gentleman</p>
               <p>'of your fortune and character should have</p>
               <p>'your name drawn in question, upon such an</p>
               <p>'occasion.</p>
               <p>'To Humphry Morice, Esq;</p>
               <p>'Member of Parliament,</p>
               <p>'Dover-Street, Piccadilly.'</p>
               <p>To which letter Mr Morice caused the following answer to be wrote.</p>
               <p>'SIR,</p>
               <p>'IF you make any discovery answerable to</p>
               <p>'what you have promised, you may depend</p>
               <p>'upon a proper return being made from me.</p>
               <p>'But I must tell you, I have something else to</p>
               <p>'do, than to waste my time in writing letters</p>
               <p>'to no purpose, and must desire to be excused</p>
               <p>'receiving any more from you, unless you are</p>
               <p>'at the place appointed to-morrow, as it will</p>
               <p>'be the second time you will have kept me<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907170009"></xptr> ' waiting for you in vain. If you do not fail</p>
               <p>'meeting, you will much oblige</p>
               <p>Your humble servant.</p>
               <p>Mr Morice wanted an interview with these fellows; resolving never to be with them alone, which was a necessary caution; and the moment he saw them to fix them, and commence a prosecution.</p>
               <p>Mr Morice finding it was in vain to hope for any thing at all, 'till he could bring them to an interview, resolved to go; and took Gosling with him, and placed him in another room. Accordingly Ross, Richardson, and Parry, went as far as the Hoop-Tavern, and Parry went in: but instead of finding Mr Morice, he saw Gosling. Now, Mr Morice, not dreaming from what spring this conspiracy took it's rise, had unluckily taken Gosling there whom Parry knew. Parry seeing Gosling, ran away, and went to the Black Horse, within a door or two where his friends Ross and Richardson were waiting. Now I should have told you, that in their way to the Hoop-Tavern, a proposal was made by Ross and Richardson, and agreed to by Parry; that Parry was to demand 500 l. of Mr Morice: but by all means he was not to take less than 300 l. and Ross and Richardson, if necessary, were to say, that they were in the adjoining room, at the Fountain-Tavern on Ludgate-Hill, and had over-heard what passed there. Now here is another circumstance, which also proves, that Scrimshaw, Ross, and Richardson, conspired together. Scrimshaw also said to Parry, if I happen to be at any interview with Mr Morice, I'll say, that I was in the adjoining room, and over-heard what passed.</p>
               <p>Gentlemen, as to Comson, he being a man of the Law, he took a little more caution than the rest had done. He was only to have ten guineas. - He is not in the indictment. - I am sorry for it.</p>
               <p>Mr Morice not appearing at the Hoop-Tavern, but Gosling in his stead; they began now to think that all was not safe. However, there was a fifth letter drawn, and that by Richardson, at their office, and copied by Parry. It bears no date, and is as follows.</p>
               <p>'BEING honoured with several letters</p>
               <p>'from you, appointing you to meet me</p>
               <p>'at a certain place, in obedience thereto I attended;</p>
               <p>'but to my great surprise, I met only</p>
               <p>'with your servant, therefore did not think</p>
               <p>'it proper to divulge any thing to him, altho'</p>
               <p>'he pretended he had a commission to open</p>
               <p>'your letters, and privy to your secrets: but I</p>
               <p>'could not credit that story. I will attend you</p>
               <p>'in person at any time and place you shall</p>
               <p>'mention and appoint. The sooner the better</p>
               <p>'for reasons to myself. A gentleman of</p>
               <p>'your fortune and character, it is a pity</p>
               <p>'but that you should be thoroughly acquainted</p>
               <p>'with what I have to say; and upon your performing</p>
               <p>'what you have mentioned in one of</p>
               <p>'your letters, I will relate upon oath, what I</p>
               <p>'have to say; and you may depend upon an</p>
               <p>'inviolable secrecy.</p>
               <p>'From your humble servant.'</p>
               <p>In the postscript he says, if I have not an answer to this from yourself, I shall take an opportunity of leaving one for you at a certain place. - What place they meant is not known, but it must be some where, where Mr Morice would not like to have one sent.* </p>
               <p>* Parry declared, they meant at the Lobby of the House of Commons.</p>
               <p>Mr Morice, upon the receipt of this letter, ordered Gosling to answer it, and he accordingly sent him the following answer.</p>
               <p>'WIlliam Parry, I write to you by my</p>
               <p>'Master's order, to tell you, that it</p>
               <p>'is in vain for you to expect he will condescend,</p>
               <p>'either to see you, or write to</p>
               <p>'you: but as you persist in saying, you have</p>
               <p>'something of consequnce, to reveal to him, he</p>
               <p>'has bid me let you know he has spoke to Mr</p>
               <p>'Fielding, to give you the hearing, and you</p>
               <p>'may wait upon him, at his house in Bow-street,</p>
               <p>'as soon as you please; if it is any</p>
               <p>'thing necessary to be told to my Master, the</p>
               <p>'Justice will acquaint him with it.'</p>
               <p>At this time, Mr Morice, not knowing of any transactions in the City of London, intended to prosecute these conspirators in Middlesex; and for that purpose made application to<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907170010"></xptr> Justice Fielding, and informed him of all the letters he had received.</p>
               <p>Parry, on his receiving this letter from Gosling, sent the following letter, copied by himself, from a draught of Richardson's in Ross's presence.</p>
               <p>'MR Gosling, your's I received dated Saturday</p>
               <p>'(yesterday). Your writing to</p>
               <p>'me by your masters order's, perhaps it may</p>
               <p>'be so; but let me tell you, it is not often,</p>
               <p>'that servants take that liberty to open their</p>
               <p>'masters letters; but serving him in the capacity</p>
               <p>'you do, it is not to be wondered at, but</p>
               <p>'such liberty might be taken. However,</p>
               <p>'what Mrs Gosling told you at the Fountain,</p>
               <p>'plainly appears now to be a matter of fact:</p>
               <p>'Why did not you contradict her then, when</p>
               <p>'such a heinous crime was laid to your charge?</p>
               <p>'But what is mentioned here is not half what</p>
               <p>'I have to say; and if it be desired, will bring</p>
               <p>'proof of it; which will make some person be</p>
               <p>'looked upon what they are now represented.</p>
               <p>'As to my going to Mr Fielding, or any other</p>
               <p>'particular gentleman, I assure you I shall</p>
               <p>'not. What I have to say I shall communicate</p>
               <p>'it immediately to the publick; and I</p>
               <p>'shall be always ready to aver what I have</p>
               <p>'to say, by sufficient witnesses to any person</p>
               <p>'I should be called upon legally. Now Sir,</p>
               <p>'you are to do as you think fit, as I look upon</p>
               <p>'you and Mr - to be one. If</p>
               <p>'you be minded, I will meet you any evening</p>
               <p>'this week; if you will do what is handsome,</p>
               <p>'if not, you may depend upon seeing</p>
               <p>'it in the publick papers, with your name in</p>
               <p>'full length, and every word that passed particularly</p>
               <p>'mentioned. Your answer to this is</p>
               <p>'immediately desired.</p>
               <p>'Your's, &amp;c. 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person29">
                  Peter 
                  Parry 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person29" type="surname" value="Parry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person29" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person29" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .'</p>
               <p>This letter was directed to Mr John Gosling at the Swan on Hay-Hill, near Dover-Street, Piccadilly; and was also laid before justice Fielding, who issued his warrant against Parry. But before he was taken, the D - l, as if he had owed the conspirators an ill turn, provides farther evidence against them; for you see here another letter wrote by Parry to Gosling, from a draught prepared by Scrimshaw: and the language, references, and circumstances of this letter, are a further evidence of Scrimshaw's communication in this matter with Richardson and Ross.</p>
               <p>'Mr Gosling.</p>
               <p>'SIR,</p>
               <p>'NOT receiving any answer to the letter</p>
               <p>'that was left you at the Swan on Hay-Hill,</p>
               <p>'therefore unless you immediately answer</p>
               <p>'this, you will oblige me to send for answer</p>
               <p>'to Dover-street. If you have any regard</p>
               <p>'to your character, or Mr Williams's, I</p>
               <p>'would have you heal up the wounds, which</p>
               <p>'you may do now on reasonable terms, otherwise</p>
               <p>'you may depend it will be made known</p>
               <p>'to the publick, with your name in full length,</p>
               <p>'and the place of residence, and that of Mr</p>
               <p>'Williams likewise, with other circumstances</p>
               <p>'which you little think I know; and such as</p>
               <p>'ought not to be mentioned, not forgetting</p>
               <p>'the affair of Hampstead, which is shocking</p>
               <p>'to think at [what he means God almighty</p>
               <p>'knows]. As yet, Mr Gosling, it is a profound</p>
               <p>'secret, and shall remain so with me,</p>
               <p>'if you think proper; and am apt to think,</p>
               <p>'that it will be for your interest, as well as</p>
               <p>'Mr Williams's character, to have it kept so.</p>
               <p>'Was I to see you, I could tell you several instances</p>
               <p>'relative to this affair more than you</p>
               <p>'are aware of. If you will do any thing in</p>
               <p>'reason it will be complied with, and that immediately.</p>
               <p>'Pray, who can hurt me for putting</p>
               <p>'it in the papers, as I can bring proof of</p>
               <p>'it? what I shall mention I shall do upon</p>
               <p>'oath, if required. Why had you not come</p>
               <p>'alone to the Hoop-Tavern; had you done</p>
               <p>'so I should have explained myself then to</p>
               <p>'you. I am apt to think it will no way</p>
               <p>'agreeable to you, to see your name in the</p>
               <p>'public paper upon such a subject; but I</p>
               <p>'would not willingly blast a man's character.</p>
               <p>'I will give you any security, to any amount,</p>

               <p>'never to mention it, if you require it. An</p>
               <p>'answer to this I shall expect to-morrow by</p>
               <p>'noon. You cannot take it ill of me if you</p>
               <p>'are exposed, but blame yourself. If you have</p>
               <p>'a mind to meet me alone, I will meet you<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907170011"></xptr> ' whenever you please. I thought to have</p>
               <p>'come and send for you to the Swan, but I</p>
               <p>'was afraid you might not approve of it. I</p>
               <p>'should have sent you this sooner, but heard</p>
               <p>'you was not in town. Fail not to let me</p>
               <p>'have your answer.</p>
               <p>' I am,</p>
               <p>'Yours, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>'
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person30">
                  Peter 
                  Parry 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person30" type="surname" value="Parry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person30" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person30" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>'Sunday 6 o'clock.</p>
               <p>'Directed to Mr 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person31">
                  John 
                  Gosling 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person31" type="surname" value="Gosling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person31" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person31" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ,</p>
               <p>'to be left at the Swan, Hay-Hill,</p>
               <p>'Piccadilly.'</p>
               <p>This Sunday must be the 22d of April.</p>
               <p>I will not, Gentlemen, waste your time with observations upon this letter, they must occur to every man's understanding, and prove the connections that subsisted between Scrimshaw and his confederates.</p>
               <p>To this letter Gosling sent Parry the following answer.</p>
               <p>'Mr Parry,</p>
               <p>'I came to town on Sunday last, and on my</p>
               <p>'arrival I received a letter from you. I</p>
               <p>'am very sorry you should give yourself so</p>
               <p>'much trouble about me; but if you will</p>
               <p>'meet me on Wednesday evening, a little before</p>
               <p>'6 o'clock, at Mr Carty's, at the King's</p>
               <p>'Head, Drury-lane, where I will be at that</p>
               <p>'time. I hope I shall be able to give you an</p>
               <p>'answer to your satisfaction.</p>
               <p>'
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person32">
                  John 
                  Gosling 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person32" type="surname" value="Gosling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person32" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person32" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>'Monday Morning, Apr. 22.</p>
               <p>'Directed to Mr R. E. at the</p>
               <p>'Paul's-Head, Lawrence-Lane,</p>
               <p>'Cheapside.'</p>
               <p>Now the place appointed being in the neighbour-hood of Mr Fielding, Parry, for a very good reason, did not chuse to come there; but sent 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person33">
                  Gosling
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person33" type="given" value="Gosling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person33" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the following letter.</p>
               <p>'SIR,</p>
               <p>'YEsterday I received your's of Monday,</p>
               <p>'appointing an interview this evening at</p>
               <p>'Drury-lane. As you are pleased to say you</p>
               <p>'are sorry I give myself so much trouble about</p>
               <p>'you, I here declare, this is the last time you</p>
               <p>'shall hear from me in this manner; neither</p>
               <p>'shall I meet you in Drury-lane; if you chuse</p>
               <p>'to come to the Golden Key, Fleet-market,</p>
               <p>'near Holborn, between six and seven this</p>
               <p>'evening, I shall be there, ready to give you</p>
               <p>'all the satisfaction you can desire; if not,</p>
               <p>'you may expect to see yourself and Mr Williams,</p>
               <p>'&amp;c. very soon in the public papers.</p>
               <p>'Your's, &amp;c. 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person34">
                  Peter 
                  Parry 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person34" type="surname" value="Parry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person34" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person34" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Parry likewise wrote 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person35">
                  Gosling
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person35" type="given" value="Gosling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person35" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             another letter, copied from a draught prepared by Richardson, to the following effect:</p>
               <p>'Mr Gosling,</p>
               <p>'SIR,</p>
               <p>'I Have from time to time received various</p>
               <p>'letters, under the sanction of your master,</p>
               <p>'I therefore now insist to know, for what</p>
               <p>'purpose, or what meaning you can have, in</p>
               <p>'the word satisfaction. I am sorry you had</p>
               <p>'not my last letter in time, which was owing</p>
               <p>'to the neglect of the person in the house, being</p>
               <p>'left there by 12 o'clock. Now, to put</p>
               <p>'an end to this mysterious affair, I desire the</p>
               <p>'favour of a line to know, for what reason</p>
               <p>'you can have so often, in your letters, desired</p>
               <p>'an interview, and for what end and purpose;</p>
               <p>'and on the receipt of your's will be</p>
               <p>'punctual at 6 o'clock, to meet you at Mr</p>
               <p>'Overall's, at the Blossom's Inn, Lawrence-Lane,</p>
               <p>'where we may have a room to ourselves,</p>
               <p>'and finally put an end to this trouble.</p>
               <p>' I am,</p>
               <p>'Your humble servant,</p>
               <p>'
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person36">
                  Peter 
                  Parry 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person36" type="surname" value="Parry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person36" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person36" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .'</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907170012"></xptr>To this letter was added the following postscript.</p>
               <p>'N. B. As you propose satisfaction in several</p>
               <p>'of your letters, your compliance in that, I</p>
               <p>'will then justly inform you who are your accusers</p>
               <p>'of an infamous affair laid to your</p>
               <p>'charge, and the gentleman's - with a dash - under the name of Williams, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>'Your immediate answer will oblige,</p>
               <p>'Your humble servant,</p>
               <p>'As before - '</p>
               <p>This letter, Gentlemen, was prepared, as I told you, by Richardson, but who, do you think, prepared the draught of the postscript? it was Scrimshaw, and we have the original draught under his own hand to lay before you.</p>
               <p>Nothing material happened after this before they were taken up: when they were taken up, Scrimshaw being charged by Parry, who was first apprehended, with having entered into a conspiracy with Parry, Ross, and Richardson, in order to extort money from Mr Morice; and with writing and sending several of these letters to that gentleman; all this he confessed, but in excuse said, that he was not so guilty as Parry; and upon his being searched, there were found upon him several papers relative to this affair. - In the first place, there was Parry's note of hand to him, to give him half the money which he should procure from Mr Morice.</p>
               <p>In the second place, there was found upon him a letter, dated the 15th of Feb. from Richardson to him, wherein they talk of going sharers, and having some infamous transactions before them.</p>
               <p>There was also found, abundance of other papers of lesser consideration, shewing the intimacy and connections between him and his accomplices.</p>
               <p>In Parry's pocket was found the draught of a letter under Scrimshaw's own hand, which he intended Parry should have sent Mr Morice. In this letter he says:</p>
               <p>'SIR,</p>
               <p>'HAving received several letters from you,</p>
               <p>'desiring an interview, one on Saturday</p>
               <p>'last, I presume the purpose of meeting is on</p>
               <p>'a very particular subject, to which I was an</p>
               <p>'evidence. I by these inform you, I have no</p>
               <p>'objection, in order to inform you what I had</p>
               <p>'related in a very extraordinary affair that materially</p>
               <p>'concerns you; as by character you</p>
               <p>'are a gentleman of a very large fortune,</p>
               <p>'I make no doubt that you will have any objection,</p>
               <p>'according to your promises, in making</p>
               <p>'me a genteel compliment, adequate</p>
               <p>'to the confidence such a subject deserves;</p>
               <p>'and you may depend on the most profound</p>
               <p>'secrecy on oath, never to divulge what I</p>
               <p>'know - '</p>
               <p>This, you see, is but part of the draught. He also confessed, he was present at the writing several of these letters; and particularly confessed the writing the letters of the 3d and 28th of March, and that he was to have had part of the money obtained from Mr Morice.</p>
               <p>There was also found in Parry's pocket Scrimshaw's draught of the postscript to the last letter sent to Gosling.</p>
               <p>And there was found in Ross's pocket, a letter from Mr Whitmore, of South Audley-Street, to him, in these words:</p>
               <p>'SIR,</p>
               <p>'I Forgot to caution you, least you should</p>
               <p>'through any mistake put forth any Advertisement,</p>
               <p>'for I would not on any account</p>
               <p>'have any advertisement relating to my affairs,</p>
               <p>'on any account whatsoever. When you</p>
               <p>'speak to the person you mentioned, you may</p>
               <p>'satisfy him, that a troop of Dragoons would</p>
               <p>'be as agreeable as a company of Invalids.'</p>
               <p>' I am,</p>
               <p>'Sir,</p>
               <p>' Your humble servant,</p>
               <p>'
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person37">
                  Edward 
                  Whitmore 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person37" type="surname" value="Whitmore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person37" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person37" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ,'</p>
               <p>It appears that these Office-keepers had grossly imposed upon, and deceived this gentleman, by telling him that they had interest with a person that was able to procure him a company<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907170013"></xptr> of Invalids, and he in return informed them, that a troop of Dragoons would be equally agreeable.</p>
               <p>Ross was charged with his part in this wicked conspiracy, and he did not deny it; but his defence was, and which is very true, that he did not write any of the Letters.</p>
               <p>Now, Gentlemen, these are the several circumstances of this case, in which you will find Parry was so deeply engaged in it, that I should think it too much for these persons, or either of them, to be convicted of so foul a crime upon his single evidence, unsupported by other evidence and circumstances. Parry deserves punishment, but he however, (for I would speak out on this occasion) does entertain hopes of forgiveness, and is encouraged only to entertain those hopes by his telling the whole truth. I admit, Gentlemen, he comes under the disadvantage of an infamous accomplice, and his testimony deserves credit no farther than 'tis supported by other evidence; but when all the circumstances I have mentioned come to be laid before you by evidence, they will manifest the guilt of the prisoners to a demonstration.</p>
               <p>Gentlemen, If the persons concerned in this conspiracy had searched the whole bills of mortality, they could not have found a more unfit object for their wicked purpose than Mr Morice - but it has been often said, that men of the most virtue, and most tender of their reputation, are most likely to yield to such conspiracies. I know no other reason why Mr Morice should be fixed upon. I beg pardon for having taken up so much of your time, and shall only add, that Mr Morice thought it his duty to the public to bring this affair to a public trial; and that he is less concerned to convict the defendants, than he is desirous, if they are innocent, that they may be acquitted.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590717-1-person38">
                  Peter 
                  Parry 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person38" type="surname" value="Parry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person38" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person38" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I first became acquainted with the two prisoners at the bar a little before Christmas last; they kept an Intelligence Office in the Fleet-market, next door to the Golden Key: I went there and gave a shilling, as is usual, in order that they should procure me a place, either with a Hop-merchant, or in some warehouse. Mr Scrimshaw and Mr Richardson kept it at that time. I used to call two or three times a day, to inquire if they had heard of a place. In December last there was Mr Steydall, Mr and Mrs Gosling, and myself, at the 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person39">
                  Fountain 
                  Tavern 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person39" type="surname" value="Tavern"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person39" type="given" value="Fountain"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person39" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             on Ludgate-Hill.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the business of that meeting?</p>
               <p>Parry. Mrs Gosling went there in order to meet her husband; and she fell in a violent passion, threw the things about the room, and amongst other bad names called her husband a Buggerer. Mr Richardson sent for me about three or four days after to the Earl of Warwick's head in Fleet-Lane: my wife went along with me; there were Mr Scrimshaw, Richardson, and one Comson an Attorney, which I think lives in St James's Street. There was also present the landlord and another gentleman, a tall man.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the business for which you was sent for?</p>
               <p>Parry. I had been a good while out of business, and I had printed some counterpanes, and Mr Scrimshaw said he could dispose of them to a good advantage: I was to have met him that night at the Golden Key, that I went to the Fountain. Mr Scrimshaw asked me the reason I did not come that night, I said I was at the Fountain on Ludgate-Hill. He asked me, what brought me there? I said, I went there with a person that belonged to the same house, and Mrs Gosling; and that she called her husband a buggerer. As soon as I mentioned that, - Scrimshaw put his finger up to his nose.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you imagine he meant by that?</p>
               <p>Parry. What I imagined was, that I should say no more. He desired I would call the next day; I did, and found him at Mrs Greens, at the Golden Key: there was another person with him; named Prince. Scrimshaw did not think proper to say any thing then, but asked me to take a walk along with him: He said he was to meet some gentlemen at John's Coffee-house by Lincoln's-Inn-Fields. We could not find the gentleman he went after there; then he desired I would meet him the next day at Mr Lambert's, at the Horse-Shoe, Charing-Cross. I met him there accordingly; there was Mr Comson and Scrimshaw. From thence we went all three into the Park. Comson<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907170014"></xptr> there said, I wish you good luck, and then left us.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not you something surprized at his words, I wish you good luck ?</p>
               <p>Parry. I was surprized. After that, Scrimshaw talked to me about Mrs Gosling's charging her husband with being a buggerer at the Fountain-Tavern. I repeated it to him. He then asked me, whether I knew Mr Morice that was Gosling's master? I told him no. He said he was certain he was a man of fortune; and if the thing was well managed it might be a fortune to us both.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any talk between you and Scrimshaw, that Gosling lived with Mr Morice ?</p>
               <p>Parry. Yes, there was; he said, if he was to have the management of this affair, he should bring Mr Morice to his bearing, and we should always have him between finger and thumb. From thence we went to the Cockpit (an Ale-house ) and had no more discourse about this, as I can recollect, 'till we came there; there we call'd for a pint of purl; then Scrimshaw drew out his pen and ink, and asked me, if Mr Morice knew my hand-writing, I said no. He said he did not chuse he should know his 'till such time as he had founded him, to see how his pulse beat. He mended two pens, and then wrote a letter in order to send to Mr Morice.</p>
               <p>Q. Look upon this letter, (he takes one into his hand) is this it?</p>
               <p>Parry. This is the very letter, he wrote it with the back part of the pen.</p>
               <p>Q. After this letter was wrote, what became of it?</p>
               <p>Parry. Mr Scrimshaw sent it to Mr Morice by the Penny-Post.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see it put in.</p>
               <p>Parry. No; he said he'd send it. I left it in his custody.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr Morice. Look at this letter - (he takes it in his hand.)</p>
               <p>Mr Morice. I received this letter on the 28th of Feb. last, to the best of my remembrance, whether by the Penny-Post, or how, I do not know (turning it up); here is the Penny-Post mark upon it.</p>
               <p>The letter read.</p>
               <p>London, Feb. 27. 1759.</p>
               <p>'Honoured Sir,</p>
               <p>'I Hope you will excuse my taking this liberty</p>
               <p>'(more so as I am a stranger to you) but</p>
               <p>'I happen'd to be at a certain place not long</p>
               <p>'since, where your name was drawn in question,</p>
               <p>'upon a subject I am certain was you to</p>
               <p>'know it, you would by no means approve of</p>
               <p>'it ( more so, as the party receives so considerable</p>
               <p>'a bounty from your hand, and is</p>
               <p>'maintained by you). If you desire to know</p>
               <p>'the particulars, will make an affidavit of</p>
               <p>'what was mentioned, and will explain other</p>
               <p>'instances to you concerning what I have here</p>
               <p>'mentioned, and must beg my name to be kept</p>
               <p>'a secret. If you think it proper may send</p>
               <p>'me a line directed thus; To R. E. to be</p>
               <p>'left at the Paul's Head, Lawrence-Lane,</p>
               <p>'Cheapside. Or if it will be more agreeable,</p>
               <p>'be pleased to put it in the Daily Advertiser</p>
               <p>'on Saturday or Monday next, and you shall</p>
               <p>'hear farther from me, and all secrecy shall be</p>
               <p>'punctually observed.</p>
               <p>' I am, Sir,</p>
               <p>' Your most obedient,</p>
               <p>'humble servant to command,</p>
               <p>'R. E.'</p>
               <p>'To Humphry Morice, Esq;</p>
               <p>'Member of Parliament, at</p>
               <p>'his house Dover-Street,</p>
               <p>'Westminster.'</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr Morice. Did you write an answer to this letter?</p>
               <p>Mr Morice. I did, to let him know I should be ready to hear what he had to tell me, at the 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person40">
                  Hoop 
                  Tavern 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person40" type="surname" value="Tavern"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person40" type="given" value="Hoop"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person40" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Coventry-street, Piccadilly, on the next Saturday evening exactly at nine. It being a strange kind of a letter, I, then having two servants in my house, determined which ever of them came first into the room, should copy over this answer, and it happened to be Gosling. I did not chuse that they should<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907170015"></xptr> see my own hand writing. I sent it by a chairman to R. E. at the Paul's Head, Lawrence-lane. This is the draught I drew (producing it) for my servant to copy from.</p>
               <p>Counsel. It cannot be read in court but the next letter takes notice of it.</p>
               <p>Parry. Scrimshaw said, if any thing is obtained of Mr Morice we will give Comson five or ten guineas; this was at the Cockpit.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see Scrimshaw, or any of the parties after this?</p>
               <p>Parry. Scrimshaw desired I would bring the answer as soon as I received it. I had before asked Scrimshaw where the letter must be directed, that came in answer; he said, not at his office; but wherever I had my letters directed to me out of the country. Then I fixed the Paul's-Head Lawrence-lane. I went to the Paul's-Head in a day or two and found a letter directed to R. E. I took and opened it and read it, and brought it to Mr Scrimshaw. He was at Mr Lambert's. I gave him the letter before I came away. It was not read there.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you recollect the contents of it?</p>
               <p>Parry. I could, if I was to hear it read again. I know the substance of it was to meet at the Hoop-Tavern, on a Sunday, I believe the next Sunday. There was no more said about it that night, but Mr Scrimshaw desired I would meet him the next night at Mr Caywood's, a Publick-House near Charing-Cross. I did not know that Comson was to be there. There was Scrimshaw and he, Comson drew up a letter that was to be sent to Mr Morice.</p>
               <p>Q. The answer that you had received, and carried to Scrimshaw, what was done with it?</p>
               <p>Parry. That was at this time lying on the table by us. Scrimshaw did not approve of part of Comson's letter; so he drew out one himself.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that sent as he wrote?</p>
               <p>Parry. It was copied over.</p>
               <p>Q. Who copied it?</p>
               <p>Parry. He himself did, and it was sent as he wrote it. Comson told Scrimshaw he ought to be careful for fear his hand-writing should be discovered.</p>

               <p>Q. How do you know that letter was sent?</p>
               <p>Parry. Scrimshaw told me he had sent it afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this letter - He takes one in his hand.</p>
               <p>Parry. This is the letter; this was wrote at Caywood's by Scrimshaw.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him write it?</p>
               <p>Parry. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr Morice. Do you know any thing of this letter?</p>
               <p>Mr Morice. This letter I received to the best of my knowledge on a Saturday, as I was at dinner, the day I wrote mine; therefore, I did not imagine it came by the penny-post, but by a messenger.</p>
               <p>The letter read.</p>
               <p>Directed to Humphry Morice, Esq; Member of Parliament, Dover-street, Westminster.</p>
               <p>March 3, 1759. 12 o'clock.</p>
               <p>'Honoured Sir,</p>
               <p>'YOur's I received, and if it be agreeable</p>
               <p>'to you, would rather meet you either</p>
               <p>'Monday or Tuesday night, at the place and</p>
               <p>'time, you mentioned; if not, will to-morrow</p>
               <p>'night, as desired and shall observe the</p>
               <p>'direction. Therefore I presume to beg the</p>
               <p>'favour of your interest, to intercede for me</p>
               <p>'with some gentleman, to procure me a place</p>
               <p>'in the Custom-House, Victualling-Office, or</p>
               <p>'in any other station under the Government,</p>
               <p>'in any part of England. As I am sensible it</p>
               <p>'is in your power to grant me a favour of this</p>
               <p>'kind, as vacancies of this nature, daily happens.</p>
               <p>'- Sir, in my asking you this favour, I</p>
               <p>'hope you will not take me (or look upon me)</p>
               <p>'to be one of those that would offer to impose</p>
               <p>'upon any gentleman. As Sir John</p>
               <p>'Glynne, Member for Flint, and 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person41">
                  Samuel 
                  Egerton 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person41" type="surname" value="Egerton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person41" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person41" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ,</p>
               <p>'Esq; Member for Cheshire, and</p>
               <p>'others, knows me extremely well, and would</p>
               <p>'do any thing to serve me: but, in asking of</p>
               <p>'this nature, it is not in their power to serve</p>
               <p>'a friend; if it is, they do not chuse to make</p>
               <p>'use of their interest, if they have any. As I</p>
               <p>'have met with great losses, and have been</p>
               <p>'out of employment about this two years, and</p>
               <p>'having a wife and child to maintain, has reduced</p>
               <p>'my circumstances very much, which is<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907170016"></xptr> ' the sole reason of my petitioning you to be</p>
               <p>'my friend. As it will be doing me a great</p>
               <p>'piece of service, and yourself no diskindness,</p>
               <p>'which shall be for ever acknowledged; your</p>
               <p>'compliance to the above, will be much better</p>
               <p>'bestowed, than on them whom now receive</p>
               <p>'your bounty; and, you may depend, I will</p>
               <p>'disclose the whole, and nothing but the truth,</p>
               <p>'as I shall make an affidavit of the same. Be</p>
               <p>'pleased to send me an answer to the above,</p>
               <p>'directed as before; and let it be there by</p>
               <p>'eight in the morning, if not to-night. Your</p>
               <p>'compliance to the within-mentioned, and you</p>
               <p>'may command</p>
               <p>'Your most obedient servant, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>'P. S. If possible, let me have your answer</p>
               <p>'to-night. I should be greatly oblig'd</p>
               <p>'to you to inclose, in the answer, a couple</p>
               <p>'of Franks.'</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr Morice. Did you answer this letter?</p>
               <p>Mr Morice. I had an answer wrote to it by the same hand; to the best of my knowledge, to let him know, if I did not meet him that Sunday night, as I was going out of town the beginning of the week, I could not meet him for some time, to hear what he had to say.</p>
               <p>Q. to Parry. What directions did you receive, as to the answer to the second letter?</p>
               <p>Parry. I received orders from Mr Scrimshaw, to go to the Paul's-head, for the answer. I went, as soon as I thought an answer could come there, either that day, or the next; there I found a letter. I took it, and carried it to the Mitre, near the Parliament-house; and delivered it to Mr Scrimshaw there.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you recollect what was the purport of that answer?</p>
               <p>Parry. I believe he mention'd, if he did not meet that evening, it would be a good while before he could.</p>
               <p>Q. What did Scrimshaw say to you?</p>
               <p>Parry. I could not find Scrimshaw that night, or there would have been a meeting that Sunday night; but I found him the next day, being Monday.</p>
               <p>Q. What was done then ?</p>
               <p>Parry. He said, he was sorry he had it not before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he prepare any farther letter?</p>
               <p>Parry. There was a letter wrote then, but that I believe was not sent: it was about this time that Richardson and Ross became acquainted with the affair.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the first time you had any conversation with either of them about it?</p>
               <p>Parry. Mr Richardson came to the house where I lodged, at Mr Jones's an Apothecary, in Fleet-lane: he ask'd me if that grand affair, that Mr Scrimshaw had taken in hand, was near compleated?</p>
               <p>Q. What answer did you make to that?</p>
               <p>Parry. I told him I did not know of any grand affair, at all: I saw him the next day at his office; then Ross was there with him: at that time Ross was become a partner with Scrimshaw and Richardson; then they asked me the same question.</p>
               <p>Q. Which ask'd that question?</p>
               <p>Parry. They both did; Richardson ask'd me, and Ross was present. Then I did imagine Scrimshaw had told them: I made no answer, but Mr Richardson said, I need not make it so strange, for they knew of that grand affair, as well as I did; and if they did not partake, they must puff. I told them, I suppos'd they had it from Mr Scrimshaw: we went from thence to the Golden-Key.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell them what Scrimshaw had been doing?</p>
               <p>Parry. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What was done at the Golden-Key?</p>
               <p>Parry. Richardson and Ross said, it might be a very good thing, if it was well looked after. Then it was agreed upon to write a letter to Mr Morice; this was at the office: then we went all three of us to the Golden-Key, and I copied a letter that Richardson had prepared; and it was sent to Mr Morice.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this letter. He takes one in his hand.</p>
               <p>Parry. This is my hand-writing: this is the letter I copied, from one drawn up by Richardson.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was it sent by?</p>
               <p>Parry. I believe it was sent by an acquaintance of Mr Ross's.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907170017"></xptr>Q. to Mr Morice. Do you know any thing of this letter?</p>
               <p>Mr Morice. I receiv'd this letter the latter end of March. It is signed R. E.</p>
               <p>The letter read.</p>
               <p>Directed to Humphry Morice, Esq; in Dover-street, Westminster.</p>
               <p>March 28. 1759.</p>
               <p>'SIR,</p>
               <p>'MY reason for not complying with your</p>
               <p>'repeated desires, of having an interview</p>
               <p>'with me at the Hoop-Tavern, in Coventry-street;</p>
               <p>'as I did not receive your letter 'till the</p>
               <p>'Monday, otherwise would have waited on you.</p>
               <p>'There was two other gentlemen of my acquaintance,</p>
               <p>'in the adjoining room, whom</p>
               <p>'will come upon oath, of what passed, as well</p>
               <p>'as myself; you may depend on the greatest</p>
               <p>'honour and secrecy. I have a relation that</p>
               <p>'has been twenty-three years in the Train of</p>
               <p>'Artillery, in the East-Indies, as Lieutenant,</p>
               <p>'lately come home; and is now Captain-Lieutenant</p>
               <p>'in the same: a gentleman of family</p>
               <p>'and fortune, who is desirous of being</p>
               <p>'promoted to the rank of Captain, in an old</p>
               <p>'company of Invalids, in Britain, or the adjacent</p>
               <p>'isles; or the Captain of an old regiment</p>
               <p>'of Foot, at home, or abroad. If this</p>
               <p>'is not agreeable to you, would be glad to</p>
               <p>'know what favours you would bestow; as the</p>
               <p>'point, now in question, takes your honour in</p>
               <p>'the most tender part. I hope, for your own</p>
               <p>'peace, you will not fail in giving me a speedy</p>
               <p>'answer, directed as before.</p>
               <p>' I am,</p>
               <p>'Sir,</p>
               <p>' your most obedient servant,</p>
               <p>'to command, R. E.'</p>
               <p>'P. S. The above-mentioned gentleman has</p>
               <p>'been twenty-three years in the King's</p>
               <p>'service, been Captain-Lieutenant upwards</p>
               <p>'of two years, but left his promotion by being</p>
               <p>'so far a distance from his friends: his</p>
               <p>'father is now in a great character abroad,</p>
               <p>'and cannot make interest enough without</p>
               <p>'a gentleman of your rank. Let me have</p>
               <p>'your answer by to-morrow, ten o'clock.</p>
               <p>R. E.'</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr Morice. Did you write an answer to this letter?</p>
               <p>Mr Morice. To the best of my remembrance I did; to this purport.</p>
               <p>I did not know what they had to discover to me; so knew not how to promise any thing, 'till I had had a meeting: which I order'd on Monday, April 2. at the Hoop-Tavern.</p>
               <p>Q. to Parry. Was you order'd to fetch Mr Morice's answer to this letter?</p>
               <p>Parry. I was, and went for it: but cannot tell how long it was after this was sent.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find an answer?</p>
               <p>Parry. I did, at the Paul's-head. I open'd, and read it, and show'd it to Ross and Richardson, and they read it in their office.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do with it afterwards?</p>
               <p>Parry. I believe I kept that myself.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell what became of it?</p>
               <p>Parry. I cannot.</p>
               <p>Q. Look upon this letter? - (He takes it in his hand.)</p>
               <p>Parry. This is the answer that was sent, and I received.</p>
               <p>Counsel. The cover in which it was sent, is lost.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr Morice. Look at this letter.</p>
               <p>Mr Morice. This is the answer that I order'd my man to copy out, from what I had before wrote.</p>
               <p>Q. to Parry. Do you recollect any conversation with these people, about Mr Morice, at this time?</p>
               <p>Parry. Yes, I saw Mr Ross; he told me he had been inquiring after Mr Morice's character, with an acquaintance of his; who had a place somewhere.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>Parry. This was at his own door, where he lodged; at the bottom of Long-Acre.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907170018"></xptr>Q. How long after you received this answer was it?</p>
               <p>Parry. It was very soon after this answer came. It was about the time that the next letter was wrote to Mr Morice.</p>
               <p>Q. And what did Ross say he had heard of Mr Morice?</p>
               <p>Parry. He said, he was a gentleman of great interest, that he belonged to the Board of Green-Cloth; and that, he lately had paid smart-money to the amount of fifteen or sixteen hundred pounds, on a like occasion.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you ever had any discourse with any of the others, about Mr Morice?</p>
               <p>Parry. Yes: I believe it was the next day, with Scrimshaw.</p>
               <p>Q. Where?</p>
               <p>Parry. I believe it was at Mr Lambert's, at Charing-Cross. He told me just the very words.</p>
               <p>Q. Repeat what Scrimshaw said -</p>
               <p>Parry. Scrimshaw said, an acquaintance of his had told him, that Mr Morice was a gentleman of fortune, and of great interest, and that he had lately paid smart-money, to a considerable sum, on the like occasion.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you recollect your giving Scrimshaw any note of hand, on any account.</p>
               <p>Parry. Yes, there was a note given at the Cockpit about this; and about this time there was another letter wrote by Mr Scrimshaw.</p>
               <p>Q. Who drew up the note?</p>
               <p>Parry. He did.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell the substance of that note drawn at the Cockpit?</p>
               <p>Parry. No.</p>
               <p>Q. After this, what was the next step taken ?</p>
               <p>Parry. There was a letter wrote at the King's Arms in Holywell-street in the Strand.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was by at the time?</p>
               <p>Parry. There was nobody there, but Scrimshaw and myself.</p>
               <p>Q. Who wrote it?</p>
               <p>Parry. Scrimshaw did, but that letter was not sent.</p>
               <p>Q. Look on this letter and tell us who wrote it ?</p>
               <p>Parry. This is Scrimshaw's hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Counsel. We shall prove by and by this letter to have been found in Parry's pocket when taken,</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be acquainted with his hand-writing?</p>
               <p>Parry. I saw him write it.</p>
               <p>Mr Steydall. I heard Mr Scrimshaw examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Look on this letter - (be takes it in his hand).</p>
               <p>Mr Steydall. This was taken upon Parry, and Mr Scrimshaw acknowledged in my hearing, that it was his own hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>Mr Steydall. This was before Mr Fielding; and when Parry was in the Round-House Covent-Garden, he tore off the date of the letter.</p>
               <p>It is read:</p>
               <p>'SIR,</p>
               <p>'HAVING received several letters from</p>
               <p>'you, desiring an interview, one on Saturday</p>
               <p>'last. I presume the purpose of meeting</p>
               <p>'is on a very particular subject, to which</p>
               <p>'I was an evidence; and by these inform you,</p>
               <p>'I have no objection in order to inform you</p>
               <p>'what I had related in a very extraordinary</p>
               <p>'affair, that materially concerns you, as by</p>
               <p>'character you are a gentleman of a very</p>
               <p>'large fortune. I make no doubt that you</p>
               <p>'will have any objection according to your</p>
               <p>'promise, in making me a genteel complement,</p>
               <p>'adequate to the confidence such a subject</p>
               <p>'deserves; and you may depend on the</p>
               <p>'most profound secrecy on oath never to divulge</p>
               <p>'what I know.' The rest torn off.</p>
               <p>Q. to Parry. What was the contents of that note, which Scrimshaw drew in Holywell-street?</p>
               <p>Parry. He drew, and I signed it, he was to take half of what ever was obtained from Mr Morice.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this note, is this that which he drew up at that time?</p>
               <p>Parry. He takes it in his hand. This is it.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907170019"></xptr>Q. to Mr Steydall. Do you know any thing of this note?</p>
               <p>Steydall. This note was found upon Scrimshaw, and he acknowledged before Mr Fielding in my hearing, that it was his own handwriting.</p>
               <p>It is read.</p>
               <p>'Memorandum,</p>
               <p>'I do hereby agree and promise to pay to</p>
               <p>'
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person42">
                  Samuel 
                  Scrimshaw 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person42" type="surname" value="Scrimshaw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person42" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person42" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , or order, one half of the</p>
               <p>'sum I do receive from Humphry Morice, Esq;</p>
               <p>'of Dover-street, Member of Parliament: as</p>
               <p>'witness my hand, signed this day March 29.</p>
               <p>'1759.'</p>
               <p>'
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person43">
                  Peter 
                  Parry 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person43" type="surname" value="Parry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person43" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person43" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .'</p>
               <p>Q. to Parry. Was any thing more done?</p>
               <p>Parry. Nothing more at that meeting: there was another letter wrote by Mr Richardson, at their office.</p>
               <p>Q. How soon after?</p>
               <p>Parry. I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was present?</p>
               <p>Parry. Only Ross and Richardson, and myself. Richardson prepared the draught, and I copied it.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this letter, - (He takes it in his hand).</p>
               <p>Parry. This is it: it is my hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr Morice. Did you receive this letter?</p>
               <p>Mr Morice. I received this letter about the time it bears date: about the beginning of April.</p>
               <p>The draught found upon Parry, first read.</p>
               <p>'I Did not know you was so far under a</p>
               <p>'cloud, not to know the full meaning of</p>
               <p>'my letter, and hope you will now excuse my</p>
               <p>'undrawing the whole curtain, as I am not</p>
               <p>'certain, but it may fall into other hands before</p>
               <p>'it reaches your's, but by what here follows,</p>
               <p>'yo u will be able to unriddle the whole.</p>
               <p>'I and two gentleman of my acquaintance,</p>
               <p>'happened to be at a Tavern on Ludgate-Hill,</p>
               <p>'a little while ago: where, in the next room,</p>
               <p>'we heard a great dispute between a certain</p>
               <p>'person and his wife: the wife not only charged</p>
               <p>'the husband with sodomitical practices,' (the last three words scratched out)' with not only</p>
               <p>'one of your domesticks; but likewise an</p>
               <p>'infant at H - d, with sod - I practices:</p>
               <p>'which we, and I think all mankind</p>
               <p>'ought to hold in the greatest detestation.</p>
               <p>'I went out of the room we was in, with a</p>
               <p>'feint of making water. The room door they</p>
               <p>'was in being open, the gentleman, who I</p>
               <p>'then found to be one of your domesticks, called</p>
               <p>'me in: the wife still exclaiming against</p>
               <p>'him and you. I heard and saw the whole.</p>
               <p>'Mr J - G - promised, if I would keep</p>
               <p>'secrecy, any thing in your power would be</p>
               <p>'granted. A few hours after I had a letter</p>
               <p>'from you,' (scratched out)' signed Williams,</p>
               <p>'wherein you mention you would give a bond</p>
               <p>'if I would keep secrecy. I for my part</p>
               <p>'would comply, thinking you mean an hundred</p>
               <p>'guineas. I shewed your letter to the</p>
               <p>'other two, who says, if you comply with the</p>
               <p>'proposals mentioned in the last letter from</p>
               <p>'me, they will do the same. They are ready</p>
               <p>'to give you an interview with me, when and</p>
               <p>'where you please, and you may depend on</p>
               <p>'the veracity of what they promise, as well as</p>
               <p>'you.</p>
               <p>'Now, Sir, if you are willing to comply</p>
               <p>'with the proposal in my last, it will bind us</p>
               <p>'to secrecy. If that is not agreeable, shall be</p>
               <p>'glad to know what you are willing to do.'</p>
               <p>Q. to Parry. Could this be a letter copied from this draught?</p>
               <p>Parry. This was drawn by Richardson for me to copy from.</p>
               <p>Q. This differs very greatly from that letter, how came that?</p>
               <p>Parry. That I can't tell, I wrote it in their presence.</p>
               <p>The letter read.</p>
               <p>March 31, 1759.</p>
               <p>'SIR,</p>
               <p>'I Did not know you was so far under the</p>
               <p>'cloud, not to know the full meaning of<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907170020"></xptr> ' my letters. And I hope you will now</p>
               <p>'excuse my drawing the whole curtain, as</p>
               <p>'I am not certain but it may fall into</p>
               <p>'other hands before it reaches you: as</p>
               <p>'by what here follows you will be able to</p>
               <p>'unriddle the whole. I myself was present</p>
               <p>'at the whole, likewise two gentlemen of</p>
               <p>'my acquaintance was in the adjoining</p>
               <p>'room, and heard what passed. A certain</p>
               <p>'person was pleased to charge you with sod - I</p>
               <p>'practices, which I think all mankind ought</p>
               <p>'to hold the greatest detestation; and that you</p>
               <p>'now have a  youth training (not far from</p>
               <p>'town for that purpose). Now, Sir, if you are</p>
               <p>'willing to comply with the proposal in my last,</p>
               <p>'it will bind an inviolable secrecy. If that is</p>
               <p>'not agreeable, shall be glad to know what</p>
               <p>'you are willing to do. Your answer by the</p>
               <p>'bearer, or to-morrow morning by nine</p>
               <p>'o'clock. And if your proposal be agreeable</p>
               <p>'to the confidence such a subject deserves, you</p>

               <p>'may depend upon the most profound secrecy,</p>
               <p>'and likewise an interview at the place mentioned,</p>
               <p>'as desired. I beg your answer immediately.</p>
               <p>'I am,</p>
               <p>'Sir,</p>
               <p>'Your humble servant, R. E.</p>
               <p>'P. S. As the bearer comes on purpose, I</p>
               <p>'hope you will pay him.</p>
               <p>* A child of eight years old, belonging to one of Mr Morice's servants, and educated by that gentleman's charity at Hampstead.</p>
               <p>'Sir, it is a thousand pities, a gentleman</p>
               <p>'of your fortune and character should have</p>
               <p>'your name drawn in question, upon such an</p>
               <p>'occasion.</p>
               <p>'To Humphry Morice, Esq;</p>
               <p>'Member of Parliament,</p>
               <p>'Dover-Street, Piccadilly.'</p>
               <p>Q. to Parry. Did you agree that this letter should be sent to Mr Morice?</p>
               <p>Parry. I did: and it was sent by an acquaintance of Mr Ross's.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr Morice. Did you send an answer to this letter?</p>
               <p>Mr Morice. I did; they had excited my curiosity by the first letter, where they take notice, that other people had said something to my disadvantage. I wrote for answer,</p>
               <p>'That</p>
               <p>'they might depend upon a proper return if</p>
               <p>'they made a discovery answerable to their</p>
               <p>'promise; but I had something else to do than</p>
               <p>'to waste time in writing letters to no purpose,</p>
               <p>'and appointed them to meet me on the morrow</p>
               <p>'at the Hoop-Tavern.'</p>
               <p>Q. to Parry. Can you recollect what answer you received to this letter?</p>
               <p>Parry. I really cannot recollect what was the answer; but I received one, and show'd it to Richardson, Ross, and Scrimshaw.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you deliver it to either of them?</p>
               <p>Parry. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. to Parry. Was you ever to meet Mr Morice at the Hoop-Tavern, in Coventry-Street, and to ask for Mr Williams?</p>
               <p>Parry. No.</p>
               <p>Mr Morice. As I did not think proper to go myself, I was afraid to mention the man's real name, Gosling; so I was obliged to give him some other name, and in that case he was to take upon himself the name of Williams, (for I was not to appear, but he was to appear) and he was the most improper man in the world to send there, (though I did not know it at that time) because they knew him.</p>
               <p>Q. to Parry. Did you receive an answer to this letter?</p>
               <p>Parry. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do with it?</p>
               <p>Parry. I show'd it to Richardson and Ross.</p>
               <p>Q. What was their advice, as to meeting at the Hoop-Tavern ?</p>
               <p>Parry. They said, by all means go and meet Mr Morice.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907170021"></xptr>Q. Did you go to the Hoop-Tavern ?</p>
               <p>Parry. I did; and Richardson and Ross went along with me. Going along I said, suppose Mr Morice should not comply in regard to the Captain's commission, what must I do? Then they said, I must ask him what he would give.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were you when you had this discourse?</p>
               <p>Parry. This was as we were going along Lincoln's-Inn-Fields. I was also to say, that the two persons that were in the adjoining room were then present, and ready to enter into any agreement, to do what he should think proper, if he would do any thing handsome; they bid me insist upon 500 l. provided he did not comply with the Captain's commission, which we designed for Mr Whitmore; and I was not to take under 300 l. and if the gentleman had not so much money I was to insist upon his note.</p>
               <p>Q. Which of them said this to you?</p>
               <p>Parry. Both of them did; Ross first, and Richardson afterwards. I could not find Scrimshaw that morning to go with us. We went to the sign of the Black Horse, which is about a door or two from the Hoop-Tavern; they stay'd there, and I went on to the Hoop-Tavern.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was you to inquire for?</p>
               <p>Parry. I was to inquire for Mr Williams.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you see there?</p>
               <p>Parry. I ask'd for Mr Williams; they sent me up stairs, and there I found Mr Gosling.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you stay there?</p>
               <p>Parry. I did not stay there above two minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you go then?</p>
               <p>Parry. I went to the Black Horse again, being apprehensive of being discovered. Mr Gosling came down stairs after me, and would sain have had me gone up, that he might speak with me, but I refused it, and went away. Mr Gosling came after me to the Black Horse, and Mr Ross and he had some words before he came there. They insisted upon my going back again, but I would not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any thing done at the Black Horse?</p>
               <p>Parry. No, nothing at all, but we all went about our business.</p>
               <p>Q. What were Ross and Richardson to have done in it?</p>
               <p>Parry. They were to have said, they were in the adjoining room, and over-heard the discourse at the Fountain-Tavern between Gosling and his wife.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear Scrimshaw say any thing relating to that?</p>
               <p>Parry. Yes, Scrimshaw was to have said the same, provided he had been present at any interview with Mr Morice. They all three agreed to say this, provided they had seen Mr Morice.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was Scrimshaw when he agreed to say this?</p>
               <p>Parry. It was at Hibbard's (I believe) at Charing-Cross.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the next letter sent?</p>
               <p>Parry. The next letter, I believe, was wrote at the Golden Key by Fleet-ditch.</p>
               <p>Q. Who were present at the time?</p>
               <p>Parry. There was Richardson, Ross, and myself.</p>
               <p>Q. Who prepared it?</p>
               <p>Parry. Richardson did; and it was sent; and there was an answer brought to it.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this letter - (he takes it in his hand.)</p>
               <p>Parry. This is the letter.</p>
               <p>Q. Who wrote it?</p>
               <p>Parry. I did, from Richardson's copy.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr Morice. Did you receive this letter? ( he takes it in his hand.)</p>
               <p>Mr. Morice. I received it on the 4th of April, the day after I had been with Mr Fielding, who was of opinion, that I should never hear any more from them.</p>
               <p>It is read.</p>
               <p>Directed to Humphry Morice, Esq; at his house, Dover-Street, Piccadilly.</p>
               <p>'SIR,</p>
               <p>'BEING honoured with several letters</p>
               <p>'from you, appointing you to meet me</p>
               <p>'at a certain place, in obedience thereto I attended;</p>
               <p>'but to my great surprise, I met only</p>
               <p>'with your servant, therefore did not think</p>
               <p>'it proper to divulge any thing to him, altho'</p>
               <p>'he pretended he had a commission to open</p>
               <p>'your letters, and privy to your secrets: but I</p>
               <p>'could not credit that story. I will attend you<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907170022"></xptr> 'in person at any time and place you shall</p>
               <p>'mention and appoint. The sooner the better</p>
               <p>'for reasons to myself. A gentleman of</p>
               <p>'your fortune and character, it is a pity</p>
               <p>'but that you should be thoroughly acquainted</p>
               <p>'with what I have to say; and upon your performing</p>
               <p>'what you have mentioned in one of</p>
               <p>'your letters, I will relate upon oath, what I</p>
               <p>'have to say; and you may depend upon an</p>
               <p>'inviolable secrecy.</p>
               <p>'From your humble servant.'</p>
               <p>Mr Morice. I sent this to Mr Fielding, and he advised me to write no answer to it; then I directed Gosling to answer it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590717-1-person44">
                  John 
                  Gosling 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person44" type="surname" value="Gosling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person44" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person44" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This letter (taking it in his hand ) I wrote an answer to.</p>
               <p>Q. to Parry. Do you recollect who the answer to this letter came from?</p>
               <p>Parry. It came from Mr Gosling, directed to me by name.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the purport of it?</p>
               <p>Parry. It was, that I should go and acquaint Mr Fielding with whatever I had to say, if I knew any thing necessary to be told.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do with that letter you received from Gosling?</p>
               <p>Parry. I told the contents of it to Ross, Richardson, and Scrimshaw, and brought it to them all three in a day or two after.</p>
               <p>Q. What did they say to it, when you shewed it to them?</p>
               <p>Parry. Richardson and Ross were at the Golden Key, when I shewed it to them; and two days after I shewed it to Scrimshaw. They were for my writing an answer to it.</p>
               <p>Q. How soon after was it, that you met to write the next letter?</p>
               <p>Parry. That I cannot directly tell. I Know we did write an answer: part of it was wrote at their office, which I copied out.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this letter. (He takes it in his hand.)</p>
               <p>Parry. This is it, dated Wednesday, 11th of April, 1759. I wrote it from a draught of Richardson's in Ross's presence.</p>
               <p>Q. to Gosling. Did you receive this letter?</p>
               <p>Gosling. I did.</p>
               <p>It is directed to 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person45">
                  John 
                  Gosling 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person45" type="surname" value="Gosling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person45" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person45" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , to be left at the Swan, near Hay-Hill.</p>
               <p>It is read.</p>
               <p>'MR Gosling, your's I received dated Saturday</p>
               <p>'(yesterday). Your writing to</p>
               <p>'me by your master's orders, perhaps it may</p>
               <p>'be so; but let me tell you, it is not often,</p>
               <p>'that servants take that liberty to open their</p>
               <p>'masters letters; but serving him in the capacity</p>
               <p>'you do, it is not to be wondered at, but</p>
               <p>'such liberty might be taken. However,</p>
               <p>'what Mrs Gosling told you at the Fountain,</p>
               <p>'plainly appears now to be a matter of fact:</p>
               <p>'Why did not you contradict her then, when</p>
               <p>'such a heinous crime was laid to your charge?</p>
               <p>'But what is mentioned here is not half what</p>
               <p>'I have to say; and if it be desired, will bring</p>
               <p>'proof of it; which will make some persons be</p>
               <p>'looked upon what they are now represented.</p>
               <p>'As to my going to Mr Fielding, or any other</p>
               <p>'particular gentleman, I assure you I shall</p>
               <p>'not. What I have to say I shall communicate</p>
               <p>'it immediately to the publick; and I</p>
               <p>'shall be always ready to aver what I have</p>
               <p>'to say, by sufficient witnesses, to any person</p>
               <p>'I should be called upon legally. Now Sir,</p>
               <p>'you are to do as you think fit, as I look upon</p>
               <p>'you and Mr - to be one. If</p>
               <p>'you be minded, I will meet you any evening</p>
               <p>'this week; if you will do what is handsome,</p>
               <p>'if not, you may depend upon seeing</p>
               <p>'it in the publick papers, with your name in</p>
               <p>'full length, and every word that passed particularly</p>
               <p>'mentioned. Your answer to this is</p>
               <p>'immediately desired.</p>
               <p>'Your's, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>'
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person46">
                  Peter 
                  Parry 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person46" type="surname" value="Parry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person46" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person46" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .'</p>
               <p>'P. S. If you think by my plain way of dressing</p>
               <p>'I am a person of no consequence, I refer</p>
               <p>'you to 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person47">
                  Nicholas 
                  Kent 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person47" type="surname" value="Kent"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person47" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person47" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; of Clifford's-Inn,</p>
               <p>'and 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person48">
                  Francis 
                  Wardel 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person48" type="surname" value="Wardel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person48" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person48" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; Castle-Yard,</p>
               <p>'to whom I pay an annual rent of 123 l. per<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907170023"></xptr> ' annum, besides a sufficiency of my own,</p>
               <p>'therefore if you do not salve up the matter,</p>
               <p>'blame yourself for the consequence.</p>
               <p>'
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person49">
                  Peter 
                  Parry 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person49" type="surname" value="Parry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person49" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person49" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .'</p>
               <p>Q. Do you pay that rent annually?</p>
               <p>Parry. I did, for the tithes of the parish of Burton, within a mile and a half of Park-Gate. I did live there; but lost it by misfortunes. I had the term of 16 years to come in it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Scrimshaw see this letter before you sent it?</p>
               <p>Parry. He did, and approved of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Who wrote that direction on this letter?</p>
               <p>Parry. It is Richardson's own hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you recollect, whether you received any answer to it?</p>
               <p>Parry. I do not recollect that I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this letter. (Another letter produced, he takes it in his hand.)</p>
               <p>Parry. I believe this letter was wrote at Mr Hibbard's.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was present?</p>
               <p>Parry. I believe Scrimshaw was.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does Mr Hibbard live?</p>
               <p>Parry. At Charing-Cross. Scrimshaw wrote it first, and I copied it afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Who wrote the direction?</p>
               <p>Parry. The direction is of Mr Scrimshaw's own hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Q. to Gosling. Did you receive this letter? (He takes it in his hand.)</p>
               <p>Gosling. I did. It is directed to Mr 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person50">
                  John 
                  Gosling 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person50" type="surname" value="Gosling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person50" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person50" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at the Swan, Hay-Hill, Piccadilly.</p>
               <p>It is read.</p>
               <p>'Mr Gosling,</p>
               <p>'NOT receiving any answer to the letter</p>
               <p>'that was left you at the Swan on Hay-Hill,</p>
               <p>'therefore unless you immediately answer</p>
               <p>'this, you will oblige me to send for answer</p>
               <p>'to Dover-street. If you have any regard</p>
               <p>'to your character, or Mr Williams's, I</p>
               <p>'would have you heal up the wounds, which</p>
               <p>'you may do now on reasonable terms, otherwise</p>
               <p>'you may depend it will be made known</p>
               <p>'to the publick, with your name in full length,</p>
               <p>'and the place of residence, and that of Mr</p>
               <p>'Williams likewise, with other circumstances</p>
               <p>'which you little think I know; and such as</p>
               <p>'ought not to be mentioned, not forgetting</p>
               <p>'the affair of Hampstead, which is shocking</p>
               <p>'to think at. As yet, Mr Gosling, it is a profound</p>
               <p>'secret, and shall remain so with me,</p>
               <p>'if you think proper; and am apt to think,</p>
               <p>'that it will be for your interest, as well as</p>
               <p>'Mr Williams's character, to have it kept so.</p>
               <p>'Was I to see you, I could tell you several instances</p>
               <p>'relative to this affair more than you</p>
               <p>'are aware of. If you will do any thing in</p>
               <p>'reason it will be complied with, and that immediately.</p>
               <p>'Pray, who can hurt me for putting</p>
               <p>'it in the papers, as I can bring proof of</p>
               <p>'it? what I shall mention I shall do upon</p>
               <p>'oath, if required. Why had you not come</p>
               <p>'alone to the Hoop-Tavern; had you done</p>
               <p>'so I should have explained myself then to</p>
               <p>'you. I am apt to think it will be no way</p>
               <p>'agreeable to you, to see your name in the</p>
               <p>'public paper upon such a subject; but I</p>
               <p>'would not willingly blast a man's character.</p>
               <p>'I will give you any security, to any amount,</p>
               <p>'never to mention it, if you require it. An</p>
               <p>'answer to this I shall expect to-morrow by</p>
               <p>'noon. You cannot take it ill of me if you</p>
               <p>'are exposed, but blame yourself. If you have</p>
               <p>'a mind to meet me alone, I will meet you</p>
               <p>'whenever you please. I thought to have</p>
               <p>'come and send for you to the Swan, but I</p>
               <p>'was afraid you might not approve of it. I</p>
               <p>'should have sent you this sooner, but heard</p>
               <p>'you was not in town. Fail not to let me</p>
               <p>'have your answer.</p>
               <p>' I am,</p>
               <p>'Yours, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>'
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person51">
                  Peter 
                  Parry 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person51" type="surname" value="Parry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person51" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person51" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>'Sunday 6 o'clock.</p>
               <p>'Directed to Mr 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person52">
                  John 
                  Gosling 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person52" type="surname" value="Gosling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person52" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person52" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ,</p>
               <p>'to be left at the Swan, Hay-Hill,</p>
               <p>'Piccadilly.'</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907170024"></xptr>Counsel. Gosling having sent his letter to Parry in a cover, they turned that cover inside out, and they inclosed in it this letter to Gosling, and Scrimsh aw wrote the direction on this cover, which so far fixes Scrimshaw.</p>
               <p>Q. to Gosling. Did you write an answer to this letter?</p>
               <p>Gosling. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this paper. (He takes another letter in his hand.)</p>
               <p>Gosling. This is my hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Q. to Parry. Look at this letter. (He takes it in his hand.)</p>
               <p>Parry. This is the answer I received from Gosling to the last letter.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you communicate the substance of it to either of the prisoners?</p>
               <p>Parry. I did, first to Ross and Richardson, at their office, and afterwards to Scrimshaw. I do not know whether I show'd it to Scrimshaw at Hibbard's, or at the Mitre.</p>
               <p>It is read.</p>
               <p>'Mr Parry,</p>
               <p>'I Came to town on Saturday last, and on my</p>
               <p>'arrival I received a letter from you. I</p>
               <p>'am very sorry you should give yourself so</p>
               <p>'much trouble about me; but if you will</p>
               <p>'meet me on Wednesday evening, a little before</p>
               <p>'6 o'clock, at Mr Carty's, at the King's</p>
               <p>'Head, Drury-lane, where I will be at that</p>
               <p>'time. I hope I shall be able to give you an</p>
               <p>'answer to your satisfaction.</p>
               <p>'
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person53">
                  John 
                  Gosling 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person53" type="surname" value="Gosling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person53" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person53" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>'Monday Morning, Apr. 23.</p>
               <p>'To Mr R. E. at the Paul's-Head,</p>
               <p>'Lawrence-Lane,</p>
               <p>'Cheapside.'</p>
               <p>Q. to Parry. Did you meet Gosling at the King's Head in Drury-Lane, according to this letter?</p>
               <p>Parry. No. I did not go.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this letter. ( Another letter put into his hand.)</p>
               <p>Parry. This letter I wrote either at the Office, or at the Golden Key, from a draught prepared by Richardson, in Ross and Richardson's presence. It is dated 25th of April, 1759.</p>
               <p>It is read.</p>
               <p>Directed to Mr 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person54">
                  John 
                  Gosling 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person54" type="surname" value="Gosling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person54" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person54" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , or Mr Williams, to be left at the King's Head, Drury-Lane.</p>
               <p>'SIR,</p>
               <p>'YEsterday I received your's of Monday,</p>
               <p>'appointing an interview this evening at</p>
               <p>'Drury-lane. As you are pleased to say you</p>
               <p>'are sorry I give myself so much trouble about</p>
               <p>'you, I here declare, this is the last time you</p>
               <p>'shall hear from me in this manner; neither</p>
               <p>'shall I meet you in Drury-lane; if you chuse</p>
               <p>'to come to the Golden Key, Fleet-market,</p>
               <p>'near Holborn, between six and seven this</p>
               <p>'evening, I shall be there, ready to give you</p>
               <p>'all the satisfaction you can desire; if not,</p>
               <p>'you may expect to see yourself and Mr Williams,</p>
               <p>'&amp;c. very soon in the public papers.</p>
               <p>'Your's, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>'
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person55">
                  Peter 
                  Parry 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person55" type="surname" value="Parry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person55" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person55" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .'</p>
               <p>Q. to Parry. Look at this letter. (Another letter put into his hand.)</p>
               <p>Parry. This I wrote at the Rummer: Ross and Richardson were present.</p>
               <p>Q. Who prepared the draught?</p>
               <p>Parry. Richardson did, and I copied it over, and showed it to Scrimshaw, and he approved of it.</p>
               <p>Q. There is a postscript to it; who wrote that?</p>
               <p>Parry. Scrimshaw wrote that N. B. and I copied it and sent it away.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did Scrimshaw draw that draught?</p>
               <p>Parry. At the Rummer, Charing-Cross.</p>
               <p>Q. to Gosling. Did you receive this letter? (He takes it in his hand.)</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907170025"></xptr>Gosling. I did; but I can't recollect the time.</p>
               <p>It is read.</p>
               <p>Directed to 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person56">
                  John 
                  Gosling 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person56" type="surname" value="Gosling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person56" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person56" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at Humphry Morice's, Esq; Dover-Street, Piccadilly, Saturday morning, 8 o'clock.</p>
               <p>'SIR,</p>
               <p>'I Have from time to time received various</p>
               <p>'letters, under the sanction of your master,</p>
               <p>'I therefore now insist to know, for what</p>

               <p>'purpose, or what meaning you can have, in</p>
               <p>'the word satisfaction. I am sorry you had</p>
               <p>'not my last letter in time, which was owing</p>
               <p>'to the neglect of the person in the house, being</p>
               <p>'left there by 12 o'clock. Now, to put</p>
               <p>'an end to this mysterious affair, I desire the</p>
               <p>'favour of a line to know, for what reason</p>
               <p>'you can have so often, in your letters, desired</p>
               <p>'an interview, and for what end and purpose;</p>
               <p>'and on the receipt of your's will be</p>
               <p>'punctual at 6 o'clock, to meet you at Mr</p>
               <p>'Overall's, at the Blossom's-Inn, Lawrence-Lane,</p>
               <p>'where we may have a room to ourselves,</p>
               <p>'and finally put an end to this trouble.</p>
               <p>' I am,</p>
               <p>'Your humble servant,</p>
               <p>'
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person57">
                  Peter 
                  Parry 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person57" type="surname" value="Parry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person57" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person57" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .'</p>
               <p>'N. B. As you propose satisfaction in several</p>
               <p>'of your letters, your compliance in that, I</p>
               <p>'will then justly inform you who are your accusers</p>
               <p>'of an infamous affair laid to your</p>
               <p>'charge, and the gentleman - under the</p>
               <p>'name of Williams, &amp;c. Your immediate answer</p>
               <p>'will oblige,</p>
               <p>'Your humble servant,</p>
               <p>'As before - '</p>
               <p>Mr Steydall. The draught of this postscript, or N. B. was found in the pocket of Scrimshaw when taken.</p>
               <p>It is read in court, the same as that in the letter.</p>
               <p>Q. to Gosling. Look at this letter. ( Another letter put into his hand. )</p>
               <p>Gosling. This is an answer that I sent to Parry, appointing him to meet me at the Golden Key in the Fleet-Market: It is dated April 30.</p>
               <p>Q. to Parry. Look at this letter; do you know it?</p>
               <p>Parry. This I received, and show'd it to Ross and Richardson at the Golden Key, but I could not find Scrimshaw. Mr Ross had left word at the Golden Key, that if any body came there to inquire for me to show them up stairs, and send for me; I was in their Office at the Fleet-Market. Gosling came to the Golden Key, I went to him, and Ross was immediately to follow me.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the consequence of your going there?</p>
               <p>Parry. There was an officer there ready, and I was taken up, and carried before a magistrate, and there I confessed the whole.</p>
               <p>Q. from Scrimshaw. He asserts I met him at the Golden Key, I would ask him, whether, ever since he has had any connection in this case, did ever he see me at the Golden Key?</p>
               <p>Parry. I have seen him there, but not on this occasion.</p>
               <p>Q. from Scrimshaw. He has said, I wrote a letter with the back of a pen; I beg to see that letter.</p>
               <p>Parry takes that letter in his hand. This I saw Scrimshaw write with the back part of the pen at the Cockpit.</p>
               <p>Scrimshaw. (Takes it in his hand,) I never penn'd one letter of this.</p>
               <p>Mr Recorder. Take care how you give Parry credit, for he is so bad a man, that we cannot believe him, unless he is supported by farther evidence; perhaps you do not know, that by these questions you give him credit.</p>
               <p>Q. from Scrimshaw. There is another letter that he says I wrote, which is not my handwriting (it is put into his hand). This he says<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907170026"></xptr> I wrote at Caywood's; it is not my hand-writing; I never saw it before.</p>
               <p>Q. from Scrimshaw. Parry says he met me at the King's Arms in Holywell-Street; I beg to know, whether he ever saw me there in his life?</p>
               <p>Parry. I am positive I saw him there. He wrote a letter there which was not sent; and it was there that the promissory note was drawn.</p>
               <p>Q. from Scrimshaw. He says, this affair first began at the Golden Key in the Fleet-Market, or at our Office; I ask him, whether he ever heard mentioned, or the least syllable relating to it, 'till he met me at Caywood's in the beginning of March, and desired me to go with him into the Park.</p>
               <p>Mr Recorder. You shall have an answer to that question if you chuse it, but it is a very dangerous one.</p>
               <p>Parry. The first time that this was mentioned was at the Earl of Warwick's Head, at the corner of the Fleet-Market; when he put his finger to his mouth, and desired I would say no more 'till next morning. The second letter was wrote at Caywood's.</p>
               <p>Q. from Scrimshaw. There is a fourth letter he mentions; I would beg leave to see it, for I know it is not my hand-writing; and likewise a fifth.</p>
               <p>Mr Recorder. He did not say they were wrote by you. Mr Ford shall show you what is charged to have been wrote by you.</p>
               <p>Mr Ford. First, here is the body of the note of hand (putting it into his hand.)</p>
               <p>Scrimshaw. I did not write this.</p>
               <p>Parry. I saw you write it.</p>
               <p>Mr Ford. Here is a N. B. said to be wrote by you, putting it into Scrimshaw's hand.</p>
               <p>Scrimshaw. This was taken from Parry's own pocket. But he did not deny his writing it.</p>
               <p>Mr Ford. Here is the second letter to Gosling, the direction said to be wrote by you, putting it into Scrimshaw's hand.</p>
               <p>Scrimshaw. This is not my hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Mr. Ford. Here is the seventh letter, said to he copied from a draught of Scrimshaw's. Putting the draught into his hand.</p>
               <p>Parry. This was wrote by Scrimshaw at Hibbard's.</p>
               <p>Mr Ford. Here is another, said to be your hand-writing, found in your own pocket. (He takes it into his hand.)</p>
               <p>Scrimshaw made no answer to this.</p>
               <p>Q. from Ross. Whether Parry did not declare to me in New-Prison, that he was offered bribes to come to terms, in swearing on this indictment against Scrimshaw and me.</p>
               <p>Parry. I never was offered a farthing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever, in any prison, say to any body, that you had been offered any bribe or reward, to give evidence on this affair?</p>
               <p>Parry. No never. The prisoners have asked me, if I was not bribed; I told them no: no body ever gave me a farthing.</p>
               <p>Q. from Ross. Whether he is not to have some reward, or see, or gratuity, for giving his evidence?</p>
               <p>Parry. No. I never was to have any.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you expect any?</p>
               <p>Parry. No; I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. Has any been promised you?</p>
               <p>Parry. No.</p>
               <p>Q. from Ross. Whether you did not declare to me in New-Prison, that it is not in their power to hurt you, saying, I have thrown them on their backs; for what has been acted by Steydall and 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person58">
                  John 
                  Gosling 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person58" type="surname" value="Gosling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person58" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I am capable of throwing their indictment all aside?</p>
               <p>Parry. I never mentioned those words in my life, nor heard them mentioned.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you expect, in consequence of impeaching these people, that you yourself shall not be prosecuted?</p>
               <p>Parry. I cannot tell whether I shall be prosecuted or not, I hope not.</p>
               <p>Mr Morice. I never saw Parry in my whole life 'till this morning; then he went down on his knees, and begged for mercy of me.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you had any promises made you from Mr Morice, or any person on his account, that you shall have any reward, or any thing else, in consequence of your telling the truth, concerning these people?</p>
               <p>Parry. No, never in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever make any declarations to<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907170027"></xptr> Ross, of your having it in your power to defeat this prosecution ?</p>
               <p>Parry. No, never in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. from Ross. Whether he did not desire that one Mr Jones and his wife, should be called as evidences, relative to this affair, when tried?</p>
               <p>Parry. I said, perhaps it may be proper to have Mr Jones and his wife called.</p>
               <p>Q. from Ross. Whether you did not say, without the wife of 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person59">
                  John 
                  Gosling 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person59" type="surname" value="Gosling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person59" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             there could be no trial?</p>
               <p>Parry. No, I never said so. I heard Scrimshaw say so.</p>
               <p>Q. from Ross. Did not you communicate this to me?</p>
               <p>Parry. No, never in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. from Ross. Did not you tell me that when you was examined before Mr Fielding, you did not swear that 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person60">
                  Samuel 
                  Scrimshaw 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person60" type="surname" value="Scrimshaw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person60" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person60" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person61">
                  John 
                  Ross 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person61" type="surname" value="Ross"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person61" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person61" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person62">
                  John 
                  Richardson 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person62" type="surname" value="Richardson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person62" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person62" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , did frequently meet about this affair?</p>
               <p>Parry. In the examination that Justice Fielding's clerk drew out, it was put in that 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person63">
                  Samuel 
                  Scrimshaw 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person63" type="surname" value="Scrimshaw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person63" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person63" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person64">
                  John 
                  Ross 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person64" type="surname" value="Ross"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person64" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person64" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person65">
                  John 
                  Richardson 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person65" type="surname" value="Richardson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person65" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person65" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , did meet all together; but I told Mr Fielding that was not right, for they all three never were together at one time, about this affair with me.</p>
               <p>Ross. We are able to prove we have not seen one another for three months; but I see the evidence Parry, is fully determined to swear, be the consequence what it will, so I will say no more.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590717-1-person66">
                  George 
                  Steydall 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person66" type="surname" value="Steydall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person66" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person66" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the meeting at the Fountain-Tavern on Ludgate-Hill. I went there along with 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person67">
                  John 
                  Gosling 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person67" type="surname" value="Gosling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person67" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person67" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . There was some misunderstanding between Gosling and his wife: they had parted in Ireland; and when Mr Morice came to town, Gosling came to me and begged I would go with him to meet his wife at the Fountain: there she was in a violent passion, and amongst other names, did call her husband Buggerer.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Mr Morice's name mentioned there at that time?</p>
               <p>Steydall. No: his name was not so much as mentioned.</p>
               <p>Q. What were the words the woman made use of?</p>
               <p>Steydall. She said to her husband, You are a Buggerer: that was all that was remarkable there.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you there all the time?</p>
               <p>Steydall. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at Justice Fielding's when the prisoners and Parry were there?</p>
               <p>Steydall. I was: there were some letters produced.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this letter - (the first letter read). He takes it in his hand.</p>
               <p>Steydall. This was delivered to me by Mr Morice, and it was shewed to Scrimshaw, and he acknowledged it to be his own hand writing.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he then under examination?</p>
               <p>Steydall. He was.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether in order to obtain such a confession, any undue measure was taken?</p>
               <p>Steydall. No, none at all: he acknowledged it very frankly and freely.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this letter - (the second letter put into his hand).</p>
               <p>Steydall. This was shewn him: this he acknowledged to be his own hand-writing in the same free manner as before. I had him searched, and I gave the papers found upon him to the officer. This promissory note, taking it in his hand, was found in Scrimshaw's pocket-book, and he freely owned he wrote the body of it. (He took another paper in his hand). This was found in Parry's pocket, it is the N. B. I shewed to Scrimshaw, and he acknowledged it to be his hand-writing. There was also a piece of a letter found upon Parry; I shewed it to Scrimshaw; and he acknowledged it to be his hand-writing. There was found upon Ross, a letter sent by Mr Whitmore to them about a commission. Taking it in his hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Scrimshaw own or deny a conspiracy ?</p>
               <p>Steydall. He partly owned it.</p>
               <p>Q. Explain that.</p>
               <p>Steydall. He was charged with it and did not deny it; and acknowledged he wrote two o the letters.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he charged with conspiring?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907170028"></xptr>Steydall. He was, and he made no defence.</p>
               <p>Ross. Parry said to me that Mr Steydall and and Gosling, came frequently to New-Prison to him, to tell him he was not to be hurt, and desired him not only once, but frequently to say, that 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person68">
                  Samuel 
                  Scrimshaw 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person68" type="surname" value="Scrimshaw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person68" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person68" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was concerned in a conspiracy with 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person69">
                  John 
                  Richardson 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person69" type="surname" value="Richardson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person69" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person69" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and me. The question is whether Mr Steydall was not privy to telling Parry, that he was to have a handsome reward for his trouble?</p>
               <p>Steydall. There never was any promise made to Parry that I know of.</p>
               <p>Q. from Ross. When 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person70">
                  Peter 
                  Parry 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person70" type="surname" value="Parry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person70" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person70" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was brought before the Grand-Jury, whether Mr Steydall did not desire Parry to insist upon one particular letter, that it should not be read before the Grand-Jury?</p>
               <p>Steydall. I never heard of any such thing 'till this moment: I read every letter to the Grand-Jury myself, and did not suppress one syllable.</p>
               <p>Q. from Ross. Whether Mr Steydall did not desire Parry, not to insist upon bringing the wife of 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person71">
                  John 
                  Gosling 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person71" type="surname" value="Gosling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person71" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person71" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and Mr Jones and his wife to the trial?</p>
               <p>Steydall. This is the first time of my hearing thing of this.</p>
               <p>Ross. I do not think it necessary to ask Mr Steydall any more questions. I believe he is an honest man: but Parry the evidence is a very bad man. The Reverend Mr Mason is a principal evidence for me, but he is not here.</p>
               <p>Q. from Ross to Gosling. Whom did you see at the Hoop-Tavern ?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590717-1-person72">
                  John 
                  Gosling 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person72" type="surname" value="Gosling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person72" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person72" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the Hoop-Tavern. Parry came to me, but did not stay any time. I followed him to the Black-Horse, at the corner of the street, two or three doors from the Hoop-Tavern. There I found Mr Ross and another man, which they say was Richardson.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590717-1-person73">
                  Edward 
                  Parker 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person73" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person73" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person73" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Guy of Warwick, at the corner of Fleet-lane. I have seen Parry about three times: once or twice along with Scrimshaw: one time I particularly remember.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any body else in company?</p>
               <p>Parker. There was Ross with them, and another little man.</p>
               <p>Q. How many times may you have seen them together?</p>
               <p>Parker. I have seen them twice together; that is, Parry, and Scrimshaw, and Ross. Scrimshaw and Ross kept an Office of Intelligence; I did not know who were the partners: Richardson was a little man, he might be one of the partners; he was backwards and forwards there: I can't say, that I ever saw them all together.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Comson, an Attorney ?</p>
               <p>Parker. I do; I saw him with Scrimshaw.</p>
               <p>Q. How many times may you have seen Scrimshaw at your house ?</p>
               <p>Parker. About a dozen times.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does Comson live ?</p>
               <p>Parker. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Mrs Green. I keep the Golden-Key at the corner of the Fleet-Market: my house is next door to Mr Richardson's office. I do not know whether Scrimshaw belonged to it or not: he used to be in it sometimes. They frequently used my house. I have seen Scrimshaw and Ross there, and Parry with them, I believe half a dozen times.</p>
               <p>Scrimshaw's Defence.</p>
               <p>I beg leave to observe to this Honourable Court, that I neither know Mr Morice, nor Mr Gosling, and that I never saw either of them, 'till I saw Mr Gosling with Justice Fielding. I will defy any man in the world, to say he ever heard me speak a word to the disreputation of Esquire Morice. Parry did mention to me an affair he had with a gentleman, and said, he had received several letters, and that he desired him to meet him at the Hoop-Tavern in Coventry-street. I had a good deal of conversation with him about it. I told him he should be cautious how he meddled with gentlemens characters. He told me he had something to say to the gentleman: and that he had sent to him to come to him, that he might divulge what he had heard. I never spoke a disrespectful word of Esquire Morice. I have heard he is a very worthy gentleman, and I am sorry he should think, that I have been any way instrumental<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907170029"></xptr> in attempting to hurt or touch his character any way whatever. I am very cautious in touching any man's character, much more a gentleman's character. After I had the misfortune to be acquainted with this Parry, I heard something laid to his charge by Parry that was bad. I had not seen Parry a considerable time. I wrote him a letter, that I believed him to be a very bad man, as I apprehended he had wronged a very worthy gentleman's character, and told him I hoped he would be careful.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Look upon this letter - (This was found in Parry's pocket-book, when taken.)</p>
               <p>Scrimshaw. This is the letter: I desire it may be read.</p>
               <p>It is read.</p>
               <p>Directed to 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person74">
                  Peter 
                  Parry 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person74" type="surname" value="Parry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person74" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person74" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , to be left at the Paul's-Head, Lawrence-Lane.</p>
               <p>'Mr Parry,</p>
               <p>'I Received a billet from you with initial letters,</p>
               <p>'which I believe ment Mr Gosling:</p>
               <p>'I accordingly appointed the house, the corner</p>
               <p>'of Buckingham-Court: you never came, nor</p>
               <p>'have I heard of you since; which gives me</p>
               <p>'some reasons to believe your tale on that reproachul</p>
               <p>'affair, was calculated to answer to</p>
               <p>'some private end of your own; and strongly</p>
               <p>'corroborates with several circumstances, I</p>
               <p>'have lately been informed of, relative to yourself</p>
               <p>'self. If so, think how greatly you have abused</p>
               <p>'the character of the gentleman of fortune,</p>
               <p>'and of which scandalous reports I should think</p>
               <p>'it justice to inform him, if not, should be glad</p>
               <p>'to be convinced to the contrary, and other</p>
               <p>'affairs, that are greatly to your prejudice, and</p>
               <p>'desire you to consider when I lent you that</p>
               <p>'money out of my pocket, I greatly wanted it</p>
               <p>'myself.</p>
               <p>' I am,</p>
               <p>'Your's,</p>
               <p>'
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person75">
                  Samuel 
                  Scrimshaw 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person75" type="surname" value="Scrimshaw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person75" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person75" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>'Please to be on Saturday morning at ten</p>
               <p>'o'clock, at the house in Buckingham-Street.</p>
               <p>'Thursday the 26th, 1759.'</p>
               <p>Mr Ford. I have looked into the almanack, and find there was no other Thursday which happened on the 26th, but that in April.</p>
               <p>Scrimshaw. One thing I have to observe, I never was with Parry in the city of London from the first time he mentioned any thing relating to the prosecutor; nor I never saw him in the city since, which he very well knows. I bid him be careful how he meddled with a gentleman's character, and told him I thought the gentleman should rather punish him, than give him any reward.</p>
               <p>Ross's defence.</p>

               <p>I have nothing to give the Court any trouble about. My Lord, You have heard in all the the letters produced that have been read, that I never wrote, sealed, nor delivered (and if Parry had told the truth) never indited one syllable, as God is my judge, he is the only judge that knows the wickedness of the evidence. I never saw 
               <persName id="t17590717-1-person76">
                  Peter 
                  Parry 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person76" type="surname" value="Parry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person76" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person76" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             write one scribe with a pen. I never had one of the letters that came from the honourable gentleman whom I never saw in all my life. I hope the court will consider, I am a poor unfortunate man, and grant me mercy. I have a wife and two small children, and quite innocent. We have circumstances every day of the badness of Parry; and had we had the liberty to have put off our trial, I believe we could have proved him perjur'd. That I am pretty certain of.</p>
               <p>Scrimshaw. I believe Parry is the whole and sole inventer of this wicked affair; and he is purjured as there is a living God in Heaven.</p>
               <p>Q. to Steydall. Did Ross confess any thing before the justice.</p>
               <p>Steydall. He confessed before the justice, that he was privy to the 3 d and 4th letters dictated by Richardson in his presence.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907170030"></xptr>Q. from Ross. Whether I said I ever had one of them in my hand?</p>
               <p>Steydall. That I cannot say.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe him to look at either of the letters at the time he owned he was privy to them.</p>
               <p>Steydall. As the letters were read in their order; these two letters Parry pointed out, and said, Ross had a hand in them, to which Ross owned he was privy.</p>
               <p>Ross. They might be read to me, but if I was to be put to death I cannot recollect one syllable of one letter. I beg leave to ask the honourable court (as I am a stranger to the courts in England) whether it is a common rule, to inquire into the characters of evidences or not.</p>
               <p>Mr Recorder. It is very common; and I shall tell the jury, they are not to believe the evidence which Parry has given upon his own credit.</p>
               <p>Q. from Ross. Whether men that are in a public way of business are not often to be seen in different companies, and cannot say, whether they are honest or dishonest? We pay 16 l per year, and keey an open office. I have one circumstance with regard to the letters, said to be copied from Richardson's draughts in my presence. I do not know, that for a week together, I was two hours in a day in my office, I kept at the Coffee-House, the place of meeting gentlemen on my business; I do not know that ever I saw a letter that either Parry or Richardson had wrote: I have seen them at the desk a-writing when I have came in. If I knew my self guilty I should not have spoke one syllable. I never confessed any one circumstance, only one letter.</p>
               <p>To Scrimshaw's character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590717-1-person77">
                  William 
                  Dodd 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person77" type="surname" value="Dodd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person77" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person77" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Scrimshaw 18 years.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Dodd. I am a Periwig-maker.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Dodd. I never heard any thing bad of him in my life. He was a Periwig-maker; I have speak with him; I always believed him to be a honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590717-1-person78">
                  William 
                  Bathoe 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person78" type="surname" value="Bathoe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person78" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person78" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him 17 or 18 years. I am a Periwig-maker; I have the honour to work for his Royal Highness the Prince of Wales.</p>
               <p>Q. What is Scrimshaw's character?</p>
               <p>Bathoe. I never knew any harm of him in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590717-1-person79">
                  William 
                  Grinley 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person79" type="surname" value="Grinley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person79" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person79" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Linnen-draper, and live at Charing-Cross, I have known Scrimshaw about 14 years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character?</p>
               <p>Grinley. I never knew any thing ill of his character in my life. He kept a Periwig-maker's shop pretty near where I live. He had misfortunes came upon him, but I never heard any ill of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590717-1-person80">
                  Thomas 
                  Hearne 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person80" type="surname" value="Hearne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person80" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person80" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about 10 Years.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Hearne. I am a Hair-seller. He is an honest man, for what I know.</p>
               <p>To Ross's character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590717-1-person81">
                  Thomas 
                  Hunter 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person81" type="surname" value="Hunter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person81" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person81" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Stay-maker. I have known Ross upwards of nine years, he always was a very honest man. I never knew any ill of him to this present moment.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590717-1-person82">
                  John 
                  Read 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person82" type="surname" value="Read"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person82" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person82" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him five years. His character was always good since I knew him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590717-1-person83">
                  Joseph 
                  Brigs 
               <interp inst="t17590717-1-person83" type="surname" value="Brigs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person83" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-person83" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was bred to the Law originally, but have been 18 years in trade.</p>
               <p>Q. What trade?</p>
               <p>Brigs. A Stationer in Lincoln's-Inn. I have known Ross since November last; and have had some conversation with him, and found him to be a very honest good man.</p>
               <p>Ross. It was in the month of October last that I came to London.</p>
               <p>The Jury went out, and returned in about seven minutes, and brought in their verdict, both <rs id="t17590717-1-verdict4" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-verdict4" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>They received sentence, To be <rs id="t17590717-1-punish5" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-punish5" type="punishmentCategory" value="imprison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-punish5" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="newgate"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590717-1-defend19 t17590717-1-punish5"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590717-1-defend21 t17590717-1-punish5"></join>
               imprisoned in his Majesty's gaol of Newgate for the term of three years
            </rs>; and to <rs id="t17590717-1-punish6" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-punish6" type="punishmentCategory" value="corporal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590717-1-punish6" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="pillory"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590717-1-defend19 t17590717-1-punish6"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590717-1-defend21 t17590717-1-punish6"></join>
               stand in the Pillory twice, once at the upper end of Cheapside; and once by Fleetditch
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
