<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17551204-45">
               <interp inst="t17551204-45" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551204-45" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551204-45" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17551204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551204-45" type="date" value="17551204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17551204-45-off238-c429" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-45-defend504 t17551204-45-off238 t17551204-45-verdict241"></join>
         
               <p>53. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17551204-45-defend504" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Wilson 
                  <interp inst="t17551204-45-defend504" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-45-defend504" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-45-defend504" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17551204-45-off238" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17551204-45-off238" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-45-off238" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               that he in the dwelling house of 
                     <persName id="t17551204-45-person505">
                        Alexander 
                        Macdaniel 
                     <interp inst="t17551204-45-person505" type="surname" value="Macdaniel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17551204-45-person505" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17551204-45-person505" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17551204-45-victim507" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Innis 
                        <interp inst="t17551204-45-victim507" type="surname" value="Innis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17551204-45-victim507" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17551204-45-victim507" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-45-off238 t17551204-45-victim507"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and stealing from his person 10 shillings in money numbered, his property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17551204-45-cd239" type="crimeDate">Nov. 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-45-off238 t17551204-45-cd239"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-45-person508">
                  William 
                  Innis 
               <interp inst="t17551204-45-person508" type="surname" value="Innis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-45-person508" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-45-person508" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was taken up by my master, who is a chaser, upon suspicion of robbing him of some prints, and carried before justice Fielding, who committed me. There was at the same time one Wigmore, a stranger to me, who was committed also. We were handcuffed together. Going along Longacre, in our way to the Gatehouse, a parcel of people came behind us: one struck me cross the shoulder, another cross the loins, which brought me to the ground. I did not know the meaning of it; but soon found they wanted to rescue Wigmore. As we were fastened together they took us away through several turnings, till they brought us into the Long Fields. The prisoner was one of the rescuers. The prisoner demanded six-pence of me to file the irons off. I gave him six-pence, and he and another went to buy the files, while another man stood with us there. When they came with the files, they brought us near a lamp, at the entrance of the field; there Wilson attempted to file the hand-cuffs off from Wigmore. They were afraid of being discovered, as they were so near a lamp; so they agreed to go to a room of their acquaintance: upon which they carried us into <placeName id="t17551204-45-crimeloc240">Gray's-Inn-Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17551204-45-crimeloc240" type="placeName" value="Gray's-Inn-Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17551204-45-crimeloc240" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-45-off238 t17551204-45-crimeloc240"></join>, to the house of 
               <persName id="t17551204-45-person509">
                  Alexander 
                  Macdaniel 
               <interp inst="t17551204-45-person509" type="surname" value="Macdaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-45-person509" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-45-person509" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a shoemaker; there Wilson was the chief person that assisted in filing the hand-cuffs off Wigmore. They released him; but the irons were left upon me. Then I said, I hoped they would release me, as they had done the other. Then Wilson said, Let's see what money you have got. I told him, I had but little. He put his hand into my pocket, and took out 10 s. and three halfpence.</p>

               <p>Q. Did he threaten you at that time?</p>
               <p>Innis. No, he did not. I told him, I hoped he would not take it and he said do you grudge and took up a hanger, and drew it about half way out of the scabbard; and gave me the money again. I was afraid he was going to murder me. So I told him I did not grudge it, and gave it him again.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you put in fear when you gave it him again ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175512040057"></xptr>Innis. I did it through fear. Then he said there's a brave fellow, and gave me back a shilling.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you what use he'd make of the money?</p>
               <p>Innis. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I returned the money to him, and said I did not want it; he said you deserve it for the good services you have done in the rescuing of me.</p>
               <p>Innis. I did not mention such a word.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. Did not you and your comrade say, if you had 20 l. you would give it me for rescuing you?</p>
               <p>Innis. I had no comrade. I did not mention such a word. After my hand-cuffs were off, I went and voluntarily surrender'd myself to justice Fielding.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-45-person510">
                  Hugh 
                  Kelley 
               <interp inst="t17551204-45-person510" type="surname" value="Kelley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-45-person510" type="given" value="Hugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-45-person510" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I follow'd these men till they came to Macdaniel's house. After the irons were off, the prisoner ask'd Innis if he had got any money; he said he had got but a very little. Then Wigmore said I have got no money; I will pawn my coat. Then the prisoner put his hand into Innis's pocket, and took out some money, and said here's nine or ten shillings of it, and held it out in his hand; after that he said do you grudge it, if you do, take it again; and put it back into his hand. No, said Innis, I don't grudge it, and gave it him again.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see a hanger in Wilson's hand at the time, part drawn out ?</p>
               <p>Kelley. I can't be positive whether the hanger was drawn out, or not. After that he gave him back a shilling, to get him a lodging.</p>
               <p>Q. Had Wilson a hanger?</p>
               <p>Kelley. He had, at the time of the rescue; after that I saw it lying on a chest of drawers in Macdaniel's house.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>They call'd me out of a house in Drury-Lane, and said there is such a one going to Bridewell, for a quarrel, it is a pity he should go. So I went out. Afterwards that lad gave me 10 s. and I gave him a shilling back again.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17551204-45-verdict241" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17551204-45-verdict241" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was detain'd to take his trial at Hick's-Hall for rescuing Wigmore.</p>
            </div1>
