<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17550515-30">
               <interp inst="t17550515-30" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550515-30" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550515-30" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550515"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550515-30" type="date" value="17550515"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550515-30-off147-c208" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-30-defend266 t17550515-30-off147 t17550515-30-verdict150"></join>
         
               <p>238. (L.) Susannah <rs id="t17550515-30-deflabel146" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-30-defend266 t17550515-30-deflabel146"></join> to - Kirby, otherwise 
               <persName id="t17550515-30-defend266" type="defendantName">
                  Susannah 
                  Kirby 
               <interp inst="t17550515-30-defend266" type="surname" value="Kirby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-30-defend266" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-30-defend266" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , spinster, was indicted for <rs id="t17550515-30-off147" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550515-30-off147" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-30-off147" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing one silk purse, value 1 d. one guinea, and 8 s. in money, numbered, the property of 
                     <persName id="t17550515-30-person267">
                        Margaret 
                        Nelson 
                     <interp inst="t17550515-30-person267" type="surname" value="Nelson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550515-30-person267" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550515-30-person267" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , from the person of the said Margaret, privately and secretly
            </rs>, <rs id="t17550515-30-cd148" type="crimeDate">April 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-30-off147 t17550515-30-cd148"></join>*. </p> 
               <p>Margaret Nelson. I was at the rehearsal at <placeName id="t17550515-30-crimeloc149">St. Paul's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17550515-30-crimeloc149" type="placeName" value="St. Paul's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550515-30-crimeloc149" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-30-off147 t17550515-30-crimeloc149"></join> walking with my arm in Mr. Law's. I felt a hand in my pocket; and said to him, there is a hand in my pocket; I bid him not say any thing till I saw whether it was picked or not. I turned about, and saw the prisoner's hand coming from under my petticoat, and my sack was up, I had a hoop on; the prisoner went to make off, I felt and found my purse was gone.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>M. Nelson. It was on the 15th of April.</p>
               <p>Q. In the church, or church-yard?</p>
               <p>M. Nelson. In the church. It was after the music was over; there was a very great crowd of people walking. I told Mr. Law my purse was gone, and he went and laid hold of the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. What was in your purse ?</p>
               <p>M. Nelson. There was a guinea, a crown-piece, and some other silver, I don't know how much.</p>
               <p>Q. How long before this happened had you felt your purse in your pocket?</p>

               <p>M. Nelson. I had taken my purse out about half an hour before, to give to the collection at the door, and put it in my pocket again.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you put it in your pocket?</p>
               <p>M. Nelson. I am sure I did; but am not sure the prisoner picked it out. The rehearsal was just over when I went in, and the coronation anthem was singing then. We took the prisoner to a house in Cheapside, I asked her to give me my money again; she said she had it not; we had her to the Compter.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you search her?</p>
               <p>M. Nelson. No, we did not; we suspected, if she had taken it, she had given it to some others that were near her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550515-30-person268">
                  John 
                  Law 
               <interp inst="t17550515-30-person268" type="surname" value="Law"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-30-person268" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-30-person268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in company with Mrs. Nelson at the rehearsal at St. Paul's; as we were walking at the west door, she said there is somebody picking my pocket; she turned about, and the prisoner at the bar was just behind her, with her hand under her sack.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her hand under her sack ?</p>
               <p>Law. I did; likewise I observed two more that seemed to be acquaintances of hers arm in arm; as soon as ever the lady discovered her hand in her pocket, the other two turned short and made off; she said, I believe I have lost my purse, keep your eye upon that person (meaning the prisoner) till I examine my pocket; she did, and found her purse gone; after that we had her taken up and carried her to the Nag's-head tavern, Cheapside, there I sent for a constable; we asked her to produce the purse, and said, if she was agreeable we would not prosecute her. She stiffly denied it; we were apprehensive she had given it to her companions, so we did not search her.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>That morning I had a message come from my husband (he belongs to a man of war) to come to him at the King's-arms on Tower-hill; going by St. Paul's church, I saw a prodigious great crowd, I went in but it was all over; the lady's hoop lay, I believe, on my shoulder, but I know nothing of the taking the money.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175505150029"></xptr>To her character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550515-30-person269">
                  Mary 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17550515-30-person269" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-30-person269" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-30-person269" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner sixteen or seventeen years; she was at a boarding-school at Northampton, and I waited on her there, I was her servant, then she was a young gentlewoman of very good character. She is daughter of Sir 
               <persName id="t17550515-30-person270">
                  Ralph 
                  Hare 
               <interp inst="t17550515-30-person270" type="surname" value="Hare"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-30-person270" type="given" value="Ralph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-30-person270" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Have you had any acquaintance with her since?</p>
               <p>M. Johnson. No, I have not till within these two or three days.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I had no thoughts of being tried; the prosecutrix sent me word the bill would not be found, so I have not called all my friends about me.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutrix. Did you send her word the bill would not be found?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. No, I did not; I have a letter in my pocket now which the prisoner sent to me to desire me not to appear against her, and I sent her word it would be tried to-day, and it was not in my power to help it, and I hoped she would not be found guilty.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Did not I insist upon being searched?</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Law. Did she desire to be searched?</p>
               <p>Law. She desired the constable to search her, but we imagined if she had got it about her she would not have desired to have been searched.</p>
               <p>Court. That is not always a sure rule to go by.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17550515-30-verdict150" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550515-30-verdict150" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
