<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510227-3">
               <interp inst="t17510227-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510227-3" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510227-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510227"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510227-3" type="date" value="17510227"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510227-3-off10-c33" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510227-3-defend38 t17510227-3-off10 t17510227-3-verdict13"></join>
         
               <p>189. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17510227-3-defend38" type="defendantName">
                     Henry 
                     Grover 
                  <interp inst="t17510227-3-defend38" type="surname" value="Grover"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-3-defend38" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-3-defend38" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17510227-3-off10" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510227-3-off10" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-3-off10" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing one black gelding, value 11 l.
            </rs> the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17510227-3-victim40" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Groves 
                  <interp inst="t17510227-3-victim40" type="surname" value="Groves"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-3-victim40" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-3-victim40" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510227-3-off10 t17510227-3-victim40"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            .</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510227-3-cd11" type="crimeDate">Jan. 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510227-3-off10 t17510227-3-cd11"></join>.*</p>
               <p>Thomas Groves. I live at <placeName id="t17510227-3-crimeloc12">Belsise , near Hampstead</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17510227-3-crimeloc12" type="placeName" value="Belsise , near Hampstead"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510227-3-crimeloc12" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510227-3-off10 t17510227-3-crimeloc12"></join>. On the 21st of Jan. my stable door was broke open, after 11 o'clock at night, and my black gelding was taken away.</p>
               <p>Q. Describe this gelding.</p>
               <p>Groves. He had three white feet, and a blaze in his face, and two wall eyes.</p>
               <p>Q. Why do you charge the prisoner at the bar?</p>
               <p>Groves. The prisoner had been loitering about us for about a fortnight: he had work'd for me last hay-time, and he had done little things before. When my horse was missing, he was also. I inquired after him; I went as far as St. Alban's (knowing he came from near Luton, in Bedfordshire ) but did not find him. I had my horse cry'd at Watford, and found him again on Wednesday, being the day after, in the possession of 
               <persName id="t17510227-3-person41">
                  Abraham 
                  Chapel 
               <interp inst="t17510227-3-person41" type="surname" value="Chapel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-3-person41" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-3-person41" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at Enfield.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your horse worth?</p>
               <p>Groves, He is worth 11 or 12 l.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510227-3-person42">
                  Abraham 
                  Chapel 
               <interp inst="t17510227-3-person42" type="surname" value="Chapel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-3-person42" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-3-person42" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner brought the horse to me on Tuesday, the 22d of Jan. about nine o'clock in the morning: he had three white feet, a blaze down his face, and two wall eyes. I work with Mrs. Clayton. The prisoner ask'd if our bailey was at home. I said I expected him every hour. He said, he heard my mistress wanted to buy some horses, which she did. He staid some time, but seem'd very uneasy; often looking out, as though he suspected every body he saw. I sent the boy to inquire at a house in the town for our bailey; who return'd, and told me, the prisoner had been at that house and proffer'd the horse for<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175102270003"></xptr> nine guineas ; which the prisoner said was true. Then I said, I am but a poor man, and could not afford to give much; but ask'd what I should give for him; adding, I would give him 3 l. 10 s. Upon which he pull'd me by the collar, and whispering, said, you shall have him for the other ten shillings. I answered, no. Then he said I should have him. So I gave him a shilling earnest, and said, if he would fetch a voucher to tell how he came by the horse, I would pay him the remainder of the money; otherwise I would not. Then he told me his father's name was 
               <persName id="t17510227-3-person43">
                  John 
                  Long 
               <interp inst="t17510227-3-person43" type="surname" value="Long"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-3-person43" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-3-person43" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and liv'd at Bushey, near the common side, and that his own name was 
               <persName id="t17510227-3-person44">
                  John 
                  Long 
               <interp inst="t17510227-3-person44" type="surname" value="Long"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-3-person44" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-3-person44" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17510227-3-person45">
                  Thomas 
                  Kendal 
               <interp inst="t17510227-3-person45" type="surname" value="Kendal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-3-person45" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-3-person45" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who was by, proffer'd to go to his father's house for 1 s. 6 d. but the prisoner said no, he would go himself. Then I offer'd to be 9 d. towards that charge; but he said he would not send, he would go himself. I answered he should not go. So we held him, and he struggled with us, till we tore his cloaths; and at last we, with much difficulty, secured him. The next morning I went to enquire after his father, but found no such man lived there; and calling at a house to get my breakfast, I heard the prosecutor had been about there to seek after such a horse, and subscribing the prisoner. Thus having obtain'd the prisoner, and found the prosecutor had subscrib'd him, I went to the prosecutor's house on the Wednesday, about one o'clock; when I saw his wife, and told her, I had got a man in curtisey. She said her husband was gone to London to have the horse advertised. She sent a man after him, and he came back and went along with me, and owned the horse.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510227-3-person46">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Parker 
               <interp inst="t17510227-3-person46" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-3-person46" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-3-person46" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable at Enfield. The prisoner at the bar was stopp'd upon suspicion of stealing this horse on the 21st of Jan. (describing him as 
               <persName id="t17510227-3-person47">
                  Abraham 
                  Chapel 
               <interp inst="t17510227-3-person47" type="surname" value="Chapel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-3-person47" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-3-person47" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had done.) He was put into my custody; he said his name was 
               <persName id="t17510227-3-person48">
                  John 
                  Long 
               <interp inst="t17510227-3-person48" type="surname" value="Long"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-3-person48" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-3-person48" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and that he came from Bushey. I said I wish'd he was not John Short. It was as much as seven men could do to get him down to the watch-house. I put hand-cuffs on him, and lock'd him up safe, and chain'd him too, yet he releas'd himself. He told me afterwards he tore his hand-cuffs off with his teeth.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510227-3-person49">
                  Thomas 
                  Kendal 
               <interp inst="t17510227-3-person49" type="surname" value="Kendal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-3-person49" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-3-person49" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was along with 
               <persName id="t17510227-3-person50">
                  Abraham 
                  Chapel 
               <interp inst="t17510227-3-person50" type="surname" value="Chapel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-3-person50" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-3-person50" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             on Saturday, the 22d of Jan. when we took the prisoner into custody. I saw Chapel buy the horse for 3 l. 10 s. ( he described the horse as the others did ) When Ab. Chapel talk'd of a voucher, the prisoner said his father was in trouble, and he did not care any body should go. I offer'd to go for 1 s. 6 d. Chapel said he would be one part, and the prisoner the other. He got out of the chair where he sat, and said he would go himself. Then we secured him. The prosecutor came afterwards and own'd the horse.</p>
               <p>All that the prisoner could say, was, they were mistaken in their man.</p>
               <p>The witness being all ask'd again, if they were certain as to the prisoner, they answered in the affirmative.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510227-3-verdict13" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510227-3-verdict13" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17510227-3-punish14" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510227-3-punish14" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510227-3-defend38 t17510227-3-punish14"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
