<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17540424-73">
               <interp inst="t17540424-73" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540424-73" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540424-73" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540424"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540424-73" type="date" value="17540424"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540424-73-off381-c618" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540424-73-defend752 t17540424-73-off381 t17540424-73-verdict385"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175404240061"></xptr>304. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17540424-73-defend752" type="defendantName">
                     George 
                     Capper 
                  <interp inst="t17540424-73-defend752" type="surname" value="Capper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-defend752" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-defend752" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for the <rs id="t17540424-73-off381" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-off381" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-off381" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               wilful murder
            </rs> of 
               <persName id="t17540424-73-victim753" type="victimName">
                  Elizabeth, the <rs id="t17540424-73-viclabel382" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540424-73-victim753 t17540424-73-viclabel382"></join>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540424-73-person754 t17540424-73-viclabel382"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17540424-73-person754" type="victimName">
                        John 
                        Webb 
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person754" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540424-73-person754" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540424-73-person754" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540424-73-off381 t17540424-73-person754"></join>
                     </persName>
                  
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-victim753" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-victim753" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-victim753" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540424-73-off381 t17540424-73-victim753"></join>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17540424-73-cd383" type="crimeDate">Nov. 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540424-73-off381 t17540424-73-cd383"></join>. He stood likewise charged on the coroner's inquest for the said murder. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540424-73-person755">
                  John 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17540424-73-person755" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person755" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person755" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I met my wife at St. Dunstan's Church in Fleetstreet, and asked her where she was going? she said, a great way: I asked her where? she fell a crying, and said, her mother was dead, and she was going to tell her grandmother. I said, I will go along with you; she said no, you have been up too or three nights, go home and get some sleep. I persuaded her not to go but l et me write a penny-post letter.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did your grandmother live?</p>
               <p>Webb. At Wandsworth near the Golden Anchor.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Webb. Upon the 15th of November about three o'clock in the afternoon. I went with her as far as <placeName id="t17540424-73-crimeloc384">Chelsea-horse-ferry</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17540424-73-crimeloc384" type="placeName" value="Chelsea-horse-ferry"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17540424-73-crimeloc384" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540424-73-off381 t17540424-73-crimeloc384"></join> by water, and there I handed her into the prisoner's boat, and agreed with him for 6 d. I gave him a pint of beer at the White-hart, and asked him, what time he thought she would be at home? he said, if God permit, she will be at home about seven o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you leave your wife?</p>
               <p>Webb. I put her in at the horseferry a little after four o'clock, and agreed with him for 6 d. to carry her to Wandsworth and bring her back again the same day. I did not know the prisoner then, he said he knew old 
               <persName id="t17540424-73-person756">
                  Harry 
                  Nichols 
               <interp inst="t17540424-73-person756" type="surname" value="Nichols"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person756" type="given" value="Harry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person756" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , commonly called old Ball of Wax, which is my grandfather: I was very glad she was in the boat of a person who knew him. I stood by the water side and saw her as far as I could see. The prisoner was a sculler and there was no-body with him but my wife and himself; I did not see her any more till the Tuesday following, when I saw her lay dead at the Black-Lyon at Hammersmith.</p>
               <p>Q. What day of the week did you put her in the boat?</p>
               <p>Webb. On a Thursday. When I saw her on Tuesday she was all over mud, and appeared to have been drowned; both her hands were sodden, as the washer-womens hands are, but her hands were not tied then.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. That is the man who put her in my boat and bargained for 6 d.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540424-73-person757">
                  Henry 
                  Nichols 
               <interp inst="t17540424-73-person757" type="surname" value="Nichols"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person757" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person757" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My wife was grandmother to the deceased. I have known the prisoner a good many years; he came to me on the 15th of November with the deceased.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Webb. At Wandsworth. When the prisoner came he beckoned to me as I was standing at an alehouse, and said, he wanted to speak with me; I said, I would not come; he said you must, here is a young woman wants you; it was very dark, and the deceased said, you don't know me, grandfather: Yes, says I, I do. I took her to her grandmother; she said, she came up with the waterman that knew us both very well; and the prisoner came in presently after; I went and fetched a pot of beer and set out some victuals; then I went upon the plying-place and drank with the prisoner; he had cut some victuals before. When we came to the alehouse there was one 
               <persName id="t17540424-73-person758">
                  Richard 
                  Sharp 
               <interp inst="t17540424-73-person758" type="surname" value="Sharp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person758" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person758" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             standing there, and he said, he did not care if he was a penny with us, upon which we had three pints of beer. I said, when they were ready, I would go and fetch her; they said, they were ready; I went and fetched her; Sharp was then got into the boat, and I handed her into the boat.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was that?</p>
               <p>Nichols. It was between seven and eight o'clock. She made a sort of a stumble after she was in the boat.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is Sharp?</p>
               <p>Nichols. He has absented himself ever since, when she went into the boat she sate close to Sharp; the prisoner said to me, give me a shove, which I did; he called London boy, and they went towards London.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Sharp assist the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Nichols. He did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any more than them three in the boat?</p>
               <p>Nichols. There was not. The next day, as I was at work, a young man, whose name is Soaper, he is a fisherman, came to me, and asked, if there was not a young woman last night at my house.</p>

               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>Nichols. It was between two and three o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you tell him?</p>
               <p>Nichols. I told him it was my grand-daughter; he said if it is she is drowned; I asked him how he knew that; he said, as he and some more fishermen were coming by St. George's, Surry, there came a man and asked them, if they did not come from London, they said, yes; and that as they were coming home a man came out to them and told them that the woman who came from Wandsworth last night was drowned. Upon Saturday John<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175404240062"></xptr> Webb came to me and asked me if his wife was not here last night; I had never seen him before; I said to him, I hear she is drowned; he said, he had heard so too; and said, do you know the waterman that carried her? I then wrote down where Capper lodged.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the body of the deceased?</p>
               <p>Nichols. Yes, at the Black-Lyon at Hammersmith, upon the Tuesday or Wednesday after hearing the body was found.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you there before the body was taken out of the water, and after her husband had been there?</p>
               <p>Nichols. No, not till afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she swelled when you saw her?</p>
               <p>Nichols. She was not swelled much, but when I saw her face I did not know it; being shewn the cloak I knew that.</p>
               <p>Q. Had she the appearance of a drowned person ?</p>
               <p>Nichols. She had; and she had a colour in her face and looked very beautiful.</p>
               <p>Q. Was her face swelled?</p>
               <p>Nichols. It was a little swelled.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. What he says is very true.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540424-73-person759">
                  James 
                  Gold 
               <interp inst="t17540424-73-person759" type="surname" value="Gold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person759" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person759" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a bargeman, but cannot say I know the prisoner. Upon Sunday the 18th of November, as I, my wife, and child, were coming from Chiswick to Hammersmith we heard of a drowned woman; I was determined to walk down to see her, and walked as far as the mud and water would let me go, and believe I went within four inches of my knees in mud, for I garter below knee and believe my garters touched the mud; she lay in mud and water, but over-hawling her very strictly I lifted up her head, and then came to her hands, and lifting up her left hand, as they both lay upon her breast, they both came up together; there was a cord came round her wrists and they were tied together.</p>
               <p>Q. How near the shore was this?</p>
               <p>Gold. 'Twas about twenty yards off the shore; I took out my knife and cut it, it was about as big as the lower end of a pipe, it was three stranded; she had two black hats on, her knees lay bare and laid up, I covered them; afterwards two burgemen taking her up, asked me, if I had made her fast; I said no; being afraid of coming into trouble.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did she lay before she was taken up ?</p>
               <p>Gold. From the Sunday to the Monday. I staid upon the wharf at Chiswick and saw the bargemen carry her to the Black Lion; I saw her there afterwards.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540424-73-person760">
                  William 
                  Catchley 
               <interp inst="t17540424-73-person760" type="surname" value="Catchley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person760" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person760" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went with the husband to see the wife when drowned, and looking upon her saw the marks of a cord upon her left arm.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Catchley. 'Twas on the Thursday at the Black-Lion at Hammersmith; there were several more neighbours of us went at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any cord there ?</p>
               <p>Gold. There was none; there were several more neighbours took notice of that mark upon her left arm.</p>
               <p>Q. to Webb. Did you find any money in your wife's pocket ?</p>
               <p>Webb. I felt in her pocket but found none.</p>
               <p>Q. Had she any when you left her?</p>
               <p>Webb. She might have 6 d. or 1 s. she was to pay the prisoner, she had likewise a large brass snuff box about four or five inches over, and a crooked King Charles's halfpenny, but she had nothing at all when I searched her: I went with these people on the Thursday.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the first time you went?</p>
               <p>Webb. 'Twas on the Tuesday.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe the mark of the cord then?</p>
               <p>Webb. I did not; I was informed the man that first saw her cut the cord; she tied a handkerchief over her hat when I left her?</p>
               <p>Q. Were any of her clothes taken from her?</p>
               <p>Webb. No, they were not; I saw the handkerchief (which was a very old thing) and the hat.</p>
               <p>Q. to Gold. What did you do with the cord; is it here?</p>
               <p>Gold. I threw it away with my left hand, so I have it not here: there are two men that heard the prisoner say her hands were tied, he was subpoena'd in the prisoner's behalf.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540424-73-person761">
                  James 
                  Ivers 
               <interp inst="t17540424-73-person761" type="surname" value="Ivers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person761" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person761" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner told me last Saturday was three weeks at Kingston that he heard a fisherman had tied her hands.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he mention his name?</p>
               <p>Ivers. He did, but I have forgot his name.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it Sharp?</p>
               <p>Ivers. No, it was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>Ivers. At Kingston, last Saturday was three weeks; I was upon the Jury, we could not come at where he set her down.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Ivers. I am a waterman; I remember it was a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175404240063"></xptr> very turbulent night; the prisoner told me that in turning his boat about she fell over board.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I sent him word the very next morning, by a fisherman, that she sell overboard.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I found the wind blow so hard, I thought proper to wind my boat stern foremost; there was a great swell and a very dismal night; she rolled out of my boat, I laid down my seulls and put down my hand; I could not see her for it was such a dark night I could hardly see my finger; the other man and she both got up and endeavoured to turn their backs to the wind.</p>
               <p>Q. How came that man in your boat?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I gave him a cast down.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is he?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He is gone to sea.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540424-73-person762">
                  Abraham 
                  Dent 
               <interp inst="t17540424-73-person762" type="surname" value="Dent"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person762" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person762" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Spotted-Dog at Strand-lane, near Somerset-house; upon a Thursday night in November the prisoner and 
               <persName id="t17540424-73-person763">
                  Richard 
                  Sharp 
               <interp inst="t17540424-73-person763" type="surname" value="Sharp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person763" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person763" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came in, and after they had been in some time they said they had had a sad accident.</p>
               <p>Q. How soon was this after they came in ?</p>
               <p>Dent. I believe they might have been in five or six minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. What day of the month was this?</p>
               <p>Dent. I don't directly remember.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know them?</p>
               <p>Dent. I knew Sharp before, but I never saw the prisoner before to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was it?</p>
               <p>Dent. I believe it might be about seven o'clock, but I cannot justly say what o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it dark?</p>
               <p>Dent. It was.</p>
               <p>Q. What accident did they say they had?</p>
               <p>Dent. They said they had lost a woman out of the boat; I asked them in what manner they lost her? they both of them said, they did not know how she was lost; I said, is it possible you can make me believe that? then they both said, they knew nothing at all how she did go out: Sharp said, he was looking another way and did not see her go. 'Twas a very windy boisterous night.</p>
               <p>Q. What is become of Sharp?</p>
               <p>Dent. I don't know.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know whether Sharp belongs to any ship ?</p>
               <p>Dent. I do not know. I asked the prisoner why he did not go back to Wandsworth again, he said the wind blew so he could not; but he rowed about and felt with his hands in the water about half an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever seen Sharp since?</p>
               <p>Dent. No, I never saw him afterwards; he said, he came from Wandsworth that day.</p>
               <p>Q. What trade is Sharp?</p>
               <p>Dent. He used to work upon the water, but I cannot say whether he had a boat of his own or not.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you known him?</p>
               <p>Dent. I don't think I had known him above two months.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this a boisterous night?</p>
               <p>Dent. It was very boisterous; I don't know there has been such a night since. We had them both down to the watch-house that night, and they both set their names down there in a book. I would have had the constable take charge of them; but he said he saw no reason to take charge of them without I would give him charge. I left them there, but they were not stopped.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540424-73-person764">
                  Robert 
                  Boyle 
               <interp inst="t17540424-73-person764" type="surname" value="Boyle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person764" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person764" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was the first person who touched the woman, at a place called the Hope, at Hammersmith, on a Sunday night about four or five o'clock in the afternoon, just within the water, near the Hope; she lay with her head right down in the mud and all naked; I covered her cloaths over her back side, and turned her afterwards and looked over her, and to the best of my knowledge her hands were not tied.</p>
               <p>Q. Will you swear they were, or were not?</p>
               <p>Boyle. I cannot swear any otherwise, nor can I swear they were not tied; I just laid hold of one of her arms but never moved them; and to the best of my opinion they were not tied; I saw no cord at all, nor did I tie them. I believe there were a hundred people on the bank side at that time; I went to her with a fishing boat.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540424-73-person765">
                  Henry 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17540424-73-person765" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person765" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person765" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Our barge lay at anchor at the Hope at Hammersmith; upon Monday morning there was a fishing boat came down, they shot at her with their nets to get at her; the net went over her and pulled some of her cloaths; we stept into our boat and took hold of her and had her upon shore; I threw her upon a piece of board and carried her up to the Black-Lion and laid her there; there were five or six of us carried her up, but her hands were not tied then.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any marks of a string upon her wrists?</p>
               <p>Smith. I did not mind whether there were or not.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175404240064"></xptr>Q. Was she ever in the water after you carried her ashore?</p>
               <p>Smith. No, she never was.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540424-73-person766">
                  Charles 
                  Dunn 
               <interp inst="t17540424-73-person766" type="surname" value="Dunn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person766" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person766" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed the same.</p>
               <p>Q. to Gold. When did you find the deceased?</p>
               <p>Gold. Upon the Sunday, between five and six o'clock; there was nobody under shore when I found her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Boyl there?</p>
               <p>Gold. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. How many times did the cord go round her arms ?</p>
               <p>Gold. To the best of my remembrance three times round, it was tied in two seafaring knots, and her arms lay across her breast (he produced the knife with which he says he cut the cord.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540424-73-person767">
                  John 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17540424-73-person767" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person767" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person767" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodge at the spotted dog; I came over the water about some business, there I saw the prisoner, I clapped him upon the shoulder, and asked him how he did? he was at first a little surprized; he made answer, and said, he was very uneasy about the woman he had lost over-night: I asked him how it came about, he said, as he was coming from Wandsworth, the wind blew very hard, and he was obliged to wind his boat stern foremost; that Sharp said to the deceased, let's get up, and move the seat forwards; this they did, and the woman was lost out of the boat; he said, he did not see her go over-board because his back was towards them.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Jones. I am a waterman.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it usual for you to wind your boat when there are two persons in it?</p>
               <p>Jones. Yes, if the wind blows very hard.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it safer so than going the right way?</p>
               <p>Jones. It is; I have done it myself with two people in my boat.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540424-73-person768">
                  John 
                  Westwood 
               <interp inst="t17540424-73-person768" type="surname" value="Westwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person768" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person768" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , with whom the prisoner served his apprenticeship, deposed he was a quit honest man.</p>
               <p>Richard Green. I live at Wandsworth at the Anchor, and have known the prisoner fourteen years; his character is that of a quiet fellow, he went out of my house with Sharp the night the woman was drowned, who is since gone off.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540424-73-person769">
                  Silvanus 
                  Foster 
               <interp inst="t17540424-73-person769" type="surname" value="Foster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person769" type="given" value="Silvanus"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-person769" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew the prisoner all the time of his apprenticeship, and knew him to be a sober careful lad in his master's business then.</p>
               <p>All the witnesses for the prisoner knew the man, who said he cut the cord, and gave him a good character and that of an honest man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540424-73-verdict385" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540424-73-verdict385" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
