<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17590912-14">
               <interp inst="t17590912-14" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590912-14" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590912-14" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17590912"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590912-14" type="date" value="17590912"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17590912-14-off90-c133" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-14-defend164 t17590912-14-off90 t17590912-14-verdict95"></join>
         
               <p>260. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17590912-14-defend164" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Bowers 
                  <interp inst="t17590912-14-defend164" type="surname" value="Bowers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-14-defend164" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-14-defend164" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17590912-14-off90" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590912-14-off90" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-14-off90" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one guinea
            </rs>, the money of 
               
                  <persName id="t17590912-14-victim166" type="victimName">
                     Samuel 
                     Jourdan 
                  <interp inst="t17590912-14-victim166" type="surname" value="Jourdan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-14-victim166" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-14-victim166" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-14-off90 t17590912-14-victim166"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17590912-14-cd91" type="crimeDate">December 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-14-off90 t17590912-14-cd91"></join>.*.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590912-14-person167">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Higgs 
               <interp inst="t17590912-14-person167" type="surname" value="Higgs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-14-person167" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-14-person167" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was <rs id="t17590912-14-deflabel92" type="occupation">foreman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-14-defend164 t17590912-14-deflabel92"></join> to my grandfather, in <placeName id="t17590912-14-crimeloc93">Queen-street, Tower-hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17590912-14-crimeloc93" type="placeName" value="Queen-street, Tower-hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17590912-14-crimeloc93" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-14-off90 t17590912-14-crimeloc93"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your grandfather?</p>
               <p>Higgs. He is a <rs id="t17590912-14-viclabel94" type="occupation">Taylor</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-14-victim166 t17590912-14-viclabel94"></join>, named 
               <persName id="t17590912-14-person168">
                  Samuel 
                  Jourdan 
               <interp inst="t17590912-14-person168" type="surname" value="Jourdan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-14-person168" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-14-person168" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner made love to me; I acquainted my grandfather and mother with it; they were not willing that I should keep him company.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you charge the prisoner with?</p>
               <p>Higgs. Between the eighteen and nineteenth of December last he took me into the dining-room, and said, Where does the old dog keep his money?</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by his taking you there?</p>
               <p>Higgs. He went in there with me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did your grandfather turn him away after he knew he made love to you ?</p>
               <p>Higgs. No: the prisoner said it was pity I had not the key belonging to his drawer.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell him where your grandfather's money was?</p>
               <p>Higgs. I did: I told him it was in the bureau; then he ask'd me if I had not a key belonging to my box; I said, yes; he said, let's look at it; I did; he took it, and tried the lock, and accordingly it happened to fit my grandfather's lock of the bureau; he opened it and took out a green purse with ten guineas in it; he took one out and put it in his pocket, then he went up to his work again; after that he call'd me into another room and advised me never to discover it.</p>

               <p>Q. Where was your grandfather at that time?</p>
               <p>Higgs. He was out.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was your mother?</p>
               <p>Higgs. She was below stairs in the kitchen.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you give him your key willingly?</p>
               <p>Higgs. Yes: but I did not know what his intent was?</p>
               <p>Q. Did you think there was any thing of his in that bureau?</p>
               <p>Higgs. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you ask him what he wanted there?</p>
               <p>Higgs. No.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you say to him when you saw him take the guinea out?</p>
               <p>Higgs. Nothing at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any part of that guinea?</p>
               <p>Higgs. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he make you no present?</p>
               <p>Higgs. No.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after this was it that you told your grandfather of this?</p>
               <p>Higgs. Three months, I believe.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he continue working for your grandfather after he had taken this guinea?</p>
               <p>Higgs. Not above two or three days.</p>
               <p>Q. How came he to go away?</p>
               <p>Higgs. My grandfather turn'd him away.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he turn him away for?</p>
               <p>Higgs. For some misdemeanor.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you not to tell it sooner?</p>
               <p>Higgs. He gave me a strict charge never to tell it.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175909120017"></xptr>Q. Did you love him better than you did your grandfather?</p>
               <p>Higgs. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you keep him company after he went away?</p>
               <p>Higgs. I did, for about three or four hours.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he ever take any money besides that time?</p>
               <p>Higgs. No, never but that time; he obliged me to murder my grandfather and mother.</p>
               <p>Q. Why?</p>
               <p>Higgs. Because they were against my having him.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. What time was this?</p>
               <p>Higgs. This was in December, betwixt the 18th and 19th.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that the first time the prisoner was in the dining-room?</p>
               <p>Higgs. It was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he ever in that room afterwards?</p>
               <p>Higgs. He was: he came in a second time to take an inventory of the goods.</p>
               <p>Q. Had your grandfather ordered him to take an inventory of the goods?</p>
               <p>Higgs. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he want to take an inventory of the goods for?</p>
               <p>Higgs. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was this second time of coming into the room?</p>
               <p>Higgs. It was past two o'clock.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590912-14-person169">
                  Samuel 
                  Jourdan 
               <interp inst="t17590912-14-person169" type="surname" value="Jourdan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-14-person169" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-14-person169" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I thought I had mis-told my money, but could not tell how it was; then the girl told me the design was to murder me and her mother, and take possession of my effects; I miss'd money at several times about Christmas last, and thought I was strangely mistaken.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of your own knowledge, of the prisoner's taking your money?</p>
               <p>Jourdan. No, I know nothing of his taking the money, besides what my grand-daughter told me.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you take him up?</p>
               <p>Jourdan. About a month ago.</p>
               <p>Q. When did your grand-daughter tell you of it?</p>
               <p>Jourdan. She told me of it about a month before.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you not to take him up sooner?</p>
               <p>Jourdan. I was afraid to hurt the man; but the iniquity was so great I thought I must take him up.</p>
               <p>Court. The iniquity was as great, a month before as a month after.</p>
               <p>Jourdan. I can't justly swear to the time; I would not have appeared against him, but from what I had from the girl.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you miss your money?</p>
               <p>Jourdan. I missed my money about December last.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing of what the girl says against me: after the last day of the last year Mr Jourdan had no work for me. He did not discharge me because he did not like me, but he had no work; he kept one man that did jobbs for him, and if he had work or not he paid him. After I was gone this girl broke out into her loose tricks as she use to do. On the Wednesday at twelve o'clock, a fortnight after New-Year's-Day, she came and called me, and said, I believe my grand-father wants you. I used to cut for him, and manage his business as well as I could. She told me there was some cloaths come in to be done. I went and knocked at his door: he said, I am glad you are come to assist me. I went up stairs and cut out the body of a frock for him: just as I had done he asked me to drink, and insisted upon it, I should drink either a dram of rum or brandy. The rum was fetched out, and he drank to me and I to the girl; then I went away.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I did not know of any iniquity then.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. She is a wicked girl; she went and bought a suit of man's apparel and put them on, and came on horse-back with a letter to her grand-father, and he gave her sixpence for bringing it, he did not know her. She nor he neither will not deny this. She will swear any thing.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>John Hall. I worked with the prisoner eight days for Mr Jourdan. The grand-daughter<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175909120018"></xptr> lived upon her grand-father's bounty. I have seen her have plenty of money, but how she came by it I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner's character?</p>
               <p>Hall. I never heard any thing of him 'till now but what was honest.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590912-14-person170">
                  Benjamin 
                  Steward 
               <interp inst="t17590912-14-person170" type="surname" value="Steward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-14-person170" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-14-person170" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner some time, he is a very honest industrious man, he has worked journey-work for me and never wronged me.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17590912-14-verdict95" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590912-14-verdict95" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
