<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17520914-48">
               <interp inst="t17520914-48" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520914-48" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520914-48" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520914"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520914-48" type="date" value="17520914"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520914-48-off244-c323" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-48-defend419 t17520914-48-off244 t17520914-48-verdict247"></join>
         
               <p>457. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17520914-48-defend419" type="defendantName">
                     Garret 
                     Conner 
                  <interp inst="t17520914-48-defend419" type="surname" value="Conner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-48-defend419" type="given" value="Garret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-48-defend419" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17520914-48-off244" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520914-48-off244" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-48-off244" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 7 yards and 3 quarters of woollen cloth, and 18 yards of salloon, val. 58 s. the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17520914-48-victim421" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Bradshaw 
                        <interp inst="t17520914-48-victim421" type="surname" value="Bradshaw"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520914-48-victim421" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520914-48-victim421" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-48-off244 t17520914-48-victim421"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in his dwelling house
            </rs>, <rs id="t17520914-48-cd245" type="crimeDate">June 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-48-off244 t17520914-48-cd245"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520914-48-person422">
                  John 
                  Bradshaw 
               <interp inst="t17520914-48-person422" type="surname" value="Bradshaw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-48-person422" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-48-person422" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live <placeName id="t17520914-48-crimeloc246">beyond Algate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17520914-48-crimeloc246" type="placeName" value="beyond Algate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520914-48-crimeloc246" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-48-off244 t17520914-48-crimeloc246"></join>, in London, the prisoner worked for me, he had been at work for the train of artillery under me; his book answered to mine, of what I gave out and he brought in. I found myself a loser, but did not mistrust him more than others. I never delivered any goods to be made but what was ready cut, and they lay in the cutting room.</p>
               <p>Q. Is your cutting room part of your dwelling house?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520914-48-person423">
                  Bradshaw 
                  It 
               <interp inst="t17520914-48-person423" type="surname" value="It"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-48-person423" type="given" value="Bradshaw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-48-person423" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is. I believe what I lost were no part of what I delivered out to him to make up. I frightened him one night by saying I would search his lodgings, upon which account very likely he carried them out. My son in law, 
               <persName id="t17520914-48-person424">
                  Thomas 
                  Fothergall 
               <interp inst="t17520914-48-person424" type="surname" value="Fothergall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-48-person424" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-48-person424" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , told me some of my goods were at the house of Welch. I went there with two or three people that knew them, there I found 7 linings for coats, above 18 yards of shalloon, some red cloth, the same we make the drummers coats on for the artillery at Woolwich, about 5 or 6 shillings a yard, 3 coats ready cut for matrosses, the least as can make one must be two yards and a quarter, all blue cloth, at about 6 s. per yard.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see it in your dwelling house?</p>
               <p>Bradshaw. I can't tell that.</p>
               <p>The red cloth produced, and deposed to as part be lost. The others were made up and delivered. All that I lose I am obliged to make good. He was carried before Sir 
               <persName id="t17520914-48-person425">
                  Samuel 
                  Gore 
               <interp inst="t17520914-48-person425" type="surname" value="Gore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-48-person425" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-48-person425" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , there he said my son-in-law gave him this red cloth, and that one Irish Tom left the other cloth and shalloon at his house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520914-48-person426">
                  Joseph 
                  Welch 
               <interp inst="t17520914-48-person426" type="surname" value="Welch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-48-person426" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-48-person426" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On monday morning the 15th of June the prisoner's daughter brought a bundle of rags to my yard at the Rose and Crown, Catharine-wheel Alley, Whitechapel. It was these things put up in rags. She came again in about two hours and desired to put them into the cellar, that was not granted. Then she went and hid them in a coalshed. The next day we laid in some coals, and the men in removing some boards found the bundle. There was cloth cut out for three coats, and linings for them, and a piece of red cloth. The prisoner's wife came to demand them of me the 16th of June, and threatened me if I would not deliver them. Mr. Bradshaw came to me and asked me if I had such cloth. Mr. Bradshaw's son came and said he was the person that cut it out, so I delivered them to him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520914-48-person427">
                  Thomas 
                  Fothergall 
               <interp inst="t17520914-48-person427" type="surname" value="Fothergall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-48-person427" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-48-person427" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am son-in law to the prosecutor, the prisoner's daughter came to me and desired that I would go to her father, for he was in a little trouble. I went with her to Welch's house, she told me they had stopped some of her father's work. They finding that I was not the master I went and fetched my father. Then they delivered two drummers linings, this bit of red cloth, and some coats ready cut out. He said I gave him the red cloth, but I did not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>The last witness gave me 17 coats to make up, and the red cloth to make up the first two coats; I made up the coats without it, so saved the piece. There was a man that worked for him left three coats in my room, and went away. I put them together and desired my daughter to carry them to Bradshaw and tell him I would not work any more for him. She left them at Mr. Welch's house, when she went for the things to carry, as I had directed, and they stopped them.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520914-48-verdict247" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520914-48-verdict247" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acq
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
