<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17590711-14">
               <interp inst="t17590711-14" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590711-14" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590711-14" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17590711"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590711-14" type="date" value="17590711"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17590711-14-off76-c101" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590711-14-defend127 t17590711-14-off76 t17590711-14-verdict79"></join>
         
               <p>227. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17590711-14-defend127" type="defendantName">
                     Anne 
                     Bennet 
                  <interp inst="t17590711-14-defend127" type="surname" value="Bennet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-defend127" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-defend127" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17590711-14-deflabel75" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590711-14-defend127 t17590711-14-deflabel75"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17590711-14-off76" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-off76" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-off76" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch, value 3 l. 10 s. the property of 
                     <persName id="t17590711-14-person128">
                        Joseph 
                        Vialls 
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-person128" type="surname" value="Vialls"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590711-14-person128" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590711-14-person128" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  ; privately, and secretly, from his person
            </rs>; <rs id="t17590711-14-cd77" type="crimeDate">June 28</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590711-14-off76 t17590711-14-cd77"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590711-14-person129">
                  Joseph 
                  Vialls 
               <interp inst="t17590711-14-person129" type="surname" value="Vialls"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-person129" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-person129" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went across Smithfield, to the Rose, to inquire about a waggon that came out of Northamptonshire, last Thursday was se'nnight.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was this?</p>
               <p>Vialls. This was about ten o'clock in the morning; I met with two countrymen, and I staid there with them 'till about one o'clock; then we went down Chick-lane together; there were three women stood in my way; I said, let us come by; the prisoner took me by my cloaths, and took me up to a private place, a room, where was a bed; I told them, I had not above three-pence, or a groat, about me; the woman of the house said, I must go down; and said, there is no room for such customers as you.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any other person along with you?</p>
               <p>Vialls. No; none but the prisoner, and myself; the woman desir'd us to walk down again.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober?</p>
               <p>Vialls. I was sensible, but I had been drinking wine; the prisoner took hold of my cloaths; and said, You must go down stairs, come along with me; she took me up a hill, and into a ruinous house; and up one pair of stairs, there was a door, lock'd, and one pannel of it cut out, at the bottom of the door, I imagine, for the purpose; to take others in, as she did me; she said, You must come in here; she got in first, and drew me in afterwards; I had a blue apron on.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>Vialls. I am a <rs id="t17590711-14-viclabel78" type="occupation">Scowerer, and Dyer</rs>, by trade; I felt under my apron, and felt my watch safe then, in my pocket; she drew me into a little room, and laid herself down, and pull'd me over her; after that, she said she was sleepy, she must needs go to sleep, and would have me to go to sleep also; in about five or six minutes time, I might be a trifle dosing, I turn'd a little sickish; as soon as she found me stir, she said, I must be gone; for somebody wants me below; she went away; as I continued sick, I felt for my watch, and found it was gone; I made the best of my way after her; but, when I came to the bottom, I could not find her.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907110013"></xptr>Q. How came you to find her; at last?</p>
               <p>Vialls. I was told, by a countryman, that she would be at the Chequers in Chick-lane, at such an hour at night; for she was always there.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Vialls. This was the same night, I went and found her there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see your watch again?</p>
               <p>Vialls. No, never; she had a black sattin hat on her head; I look'd at it, and said; I believe you have a piece of my watch on your head; said she, You had but three pence, in your pocket, when you was with me; she had on, when I took her, a pair of new pumps, and new buckles; which she had not on before.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What day of the month was this?</p>
               <p>Vialls. This was the twenty-eighth of June last, much about one o'clock in the day.</p>
               <p>Q. You say she took hold on your cloaths, and she pull'd you; did you chuse to have been from her?</p>
               <p>Vialls. I can't say that; but I had as lieve been at liberty, as to have came there.</p>
               <p>Q. How near to the Chequers was that house to which she carried you?</p>
               <p>Vialls. It was pretty near the Chequers; it is opposite to it in Chick-lane.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you obliged to go up stairs with her?</p>
               <p>Vialls. She push'd me up; so I was oblig'd to go up.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a watch was it?</p>
               <p>Vialls. It had silver cases, and a silver dial-plate.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you had it in your pocket, when you went into the ruinous place?</p>
               <p>Vialls. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. How soon did you miss it?</p>
               <p>Vialls. I miss'd it as soon as she was gone.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590711-14-person130">
                  William 
                  Saunders 
               <interp inst="t17590711-14-person130" type="surname" value="Saunders"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-person130" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-person130" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prosecutor came to my quarters, (I am a Soldier) at Mr Ashby's, the Globe and Dolphin, in Liquorpond-street; he was my landlord's acquaintance; he was complaining to him, how he had lost his watch; and said, he believ'd he could find the person at night, if he had any assistance: my landlord desir'd I would go along with him; I went with him to the Chequers in Chick-lane, there was the prisoner: My girl, said he, I believe you have got some of my watch on your head; I said to him; if he could make it appear, that she was the woman that stole the watch, she was my prisoner: she said, she would not go along with us, without a proper officer; he went for a constable, and left me to take care of her while he was gone; she desir'd me to let her go out to the door; I told her, she should not go, 'till he came; said she, let me go but to the door; I went to the door with her; then I said, the gentleman says, if you will confess where the watch is, if it cost him a guinea, or a guinea and a half, so that he can but get it again, he will not trouble you: she said, the watch is gone, and I do not know the person it is sold to; but she wished she could know the person; we stay'd 'till the prosecutor came back; he could not find a constable, so we took her to the Watch-house, and left her there with the constable.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I never saw either of these gentlemen in my life, before they came and took me up; the prosecutor took hold of three or four women, before he took hold of me; and said, I do not know who is the woman; one of the women that he laid hold of, said, what do you want with me? said he, you are the woman that took my watch; she said, are not you ashamed of yourself? then he went to another, and said, I believe this is she: then he laid hold of me; and said, he would swear to me; he carried me to the Watch-house directly; I was very willing to go along with him; the soldier drew out a naked sword upon me, and from the Watch-house, I was committed to the Counter.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590711-14-person131">
                  Hannah 
                  Armstead 
               <interp inst="t17590711-14-person131" type="surname" value="Armstead"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-person131" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-person131" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Thursday was se'nnight, the Prisoner at the bar, had her mother's hat on: her mother said to me, I wish you would be so good as to call upon my Hannah, and ask her for my hat. I went to the Chequers, and she was not there; a young woman there, said she was at such a house.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>Armstead. This was at ten in the morning: I went to her, and said, where is your mother's hat? said she, it is at the Chequers; said she, if I had money, I'd treat you with a pint of beer; I said, I have money: I told her, I was<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907110014"></xptr> going to Shoreditch, to tell my mistress I could not bring home any work 'till next week, and I would come back for the hat: then I went into Shoreditch, and came back again, at about half an hour after eleven; I staid with her, 'till within a quarter of four, and had four pints of beer.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this ?</p>
               <p>Armstead. This was at the Chequers in Chick-lane: she never was out of my company, but only once, to go out into the yard to make water, (excuse me) all that time.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you ? how do you get your livelihood?</p>
               <p>Armstead. My husband is a Tinman; he works in Fleet-street, at Mr Monkland's.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Armstead. I live in Stonecutter-street, in the New-market, at Mrs Graham's, a Mantua-maker; we dined together at that house in Chick-lane, that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was your husband?</p>
               <p>Armstead. He was at work.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does he dine?</p>
               <p>Armstead. He goes to an Ale-house commonly, every day, to dine.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to go to an ale-house in Chick-lane?</p>
               <p>Armstead. I went there for her mother's hat; and she said, I'll be with my mother at four o'clock, and bring it; the next morning, I heard she was in trouble; as for the hat, I can bring proof where that was bought.</p>
               <p>Q. What had you for dinner ?</p>
               <p>Armstead. We had a piece of boiled buttock of bee f, and cabbage; and the people of the house had beans and pickled pork.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. Can you swear the prisoner at the bar, is the same woman that was with you in that empty house?</p>
               <p>Vialls. She is the same woman.</p>
               <p>Q. About what time can you say, it was, that you missed your watch?</p>
               <p>Vialls. It was much about one o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see this evidence that day?</p>
               <p>Vialls. No; I never saw her, 'till I saw her in the Counter, the next morning, with the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. to Armstead. Who saw you together at that time?</p>
               <p>Armstead. The people of the house.</p>
               <p>Q. Where are they? are they here?</p>
               <p>Armstead. They are none of them here. [A messenger is sent to fetch the man and woman, that keep the Chequer Ale-house; they soon came into court.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590711-14-person132">
                  Thomas 
                  Freeman 
               <interp inst="t17590711-14-person132" type="surname" value="Freeman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-person132" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-person132" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner, I believe, ten years, and more.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her character?</p>
               <p>Freeman. It is that of an honest, industrious woman.</p>
               <p>Q. What does she get her living by?</p>
               <p>Freeman. She gets her living about the streets, by buying and selling old cloaths; I never heard any thing dishonest of her, 'till this; and it was so great a shock to me, when I heard it, that I could hardly contain myself; I was with the prosecutor to-day, and he said she was a very wicked creature; I ask'd him how he came to want to make it up with her, if she was wicked ?</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know he wanted to make it up?</p>
               <p>Freeman. Her mother told me so.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. This witness I never saw 'till today; he told me he was own brother to the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Freeman. I said she is my sister-in-law.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590711-14-person133">
                  Mary 
                  Lee 
               <interp inst="t17590711-14-person133" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-person133" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-person133" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the prisoner's mother.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of the prosecutor?</p>
               <p>Lee. I never saw him in my life. I never knew my daughter to behave amiss, or wrong man, woman, or child, in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. How does she get her livelihood?</p>
               <p>Lee. She buys and sells old cloaths.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590711-14-person134">
                  Mary 
                  Waters 
               <interp inst="t17590711-14-person134" type="surname" value="Waters"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-person134" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-person134" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner and I were children together; I am no relation; I never heard any body say any thing amiss of her in my life; she buys and sells old cloaths, and bears the character of an honest woman.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of the prosecutor?</p>
               <p>Waters. I never saw him in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590711-14-person135">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Armstead 
               <interp inst="t17590711-14-person135" type="surname" value="Armstead"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-person135" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-person135" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about two years and a half.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her general character?</p>
               <p>Armstead. I never heard any thing amiss of her in my life before this time; I have been a shop-mate with her father-in-law this two years.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907110015"></xptr>For the crown.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590711-14-person136">
                  James 
                  Carden 
               <interp inst="t17590711-14-person136" type="surname" value="Carden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-person136" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-person136" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Chequer-Alehouse in Chick-lane.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know 
               <persName id="t17590711-14-person137">
                  Hannah 
                  Armstead 
               <interp inst="t17590711-14-person137" type="surname" value="Armstead"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-person137" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-person137" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Carden. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you recollect what company you had at your house last Thursday was se'nnight ?</p>
               <p>Carden. I have great reason to remember that day, for if it had not been for me the prisoner had been rescued; she was taken up at my house.</p>
               <p>Q. When did the prisoner at the bar come into your house first that day ?</p>
               <p>Carden. She first came in about nine o'clock at night: I know the prosecutor took her before the Watch was set, and she refused to go along with him; I told him he himself was a proper officer to take up a thief wherever he found her; and if he wanted any assistance I would assist him; at last she got out at the door; there the soldier stood over her while the prosecutor went for an officer; in a minute's time I heard a mob about the door; I ran out to the soldier for him to make use of his sword; and said, if he did not very smartly, they would rescue her. I assisted him from the door all the way up the court, and there I left him.</p>

               <p>Q. Had the prisoner ever used to dine at your house?</p>
               <p>Carden. She has come into my tap-room.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you recollect her dining at your house that day?</p>
               <p>Carden. I do not recollect her coming into my house that day, 'till the men came in and charged her.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she not in your house in the forenoon?</p>
               <p>Carden. I cannot be positive that she was; to the best of my knowledge she came into my house first, about a quarter of an hour before the prosecutor came in and took her.</p>
               <p>Q. Look well at the evidence 
               <persName id="t17590711-14-person138">
                  Hannah 
                  Armstead 
               <interp inst="t17590711-14-person138" type="surname" value="Armstead"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-person138" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-person138" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; was she in your house that day?</p>
               <p>Carden. I really cannot be sure.</p>
               <p>Q. If the prisoner and she had come into your house, and dined on a piece of boiled beef that day, and staid between four and five hours together, should not you have remembered it?</p>
               <p>Carden. Yes, I should: but I do not remember the prisoner being in my house that day, 'till about a quarter of an hour before she was taken up by the prosecutor.</p>
               <p>Q. What had you for dinner that day?</p>
               <p>Carden. I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you boiled beef ?</p>
               <p>Carden. I think I had not: the season is partly over for boiled beef.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you had not a buttock of beef ?</p>
               <p>Carden. I have not had a buttock of beef in my house this twelve months.</p>
               <p>[Mrs Carden having been put out of court the time her husband was giving his evidence, was called in and sworn.]</p>
               <p>Mrs Carden. The prisoner at the bar was taken up at my house.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at home all that day?</p>
               <p>Mrs Carden. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body besides your own family dine at your house that day?</p>
               <p>Mrs Carden. No, not to my own knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. If the prisoner had dined at your house that day, and spent about four hours there, do you think you should not remember it?</p>
               <p>Mrs Carden. The prisoner never in her life dined in my house except on bread and cheese.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember Hannah Armstead being at your house?</p>
               <p>Mrs Carden. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember she and the prisoner at the bar dined that day at your house?</p>
               <p>Mrs Carden. That I cannot say: I can't remember whether she did or not, I have too many in my family.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner in your house from one o'clock that day 'till she was taken up?</p>

               <p>Mrs Carden. No, I am positive she was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at home from one o'clock 'till night?</p>
               <p>Mrs Carden. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. How long do you think she had been in your house before she was taken up?</p>
               <p>Mrs Carden. I believe she could not have been in our house above a quarter of an hour before: she was taken up about nine o'clock.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17590711-14-verdict79" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-verdict79" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-verdict79" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               Guilty of stealing, but not privately from his person
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The evidence 
               <persName id="t17590711-14-person139">
                  Hannah 
                  Armstead 
               <interp inst="t17590711-14-person139" type="surname" value="Armstead"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-person139" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-person139" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was committed for perjury, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17590711-14-punish80" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590711-14-punish80" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590711-14-defend127 t17590711-14-punish80"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
