<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570223-19">
               <interp inst="t17570223-19" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570223-19" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570223-19" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570223"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570223-19" type="date" value="17570223"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570223-19-off105-c129" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570223-19-defend166 t17570223-19-off105 t17570223-19-verdict109"></join>
         
               <p>112. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17570223-19-defend166" type="defendantName">
                     Gabriel 
                     Savoy 
                  <interp inst="t17570223-19-defend166" type="surname" value="Savoy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-19-defend166" type="given" value="Gabriel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-19-defend166" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17570223-19-off105" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570223-19-off105" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-19-off105" type="offenceSubcategory" value="housebreaking"></interp>
               breaking and entering the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17570223-19-victim168" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Moss 
                        <interp inst="t17570223-19-victim168" type="surname" value="Moss"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570223-19-victim168" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570223-19-victim168" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570223-19-off105 t17570223-19-victim168"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , on the <rs id="t17570223-19-cd106" type="crimeDate">21st of January</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570223-19-off105 t17570223-19-cd106"></join> in the day time, no person being therein, and stealing six silver teaspoons, value 12 s. one silver strainer, value 2 s. two table spoons, value 20 s. one milk pot, value 20 s. one silk gown, one stuff gown, one linen gown, one shirt, one neckcloth, and one pair of stays; the goods of the said William, in his dwelling house
            </rs>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570223-19-person169">
                  Mary 
                  Moss 
               <interp inst="t17570223-19-person169" type="surname" value="Moss"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-19-person169" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-19-person169" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My husband's name is William, we live in <placeName id="t17570223-19-crimeloc107">Montague-Court, Little-Britain</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17570223-19-crimeloc107" type="placeName" value="Montague-Court, Little-Britain"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17570223-19-crimeloc107" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570223-19-off105 t17570223-19-crimeloc107"></join>, he is a <rs id="t17570223-19-viclabel108" type="occupation">paper stainer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570223-19-victim168 t17570223-19-viclabel108"></join>; on the 21st of January I went to a house in our court which was in sight of my own door, coming back I stood talking to a neighbour and saw the prisoner come out at my door with a bundle.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you leave any body at home?</p>
               <p>M. Moss. I left a young woman there, and desired her when she went out to lock the door, and leave the key in a certain place in the window.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you been gone from home?</p>
               <p>M. Moss. I believe I was gone about ten minutes, or a quarter of an hour. I asked the prisoner what he did there. He said with some fighting speech, what is that to you. My neighbour said, he has strip'd your room. He ran down the court. I pursued him, and called stop thief. Two men stop'd him, and brought him to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your street door shut or open?</p>
               <p>M. Moss. It was open. The young woman said before the Lord-mayor, she locked my room door when she went away.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is she?</p>
               <p>M. Moss. She is not here.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you lose?</p>
               <p>M. Moss. The following things, which we found upon the prisoner, a white gown, a silk gown, a stuff gown, a pair of stays, a shirt, a neckcloth, 6 tea-spoons, 2 table spoons, and a milk pot. He said he would give me all my things if I would let him go, he beg'd for mercy on his knees. I asked him how he got into the room, he said, with his own keys; he had several keys found upon him.</p>
               <p>Five keys and two long spike nails produced in court. These I saw found upon him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you try to see if any of them would fit your lock?</p>
               <p>M. Moss. I did not try them, he wanted to conceal these keys under my bed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570223-19-person170">
                  Richard 
                  Nash 
               <interp inst="t17570223-19-person170" type="surname" value="Nash"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-19-person170" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-19-person170" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I tried these keys, but none of them would fit the lock, but one of these nails seems to have been used in wrenching the door open; there was a mark made much like what this would have made on the door and post.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570223-19-person171">
                  John 
                  Wayman 
               <interp inst="t17570223-19-person171" type="surname" value="Wayman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-19-person171" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-19-person171" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was the first man that laid hold of the prisoner. We carried him back to the prosecutor's house, and he deliver'd the things directly; he kneeled down by the bed and fell a crying, then took these keys out of his pocket, and was going to conceal them under the prosecutor's bed; we asked him how he open'd the door, he said with one of his own keys.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570223-19-person172">
                  John 
                  Craft 
               <interp inst="t17570223-19-person172" type="surname" value="Craft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-19-person172" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-19-person172" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the bottom of the court, when the woman call'd out stop thief. I pursued him. The other witness took him, and we brought him back, and he delivered the goods to the woman directly; he beg'd to be let go. I went to see for a constable, but could not find one in two parishes. When I came back, I was told they had found the keys; we took him to the Mansion-house and delivered him into Mr. Nash's custody. Upon the woman's saying where she ordered her key to be left, he said he open'd the door with her key.</p>
               <p>Q to M. Moss. Where did you find your key?</p>
               <p>M. Moss. I found it on the ground afterwards by the bed. It appeared my door had been wrench'd, there was a mark made seemingly with one of these nails.</p>
               <p>Q to Nash. Did that mark seem to have been fresh done?</p>
               <p>Nash. It did, and in a violent manner.</p>
               <p>Q to prosecutrix. What is the value of these goods?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. The two table spoons cost 13 s. each, the six tea-spoons 18 s. the milkpot 30 s. the strainer half a crown.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175702230012"></xptr>Q. Would the other things sell for 20 s.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I dare say they would and more.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570223-19-verdict109" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570223-19-verdict109" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17570223-19-punish110" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570223-19-punish110" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570223-19-defend166 t17570223-19-punish110"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
