<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17550116-26">
               <interp inst="t17550116-26" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550116-26" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550116-26" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550116-26" type="date" value="17550116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550116-26-off137-c232" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-26-defend284 t17550116-26-off137 t17550116-26-verdict141"></join>
         
               <p>77. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17550116-26-defend284" type="defendantName">
                     Solomon 
                     Gabriel 
                  <interp inst="t17550116-26-defend284" type="surname" value="Gabriel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-defend284" type="given" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-defend284" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for <rs id="t17550116-26-off137" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-off137" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-off137" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               that he on the <rs id="t17550116-26-cd138" type="crimeDate">9th day of December</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-26-off137 t17550116-26-cd138"></join>, about the hour of one in the night, on the same day, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17550116-26-victim286" type="victimName">
                           Benjamin
                            Mendez Decosta
                        <interp inst="t17550116-26-victim286" type="surname" value="Mendez Decosta"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550116-26-victim286" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550116-26-victim286" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                     
                  , did break and enter, and steal one silver lamp, value 6 l. five silver candlesticks, value 16 l. two other silver candlesticks, thirty-five silver table-knives, thirty-six silver-handle forks, one silver tea-pot, eighteen silver tea-spoons, one silver tea-strainer, one silver milk-pot, three silver waiters, two silver salts, two silver salt-spoons, one silver pepper-box, three table-cloths, three napkins, the goods of the said 
                     <persName id="t17550116-26-person287">
                        Benjamin Mendez 
                        Decosta 
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person287" type="surname" value="Decosta"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550116-26-person287" type="given" value="Benjamin Mendez"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550116-26-person287" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  ; one pair of silver shoe-buckles, one gold ring, with a bristol-stone, one gold ear-ring, one silver seal, one Pinchbeck metal seal, seven shirts, six pair of stockings, and six guineas, the property of 
                     <persName id="t17550116-26-victim288" type="victimName">
                        Sampson 
                        Levi 
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-victim288" type="surname" value="Levi"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550116-26-victim288" type="given" value="Sampson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550116-26-victim288" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   , <rs id="t17550116-26-viclabel139" type="occupation">Gent.</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-26-victim288 t17550116-26-viclabel139"></join> in the dwelling-house
            </rs> of the said Benjamin. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-26-person289">
                  Levi 
                  Woolf 
               <interp inst="t17550116-26-person289" type="surname" value="Woolf"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person289" type="given" value="Levi"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person289" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Saturday was seven weeks one 
               <persName id="t17550116-26-person290">
                  Joseph 
                  Elias 
               <interp inst="t17550116-26-person290" type="surname" value="Elias"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person290" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person290" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (he goes by the name of Joe the old-cloaths-man) came to me to know where he could get a ladder a story and half high, I said I would see for one. He came the whole week every day to see if I had got one. The week following I met him in Camomile-street; he asked me, how I came to disappoint him? I said, to-morrow is Monday, give me money, I'll borrow one. That Sunday was six weeks, at nine in the morning, he came to me again in Duke's-place, and said, don't trouble yourself about a ladder, for I have got one; and asked me, where I would be at night? I said, I shall be here puddling about; you may see me all day long. Between five and six in the evening, he and 
               <persName id="t17550116-26-person291">
                  Solomon 
                  Gabriel 
               <interp inst="t17550116-26-person291" type="surname" value="Gabriel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person291" type="given" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person291" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the prisoner came to me; we went all three together behind the back-part of alderman Gascoyne's brewhouse, there Joe the old-cloaths-man and I took up a ladder, and carried it across Little-duke's-place, and Broad-court, and hung it up in a dark entry in a thoroughfare; then they went away, and told me, I must be at the Nag's-head in Houndsditch at eleven o'clock at night. I went; there was Elias, who told me Joe was at the King's-arms. I sat down and drank with him; he said, do you know what we are going to do? We are going to get over a wall in <placeName id="t17550116-26-crimeloc140">James's-court</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17550116-26-crimeloc140" type="placeName" value="James's-court"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550116-26-crimeloc140" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-26-off137 t17550116-26-crimeloc140"></join>, and break Mr. 
               <persName id="t17550116-26-person292">
                  Benjamin Mendez 
                  Decosta 
               <interp inst="t17550116-26-person292" type="surname" value="Decosta"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person292" type="given" value="Benjamin Mendez"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person292" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's house, the back part of it, and said he had got an information on a card in his pocket, that the footman had given him, with the dimensions of the house and rooms, and how to get into it. He said, you must get over the wall. I said, I will do any thing in the world to serve you; but I cannot get over the wall, I am so stiff and clumsy. He took the card out of his pocket, and said, there is a glass window, ten to one if the shutters are shut, then we can get up the glass, and the footman says there is no company in the house. Then he said, let us go to Joe, and ask him. We went; Joe told me, they did not want me to get over, they were two good hands themselves. Then it was proposed I should stand without, and receive what they brought out. Solomon said, you can't expect a whole share. Well, said I, g ive me what you think proper; but I deserve something. He said, you shall have a guinea, or a guinea and a half. I said, I am content. They said, may-be they might give me more. We went to the place where the ladder hung; we staid till the watchman had gone past twelve. Solomon went and got up to a lamp, and lighted up a dark lanthorn; then Joe came and gave us an order to come with the ladder, which we carried to James's-court, and set it against the wall; they two went over, and bad me walk about there and watch. They pulled the ladder up, and I shoved as far as I could; and they set it down on the other side. After some time they came over again; they had a great broad bag, which they set on the ground, and as they were putting their shoes on, I looked into the bag, there I saw many silver-handled knives and forks, silver candlesticks, a silver sabbath-lamp, which we light up on Friday nights, silver spoons, and linen between them, that they might not chink. One of them said to me, are not you ashamed to look in it in the street? I said, but I will look, that you shall not cheat me afterwards out of my share, and say you have had nothing. Then Joe and I took the ladder, and went over Duke's-place, and the prisoner carried the bag. After that, we changed, and I carried the bag. Solomon said he had borrowed the ladder of a neighbour, and if it was not carried safe, it would blow us. The watchman coming round in Duke's-place, calling one o'clock, we dropt the ladder, and went all three together to shoemaker-row; we went through Aldgate, and carried the bag into Joe's lodgings, facing alderman Gascoyne's brewhouse; there he bid us stay, and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175501160028"></xptr> said he would come out in less than two minutes. He came out, and said, here is a shilling for you to drink. Solomon bid me go to my mistress's house, and he would call on me in less than half an hour. They both came there, to me; then we contrived to go and put the ladder in its place. We went there, and there stood two watchmen by it, so we let it lie. Solomon went home and lay with me. In the morning about six we got up; he said he would go to Joe. I got up to go to work, and met with Solomon (he is a painter); he ordered me to come to him about six, and said they would satisfy me. I went at the time to the place appointed, that is Marcelous's coffee-house. There they came to me, and took me to the Wool-pack; Joe gave me a thirty-six-shilling piece. I said, I thought I was to have four guineas. Said he, can't you have patience? The goods are not all sold yet; when they are, we'll satisfy you. I parted from them, and went after them the next Wednesday, and found they were gone; then on the Thursday I went to the constable, hearing there was suspicion of me, and surrendered myself.</p>
               <p>Q. How high was the wall?</p>
               <p>L. Woolf. That was about a story high; there was a yard betwixt that and the house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-26-person293">
                  Clare 
                  Isaac 
               <interp inst="t17550116-26-person293" type="surname" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person293" type="given" value="Clare"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person293" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am cook to Mr. Decosta; I was the first person that came into the kitchen the next morning, betwixt five and six o'clock; I found the window open.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it fast over-night?</p>
               <p>C. Isaac. The window-shutters were closed, but one shutter was not bolted; I always have the care of them; and that was the window I found open. We frequently left them unbolted; we did not think any body could come in that way, except they had intelligence from somebody in the house; the Sashes were shut down.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you miss?</p>
               <p>C. Isaac. The first things I missed were three silver candlesticks, and a table-cloth from the kitchen table. Then I called my other fellow-servant down; he came, and went backward, and found the pantry broke open; there lay a whole heap of chips broke from the door; I suppose it was done with the kitchen-poker, for I found that out of its place near the door. I can't tell what things were missing out of the pantry, because I have not them things under my care; I saw there was a drawer there open.</p>

               <p>Q. Who did these things you missed belong to?</p>
               <p>C. Isaac. They were Mr. Decosta's property.</p>
               <p>Sampson 
               <persName id="t17550116-26-person294">
                  Levi 
                  Gant 
               <interp inst="t17550116-26-person294" type="surname" value="Gant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person294" type="given" value="Levi"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person294" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Decosta; after the last witness had found the house had been robbed, she sent up for me; I came down, and found the pantry-door broke open, out of which I missed two large silver candlesticks, two silver tea-candlesticks, the nozles were pewter; one silver tea-pot, three little silver waiters, eighteen silver tea-spoons, one silver strainer, fourteen large silver table-spoons, one large silver soup-ladle, thirty-five silver-handle knives, thirty-six silver-handle forks, two silver salt-tellers, two silver salt-shovels, a little silver pepper-box, a silver sabbath-lamp, which we light up on Friday nights; there are seven pipes in it to burn; my master's name, with the weight, was engraved on all the silver. I missed also three table-cloths, three napkins; the drawer in which these things were put was broke open; they were my master's property. I missed my purse from thence, in which were two gold rings, one had Bristol-stones set it, one gold ear-ring, two seals, a pair of silver shoe-buckles, five guineas, six or seven shirts, and six or seven pair of stockings; these were my property.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever heard of any of these goods again?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-26-person295">
                  S.
                   Levi Gant
               <interp inst="t17550116-26-person295" type="surname" value="Levi Gant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person295" type="given" value="S."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person295" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . No, we had not. The evidence Woolf was taken on the Thursday after the fact was committed, and the prisoner was taken on a Sunday, three weeks ago; I was with the prisoner before alderman Porter, there he confessed he was in the yard, and stood in the kitchen-window while 
               <persName id="t17550116-26-person296">
                  Joe 
                  Elias 
               <interp inst="t17550116-26-person296" type="surname" value="Elias"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person296" type="given" value="Joe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person296" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             broke the pantry-door open, that is, a door next to the kitchen; he also said, one of the window-shutters they found bolted, the other was not, and they shoved up the sash, and Joe went in.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he mention what goods were taken?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-26-person297">
                  S.
                   Levi Gant
               <interp inst="t17550116-26-person297" type="surname" value="Levi Gant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person297" type="given" value="S."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person297" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He said he saw my shoe-buckles; and that he carried the bundle, but he did not see the other things, and Elias sold them all, and he had but three guineas for his share.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-26-person298">
                  William 
                  Lamb 
               <interp inst="t17550116-26-person298" type="surname" value="Lamb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person298" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person298" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watchman; on the 10th of December as I was calling the hour one I heard some people talking behind me, I staid till they came up to me, there were three men, and the last of the three had a bag on his back, with something in it; I held up my lanthorn and looked at them; I heard the first call upon God to d - n the other, saying, they had kept him too long; the other watchman that called the hour with me called halloo, I said, what is the matter? I went to him, there lay a ladder under a gateway, at the bottom of Cree-church-lane, we<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175501160029"></xptr> took it to the watch-house and went out again in quest of the people that had laid it there; finding nobody, we went into Shoemaker-row, as we were there, there came three men from Aldgate way, we followed them across Broad-court to a barber's house in Duke's-place, they knocked at the door, one went in and bid the other two a good night; we followed them, but it being dark they got from us.</p>
               <p>Lion Toby. I am a constable; on the Tuesday morning that this robbery was committed, I was sent for to Mr. Decosta's, he said, he had been robbed, and desired me to see if I could find the persons that did it; the first thing I discovered was where the ladder was hid for that purpose; knowing the person that had that, I laid hold on him, which was the evidence, and told him he was concerned in the affair; his master whom he worked for, said, come, come, we must do our business, and he took him away; in about an hour after he came again, and said, here, I shall have a scandal upon me, they say I am concerned, then I secured him and sent for my watchman, and when the evidence saw him he was all on a tremble, and fainted away, after that he was examined before Mr. alderman Porter, then he denied he knew any thing of the affair; the alderman said to Mr. Decosta, the best thing will be to get his majesty's pardon for the person that will discover it, which the alderman was as good as his word to get for him, accordingly it was printed in the Gazette, after which the evidence made a discovery, I took him before Mr. alderman Porter, there he impeached the prisoner and Joe the old-cloaths-man, as being concerned with him in it; sometime after that, there came a fellow from the country, and told me the prisoner was there, and if I would take him I might, I went as directed, and took him at Whetstone, he was shocked when I told him of it, and he opened the whole affair to me and others; when we were on the road he confessed he had borrowed the ladder of a person in his master's name, and that they three (he, Joe the old-cloaths-man and the evidence conveyed the ladder to the wall, and that he and Joe got upon it, and the evidence helped them over with the ladder, and they went down on the other side, and the evidence stood watching, and that some time after they came over again with a bag full of silver, and that Joe the old-cloaths-man did not use him well, because he gave him but three guineas, and bid him go and travel in the country with that, and he'd see how he could reward him, and that he bought himself some hard-ware to sell in the country; when I took him he had some hard-ware upon him, but I found no plate; we carried him on the Friday following before Mr. alderman Alexander, there he made his confession, and owned it all, and I think it was on the Thursday after that he owned the same before Mr. alderman Porter.</p>
               <p>Q. How came he to be so open in his confession on the road?</p>
               <p>L. Toby. He told me he hoped he should be admitted an evidence. I said I can't promise you such a thing, for there is one taken already.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-26-person299">
                  Samuel 
                  Fulk 
               <interp inst="t17550116-26-person299" type="surname" value="Fulk"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person299" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person299" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner came to me and shewed me three guineas, and said, I must go along with him to sell goods for him, I went with him about six or eight miles, and on the road he told me the whole story, that on the Wednesday morning he carried a ladder which he had helped the others to, and went over the wall with one of them, and they did the robbery, and had the three guineas paid him for it; I said I would not go any farther with him, fearing trouble, so I came and told the constable, and went with him on the Sunday morning when he took the prisoner at Whetstone, after that he told the constable the same in my hearing.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>Joe Elias came to me and asked me to lend him a ladder for two hours. I asked him what he wanted it for, he said, it was to learn a young woman to balance; I went and took the ladder from my master's work and lent it to him, he said he would pay me for it; after the two hours were over I went for it, he said he did not know what he had done with it, he could not find it; I went into the next alley in Hounsditch, there I found 
               <persName id="t17550116-26-person300">
                  Joe 
                  Elias 
               <interp inst="t17550116-26-person300" type="surname" value="Elias"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person300" type="given" value="Joe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person300" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Lion Woolf, and Lion Saunders together at the Nag's-head. I asked him for the ladder, they made me drink, and said, I should have it the next morning; I went away, and came again the next morning; I saw Lion Saunders in the street, and asked him where 
               <persName id="t17550116-26-person301">
                  Joe 
                  Elias 
               <interp inst="t17550116-26-person301" type="surname" value="Elias"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person301" type="given" value="Joe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person301" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was; he said he knew where, and he would come to me in the afternoon, and I should be paid for the ladder. I said, where is he? I wanted to speak with him, he said, he could not bring him to me till the afternoon, and in the afternoon I met them all three together, I wanted to mob them in the street for my ladder, they called me into an alehouse, and said they would pay me for it, and 
               <persName id="t17550116-26-person302">
                  Joe 
                  Elias 
               <interp inst="t17550116-26-person302" type="surname" value="Elias"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person302" type="given" value="Joe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person302" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave me three guineas<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175501160030"></xptr> in my hand, and bid me go and pay for the ladder. I said, I cannot go to my master, what shall I do, he will transport me for it? Said he, go and get some goods and go into the country; he said, I should take somebody with me, so I took that young fellow to a place at Aldgate, and laid out about fifty shillings in hard-ware, and went the next day into the country, and met with another young man, and he had some goods and we put them together, I thought no harm.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-26-person303">
                  Daniel 
                  Mentz 
               <interp inst="t17550116-26-person303" type="surname" value="Mentz"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person303" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person303" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner upwards of three years, he has done jobs for me, I thought him to be an honest young man, had he been otherwise he might have stole forty or fifty pounds from me in plate. I never suspected him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-26-person304">
                  Charles 
                  Legg 
               <interp inst="t17550116-26-person304" type="surname" value="Legg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person304" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I employed the prisoner about a month or six weeks; about four months ago, he behaved very well with me as far as I could find. I know no more of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-26-person305">
                  Jenny 
                  Coban 
               <interp inst="t17550116-26-person305" type="surname" value="Coban"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person305" type="given" value="Jenny"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person305" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner has been my lodger twice; I never found but he was an honest man.</p>
               <p>Hart Michael. I am a master-painter; the prisoner has been with me upwards of three years, off and on, he behaved very honest to me in a great many gentlemens houses, where was money and goods, he was always honest and true, and a hard-working fellow.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-26-person306">
                  Moses 
                  Barnet 
               <interp inst="t17550116-26-person306" type="surname" value="Barnet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person306" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-person306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about twelve months, I always knew him to be a very honest man, and never knew any thing amiss of him.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17550116-26-verdict141" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550116-26-verdict141" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
