<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17590117-29">
               <interp inst="t17590117-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590117-29" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590117-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17590117"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590117-29" type="date" value="17590117"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17590117-29-off173-c232" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590117-29-defend289 t17590117-29-off173 t17590117-29-verdict175"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17590117-29-off173-c233" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590117-29-defend291 t17590117-29-off173 t17590117-29-verdict175"></join>
         
               <p>92, 93. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17590117-29-defend289" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Falkner 
                  <interp inst="t17590117-29-defend289" type="surname" value="Falkner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-defend289" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-defend289" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17590117-29-defend291" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Fielder 
                  <interp inst="t17590117-29-defend291" type="surname" value="Fielder"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-defend291" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-defend291" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17590117-29-off173" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-off173" type="offenceCategory" value="miscellaneous"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-off173" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pervertingJustice"></interp>
               unlawfully aiding 
                     <persName id="t17590117-29-person292">
                        Abraham 
                        Jones 
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person292" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590117-29-person292" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590117-29-person292" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , who had been committed to Wood-street Counter, on suspicion of felony, to make his escape from the said Counter
            </rs>, <rs id="t17590117-29-cd174" type="crimeDate">November 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590117-29-off173 t17590117-29-cd174"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590117-29-person293">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Crompton 
               <interp inst="t17590117-29-person293" type="surname" value="Crompton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person293" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person293" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner Falkner was in my prison on the 16th of November; I had been out in the afternoon, I came home<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175901170019"></xptr> about ten at night, my man told me there was a prisoner escaped; I asked if he could tell who assisted? he told me he was sure that the prisoner was up in Falkner's room; I sent for Falkner, and asked him what he knew of it? at first, he said he knew nothing of it; at last, he said the cloaths were deposited in his room, and the man that was escaped was shaved in his room, and that he knew two hours before he would escape, or at least, attempt it.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the prisoner's name that escaped ?</p>
               <p>Crompton. His name was 
               <persName id="t17590117-29-person294">
                  Abraham 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17590117-29-person294" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person294" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person294" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner give you any reason why he knew he would attempt to escape?</p>
               <p>Crompton. No, he did not; I ask'd him how he could be so cruel as not to discover it to me, when he knew I had been so good to him; he turn'd himself round, and said, D - n it, it was nothing to him.</p>
               <p>Q. from Falkner. When you sent for me, do you think I was sober or fuddled?</p>
               <p>Crompton. I think he was in liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you say as to the other prisoner?</p>
               <p>Crompton. When I found the cloaths had been brought into Falkner's room, then I made enquiry who brought them there? and found that Fielder brought them there from Kensington.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he any business in your goal?</p>
               <p>Crompton. He came to a woman that is a prisoner there; I went to Kensington and made enquiry where I had been directed, and found he had given a receipt for the things.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear Fielder examined upon this?</p>
               <p>Crompton. He did not say in my hearing to what purpose he brought them. My man will give a farther account.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you find Jones's old cloaths?</p>
               <p>Crompton. They were found in a sack, which will be proved to be the same sack as the other cloaths were brought in, at the bottom of the stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is the commitment of 
               <persName id="t17590117-29-person295">
                  Abraham 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17590117-29-person295" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person295" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person295" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Crompton. Here it is, producing it. signed by the Lord Mayor.</p>
               <p>It is read in court.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590117-29-person296">
                  Thomas 
                  Chadwick 
               <interp inst="t17590117-29-person296" type="surname" value="Chadwick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person296" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person296" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17590117-29-person297">
                  Abraham 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17590117-29-person297" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person297" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person297" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was committed to Wood-street-compter by my Lord-Mayor, on Friday the 18th of November, on suspicion of felony, he was iron'd on one leg for security; on the Monday or Tuesday following Fielder at the bar came up to the gate with a bag a-cross his shoulder.</p>

               <p>Q. What day of the month?</p>
               <p>Chadwick. It was the 20th or 21st.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Chadwick. I am turnkey there; I felt on the out-side of it to see if I could perceive any spirituous liquours in it; I ask'd him what he had got in it; he said he had got some cloaths; I ask'd who they were for; he answered, I am going up to Falkner's room with them; he went in, and up to that room.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure he went into that room with them?</p>
               <p>Chadwick. He went that way.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was 
               <persName id="t17590117-29-person298">
                  Abraham 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17590117-29-person298" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person298" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person298" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             then?</p>
               <p>Chadwick. I saw him about 4 in the afternoon on the 26th of that month with his beard on, and his own slouch'd hat, and a great coat on, the same day he made his escape.</p>
               <p>Q. Who let him out?</p>
               <p>Chadwick. I believe I did, not knowing who I let out; I took him for a stranger, the old cloaths, that he had on then, were left in the bag that the other cloaths were brought in.</p>
               <p>Q. If he had appear'd at the gate in his old cloaths should you have let him out?</p>
               <p>Chadwick. No, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he let out in mens or womens cloaths?</p>
               <p>Chadwick. They were mens cloaths I believe.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590117-29-person299">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Young 
               <interp inst="t17590117-29-person299" type="surname" value="Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person299" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person299" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming down stairs just before 6 o'clock at night, and met the prisoner 
               <persName id="t17590117-29-person300">
                  Abraham 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17590117-29-person300" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person300" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person300" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I stopp'd at the head of the second pair of stairs to let him come by.</p>
               <p>Q. What day of the month was this?</p>
               <p>Young. It was on a Sunday-night; my room is up three pair of stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. Had Jones his irons on?</p>
               <p>Young. He had, and the cloaths as he usually wore; I went out of the goal and return'd again about 8 or a little after, then there was an alarm that 
               <persName id="t17590117-29-person301">
                  Abraham 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17590117-29-person301" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person301" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person301" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was got away.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see him after that ?</p>
               <p>Young. No.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175901170020"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17590117-29-person302">
                  Thomas 
                  Davidson 
               <interp inst="t17590117-29-person302" type="surname" value="Davidson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person302" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person302" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I draw beer for a gentleman in the compter that keeps the tap there; I have heard the prisoner Falkner talking amongst the rest of the prisoners say, that if he knew any man committed, that was for life and death he knew which way to let him out. This I have heard him say over and over again; I drew beer for 
               <persName id="t17590117-29-person303">
                  Abraham 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17590117-29-person303" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person303" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person303" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             at not quite 7 o'clock that evening that he was missing.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he dress'd?</p>
               <p>Davidson. He had then his old cloaths on</p>
               <p>Q. Was Falkner in that room that evening?</p>
               <p>Davidson. Yes, and Fielder too?</p>
               <p>Q. from Falkner. What time was I there ?</p>
               <p>Davidson. I don't know.</p>
               <p>Q. from Fielder. What time was I there?</p>
               <p>Davidson. I don't know.</p>
               <p>Falkner's defence. I am a poor debtor, and have been in that goal six months; I desire to be hang'd up now in the yard if I know any thing of it; they don't care what they swear against a poor debtor to clear themselves.</p>
               <p>Fielder's defence. That fellow that is gone out of the goal was in Falkner's room the Sunday before; he ask'd me to go of an errand for him; I said I would; he said it was to fetch him some cloaths; I went and brought them from his lodgings at Kensington, he sent a letter for every thing he had there; 2 shirts, 2 night-caps, 2 or 3 handkerchiefs, and other things; I brought them to him, he was standing on the foot of the stairs, I gave him the sack with all the cloaths in it, and where he carried them I don't know; he took his shoes out of the sack and brought them down and put them on, and gave Mr Chadwick his shoes which he had borrow'd of him, and Mr Chadwick charg'd him sixpence for the use of them.</p>
               <p>For Falkner.</p>
               <p>Mr Boudler. I have known Falkner twenty-one years; he lived in my neighbourhood in Black-Fryers; he has made shoes for me, and always used me very well.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you ?</p>
               <p>Boudler. I am a Carpenter.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Boudler. He is an honest man as far as I know.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590117-29-person304">
                  John 
                  Levet 
               <interp inst="t17590117-29-person304" type="surname" value="Levet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person304" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him many years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Levet. I never knew any ill of him.</p>
               <p>Mr Chillingsworth. I have known him 15 years or better.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Chillingsworth. He has bore a very good character of an industrious man in the neighbourhood; I never heard any thing against him 'till this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590117-29-person305">
                  William 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17590117-29-person305" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person305" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person305" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about eighteen or twenty years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character?</p>
               <p>Clark. I never knew any dishonesty by him, he has made and mended shoes for me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590117-29-person306">
                  Joshua 
                  Sparks 
               <interp inst="t17590117-29-person306" type="surname" value="Sparks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person306" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him eighteen years; he is counted a very honest man in the neighbourhood.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590117-29-person307">
                  John 
                  Jenkins 
               <interp inst="t17590117-29-person307" type="surname" value="Jenkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person307" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person307" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him fourteen or fifteen years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Jenkins. It is that of an honest man.</p>
               <p>For Fielder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590117-29-person308">
                  William 
                  Jenkins 
               <interp inst="t17590117-29-person308" type="surname" value="Jenkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person308" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-person308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Fielder a bout five years, he is a very honest man.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17590117-29-verdict175" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590117-29-verdict175" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
