<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510116-11">
               <interp inst="t17510116-11" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510116-11" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510116-11" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510116-11" type="date" value="17510116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510116-11-off47-c92" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-11-defend108 t17510116-11-off47 t17510116-11-verdict50"></join>
         
               <p>106. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17510116-11-defend108" type="defendantName">
                     Hugh 
                     Dunn 
                  <interp inst="t17510116-11-defend108" type="surname" value="Dunn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-defend108" type="given" value="Hugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-defend108" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17510116-11-off47" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-off47" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-off47" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               falsely forging and counterfeiting a certain paper writing, in the name of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17510116-11-victim110" type="victimName">
                           Charles 
                           Legrass 
                        <interp inst="t17510116-11-victim110" type="surname" value="Legrass"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510116-11-victim110" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510116-11-victim110" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   
                     <rs id="t17510116-11-viclabel48" type="occupation">Merchant of Yarmouth</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-11-victim110 t17510116-11-viclabel48"></join>, for the sum of 50 l. 18 s. 6 d. with intent to defraud 
                     
                        <persName id="t17510116-11-victim112" type="victimName">
                           George 
                           Nelson 
                        <interp inst="t17510116-11-victim112" type="surname" value="Nelson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510116-11-victim112" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510116-11-victim112" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17510116-11-cd49" type="crimeDate">Nov. 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-11-off47 t17510116-11-cd49"></join>.* </p>
               <p>George Nelson. Here is a Bill of Exchange that was brought inclosed, in a letter by one Wallice a porter, it came on the 1st of November in the evening, about 6 or 7 o'clock. I opened the letter, it was signed Sydne Stafford Smythe; the porter said, it came from one of the barons of the Exchequer, who lives in Cary-street. The contents to this purport.</p>
               <p>Please to pay the bearer the contents within, &amp;c. Cary-street, Sydnea Stafford Smythe. On the back of it was a Receipt wrote ready to sign.</p>
               <p>Received the contents, for the use of Sydnea Stafford Smythe, Esq; by me a blank left for the porter to write his name.</p>
               <p>I told the porter I had no advice of this Bill, and that it was a larger bill than what Mr. Legrass used to draw without advice.</p>
               <p>Q. Did it appear to you to be like Mr. Legrass's writing, or had you any doubt about it?</p>
               <p>Nelson. I then thought it was, but he happened to have a clerk in town, and I told the porter I chose to shew it to him before I paid it; so I told him to come the next day, being Friday, about 2 o'clock, and I'd endeavour to see the Clerk before that time; he came accordingly, but I had not seen the clerk, so I told him he must come<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175101160007"></xptr> again, which I ordered on Saturday any time between two and four; he came about six or seven; I staid at home till five, then went out of town, and had left word, if the porter came to appoint him to come again at 3 o'clock on the Tuesday following. He came at that time, and when he came I laid hold on him, and told him the bill he had in his hand was forged; he said he could not tell any thing about that, he was only sent with it. I told him he must produce the man he had it of, he said he could easily do that, saying, the man was at my gate at the same time. I said that did not appear well to me; nor to me neither said the porter, but he said to me he ow'd some of your men money, which was the reason he did not care to come himself; but said the porter, if you desire me, I'll fetch him in directly. I did not think that proper, because the porter was a stranger to me. So he described him to a servant of mine, 
               <persName id="t17510116-11-person113">
                  John 
                  Haynes 
               <interp inst="t17510116-11-person113" type="surname" value="Haynes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person113" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person113" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who went out and fetch'd him in: when they were both in my compting house, I asked the porter, whether that was the person that gave him the bill? The porter replied, yes, he sent me 4 times with it; then I asked the prisoner, if that was true? He said yes, and what then? I told him the bill was forged, and I believed he was concerned in it: and I sent for a constable; then he fell down on his knees, and begged very hard I would let him go. I told him for my own part I freely forgave the offence against me, but it was what I could not answer to the community.</p>
               <p>This is the identical bill, and had never been out of his custody.</p>
               <p>It was read in court to this purport.</p>
               <p>Yarmouth, Oct. 29, 1750.</p>
               <p>Pay to 
               <persName id="t17510116-11-person114">
                  Samuel 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17510116-11-person114" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person114" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; or order, the sum of 50 l. 18 s. 6 d. without further advice.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-11-person115">
                  Charles 
                  Legrass 
               <interp inst="t17510116-11-person115" type="surname" value="Legrass"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person115" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person115" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>I forgot mentioning this in my last.</p>
               <p>Directed to 
               <persName id="t17510116-11-person116">
                  George 
                  Nelson 
               <interp inst="t17510116-11-person116" type="surname" value="Nelson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person116" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person116" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-11-person117">
                  John 
                  Wallice 
               <interp inst="t17510116-11-person117" type="surname" value="Wallice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person117" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person117" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 1st of Nov. the prisoner at the bar came to the Bell alehouse in Friday-street, (I ply as a porter there) and inquired for a porter, and desired I would take a letter and go to Mr. Nelson's, saying, there was inclosed a bill of Exchange for 50 l. 18 s. 6 d. so I took the letter and carried it accordingly. He went on and varied in nothing from what Mr. Nelson had before deposed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-11-person118">
                  John 
                  Haynes 
               <interp inst="t17510116-11-person118" type="surname" value="Haynes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person118" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person118" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Mr. Nelson's servant, Mr. Nelson sent me out the 6th of November last, when the porter had described the prisoner; so I went and found him in Mr. Hotchkins's a grocer's shop, over-right my master's gate, he was looking towards my master's gate; I stepped into the shop and took him by the collar, and told him, he must go along with me; he seemed very much affrighted, and asked me where? I told him it was no matter where, he must go, and if I had wronged him I'd ask his pardon. I took him to my master's house; as soon as the porter saw him, said he to me, you are right, that is the man; then my master sent me for a constable ; I know no more.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I had the misfortune to become acquainted with one Mr. Oroath, I was clerk to my uncle Mr. Kelley. I being an intire stranger to him, he appeared very genteel, with lac'd cloaths, &amp;c. I did not suspect any ill from him. He came into my office on the 1st of November, where I was writing, the servant of the house was then with me; he turned the servant out, fearing he should know the business; then he produced me this letter, and directed me to go and send a porter with it to Mr. Nelson, and told me the contents of the bill, and at the same time produced a note of 200 l, payable to himself, from one 
               <persName id="t17510116-11-person119">
                  John 
                  Chilton 
               <interp inst="t17510116-11-person119" type="surname" value="Chilton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person119" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person119" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , which I suppose he did in order to induce me to believe the bill to be a good one; what I did I was innocent of, not thinking it to be what it appears to be.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-11-person120">
                  John 
                  Carr 
               <interp inst="t17510116-11-person120" type="surname" value="Carr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person120" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person120" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner ever since he came to live with Mr. Kelley, which is I believe between two and three years; I have been intimate with him; really he was the last person that I should have thought guilty of forgery, nor did he appear to me to be necessitated.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does Mr. Kelley live?</p>
               <p>Carr. He is an attorney, and lives in Fetter-lane.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-11-person121">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Barker 
               <interp inst="t17510116-11-person121" type="surname" value="Barker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person121" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person121" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about three-years, ever since he came to England; I believe him to be as innocent a creature as ever came to England; I never heard any thing ill of him; he is constant and diligent in his business.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-11-person122">
                  Thomas 
                  Norris 
               <interp inst="t17510116-11-person122" type="surname" value="Norris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person122" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person122" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner between 2 and 3 years, and never heard any thing bad concerning him; he is one of the last I should think guilty of such a thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-11-person123">
                  Edmund 
                  Hanley 
               <interp inst="t17510116-11-person123" type="surname" value="Hanley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person123" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person123" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner almost 3 years; he is a very sober young fellow; I have received money of his master by his hand; I never saw him drink a glass of wine in my life.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175101160008"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-11-person124">
                  John 
                  Kelley 
               <interp inst="t17510116-11-person124" type="surname" value="Kelley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person124" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person124" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner better than a twelve month, he has a very good character; on the first of Nov. last Mr. Oroath came to master Kelley's house, he came through the passage into the office; I went into the office, he sat down next chair to the prisoner, he wanted me to leave the office, (which I did, and drew the door too after me) saying, he wanted the young man to do a private job for him, drawing forth a slip of paper from his pocket; after that I was called to bring a pair of scissars from above-stairs, I carried them, that is all I know of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-11-person125">
                  James 
                  Carrol 
               <interp inst="t17510116-11-person125" type="surname" value="Carrol"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person125" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person125" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner between two and three years, his master has often done business for me; I always looked upon him to be a sober lad. I believe him to have the least vice in him of any young man in England; I never could prevail upon him, when he came upon business, to drink so much as a glass of Wine, or a drop of porter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-11-person126">
                  Joseph 
                  Lethree 
               <interp inst="t17510116-11-person126" type="surname" value="Lethree"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person126" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person126" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him ever since he came to live with Mr. Kelley. He has frequently been at my house, I thought him to have been an honest sober young man; I have asked him to drink wine, but he never would with me.</p>
               <p>Mr. Edwards. I have known him about twelve months, I look upon him to be a modest sober young fellow.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-11-person127">
                  John 
                  Macoombe 
               <interp inst="t17510116-11-person127" type="surname" value="Macoombe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person127" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-person127" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about ten months, his character was that of a very sober young fellow; he has frequented my house.</p>
               <p>Counsel for the Crown.</p>
               <p>The prisoner has said in his defence, that he received this bill of exchange from Mr. Oroath, and the man was turn'd out of the office before he received any thing; and this man, who says he is a servant to Mr. Kelley, says he saw the gentleman give him a slip of paper; that is directly contrary to the prisoner's defence; and as to this Mr. Oroath, if it would have been of Service to them, they would have called him, he is now in Court.</p>
               <p>[The paper is put into Mr. Oroath's hand.]</p>
               <p>Mr. Oroath. I saw this at my Lord Mayor's, but never before, till I saw Mr. Nelson take it out of his pocket there; the prisoner at the bar had accused me, by sending a letter to his uncle, telling him, I was the person that gave him this draught. I came to my Lord Mayor, and brought a Gentleman who had seen me write, to prove it was none of mine. I had proof enough, and I believe was I to be at school 99 years, I could not write such a hand as that, neither did I ever hear talk of Yarmouth, till after this.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you deliver that paper to the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Oroath. No, I did not, the prisoner's uncle was my attorney. I had no intimacy with him, in my life time.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in his office on the 1st of Nov.?</p>
               <p>Oroath. I cannot be positive. I lodge just by Chancery-Lane, and as his uncle was my attorney, I used to be there sometimes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever desire the footman to go out of the room, when you was with the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Oroath. No, I never did at any time.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510116-11-verdict50" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-verdict50" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-verdict50" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               Acquit. of the forgery, Guilty of publishing it
            </rs>, <rs id="t17510116-11-punish51" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510116-11-punish51" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-11-defend108 t17510116-11-punish51"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
