<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17540717-55">
               <interp inst="t17540717-55" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540717-55" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540717-55" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540717"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540717-55" type="date" value="17540717"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540717-55-off274-c386" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-55-defend498 t17540717-55-off274 t17540717-55-verdict277"></join>
         
               <p>403. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17540717-55-defend498" type="defendantName">
                     Francis 
                     Collins 
                  <interp inst="t17540717-55-defend498" type="surname" value="Collins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-55-defend498" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-55-defend498" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17540717-55-off274" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540717-55-off274" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-55-off274" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one cloth coat, value 10 s. one cloth waistcoat, value 2 s. and one pair of cloth breeches
            </rs>, the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17540717-55-victim500" type="victimName">
                     Mary 
                     Magennis 
                  <interp inst="t17540717-55-victim500" type="surname" value="Magennis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-55-victim500" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-55-victim500" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-55-off274 t17540717-55-victim500"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17540717-55-viclabel275" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-55-victim500 t17540717-55-viclabel275"></join>, <rs id="t17540717-55-cd276" type="crimeDate">June 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-55-off274 t17540717-55-cd276"></join>*.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-55-person501">
                  Mary 
                  Magennis 
               <interp inst="t17540717-55-person501" type="surname" value="Magennis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-55-person501" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-55-person501" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The things mentioned in the indictment were pawned to me; I have had the waistcoat and breeches 2 years.</p>
               <p>Q. Who pawned them to you ?</p>
               <p>Magennis. One Steward did, He owed me 25 shillings, and left them with me, and told me if I wanted my money I night sell them before he came back. The coat a young man bought last Christmas, I lent him 5 s. to pay for it, it cost<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175407170038"></xptr> him 10; he bid me keep the coat till he could pay me, or to Tell it and pay myself. I went to felt them to the prisoner at the bar; he desired to try them on, and when he had them on his back a woman came in, and they had a word or two together : I took hold of him, and said, pray let me have the things, I got the coat and waistcoat, then I said let me have the breeches; he would not pull them off; but said his wife would pay me for them. I said, I will not trust your wife nor you neither, for she is another man's wife. He took the coat and waistcoat up stairs, and lay in my house all that night. The next morning, betwixt seven and eight o'clock, I went up to his room, and brought the coat and waistcoat down, but I never could get the breeches; he lay in them. I put the coat and waistcoat in a box in my shop, and did not know but they were there till about three weeks after.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to miss them then ?</p>
               <p>Magennis. 
               <persName id="t17540717-55-person502">
                  Richard 
                  Sullivan 
               <interp inst="t17540717-55-person502" type="surname" value="Sullivan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-55-person502" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-55-person502" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came into my house, and said, he met the prisoner very fine. I said, With what? He said with the coat and waistcoat upon him. Then I went and looked in my box, and found they were missing. I enquired after him, and found him in bed. I saw the breeches under his head. I took hold of them, and asked him where my coat and waistcoat were. He said, Don't make a noise, I'll go and get them. He took me to a pawnbroker, where he had pawned them, but they would not deliver them without the money. Then I went and got a constable, and went again for them, and then they denied they were there. For the Lord's sake, my lord, don't hang him.</p>
               <p>Q. from the prisoner. Did I not wear them publickly in the house?</p>
               <p>Magennis. No, never but that night.</p>
               <p>Q. from the prisoner. Did not you say before the Justice, if I would pay you 15 s. 6 d. for them, which you had sold them to me for, you'd never appear against me?</p>

               <p>Magennis. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-55-person503">
                  Catharine 
                  Sullivan 
               <interp inst="t17540717-55-person503" type="surname" value="Sullivan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-55-person503" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-55-person503" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the prisoner with the breeches on, and heard him promise payment for the cloaths at the same time.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he mention any time when he'd pay the money ?</p>
               <p>Sullivan. No, my Lord.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-55-person504">
                  John 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17540717-55-person504" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-55-person504" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-55-person504" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was constable, I served the warrant upon the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of the agreement talk'd of between them?</p>
               <p>Clark. No, I do not</p>
               <p>Q. from the prisoner. Did not you hear Mrs. Magennis say she would not prosecute me if I would pay her?</p>
               <p>Clark. I heard her say before Justice Chamberlain; if she had but her money it was all she required, and that she never wanted to carry on a prosecution against the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I proposed payment for these cloaths, and bought them of the prosecutrix; I then lodged in her house; after that I went to lodge with Mrs. Bready upon Snowhill. After some time I was taken ill, and was obliged to pawn them; then she came to me and asked me for the money. I said, if God spares me, and gives me health, I'll pay you. She said, You rogue, if you die I must lose them. She took the breeches from under my head, and swore she'd go and swear a robbery against me on the morrow. I said, Have patience, and don't take a poor man's life away. At last she came to be civil, and gave me the breeches again, and it was settled that I should pay her the money at such a time, and when the time came I could not; she goes and swears a robbery against me.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-55-person505">
                  William 
                  Lawrence 
               <interp inst="t17540717-55-person505" type="surname" value="Lawrence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-55-person505" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-55-person505" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prosecutrix told me the day after the bargain, she had sold 
               <persName id="t17540717-55-person506">
                  Frank 
                  Collins 
               <interp inst="t17540717-55-person506" type="surname" value="Collins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-55-person506" type="given" value="Frank"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-55-person506" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the cloaths for 15 s. 6 d.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know it was the day before that, that she sold them?</p>
               <p>Lawrence. Because she said, I sold 
               <persName id="t17540717-55-person507">
                  Frank 
                  Collins 
               <interp inst="t17540717-55-person507" type="surname" value="Collins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-55-person507" type="given" value="Frank"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-55-person507" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the cloaths yesterday; the cloaths were fitted on and delivered to him. After some little time she was dubious of getting the money, and she said to me, before she would be tricked out of the cloaths she would swear a robbery against the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-55-person508">
                  Ann 
                  Lawrence 
               <interp inst="t17540717-55-person508" type="surname" value="Lawrence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-55-person508" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-55-person508" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live over-against the prosecutrix; she keeps a chandler's shop; I went in there for some things I wanted; she said she had sold the prisoner at the bar a suit of cloaths, (I have forgot the price, but she told it me then;) she said she supposed she should have no money for them, and she did not expect it; but if he did not pay her, she said she would swear a robbery against him. I said in answer, You say you sold them, and the man says he'll pay you for them how can you go to swear a robbery against him if that is the case ?</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540717-55-verdict277" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540717-55-verdict277" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
