<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17550116-13">
               <interp inst="t17550116-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550116-13" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550116-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550116-13" type="date" value="17550116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550116-13-off68-c128" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-13-defend152 t17550116-13-off68 t17550116-13-verdict71"></join>
         
               <p>61. (M. 2.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17550116-13-defend152" type="defendantName">
                     Isaiah 
                     Robins 
                  <interp inst="t17550116-13-defend152" type="surname" value="Robins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-13-defend152" type="given" value="Isaiah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-13-defend152" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, <rs id="t17550116-13-off68" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550116-13-off68" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-13-off68" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               for that he on the King's highway on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17550116-13-victim154" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Richardson 
                        <interp inst="t17550116-13-victim154" type="surname" value="Richardson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550116-13-victim154" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550116-13-victim154" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-13-off68 t17550116-13-victim154"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175501160013"></xptr> corporal fear and danger of his life, and taking from his person one pair of silver shoe-buckles, value 10 s. one pair of knee-buckles, one linen neckcloth, one half-guinea, and 2 s. in money, numbered
            </rs>, his property, <rs id="t17550116-13-cd69" type="crimeDate">Dec. 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-13-off68 t17550116-13-cd69"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-13-person155">
                  Richard 
                  Richardson 
               <interp inst="t17550116-13-person155" type="surname" value="Richardson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-13-person155" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-13-person155" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . As I was coming down <placeName id="t17550116-13-crimeloc70">Whitechapel</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17550116-13-crimeloc70" type="placeName" value="Whitechapel"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550116-13-crimeloc70" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-13-off68 t17550116-13-crimeloc70"></join> a little past one o'clock in the morning, on the 19th of December, I saw the prisoner about 50 yards before me, and when I came by the Mount, as I was going towards Mile-end, I saw another man about thirty yards before him, they seemed to walk on, but not so fast as I did expect people at that time of the night; they kept at the same distance from each other; I kept my pace, and passed the prisoner a little before I came to Whitechapel-gaol, he then had his right-hand in his bosom, and his left hanging down. I passed betwixt the wall and him; he said, what o'clock is it master, I said the watch called past one; I had not walked above ten or a dozen yards before he called hip, he came running and overtook me, and clapped a pistol to my left-ear, and said, d - n your blood, you villain, deliver your money, and if you offer to molest, or speak a word, I'll blow your brains out; the other man came running back to me, and said, what is the matter? I desired the prisoner to spare my life, and said my money he was welcome to, and pulled it out and gave it into his hand. He said, d - n you, you scoundrel, here is nothing but half-pence; I said there is both gold and silver; he said, what gold? I said, half a guinea, he holding the pistol to my head all the time, said to the other man, search his pockets, seel for his watch; that man turned my pockets wrong-side out; then the prisoner said to him, examine his buckles, the man immediately stooped to my right-foot, taking the buckle out, said, are they silver? I said, no; he took it out, and perceiving the stamp, said, d - n you, you scoundrel, they are; then he took the other out, and likewise the buckles from my knees; then the prisoner said, I want a neckcloth, and took hold of mine and pulled it off, and held the pistol all the time to my face; at the time I looked him in the face, he said, d - n you, you scoundrel, if you look me down so I'll blow your brains out; then he clapped his hand to my left-shoulder, and said, go over the way, I went over, and my shoe came off, the prisoner followed me, and the other man followed him. I looked back, and said, for God's sake don't murder or disable me, I have got a wife and two small children; the prisoner said, I will not hurt a hair of your head, we rob a great many men and have not hurt one yet. After I came to the corner of Whitechapel-mount, I was obliged to come back again; I asked the prisoner where I was to go then? he said, behind the mount, and at a turnstile he bid me stand still, then he said, d - n the scoundrel, he says here is half a guinea, let us see; I and the other man stood close together, I don't know that I could know him, but as for the prisoner he had a short cockup hat on, with a sharp cock, thought I, I am sure of thee; he looked at the money and said, yes, here is half a guinea.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it light enough to discern him plain?</p>
               <p>R. Richardson. The moon was at the full, and shone a shadow.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by shadow?</p>
               <p>R. Richardson. It shone so as to see my shadow as I walked along.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain as to the prisoner?</p>
               <p>R. Richardson. I am very certain he is the man. I have nothing on my conscience about swearing to him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was in bed two hours before the time he swears I robbed him.</p>
               <p>R. Richardson. When we were before Sir 
               <persName id="t17550116-13-person156">
                  Samuel 
                  Gore 
               <interp inst="t17550116-13-person156" type="surname" value="Gore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-13-person156" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-13-person156" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Sir Samuel asked him how he lived, he said he had been about ten or a dozen days from sea. I was informed there was such a man used the Bull and Butcher in Rag-fair, I, 
               <persName id="t17550116-13-person157">
                  Paul 
                  Penrith 
               <interp inst="t17550116-13-person157" type="surname" value="Penrith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-13-person157" type="given" value="Paul"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-13-person157" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17550116-13-person158">
                  Thomas 
                  Blackmore 
               <interp inst="t17550116-13-person158" type="surname" value="Blackmore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-13-person158" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-13-person158" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             went there, it is a very bad house, there we saw the vilest of women in the house that ever I saw; there I saw the prisoner, I am sure he is the man. I went and told Sir 
               <persName id="t17550116-13-person159">
                  Samuel 
                  Gore 
               <interp inst="t17550116-13-person159" type="surname" value="Gore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-13-person159" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-13-person159" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and he recommended me to an officer, and we went and took him.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you described the man to them before you came there?</p>
               <p>R. Richardson. Yes, my lord, I had.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-13-person160">
                  Daniel 
                  Penrith 
               <interp inst="t17550116-13-person160" type="surname" value="Penrith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-13-person160" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-13-person160" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 30th of last month I and 
               <persName id="t17550116-13-person161">
                  Thomas 
                  Blackmore 
               <interp inst="t17550116-13-person161" type="surname" value="Blackmore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-13-person161" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-13-person161" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             went with the prosecutor to the Bull and Butcher, when the prisoner came in after we were there, the prosecutor told me that is the man at his coming in; we staid there till after he had dined, he laid down his head on the table and slept. Mr. Richardson went to Sir Samuel in order to get a warrant while we watched him, he returned with an officer, then we secured him.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the prosecutor given you a description of him before you came there ?</p>
               <p>D. Penrith. He had, and he answered exactly.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. Could you observe his cloaths at the time you was robbed?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175501160014"></xptr>Prosecutor. I could, they were the same he has on now, I saw them very perfectly.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-13-person162">
                  Thomas 
                  Blackmore 
               <interp inst="t17550116-13-person162" type="surname" value="Blackmore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-13-person162" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-13-person162" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was along with the prosecutor and the last evidence at the Bull and Butcher at the taking of the prisoner, when Mr. Richardson saw him put his head in at the door, he said that is the man; and as he had told us what sort of a man he was, I saw he answered that account; seeing us in the room he turned back, there was a woman in the room, she said he was her husband; she went out and brought him in, and set him down on the farther side of the room; in about ten minutes after she took up his dinner, he eat it and laid his head down on the table, and slept better than an hour, when he held up his head he went into the kitchen; I followed him to watch him till Mr. Richardson returned; I called for a tankard of beer, and desired them to put a bit of bread in it. I got the spit and toasted the bread. When Mr. Richardson came in we took him, and had him before Sir 
               <persName id="t17550116-13-person163">
                  Samuel 
                  Gore 
               <interp inst="t17550116-13-person163" type="surname" value="Gore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-13-person163" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-13-person163" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Gill, that took his trial to-day, owned that he did this robbery, and said he would own it in court, and would do me all the service he could.</p>
               <p>Q. to Blackmore. Was the prisoner in liquor in the alehouse at the time he was taken?</p>
               <p>T. Blackmore. I did not see that he was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there ever a back-door to that house?</p>
               <p>T. Blackmore. We well observed the house, there was no other door but that out into the street that he could get away at, there was a door into the yard, but we could not conceive he could get away that way without getting over a wall.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he see the prosecutor in the room where you was?</p>
               <p>T. Blackmore. Yes, he did, and went out, then the woman went and brought him in, and set him down in the farther part of the room. There were fourteen or sixteen women in the house who behaved very bad.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-13-person164">
                  Edward 
                  Kirk 
               <interp inst="t17550116-13-person164" type="surname" value="Kirk"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-13-person164" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-13-person164" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew the prisoner some years ago, he went then for a gentleman, but I have not known any thing of him for six or seven years last past.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17550116-13-verdict71" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550116-13-verdict71" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17550116-13-punish72" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550116-13-punish72" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-13-defend152 t17550116-13-punish72"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
