<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17580628-26">
               <interp inst="t17580628-26" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580628-26" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580628-26" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580628"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580628-26" type="date" value="17580628"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580628-26-off143-c188" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580628-26-defend234 t17580628-26-off143 t17580628-26-verdict146"></join>
         
               <p>245. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17580628-26-defend234" type="defendantName">
                     Anne 
                     Harrison 
                  <interp inst="t17580628-26-defend234" type="surname" value="Harrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-26-defend234" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-26-defend234" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17580628-26-deflabel142" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580628-26-defend234 t17580628-26-deflabel142"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17580628-26-off143" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580628-26-off143" type="offenceCategory" value="miscellaneous"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-26-off143" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pervertingJustice"></interp>
               conveying, and causing to be conveyed into the goal of <placeName id="t17580628-26-crimeloc144">Newgate</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-26-crimeloc144" type="placeName" value="Newgate"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-26-crimeloc144" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580628-26-off143 t17580628-26-crimeloc144"></join>, a frame saw, with intent to facilitate the escape of 
                     <persName id="t17580628-26-person235">
                        William 
                        Coffield 
                     <interp inst="t17580628-26-person235" type="surname" value="Coffield"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580628-26-person235" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580628-26-person235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  ,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175806280028"></xptr> then under sentence of transportation, without the privity of 
                     <persName id="t17580628-26-person236">
                        Richard 
                        Akerman 
                     <interp inst="t17580628-26-person236" type="surname" value="Akerman"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580628-26-person236" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580628-26-person236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , gent. keeper of the said goal
            </rs>, <rs id="t17580628-26-cd145" type="crimeDate">June 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580628-26-off143 t17580628-26-cd145"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>The record of the trial and conviction of 
               <persName id="t17580628-26-person237">
                  William 
                  Coffield 
               <interp inst="t17580628-26-person237" type="surname" value="Coffield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-26-person237" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-26-person237" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             read to this purport:</p>
               <p>The jurors present that 
               <persName id="t17580628-26-person238">
                  William 
                  Coffield 
               <interp inst="t17580628-26-person238" type="surname" value="Coffield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-26-person238" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-26-person238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , on the 4th of May, in the 31st year of the reign of our sovereign lord the king, did about the hour of two in the morning, on the same day, burglariously break and enter the dwelling-house of 
               <persName id="t17580628-26-person239">
                  Thomas 
                  Garret 
               <interp inst="t17580628-26-person239" type="surname" value="Garret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-26-person239" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-26-person239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and stealing out thence forty-six pair of silk-hose, value 20 l. twenty-eight pieces of silk, value 20 l. nine guineas, one half guinea, three 36 s. pieces, one moidore, and forty shillings in money numbered, the goods of the said Thomas.</p>
               <p>(See Numb. 213 in last paper.) That he puts himself on his country; jurors say guilty of grand larceny, not guilty of the burglary (no goods) to be transported for the term of seven years.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580628-26-person240">
                  Richard 
                  Akerman 
               <interp inst="t17580628-26-person240" type="surname" value="Akerman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-26-person240" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-26-person240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Gent. On the 1st of June I had an information that some of my prisoners, that were transports, were endeavouring to make their escape; there were at least twenty or thirty in a ward. After searching a little time, we found the bars almost saw'd through, and in eight different places, some quite through. We afterwards found a clock spring saw, (producing one.) This is it, it was buried under one of the planks, or barracks, which they lie upon, we found two or three pieces more of saws, that were broke. Some of the prisoners told me they were broke while we were searching. Upon this I ordered the prisoners to be secured. My turnkey told me that the wife of Coffield, one cast for transportation, brought in the saws. I ordered my servant, when the woman came to her husband, to stop her, which he did, and she readily confessed she brought in the saws to Coffield, which then she said was her husband.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you shew her this saw?</p>
               <p>Akerman. I did, she said she bought it, and her husband gave her the money. She said she was very sorry for what she had done. I asked her where she bought it, she said at the White-Lion, in a street at the upper end of Newgate-street. I took her with me there, and she went into a shop, and pitched on a young man that she said sold her the saw; (it was the White-Lion; Foster-Lane,) the young man compared it with the rest of his saws, which they have in half dozens, it appeared to be one of the same. I desired the young man to go along with me to my Lord-Mayor; there he said he believed he sold this saw to the woman at the bar; (he is here now, if there will be any occasion to examine him.) My Lord was a little dubious about committing the woman, as she said she was the wife of Coffield; she said she was asked at church, and married at Hanover-square. I took it down, and told her I should take the trouble of searching. She once or twice said she was his wife, at last she confess'd she was asked in the church to him, but never married to him.</p>
               <p>Q. It is necessary to ask you, because it is laid in the indictment, to be without your privity, did you consent to this saw being brought into Newgate ?</p>
               <p>Akerman. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580628-26-person241">
                  William 
                  Freeborn 
               <interp inst="t17580628-26-person241" type="surname" value="Freeborn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-26-person241" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-26-person241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was ordered by Mr. Akerman, my master, to stop the prisoner, as one of the prisoners had given information she had brought this saw into Newgate. She came in the morning, and I stopped her, and had her search'd, there was nothing found upon her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear her acknowledge she brought it into Newgate?</p>
               <p>Freeborn. I did, she said she brought it in to her husband.</p>
               <p>Q. Who found it?</p>
               <p>Freeborn. I did, under the barracks where they lie.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>My husband did not tell me what it was for.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580628-26-person242">
                  Mary 
                  Glassbrook 
               <interp inst="t17580628-26-person242" type="surname" value="Glassbrook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-26-person242" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-26-person242" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner is a neighbour of mine.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her general character?</p>
               <p>Glassbrook. I never saw any thing hurtful by her, she has a very good character.</p>
               <p>Q. How does she get her livelihood?</p>
               <p>Glassbrook. By doing plain-work, and teaching little children. She has behaved like a very prudent woman.</p>
               <p>Q. Is she a married woman?</p>
               <p>Glassbrook. She was, for what I know, to 
               <persName id="t17580628-26-person243">
                  William 
                  Coffield 
               <interp inst="t17580628-26-person243" type="surname" value="Coffield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-26-person243" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-26-person243" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175806280029"></xptr>Q. Where is he now?</p>
               <p>Glassbrook. I suppose he is now in Newgate.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580628-26-person244">
                  Martha 
                  Swannel 
               <interp inst="t17580628-26-person244" type="surname" value="Swannel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-26-person244" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-26-person244" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner six years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her general character?</p>
               <p>Swannel. I never knew any thing of her, but that she bore a very honest good character; I knew her husband, I did not know till lately but that he bore the same good character.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17580628-26-verdict146" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580628-26-verdict146" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
