<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570914-3">
               <interp inst="t17570914-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-3" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570914"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-3" type="date" value="17570914"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570914-3-off14-c49" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-3-defend53 t17570914-3-off14 t17570914-3-verdict21"></join>
         
               <p>300. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17570914-3-defend53" type="defendantName">
                  
                     John 
                     Bradbury 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17570914-3-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-3-defend53 t17570914-3-alias-1"></join>Bradley</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-3-defend53" type="surname" value="Bradbury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-3-defend53" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-3-defend53" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for that <rs id="t17570914-3-off14" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570914-3-off14" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-3-off14" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he in a certain field or open place, near the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17570914-3-victim56" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Stile 
                        <interp inst="t17570914-3-victim56" type="surname" value="Stile"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570914-3-victim56" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570914-3-victim56" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-3-off14 t17570914-3-victim56"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and taking from his person 6 s. his property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17570914-3-cd15" type="crimeDate">Aug. 26</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-3-off14 t17570914-3-cd15"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-3-person57">
                  William 
                  Stile 
               <interp inst="t17570914-3-person57" type="surname" value="Stile"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-3-person57" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-3-person57" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. How old are you?</p>
               <p>Stile. I am <rs id="t17570914-3-viclabel16" type="occupation">thirteen years of age</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-3-victim56 t17570914-3-viclabel16"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the nature of an oath ?</p>
               <p>Stile. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Suppose you were to forswear yourself in accusing the prisoner of a felony, what would become of you ?</p>
               <p>Stile. I should be d - 'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Stile. I <rs id="t17570914-3-viclabel17" type="occupation">belong to Christ's-Hospital; I am in the school there</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-3-victim56 t17570914-3-viclabel17"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you read your Bible ?</p>
               <p>Stile. I can, very well.</p>
               <p>Court. Give an account of what happen'd to you, and be sure say nothing but what is truth.</p>
               <p>Stile. I had been to my father's house at Charlton. Returning on the 26th of August to Christ's-Hospital, a little after three in the afternoon  I met the prisoner at the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you leave to go and visit your father ?</p>
               <p>Stile. I had.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you meet the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Stile. <placeName id="t17570914-3-crimeloc18">Between Twickenham and Isteworth, in a little narrow lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17570914-3-crimeloc18" type="placeName" value="Between Twickenham and Isteworth, in a little narrow lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17570914-3-crimeloc18" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-3-off14 t17570914-3-crimeloc18"></join>, He ask'd me whether I had been to see my friends.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Stile. He is a <rs id="t17570914-3-deflabel19" type="occupation">tinker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-3-defend53 t17570914-3-deflabel19"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that?</p>
               <p>Stile. By his budget and blackness. He had a bluish coat on.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he meet or overtake you?</p>
               <p>Stile. He first past by me, after that he went round and met me another way.</p>
               <p>Q. What answer did you make him ?</p>
               <p>Stile. I said yes. He ask'd me what money they gave me. I told him none. He said I should never come so far without my friends giving me some money. Then he search'd my pockets. Finding nothing there he pull'd off my shoes, and in one of them I had put six shillings, which he took.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell him where it was?</p>
               <p>Stile. No, I did not. He said if I made any noise he would kill me. Then he ran away towards the Thames. I ran home to the hospital as fast as I could, and told a man in Isleworth fields of what had happen'd, but don't know who it was. I have three brothers that live in London. I told one of them of this robbery (he lives in Aldermanbury, an apprentice to a chair carver) the same night. He went on the Saturday night to my father's house, and, as he told me, gave him a description of the person that had rob'd me. After which my brother came and fetch'd me from London. I went, and they had taken the prisoner up, I saw him, and knew him to be the same man that had rob'd me.</p>
               <p>Q. Who took up the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Stile. My brother that lives with a farmer at Walton.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you see him?</p>
               <p>Stile. I saw him at Moulsey.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he dressed ?</p>
               <p>Stile. He was dressed just the same as now, with a blue patch'd coat on, and a long brown stick.</p>
               <p>Q. In what capacity is your brother at Walton?</p>
               <p>Stile. He lives with a farmer there.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you by this money?</p>
               <p>Stile. My father gave me a shilling, my mother another, my cousin Stile, who is a farmer just by my father, gave me a shilling: my cousin Lenton, at Sunbury-Green, gave me a shilling; madam Brest gave me a shilling, and my cousin Spencer, at Hampton-Court, gave me a shilling.</p>
               <p>Q. Had not you talk'd something to the man that your friends had given you some money?</p>
               <p>Stile. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was he committed to?</p>
               <p>Stile. He was committed to Kingston Gaol.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175709140004"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-3-person58">
                  Isaac 
                  Stile 
               <interp inst="t17570914-3-person58" type="surname" value="Stile"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-3-person58" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-3-person58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Charlton, in the parish of Sunbury; I am father to the lad. My son came to my house on the Thursday, and return'd on the Friday, the day he was rob'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you more sons than this?</p>
               <p>I. Stile. I have three sons in London. One of them, who is an apprentice to a chair carver in Aldermanbury, told me this had been rob'd coming to town, and described what sort of a man it was that rob'd him. My other son took the prisoner as he was begging in Walton church-yard. Then I went and fetch'd this witness from London, to see if it was the person that rob'd him. As soon as he saw him he said it was the same man; we took him to Kingston, to Mr. Rowl, and he committed him.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of any money he had?</p>
               <p>I. Stile. My wife and I gave him a shilling each, my landlord's mother gave him a shilling, a farmer his nephew gave him a shilling, a butcher (named Spencer, who married my niece) gave him a shilling, and a relation that keeps the sign of the George gave him a shilling.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see where he put it?</p>
               <p>I. Stile. He put it in his pocket, I believe.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of his putting it in his shoe?</p>
               <p>I. Stile. No, I did not, till he told me he had put it there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-3-person59">
                  Thomas 
                  Bliss 
               <interp inst="t17570914-3-person59" type="surname" value="Bliss"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-3-person59" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-3-person59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable. I was charged with the prisoner, and took him before justice Rowl. The boy said the same there as here. The tinker could not contradict it, but was in different stories, as to where he had been the day of the robbery.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I never saw the lad in my life, till I saw him at Moulsey. I am <rs id="t17570914-3-deflabel20" type="occupation">a piece of a brasier, and go from farm house to farm house, to mend brass saucepans and such things</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-3-defend53 t17570914-3-deflabel20"></join>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570914-3-verdict21" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570914-3-verdict21" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17570914-3-punish22" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570914-3-punish22" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-3-defend53 t17570914-3-punish22"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
