<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17550515-24">
               <interp inst="t17550515-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550515-24" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550515-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550515"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550515-24" type="date" value="17550515"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550515-24-off111-c172" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-24-defend215 t17550515-24-off111 t17550515-24-verdict115"></join>
         
               <p>231. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17550515-24-defend215" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Christopher 
                     Gray 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17550515-24-alias-6" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-24-defend215 t17550515-24-alias-6"></join>Bray</rs> 
                     <interp inst="t17550515-24-defend215" type="surname" value="Gray"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-24-defend215" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-24-defend215" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17550515-24-off111" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550515-24-off111" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-24-off111" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing four pounds weight of indigo, value 30 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17550515-24-victim218" type="victimName">
                     George 
                     Ribingrode 
                  <interp inst="t17550515-24-victim218" type="surname" value="Ribingrode"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-24-victim218" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-24-victim218" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            ; it was laid over again to be the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17550515-24-victim220" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Sittwell 
                  <interp inst="t17550515-24-victim220" type="surname" value="Sittwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-24-victim220" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-24-victim220" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17550515-24-viclabel112" type="occupation">merchant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-24-victim220 t17550515-24-viclabel112"></join>, <rs id="t17550515-24-cd113" type="crimeDate">April 28</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-24-off111 t17550515-24-cd113"></join>. +</p>
               <p>Thomas Rayment. I am chief-mate of the merchant-ship called the Duke of Cumberland, which lay off <placeName id="t17550515-24-crimeloc114">Stone stairs</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17550515-24-crimeloc114" type="placeName" value="Stone stairs"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550515-24-crimeloc114" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-24-off111 t17550515-24-crimeloc114"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Which side of the river Thames ?</p>
               <p>Rayment. She lay on the Middlesex side.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is the owner of the ship?</p>
               <p>Rayment. Mr. 
               <persName id="t17550515-24-person221">
                  William 
                  Sittwell 
               <interp inst="t17550515-24-person221" type="surname" value="Sittwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-24-person221" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-24-person221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is, and Mr. 
               <persName id="t17550515-24-person222">
                  Geo 
                  Ribingrade 
               <interp inst="t17550515-24-person222" type="surname" value="Ribingrade"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-24-person222" type="given" value="Geo"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-24-person222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is the owner of the indico; we lost a large quantity of indico about the 28th of April; I went down into the hold, and there I saw the prisoner at the bar move forwards, I thought I saw him take something up in his hand, but could not tell what it was; after that I called up upon deck to the carpenter to bring me down a light, they called and told me he could not come, then I bid them send the captain down; after that I saw the prisoner sidle sideways towards the head of the ship; I said to him, my friend, what have you got there? I came close up to him, and he tumbled down on his back with his hands behind him, and just under him, where he had laid, I took up this indico ( producing about four pounds weight).</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find any of the casks broke?</p>
               <p>Rayment. I found a hole in the staves of a cask supposed to be drove in by an iron crow.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the indico loose when you found it?</p>
               <p>Rayment. No, it was tied up as it is now in a piece of an old apron. I asked him how he came by it? but he did not own he had had it; our people were impressed for his Majesty's service, so that I had none on board, only what are called Lumpers, he was one of them employed to empty the ship.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he been on board long?</p>
               <p>Rayment. He came every day to work on board.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was this?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175505150020"></xptr>Rayment. This was about ten in the morning.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he employed?</p>
               <p>Rayment. He was in the hold with the rest, breaking loose the casks, that is, to roll them into the hatchway, in order to take them up out of the hold.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any other person near the cask that was broke at that time?</p>
               <p>Rayment. There were several more of them in the hold; but none so near it as he; the merchant that the indico was consign'd to missed sixty pounds weight.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the value of sixty pounds weight?</p>
               <p>Rayment. It is worth twenty-five pounds.</p>
               <p>Cross-examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know who broke the hole in the cask ?</p>
               <p>Rayment. I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. Were not there some more of the casks broke by the ship's rolling?</p>
               <p>Rayment. Not that I saw.</p>
               <p>Q. How many casks of indico were there?</p>
               <p>Rayment. There were upwards of twenty casks.</p>
               <p>Q. When you go before the wind, the ship turning to one side and t'other, might not this cask be staved by the sailing of the ship?</p>
               <p>Rayment. Yes, it might.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it not possible this indico might be loose in the hold?</p>
               <p>Rayment. Yes, but then that would have gone down to the lower tear.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you say you saw that parcel in the prisoner's hand?</p>
               <p>Rayment. No, I cannot.</p>
               <p>Q. How much may the casks contain?</p>
               <p>Rayment. Some of them contain two hundred weight; there are all sizes.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the place where you first observed him near the cask that was broken?</p>
               <p>Rayment. No, I imagine he had taken it before, and put it in the place where I saw him sidle from.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was but just gone down into the ship's hold before the mate, it was dark; I went forward to bring the casks to the hatchway; there was some logwood and staves in my way, and I tumbled down. He took up this indico, and asked what it was? I said, nothing that I know of. I did not know what it was any more than the man born.</p>
               <p>Q. to Rayment. How long had he been in the hold that day?</p>
               <p>Rayment. He had been there about half an hour or better before I went down.</p>
               <p>Q. How much is the value of this indico?</p>
               <p>Rayment. Here is about four pounds, it is worth about 9 s. per pound.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550515-24-person223">
                  William 
                  Lacy 
               <interp inst="t17550515-24-person223" type="surname" value="Lacy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-24-person223" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-24-person223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner eight years down to this present time.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Lacy. He is an honest industrious man; he has lain several times at my house, where he might have wronged me of things of more value than this indico, such as silver tankards, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Q. Would you now trust him in your house as usual?</p>
               <p>Lacy. I would now at this time, was he at large.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Lacy. I live in Cable-street, near Well-close-square.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17550515-24-verdict115" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550515-24-verdict115" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
