<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510703-42">
               <interp inst="t17510703-42" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510703-42" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510703-42" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510703"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510703-42" type="date" value="17510703"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510703-42-off195-c321" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-42-defend402 t17510703-42-off195 t17510703-42-verdict198"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510703-42-off195-c322" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-42-defend403 t17510703-42-off195 t17510703-42-verdict198"></join>
         
               <p>455. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17510703-42-defend402" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Holland 
                  <interp inst="t17510703-42-defend402" type="surname" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-defend402" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-defend402" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               <persName id="t17510703-42-defend403" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Daniel 
                     Thoroughgood 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17510703-42-alias-4" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-42-defend403 t17510703-42-alias-4"></join>Dann the baker</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-defend403" type="surname" value="Thoroughgood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-defend403" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-defend403" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , were indicted, that <rs id="t17510703-42-off195" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-off195" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-off195" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               they, on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17510703-42-victim406" type="victimName">
                           Henry 
                           Debins 
                        <interp inst="t17510703-42-victim406" type="surname" value="Debins"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510703-42-victim406" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510703-42-victim406" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-42-off195 t17510703-42-victim406"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, one metal watch, value 30 s. one pocket book and leather case, one piece of silver coin, value 6 d. and 5 s. in money numbered, from his person did steal
            </rs>, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510703-42-cd196" type="crimeDate">June 11</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-42-off195 t17510703-42-cd196"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-42-person407">
                  Henry 
                  Debins 
               <interp inst="t17510703-42-person407" type="surname" value="Debins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-person407" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-person407" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Tuesday the 11th of June, a little after twelve at night. I was stopped in <placeName id="t17510703-42-crimeloc197">Prince's-street over-against Gerard-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17510703-42-crimeloc197" type="placeName" value="Prince's-street over-against Gerard-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510703-42-crimeloc197" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-42-off195 t17510703-42-crimeloc197"></join> by two men, one of them put a pistol to my breast, and said, if I spoke a word I was a dead man; then they rifled my pockets of a metal watch, some silver, a pocket-piece, a little pocket-book with some notes in it, the book was in a letter-case, and a handkerchief; I could not distinguish the persons so as to know them; either they or I myself held my hat over my face; I was much affrighted.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-42-person408">
                  Mark 
                  Chailes 
               <interp inst="t17510703-42-person408" type="surname" value="Chailes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-person408" type="given" value="Mark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-person408" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 11th of June the rejoycing-day, Dann the baker came and asked me if I would go upon the scamp with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>Chailes. This was opposite the Fox in Drury-lane; he brought me a little lower down the lane; I said I had no arms. Holland and his wife were there, and she gave Holland a pistol which she took out of her bosom, and gave Dann the baker a hanger.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was this?</p>
               <p>Chailes. This was about eight o'clock at night. Holland said he heard there was to be a masquerade at Marybon-gardens that night, and was in a hurry, saying we should have no chance; he made us run almost all the way, and said, that those who did not go home now, would stay all night. We met with nothing going thither; on coming back again he brought us a new way in the fields, where we heard people talking: we met a man with a lanthorn, who said he was prepar'd for us, so we did not attack him.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>Chailes. I guess it was betwixt ten and eleven o'clock. Then Holland said, we can do nothing in London streets till between twelve and one. We heard the clock strike one as we were coming down Tyburn-road, where we stop'd a gentleman, and desired him to deliver; he said, he had no money but his ring.</p>
               <p>Q. Where abouts in Tyburn-road was this?</p>
               <p>Chailes. It was about half way from St. Giles's pound to the gallows. Then we went on farther<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175107030029"></xptr> and came to Prince's-street, hard by Leicester-fields, and met a gentleman there; Holland was the first man, and I went last; I cannot rightly swear to his face, but I believe the prosecutor to be the man. Holland desir'd him to stand, saying, if he made any noise he would blow his brains out, and put a pistol to him; the gentleman never spoke a word. Then Dan the baker, and Holland ran to his pockets, the baker handed to me the pocket-book behind him, and I put it into my pocket; there were a case and some notes in it, but I did not examine them at that time. I stood behind Holland's back, and what they gave me I took; they gave me no money. Going to Grosvenor-square Holland said he had got but 6 s. 6 d. and gave me 2 s. for my share; he also gave Thorowgood 2 s. There was a pocket-piece which we took to be gold, and went to a stone at a gentleman's door and rubb'd it. Holland said to me, keep the pocket-book till To-morrow when we go out again, and I'll keep this, when we will share it. The piece was not so large as a shilling, for we compared them together, and one side of it was a little like that of a guinea.</p>
               <p>Q. to P rosecutor. Had you such a piece about you?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I had a piece of foreign coin about me, it was silver.</p>
               <p>Chailes. After we had divided the money we walk'd about the streets till day-light, when Holland said we had better go home, which we did, but were to meet next day in Drury-lane. Dann and I went together, and we were to give an account whether there were any bank notes in the pocket-book. Dann told me he'd get me a lodging, so we went to Newtoner's lane, and knock'd up the people of a house, and a woman came down and let me in, but would have the money before-hand, so we gave her 3 d. each, and got a candle. Dann ask'd me for the pocket-book, which when we open'd we found a letter, this he burnt, and there was a note which he did not burn; there were two pieces of sealing-wax also, red and black, he kept the red and gave me the black, and I kept the pocket-book. The next morning when we went down stairs he wanted to ease himself, so he tore the note in two and used half of it; I wanting to do the same he gave me the other half, which I kept. Then we went to Clare-market, and got a kidney and sweetbreads, and in Drury-lane I happen'd to meet with 
               <persName id="t17510703-42-person409">
                  Tom 
                  Pendigrast 
               <interp inst="t17510703-42-person409" type="surname" value="Pendigrast"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-person409" type="given" value="Tom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-person409" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who said, what the Devil did you go out last night with Holland, he will hang you, he made himself an evidence once before? See No. 19, in last Kingston-assize paper. This made me so afraid that I went directly to one Mr. Stanley, and told him I had been out the night before with Holland and Dan the baker.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the reason you went and told this?</p>
               <p>Chailes. Because I was afraid I would be hang'd, so I told Stanley they were to meet me in Drury-lane that night.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does Stanley live?</p>
               <p>Chailes. He lives in Rosemary-lane; he and two or three more went and took them in the place where we were to meet.</p>
               <p>Q. from Holland. Can that evidence produce any body that ever saw me in his company?</p>
               <p>Chailes. Dann the baker brought me into his company, I never was in his company before.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known Dann the baker?</p>
               <p>Chailes. I have known him two months, and have drank with him at the Crown in Russel-street three or four times : he used to serve my uncle with bread, who keeps a cook's shop in St. Giles's. I have also drank with him at the Fox in Drury-lane.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-42-person410">
                  Thomas 
                  Stanley 
               <interp inst="t17510703-42-person410" type="surname" value="Stanley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-person410" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-person410" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About the 12th of last June the evidence, Chailes, came to my house: he sent up stairs for me, and when I came down he told me he had a thing to reveal to me, hoping I would be of service to him; upon this he put his hand in his pocket and pull'd out this pocket-book, and said, the night before he had been in company with Holland and Dan the baker, and they had robb'd a gentleman near Piccadilly of that book, a silver medal, and some small trifle of silver; saying he was told by one Pendigrast, that this Holland had made himself an evidence against some people he had been concern'd with before, and had hang'd them, and therefore he wanted to know of me how he could make himself a clear man, and get shut of such people, saying, he was told they were men that would hang any body. He showed me part of the note belonging to the gentleman he said they robb'd, and if I could get Holland I should find the piece of money in his pocket if he had not made away with it; he also told me Dan the baker and he went to a house in Newtoner's lane, and that Dan had torn the notes left they should come in evidence against them, and that he pick'd up the piece of a note. Then I told him the only way was to apply to a justice of peace, and give evidence in regard to what he had seen committed. Then he said he had parted that night in Leicester-fields, and they were to meet<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175107030030"></xptr> at the Fox in Drury-lane at 11 o'clock. Accordingly I went, in company with Mitchel, Harris, and Penprise, and at the door we took them both, in company with some idle huffies, a little in liquor, and we brought them down to my house, at the ship in Rosemary-lane, where Penprise pull'd a silver medal out of Holland's pocket; and we search'd Thorowgood also, but found nothing upon him. When Thorowgood saw the pocket-book at my house, and I said here is the robbery quite plain, he said, I will go to justice of peace and make myself an evidence. He owned the fact, saying, he was along with Holland. Said Holland, hold your tongue, you'll do yourself no good. Holland, cursing and swearing, said, he could never be hang'd above once.</p>
               <p>Holland. When we were carried before the justice the evidence swore the pocket piece was taken out of his own pocket.</p>
               <p>Chailes. I did not, my information will tell to the contrary.</p>
               <p>Q. to Stanley. Did Chailes own before the justice it was taken out of his own pocket?</p>
               <p>Stanley. No, my lord, he did not. I was sworn before the justice, and I saw Penprise take it out of Holland's pocket.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-42-person411">
                  James 
                  Penprise 
               <interp inst="t17510703-42-person411" type="surname" value="Penprise"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-person411" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-person411" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Holland about a year. I was at Mr. Stanley's house when the evidence came there, and went with Stanley to the Fox in Drury-lane in order to take the two men; about eleven at night we took them, and carried them to Stanley's house, where, on searching them, I found this piece in Holland's pocket, and have had it in my custody ever since. They searched Thorowgood in another room, so I don't know what they found upon him. The pocket piece or medal, as it was called, produced in court.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. Is this your property?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I had such a piece of money as this in my pocket; but as it is a coin, there may be such another. It is like mine. It is, I believe, a Hungarian piece.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-42-person412">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17510703-42-person412" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-person412" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-person412" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the taking the prisoners on the 12th of June at the Fox in Drury-lane. Dan the baker confess'd the fact, and desired to be made an evidence, provided he could go before the justice first of all. When he found Chailes was carried out to be made an evidence, he cried, I am a dead man, and if he is gone it does not signify any thing to carry me. Holland, at that time, said he was sick before the justice of peace; but he appear'd well and hearty, and swore at a prodigious rate.</p>
               <p>Holland's Defence.</p>
               <p>I can give proof where I was at this time.</p>
               <p>Thorowgood's Defence.</p>
               <p>I am as innocent as the child unborn.</p>
               <p>For Holland.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-42-person413">
                  Mary 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17510703-42-person413" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-person413" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-person413" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When Holland first came out of goal he came directly to my mother's house.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he come out of goal?</p>
               <p>M. Brown. It was about April towards the latter end: after that he fell sick, and while he was sick he never went out of our house but one night, and that was when he was taken.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he continue sick?</p>
               <p>M. Brown. About ten days.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-42-person414">
                  John 
                  Brianey 
               <interp inst="t17510703-42-person414" type="surname" value="Brianey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-person414" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-person414" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When the prisoner was discharged from this court he came to my habitation, he was taken ill there, and never was out of my house till he was taken.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know this 
               <persName id="t17510703-42-person415">
                  Mary 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17510703-42-person415" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-person415" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-person415" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Brianey. She is my daughter.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had he been out of your house when he was taken?</p>
               <p>Brianey. He had not then been gone out above half or threequarters of an hour, he went out half an hour after eight o'clock. He was ill about nine or ten days.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that the only reason he never went out?</p>
               <p>Brianey. He kept in the house because he was low in habit, he had no shoes or stockings.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he been ill?</p>
               <p>Brianey. He had been so ill that I did not think he could recover it. I was at home every night, and so was Holland, he lay with two of my children.</p>
               <p>Q. to the prosecutor. How did Holland look when you saw him?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. He was taken the 12th, and I saw him the Saturday following at the Justice's; he then appear'd to be in a good state of health.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-42-person416">
                  Alice 
                  Brianey 
               <interp inst="t17510703-42-person416" type="surname" value="Brianey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-person416" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-person416" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Holland came out of Newgate the latter end of April to my house, and he never went out of it till the day he was taken. He had no shoes, so I went and got him a pair of shoes a day or two before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-42-person417">
                  Tracy 
                  Avey 
               <interp inst="t17510703-42-person417" type="surname" value="Avey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-person417" type="given" value="Tracy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-person417" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the same house where Holland did, I never saw him out of the house till the day he was taken.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17510703-42-verdict198" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-verdict198" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510703-42-punish199" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510703-42-punish199" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-42-defend402 t17510703-42-punish199"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-42-defend403 t17510703-42-punish199"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
