<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17540911-42">
               <interp inst="t17540911-42" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-42" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-42" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-42" type="date" value="17540911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540911-42-off225-c337" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-42-defend410 t17540911-42-off225 t17540911-42-verdict228"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540911-42-off225-c338" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-42-defend412 t17540911-42-off225 t17540911-42-verdict228"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540911-42-off225-c339" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-42-defend414 t17540911-42-off225 t17540911-42-verdict228"></join>
         
               <p>457, 458, 459. (M) 
               
                  <persName id="t17540911-42-defend410" type="defendantName">
                     Benjamin 
                     Ball 
                  <interp inst="t17540911-42-defend410" type="surname" value="Ball"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-42-defend410" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-42-defend410" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17540911-42-defend412" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Curier 
                  <interp inst="t17540911-42-defend412" type="surname" value="Curier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-42-defend412" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-42-defend412" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17540911-42-defend414" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Shovel 
                  <interp inst="t17540911-42-defend414" type="surname" value="Shovel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-42-defend414" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-42-defend414" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted for <rs id="t17540911-42-off225" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540911-42-off225" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-42-off225" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that they, on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17540911-42-victim416" type="victimName">
                           Andrew 
                           Tate 
                        <interp inst="t17540911-42-victim416" type="surname" value="Tate"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540911-42-victim416" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540911-42-victim416" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-42-off225 t17540911-42-victim416"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear, and one silver watch, val. 5 l. one pair of Bristol stone sleeve buttons set in silver, val. 5 s. one linen handkerchief, one snake-stone, one knife, one iron key, and 10 s. in money numbered
            </rs>, the goods of the said Andrew, did steal, &amp;c. <rs id="t17540911-42-cd226" type="crimeDate">Aug. 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-42-off225 t17540911-42-cd226"></join>.*</p> 
               <p>Andrew Tate. I came home from a voyage the last day but one in July. I had been seeing some of my friends the last day, and staid pretty late. Coming by <placeName id="t17540911-42-crimeloc227">Church Lane, Whitechapel</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17540911-42-crimeloc227" type="placeName" value="Church Lane, Whitechapel"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17540911-42-crimeloc227" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-42-off225 t17540911-42-crimeloc227"></join>, I met 
               <persName id="t17540911-42-person417">
                  Mary Ann 
                  More 
               <interp inst="t17540911-42-person417" type="surname" value="More"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-42-person417" type="given" value="Mary Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-42-person417" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and asked her my way; she said, she would go home with me. I said, then she should drink some beer, and took her into the Rose and Crown alehouse; this was about eleven o'clock at night, or after, and we had two pots of beer. I took out my watch and found it past 12 o'clock. I had seen the three prisoners in the house. Being sickish, I came to the door and sat down on the bench, where I received several blows on my head. I am sure the three prisoners were all about me. They overcame me and abused me, and I lost the things mentioned in the indictment. I know 
               <persName id="t17540911-42-person418">
                  Benjamin 
                  Ball 
               <interp inst="t17540911-42-person418" type="surname" value="Ball"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-42-person418" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-42-person418" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             took hold on me, and pulled me on the ground. I can't tell what the other two little ones did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know 
               <persName id="t17540911-42-person419">
                  Mary Ann 
                  More 
               <interp inst="t17540911-42-person419" type="surname" value="More"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-42-person419" type="given" value="Mary Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-42-person419" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             before?</p>
               <p>Tate. No, I never saw her before that night. When she called out for assistance, the watchmen<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175409110038"></xptr> came up. The two little ones, that is Curier and Shovel, confessed the fact before Sir 
               <persName id="t17540911-42-person420">
                  Samuel 
                  Gore 
               <interp inst="t17540911-42-person420" type="surname" value="Gore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-42-person420" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-42-person420" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in my hearing. I lost ten shillings in silver, but had some halfpence again.</p>
               <p>Q. to Curier. How old are you?</p>
               <p>Curier. I am going in twelve years of age.</p>
               <p>Shovel. I am going in my fourteenth year.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-42-person421">
                  Mary Ann 
                  More 
               <interp inst="t17540911-42-person421" type="surname" value="More"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-42-person421" type="given" value="Mary Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-42-person421" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 1st of August, between twelve and one o'clock, I was going with the prosecutor to shew him his way home, and we went in to drink at a house where I used to work. He went out and was sitting down on the bench very sick, I sat down by him. The three prisoners came round him, and all struck him on the head several times. To see whether he would speak Ball took him by his two shoulders, and pulled him from the bench upon the stones.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you say to them upon this usage?</p>
               <p>More. I said nothing to them till I saw they were robbing him. The two youngest were at his pockets, but I did not see them take any thing. Seeing Ball take his watch out of his sob, I knocked at the door, but they did not open it, although the candle was not out, and I called out as loud as I could to Mr. Stevens, the man of the house. I said to Ball when he was taking the watch, You have robbed the man of all you can, don't take his watch. He said, What need you care? you know nothing of the man, when we have robbed him you shall have part of it; this was before I called out for help. As the watchman came, Ball gave me the watch into my lap, and said, If you belong to the man take the watch, you bitch, blast your eyes. I clapped it into my bosom, and they ran away. As soon as the watchman came up, I gave him the watch, with some halfpence and a key, which they had flung into my lap.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-42-person422">
                  Robert 
                  Medal 
               <interp inst="t17540911-42-person422" type="surname" value="Medal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-42-person422" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-42-person422" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watchman; beating my rounds I heard a noise in Church-lane; going towards it Ball met me, and said, A good morning to you. I said the same to him. I went a little farther, there lay the prosecutor on the ground. He said he had been knocked down. This evidence was by him. She gave me the watch, and said she had been used ill in taking his part; and she also gave me a knife, a key, and a bit of snake-stone.</p>
               <p>Jos. Gaul. I was officer of the night; my watchman informed me he heard a noise, we went and found the prosecutor. The three prisoners were taken and carried before Sir 
               <persName id="t17540911-42-person423">
                  Samuel 
                  Gore 
               <interp inst="t17540911-42-person423" type="surname" value="Gore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-42-person423" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-42-person423" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; there Curier acknowledged he had done the fact, and said they had ordered him to break the christal of the watch, and bury under shore, and they'd say they found it.</p>
               <p>Court. According to the evidence given, the watch was never out of Ball's Hands till he flung it into the evidence's lap.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Ball acknowledge any thing before the justice?</p>
               <p>Gaul. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Ball's defence.</p>
               <p>It seems strange for me to throw this money into her lap that I never saw with my eyes before that night. I had been in the hous e for a pint of beer, and at coming out, there lay the man. I said, Hallow! who lies here? The woman said, It is my husband. I said, God bless your husband, and bid her good night, and went away.</p>
               <p>Shovel and Curier's defence.</p>
               <p>We never saw the man till we saw him before the justice.</p>
               <p>All three <rs id="t17540911-42-verdict228" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540911-42-verdict228" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
