<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17520116-16">
               <interp inst="t17520116-16" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520116-16" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520116-16" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520116-16" type="date" value="17520116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520116-16-off90-c149" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520116-16-defend185 t17520116-16-off90 t17520116-16-verdict92"></join>
         
               <p>96. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17520116-16-defend185" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Brezeau 
                  <interp inst="t17520116-16-defend185" type="surname" value="Brezeau"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-defend185" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-defend185" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             (a), was indicted <rs id="t17520116-16-off90" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-off90" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-off90" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               for the willful murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17520116-16-victim187" type="victimName">
                           Daniel 
                           Cutting 
                        <interp inst="t17520116-16-victim187" type="surname" value="Cutting"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520116-16-victim187" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520116-16-victim187" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520116-16-off90 t17520116-16-victim187"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>. He also stood charged on the Coroner's Inquest for the said murder, <rs id="t17520116-16-cd91" type="crimeDate">Dec 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520116-16-off90 t17520116-16-cd91"></join>.</p>
               <p>(a) The prisoner being a Frenchman, and not understanding English, he was allowed an interpreter, and tried by a jury of half foreigners, at his own request.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520116-16-person188">
                  Robert 
                  Thomas 
               <interp inst="t17520116-16-person188" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person188" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person188" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Tipstaff to Mr. Justice Foster. On Tuesday the 10th of December I was employed by some people to execute this warrant, [holding one in his hand] which I had from Mr. Justice Foster, on the prisoner at the bar. When we had spent some time in Spital-Fields, we were informed, the prisoner had secreted himself, so that we could not take him: I parted with them, and we appointed another time, which was Sunday the 15th. I was informed he had been convicted upon an action, brought at Westminster, by some Weavers. On the day appointed, I and another Tipstaff met the people in Wheeler-street. almost opposite where the prisoner lived. We several times went into the stair-case, and found his door was shut. We returned to the public-house, the landlord's name is Virtue Hughes, he was Headboborough : there was a man with these people, who, they said, would assist me; his name was 
               <persName id="t17520116-16-person189">
                  Daniel 
                  Cutting 
               <interp inst="t17520116-16-person189" type="surname" value="Cutting"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person189" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person189" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a watchman in the parish where the prisoner had lived: he said, he knew the prisoner well, and I could make no mistake if he was with me: that day also being spent, I desired they would excuse me. I understanding the landlord would execute it, they said, they would take care to do it: I desired them to make no breach in the law whatsoever. I also said to the Headborough, take care of yourself, for, from the character these people give him, he is a very dangerous man: the watchman said, if I see him, I'll fasten him, I am strong enough for him. I left the warrant with one Williams, before the officer in his house; I did not expect they would have attempted to take him that night.</p>
               <p>Cross examin'd.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you leave the warrant in Williams's hand for?</p>
               <p>Thomas. For him to deliver it to the Headborough; it was he that employed me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the Constable see you deliver it?</p>
               <p>Thomas. Yes, Sir, and said he'd execute it if he could.</p>
               <p>[The warrant was read in court, dated December 9, 1751, signed by Mr. Justice Foster.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520116-16-person190">
                  John 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17520116-16-person190" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person190" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person190" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Weaver, and live in Betnnal-Green Parish : I remember Mr. Thomas, the Tipstaff, delivering that warrant to me, in the presence of the officer in his own house, on the 15th of December, there being no possibility of coming at the prisoner, about four or five in the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175201160017"></xptr> evening: about an hour after that, Mr. Hughes asked me for the warrant, I delivered it to him, he read it, and delivered it to me again: I put it in my pocket, then we agreed to make no attempt to take him that night. Between six and seven I went out into the street, in order to tell the deceased and two or three more, who were waiting to see him come down stairs, that we had no thoughts of taking the man that night. Mr. Cutting said to me, have you a mind to see Brezeau ? I said, yes, I could like to see him and his lodging; then said he, come along with me. We went up the stairs, which came down into the street; he ordered me to take hold on the bottom of his coat ; on the second landing place, we look'd through a little pane of glass on the right-hand side, about the breadth of the palm of my hand, I saw Brezeau sitting by the fire, and a little boy sitting by him, eating out of a porringer, with a spoon: then I was for coming down stairs again: I left Cutting on the landing-place, and when I had got six or seven stairs down, or thereabouts, it was so dark that I fell up and took hold of Cutting's shoe, and gave it a pinch to come down, at which time I heard Mrs. Brezeau say, Who is that? I think she repeated it a second time; I knew her voice well, having known her some years, immediately I heard a chair rattle: as soon as that noise was over, I saw the door thrown open, and saw Mrs. Brezeau and a candle upon the table by the fire-side, and the prisoner was standing in the center of the room, and the deceased went into the room.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the deceased when the door was flung open?</p>
               <p>Williams. He was standing upon the landing-place.</p>
               <p>Q. Who had the warrant then?</p>
               <p>Williams. I had it then in my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. What was done upon Cutting's going into the room?</p>
               <p>Williams. I saw them close directly in the center of the room.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the door opened, do you think, by violence, or otherwise?</p>
               <p>Williams. There seemed to be no force, I believe it was thrown open by the woman within: they being two strong men, I imagined I saw something of a struggling ; I supposed the prisoner went to turn him out of the room; I called while I was upon the stairs for assistance; for when we went up, we had no design upon the man, therefore we were unprepared : one 
               <persName id="t17520116-16-person191">
                  Leonard 
                  Provost 
               <interp inst="t17520116-16-person191" type="surname" value="Provost"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person191" type="given" value="Leonard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person191" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was the first. As I was going out, when I got at the bottom of the stairs, there stood one Virtue Hughes, said he, where is the warrant? here it is, said I, I delivered it to him and went over to his house, and said, I believed the man was taken : then I returned to go up again, which was in about five or six minutes, and I saw the deceased at the bottom of the stairs, with his hand to his side, saying, I am killed, I am killed! I passed by him and went up stairs in Brezeau's room, where I found Mr. Hughes, 
               <persName id="t17520116-16-person192">
                  Robert 
                  Bennet 
               <interp inst="t17520116-16-person192" type="surname" value="Bennet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person192" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person192" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17520116-16-person193">
                  Charles 
                  Russel 
               <interp inst="t17520116-16-person193" type="surname" value="Russel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person193" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person193" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and, I believe, 
               <persName id="t17520116-16-person194">
                  Leonard 
                  Provost 
               <interp inst="t17520116-16-person194" type="surname" value="Provost"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person194" type="given" value="Leonard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person194" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            : Bennet had hold on the prisoner with his arm extended and a hanger in his hand.</p>
               <p>Cross Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. How came the constable to return the warrant again to you?</p>
               <p>Williams. I imagine it to be because he and I had agreed to make no attempt to take him that night.</p>
               <p>Q. What trade was Cutting?</p>
               <p>Williams. He was a Weaver.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the deceased offer to come down when you took hold of his foot?</p>
               <p>Williams. He did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you talk to each other on the stairs ?</p>
               <p>Williams. Not a word.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he standing with his back to the fire, or the door?</p>
               <p>Williams. He was standing with his face to the door, in the middle of the room.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a large or small room?</p>
               <p>Williams. There was a bed and a loom in it; I imagine it not to be a small room.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner say any thing when Cutting went into the room?</p>
               <p>Williams. I did not hear him say any thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you say any thing upon seeing the door open?</p>
               <p>Williams. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he advance towards the prisoner, or the prisoner towards him?</p>
               <p>Williams. I cannot tell, it was in a moment.</p>
               <p>Q. In what manner did they close?</p>
               <p>Williams. I imagined it was the design in the struggling to try which should get the better.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was with the deceased when you went to tell him your thoughts were laid aside for that night?</p>
               <p>Williams. 
               <persName id="t17520116-16-person195">
                  Leonard 
                  Provost 
               <interp inst="t17520116-16-person195" type="surname" value="Provost"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person195" type="given" value="Leonard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person195" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any body within the hearing the deceased when he ask'd you to go up stairs ?</p>
               <p>Williams. Leonard Provost was.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175201160018"></xptr>Q. Were the stairs wide or narrow?</p>
               <p>Williams. They were very narrow, I was obliged to clap my back against the wall to let him get by.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you, seeing a man go into the room improperly, and having this warrant in your pocket, to let a man pass you, and you not go up to second him?</p>
               <p>Williams. I imagined the warrant was of no effect in my possession, and accordingly. I run down stairs to deliver it to Hughes that he might come up and serve it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go up with him?</p>
               <p>Williams. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520116-16-person196">
                  Leonard 
                  Provost 
               <interp inst="t17520116-16-person196" type="surname" value="Provost"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person196" type="given" value="Leonard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person196" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 15th of December I was at the bottom of the prisoner's stairs: I heard Mr. Williams, come running down, crying out assistance: I advanced up directly, I pass'd by him on the stairs: I heard the cry of murder very load, I apprehended it to be Mr. Cutting's voice: I knew it well: I went up, the door was fast, it: had a thin latch, I clap'd my hand upon it in order to open it, and said, open the door, they did not: I was by myself about a minute or two, there the man cry'd out murder all the while, he repeated it a good many times.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear above one voice ?</p>
               <p>Provost. I heard none but Cutting's voice: I am sure it was his voice, and the cry was murder.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any bufallng about?</p>
               <p>Provost. I did not, Mr. Hughes, and Mr. Gosset came up: they knocked at the door, and Mr. Hughes said, open the door here is an officer: we asked them several times: they did not, the man was then crying murder, we pushed against the door, and burst it open: the first: thing I observed was Cutting: he was lying on the bed, on his back, and the prisoner bent over him, and something betwixt them: I saw they both had their hands upon the thing: I clapt the prisoner on the right shoulder and said, you villain you are murdering the man: I had no sooner said so, but the sword was drawn out of the deceased's body, and extended upwards by the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner's feet on the floor ?</p>
               <p>Provost. They were, Mr. Bennet clapp'd hold of the prisoner's wrist and rung the hanger out of his hand: the deceased got up and went down stairs, and said he was murdered and killed, &amp;c. the prisoner did not speak a word at that time: I saw the deceased again about eleven o'clock at night: he had two wounds, one was under his pap, and the other lower down on the side of his belly: and his finger were cut on one hand. I saw the hanger afterwards Woody; I asked the deceased before several people, who killed him? he was in his senses, and answered, Brezeau the Frenchman: I asked him with what, he said with a sword: I asked him how many times he stabb'd him: he said twice, he was asked the same over again, he answered as before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he give any further account?</p>
               <p>Provost. No, he did not, this was about eleven at night.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did not you go up with the deceased and Williams ?</p>
               <p>Provost. Because I heard Mr. Williams say, they did not think of taking the prisoner that night.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear murder call'd out before or after Mr. Williams call'd assistance?</p>
               <p>Provost. It was after that, I heard that try as soon as I passed Mr. Williams.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you been at the door, before Mr. Hughes came up ?</p>
               <p>Provost. He came up about a minute or two after I was there.</p>
               <p>Q. Which way did the door open ?</p>
               <p>Provost. It opened inwards.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is the bed from the fire place?</p>
               <p>Provost. I believe it is about three yards distance: the fire is on the right hand side going in, and the bed stands facing the fire: there was a small table by the fire, and a loom in the room.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you give any account who took hold of the hanger first?</p>
               <p>Provost. No, I cannot.</p>
               <p>Q. How were they struggling? in what manner ?</p>
               <p>Provost. The prisoner was like bearing the instrument towards the deceased.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the door locked or bolted ?</p>
               <p>Provost. I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Virtue Hughes. I am headborough : I went to the prisoner's lodgings about seven o'Clock that night: one Mr. Liesaword came running to my house, and said, Come along, there is murder called out: I asked for Mr. Williams, I went over; and at the bottom of the stairs I met him: I asked for the warrant, he gave it me: Mr. Gosset and Mr. Bennet went up to the landing place: I heard a man call out Murder ! Murder! Murder! which surprised me very much: I clapp'd my thumb on the latch, and shov'd the door hard, but the door would not open: I ordered Mr. Gosset and Mr. Bennet to break it open they did: Bennet<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175201160019"></xptr> crowded by me; I saw the deceased on his back on the bed, and the prisoner over him, his arm went backwards and forwards, I pulled out my staff as soon as I got in, and Mr. Bennet took hold on the prisoner, he turned about, and was going to chop me down; Bennet caught hold on his arm, and said, take care of the sword, and twisted it out of the prisoner's hand: the deceased went out, and dapped his hand on the side of his belly, saying, Oh, I am stabb'd, I am kill'd, I am a dead man! his fingers were bloody, at the same time while they were struggling the candle went out.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe where the deceased's hands were.</p>
               <p>Hughes. No, Sir, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any more instruments besides the hanger ?</p>
               <p>Hughes. No, not as I saw: I believe the deceased had never a stick: I don't remember I ever saw the deceased or prisoner before that day: we secured the prisoner, and brought him down to my house; I left people with him, and went into another room to the deceased, he was sitting in a two-arm chair, and a surgeon examining the wounds: I could not see them then as I did when the Corner was there, then I saw four wounds on the sore part of his body.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any conversation with the prisoner about it after that?</p>
               <p>Hughes. No, I had not.</p>
               <p>Cross examin'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Did y ou observe whether there was a lock on the door?</p>
               <p>Hughes. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe whether the bolt or staple were broke or bent?</p>
               <p>Hughes. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the prisoner and the deceased struggling ?</p>
               <p>Hughes. I cannot say as to that; I saw the prisoner on the deceased holding him back, and his hand up.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Cutting's hands on the instrument?</p>
               <p>Hughes. No, I did not: Mr. Bennet ran directly by me, in such a hurry, that I did not observe the deceased's hands.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think he held the instrument up to prevent farther mischief, or to chop you down ?</p>
               <p>Hughes. I think to chop me down.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you be positive as to that ?</p>
               <p>Hughes. I will not be positive, I cannot tell a man's mind.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he strike ?</p>
               <p>Hughes. He did.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell but what the extending his arm was upon Mr. Bennet's holding his arm up?</p>
               <p>Hughes. I cannot tell but that might be the case.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in that room before?</p>
               <p>Hughes. No, I never was.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520116-16-person197">
                  Robert 
                  Bennet 
               <interp inst="t17520116-16-person197" type="surname" value="Bennet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person197" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person197" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went into the prisoner's room with the last evidence: I observed the prisoner lying on the deceased, and his hand moving backwards and forwards: I observed something to glitter in his hand; I stopped down and said, he has got a sword in his hand: I took hold of him, and drew up his hand: I called out immediately, and twisted the sword out of his hand, as he threw it up. (The hanger produced in court. )</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the deceased move his hands?</p>
               <p>Bennet. I was not so nigh the bed as to see that.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the prisoner hold on the hist?</p>
               <p>Bennet. He had, and the other's hands were cut all to pieces with it.</p>
               <p>Q. For what you know, the struggle might be to strive who should have the hanger ?</p>
               <p>Bennet. It might for ought I know: I heard the officer demand the King's peace several times before.</p>
               <p>Q. In what position were they when you entered the room?</p>
               <p>Bennet. The deceased was lying on his back on the bed, the other leaning over him on his knees, half bent.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the wounds afterwards ?</p>
               <p>Bennet. I did, they were all on his left side.</p>
               <p>Q. On which side did the prisoner lie ?</p>
               <p>Bennet. On the right side.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did the candle go out?</p>
               <p>Bennet. When I first went in, the candle was alight, and till after I got the sword: I laid hold of the prisoner's cloaths, by the nape of his neck, and pull'd him from the deceased, when the deceased got up and said, I am killed, I am stabbed, I am dead; he went down stairs, and I went to the door with him. While I was gone the prisoner flung down Provost and Gosset on the opposite side of the bed: Gosset called for assistance, and I went<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175201160020"></xptr> back and laid hold on the prisoner, and said, you have done mischief enough. While I was with him, on the other side the bed, the candle was put out, I cannot say how, or by what.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you imagine the prisoner was going to make a blow at any body when he extended his sword upwards?</p>
               <p>Bennet. I did imagine that, and no otherwise.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see his Wife?</p>
               <p>Bennet. She was in the room after I had taken him from Gosset: she came from the fire-side, and took the sword out of my hand.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520116-16-person198">
                  Charles 
                  Gosset 
               <interp inst="t17520116-16-person198" type="surname" value="Gosset"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person198" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person198" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About seven o'Clock I was at the Headborough's door along with him: he, Bennet, and I, upon hearing the dismal cry of murder, went up the stairs to the prisoner's room as fast as we could: the officer said to me; do you break open the door; said I, you are the officer, do you: I clapped my two hands with violence to it, but it would not open; then I turned my back part, and forc'd it open, and tumbled into the room: I saw the deceased lying on his back, and the prisoner bent over him, as if he was spitting a pig: With my fall I turned round, and saw the sword: I said, as I recovered myself, he has got a sword in his hand: the prisoner drew the sword out of the deceased's body; I saw it go up, and it seemed to fall again: I said to Bennet, catch hold on his hand: he made a blow at me, the officer, and all of us together.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he make a blow ?</p>
               <p>Gosset. By turning his body about.</p>
               <p>Q. What trade are you?</p>
               <p>Gosset. I'm a Weaver.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the wounds afterwards?</p>
               <p>Gosset. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Supposing the deceased had had the instrument in his body, I want to know whether it must not have passed through him?</p>
               <p>Gosset. I say I saw him, like spitting of a pig, stooping, moving forwards, I don't say backwards and forwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see no struggling?</p>
               <p>Gosset. No, none.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you talk French?</p>
               <p>Gosset. Yes, as well as I can English.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you in French expostulate with the prisoner ?</p>
               <p>Gosset. I asked him how he could be guilty of killing that man? I spoke but little French to him, only to get him to the officer's house; then he struggled, so that the candle was knocked out of the candlestick.</p>
               <p>Q. What was his answer?</p>
               <p>Gosset. He gave me but little answer; he said, the man was a rogue and a thief; and that he, held his cutteau, and the man jumped upon it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he took the man to be a thief?</p>
               <p>Gosset. He might say so.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you swear before the Corner, that he said he thought the man to be a thief ?</p>
               <p>Gosset. I don't know but I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you contribute to the carrying on this prosecution?</p>
               <p>Gosset. The widow carries it on?</p>
               <p>Q. Do you contribute towards it?</p>
               <p>Gosset. We have assisted her to buy her some cloaths to go to the burying.</p>
               <p>Q. Have not you contributed towards the carrying on this prosecution?</p>
               <p>Gosset. I have given some money to her and her friends?</p>
               <p>Q. Did you fall to the floor at coming into the room?</p>
               <p>Gosset. I did not fall, I made a sort of a stumbling.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he strike at the officer and you?</p>


               <p>Gosset. There was a sort of an offer; his hand came downwards, somewhat falling, had it not been prevented; it came almost by my face.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see the prisoner and the deceased before?</p>
               <p>Gosset. No, never.</p>
         
               <p>The Second Part of these Proceedings with be publish'd in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17520116-16">
                  <interp inst="t17520116-16" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520116-16" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520116-16" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520116"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520116-16" type="date" value="17520116"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175201160021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Goal Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the Goal Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Thursday the 16th, Friday the 17th, Saturday the 18th, and Monday the 20th of January.</p>
                  <p>In the 25th Year of His MAJESTY's Reign. BEING THE Second SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of the Right Honble 
                  <persName id="t17520116-16-person199">
                     Thomas 
                     Winterbottom 
                  <interp inst="t17520116-16-person199" type="surname" value="Winterbottom"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520116-16-person199" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520116-16-person199" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Esq. LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>NUMBER II. PART II.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>

                  <p>Printed, and sold by M. COOPER, at the Globe in Pater-noster Row. 1752.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-Pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175201160022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery held for the City of London, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520116-16-person200">
                  John 
                  Milward 
               <interp inst="t17520116-16-person200" type="surname" value="Milward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person200" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person200" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I Am a Surgeon, I attended 
               <persName id="t17520116-16-person201">
                  Daniel 
                  Cutting 
               <interp inst="t17520116-16-person201" type="surname" value="Cutting"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person201" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person201" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             after he had received these wounds, on Sunday the 15th of December, about a quarter after seven in the evening; he was sitting in an arm chair, in a bent posture; I observed one on the left side of his belly; that wound appeared very small; I passed my finger into it, and found it went between the Muscles and the Abdomen; but did not pass into the belly; he was very languid, as if dying, which I could not account for from that wound; so ordered him to be stripped and laid down; I gave him a little pain, and nobody being there to put him as I wanted him, I told the people, if they would get him to bed, as I lived near, I would return; so I went back: I was fetched again, in about an hour and half, and examined him on the bed, and found another wound under his left pap, I passed my finger into it, and found it went between his ribbs; I found a great quantity of extravasated blood, that seemed to proceed from the loins on each side the back-bone; I perceived there was a blood vessel wounded, and the Abdomen was full of blood; I dressed both the wounds; there was another small wound on one of his fingers on the left hand; I observed no other wound at all: after the man was dead, the people described more wounds on his body, but I found it was only blood dried on his body, which with my finger I scratched off.</p>
               <p>Q. How deep do you imagine the wound might be?</p>
               <p>Milkward. I believe it might be seven or eight inches deep; it went thro' part of the loins and into the Viscera cavity downwards: it had let out most of the blood of the body into the cavity of the Abdomen; that wound was the occasion of his death.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Did that wound go upwards or downwards?</p>
               <p>Milward. It went rather downwards.</p>
               <p>Q. You have heard what the witnesses have deposed as to the position of the two men on the bed, do you think that wound could be given while in that position?</p>
               <p>Milward. No, Sir, I believe it could not; I apprehend the wound given at that time was the other which was in the lower part of the belly, which ascended into the stomach.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think it might not be done in struggling for the hanger?</p>
               <p>Milward. I think it is impossible it should; that which went into the stomach might be given as he was lying.</p>
               <p>Q. Which wound do you imagine most mortal?</p>
               <p>Milward. That which went downwards, not but the other in its consequences might have been mortal had not the downward been given.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence</p>
               <p>I took the person that came into my room to be a thief; and he laid hold on me before I stirred in my defence; the rest I leave to the management of my counsel.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175201160023"></xptr>To his character.</p>
               <p>The Revd. Mr. Bouldone. I have known the prisoner a few months; I always looked upon him to be a man of a good character, a quiet peaceable man, and religiously disposed.</p>
               <p>The Revd. Mr. Emanuel. The prisoner used to attend divine service with me, he was a good protestant; I have taken notice of him from my pulpit, of his assiduity at divine service; since this fatal accident, I have been very particular in enquiring after his character; I have found him to be an honest laborious man ; he has been in England about two years.</p>
               <p>Mr. Lamboe. The prisoner has been in England about two years and half; he was in my service ; I never knew him but an honest, sober, quite, and religious man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520116-16-person202">
                  John 
                  Russel 
               <interp inst="t17520116-16-person202" type="surname" value="Russel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person202" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person202" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never saw the prisoner but now at the bar ; I have dealt with him, his wife speaks English; he paid me very honestly except the last parcel of goods.</p>
               <p>Mr. Gyles. I have known him about a year and half, his general character is that of a very honest industrious man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520116-16-person203">
                  James 
                  Gautier 
               <interp inst="t17520116-16-person203" type="surname" value="Gautier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person203" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person203" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about a year and half ; I have been in his company many times; he is a very honest sober man: I belong to Mr. Emanuel's congregation; I used to see him there most Sundays; I was much surprised when I heard of this fatal accident: I always took him to be a very godly man, not at all disposed to acts of cruelty.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520116-16-person204">
                  John 
                  Ouscourne 
               <interp inst="t17520116-16-person204" type="surname" value="Ouscourne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person204" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person204" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about a year and half, I used to see him at our church, in my own pew, every Sunday since I have been here: he seemed very attentive; I always looked upon him to be a religious peaceable dispos'd man, quiet and honest as any in the world.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520116-16-person205">
                  James 
                  Protear 
               <interp inst="t17520116-16-person205" type="surname" value="Protear"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person205" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-person205" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him ever since he has been in this country: my opinion of his general character is, that it is a very good one, and that he is a very good Christian. I knew his family in France; and though it is reported, he had done ill things there, he never did, but is a peaceable honest man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520116-16-verdict92" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-verdict92" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-verdict92" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520116-16-punish93" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-punish93" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-punish93" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520116-16-defend185 t17520116-16-punish93"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520116-16-punish94" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-punish94" type="punishmentCategory" value="imprison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-16-punish94" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="newgate"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520116-16-defend185 t17520116-16-punish94"></join>
               
                     <note>[Imprisonment. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
