<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17540911-39">
               <interp inst="t17540911-39" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-39" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-39" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-39" type="date" value="17540911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540911-39-off214-c311" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-39-defend379 t17540911-39-off214 t17540911-39-verdict216"></join>
         
               <p>454. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17540911-39-defend379" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     More 
                  <interp inst="t17540911-39-defend379" type="surname" value="More"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-39-defend379" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-39-defend379" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was <rs id="t17540911-39-off214" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540911-39-off214" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-39-off214" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               indicted, upon the coroner's inquisition, for feloniously killing 
                     
                        <persName id="t17540911-39-victim381" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Whittman 
                        <interp inst="t17540911-39-victim381" type="surname" value="Whittman"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540911-39-victim381" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540911-39-victim381" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-39-off214 t17540911-39-victim381"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17540911-39-cd215" type="crimeDate">Sept. 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-39-off214 t17540911-39-cd215"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-39-person382">
                  Isaac 
                  Tompson 
               <interp inst="t17540911-39-person382" type="surname" value="Tompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-39-person382" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-39-person382" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the making of the battle between the prisoner and the deceased, last Sunday was seven-night in the evening, and they fought the Tuesday after at night. They had words about the deceased being turned from his work. 
               <persName id="t17540911-39-person383">
                  Young 
                  Mr 
               <interp inst="t17540911-39-person383" type="surname" value="Mr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-39-person383" type="given" value="Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-39-person383" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Souch came and said to the prisoner, if you do not fight I'll kick you about; the deceased was very much in liquor at that time. After that they agreed to fight for a crown on the Tuesday night, to meet at 5 o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. How to fight ?</p>
               <p>Tompson. To fight with fists. On the Tuesday morning the deceased called me up. We saw old Mr. Souch, he wanted them to make it up, the deceased said it was best: the old gentleman said he'd give them a dozen of beer to shake hands and make it up. The deceased and I worked together till half an hour after five, then he said, now, let us go and drink together, while we are friends, do you know Mr. Souch is to give us a dozen of beer, so we went to the Bull together, there was one Gilbert there, who said, I believe there will be a battle now, for I see one is come. The deceased said I am come to drink part of this dozen of beer.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the battle ?</p>
               <p>Tompson. No, I never saw More there. I left them; but I saw the deceased after he was dead.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see him dead?</p>
               <p>Tompson. About twelve minutes after I left them, in a field behind the Bull Head.</p>
               <p>Q. How was the deceased for health before they fought?</p>
               <p>Tompson. He was a very healthy man at other times.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any marks upon the deceased's body?</p>
               <p>Tompson. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear More say any thing about it?</p>
               <p>Tompson. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-39-person384">
                  Edward 
                  Eagle 
               <interp inst="t17540911-39-person384" type="surname" value="Eagle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-39-person384" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-39-person384" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going by the Bull Head last Tuesday was seven-night, and saw the prisoner and deceased strip to fight, betwixt 5 and 6, as near as I can guess, I heard they were to fight for</p>
               <p>Q. Who said so ?</p>
               <p>Eagle. I heard them both mention it. They set to and fought for eight or ten minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. Who struck the first blow ?</p>
               <p>Eagle. They made many offers to hurt one another as much as they could. There were a great many blows, and a great many falls.</p>
               <p>Q. What did they fight with?</p>
               <p>Eagle. With their fists. More had the best of the battle at first, but Whittman had the best of it at the middle, till after a fall or two the misfortune happened. They both fell down together, and both struck at one time. I lifted More up, for he had chose me his second, but Whittman never arose more.</p>
               <p>Q. How did they fall?</p>
               <p>Eagle. They both fell on their sides. More was very much beat, and very weak.</p>
               <p>Q. How was Whittman for health before they fought ?</p>
               <p>Eagle. He was a very healthy hearty man before.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of any grudge between them?</p>
               <p>Eagle. I did not hear of any. They had been fellow servants together, and went with much good humour, shaking hands before they began, and saying they would drink together after the battle was over.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the deceased after this?</p>
               <p>Eagle. After he was laid out the next morning I saw him, he was very black down the left side, and was very much bruised.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think that happened by the blows, or by the fall?</p>
               <p>Eagle. I suppose by the blows.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe the face?</p>
               <p>Eagle. I observed nothing there but a little bit of skin off his lip.</p>
               <p>Q. How was the head?</p>
               <p>Eagle. He had no bruises about the head, but his sides and arms were black.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you think was the occasion of his death?</p>
               <p>Eagle. I believe he died of the wounds he received from that man, but the prisoner seemed, by outward appearances, to be more hurt than the deceased after the battle was over.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-39-person385">
                  Thomas 
                  Lloyd 
               <interp inst="t17540911-39-person385" type="surname" value="Lloyd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-39-person385" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-39-person385" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the battle, and went into the field. There they both pulled off their shirts, hats, and wigs, and shook hands together. They were to have come into my house, and drink after the battle was over.</p>
               <p>Q. Which agreed to that ?</p>
               <p>Lloyd. They both agreed to it; they fought about ten minutes with their fists, and had blows<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175409110035"></xptr> on both sides. I believe they were down four or five times each.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the last blow struck?</p>
               <p>Lloyd. I did not, but heard somebody say the man was dead. I went to fetch some water for him, but he was quite dead. On coming out of the field I saw the prisoner cry, and heard him say he was very sorry.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe the body?</p>
               <p>Lloyd. I did, and that night there were but little signs of any thing, but the next day, about twelve at noon, he looked very black on both sides and his thighs; the bottom of his ribs looked very green. I don't know whether it was occasioned by the falls or blows.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I ha d been at London on my master's business. Coming home the deceased sat at the door and said, You are d - n'd proud, that you will not speak to poor folks. I said, I could not stay, but would come presently. I went and came again, and he asked me to drink. I said, I would with all my heart, if he had been at another house, but I had swore I would spend no money there. I went home and fetch'd my supper and came again. He then got off his seat and said, Are not you a blackguard scoundrel, you deserve to be well lick'd. I said, I don't want to wrangle and quarrel with you, come another day and I'll fight you, but this is Sunday night. He said, D - n you, I'll fight you for a guinea or two, and aggravated me much. I believe, if it had not been for my master, I should have been abused by him and his brother. Then my master said, I should fight, so we put down a shilling each to fight on Tuesday. Upon his coming then he was not for fighting, but his brother put him on. When he went into the field, I said, William, do you intend to fight me? He said, As long as I have life in my body. Then we stripped, and shook hands. I said, I hoped there was no malice between us, and he said, no.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-39-person386">
                  Samuel 
                  Souch 
               <interp inst="t17540911-39-person386" type="surname" value="Souch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-39-person386" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-39-person386" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the gate, and heard the prisoner and deceased quarrel. I stepped over to them; the deceased challenged the prisoner many times before he would fight him, but afterwards they would have fought that night if something had not prevented them, and upon this they put it off till half an hour after five on Tuesday. When the time came he asked me if Will Whittman was come, I said, no. I said, You shall not stir out of the door till he sends for you. Then there came a person and said that he was come. Then he went out, and going into the field they stripped to fight. As to the battle, I thought it was very fair, the prisoner had rather the worst of it till that blow by which the man dropped.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did that blow fall on the deceased ?</p>
               <p>Souch. As far as I could perceive, it fell somewhere about the ribs.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see the body after it was dead?</p>
               <p>Souch. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you the deceased's master's son?</p>
               <p>Souch. I am.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you the man that told the prisoner, if he did not fight the other you'd kick him about?</p>
               <p>Souch. I told him I'd lend him the money.</p>
               <p>Q. Don't you know that it is your duty when people are exasperated, to make up the matter ?</p>
               <p>Souch. I was in hopes of making it up.</p>
               <p>Court. That was not the way.</p>
               <p>Souch. My father would have given them two shillings to spend to make it up.</p>
               <p>Court. I am speaking of you. His behaviour was very proper, but yours was not.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540911-39-verdict216" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540911-39-verdict216" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-39-verdict216" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540911-39-punish217" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540911-39-punish217" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-39-punish217" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-39-defend379 t17540911-39-punish217"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
