<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17540530-22">
               <interp inst="t17540530-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540530-22" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540530-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540530"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540530-22" type="date" value="17540530"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540530-22-off103-c198" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-22-defend231 t17540530-22-off103 t17540530-22-verdict106"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540530-22-off103-c199" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-22-defend234 t17540530-22-off103 t17540530-22-verdict106"></join>
         
               <p>326, 327. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17540530-22-defend231" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Elizabeth 
                     Preston 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17540530-22-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-22-defend231 t17540530-22-alias-1"></join>Tachbourn</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-defend231" type="surname" value="Preston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-defend231" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-defend231" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             
                  <rs id="t17540530-22-deflabel101" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-22-defend231 t17540530-22-deflabel101"></join>, and 
               
                  <persName id="t17540530-22-defend234" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Phillips 
                  <interp inst="t17540530-22-defend234" type="surname" value="Phillips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-defend234" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-defend234" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17540530-22-deflabel102" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-22-defend234 t17540530-22-deflabel102"></join>were indicted for <rs id="t17540530-22-off103" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-off103" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-off103" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one gold watchvalue 10 l. 10 s. one watch chain, value 6 s. and sixteen shillings in money numbered
            </rs>, the goods and monies of 
               
                  <persName id="t17540530-22-victim236" type="victimName">
                     Samuel 
                     Woodcock 
                  <interp inst="t17540530-22-victim236" type="surname" value="Woodcock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-victim236" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-victim236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-22-off103 t17540530-22-victim236"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17540530-22-cd104" type="crimeDate">May 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-22-off103 t17540530-22-cd104"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-22-person237">
                  Samuel 
                  Woodcock 
               <interp inst="t17540530-22-person237" type="surname" value="Woodcock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person237" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person237" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live upon my estate at Stoke-Newingtonwhich also is situated there, and on Saturday sev'nnight last, as I was going from Mile-End home to Stoke-Newington, my hat blew off, so I got off to pick it up.</p>
               <p>Court. What then you was on horseback?</p>
               <p>Woodcock. A mare backan it please you, my Lord. Then my mare got away, and as I was walking down Whitechapel, looking for my maremuch about Whitechapel bars I met with these two women. I was a little in liquor, and on their asking me if I would give them any thing to drinkI replied I would treat them with a pot of gin hot; upon which they took me down Petticoat-Lane, I believe, and one of them said I should go to her lodgings.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you go?</p>
               <p>Woodcock. I went into <placeName id="t17540530-22-crimeloc105">Honey-Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17540530-22-crimeloc105" type="placeName" value="Honey-Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17540530-22-crimeloc105" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-22-off103 t17540530-22-crimeloc105"></join>to one of their lodgings (though I think they said they paid for the room between them), and we sent for the pot of gin hot from the Black Horseor Black Lion, but which of these I cannot be certain. After this, my Lord, I agreed to give them half a crown apiece to lie between them both, and we went to bed accordingly: - but to tell you the truth, my Lord, I was not concerned with them -  when I awaked in the morning, which was about four o'clock, I found I had lost my waistcoatbreeches, and stockings.</p>
               <p>Court. There is nothing in this indictment but the watch and chain, and sixteen shillings, therefore confine yourself to that.</p>
               <p>Woodcock. I lost my watch and chain, and sixteen shillings and sixpence, according to their confession.</p>
               <p>Q. Then you dont't know what money you had in your pocket ?</p>
               <p>Woodcock. It was something thereabouts. When I had got my breeches and things, my mare was got home.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you go away ?</p>
               <p>Woodcock. I went away in the morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were the women ?</p>
               <p>Woodcock. They were gone.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you find your watch?</p>
               <p>Woodcock. I found it in the possession of a Jew, and it is now in the constable's hands, whose name is 
               <persName id="t17540530-22-person238">
                  Daniel 
                  Hambleton 
               <interp inst="t17540530-22-person238" type="surname" value="Hambleton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person238" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When I went to bed, my watch and money were in my pocketbut when I awoke in the morning, there were neither watch nor money; and I thought likewise I had lost my breechesbut I found them underneath the bed.</p>
               <p>Q. What place was this where you went to; do you know the name?</p>
               <p>Woodcock. It is Honey-Lane, but I don't know whose house it was. There were a great many lodgers in it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you complain to any body about it?</p>
               <p>Woodcock. I did to several people, and they were taken up on the Sunday.</p>
               <p>Q. When was it you was there?</p>
               <p>Woodcock. On the Saturday night, and I went to see them in the Counter on Sunday night, at which time they confessed it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know them again ?</p>
               <p>Woodcock. Yes, my Lord. I asked them how they could serve me soand 
               <persName id="t17540530-22-person239">
                  Bet 
                  Preston 
               <interp inst="t17540530-22-person239" type="surname" value="Preston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person239" type="given" value="Bet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person239" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said it was very wrong, but hoped I would be favourable to them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you get the watch from her ?</p>
               <p>Woodcock. No, for 
               <persName id="t17540530-22-person240">
                  Bet 
                  Preston 
               <interp inst="t17540530-22-person240" type="surname" value="Preston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person240" type="given" value="Bet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person240" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had taken the constable to the Jew'swhere the watch was sent.</p>
               <p>Q. What did they confess ?</p>
               <p>Woodcock. They confessed they took it, and that one was to carry it to pawn, and the other to have part of the money. They began to quarrel about it, and charged one another with the fact. They also said that one of them had got her hand in my pocket, and that the other ordered her to let me alone, for that she had got my load; by which I suppose she meant my watch and money.</p>
               <p>Preston. Did I ever own I took your watch?</p>
               <p>Woodcock. She did not; she said the other took it, the other said she took it, and thus they charged one another with it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-22-person241">
                  Daniel 
                  Hambleton 
               <interp inst="t17540530-22-person241" type="surname" value="Hambleton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person241" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . A man that is here in Court took the prisoners, and gave me charge of them.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175405300015"></xptr>Q. What did you do with them?</p>
               <p>Hambleton. I carried them to the Counter, when I understood there was a robbery committed. There 
               <persName id="t17540530-22-person242">
                  Mary 
                  Phillips 
               <interp inst="t17540530-22-person242" type="surname" value="Phillips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person242" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person242" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             acknowledged she was the person that picked the young man up, and that 
               <persName id="t17540530-22-person243">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Preston 
               <interp inst="t17540530-22-person243" type="surname" value="Preston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person243" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person243" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             insisted he should go to her lodgings. When they got him home, she said he sent for some liquor for them, and that he then refused to go to bed.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear them speak any thing about the watch or money?</p>
               <p>Hambleton. Yesmy Lord, 
               <persName id="t17540530-22-person244">
                  Mary 
                  Phillips 
               <interp inst="t17540530-22-person244" type="surname" value="Phillips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person244" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person244" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             told me, that in the morning as she lay in bed with the young fellow, she felt the other gropeing about underneath him, and asked her what she was about; she repliedHold your tongue, for I have got his load. Phillips said she saw Preston take some money, and put it into her shoe.</p>
               <p>Q. What did Preston say?</p>
               <p>Hambleton. Preston was not taken by me that night, so I did not see her till five or six o'clock the next morning, when they came and knocked at my door.</p>
               <p>Q. Who came and knocked at your door?</p>
               <p>Hambleton. This Jemmy PlumpI think they call him. I got up, and they desired me to go along with them, for that Preston had told them where the watch was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her in custody at any time?</p>
               <p>Hambleton. Yes, on Monday morning. I went along with her to the Jew's house where she left the watch, whose name is 
               <persName id="t17540530-22-person245">
                  Solomon 
                  Sampson 
               <interp inst="t17540530-22-person245" type="surname" value="Sampson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person245" type="given" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , but he was gone out, so we went to Duke's Place, and other placesto look for him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see the watch?</p>
               <p>Hambleton. No, not till it was delivered to my Lord-Mayor.</p>
               <p>Q. Who delivered it to my Lord-Mayor?</p>
               <p>Hambleton A person the Jew sent with it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear Preston say where the watch was?</p>
               <p>Hambleton. I heard her say she had left it with the Jew. He produced the watch.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you by that watch?</p>
               <p>Hambleton. My Lord-Mayor gave it me.</p>
               <p>Q. from Preston. Did I own I carried the watch to the Jew?</p>
               <p>Hambleton. She owned that she and one 
               <persName id="t17540530-22-person246">
                  Nell 
                  Riley 
               <interp inst="t17540530-22-person246" type="surname" value="Riley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person246" type="given" value="Nell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person246" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             went to the Jew to sell the watch; and I heard Preston say further, that the Jew had agreed with her to give ten guineas for it; that the Jew said he had not all the money, but that he would go and borrow it; that he went and left them in his room, but presently returned, and said the watch was advertised and stopt; and that Preston d - d him for a Jew son of a bitch, and asked him how that could be, when it was past twelve o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. When was it she went to the Jew?</p>
               <p>Hambleton. On Sunday, as I understood her: but here is a man in the Court, to whom she confessed it before she did to me. They call him Plump, but his name is Bradbrook.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-22-person247">
                  James 
                  Bradbrook 
               <interp inst="t17540530-22-person247" type="surname" value="Bradbrook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person247" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you heard these women, or either of them, declare any thing in relation to this watch?</p>
               <p>Bradbrook. I heard the constable had the other in the alehouse, but what she said I did not hear.</p>
               <p>Preston's defence.</p>
               <p>As Phillips and I were going through Black-Horse-Yard, Whitechapel, we met with Mr. Woodcock, who said he had lost his mare, and that he was looking for her. He laid hold of us, upon which we asked him if he would give, us any thing to drink, and he replied he would with all his heart. He insisted on going home to our appartment , for that he was tiredand more fit for sleep than any thing else; so we took him home. When he came into the room, we asked him if he would give us any thing; he sent for a pot of hot, and in the mean time he was for undressing himself and going to bed, but before he was quite undrest, he wanted to have projects and fancies shewed him, which are things that were not at all agreeable; on this we were obliged to tell him one way, and make him think another. He then undrest himself, and insisted on going to bed with us both, giving us. half a crown a piece for that purposeand we went to bed to him. Being abed and asleep, there came one 
               <persName id="t17540530-22-person248">
                  Mary 
                  Strutton 
               <interp inst="t17540530-22-person248" type="surname" value="Strutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person248" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person248" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             up into the room, who awaking us, told us the watch and constable were coming, and knowing the constable to be a very rigid man, we for fear of him got up from Mr. Woodcock, and went down stairs; and when we were down stairs, 
               <persName id="t17540530-22-person249">
                  Mary 
                  Phillips 
               <interp inst="t17540530-22-person249" type="surname" value="Phillips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person249" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person249" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and I went to have a pot or two of drink together, and we drank till we had spent our half crowns apiece. When we had so done, I found myself greatly disguised in liquor, and in the morning, whilst I was sitting in the publick house, there came one 
               <persName id="t17540530-22-person250">
                  Eleanor 
                  Riley 
               <interp inst="t17540530-22-person250" type="surname" value="Riley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person250" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person250" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who said a gentleman had been robbed so and so, to which I replied that I knew nothing of it. She had been up into the room<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175405300016"></xptr> several times during our absenceand Mr. Woodcock owned she had been in the room, as also that he talked with her; all which she herself likewise acknowledged. After this another woman went up into the room, and Mr. Woodcock and she went over to the Black Lion. This Mr. Woodcock said himself. The woman's name was 
               <persName id="t17540530-22-person251">
                  Rebecca 
                  Holding 
               <interp inst="t17540530-22-person251" type="surname" value="Holding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person251" type="given" value="Rebecca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person251" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and they went there to have a pot of ale. In regard to 
               <persName id="t17540530-22-person252">
                  Mary 
                  Phillips 
               <interp inst="t17540530-22-person252" type="surname" value="Phillips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person252" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person252" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I asked her if she said that I should say I was getting her the load, and she declared that she never said any such thing. I believe she never could with justice, but they made her drink liquorin order to swear my life away for the sake of the reward: and they proffered to give her money. 
               <persName id="t17540530-22-person253">
                  Eleanor 
                  Riley 
               <interp inst="t17540530-22-person253" type="surname" value="Riley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person253" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person253" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             carried the watch to the Jew after this gentleman was gone from my room, for she came and asked me if I would go to Drury-Lane; I accordingly went with her to one Sampson's a Jew, a man whom I never saw before or since; she took him into a private room and talked with him, but I do not know what passed between them. After they came out Mr. Sampson put half a guinea into her hand, and she delivered that watch, or a gold watch, into his hand; he then went down stairsin order to borrow more money to give her, but returned in about two hours, and said the watch was stopt. There was no living creature there but 
               <persName id="t17540530-22-person254">
                  Eleanor 
                  Riley 
               <interp inst="t17540530-22-person254" type="surname" value="Riley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person254" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person254" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and myself, for he would not suffer any body to come in besides.</p>
               <p>Phillips's defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing at all of it; I never saw the watch.</p>
               <p>Q. to Woodcock. When you awoke in the morning, I think you say these two women were gone?</p>
               <p>Woodcock. There was a staple broke off the door.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body come up?</p>
               <p>Woodcock I was pulling the bed about to look for my things when 
               <persName id="t17540530-22-person255">
                  Nell 
                  Riley 
               <interp inst="t17540530-22-person255" type="surname" value="Riley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person255" type="given" value="Nell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person255" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came up (though she was but once up); she said, Moll and Sue get up, and let us take a walk to Stepney. She stood still and laughed at me, but I said I should find them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any other woman come up? did one 
               <persName id="t17540530-22-person256">
                  Rebecca 
                  Holding 
               <interp inst="t17540530-22-person256" type="surname" value="Holding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person256" type="given" value="Rebecca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person256" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             come up?</p>

               <p>Woodcock. I don't know her name, but that is the woman that sent for the pint of ale.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you been up before this 
               <persName id="t17540530-22-person257">
                  Eleanor 
                  Riley 
               <interp inst="t17540530-22-person257" type="surname" value="Riley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person257" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person257" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came up?</p>
               <p>Woodcock. About ten minutes, or more.</p>
               <p>Preston. My Lord, 
               <persName id="t17540530-22-person258">
                  Mary 
                  Strutton 
               <interp inst="t17540530-22-person258" type="surname" value="Strutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person258" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person258" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was taken up with us on suspicion of the watch, but discharged by my Lord-Mayor. She likewise lodged in the room.</p>
               <p>Q. to Woodcock. Who was it you saw in the Counter on Sunday night?</p>
               <p>Woodcock. Both the prisoners.</p>
               <p>Q. to Hambleton. When was it that 
               <persName id="t17540530-22-person259">
                  Mary 
                  Phillips 
               <interp inst="t17540530-22-person259" type="surname" value="Phillips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person259" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-person259" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             declared to you she felt her taking something from him?</p>
               <p>Hambleton. On Sunday Night, on our way to the Counter.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Preston in custody in the Counter then?</p>
               <p>Hambleton. No, she was not in the Counter till the Monday.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure she was not in the Counter till Monday?</p>
               <p>Hambleton. I cannot take upon me particularly to say.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17540530-22-verdict106" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540530-22-verdict106" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
