<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510911-3">
               <interp inst="t17510911-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510911-3" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510911-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510911-3" type="date" value="17510911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510911-3-off8-c33" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-3-defend35 t17510911-3-off8 t17510911-3-verdict10"></join>
         
               <p>471. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17510911-3-defend35" type="defendantName">
                  Jos.
                   Godard
               <interp inst="t17510911-3-defend35" type="surname" value="Godard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-defend35" type="given" value="Jos."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-defend35" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for that he <rs id="t17510911-3-off8" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-off8" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-off8" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               in his own dwelling house on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17510911-3-victim37" type="victimName">
                           Henry 
                           Symonds 
                        <interp inst="t17510911-3-victim37" type="surname" value="Symonds"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510911-3-victim37" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510911-3-victim37" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-3-off8 t17510911-3-victim37"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear, &amp;c. and stealing from him, one leather girdle value one penny and 554 pieces of foreign gold coin called duckets, value 250 l.
            </rs> ++</p>
               <p>The prosecutor was a Polander, and could not speak English, 
               <persName id="t17510911-3-person38">
                  Henry 
                  Samuel 
               <interp inst="t17510911-3-person38" type="surname" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person38" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person38" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was sworn interpreter, and spoke it in English as follows. 
               <persName id="t17510911-3-person39">
                  Henry 
                  Symonds 
               <interp inst="t17510911-3-person39" type="surname" value="Symonds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person39" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person39" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I am a Jew from Poland; I came over with the packet, with one Higham Levi, and landed at Harwich to morrow will be 5 weeks; I am a merchant, and came to buy watches, and cloaths, and what I could get for my money. I brought 558 duckets to England all in gold, I shew'd them to my landlady, 
               <persName id="t17510911-3-person40">
                  Sarah 
                  Abrahams 
               <interp inst="t17510911-3-person40" type="surname" value="Abrahams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person40" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person40" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , where I lodged a fortnight ago yesterday, and set out the day after in the morning for Bristol. I wanted to go to the synagogue there, and thought it would do me a deal of good to read there; and also to lay out some money, if I could see any thing worth while. There were then 554 duckets; I always carry my money girded about my body; I stop'd at the Red Lion at Brentford and din'd and had the money about me then. I paid my reckoning with some English coin; I staid there till about half an hour after three, then I went to Hounslow, to the Coach and Horses; I did not stay there a quarter of an hour. I got to the prisoner's house a little before seven; he lives at Cranford bridge ; I went into the sore room, no body was there, a young woman came in when I call'd for a pint of beer, a penny-worth of bread, and a penny-worth of butter; within half an hour, as I was eating it, the landlord came in; I made a bow to him, and ask'd him if he would drink, and also if he would<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175109110003"></xptr> accept of a lemon: he took it, and went out of the room: the young woman came in, and ask'd if I design'd to go further? I said, I design'd to stay there all night. After that the landlord came in with the servant; the servant went and fetch'd another pint of beer, I pull'd out my shirt sleeve and shew'd him I was a clean man, and shew'd him a handful of my money, and said I am a <rs id="t17510911-3-viclabel9" type="occupation">merchant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-3-victim37 t17510911-3-viclabel9"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was by at that time?</p>

               <p>Symonds. There was no body by; then he went out of the room and the young woman came in and ask'd me, how much I would pay for a bed? I said, I'd pay as a merchant, a groat or six pence. Then she went away again, and another young woman came in and asked me if I was ready to go to bed? this was about eight o'clock. After that I pull'd out a book, and was reading: I had also a pen and ink, and wrote down how to call for beer, butter, &amp;c. I went to bed a little before nine: a young woman lighted me up, and she gave me to understand by signs, I must turn the candle upside down when I was in bed. I gave her to understand I should knock with my stick when I was in bed, for her to fetch it, which I did, and she came up and fetch'd it accordingly, and lock'd the door, and went down stairs. Then I am sure I had the girdle and money about my body upon my shirt; I went to bed so. When it was almost twelve o'clock, I heard the door come open, and saw my landlord, the prisoner, come into the room with a candle in his hand alone. I started up in my bed and ask'd him in Dutch what was the matter? he answered, sleep, sleep, there were no curtains to the bed, the landlord went away, and lock'd the door. I did not move out of the bed but went to sleep, and I believe it was between three and four o'clock, some body took hold on me and put a hand to my mouth, and with his knee squeez'd me to the bed. I struggled up and there were two men, it was the prisoner that took hold on me, I could see his face by the moon light; the other person took from me my girdle and money, and went to the window and drew back the curtain, and shot the money out into his hat. I found the girdle in the room on the ground; the girdle produced in Court made of leather like a purse.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you distinguish the prisoner's face before the curtain of the window was drawn back?</p>
               <p>Symonds. No, I could not: he continued holding my mouth; when the other had the money in his hat, I heard him say to the prisoner, I have got the money; then he took the money from the other person, and went down stairs. I got up and opened the window, and call'd I am in distress, once or twice, &amp;c. in the German language, this was as soon as they were out of the room: I heard them lock the door, they came in again directly upon my calling out at the window. The prisoner stood behind, the other person came, and knock'd me down; and in the mean time gave me a punch in the face; I don't know with what; then he took a knife and held to my throat, and said; bush, bush - your life : from which I understood, if I did not hold my tongue, my life was in danger. When they went down, I went to the door, to see if it was fast, and found it shut; I held my shirt up to the wound on my head; he shew'd a small scar on the top of his head: I put my cloaths on, and went to go down but did not chuse it. I watch'd at the window; when it was daylight somebody came and opened the door softly, when there was a coach call'd at the door. I went down, and the coach was gone; the landlord and two servants stood at the door; I went to him and said, you have my money, (in Dutch.)</p>
               <p>Q. Repeat it in the same manner you did then?</p>
               <p>Symonds. I said, you have my moone when you knock me down, you must be slung by the naik, (making signs to his neck) they laught at me; then I laid down my stick and my knapsack at the door, and went away towards London; a servant came after me, and desired me to come back ; I did, then the landlord shook his hand to me, and desired the servant to hold me fast. I was affrighted and took up my things and went away, crying. I went to the Coach and Horses, where I had quartered the week before at Hounslow, there I complained and shew'd my bloody shirt, but could not make them understand what I said, Then I went to Brentford ; there I had chang'd a ducat, and had about five shillings English money in my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the two persons that came into your room search your breeches?</p>
               <p>Symonds. No, they did not: when I came to London I complain'd to a merchant, Higham Levi, of whom I had be spoke watches to the value of a 100 l. I had also offer'd 40 l. for some second hand cloaths, that came from the Princess of Wales's ; I had also been looking upon some knives, and corkscrews, and was to have paid for these things, when I came back from Bristol.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you, as you was to dispose of so<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175109110004"></xptr> much money in London, to carry it all with you to Bristol, such dangerous times for robbing as is now?</p>
               <p>Symonds. I only bespoke these goods.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you not lodge it in the Bank or elsewhere ?</p>
               <p>Symonds. I have been a merchant ten years, and have travell'd in Turkey, and other places, and never trusted my money out of my sight.</p>
               <p>On his cross examination he said, the money was first seen in England, by a custom-house officer, who had got the girdle in which it was, to search it; who seeing it was gold coin, returned it; that he also shewed one piece at the Coach and Horses at Hounslow, and told the landlady it was worth 9 s. 6 d. a week before he was robbed, where he had lain one night; that his feet were blistered, and he returned to London again; that it was very light in the room; that he had no hurt on his head before he came there that night. When he heard the coach come, it was between five and six in the morning; that the key was the inside the door when he went to bed; that there is no synagogue at Bristol, but a room where the Jews come together; that he had not sent word before hand of his coming; that 100 ducats of this money was his own, and 350 belonged to chancellor Corroney, the governor where he lives under, and the rest to another gentleman in that dominion, named Gobernator, that he was to have bought fine second-hand suits of cloaths for the governor's lady to wear, and also to buy watches for them.</p>
               <p>Higham Levi deposed, they landed together at Harwich ; that they first met together at Helver, and he saw the ducats when the officer wanted to examine the girdle; that he recommended him to a lodging in Duke's place, at 
               <persName id="t17510911-3-person41">
                  Barnard 
                  Abrahams 
               <interp inst="t17510911-3-person41" type="surname" value="Abrahams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person41" type="given" value="Barnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person41" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's house; that he wanted to buy a repeating gold watch; he shewed him one, and asked 30 guineas for it; that after that he came and told him of the robbery about a fortnight ago.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-3-person42">
                  Barnard 
                  Abrahams 
               <interp inst="t17510911-3-person42" type="surname" value="Abrahams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person42" type="given" value="Barnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person42" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed the prosecutor came from Holland, and lodged with him; that he himself deals in old cloaths, and was to supply the prosecutor that way; that he shewed him some which were wore by the princess for which he bid him 40 l. that he directed him on his way as far as Piccadilly for Bristol; and that he return'd, and told him he had been robb'd; that when he went out his gridle was half full of gold.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-3-person43">
                  Sarah 
                  Abrahams 
               <interp inst="t17510911-3-person43" type="surname" value="Abrahams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person43" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person43" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , wife to Bernard, deposed to the prosecutor's lodging with her a fortnight; that she and he reckon'd the money, which was 554 duckets, the day before he was robb'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-3-person44">
                  Jacob 
                  Abrahams 
               <interp inst="t17510911-3-person44" type="surname" value="Abrahams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person44" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person44" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, he travell'd with goods, upwards of 400 l. stock; that he has hid at the prisoner's house frequently, and was always used well; that he lay in Hounslow the night Symonds did, at the prisoner's; there he heard that an outlandish man had been robb'd, who was dressed in an odd manner, and if he had been there, he was told, perhaps, he might have understood his language, &amp;c. and talk for him. Being asked his opinion of the prisoner, he reply'd, he was an honest man.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>This man, the prosecutor, came to my house, when I was in another apartment with a gentleman drinking a bottle of wine. I went into the kitchen, and was told there was a strange man in the bar room, (he had ask'd for some bread, butter and beer, some of my people had carry'd it to him) he was eating it; I went to him, and he made a sort of a congee to me two or three times, he had a lemon lay by him, which he almost insisted upon my taking, which I did, and went out of the room into the kitchen; my man came, and said he wanted a bed; said I, you know I never make beds for foot passengers; tell him he can't lie here. A little time after this, my niece came, and desir'd I would let him have a bed; said I, take the lemon, and give it him, and say it is impossible for him to lie in my house; for I have a family coming, and the servants will take up all my beds. There was a gentlewoman there, which came with my niece, and they then both desir'd I'd let him lie there that night, which I did: the chamber-maid shew'd him up stairs, and fetch'd away his candle; the next morning he came down stairs, and said he had been robb'd. I was much surprized; he said it was by two men that came in at the window, pointing up to the window. I went up-stairs, the curtains at the window were drawn, and the windows were as clean as possible, not so much as the print of a cat's foot, and the key was on the inside the door; he threw down his belt and stick, and went about half a mile towards London; he came back; said I, are not you a scoundrel and a villain to say you have been robb'd, to bring a scandal upon my house? Go and fetch a constable, said I; then he took up his things, and went away. My cook said, I have known two or three people ruin'd by such things,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175109110005"></xptr> as those, where houses have lost their characters on such accounts. I then went with a friend with me, and pursued him as far as Brentford turnpike; we heard of him two or three times upon the road; then we went to Turnham green, where we had a Negus: we return'd back to Brentford again, but could hear nothing of him there; then we got a man to go and search all the houses in the town, to see for this Jew; we went to the Red Lion at Hounslow ; being fatigued, I staid at Mr. Roberts's till the morning, when I went home to Cranford bridge, from whence I went in a post chaise to Smithfield with another person, and bought a horse: we then went and spent the evening at Sadler's wells, from thence to the Salutation in Newgate-street, and likewise to a great many parts of the town, and were never a-part from the time we got up to the time we went to-bed; this was on Saturday: the next morning, when I got to Mr. Roberts's at Hounslow, he shew'd me the advertisement, which struck me much; I took my horse, and went home and clean'd myself; soon after came a messenger to let me know this man was in Hounslow ; I went to take my horse to go there; somebody told me he had a warrant against me; I thought it more proper to return back than to fly in the face of the warrant; every-body desir'd me to go away till I could hear what it was. I said I had no occasion to fly; they insisted upon it I should; then I went over to Hatton, but said to several friends nothing vex'd me more than to think I should fly for an innocent thing; from thence I return'd to Hounslow; then Mr. Roberts and I went in a post chaise-to London, in order to have advice ; and upon that advice, I went and surrendered myself up to justice.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-3-person45">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Perrin 
               <interp inst="t17510911-3-person45" type="surname" value="Perrin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person45" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person45" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am niece to Mr. Godard, who keeps the White Hart at Cranford bridge; this day fortnight, in the evening, the Jew came in about seven o'clock; our drawer and I were in the kitchen, who went into the bar room that is near the road; our drawer went to him, and came back again, and said he ask'd for beer, bread and butter; he ask'd for some water; our drawer carried him some, and presently after that Mr. Godard came: I said, uncle, there is a very odd fort of a fellow in the fore-room, they tell me he is a Hermit ; accordingly he went in, and the man pull'd off his hat, and ask'd, in English, if he was landlord ; I said, yes; he had a lemon lay by him that he had taken out of his bag, and insisted upon Mr. Godard's having it; saying, pray, sir, have it; then he took it, turn'd round, smiled, and went out of the room. I asked him, where he intended to lie? but he gave me no answer: I ask'd him again; he said he was a Polish merchant, and dealt in diamonds, watches, and such things; then I ask'd him a third time; he said, he would lie here; I then told him we never lodg'd any foot passengers. I understood him he said he would give 6 d. but since I thought he said, be at any expence, which I mention'd to Mr. Godard ; he said, how could you ask him, knowing I never lodge such kind of people ? At that time he had shew'd me no money; I told him, here is a family coming, and a gentleman and his servants would take up all our beds. He said, he would die here, for here was his money. Then I went to Mr. Godard again, and said, suppose you was in this man's country, and to be turn'd out at such a time, you would not like it; then he said, let him lie in the dining room bed, there being no furniture on that bed. Mr. Godard went to sleep. I believe, by the kitchen fire: I told the Jew he might lie there; then I found him with a book in his hand, and folding his hands together; I thought it was a prayer book. He took out a little leather purse with clapses, in which I saw about six or seven shillings, and paid me 13 d. for his eating, drinking, and bed. I asked him if he would please to go to bed; he said, he'd speak when he had a mind to go to bed. I talked to him a good while; he asked the name of the place, and I told him; he set it down in a book; I saw he wrote backwards. He asked my uncle's name, but I could not make him understand it; then I gave him a printed bill, and after that he could say 
               <persName id="t17510911-3-person46">
                  Joseph 
                  Godard 
               <interp inst="t17510911-3-person46" type="surname" value="Godard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person46" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person46" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             as plain as I cou'd; presently he said he'd go to bed. I called the chamber maid about a quarter before nine; I never was out of the room from him: he went to bed, and the maid fetched away the candle; my uncle was never in the room but that one time with him; he produced no belt nor gold to my uncle or me; neither was my uncle in the room when he pulled out his silver. When I came down stairs between seven and eight the next morning. I heard he had been robbed; then I went up, and found there was some blood on the sheet, the bed only turned down, as is usual, when one person gets out of it, and not disturbed at all: there was one drop of blood by the window, and two or three more by the bedside; the blood looked very black, as though it had been old blood kept in a bottle two or three days.</p>

               <p>On her cross examination she said, he shewed<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175109110006"></xptr> her his shirt on his left hand sleeve, saying, I am very clean; this was by the kitchen fire; he was such an odd man that she liked to ask him questions; that he answered her by signs with his hands, and talked broken English.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-3-person47">
                  Anne 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17510911-3-person47" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person47" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person47" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the chamber-maid; I was in the room before my master came in; the Jew asked if he was the landlord of the house; he shook hands with him, drank to him, and gave him the lemon; my master took it, turned himself about, went out of the room, and went and sat down by the kitchen fire; I lighted him up to bed, and when we were in the room, he shook hands with me, and bid me good night. I ask'd him if he would blow the candle out? he made signs that he would knock with his stick, which he did, and I went and fetched it; he was then in bed, and I pulled too the door, which is a spring lock. I cannot tell which side of the door the key was on, but in the morning it was on the inside. I heard no noise all the night, only that of the coach stopping: my young mistress was in the room with him all the time he was below, but I was in but twice, and saw no money of his, nor heard him say any thing about it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-3-person48">
                  Anne 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17510911-3-person48" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person48" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person48" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am cook; they said there was a Hermit in the sore room; the young woman asked if her uncle would lodge him, but he said, no; I went and looked at him, and he then pull'd out a spring purse, and took out some shillings, which is all I saw.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-3-person49">
                  John 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17510911-3-person49" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person49" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person49" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I remember this Jew coming down stairs about seven in the morning; he said he had been robbed, saying, two men, two men, (pointing to the window.) I ask'd him, if he knew the persons? but he made me no answer: we then went up stairs, and found the curtains drawn, and the bed was no more tumbled than in common, after a single person had laid in it, and when I came down, he was gone.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-3-person50">
                  Thomas 
                  Ashley 
               <interp inst="t17510911-3-person50" type="surname" value="Ashley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person50" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person50" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I met with this Jew near Brentford turnpike, and asked him if he would drink a pint of beer; I then took hold of his beard in a joke, and he held up his staff and struck me; a man there said, go along old Jew, or you'll have your drubbing; I ran after him, and put him in a ditch, and scratched him in the bushes; then I flung a stone, and it fell on his head, and broke it, which bled: this was three weeks ago.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-3-person51">
                  Thomas 
                  Rickets 
               <interp inst="t17510911-3-person51" type="surname" value="Rickets"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person51" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person51" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Rose and Crown a little on this side the turnpike, near Smallberry green ; I think this Jew is the man, but I can't swear it, who came there and asked for lodgings; I told him you are of the wrong country, for you shall not lodge here: this last evidence came out with some beer, and said to the Jew, will you drink? when he went to lay hold of the mug, Ashley laid hold on his beard: then the Jew shook his stick at him, and Ashley ran after him, I believe, 400 yards before he catch'd him: there were 2 gentlemen came by and said, there was a man had misus'd the poor Jew.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-3-person52">
                  Wm.
                   Taylor
               <interp inst="t17510911-3-person52" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person52" type="given" value="Wm."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person52" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the inn exactly over against Mr. Godard's; I was up at two o'clock, that very morning the Jew says he was robb'd; I saw a coach come by, about half an hour after two: I gave the horses hay, and water, at the door; the clock struck three as they went away. A waggon went by much about four, I lay down on the bed, and got up again between five and six, there was no calling, had there been any I should have heard it. My Ld. Berkeley, Justice Bulstroud, Mr. Withers, Mr. March, 
               <persName id="t17510911-3-person53">
                  Wm 
                  Day 
               <interp inst="t17510911-3-person53" type="surname" value="Day"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person53" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-person53" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Mrs. Barret, each gave the prisoner a good character. There were others to have done the same, but the Jury said it was needless.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510911-3-verdict10" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510911-3-verdict10" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
