<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17540424-29">
               <interp inst="t17540424-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540424-29" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540424-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540424"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540424-29" type="date" value="17540424"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540424-29-off138-c157" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540424-29-defend202 t17540424-29-off138 t17540424-29-verdict142"></join>
         
               <p>258. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17540424-29-defend202" type="defendantName">
                  Hugh
                   M'kave
               <interp inst="t17540424-29-defend202" type="surname" value="M'kave"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-29-defend202" type="given" value="Hugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-29-defend202" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17540424-29-off138" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540424-29-off138" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-29-off138" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               committing a rape on the body of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17540424-29-victim204" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Holmes 
                        <interp inst="t17540424-29-victim204" type="surname" value="Holmes"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540424-29-victim204" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540424-29-victim204" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540424-29-off138 t17540424-29-victim204"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17540424-29-viclabel139" type="occupation">spinster, an infant not five years of age</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540424-29-victim204 t17540424-29-viclabel139"></join>
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17540424-29-cd140" type="crimeDate">March 28</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540424-29-off138 t17540424-29-cd140"></join>. + .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540424-29-person205">
                  Margaret 
                  Holmes 
               <interp inst="t17540424-29-person205" type="surname" value="Holmes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-29-person205" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-29-person205" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am mother to the child. [ She had it in her arms.] On the 28th of March last the prisoner was in my room, and the child was going wriggling about in a strange manner. I asked her what was the matter with her? I thought her petticoats were not tied tight enough, so I tied them tighter; but still she went the same. Then I took her down into the kitchen, and setting her in my lap looked at her, and found her shift was spotted as though a person had spit upon it who had a consumption; she was as raw about the private parts as if she had been skinned. I then sent a porter for my husband, and after that we took her to Mr. Hawkins's, a surgeon in Pallmall. He was not at home, but his servant was. I told him I suspected that the prisoner had used her ill, for he had but the day before confessed he had the foul disease, and also where he got it. It was his opinion the child had the foul disease. After this I went to Mr. Pinkstone in St. Alban's-Street; he examined the child, and said she had been very ill used by some man.</p>
               <p>Q. How old is the child?</p>
               <p>M. Holmes. She was born Jan. 3, 1750. My husband is a <rs id="t17540424-29-deflabel141" type="occupation">tailor</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540424-29-defend202 t17540424-29-deflabel141"></join>, and so is the prisoner, he worked with us. On going out myself I have left the child for a day together in the prisoner's care, and our house being down through an entry in a very by place, very few people come there.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175404240011"></xptr>Q. Is the child cured now?</p>
               <p>M. Holmes. She is not. Mr. Pinkstone gave me an unction to anoint her, and ordered me to wash the part with warm milk, which I still continue to do.</p>
               <p>Q. Is the surgeon here ?</p>
               <p>M. Holmes. No, he is not. He is gone to-day to set a person's leg, I think.</p>
               <p>Jane Thomas. I am a midwife. The mother shewed me the child about a fortnight ago, and I never saw a child in such a condition, unless she had been ill used by a man who had forced her. I suppose this child had and has now the foul distemper upon her, though the ointment has done her some good.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540424-29-person206">
                  Henry 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17540424-29-person206" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-29-person206" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-29-person206" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable. I took the prisoner up, and heard him acknowledge to the justice's clerk that he had the foul distemper upon him; but he denied the fact he was charged with.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540424-29-person207">
                  Ann 
                  Holmes 
               <interp inst="t17540424-29-person207" type="surname" value="Holmes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-29-person207" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-29-person207" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am aunt to the child. My sister came to me on the 28th of March, and told me she feared her child had been used ill by some man, and she suspected the prisoner. I went with her to Mr. Hawkins's, whose servant said she had been used ill by some man, and gave us a letter to go with her to the hospital. I saw the child's private parts were as raw as a piece of beef, and her thighs as hard as a stone; she ran like a tap, and her shift was black and yellow with the filth.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I worked with this woman's husband three years. He owed me some money, and I asked him for it the day before I was taken up As to the fact I am innocent of it, and believe myself clear of that distemper now, though I had it about four years ago.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540424-29-verdict142" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540424-29-verdict142" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17540424-29-punish143" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540424-29-punish143" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540424-29-defend202 t17540424-29-punish143"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
