<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17500425-29">
               <interp inst="t17500425-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500425-29" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500425-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17500425"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500425-29" type="date" value="17500425"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500425-29-off151-c174" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500425-29-defend232 t17500425-29-off151 t17500425-29-verdict153"></join>
         
               <p>325. 
               <persName id="t17500425-29-defend232" type="defendantName">
                  John 
                  Thrift 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-defend232" type="surname" value="Thrift"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-defend232" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-defend232" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for the <rs id="t17500425-29-off151" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-off151" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-off151" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               murder
            </rs> of 
               
                  <persName id="t17500425-29-victim234" type="victimName">
                     David 
                     Faris 
                  <interp inst="t17500425-29-victim234" type="surname" value="Faris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-victim234" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-victim234" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500425-29-off151 t17500425-29-victim234"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17500425-29-cd152" type="crimeDate">March 11</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500425-29-off151 t17500425-29-cd152"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500425-29-person235">
                  Rebecca 
                  Faris 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person235" type="surname" value="Faris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person235" type="given" value="Rebecca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person235" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the widow of the deceased. My husband, 
               <persName id="t17500425-29-person236">
                  Patrick 
                  Farrel 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person236" type="surname" value="Farrel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person236" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Timothy Garvy, and myself, were coming by the Prisoner's Door, on the 11th of March, between five and six in the evening; 
               <persName id="t17500425-29-person237">
                  Patrick 
                  Farrel 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person237" type="surname" value="Farrel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person237" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person237" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said to the deceased, David, Do you know that Man? (meaning the prisoner, who was then standing at his own door). No, says he, I do not, I never saw him in my life to my knowledge. The prisoner's wife sitting at the door overheard the words, and said, you pack of Thieves, suppose it is 
               <persName id="t17500425-29-person238">
                  Jack 
                  Ketch 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person238" type="surname" value="Ketch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person238" type="given" value="Jack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , do you want to rob him? Said 
               <persName id="t17500425-29-person239">
                  Patrick 
                  Farrel 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person239" type="surname" value="Farrel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person239" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I do not want to rob him. and if I have given offence, I am sorry for it. Then the prisoner came out of his house, and struck this Farrel in the Face two or three times, with his fist; he was not satisfied with that, but he went back, pulled off his coat, hat, and wig, and was then in a flannel waistcoat without sleeves; he went in and fetch'd a Cutlass, drawed it, delivered the scaboard to his wife, and pursued the three men, who were then got to the head of the Cole yard, Drury-lane. 
               <persName id="t17500425-29-person240">
                  David 
                  Faris 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person240" type="surname" value="Faris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person240" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             turned round, and saw him coming, on which they three ran; he pursued them cross Drury-lane, into an Arch-way, going under Short's Gardens, and as the deceased ran forward the prisoner struck him on the left Side of his Head, but he held up his stick and kept off several blows from his head, till his foot slipp'd in the Dung, then he fell down, and the prisoner gave him several cuts, but where about I cannot tell. The other man who was confined with the prisoner, 
               <persName id="t17500425-29-person241">
                  Enoch 
                  Stock 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person241" type="surname" value="Stock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person241" type="given" value="Enoch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , upon my crying out my husband was killed, made a blow at me with a stick, which hit the infant in my arms, and stunn'd it. My husband died on the 19th of March</p>

               <p>Cross Examined.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. When this witness was before Justice Fielding, she was very loath to swear to me, till she was ordered to be committed, then she did.</p>
               <p>Reb. Faris. They gave me the book to swear before they asked me any Questions, I did not know what I was going to do; said the Justice if she will not swear commit her directly : Then I swore the prisoner brought out the cutlass, and pursued my husband.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you examined before the Coroner?</p>
               <p>Reb. Faris. Yes, I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you say the same there you do now?</p>
               <p>Reb. Faris. No, I did not, I have now consulted myself.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you give the same account before the Justice you do now?</p>
               <p>Reb. Faris. No, I did not. They asked me who was the man that gave my husband the wound, I could not tell them.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the difference between what you said then and now?</p>
               <p>Reb. Faris. I did not know who struck my husband, nothing else.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175004250012"></xptr>Q. Did the prisoner say one word, till it was said by some of you that he was broke out of Newgate ?</p>
               <p>Reb. Faris. I did hear something like that, but there is no reason that for what another said, my husband should lose his life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500425-29-person242">
                  Timothy 
                  Garvey 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person242" type="surname" value="Garvey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person242" type="given" value="Timothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . As I was walking along with the deceased and Farrel, Farrel said something about 
               <persName id="t17500425-29-person243">
                  Jack 
                  Ketch 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person243" type="surname" value="Ketch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person243" type="given" value="Jack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person243" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , whose wife was coming along, and overheard us; she said, You Thieves, do you want to murder, or rob us? She was coming from towards Drury-lane, and called to her husband, who came out and fell a beating the Man with his fist, in the face, two or three blows. I said, Mr. Thrift don't strike the man any more, perhaps he is in liquor. Then somebody hollowed, I looked back, and saw the prisoner coming with a Hanger in his left hand, in a striped flannel waistcoat without sleeves I stood on one side, he pursued the two men, till they came under the Arch-way at Short's Gardens, where I saw him give the deceased a cut with a hanger or cutlass, on the left side of the head. Faris had a cane in his hand, and held it up with an intent to keep off the blows.</p>
               <p>Cross Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Who struck the first blow?</p>
               <p>Garvey. I saw no blow struck, but what the prisoner gave. The man never struck him.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon what words did this squabble begin ?</p>
               <p>Garvey. Farrel said, that was 
               <persName id="t17500425-29-person244">
                  Jack 
                  Ketch 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person244" type="surname" value="Ketch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person244" type="given" value="Jack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person244" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and his wife overheard him, that was all he said.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any thing about Newgate?</p>
               <p>Garvey. No, not a word. The deceased stood up, and never attempted to strike, or lift up his Hand against the prisoner; he only said, if you don't let me alone I'll strike you, so I took Thrist away.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500425-29-person245">
                  Patrick 
                  Farrel 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person245" type="surname" value="Farrel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person245" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I was present on the 11th of March, in the afternoon between five and six of the clock, we were going along the Cole-yard, and as we went by the prisoner's house, his wife was at the Door, and said, you blackguard what do you look at me for. We then had said nothing at all. Said I, if we do look at you, Mistress, we are not looking at you for any harm at all. You lie, you Teague, said she, but you want to rob the house. We don't, said I, we work very hard for our bread. We went forward, and I saw the prisoner behind, near his own door, who came up and said, what do you want with me? Said I, nothing at all. You do, said he. I said no. He takes hold of me with one hand, and fails a poking me with the other : Then said 
               <persName id="t17500425-29-person246">
                  Timothy 
                  Garvey 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person246" type="surname" value="Garvey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person246" type="given" value="Timothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to him, pray be so good as to go home, and let the young Man go about his business, perhaps he may be a little in liquor ; so he went into the house, and the deceased and Garvey went on: When we were gone about twenty yards, we looked back, and saw him come running with a naked Hanger in his hand, in a white flannel waistcoat. I said to the deceased let us go on fast, for he is coming with something in his hand, which we did, till we got to Short's Gardens, under the Gateway, and there he overtook us; but before he came to the deceased, the deceased took up a little Cane to save himself from damage. The prisoner gave him several blows, which he catch'd; but at last he got a blow over his head, which cut him down under the Gateway. The deceased did not strike at the prisoner at all; the prisoner's man came and knocked me down with a stick, and the prisoner made two blows at me with the hanger: I held my stick up by the middle to keep off the blows, which was broke by that means. I did not strike any blows.</p>
               <p>Cross Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. What words did this fray begin upon ?</p>
               <p>Farrel. There were no words at all, but what I told now.</p>
               <p>Q. Was nothing said by you before the prisoner's wife spoke to you?</p>
               <p>Farrel. No, she said, you blackguard, what do you look at me for? was the very first words.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any mention made about Newgate, or a gold watch?</p>
               <p>Farrel. No, not a word. Without any provocation at all he came up.</p>

               <p>Court. Recollect yourself whether some of your company did not speak something first.</p>
               <p>Farrel. I said as thus, to the deceased, do you know that woman? said I, her husband is 
               <persName id="t17500425-29-person247">
                  Jack 
                  Ketch 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person247" type="surname" value="Ketch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person247" type="given" value="Jack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Then he came up and said, what do you want with me?</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you say, that was 
               <persName id="t17500425-29-person248">
                  Jack 
                  Ketch 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person248" type="surname" value="Ketch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person248" type="given" value="Jack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who had stolen a gold watch and two silver spoons, and was broke out of Newgate ?</p>
               <p>Farrel. No, I did not, nor nobody else that I know of.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500425-29-person249">
                  Thomas 
                  Clutton 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person249" type="surname" value="Clutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person249" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 11th of March, about five o'clock, I was sitting at the Nine-pin house door, the time these three men, and one woman, was going by the door; I heard this last Witness call the prisoner's Wife whore several times, and an eternal whore; after which the prisoner came out of his house, and said, What do you want to rob the house ? He brought out a thing in a scabbard. Then Mr. Strutton, a Baker, met him, and put his hand to his breast, and said, do not bring such a weapon out to naked man. He went in with it directly, and came out again, and stripped into a flannel waistcoat, and said, he'd fight them manfully. Then he went in again, and two<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175004250013"></xptr> men, one of them with a stick, overtook these men, he that hanged the last prisoners was one. The prisoner followed them to the end of Short's Gardens, when the men was engaged one with another: he came up, and chopp'd one over the Forehead. There were two men that ran fighting with the deceased, and Farrel was one: I saw the sticks going as fast as they could go.</p>
               <p>Q. to Farrel. Did not you say, you did not strike any blows? you hear what this witness says.</p>
               <p>Farrel. There were the prisoner, his man, the deceased, and I a fighting.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. This Farrel was the first man who began the quarrel.</p>
               <p>Q. to the deceased's widow. Did you see nothing of this fighting?</p>
               <p>Widow. No, I saw nothing at all of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500425-29-person250">
                  Alice 
                  Waring 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person250" type="surname" value="Waring"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person250" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person250" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw part of this affair on the 11th of March, there were four men and two women just pass'd, and in about a quarter of an hour after I saw a great mob about the prisoner's door. Just as they were gone the prisoner took off his coat, his hat and wig was off before, then he took off his neckcloth, and unbuttoned the neck of his shirt, and followed the men : I saw him give the blow on the deceased's head, and believe there were a thousand People about them then. I saw 
               <persName id="t17500425-29-person251">
                  Enoch 
                  Stock 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person251" type="surname" value="Stock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person251" type="given" value="Enoch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             bleeding as they were coming back, but did not see the deceased do any thing.</p>
               <p>Cross Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he engaged in fighting, when the prisoner struck him with the hanger?</p>
               <p>Waring. He was not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500425-29-person252">
                  Philip 
                  Lisle 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person252" type="surname" value="Lisle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person252" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was sitting at my own door at this time, facing the Green Man, I saw the prisoner in a white waistcoat, and a Scymiter in his hand, follow those people into Drury-lane; he overtook them at a Gateway, and there I saw him take three cuts at the man that is dead. There was another man, named Farrel, with the deceased, with a white coat on, and a stick in his hand. There was a great crowd of people: I saw Farrel making strokes at a little man who was there: The prisoner had first a blow at the deceased's arm, which falling, he then got a blow on his head. I saw the prisoner coming back again, and a man along with him all bleedy. He said, he had been besieged, and he was sorry he had not cut one of their heads off.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500425-29-person253">
                  Robert 
                  Heastfield 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person253" type="surname" value="Heastfield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person253" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a surgeon of Westminster Infarmary; the deceased was brought there, my brother surgeon dressed him. There was a piece cut out of the left side of his head, through the first table, flesh and all. There were four other wounds on different parts of his head, and a wound on his left wrist; I imagined they were from some cutting instrument. Two or three days after he was there, came a friend of the prisoner's, and his wife, and begg'd I would go before the Justice, and give an account how the man was; I said if I go, I must hurt your husband. She went and told the justice I did not care to come. The justice sent for me; I went to the hospital to see the deceased, who then said, as I hope for salvation I am a dying man; I know not how soon I shall go to eternity, and nobody gave me the wound but 
               <persName id="t17500425-29-person254">
                  John 
                  Ketch 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person254" type="surname" value="Ketch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person254" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person254" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; and added, if I die, I hope my friends will do me justice. I think this wound was the cause of his death. At the desire of the justice I went up, there 
               <persName id="t17500425-29-person255">
                  Enoch 
                  Stock 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person255" type="surname" value="Stock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person255" type="given" value="Enoch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person255" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             owned before the justice that he gave the wound, which I thought very extraordinary. Two days before the deceased died, I said to him, seeing him speechless, Consider, hold up your right hand if 
               <persName id="t17500425-29-person256">
                  Jack 
                  Thrist 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person256" type="surname" value="Thrist"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person256" type="given" value="Jack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person256" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             did give you the wound, instead of that he held up the left hand. I thought it strange, but I was told he had lost the use of his right side. Then said I, friend, for God's sake consider, if he did it, then hold up your left hand; he held up his left hand, and shook his head.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence. I did not give the blow. 
               <persName id="t17500425-29-person257">
                  Enoch 
                  Stock 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person257" type="surname" value="Stock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person257" type="given" value="Enoch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person257" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             did take the hanger out of my hand, and cut this man the deceased.</p>
               <p>This being the prisoner's defence, there were other witnesses called for the prosecution.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500425-29-person258">
                  Jacob 
                  Crane 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person258" type="surname" value="Crane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person258" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person258" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a sailor. On the 11th of March, I saw the prisoner at the bar cut the deceased several strokes with a hanger.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500425-29-person259">
                  William 
                  Carrier 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person259" type="surname" value="Carrier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person259" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person259" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the prisoner at this time strike the deceased one blow on the left side of the head with a hanger; I was about five yards distance, and live directly opposite him. He was in a stannel waistcoat without sleeves.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500425-29-person260">
                  William 
                  Clayton 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person260" type="surname" value="Clayton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person260" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person260" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at a house opposite Short's Gardens, and hearing a noise, I went out and saw two persons engaged with Mr. Thrist, and he struck the deceased with a hanger.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500425-29-person261">
                  Daniel 
                  Boseen 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person261" type="surname" value="Boseen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person261" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person261" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the prisoner at this time give a blow to the deceased</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500425-29-person262">
                  Ann 
                  Boseen 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person262" type="surname" value="Boseen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person262" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person262" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed the same.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500425-29-person263">
                  John 
                  Bailey 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person263" type="surname" value="Bailey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person263" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person263" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I looked over the croud, and saw the prisoner in a flannel waistcoat strike the deceased with a hanger; I was about five yards off.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500425-29-person264">
                  William 
                  Symonds 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person264" type="surname" value="Symonds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person264" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person264" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the prisoner strike the deceased with a hanger.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175004250014"></xptr>Prisoner. I had been twice at St. Giles's church that day, and as I was coming home through Drury-lane, Farrel began the quarrel. There were four of them, the deceased's wife was one, with a child in her arms. I turned into the Coal-yard where I live. Blood and ounds, said Farrel, do you know who this is coming along? No, said the deceased, I do not know him; he said again, that is 
               <persName id="t17500425-29-person265">
                  Jack 
                  Ketch 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person265" type="surname" value="Ketch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person265" type="given" value="Jack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person265" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he stole a gold watch, and two silver spoons, and has broke out of Newgate. Said I, go along, you black-guard dog; they said, there was ten guineas reward for taking of me. Farrel knock'd me down at my own door. I strove to take the stick out of his hand, the others of them gave me another blow, and knock'd me down again. I desired my wife to fetch the hanger, and I do declare it never was out of the scabbard, till 
               <persName id="t17500425-29-person266">
                  Enoch 
                  Stock 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person266" type="surname" value="Stock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person266" type="given" value="Enoch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person266" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             took it out.</p>
               <p>Elliet. On the 11th of March, I saw the prisoner coming down the Coal-yard. I saw four men and two women, one had a child there. One said to the other, do you know that man? meaning the prisoner. The other answered, no He said, it is 
               <persName id="t17500425-29-person267">
                  Jack 
                  Ketch 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person267" type="surname" value="Ketch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person267" type="given" value="Jack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he is broke out of Newgate, let's take him. Thrift said, if you want him, come and take him. One of them took up a stick by the middle, intending to strike the prisoner; he fetched a blow at him, and I took hold of the stick, and got it out of his hands. Then the prisoner pulled off his coat and waistcoat, and said, put down your stick, and fight me like a man. Then Enoch Stock coming, said, what is the matter ? The prisoner said, for God's sake, help me, or I shall be killed; then he was knock'd down. He got up again, then he snatch'd the hanger out of Thrift's hand, and fought his way through the mob to Short's-gardens, where the people were fighting. After the fight was over, and the deceased was cut, I took the hanger from 
               <persName id="t17500425-29-person268">
                  Enoch 
                  Stock 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person268" type="surname" value="Stock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person268" type="given" value="Enoch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and brought it to the prisoner's house. Enoch followed me, bleeding in a sad manner, which seemed to be done with sticks; then the prisoner washed his wounds; afterwards he said, he made it reek go against the deceased's head. I saw him fighting with it, &amp;c. I live in the prisoner's house; since he has been in trouble, I have done business for him.</p>
               <p>On his cross examination, he said 
               <persName id="t17500425-29-person269">
                  Enoch 
                  Stock 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person269" type="surname" value="Stock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person269" type="given" value="Enoch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was dressed in a brown wig, but he lost it then.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500425-29-person270">
                  Patience 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person270" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person270" type="given" value="Patience"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person270" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw some of this squabble, and saw three or four men with sticks in their hands; they swore they would knock the prisoner's brains out as he was coming from church, and had he not ran behind some women, they would have killed him. He desired his wife to fetch the hanger, and it was brought out not drawn. They knock'd the prisoner down, then Enoch Stock snatched the hanger out of his hand, and went under the gate-way at Short's gardens; I saw him cutting at some body, they with sticks, and he with a hanger. I never changed three words with the prisoner in my days before this happened.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500425-29-person271">
                  John 
                  Collison 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person271" type="surname" value="Collison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person271" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person271" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw at this time three men fighting two men, Enoch Stock was one ; they fought with sticks blow for blow, and they knock'd Enoch down; then there came up a young fellow, and knock'd one of them down. Enoch got up again, and the Irishmen went off; then Stock pulled his coat off, and went to Garbey, and said you are one of them. I laid hold of him, and said what are you at, you fool? He then had a hanger in his hand, and struck the deceased with it. The prisoner was about three yards behind Enoch at that time. There was a great croud, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500425-29-person272">
                  William 
                  Cook 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person272" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person272" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person272" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in Drury-lane the 11th of March, and saw some men fighting with sticks, but I saw no hanger at all. I heard one of them swear he'd cut Jack Ketch's brains out; this was at Short's-gardens.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Call 
               <persName id="t17500425-29-person273">
                  Enoch 
                  Stock 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person273" type="surname" value="Stock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person273" type="given" value="Enoch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person273" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Court. What do you call him for?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He knows, and has owned he did it, and I think he will not deny it.</p>
               <p>Court. We shall not ask him that question, for he'll not own it here.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500425-29-person274">
                  Enoch 
                  Stock 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person274" type="surname" value="Stock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person274" type="given" value="Enoch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person274" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 11th of March, I was drinking a pint of beer at a publick house in Drury-lane with a friend. About a quarter of an hour after five in the evening, I parted with him, and was standing to make water; I heard a great noise, and I went up to the mob to see what was the matter, as far as the gate-way near Short's-gardens. I heard the prisoner say, you thieves, have you a mind to murder me; they were beating him with sticks, four of them. He said, for God's sake, help me, for these rogues will kill me. When he saw me, I had known him nineteen or twenty years. I did not see him hit any of them, but stood against the wall in a white flannel waistcoat. They knock'd me down several times, and broke my head in several places, also my little finger in defending my head. I was quite stunned, and lost my senses; I strove to get up two or three times, and they knocked me down again.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175004250015"></xptr> I went home hanging on the prisoner's shoulder. He produced his shirt all bloody. &amp;c.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you see the hanger?</p>
               <p>Stock. Yes, but I do not know what became of it, I do not know how I got way, they beat me so unmercifully.</p>
               <p>Justice Fielding. The same night the deceased's wife came to my house, and I was told there was a man below, it was thought had received his death's wound, all over blood: I offered the woman the book to swear; she was some time before she would, at last she was sworn; all she said was, A man, whom they call 
               <persName id="t17500425-29-person275">
                  Jack 
                  Ketch 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person275" type="surname" value="Ketch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person275" type="given" value="Jack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person275" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , had given her husband this wound. I asked her over and over, she said she did not know him; repeating that often, she did not know him; but was told it was 
               <persName id="t17500425-29-person276">
                  Jack 
                  Ketch 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person276" type="surname" value="Ketch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person276" type="given" value="Jack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person276" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; the Deceased he said the same: On the Monday the prisoner came himself before me, and desired me to grant a warrant for a violent assault; I told him I had granted a warrant on that occasion already, and I should not grant cross warrants, &amp;c. I told him he had best go and get himself bail; he said he would go and surrender himself; after the surgeon told me he believed the man was not likely to recover, the prisoner came, then I refused bail, and committed him; and there was a positive oath against 
               <persName id="t17500425-29-person277">
                  Enoch 
                  Stock 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person277" type="surname" value="Stock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person277" type="given" value="Enoch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person277" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , that he committed the fact, so I committed him too. The prisoner did surrender himself.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500425-29-person278">
                  John 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17500425-29-person278" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person278" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-person278" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable; the prisoner did surrender himself to me. I let him walk before me to Justice Fielding's. I was afraid of amob, so I bid him walk before, which he did, there the woman said she could not swear to him.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500425-29-verdict153" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-verdict153" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17500425-29-punish154" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500425-29-punish154" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500425-29-defend232 t17500425-29-punish154"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
