<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510523-15">
               <interp inst="t17510523-15" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510523-15" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510523-15" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510523"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510523-15" type="date" value="17510523"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510523-15-off81-c101" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-15-defend130 t17510523-15-off81 t17510523-15-verdict84"></join>
         
               <p>367. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17510523-15-defend130" type="defendantName">
                     Ralph 
                     Suthernwood 
                  <interp inst="t17510523-15-defend130" type="surname" value="Suthernwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-15-defend130" type="given" value="Ralph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-15-defend130" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17510523-15-off81" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510523-15-off81" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-15-off81" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               putting in corporal fear, and robbing 
                     <persName id="t17510523-15-victim131" type="victimName">
                        
                           
                              <persName id="t17510523-15-victim133" type="victimName">
                                 Paul Isaac 
                                 Gandon
                              <interp inst="t17510523-15-victim133" type="surname" value="Gandon"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17510523-15-victim133" type="given" value="Paul Isaac"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17510523-15-victim133" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        </persName>
                           
                        , of a hat, value 4 s. and Ann his wife<interp inst="t17510523-15-victim131" type="surname" value="Gandon"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510523-15-victim131" type="given" value="Paul Isaac"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510523-15-victim131" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , of one linen handkerchief, value 1 s. 6 d. on the king's highway
            </rs>, <rs id="t17510523-15-cd82" type="crimeDate">May 6</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-15-off81 t17510523-15-cd82"></join>. * </p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-15-person134">
                  Paul Isaac 
                  Gandon 
               <interp inst="t17510523-15-person134" type="surname" value="Gandon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-15-person134" type="given" value="Paul Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-15-person134" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Great Earl Street, seven Dials. On the sixth of May, I and my wife had been at Old Bethlam to sup with a friend, and were coming home; I had my young child in my arms. My two apprentices were with me; 
               <persName id="t17510523-15-person135">
                  Paul 
                  Gibson 
               <interp inst="t17510523-15-person135" type="surname" value="Gibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-15-person135" type="given" value="Paul"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-15-person135" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the youngest, had a flambeaux lighting us, going before us, after 10 o'clock. When I got to the bellows maker, within two or three doors of <placeName id="t17510523-15-crimeloc83">Broad St. Giles's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17510523-15-crimeloc83" type="placeName" value="Broad St. Giles's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510523-15-crimeloc83" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-15-off81 t17510523-15-crimeloc83"></join>, the prisoner at the bar stopped my apprentice and put his flambeaux out. I gave my wife the child and went up to them; they had each of them hold of it. I took and shook it in again. The prisoner swore, d - n his eyes, he'd knock my brains out. I bid my wife go before me; when I had gone 20 or 30 yards, on a sudden I received a blow on the back part of my head, which knocked me down. I got up and missed my hat; I went into a distiller's shop at the corner of Drury-lane, and desired I might leave my wig there, it being dirty. My wife was crying out, murder! thieves! the rogue in a white coat has knocked my husband down. I followed the prisoner down Drury-lane ; a person met and stop'd him; there came a watchman, he would not assist us, he got away. The day after I found him at the King's head, the corner of Monmouth-street.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-15-person136">
                  Ann 
                  Gandon 
               <interp inst="t17510523-15-person136" type="surname" value="Gandon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-15-person136" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-15-person136" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was with my husband going home that night between 10 and 11 o'clock; the youngest apprentice was lighting us. My husband was knock'd down at the corner of the brandy shop by the prisoner. I saw him as he was going to strike the blow, it was with his fist. When my husband was down the prisoner took his hat from the ground, then he came and snatched the handkerchief from my child's neck, as it was in my arms, and struck me up against a bulk, and swore he would knock my eyes out; he wrap'd it up and put it into his right hand pocket and run away down Drury-lane; he was stop'd near a window. There came a watchman up, to whom I said, it is very hard you will not take care of my husband and me; he would not assist. I got my husband away fearing mischief.</p>
               <p>Ogle. Taylor. I am an apprentice to the prosecutor, the other apprentice was before at this time with the flambeaux in his hand. We were near the corner of Drury lane in Broad St. Giles's. The prisoner blew the light out, and went to take it out of 
               <persName id="t17510523-15-person137">
                  Paul 
                  Gibson 
               <interp inst="t17510523-15-person137" type="surname" value="Gibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-15-person137" type="given" value="Paul"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-15-person137" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's hand; then my mater took the flambeaux and shook it in, saying, what was that for? then my master went on; the prisoner d - d his eyes and limbs, and said something, I know not what. The prisoner went up to my master, and knock'd him down. I saw him do it, and sell on my master, and getting up, he took my master's hat that lay on the ground, and put it on his own head; then he came up to my mistress, and shoved her up against a bulk, and took the handkerchief from the child's neck, and ran down Drury-lane. My mistress crying out, stop thief! the man in the white coat has rob'd my husband; he was stop'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain the prisoner is the man?</p>
               <p>Taylor. I could see his face when he blow'd the light out, and also the distiller's shop door was open, I saw him plainly. They were all ask'd if they ever saw the prisoner before this night, to which they answer'd in the negative.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-15-person138">
                  Paul 
                  Gibson 
               <interp inst="t17510523-15-person138" type="surname" value="Gibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-15-person138" type="given" value="Paul"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-15-person138" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am fourteen years old. I was coming lighting master and mistress along, the prisoner came and said something to me, I can't tell what, I think it was, what, are you going to run the flambeaux in my face. I said to him, I cannot as I hold it; I had got it underhanded with the light downwards; he immediately blew it out and took hold of it; my master came and took it and shook it in; then we went on about twenty or thirty yards I believe; the prisoner came up and struck my master over the top of his head and knock'd him down with his fist, and fell upon him; my master's hat fell from his head, the prisoner got up, took it, and ran down Drury-lane; my mistress cry'd out, stop thief, the man in the white coat has knock'd my husband down and robb'd him. I did not see him take any thing from my mistress. A man coming along stop'd the prisoner, their heels slip'd and they broke two panes of glass at a window, I knew him to be the man; we call'd a watchman, he would not lay hold of him, so he got off, but was taken the next day.</p>

               <p>James M'Pearson. I am a smith by trade, I was coming home from work, I heard a great cry of murder, stop thief, &amp;c. hearing the words, by the light of a shop where they sell old glass bottles, I saw the prisoner's coat, which was a white one, his foot slip'd as he ran and fell down,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175105230010"></xptr> I took him by the collar; the prosecutor came up who said, this is the villain that robb'd me.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the night was this?</p>
               <p>M'Pearson. The watch was going past ten o'clock at the end of Drury-lane.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain the prisoner is the man?</p>
               <p>M'Pearson. I am certain of that, my Lord. They call'd out to the watch to come and take charge of him, but he would not, so he got away.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was going to see after my wife but could not find her, coming home I saw a great mob of people, there was fighting; as I came by the bottle shop a man took me by the collar, and shoved me against the wall, and broke two panes of glass; they call'd out, watch, watch; the watch came and said, what has the man done, I see nothing upon him; and said to me, honest man go about your business, you have not wrong'd any body; they said, I had robb'd them of a hat and handkerchief. I live with my father at the Plough in Thomas street.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-15-person139">
                  Ann 
                  Crow 
               <interp inst="t17510523-15-person139" type="surname" value="Crow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-15-person139" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-15-person139" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a distiller's shop, and live at the corner of Drury-lane. I remember the prosecutor's coming to my house that evening, the 6th of May, he laid a wig down on the compter. I said, pray friend take your wig away, I'll suffer no disturbance in my shop. He said, I'll return and give you all the satisfaction you can desire. There was a prodigious noise abroad. He went out; I look'd out, and saw him and another man had hold of the prisoner at the bar. They charged him with a robbery. After this the prosecutor's wife came into my shop, and beg'd I'd take hold of her child, for her husband would be murder'd. She laid her child down, went out again, and immediately return'd with her husband and apprentices, and several other people. She said to him, have you lost your watch? He said he had lost nothing but his hat, which was knock'd off his head. At the same time he brought a dirty hat and wig, and laid them on the compter, saying, if that hat and wig were enquir'd for, he would then find out the man who had robb'd him. Then his wife seem'd to be in a great fright, saying, she had lost her bundle. I said, it is here. She open'd it and said nothing was lost. Said I, have you lost any thing else? She said, no. The child was wrap'd up in a petticoat, and a cloak round it; it had nothing about it's neck, neither did it appear by the bundle as though it had had a handkerchief about it. She desir'd I'd take notice that she had lost nothing.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs. Gandon. Did you say so?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Gandon. I said at the door of the shop, I had lost a handkerchief from the child's neck.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-15-person140">
                  Philip 
                  Short 
               <interp inst="t17510523-15-person140" type="surname" value="Short"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-15-person140" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-15-person140" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner seven years, he is a chair-man, and bears a very honest character.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Carral. I live opposite Mrs. Crow. The prisoner was stop'd at my door: when all was over, I pick'd up a cap and feather at our door, it belong'd to the prosecutor's wife. She first said she had lost her bundle; but when Mrs. Crow told her it was safe, then she did not say she had lost any thing at all.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-15-person141">
                  Jane 
                  Graves 
               <interp inst="t17510523-15-person141" type="surname" value="Graves"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-15-person141" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-15-person141" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never heard any thing amiss of the prisoner in my life; I have known him many years.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510523-15-verdict84" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510523-15-verdict84" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
