<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510227-47">
               <interp inst="t17510227-47" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510227-47" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510227-47" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510227"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510227-47" type="date" value="17510227"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510227-47-off232-c389" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510227-47-defend473 t17510227-47-off232 t17510227-47-verdict236"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510227-47-off237-c389" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510227-47-defend473 t17510227-47-off237 t17510227-47-verdict236"></join>
         
               <p>243 . (L.) 
               <persName id="t17510227-47-defend473" type="defendantName">
                  Mary, the <rs id="t17510227-47-deflabel231" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510227-47-defend473 t17510227-47-deflabel231"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17510227-47-person474">
                        Henry 
                        Pearson 
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-person474" type="surname" value="Pearson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510227-47-person474" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510227-47-person474" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-defend473" type="surname" value="Pearson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-defend473" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-defend473" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17510227-47-off232" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-off232" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-off232" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 4 linen shirts val. 20 s. a pair of stockings, a green silk gown, a velvet hood, a metal tweezer case, the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17510227-47-victim476" type="victimName">
                           Elizabeth 
                           Boomer 
                        <interp inst="t17510227-47-victim476" type="surname" value="Boomer"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510227-47-victim476" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510227-47-victim476" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17510227-47-viclabel233" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510227-47-victim476 t17510227-47-viclabel233"></join>. One pair of sleeve buttons, val. 2 s. 6 d. one cambrick handkerchief laced, val. 10 s. one muslin handkerchief
            </rs>, the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17510227-47-victim478" type="victimName">
                     Mary 
                     Boomer 
                  <interp inst="t17510227-47-victim478" type="surname" value="Boomer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-victim478" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-victim478" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17510227-47-viclabel234" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510227-47-victim478 t17510227-47-viclabel234"></join>, <rs id="t17510227-47-cd235" type="crimeDate">Feb. 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510227-47-off232 t17510227-47-cd235"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510227-47-off237 t17510227-47-cd235"></join> ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510227-47-person479">
                  Mary 
                  Boomer 
               <interp inst="t17510227-47-person479" type="surname" value="Boomer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-person479" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-person479" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , spinster. 
               <persName id="t17510227-47-person480">
                  Mary 
                  Boomer 
               <interp inst="t17510227-47-person480" type="surname" value="Boomer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-person480" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-person480" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , widow, is my aunt, the prisoner lodged in our house.</p>
               <p>Q. Is your aunt a house-keeper ?</p>
               <p>M. Boomer. She is.</p>
               <p>Q. Did your aunt lose any thing lately?</p>
               <p>M. Boomer. Yes, my lord, the tenth of February. The prisoner had hired the room about three weeks or a month before we missed the things.</p>
               <p>Q. What things?</p>
               <p>M. Boomer. Things taken out of a chest of drawers in her lodging room.</p>
               <p>Q. There is another indictment for things she took out of her lodging room, I perceive, but you must say nothing of them now.</p>
               <p>M. Boomer. The chest of drawers were not let to her as part of the furniture. She had no right to them.</p>
               <p>Q. What were taken out of these drawers?</p>
               <p>M. Boomer. There was a green silk night gown, four shifts, a pair of green silk stockings, a metal tweezer case; they belong to my aunt.</p>
               <p>Q. Were these drawers locked up?</p>
               <p>M. Boomer. To the best of my knowledge they were locked, but I cannot be certain. There were three handkerchiefs taken ( a cambrick apron, some silver lace, a pair of sleeve buttons) out of a pair of drawers in my room.</p>
               <p>Q. Why do you charge the prisoner?</p>
               <p>M. Boomer. Because she owned it, and told us she had pawned them to three different pawnbrokers;<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175102270033"></xptr> two of them lived in Aldersgate-street, the other in Barbican. I also had been told she was seen in my room.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you upon that examine your drawers?</p>
               <p>M. Boomer. No, my lord, I did not. I found all my aunt's things except the velvet hood, that we could not find. The four shifts of my aunt I had put into the drawers but a little before. Part of the goods produced in court and deposed to.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510227-47-person481">
                  Edward 
                  Shepherd 
               <interp inst="t17510227-47-person481" type="surname" value="Shepherd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-person481" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-person481" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard the prisoner confess she took these goods clandestinely out of the room, and that she had pawned them.</p>
               <p>Q. Had she any promises of mercy or threats made to her when she confessed this ?</p>
               <p>Shepherd. She had favourable promises made her when she confessed the first time.</p>
               <p>Q. By who ?</p>
               <p>Shepherd. Mrs. Boomer promised her if she would fetch them out of pawn she would put it into a debt, a nd the prisoner should pay so much a week till it was out.</p>
               <p>Q. Then she was willing to give her credit for them, if she could have them again, was she?</p>
               <p>Shepherd. Yes, my lord, she was. The goods were delivered into Mr. Parks's hands.</p>
               <p>Mr. Parks. I am constable, I did not make any memorandum of the day of the month. They brought me a warrant from my lord mayor, and I went along with Mrs. Boomer and the prisoner. The prisoner asked for the things at the pawnbroker's. I took the things to my house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear these promises made her in case she would confess?</p>
               <p>Parks. They did tell her in my hearing she should not suffer on condition she would make good the damages.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her character?</p>
               <p>Parks. I have heard several people give her a good character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510227-47-person482">
                  Richard 
                  Pinfold 
               <interp inst="t17510227-47-person482" type="surname" value="Pinfold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-person482" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-person482" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live near the prosecutrix, she sent for me to go along with the prisoner to see the things taken out of pawn; two went with her to three pawnbrokers, two lived in Aldersgate-street, and one in Barbican; they were left in the pawnbroker's hands till the next day, then they were fetched out by the constable.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>When I took the lodgings in this house, the things Mrs. Boomer lent me, and the young woman said if I could raise two guineas she would not let me see my lord mayor, when I was in the hall.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs. Boomer, spinster. Is this true?</p>
               <p>M. Boomer. It is false every word of it, my lord.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Martha Hill. I have known the prisoner from a child ; she has lived near me. Before this I never heard she did a dishonest thing or ever was suspected. She has been in great distress of thro' the unkindness of her husband.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510227-47-person483">
                  John 
                  Clarkson 
               <interp inst="t17510227-47-person483" type="surname" value="Clarkson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-person483" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-person483" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner seven or eight years, I know no ill of her. I know her husband, and I fear he was the occasion of this misfortune.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510227-47-person484">
                  Thomas 
                  Robins 
               <interp inst="t17510227-47-person484" type="surname" value="Robins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-person484" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-person484" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her about seven years, I never heard any harm of her before, or that she was ever guilty of an ill action.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510227-47-person485">
                  John 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17510227-47-person485" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-person485" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-person485" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner eleven or twelve years, she has a very good character.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510227-47-person486">
                  John 
                  Ross 
               <interp inst="t17510227-47-person486" type="surname" value="Ross"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-person486" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-person486" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was by when the prisoner was carried before my lord-mayor; there was M. Boomer, spinster; I remember there was some conversation between the prisoner and she: I heard her say she had no intent to hurt her, upon this condition, that if she could get any friends to raise her two guineas they would not hurt her. The prisoner said she knew no friends that would raise the money.</p>
               <p>Q. to M. Boomer, spinster. Did you see this witness when you was going to my lord mayor, and do you remember this conversation?</p>
               <p>M. Boomer. I saw him, but never said any such words indeed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510227-47-person487">
                  William 
                  Vowel 
               <interp inst="t17510227-47-person487" type="surname" value="Vowel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-person487" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-person487" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodge in the prosecutrix's house, I was in the room when M. Boomer, spinster, came into it first of all. She seemed to be in a flurry of spirits, that there were things missing; she asked the prisoner if she took them, the prisoner answered she knew nothing of them: the young woman said I am afraid you are the person that is guilty, still the prisoner persisted in it that she knew nothing of it. After that the gentlewoman came and called the prisoner down stairs to her aunt; and there were proposals made, if she would come to a confession. They said they would make it a debt, and take it as she could pay. I saw the confession she made, I was before my lord-mayor with them.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you hear the proposal about the two guineas?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175102270034"></xptr>Vowel. I heard nothing at all, I kept at a distance behind them.</p>
               <p>Q. What is Mrs. Boomer?</p>
               <p>Vowel. She takes in pawns, and sells liquor privately in the way of distillery; it is a very sober house, the White Lyon coffee-house in Charter-house street.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510227-47-verdict236" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-verdict236" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acq
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>She was a second time indicted for <rs id="t17510227-47-off237" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-off237" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-off237" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a linen sheet, a brass candlestick, and a blanket, out of her lodging room let by contract
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510227-47-cd238" type="crimeDate">Feb. 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510227-47-off232 t17510227-47-cd238"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510227-47-off237 t17510227-47-cd238"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510227-47-verdict239" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510227-47-verdict239" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acq
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
