<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17571026-12">
               <interp inst="t17571026-12" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17571026-12" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17571026-12" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17571026"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17571026-12" type="date" value="17571026"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17571026-12-off64-c90" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571026-12-defend108 t17571026-12-off64 t17571026-12-verdict66"></join>
         
               <p>387. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17571026-12-defend108" type="defendantName">
                  Samuel 
                  Drybutter 
               <interp inst="t17571026-12-defend108" type="surname" value="Drybutter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-defend108" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-defend108" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17571026-12-off64" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-off64" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-off64" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing two tortoishell snuff boxes unmounted, value three pounds three shillings
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17571026-12-victim110" type="victimName">
                     James 
                     Cox 
                  <interp inst="t17571026-12-victim110" type="surname" value="Cox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-victim110" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-victim110" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17571026-12-victim112" type="victimName">
                     Edward 
                     Grace 
                  <interp inst="t17571026-12-victim112" type="surname" value="Grace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-victim112" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-victim112" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17571026-12-cd65" type="crimeDate">Sept. 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571026-12-off64 t17571026-12-cd65"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571026-12-person113">
                  Edward 
                  Grace 
               <interp inst="t17571026-12-person113" type="surname" value="Grace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person113" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person113" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 19th of September Mr. Allen call'd upon me, saying he had something to shew me; he shew'd me two snuff boxes, and I immediately said they were our's.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you a partner ?</p>
               <p>Grace. 
               <persName id="t17571026-12-person114">
                  James 
                  Cox 
               <interp inst="t17571026-12-person114" type="surname" value="Cox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person114" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is my partner. I asked him where he had them, and he said he had them of Samuel Drybutter (the prisoner at the bar) to mount for him.</p>
               <p>Q. By what do you know them?</p>
               <p>Grace. I can swear to one of them, because the mark on the inside is my own figuring of what it cost me; as to the other, the mark was rob'd out. Being sure I had never sold it myself, I asked my Partner whether he had or not, and he said no. Then I asked Mr. Allen to go with me to justice Welch. We went thither, and his worship granted a warrant for the prisoner. I went and served it, and took him before Mr. Welch, where I charged him with stealing the two boxes. Mr. Drybutter said that Mr. Cox had deliver'd them to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Mr. Cox present at the time ?</p>
               <p>Grace. He was, and took his oath that he never deliver'd them to him. (The boxes produced in court. He takes up one of them. ) This I can swear to be my property.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Grace. I believe about two years.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you look upon him to be a master or a servant ?</p>
               <p>Grace. I always look'd upon him to be a servant to his mother.</p>
               <p>Q. Does not she keep a reputable shop somewhere?</p>
               <p>Grace. She does, in Pall-Mall.</p>
               <p>Q. Does she follow the same trade as you?</p>
               <p>Grace. We are in the wholesale way, and she in the retail; she deals in some articles that we do.</p>
               <p>Q. Does she not likewise keep another shop in Westminster Hall, on the left hand?</p>
               <p>Grace. I always look'd upon it that she kept that shop.</p>
               <p>Q. In whose name do you make your bills our ?</p>
               <p>Grace. In the name of 
               <persName id="t17571026-12-person115">
                  Jane 
                  Drybutter 
               <interp inst="t17571026-12-person115" type="surname" value="Drybutter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person115" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person115" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Do you not know that she keeps another shop at Tunbridge?</p>
               <p>Grace. I do, by hear-say.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether they have not laid out a great deal of money at your shop?</p>
               <p>Grace. I believe about sixty or seventy pounds.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175710260011"></xptr>Q. Whether, supposing goods are ask'd for at one of these shops, and the party has not such goods, it is not customary for the wholesale dealer to let the retail dealer have goods to shew?</p>
               <p>Grace. Sometimes it is.</p>
               <p>Q. Don't the retail customer sometimes desire a thing to shew, when you don't know whether they will buy it or not ?</p>
               <p>Grace. Sometimes we do let them have them so, and sometimes not.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you or your partner have not let Mr. Drybutter have jewels, such as a diamond ring, worth thirty or forty guineas?</p>
               <p>Grace. My partner may, but I have not.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you deal largely ?</p>
               <p>Grace. We have a very considerable business.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he been frequently at your house?</p>
               <p>Grace. He has.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether the delivery of these boxes might not have slip'd out of your partner's head?</p>
               <p>Grace. I apprehend not.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you do not, from your own knowledge, know several instances of that fallibility of your partner, as you sell large quantities at a time ?</p>
               <p>Grace. Sometimes we sell a box alone to them that sell again, and sometimes many articles in a parcel; sometimes a hundred pounds worth at a time, and perhaps a hundred articles for it.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you keep an open shop?</p>
               <p>Grace. No, we do not.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether it is not probable your partner might make a mistake?</p>
               <p>Grace. He has sworn he has not made a mistake in this.</p>
               <p>Q. As to a note of eleven hundred pounds, did he not make a mistake once ?</p>
               <p>Grace. He once did drop a note of eleven hundred pounds upon 'Change, but that is nothing at all to the purpose, as to such an affair as this.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon settling accounts with the prisoner once, whether there was not a book, mounted with gold, omitted, which you should have charged?</p>
               <p>Grace. I do not remember such a thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he not come and return you a book worth seven guineas and a half, that you had not mention'd in your account?</p>
               <p>Grace. No; I do not remember any such thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it usual upon surmises of this sort to go and take out a warrant, without calling upon the man to talk with him first ?</p>
               <p>Grace. I don't know whether it is usual or not; but when a person loses a thing and thinks he is rob'd of it, he has a right to do himself justice.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you don't know that the prisoner at the bar was well acquainted with your dealing with Allen ?</p>
               <p>Grace. I suppose he knew that, but I am not certain; I will go so far as to say I believe he did know that.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether, if the prisoner had feloniously taken these boxes, he would have sent them there with the marks on them?</p>
               <p>Grace. I apprehend he thought they never would have came to our sight again.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether a man could not, with the least trouble in the world, take that mark of your's out?</p>
               <p>Grace. He might easily have taken them out; I could rub them out with my finger, and the mark was rub'd out of one of them.</p>
               <p>Q. How can you say the mark was taken out of one of them, when you can't swear to it.</p>
               <p>Grace. Mr Allen told me his servant rub'd out the mark from that, and was going to rub out the other, had he not forbid him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571026-12-person116">
                  Joseph 
                  Allen 
               <interp inst="t17571026-12-person116" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person116" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person116" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was sent to by Mr. Drybutter, to know if I could mount him these 2 boxes; I was very ill then. About a week after I sent my servant to know what price he would go to, and how he would have them done? He sent word he bought them cheap, and he would have them done cheap.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know this of your own knowledge, or by hear-say?</p>
               <p>Allen. He said so since to me, and that was his answer he sent me; they were good boxes, and I did not think the order was sufficient, so I mounted them well, that is, my servant did for me. Mr. Cox having some time before spoke to me to mount some of the same kind, I call'd upon him and said I had something to shew him, saying, they were like such boxes as he wanted me to mount. He and his partner looked at them and said, where had you these boxes, they are not gold, they are not such as we want; who are they mounted for? I said, for Mr. Drybutter. They said one to the other, these are our boxes, and there was their mark upon one of them; and Mr. Grace insisted upon my going with him to Westminster-Hall, which we did. Mr. Drybutter saw me at a distance, and when I came up to him he said, have you brought my boxes. I said, I don't know: I have brought the boxes your servant brought to me, if they are your's. He said, they<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175710260012"></xptr> are, so I delivered them to him. He asked me what I must have for doing them. I said, 12 s. a piece. He said, he would give but 4 s. a piece. I had a constable along with me. I would not agree to take 8 s. for them both. He said, I should take one into my possession, and he'd keep the other till he inquired the price. I said, I should keep them both, so took them, and gave the constable charge of him, he having the warrant.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571026-12-person117">
                  Richard 
                  Finch 
               <interp inst="t17571026-12-person117" type="surname" value="Finch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person117" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person117" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Allen. My mistress told me Mr. Drybutter's servant brought these two boxes to be mounted (looking upon them.) In two or three days after I went there, in order to know in what manner he would have them done. He shew'd me an oval green box, and said he would have them done in that manner. I said, they were very good tortoishell boxes, and would afford a better mount; he said, it did not signify, for he bought them cheap, and he intended to have them mounted cheap.</p>

               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you carry the boxes back and shew him them?</p>
               <p>Finch. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571026-12-person118">
                  Robert 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17571026-12-person118" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person118" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person118" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am apprentice to Mr. Drybutter, and carried two boxes to Mr. Allen's, to be mounted, by my master's order [he looks at them] these are I believe the very same.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you see there?</p>
               <p>Wright. I saw Mr. Allen.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the last evidence there?</p>
               <p>Wright. No, I did not; I deliver'd them to Mr. Allen.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it not usual for all such boxes to be mark'd by your master, or the owners of them?</p>
               <p>Wright. It is.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this that is marked, and see if it is your master's mark or not.</p>
               <p>Wright. It is not marked with any mark that I know.</p>
               <p>Q. Are there any goods brought into your shop that are not marked?</p>
               <p>Wright. Yes, there are.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember your master's bringing these goods home?</p>
               <p>Wright. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear your master say there was a lady wanted to look at some boxes ?</p>
               <p>Wright. I heard him say a gentleman and lady wanted to look at some.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they put in a place where unmounted boxes are put?</p>
               <p>Wright. They might be for what I know.</p>
               <p>Q. Has not Mr. Allen worked for your master some time?</p>
               <p>Wright. He has.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that?</p>
               <p>Wright. I have carried him things to do?</p>
               <p>Q. What is this mark made with?</p>
               <p>Wright. It is made with ink, I fancy.</p>
               <p>Q. If a person was conscious he had stoln that box, might he not easily rub that mark out by weting his finger?</p>
               <p>Wright. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he send you in the ordinary manner as with other goods, or did he give you any particular caution?</p>
               <p>Wright. He gave me no particular caution, but sent me as he does with other goods in the course of trade.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he give you any order of secrecy?</p>
               <p>Wright. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go in the day or night?</p>
               <p>Wright. In the day-time.</p>
               <p>Q. Does Mr. Allen work for other people besides your master?</p>
               <p>Wright. I believe he works for a great many of the trade.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you been at the business?</p>
               <p>Wright. About half a year.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it not usual in trade of fancy to have goods upon sale or return?</p>
               <p>Wright. Yes, my master has.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he had any of Mr. Grace or Mr. Cox in that manner?</p>
               <p>Wright. I can't say.</p>
               <p>Q. Has your master now any goods of other people on sale or return?</p>
               <p>Wright. My mistress has I believe, but I can't say.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it your master's or mistress's shop?</p>
               <p>Wright. I fancy it is my mistress's.</p>
               <p>Q. Were these as publick in the shop as any others.</p>
               <p>Wright. They were as far as I know.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571026-12-person119">
                  Henry 
                  Blake 
               <interp inst="t17571026-12-person119" type="surname" value="Blake"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person119" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person119" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the constable. When I came into Westminster-Hall to serve the warrant on the prisoner, Mr. Allen and he were talking about the price for mounting them. The prisoner was unwilling to give him 12 s. a piece for mounting them. Mr. Allen said they were very pretty boxes, and he should be glad if he would tell him where<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175710260013"></xptr> he could meet such. The prisoner answered, he bought them of a Frenchman. He would have had Mr. Allen take one of them for the security of the 24 s. till he inquir'd whether it was the usual price to pay so much money. When I had him in custody he said he bought them of Mr. Cox. I ask'd him if Mr. Cox was a Frenchman? He said, what is that to you?</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it not customary for people in that trade to conceal places where they buy such things from others of the trade?</p>
               <p>Blake. It may for what I know.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he insist upon concealing where he had them ?</p>
               <p>Blake. No, he did not; as soon as he found the inquiry was for another purpose, and I had sent Mr. Allen to fetch Mr. Grace, then it was he told me he had them of Mr. Cox. We took him to Mr. Welch, and he was committed to Newgate.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he continued there till now?</p>
               <p>Blake. No, he has been bail'd out these 3 weeks.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571026-12-person120">
                  John 
                  Cayter 
               <interp inst="t17571026-12-person120" type="surname" value="Cayter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person120" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person120" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Cox and Mr. Grace apply'd to me, and mention'd the circumstances of this affair.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Cayter. I am a tobacconist and snuff-maker, and live in Fleet-street. They desir'd I would accompany them to Justice Welch's. I went with them to Westminster-Hall, but was not in the hall till after the prisoner was in custody of the constable. The constable, prisoner, and Mr. Grace went in a coach to Mr. Welch's. I walk'd it there. The prisoner said he had the boxes of Mr. Cox. Mr. Cox was sent for. It took up a considerable time. The Justice wanted to go to dinner, after a short examination of the prisoner. He was told he might send for his friends, and the Justice would be ready at 5 o'clock to hear the case. We went to dinner, and soon after Mr. Cox came to the publick house, where the prisoner said to him, pray Mr. Cox recollect your memory, you deliver'd these things to me, pray consider my character.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>Cayter. In Long-Acre. Mr Cox said, Mr. Drybutter I am extremely sorry for you, could I recollect any thing of that nature I would, but I can recollect no such thing, What was you to have given me for them? - 27 s. said the prisoner for one, 32 s. for the other. Mr. Cox reply'd, one of them cost me above two guineas. Well I don't know, said the prisoner, the price exactly, but pray recollect yourself. I will all I can, said Mr. Cox, alledging that he could not then recollect any transactions concerning them, and moreover saying, we never sell these boxes unmounted. Mr. Drybutter desired the privilege to speak to Mr. Grace and Mr. Cox in an adjoining room, which was granted. What passed there I can't tell, but they went from thence to justice Welch, for farther examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they seem well acquainted with one another?</p>
               <p>Cayter. They knew one another as persons know their customers.</p>
               <p>Q. What passed before the justice?</p>
               <p>Cayter. The prisoner declared he had the boxes of Mr. Cox, and that the price for one was 27 s. and the other 43 or 45 s.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. At the time the prisoner was talking to the prosecutors, did he speak to them as a man that had stoln any thing, or as one that desired Mr. Cox to recollect himself?</p>
               <p>Cayter. If I could tell the look of a thief, I should take more care myself, and be able to give you an answer.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you not know of your own knowledge, that he has frequently sup'd at their house?</p>
               <p>Cayter. I don't know that he ever did.</p>
               <p>Q. Nor breakfasted?</p>
               <p>Cayter. I know of no such thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear he has been there two or three times a week?</p>
               <p>Cayter. I never heard it, but I believe I have seen him there as often.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>There seems to be great weight laid on my saying I had these boxes of a Frenchman. I some time before this had some India boxes seized in Westminster-hall, and I apprehend they came to seize these. They were found in my custody, and I spoke out of tenderness to Mr. Cox, to conceal where I bought them, for they are really French manufactury. I always lived in great friendship with Mr. Cox, and have frequently dined and sup'd at his house. I have known him five or six years, and have been trusted with things to a large amount by him; I was trusted by him lately with a ring of 32 guineas value. If I had been minded to defraud him, I could have done it in jewels and things much more considerable than these 2 boxes. I was apply'd to by a lady now in court for a box,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175710260014"></xptr> in order to set a picture in, and I was obliged to get one unmounted to have it put in first, or it must have been taken to pieces again. I had these boxes of Mr. Cox on the 3d of September last in the evening; there was nobody but him in the warehouse at the time. If he recollects himself, he said they are inlaid with gold; said I, there is some silver; no, said he, it is all gold, but some of it is colour'd to represent the flower. As to the price I mention'd I was in such a flutter that I could not so well recollect it; and besides I very often do forget, and am forced to send back to the party, to know the price I am to give for things. It is not to be supposed, that if I had stoln these boxes I should have sent them to a man who (I knew) work'd for Mr. Cox, without rubbing out the marks. There was no friendship between Mr. Allen and me, and a to the answer from whence I had them, I had a very good right to keep that to myself; neither had he a right to ask me, it was an unfair question.</p>
               <p>Q. to Allen. Do you work for Messieurs Grace and Cox ?</p>
               <p>Allen. I do; I have known them about three years.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you for the prisoner ?</p>
               <p>Allen. Very little.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mrs. 
               <persName id="t17571026-12-person121">
                  Margaret 
                  Fitzberbert 
               <interp inst="t17571026-12-person121" type="surname" value="Fitzberbert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person121" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person121" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I remember I was at Mr. Drybutter's shop, wanting a snuff box; he told me, he believed he had some better than ordinary.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at those boxes, did you ever see them before?</p>
               <p>M. Fitzberbert. I don't remember ever seeing them before now.</p>
               <p>Q. When was you there?</p>
               <p>M. Fitzberbert. It was about the latter end of August.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you want a particular box ?</p>
               <p>M. Fitzberbert. I wanted a picture to be set in one.</p>
               <p>Q. Don't you know that in such a case, the box must be approved of, before it is mounted, by the customer?</p>
               <p>M. Fitzberbert. No; I don't know any thing of that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571026-12-person122">
                  John 
                  Jacobs 
               <interp inst="t17571026-12-person122" type="surname" value="Jacobs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person122" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person122" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a shagreen case maker, and have known the prisoner ever since the year 1754.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Jacobs. All I know of him is, I believe him to be a very honest man. He has been a very good customer, and has always paid me very honestly: His mother keeps the shop, and he has acted as manager; I believe he has laid out near 200 l. with me, but I am not positive.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he came frequently to your shop ?</p>
               <p>Jacobs. He has.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he ever had an opportunity of defrauding you?</p>
               <p>Jacobs. I never thought of such a thing, neither had I the least suspicion of him in the world.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he never been in your house, when he has had an opportunity of taking things?</p>
               <p>Jacobs. No doubt but he has.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it usual for you tradesmen to let one another have goods, to shew to a customer ?</p>
               <p>Jacobs. I have done it frequently, but he generally bought what he wanted.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you call that way of trade?</p>
               <p>Jacobs. That is called sale or return.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think he'd be guilty of stealing a couple of tortoishell boxes ?</p>
               <p>Jacobs. I can't say nothing to that.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether it is customary, upon sale or return, to let the person that fetches them alter them, and after that take them again?</p>
               <p>Jacobs. If he makes an alteration according to his own humour, the goods are his.</p>
               <p>Q. Supposing the goods were taken to shew a customer, is it not customary for you to fix a price what he shall pay for them, if he sells them?</p>
               <p>Jacobs. I always fix a price, and mark it on them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571026-12-person123">
                  James 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17571026-12-person123" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person123" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person123" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about three years; I am a jeweller, and have had dealings with him; I always apprehended he took goods on his own account.</p>
               <p>Q. How many shops have he and his mother ?</p>
               <p>Johnson. I know they have two, one in Westminster-Hall, the other in Pall-Mall, and I have heard say they have another at Tunbridge.</p>
               <p>Q. Throughout the course of his dealing with you, in what manner did he behave himself?</p>
               <p>Johnson. He always paid me for every thing that he contracted for.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he been often in your shop?</p>
               <p>Johnson. He has been often in my house, but not in my work-shop; I have shew'd him goods in the parlour.</p>
               <p>Q. If he had been of that disposition, had he an opportunity to have taken goods ?</p>
               <p>Johnson. He had an opportunity if he had been so minded.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether in your business you do not assist one another with jewels, to shew to customer?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175710260015"></xptr>Johnson. Yes, all jewellers do.</p>
               <p>Q. Don't you very frequently let people have goods upon sale or return?</p>
               <p>Johnson. He has goods of mine now upon sale or return.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571026-12-person124">
                  John 
                  Jefferys 
               <interp inst="t17571026-12-person124" type="surname" value="Jefferys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person124" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person124" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Mr. Drybutter five or six years. I am a bookseller. He keeps a shop in Pall-Mall, another in Westminster-Hall, and, in the season, another at Tunbridge, but I know nothing of that shop; I think I seldom see a shop better stock'd than that in Westminster-Hall.</p>
               <p>Q. What has been his behaviour ?</p>
               <p>Johnson. He has bought books of me several times; during the course of our trading together I believe I may have taken of him about 150 l. and what he contracted for he always paid me; there is now about 1 l. 5 s. between us for goods which he had about a month ago. I always look'd upon him to be a very honest man.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you look upon to be debtor, Mrs. Drybutter or he ?</p>
               <p>Jefferys. I always look'd upon her to be debtor, but I always received my money of him; I did not know but what they were partners.</p>
               <p>Q. In whose name did you carry the account in?</p>
               <p>Jefferys. In her name, as she first contracted with me, but had he came on his own account and said he wanted ten or twenty pounds worth of goods, he should have had them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571026-12-person125">
                  Joshua 
                  Pickersgale 
               <interp inst="t17571026-12-person125" type="surname" value="Pickersgale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person125" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person125" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a silk weaver, and have known the prisoner at the bar four or five years; I have dealt with Mrs. Drybutter for that time in ribbons, and the prisoner transacted the business, all but the first parcel, which she came and bought.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Pickersgale. I always look'd upon him to be a very honest man; I never knew to the contrary.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571026-12-person126">
                  John 
                  Garset 
               <interp inst="t17571026-12-person126" type="surname" value="Garset"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person126" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person126" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a weaver, and have known the prisoner about seven years; he used to come frequently and look goods out for his mother. I always took him to be an honest man.</p>
               <p>Eliezer Chayter. I have known him near two years, and have had dealings with him.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>Chayter. I am a watchmaker, and have sold him things of value.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character ?</p>
               <p>Chayter. I never found any thing to the contrary but that he was an honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571026-12-person127">
                  Stephen 
                  Wooderfield 
               <interp inst="t17571026-12-person127" type="surname" value="Wooderfield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person127" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person127" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a pocket book maker; I have known him three years, and have had dealings with him, to the amount of 40 l.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character ?</p>
               <p>Wooderfield. A very honest man for what I ever heard or knew.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571026-12-person128">
                  Michael 
                  Parsons 
               <interp inst="t17571026-12-person128" type="surname" value="Parsons"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person128" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person128" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him four or five years, and am a linen-draper; he has often been at my shop to chuse goods for his mother, to go to Tunbridge. I always consider'd him as a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571026-12-person129">
                  John 
                  Watson 
               <interp inst="t17571026-12-person129" type="surname" value="Watson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person129" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person129" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Pall-Mall, and have known him pretty near his infancy; I never heard any ill of him till this thing happen'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571026-12-person130">
                  Michael 
                  Conner 
               <interp inst="t17571026-12-person130" type="surname" value="Conner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person130" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-person130" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a taylor; I had an apartment of his mother's, from September 1755, till March 1757, in Pall-Mall.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner's general character?</p>
               <p>Conner. I always look'd upon him to be a man of more honour than to pilfer.</p>
               <p>Court. This is a prosecution against the prisoner for stealing these goods, the property of Mess. Cox and Grace; why was not Cox examined, as his name is so often mention'd ?</p>
               <p>Cox. I am sworn, and can say no more than what Mr. Grace has already said.</p>
               <p>Q. to Grace. Did you ever trade with the prisoner in the way of sale and return ?</p>
               <p>Grace. I believe we have let him have a thing, and the next day he was to bring it again, if he did not sell it.</p>
               <p>Q. Suppose he had kept it, how then?</p>

               <p>Grace. Then we should have charged him a certain price for it, but we admit no alteration in our goods; if we deliver goods to him on this consideration, then we set them down; but these two boxes are not enter'd in my book.</p>
               <p>Q. Does Mr. Cox make entry of all his goods?</p>
               <p>Grace. There may be some omission.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17571026-12-verdict66" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17571026-12-verdict66" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
