<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560225-44">
               <interp inst="t17560225-44" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560225-44" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560225-44" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560225"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560225-44" type="date" value="17560225"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560225-44-off247-c335" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-44-defend417 t17560225-44-off247 t17560225-44-verdict252"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560225-44-off247-c336" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-44-defend419 t17560225-44-off247 t17560225-44-verdict252"></join>
         
               <p>159. 160. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17560225-44-defend417" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Wilson 
                  <interp inst="t17560225-44-defend417" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-44-defend417" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-44-defend417" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17560225-44-defend419" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Wilson 
                  <interp inst="t17560225-44-defend419" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-44-defend419" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-44-defend419" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted for <rs id="t17560225-44-off247" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560225-44-off247" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-44-off247" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               that they, on the <rs id="t17560225-44-cd248" type="crimeDate">3d of February</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-44-off247 t17560225-44-cd248"></join>, about the hour of two in the night of the same day, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17560225-44-victim421" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Cotton 
                        <interp inst="t17560225-44-victim421" type="surname" value="Cotton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560225-44-victim421" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560225-44-victim421" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-44-off247 t17560225-44-victim421"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17560225-44-viclabel249" type="occupation">Gent.</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-44-victim421 t17560225-44-viclabel249"></join> did break and enter, and steal one silver coffee-pot, value 5 l. two silver candlesticks, value 8 l. three silver salvers, value 5 l. one silver milk pot, value 10 s. one silver pint mug, two silver half-pint mugs, one knife and fork with silver handles gilt, eight silver spoons, one pair of silver tea-tongs, one silver strainer, two silver salts, two silver salt shovels, one silver pepper-box, one tea chest with three canisters, and one silver punch-ladle, the goods of the said Thomas, in the said dwelling-house
            </rs>. *</p> 
               <p>Thomas Cotton. I live in <placeName id="t17560225-44-crimeloc250">Red-Lion Street, Wapping</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17560225-44-crimeloc250" type="placeName" value="Red-Lion Street, Wapping"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17560225-44-crimeloc250" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-44-off247 t17560225-44-crimeloc250"></join>. Behind my house is a paved yard, across which is an office for my clerks.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>Cotton. I am an <rs id="t17560225-44-viclabel251" type="occupation">attorney</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-44-victim421 t17560225-44-viclabel251"></join>. There is a back-door out of an entry belonging to my office, which goes into an alley, call'd Queen's-head-alley.</p>
               <p>Q. How wide is that paved yard?</p>
               <p>Cotton. It is about as wide as the breadth of this court. To the office window in that alley are double shutters, inside and out; there are also inside and outside shutters to the parlour window, that is the back parlour belonging to my house, that looks into the yard. Between Tuesday and Wednesday, the 3d and 4th of this instant, and between 2 and 3 in the morning, my wife awak'd me, and told me she heard some uncommon noise. A lady being sick at the next door, I imagined it was somebody up with her; presently I heard it, and upon sitting up in my bed, I heard somebody walk below stairs, but still thought it was in the next house. I got up, and went out of my chamber into the next, which was the back room that<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175602250039"></xptr> looks out into my yard; my wife also went with me. I threw up the sash to look into my neighbour's yard, upon which a man jump'd out of my window into the yard; I rather say I heard than saw him, it was so dark. I heard him run across my yard into the clerks office, and at the same time I heard another person in the office very plain; I call'd out watch, but was not heard by any body. Some time after the watchman came his rounds, and I call'd him, and went down stairs. The first thing that I observed was, the back parlour door was open, and the watchman and I went in there; the sash was quite up that looks into the pav'd yard, and the outside and inside shutters cut; the outside shutter had a pannel cut out about the middle, and the inside shutter had a pannel cut out at bottom; the reason of which appear'd to be, that the bolt on the outside was in the middle, and the inside one fastened at the bottom. I have two beaufets in the two parlours, in which the plate was when we went to bed.</p>
               <p>Q. How are these parlours situated?</p>
               <p>Cotton. One looks out into Red-Lion-Street, and the other backwards into my pav'd yard.</p>
               <p>Q. Could a person get out of one parlour into the other?</p>
               <p>Cotton. They might, the sash door between them was not lock'd. I found the beaufets stripped.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you lose?</p>
               <p>Cotton. I lost a silver coffee-pot, a pair of silver candlesticks, a silver pint mug, two half pint silver mugs, a large silver salver, two small ones, a silver milk-pot, a silver handle knife and fork gilt, a shagreen case, seven tea-spoons, one table spoon, tongs and strainer, a tea-chest with three tin canisters in it, two silver saltcellers, two salt shovels, one silver pepper-box and one punch-ladle.</p>
               <p>Q. Were these taken out of the beaufets ?</p>
               <p>Cotton. They were; then we went a-cross the yard into the clerks office, for the door that came out of that entry into the pav'd yard was not fastened that night, and we seldom do fasten it; I found in the office one of the windows broke open in the same manner the other shutters were; the outside shutter of the window that looks into Queen's-head-alley, had a small piece cut off, in order to reach the bolt; the inside shutter had a pannel cut through, so as to put in a hand and lift up the bar; that sash I found wide open; I found the three desks of my clerks every one of them broke open and the papers tumbled about, but could not find any thing was taken away. I went from thence into the house and into my own study, which is even with the parlour, where I have a row of presses for papers with drawers under them; the first of these presses and that alone, I found broke open, and likewise a drawer under a table upon which I write, but the others were not touch'd; in these two drawers I sometimes had kept money, and the prisoner Robert had been an errand-boy to me about three months.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he go away?</p>
               <p>Cotton. I think it was in October last that he went away; I knew he had seen me take money out of that first drawer, and I don't know that any person in the world, out of my own house, ever did; this with his being advertised for robbing another gentleman, occasioned me to take him up upon suspicion. One thing I ought to have mention'd before: In the morning when I came down, in my parlour window I found this knife, (producing a sort of a Dutch knife with the edge back'd into a saw. )</p>
               <p>Q. Which parlour window did you find it in?</p>
         
               <p>The remainder of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17560225-44">
                  <interp inst="t17560225-44" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17560225-44" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17560225-44" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560225"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17560225-44" type="date" value="17560225"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175602250040"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON, And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 25th, Thursday the 26th, Friday the 27th, and Saturday the 28th of FEBRUARY,</p>
                  <p>In the Twenty-ninth Year of His MAJESTY'S Reign. NUMBER III. PART III. for the YEAR 1756. Being the Third SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of The Right Honble SLINGSBY BETHELL, Esq, LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by J. ROBINSON, at the Golden-Lion, in Ludgate-Street. 1756.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175602250041"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery held for the City of LONDON, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Cotton. THE window that the persons got in at out of the pav'd yard. It is a very remarkable knife with an inscription upon it, and the sheath was found by my servant, who will give the court an account of it when she is called. I took him up, and upon his being examined before justice Manwaring, the day before the fast, I thought proper to have him search'd, but nothing belonging to me was found; this knife was shewn him there, he denied he ever saw it in his life before: afterwards his mother was called in as a witness to prove where he was at the time the robbery was committed, and when this knife was produced to her, being ask'd if she knew that knife? she said immediately, that knife is my son's knife, I'll swear it (imagining, I believe, it had been taken out of his pocket with the other things of his that lay upon the table.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the prisoner Robert then ?</p>
               <p>Cotton. He was not then in the room; she had named two sons, but had not said which son owned it.</p>
               <p>Q. Are the two prisoners brothers?</p>
               <p>Cotton. They are; she was asked which son owned the knife? and she said really I can't tell which son, for they both of them claim it, sometimes one says it is his, and sometimes the other says it his; for it was given or sold to them by an acquaintance of theirs, as they told her. After that 
               <persName id="t17560225-44-person422">
                  John 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17560225-44-person422" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-44-person422" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-44-person422" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the elder was called in to give an account where his brother was that night; he came as a witness for his brothers; the justice then shew'd him this knife, but he likewise denied having ever seen it in his life before. Upon that the justice called in his mother again, and bid him not speak a word till he had asked him a question; then the justice said, before his mother, do you know this knife ? he said no, I never saw it before. The mother said, why John you know it is your knife, but he still denied it. Upon this suspicion the justice sent both the prisoners to the watch-house than night; the next day, which was the fast day, after service was over in the evening, the justice had them before him again; the youngest was brought in first and was again shew'd this knife, and asked if he would own it? he said no, he never saw it till the night before. The justice said to him, why your mother owned it last night before many people to be your knife. Yes, said he, my mother was affrighted then, and did not know what she said; but if you'll please to call her in, she has got the knife in her pocket that she mistook for this knife; the justice said he would call her in by and by, and accordingly he sent him out and called the mother in; then he asked her again, and shewed her the knife, whether that was her son's knife? she then said no, it was not: the justice said, you said it was his knife many times over last night. I did so, said she, but I was affrighted; she produced another knife, and said this is the knife that I mistook for that last night. (Produced in court a sheath knife, but it had no resemblance to the other.) The justice took it of her, laid it down and sent her out, and sent for the prisoner Robert in, an d asked him whether he would own the knife or not? he said, no; I told you my mother had that knife she mistook for this in her pocket, if you please to call her in. The justice said, he would call her in presently; then he took up a knife and said, is it like this? he said no, then he took up the knife his mother produced and said, is it like this? he said no, that knife is not so long as the blade of this.</p>
               <p>After that some people were called in to his character, and some to prove him elsewhere at the time; but they varied in most of the facts, so<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175602250042"></xptr> that when they come to be called I beg they may be examined separately, for there were not two of them that said the same thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever met with your goods, or any of them again?</p>
               <p>Cotton. No, I have not, I advertised them, and got papers from goldsmiths hall distributed about.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoners own anything?</p>
               <p>Cotton. No, nothing at all.</p>
               <p>Q. from Robert. Was there not a mistake about the knife? the justice shewed me all those knives, I said none of them was like it; I said it was a little knife not like any of these; this knife he has here is not the knife shewn to me before the justice.</p>
               <p>Cotton. This is the very knife that was produced by the mother, which he denied to be his knife; I now recollect another thing; when she produced this knife, the justice said, but you said you wou'd swear to the sheath as well as the knife. She, upon the sheath being shewn her, said her son's knife had exactly such a sheath, and he always wore it with such a sheath; that it was of that colour and that kind; but Robert said, when he was asked about the sheath, that he did not wear his knife in a sheath, and mentioned his once falling down and cutting his thigh by reason it was without a sheath, and said he wore it in his breeches pocket. The fastening of my house was very particular, I know it could not be broke open in the manner it was (being broke on the outside and inside shutter exactly where the fastenings were) but by a person that had lived in my house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-44-person423">
                  John 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17560225-44-person423" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-44-person423" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-44-person423" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . That knife that Mr. Cotton has in his hand is mine.</p>
               <p>Note, This was the knife produced by the mother.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-44-person424">
                  Jane 
                  Jobson 
               <interp inst="t17560225-44-person424" type="surname" value="Jobson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-44-person424" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-44-person424" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Cotton, when we came down in the morning we found the house broke open, and when I went to bed the doors and windows were all fast, and the things all in the house.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you go to bed?</p>
               <p>J. Jobson. I did not go to bed till after master and mistress were in bed, and that was between 12 and 1 o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. In which room do you lie?</p>
               <p>J. Jobson. I lie up three pair of stairs forwards</p>
               <p>Q. Was you before the justice?</p>
               <p>J. Jobson. I was when Mrs. Wilson own'd the knife to be her son Robert's.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him brought in?</p>
               <p>J. Jobson. I did; he denied it. When I was cleaning the stove in the back parlour, I found the sheath that belongs to that knife my master found.</p>
               <p>Street Arnot. I am clerk to Mr. Cotton, I heard the examination before the justice.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing more than that of the knife?</p>
               <p>Arnot. I know no more; I took the prisoner Robert, he seemed to be under a good deal of concern of mind.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you take him?</p>
               <p>Arnot. The Thursday after our house was broke open; when I met with him I asked him if he had heard master had been rob'd? he said no, and pretended a good deal of ignorance, but seemed very uneasy; we went to a public house and I call'd for a news paper and read it to him.</p>

               <p>Q. from Robert. Whether or not you did not tell me, Mr. Cotton saw three or four persons run cross the yard?</p>
               <p>Arnot. No, I did not; I told him Mr. Cotton saw one person run cross the yard.</p>
               <p>John's defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing at all of it.</p>
               <p>Robert's defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing of it.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoners.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-44-person425">
                  John 
                  Skirrard 
               <interp inst="t17560225-44-person425" type="surname" value="Skirrard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-44-person425" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-44-person425" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the prisoner John, he has work'd with me, I am a silk throwster, he behaved very well with me; he was in my service when he was taken up upon suspicion, and should he be cleared here I will take him into my service immediately, notwithstanding this impeachment of his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-44-person426">
                  Samuel 
                  Ware 
               <interp inst="t17560225-44-person426" type="surname" value="Ware"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-44-person426" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-44-person426" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . John work'd above a year with me, he behaved well in my service.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>Ware. I am a throwster.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Ware. I take him to be a person of good character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-44-person427">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Stracy 
               <interp inst="t17560225-44-person427" type="surname" value="Stracy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-44-person427" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-44-person427" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know Robert, I lived next door to his mother four years, he used to go to service as a footboy.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175602250043"></xptr>E. Stracy. I never heard any other than a good character, except that which was in the Daily Advertiser. On the Sunday night the robbery was committed I went to Nortonfalgate, at seven at night; my husband was sick, so I left the key with the prisoner's mother; when I came home it wanted ten minutes of one o'clock, I knock'd at her door and her sister got up and let me in, I said, don't be angry, I'm sorry to give you this trouble. I went in, and Robert was then in bed with his mother (he was fast asleep) below stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did John lie?</p>
               <p>E. Stracy. He lay above stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. How could you be so particular as to the time?</p>
               <p>E. Stracy. I went to my own room, took the drawer out and looked at my husband's watch, then it wanted 6 minutes of one.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is the house where the prisoners live from Mr. Cotton's house?</p>
               <p>E. Stracy. I never saw Mr. Cotton's house in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is the prisoners mother's house from Wapping-new-stairs?</p>
               <p>E. Stracy. I do not know where they are.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-44-person428">
                  Martha 
                  Munit 
               <interp inst="t17560225-44-person428" type="surname" value="Munit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-44-person428" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-44-person428" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known 
               <persName id="t17560225-44-person429">
                  Robert 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17560225-44-person429" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-44-person429" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-44-person429" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             from a baby; they live in a house of my father's, and have done 20 years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the general character of the prisoners at the bar?</p>
               <p>M. Munit. I never heard any ill of them except that advertisement; I accidentally went into their mother's house and saw Robert sitting upright in the bed, which startled me, this was the night the robbery was committed.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>M. Munit. This was betwixt ten and eleven.</p>
               <p>Q. What was your business there?</p>
               <p>M. Munit. I went to ask the sister a question; I said, what is that? the sister said he often does so in his sleep.</p>
               <p>Q. Does how?</p>
               <p>M. Munit. Rise up in his sleep, in his bed.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was his mother, was she in bed?</p>
               <p>M. Munit. No, she was not; she was sitting by the fire, she had a very bad leg.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-44-person430">
                  John 
                  Baxter 
               <interp inst="t17560225-44-person430" type="surname" value="Baxter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-44-person430" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-44-person430" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Robert some time, I never heard any thing amiss of him only the advertisement.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Baxter. I take him to be a very honest lad, and one of a good character.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17560225-44-verdict252" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560225-44-verdict252" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
