<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17580628-36">
               <interp inst="t17580628-36" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580628-36" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580628-36" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580628"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580628-36" type="date" value="17580628"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580628-36-off191-c274" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580628-36-defend336 t17580628-36-off191 t17580628-36-verdict193"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175806280037"></xptr>255. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17580628-36-defend336" type="defendantName">
                     Henry 
                     Myers 
                  <interp inst="t17580628-36-defend336" type="surname" value="Myers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-36-defend336" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-36-defend336" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17580628-36-off191" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580628-36-off191" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-36-off191" type="offenceSubcategory" value="perjury"></interp>
               wilful and corrupt perjury
            </rs>, <rs id="t17580628-36-cd192" type="crimeDate">April. 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580628-36-off191 t17580628-36-cd192"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580628-36-person337">
                  Thomas 
                  Gurney 
               <interp inst="t17580628-36-person337" type="surname" value="Gurney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-36-person337" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-36-person337" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I took minutes of the trial of 
               <persName id="t17580628-36-person338">
                  James 
                  Cotes 
               <interp inst="t17580628-36-person338" type="surname" value="Cotes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-36-person338" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-36-person338" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in April sessions last; he was tried for robbing Mr. 
               <persName id="t17580628-36-person339">
                  James 
                  Dunier 
               <interp inst="t17580628-36-person339" type="surname" value="Dunier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-36-person339" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-36-person339" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             on the highway of a silver-watch, in Marybone fields, on February the 27th at night. The prisoner Cotes in his defence called the present prisoner at the bar; who, after he was sworn, gave in evidence, that he was going up Tyburn-road on Monday was five weeks, which must be Monday the 27th of February, the same day the prosecutor of Cotes was robb'd. This Myers said, that on Monday, about ten in the morning, he saw Cotes, near Oxford-market, buying a pair of buttons of a Jew, in a dark red cloak; that he changed sixpence for them; that the Jew asked Cotes, if he would buy a watch; the Jew asked three guineas and a half for it, and at last they agreed for two guineas and a half. Upon being asked how long he had been acquainted with the prisoner Cotes, answered he never saw him before that time; or since, till then in the court. He was then asked, how he came to find the prisoner Cotes out? the prisoner said, because he described me to his wife, what sort of a man I was, as being a lame person; so Cotes's wife found him. Upon being asked, what sort of a watch it was, said, it had a key, and a bit of packthread to it, and it was a white one. Then Cotes asked him, if he did not pick up a paper that dropped out of the watch when he was buying it? then the prisoner produced a watch-paper. The prosecutor being shewed the paper, said there was such a one in his watch, that was taken from him; that there were two watch-papers, and, that if it was his, it lay uppermost. He was asked, if he had the paper from the prisoner Cotes? he said he had not, but that he then put it in his pocket, and had had it in his pocket ever since. Being asked, how Cotes knew that he had that paper, said, he told Cotes there was something fell out of the watch; Cotes said it was good for nothing; so he put it in his pocket. See the trial of Cotes, No 193, in April sessions last.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580628-36-person340">
                  William 
                  Humphrys 
               <interp inst="t17580628-36-person340" type="surname" value="Humphrys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-36-person340" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-36-person340" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a pawnbroker; 
               <persName id="t17580628-36-person341">
                  James 
                  Cotes 
               <interp inst="t17580628-36-person341" type="surname" value="Cotes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-36-person341" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-36-person341" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the person tried here, and since executed, delivered this watch to me on Tuesday the 28th of February; ( holding a silver watch in his hand ) I was an evidence on his trial.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the short-hand-writer give his evidence now?</p>
               <p>Humphrys. I did. What he has said is truth.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you that watch?</p>
               <p>Humphrys. Mr. Dunier put it into my hand.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580628-36-person342">
                  James 
                  Dunier 
               <interp inst="t17580628-36-person342" type="surname" value="Dunier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-36-person342" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-36-person342" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was the prosecutor of 
               <persName id="t17580628-36-person343">
                  James 
                  Cotes 
               <interp inst="t17580628-36-person343" type="surname" value="Cotes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-36-person343" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-36-person343" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            : since he received sentence, he sent for me, and confessed he robbed me of my watch, and asked my par don. The prisoner at the bar was produced as an evidence for Cotes on his trial. He then swore he saw Cotes buy a watch of a Jew-like man, near Oxford-market.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you heard the evidence the shorthand-writer has given?</p>
               <p>Dunier. I have; I remember it perfectly well; he has given a right account of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you swear to that paper, that the prisoner produced?</p>
               <p>Dunier. I cannot, it being a printed paper; I had one of the same sort in my watch, and when I received my watch from Mr. Humphrys, that paper was not in it. I remember the court was of opinion the prisoner had perjured himself on his producing that paper, which he swore fell out of a watch, which the prisoner Cotes, he said, was buying on the morning of the same day, that I was robbed of my watch in the evening: so that at the time he swore to, I must then have had my watch, with that paper in it in my pocket.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I did see 
               <persName id="t17580628-36-person344">
                  James 
                  Cotes 
               <interp inst="t17580628-36-person344" type="surname" value="Cotes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-36-person344" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580628-36-person344" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             buying a watch, as I went up Holbourn, but do not know, that it was the same watch that the gentleman lost.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17580628-36-verdict193" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580628-36-verdict193" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
