<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17590530-7">
               <interp inst="t17590530-7" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590530-7" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590530-7" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17590530"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590530-7" type="date" value="17590530"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17590530-7-off29-c81" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590530-7-defend91 t17590530-7-off29 t17590530-7-verdict32"></join>
         
               <p>184. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17590530-7-defend91" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Walker 
                  <interp inst="t17590530-7-defend91" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-defend91" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-defend91" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17590530-7-off29" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-off29" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-off29" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing ten ounces of silk, value 20 s
            </rs>. the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17590530-7-victim93" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Wilberham 
                  <interp inst="t17590530-7-victim93" type="surname" value="Wilberham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-victim93" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-victim93" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590530-7-off29 t17590530-7-victim93"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17590530-7-cd30" type="crimeDate">May 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590530-7-off29 t17590530-7-cd30"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590530-7-person94">
                  William 
                  Wilberham 
               <interp inst="t17590530-7-person94" type="surname" value="Wilberham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-person94" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-person94" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17590530-7-viclabel31" type="occupation">weaver</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590530-7-victim93 t17590530-7-viclabel31"></join>, and live in Primrose-street. On the 15th of May, a journeyman of mine came and told me, of the prisoner robbing me of silk at divers times: I us'd to put confidence in him, and let him have the liberty to go into my ware-house, he work'd for me at his own house. They can give a farther account.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590530-7-person95">
                  Mary 
                  Hays 
               <interp inst="t17590530-7-person95" type="surname" value="Hays"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-person95" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-person95" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never was in Mr Wilberham's house in my life, 'till I went and told him of this thing. The prisoner work'd in my house, for fifteen or sixteen months, for Mr Wilberham, he had a wallet hung up behind his loom. My husband in looking for a buckle that was missing, he came to me and said, he saw five bobbins in the wallet. I went to make this man's bed, I felt in the wallet, and found it of a great weight, I took out one bobbin. On the next day, my son, the prisoner, and others, went out in the evening; then I bolted the street-door, and went and took down this wallet, and in a napkin were twenty bobbins of silk, some white, some orange, and some pale yellow. I compared the mark of the bobbins, with that mark of those that hung upon his work. After that, I let it pass on 'till the twenty-fifth of February, then my husband and I were alone; I put my hand in the wallet, and found two bobbins that came between the Monday and Thursday, this is it, producing one.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. Look at this?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. It is my property, he never used to take such colour of me to work.</p>
               <p>Hays. I do not know, that there was a day, but I put my hand under it to see if it was taken away, and it was taken away the first Friday in Lent; there were twenty-two in the whole, and twelve skains of yarn. I know nothing what became of the other bobbins.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I talk'd with Walker, but he denied it, and so he did before my Lord-Mayor. Twenty or thirty of these bobbins weigh about a pound.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175905300009"></xptr>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you work for the prosecutor?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590530-7-person96">
                  M 
                  Hays 
               <interp inst="t17590530-7-person96" type="surname" value="Hays"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-person96" type="given" value="M"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-person96" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I do.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you discover this?</p>
               <p>Hays. On the 18th of February.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you not to acquaint him with it before the 15th of May?</p>
               <p>Hays. I was cautious of either hanging or transporting of him; so I let the prosecutor know by another person, and Mr Wilberham insisted on knowing who told him. Then he said it was from me. He having a good opinion of him could hardly believe it. After that, the prisoner was pleased to say, My husband was jealous of him, upon which account we made that report.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any quarrel with the prisoner ?</p>
               <p>Hays. No; only he had said he could have me whenever he pleased, but he did not like me.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you know 
               <persName id="t17590530-7-person97">
                  Sarah 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17590530-7-person97" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-person97" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-person97" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ?</p>
               <p>Hays. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you not once some conversation with her about the prisoner ?</p>
               <p>Hays. I have never seen her since Ash-Wednesday, 'till I saw her here.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you say to her, you would either hang or transport him, because he has spoke slighting of you?</p>
               <p>Hays. No never. She was the person that inform'd me of his speaking slightly of me. I said I was sure he never did, for I never left it in his power. I look'd on her feet, and saw she had hardly any shoes on. I said I would buy her a new pair of shoes, if she would prove to Walker's face, what she had said; but by the virtue of my oath, I never thought of it coming here.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Did the prisoner always return you a faithful account?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I never knew of any want but once.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590530-7-person98">
                  Nicholas 
                  Hays 
               <interp inst="t17590530-7-person98" type="surname" value="Hays"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-person98" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-person98" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am husband to Mary. I saw five bobbins in the prisoner's wallet, but did not take much notice of them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I believe they had as good an opportunity of taking things as I had.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590530-7-person99">
                  Sarah 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17590530-7-person99" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-person99" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-person99" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mrs Hays came to where I work. There happened to be some dispute between her and Walker about an affair; she came to ask me if I had heard of it.</p>
               <p>Q. What was that?</p>
               <p>Evans. It is a ridiculous speech; I am ashamed to speak it.</p>
               <p>Q. What were the words ?</p>
               <p>Evans. It was given out, that he should say, That she was B - d. And she said, she would sell her so the D - l, but she would be reveng'd him; and if I would stand by her she would give me half a crown, and a new pair of shoes.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590530-7-person100">
                  John 
                  Hailey 
               <interp inst="t17590530-7-person100" type="surname" value="Hailey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-person100" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-person100" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have work'd for several Weavers; I have had an opportunity, from time to time, of keeping a bobbin or two without stealing of it.</p>
               <p>Diana Prichard. Mrs Hays came to me about two or three hours after I was delivered and laid in my bed. Evans work'd and liv'd with me. They began a discourse about the prisoner at the bar. Evans said 
               <persName id="t17590530-7-person101">
                  John 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17590530-7-person101" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-person101" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-person101" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had said, he could have to do with her when he pleased. Mrs Hays, with a great oath said, if Evans would stand by her, she would be revenged of him above all men in England; and offer'd her a new pair of shoes, or the price of a new pa ir, if she would stand by her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590530-7-person102">
                  Nicholas 
                  Hays 
               <interp inst="t17590530-7-person102" type="surname" value="Hays"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-person102" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-person102" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17590530-7-person103">
                  Sarah 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17590530-7-person103" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-person103" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-person103" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's evidence is good for nothing; for I have catch'd the prisoner at the bar on my bed along with her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590530-7-person104">
                  William 
                  Doran 
               <interp inst="t17590530-7-person104" type="surname" value="Doran"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-person104" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-person104" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner 14 or 15 years; he always bore a good character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590530-7-person105">
                  Henry 
                  Constantine 
               <interp inst="t17590530-7-person105" type="surname" value="Constantine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-person105" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-person105" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a Publick House in Bethnal-Green. I have known the prisoner about a year and half; he has the character of an honest man, and I believe him to be such.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590530-7-person106">
                  Sarah 
                  Kennedy 
               <interp inst="t17590530-7-person106" type="surname" value="Kennedy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-person106" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-person106" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner above two years; he has a very good character.</p>
               <p>Mrs Redman. I have known him upwards of four years; I never heard to the country but that he is an honest man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17590530-7-verdict32" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590530-7-verdict32" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
