<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17550910-29">
               <interp inst="t17550910-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550910-29" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550910-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550910"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550910-29" type="date" value="17550910"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550910-29-off140-c177" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550910-29-defend228 t17550910-29-off140 t17550910-29-verdict144"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550910-29-off140-c178" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550910-29-defend230 t17550910-29-off140 t17550910-29-verdict144"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550910-29-off140-c179" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550910-29-defend232 t17550910-29-off140 t17550910-29-verdict144"></join>
         
               <p>330, 331, 332. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17550910-29-defend228" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Salter 
                  <interp inst="t17550910-29-defend228" type="surname" value="Salter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-defend228" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-defend228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17550910-29-defend230" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Hines 
                  <interp inst="t17550910-29-defend230" type="surname" value="Hines"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-defend230" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-defend230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17550910-29-defend232" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Palmer 
                  <interp inst="t17550910-29-defend232" type="surname" value="Palmer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-defend232" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-defend232" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted, <rs id="t17550910-29-off140" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-off140" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-off140" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               the first for the wilful murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17550910-29-victim234" type="victimName">
                           Owen 
                           Crane 
                        <interp inst="t17550910-29-victim234" type="surname" value="Crane"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550910-29-victim234" type="given" value="Owen"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550910-29-victim234" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550910-29-off140 t17550910-29-victim234"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  ; the two others for being accessary thereunto , by aiding, abetting, and assisting the said 
                     <persName id="t17550910-29-person235">
                        John 
                        Salter 
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person235" type="surname" value="Salter"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550910-29-person235" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550910-29-person235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17550910-29-cd141" type="crimeDate">June 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550910-29-off140 t17550910-29-cd141"></join>. 
               <persName id="t17550910-29-person236">
                  John 
                  Salter 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person236" type="surname" value="Salter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person236" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             stood charged on the coroner's inquisition for man-slaughter. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-29-person237">
                  Eleanor 
                  Crane 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person237" type="surname" value="Crane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person237" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person237" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am widow to the deceased. He had been beaten , but I did not see him till in the Gatehouse, on the 19th of June, after eight at night . He could neither speak , sit, or stand; he had no more sense than the sole of my shoe. I sent for a surgeon , and got him blooded.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he for health the day before?</p>
               <p>Crane . I dined with him that day; then he was hearty and well as ever I saw him in my life. The next day he was carried to the workhouse. This was the Friday; he remained there till the Thursday following; then he was carried in a chair to Westminster-infirmary , and was there but about two or three hours; then they carried him home by his desire. He lived after the beating five weeks and one day .</p>
               <p>Q. Did he go out of doors in the time?</p>
               <p>Crane. He did; he went to sell milk one day; he lived eight days after he took to his bed.</p>
               <p>Q. What marks did you perceive on him?</p>
               <p>Crane. He was cut under one of his eyes, I can't tell which; he had a mark on his hip, just by his groin; and he always complained of mortal bruises inwardly.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-29-person238">
                  Henry 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person238" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person238" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going from my work just about seven o'clock in the evening; I saw 
               <persName id="t17550910-29-person239">
                  Owen 
                  Crane 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person239" type="surname" value="Crane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person239" type="given" value="Owen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             walking up <placeName id="t17550910-29-crimeloc142">King-street, Westminster</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17550910-29-crimeloc142" type="placeName" value="King-street, Westminster"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550910-29-crimeloc142" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550910-29-off140 t17550910-29-crimeloc142"></join>, with a stick in his hand; it seemed to be a large stick, something like a broom-stick; somebody called out, stop thief ; there was a mob at the upper end of the street; Crane pass'd through some of the people; there was a soldier, being a chairman , drew out his chair-pole, and struck at him , but I can't say it hit him.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was you to them?</p>
               <p>Jones. I was about thirty yards off. The deceased, I believe, made a blow at him, whether he struck him I cannot tell. There was a man's servant, in a light coloured, turn'd up with red, and a silver-laced hat, she ran up to the deceased, and struck up his neck, and fell upon him. At the same time the chairman took up Owen Crane's stick, and struck him with it several times. There was an acquaintance of more laid hold of me, and carried me out of their company, or I had taken the deceased's part</p>
               <p>Q. Can you assign any reason why the chairman drew out the chair-pole, and struck at the deceased?</p>
               <p>Jones. I know of no other reason than that of their crying out, stop thief. I went to see him at the workhouse on the Sunday after; then he excessive bad, and reach'd very much with blood; I observed several marks about his body; I saw a black mark under his rib, where he said his pain lay on his left-side.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the other two prisoners do anything ?</p>
               <p>Jones. I know nothing against them.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was that gentleman's servant?</p>
               <p>Jones. I don't know.</p>
               <p>Q. How long were they on the groun d together?</p>
               <p>Jones. To the best of my knowledge they were on the ground a minute.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any struggle between them when they were on the ground?</p>
               <p>Jones. No; it is possible the fall might disorder them.</p>
               <p>Q. Which fell uppermost?</p>
               <p>Jones. The gentleman's servant .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any blows?</p>
               <p>Jones. The gentleman's servant struck him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he fall hard upon him?</p>
               <p>Jones. He fell as hard as he could upon him, to my thinking.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the chairman strike the deceased , before the deceased struck him?</p>
               <p>Jones. I saw him strike at him with his pole; but whether he struck him or not I don't know.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the deceased abroad after this?</p>
               <p>Jones. I saw him come down King-street once after.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after ?</p>
               <p>Jones . I can't say how long.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a week after?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175509100016"></xptr>Jones. It was more than a fortnight after.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him abroad more than once?</p>
               <p>Jones. No; no more than once.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he appear then?</p>
               <p>Jones. He appeared excessive bad, and was oblig'd to be led home, or partly carry'd between two men.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-29-person240">
                  James 
                  Hamilton 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person240" type="surname" value="Hamilton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person240" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to see Crane on his death-bed, about the 21st, 22d, or 23d of June; he said he was ill of the bruises he received at Westminster . I asked him, who gave him the bruises? he said, two chairmen. I ask'd him , if he knew them ? He said, they beat him till his sight left him. I ask'd him, if he knew any of them mes? he said, one was named Salter; I said, do you lay your death to any of them? he said, I lay my death to Salter in particular. We took him up the day after Crane died; we took him before esquire Manby ; Esquire Manby said, Salter, I am sorry for this; so am I, said Salter; for it is the others should be taken up as well as I, for they had a hand in it as well as I. On the 20th of June I was at Mr. Bennet's office, a justice of the peace; I said to Salter (he having a broom-stick in his hand) I suppose that is what you hurt the man with yesterday ; he said, yes it is. A man that was by said, you ought to be made to pay for it; he answered, if I had you in the street I would serve you the same; I am the king's servant, and have an authority to serve any body so that I hear make a noise in the street.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the deceased say any thing against the other men?</p>
               <p>Hamilton . No; I did not.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say any thing more, when he said he had authority to serve any man so?</p>
               <p>Hamilton . At the same time he said he had orders to aid and assist.</p>
               <p>Cicilia Read. On the day the blows happened, I was coming up King-street; I saw 
               <persName id="t17550910-29-person241">
                  Owen 
                  Crane 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person241" type="surname" value="Crane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person241" type="given" value="Owen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             before me; I said to him, all the rest of your comrades are taken prisoners; do you go home.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you mean by comrades?</p>
               <p>Read. They were his fellow-labourers; this was when he came out of Mr. Gray's house. Mr. Salter bid him stand, and said he had murder'd a woman .</p>

               <p>Q. Do you know why he told him that?</p>
               <p>Read . No; I do not, I saw nothing of that. 
               <persName id="t17550910-29-person242">
                  Owen 
                  Crane 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person242" type="surname" value="Crane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person242" type="given" value="Owen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had a broom-stick in his hand, and he held it up.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that to strike , or to defend himself?</p>
               <p>Read. I don't know which.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he point it towards the prisoner, or did he hold it cross-ways?</p>
               <p>Read. He held it cross-ways. Mr. Salter knock'd him down with a chair-pole ; I clap'd my hands together, and said, are you going to murder the man? There was a footman there; I ran away, and said they are going to murder the man . I went to the Gatehouse the next day, to see 
               <persName id="t17550910-29-person243">
                  Owen 
                  Crane 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person243" type="surname" value="Crane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person243" type="given" value="Owen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person243" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ; but he could not speak to me.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the cry, stop thief?</p>
               <p>Read. No; I never heard that.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he stop when Salter bid him stand?</p>
               <p>Read. Yes; he did.</p>
               <p>Q. What part of the deceased did the chair-pole come on?</p>
               <p>Read. I think it came on his left shoulder or side?</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure it struck him?</p>
               <p>Read. I am not sure it did; to the best of my knowledge it did; when he lay down, Salter had his left knee on him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any body else there?</p>
               <p>Read. I saw a footman, with a silver-laced hat.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the deceased and the footman struggle together?</p>
               <p>Read. No; I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any thing said when they lay on the ground?</p>
               <p>Read. No; I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you, upon your oath, say, that the reason of the deceased's falling was by the blow or the struggling?</p>
               <p>Read. To the best of my oath it was by the chair-pole knocking him down.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was you to them?</p>
               <p>Read. I think I was within about three yards of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Palmer or Hines then?</p>
               <p>Read. They were a good way off when he was knock'd down.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-29-person244">
                  Elisabeth 
                  Bowen 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person244" type="surname" value="Bowen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person244" type="given" value="Elisabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person244" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I lodge at the Coach-and-horses, the house of Mr. Gray; I was sitting at the door; I saw a mob gather'd; the deceased went to make his escape from Mr. Salter, and another man ; he was making his escape, and Salter struck him on the shoulder with a broom-stick.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175509100017"></xptr>Q. Did you see a chair-pole?</p>
               <p>Bowen . No; I saw nothing of the chair-pole .</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know how Salter came by that broom-stick?</p>
               <p>Bowen. No; I did not. I laid hold of the broom-stick, and took it out of his hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Salter say any thing when he struck him?</p>
               <p>Bowen. To the best of my knowledge he did not. After that he took the stick out of my hand again, and hit the deceased a blow cross the stomach; and immediately the blood gushed out of his mouth and nose. I saw the prisoner after that in the workhouse; he complain'd of pain in the pit of his stomach. I did not see him after that.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing against the other two prisoners?</p>
               <p>Bowen. I know nothing of them.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any body say the deceased had murder'd a woman?</p>
               <p>Bowen. No; I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see the deceased out about his business after that?</p>
               <p>Bowen. No; I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-29-person245">
                  Mary 
                  Davison 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person245" type="surname" value="Davison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person245" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person245" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going to the apothecary's for something for my husband . On the 19th of June, betwixt six and seven in the evening, going along King-street , I saw 
               <persName id="t17550910-29-person246">
                  James 
                  Hines 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person246" type="surname" value="Hines"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person246" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             take the deceased by the arm, and wanted him to go along to the justice's; the deceased was then bleeding at the nose. Hines said, d - n your blood, go along ; you can go as well as I can; you only sham it; and gave him a kick on his backside with his foot.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he standing then?</p>
               <p>Davison. No; he was lying on the ground; then John Palmer laid hold of his collar, and drag'd him along. The blood ran out of his mouth and nose.</p>
               <p>Cross examination .</p>
               <p>Q. Had you heard that a woman had been knock'd down by the deceased?</p>
               <p>Davison. I heard a woman had been used ill by the deceased. One Mr. Wilkerson said, he was used very right, for he would have kill'd all if he had not been served so.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the cry of murder?</p>
               <p>Davison . No; I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear of any body being taken up?</p>
               <p>Davison. I heard there was a warrant against four labourers, but did not hear the deceased's name.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-29-person247">
                  Mary 
                  Corbet 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person247" type="surname" value="Corbet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person247" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person247" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a publick house. I was standing in King-street; there came Mrs. Read. she said they had murdered a man. I staid in the street till the man was brought past me; it was the deceased; his face was all over bloody; I followed the mob; but whether the man was knock'd down or not, I know not; I saw him lying on the ground; I saw two men take him by the two arms, and drag him along.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Mr. Hines there?</p>
               <p>Corbet. I know him very well; I did not see him near the deceased.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-29-person248">
                  Samuel 
                  Gray 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person248" type="surname" value="Gray"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person248" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . A little before this accident happened , there came a constable with four men in custody, which he took in Mr. Watling's Buildings , near my house.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Crane one of them ?</p>
               <p>Gray. No; he was not. They were labourers. The constable desired me to be one of the men's bail ; I said I would.</p>
               <p>Q. What were they taken in custody for?</p>
               <p>Gray. For assaulting a woman. During the time I was with them , I heard a great noise of a mob in the street ; but I saw nothing done to the deceased. I saw him afterwards in the Gatehouse; he could not speak to me .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him about his business after he was beat?</p>
               <p>Gray. I did once in my own house; I ask'd him how he did? he said he was very weak .</p>
               <p>Cross examination .</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know where he had been that day?</p>
               <p>Gray. He had been at work in carrying bricks, or rubbish, or such things .</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know he had any accident in falling from a scaffold?</p>
               <p>Gray. No; I do not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-29-person249">
                  James 
                  Cockbourne 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person249" type="surname" value="Cockbourne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person249" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . About seven o'clock, on the 19th of July, I saw a soldier, and another chairman, beating the deceased with a broom-stick, as he was lying on the ground, and pulling, and hawling him along, and tearing all his cloaths off his back. There was a great mob about him but I heard no words.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175509100018"></xptr>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the first of it you saw?</p>
               <p>Cockbourne . The first was Salter beating the deceased on the ground; and another chairman had him fast by the collar; after that I saw Mr. Palmer draging him along.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-29-person250">
                  Mary 
                  Crumbel 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person250" type="surname" value="Crumbel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person250" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person250" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I sat in my master's tap-room at work, in King-street; I heard a very great noise in the street; I went to the door, and saw a great many people; presently I saw two chairmen draging the deceased along, but I can't swear to the men; I know Palmer and Hines very well; but I did not see them there at the time. When they came near our door, the man that had hold on the deceased's left arm, strip'd the cloaths off his shoulder , and beat him with a broom-stick all over his body; they throw'd him down, and called him a great many shocking names, and stamped upon him with their feet; they first kneel'd on him with their knees, and then stamp'd upon him, and said, murder the Irish dog.</p>
               <p>Squire Southern. I was at the Coach-and-horses , King-street, Westminster; I saw 
               <persName id="t17550910-29-person251">
                  John 
                  Salter 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person251" type="surname" value="Salter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person251" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             beat the deceased with a broom-stick, or such like weapon; but I did not see him on the ground.</p>
               <p>Q. How many blows might you see?</p>
               <p>Southern . I can't say how many blows, there might be two or three.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did they fall?</p>
               <p>Southern . They seem'd to me to fall on his shoulders; they seem'd to lug him along towards the Gatehouse.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the other two prisoners do any thing ?</p>
               <p>Southern. I know nothing of the other two prisoners.</p>
               <p>Salter's defence .</p>
               <p>In the fore-part of the day the deceased was using one 
               <persName id="t17550910-29-person252">
                  Mark 
                  Flood 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person252" type="surname" value="Flood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person252" type="given" value="Mark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             very ill; he was let into the house, in order to be preserved from him; and after that he was let out backwards into a little court. The deceased came and drove himself against the door so violently, that the force drove him backwards. The prisoner was strip'd, running after that man to beat him; and several more of his fellow-workmen were along with him. They raised a great mob; one had a shovel , some one thing, some another; but they could not get at him. Afterwards Mark Flood fetch'd a warrant for the deceased. When he came to serve it in the Buildings, between six and seven o'clock, the deceased went through the Buildings, and into Mr. Gray's house, and from thence to Crane-court, and got a broom-stick, and came back again, and knock'd 
               <persName id="t17550910-29-person253">
                  Mark 
                  Flood 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person253" type="surname" value="Flood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person253" type="given" value="Mark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's wife down. I was up the street, where he came running; the people call'd, stop thief, murder. I drew out the pole; he struck at me; I defended myself with the pole; I threw the pole down to take hold of him; a gentleman's servant struck up his heels; then the constable came, and told me he had a warrant against him, and ordered me to assist in taking him to the justice's.</p>
               <p>Hines's defence .</p>
               <p>I know nothing of the matter; I happened to be there, and saw 
               <persName id="t17550910-29-person254">
                  Owen 
                  Crane 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person254" type="surname" value="Crane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person254" type="given" value="Owen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person254" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             strike the woman, and knock her down; which induc'd me to want him taken before a justice; I thought he had kill'd the woman.</p>
               <p>Palmer's defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing at all of the matter . I was drinking tea in my own house; hearing the cry, stop thief, I came to the bottom of the street, and saw one Thomas; I asked him what was the matter? he said he thought the deceased had murder'd a woman. I went then into my own shop, and never touch'd the deceased's garment, or a hair of his head.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-29-person255">
                  Solomon 
                  Morgan 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person255" type="surname" value="Morgan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person255" type="given" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person255" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I remember the day this unhappy affair happened; the first beginning of it was, a man and a woman were coming down King-street, between three and four o'clock; 
               <persName id="t17550910-29-person256">
                  Owen 
                  Crane 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person256" type="surname" value="Crane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person256" type="given" value="Owen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person256" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was at work out in the street; the man happen'd to touch a basket on the deceased's shoulder; the deceased swore at him, and gave him a shove; the other shov'd him; then Crane struck the man; they fell to fighting; the other man had more skill in boxing than Crane had; he gave the deceased a great many blows, and flung him down a very hard fall, near the steps of our door; then he step'd upon the steps, and said he was not for fighting him, by reason there were so many Irishmen belonging to Crane; then I bid him go into such a house, which he did; Crane strip'd, and ran after him, but could not find him; he ran up Parliament-street, and back again; he abused me very much for letting the man through a house; he dress'd himself, and went to work again. After that the other man came to me, and ask'd if we knew the man's name he had been fighting with? saying he had<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175509100019"></xptr> used him very ill. (Crane had struck the man's wife. ) He said he'd go and get a warrant. After that I saw Crane come from opposite the Coach-and-horses, between six and seven o'clock; and whether he struck the man's wife with a broom-stick, or his two hands, I am not certain; but she stoop'd, and the blow came over her neck. Then he went towards Whitehall; I saw the mob bring him back; then he was bloody; he had some blood on his face, below his eye , from fighting the man before. Crane was a very resolute man, and would not come along; so one had hold of one leg, another the other, another an arm, and so they brought him along.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-29-person257">
                  John 
                  Sayer 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person257" type="surname" value="Sayer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person257" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person257" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I live with Mr. Aplick, a cabinet-maker, in Parliament-street; about three o'clock in the afternoon that day there was a mob running after a man, some with shovels in their hands; there was the cry, stop thief . The man that had been fighting, being let in at a door, 
               <persName id="t17550910-29-person258">
                  Owen 
                  Crane 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person258" type="surname" value="Crane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person258" type="given" value="Owen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person258" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ran against it with his shoulder, with such violence that it knock'd him backwards a great way. Several people came, and ask'd what the man had done; he said he was a thief; then he was ask'd what the man had robb'd him of; he could give no account of what; then the people abused him for saying so of the man; then he was for fighting every-body that ask'd him why he ran about so. There was a woman came after the mob; she mob'd him, and he struck her; after that he went to work; after that the man and woman were inquiring for his name, with intent to get a warrant for him. I went up into Grosvenor-square, and coming down between six and seven, I saw 
               <persName id="t17550910-29-person259">
                  Owen 
                  Crane 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person259" type="surname" value="Crane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person259" type="given" value="Owen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person259" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             come running with a stick in his hand; he seem'd as if he was getting off; I heard the cry, stop him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body else run?</p>
               <p>Sayer. No; there was nobody running but he; he brush'd by me; but I was loaded, I could not lay hold on him. After that I saw Salter with a chair-pole in his hand. Crane, as he ran, was daring any body to meddle with him, saying, let them come if they dare, flourishing his stick. I saw the deceased, when he was some yards before Salter, stop, and as Salter came up, the deceased made a blow at him with the stick; the mob was gathering.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he hit Salter?</p>
               <p>Sayer . I believe he did, on the shoulder. The first man that laid hold of the deceased was a gentleman's servant in a frock. Salter drop'd the pole as soon as they were engaged; and the deceased was on the ground before Salter could touch him. I believe the deceased got several blows from the mob; people that I can give no account of.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the prisoner Salter strike the deceased, till the deceased struck him ?</p>
               <p>Sayer . No; I did not. He could not with the pole. I believe the deceased's intention was to have knock'd Salter down, he being the nearest to him, that he might have got off. I saw Mr. Hines there, but did not see him meddle upon any account; only laid hold of one of the deceased's legs once, that he should not escape.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see 
               <persName id="t17550910-29-person260">
                  Mary 
                  Davison 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person260" type="surname" value="Davison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person260" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person260" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             there ?</p>
               <p>Sayer. I was pretty near then, and I did not see her; I believe she was not there then; I was the re all the time, till he was carried to the justice's. The deceased was for pulling and striking every body that laid hold of him; and strugling to get away, it was as much as three or four men could do to hold him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-29-person261">
                  Edward 
                  Eagle 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person261" type="surname" value="Eagle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person261" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person261" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I saw the first beginning of this affair; I was at the constable's house; 
               <persName id="t17550910-29-person262">
                  Mark 
                  Flood 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person262" type="surname" value="Flood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person262" type="given" value="Mark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person262" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came in with a warrant, and his wife was with him; they desired the constable to go and take the deceased; the constable took me with them , and charged me to aid and assist. The labourers were very mischievous with their shovels; they had been quarreling all the forenoon; the constable took four of them, and carried them into Mr. Gray's house, at the Coach-and-horses; the deceased came with a broom-stick in his hand, and said, no English booger should take him; he met Flood's wife, and gave her a lick over her arm with the stick; the constable charg'd Salter to aid and assist. As the deceased came running towards Whitehall , hallowing with his stick up, I said to Salter, as you are charg'd to aid and assist, let us stop this man if we can. Salter went to pull his chair-pole out, and in the mean time Crane got beyond him. I said to him, if you run any further I'll cut your legs off. I am a soldier, and had all my acoutrements on; but had nothing in my hand. The deceased made a stop. Salter made a stroke at him, but did not hit him . The deceased turn'd the blow, and struck Salter on the left side of his face, and made his cheek, his mouth, and nose bleed. Salter stagger'd, and drop'd the pole out of his hand. He struck Salter twice, before Salter could get to him. The mob coming up, threw the deceased down. I saw a footman kick his heels up. I never saw Salter strike him once; one hit<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175509100020"></xptr> the deceased, and another hit him, for his ill usage. They carried him before the justice, and he ordered him to the Gatehouse.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-29-person263">
                  Samuel 
                  Manton 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person263" type="surname" value="Manton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person263" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person263" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable, I was apply'd to by 
               <persName id="t17550910-29-person264">
                  Mark 
                  Flood 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person264" type="surname" value="Flood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person264" type="given" value="Mark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person264" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , to serve these two warrants (producing them) he bid me take some assistance, or perhaps they would knock my brains out with their shovels and things; the warrants were for persons unknown. He shew'd me four persons, I took them in custody, and took them in at Mr. Gray's. I had not seen the deceased then, presently after they were there, the mob brought the deceased along, then Flood told me, there is your prisoner. I charg'd the prisoner Salter and the last witness to assist me. I was in the house with the other four, and did not see what was done; but supposed the deceased would not be taken . (He produced the broom-stick.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-29-person265">
                  John 
                  Westbrook 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person265" type="surname" value="Westbrook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person265" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person265" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The deceased was sent to St. Margaret's workhouse on the twentieth of June, I attended him the time he was there, which was till the twenty-fifth. I examin'd him, and found a bruise on his left hip, another on his breast; he complain'd of great pains, and soreness all over his body; he said he had been beat by a chairman, and others had struck him; he said, he laid his death to the chairman in custody. I blooded him, and saw him once or twice a day; he grew better, and was discharg'd at his own request, I saw him no more. Before he went out, I had given it as my opinion, that he was out of danger. I inquired of the nurse that attended him, she said there had been no blood discharg'd since he came there.</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17550910-29-person266">
                  Thomas 
                  Hatch 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person266" type="surname" value="Hatch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person266" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person266" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Mr. 
               <persName id="t17550910-29-person267">
                  Lewis 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person267" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person267" type="given" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Mr. 
               <persName id="t17550910-29-person268">
                  William 
                  Russel 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person268" type="surname" value="Russel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person268" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and Mr. 
               <persName id="t17550910-29-person269">
                  John 
                  Barker 
               <interp inst="t17550910-29-person269" type="surname" value="Barker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person269" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , surgeons, deposed; they saw the body after dead. That it was in a state of putrefaction, so that it was judg'd not safe to open it; and that they observ'd no external marks, from whence they might form any judgment, what was the cause of his death.</p>

               <p>Colonel Pearson, and captain Bell, to which regiment Salter belongs; the first had known him about ten years, the other about six or seven, both gave him the character of a well behaved honest man, and a good <rs id="t17550910-29-deflabel143" type="occupation">soldier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550910-29-defend228 t17550910-29-deflabel143"></join>.</p>
               <p>All three <rs id="t17550910-29-verdict144" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550910-29-verdict144" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
