<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17551204-31">
               <interp inst="t17551204-31" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551204-31" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551204-31" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17551204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551204-31" type="date" value="17551204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17551204-31-off163-c272" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-31-defend324 t17551204-31-off163 t17551204-31-verdict166"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17551204-31-off167-c272" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-31-defend324 t17551204-31-off167 t17551204-31-verdict166"></join>
         
               <p>38. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17551204-31-defend324" type="defendantName">
                     <interp inst="t17551204-31-defend324" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-31-defend324" type="age" value="22 years"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17551204-31-off163" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17551204-31-off163" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-31-off163" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he on the king's highway on 
                     <persName id="t17551204-31-victim325" type="victimName">
                        John 
                        Upton 
                     <interp inst="t17551204-31-victim325" type="surname" value="Upton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17551204-31-victim325" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17551204-31-victim325" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                    did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and stealing from his person one metal watch, value 20 s. one cornelian seal set in gold, value 10 s. one iron key, value 1 d. and 11 s. in money numbered, his property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17551204-31-cd164" type="crimeDate">October 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-31-off163 t17551204-31-cd164"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-31-off167 t17551204-31-cd164"></join>.* </p> 
               <p>John Upton. On the 23d of October, I was upon the road, about <placeName id="t17551204-31-crimeloc165">Shepherd's Bush</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17551204-31-crimeloc165" type="placeName" value="Shepherd's Bush"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17551204-31-crimeloc165" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-31-off163 t17551204-31-crimeloc165"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-31-off167 t17551204-31-crimeloc165"></join>; a little after 6 in the evening, a single highwayman stop'd me. It being about dusk I could not discern the person, so I cannot swear to the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. What was you rob'd of?</p>
               <p>Upton. Of a metal watch, maker's name White, a cornelian seal set in gold, and 11 s. in money. The seal had a head on it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you make any pursuit after the person that rob'd you?</p>
               <p>Upton. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the number of the watch?</p>
               <p>Upton. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. Which way did the man take after he had rob'd you?</p>
               <p>Upton. He went towards Acton, and we came to town.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was with you?</p>
               <p>Upton. A young gentleman that is now at Oxford.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see your watch since ?</p>
               <p>Upton. I saw it about the beginning of this week. It was advertised, and I went to justice Fielding's, and there I saw it.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen the seal since?</p>
               <p>Upton. No, I have not. (The watch produced in court.) This is the watch which I lost at that time.</p>
               <p>Cross Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know it to be your watch ?</p>
               <p>Upton. By a stain on the back of it, and the glass not shutting close.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175512040030"></xptr>Q. How long have you had it?</p>
               <p>Upton. I have had it about 4 or 5 years.</p>
               <p>William Norden. The prisoner was apprehended last Monday was sennight. I was ordered to search him in Mr. Fielding's office: I took this watch, and two others, out of the seat of his breeches, wrap'd up in an old news paper, in the tail of his shirt. Justice Fielding asked him, how he came by them: he said, He found them in St. James's park, at the root of a tree.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you ?</p>
               <p>Norden. I am an officer in the Palace court.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to search this prisoner ?</p>
               <p>Norden. I had him in custody, he having been arrested before we took him before justice Fielding; and there were pistols found in his pocket: so he was taken before Mr. Fielding on suspicion.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you a thief catcher ?</p>
               <p>Norden. If you will define what a thief-catcher is, I will tell you.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you employed to go and apprehend people charged with felony?</p>
               <p>Norden. I have apprehended a good many in my life time.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was with you when you took the watch from the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Norden. There were several there. Here is a man in court, his name is Hull, who was by.</p>
               <p>Will. Hull. I was in Mr. Fielding's office, when Norden searched the prisoner. I saw him take out three watches, from his breeches, wrap'd up in a news-paper.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say upon that?</p>
               <p>Hull. He said he found them in a news-paper, within an old handkerchief, lying at the root of a tree, near the Mall, in St. James's park.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know how he came to be apprehended?</p>
               <p>Hull. I had a writ against him, and was at the arresting him, at a coffee-house in the Strand; and going along with him, by the corner of St. Martin's-Lane, his coat knocked against me. I said to Mr. Breaden, I believe the gentleman has got pistols in his pocket. We both laid hold on the skirts of his coat, and found pistols. We took him to Peal's house, near St. James's-Church, and locked him up. I was desired to go and acquaint his father of it; for he was arrested by the desire of his father: but, when I was gone, the pistols were taken out of his pocket.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you a thief-catcher?</p>
               <p>Hull. I never was employed in apprehending thieves in all my days.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Hull. I am a Marshal's-court officer.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the debt paid afterwards?</p>
               <p>Hull. The money was paid in about half an hour after he was arrested.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>The reason why I had pistols in my pocket was, I was told a gentleman called me coward in a coffee-room, and I was determined to call him to an account for it. The night before I was taken, I was walking in the park very solitary, and found the watches wrap'd up in that paper, and an old rag, betwixt the walk and the mall.</p>
               <p>To his Character.</p>
               <p>William Northwood. I have known the prisoner ever since he was born.</p>
               <p>Q. What has been his character ?</p>
               <p>Northwood. I never knew any thing of him, but what was very honourable and just, till this time. He has been frequent in my shop; he has always kept the best of company. I never knew he kept bad company in my days.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Northwood. I live in Gutter-Lane, Cheapside.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-31-person326">
                  Richard 
                  James 
               <interp inst="t17551204-31-person326" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-31-person326" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-31-person326" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him six or seven years; his behaviour has been very well. He used to come to me in an evening. He behaved always in a gentleman-like manner.</p>
               <p>Q. What has been his general character?</p>
               <p>James. His character has been extraordinary good.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he looked upon as an honest man?</p>
               <p>James. That was his character.</p>
               <p>Mr. Ferne. I have known him fifteen or sixteen years, or upwards, and have been acquainted with him.</p>
               <p>Q. What has been his behaviour?</p>
               <p>Ferne. His behaviour has been very well. I never heard any thing of him, but what was honest, till this time. I always looked upon him to be an honest man.</p>
               <p>Q. How old is he?</p>
               <p>Mr. Ferne. He is about 22 years of age.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Mr. Ferne. I am a gold-beater, and live at the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175512040031"></xptr> corner of the Old-Baily; his friends live in the country; he is of a very worthy family.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17551204-31-verdict166" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17551204-31-verdict166" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a second time indicted for <rs id="t17551204-31-off167" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17551204-31-off167" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-31-off167" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he on the king's highway on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17551204-31-victim328" type="victimName">
                           Elizabeth 
                           Dickson 
                        <interp inst="t17551204-31-victim328" type="surname" value="Dickson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17551204-31-victim328" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17551204-31-victim328" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17551204-31-viclabel168" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-31-victim328 t17551204-31-viclabel168"></join>, did make an assault, putting her in corporal fear and danger of her life, and stealing from her person one gold watch, value 4 l. one gold seal, value 5 s. one chain made of base metal, value 12 d.
            </rs> the goods of the said Elizabeth, <rs id="t17551204-31-cd169" type="crimeDate">Nov. 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-31-off163 t17551204-31-cd169"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-31-off167 t17551204-31-cd169"></join>.* </p> 
               <p>Elizabeth Dickson. I was stop'd between <placeName id="t17551204-31-crimeloc170">Kingston</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17551204-31-crimeloc170" type="placeName" value="Kingston"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17551204-31-crimeloc170" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-31-off163 t17551204-31-crimeloc170"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-31-off167 t17551204-31-crimeloc170"></join> and <placeName id="t17551204-31-crimeloc171">Hampton Court</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17551204-31-crimeloc171" type="placeName" value="Hampton Court"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17551204-31-crimeloc171" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-31-off163 t17551204-31-crimeloc171"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-31-off167 t17551204-31-crimeloc171"></join> by a single highwayman, between four and five o'clock, on the 19th of November last in the afternoon. He came up to the coach and said, your money, quick, quick, or to that purpose.</p>

               <p>Q. Had he any arms ?</p>
               <p>Dickson. I did not see any that he had. I gave him my purse; then he said your watch, your watch, be quick. I gave him my watch.</p>
               <p>Q. What money might there be in your purse?</p>
               <p>Dickson. As near as I can guess, between four and five pounds.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there a seal to your watch ?</p>
               <p>Dickson. There was, with a coat of arms to it.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know who rob'd you?</p>
               <p>Dickson. I can say nothing to the prisoner. I don't know him. After that he went off towards Kingston, the way we came.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a horse was it he rode?</p>
               <p>Dickson. I can't tell any thing of his horse (the watch, seal, and chain produced in court.) I never took so much notice of the watch as to know it again; there may be others like it.</p>
               <p>Q. Look upon the seal.</p>
               <p>Dickson. This is the seal that I lost; it has my coat of arms on it.</p>
               <p>Q. Look upon the chain.</p>
               <p>Dickson. The chain is like mine; but I can't swear to it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did this seal hang to the watch at the time you lost it.</p>
               <p>Dickson. It did.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you buy the watch that was taken from you of?</p>
               <p>Dickson. I bought it of Mr. Ellicote.</p>
               <p>Q. How long ago?</p>
               <p>Dickson. It is a great many years ago.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-31-person329">
                  John 
                  Ellicote 
               <interp inst="t17551204-31-person329" type="surname" value="Ellicote"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-31-person329" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-31-person329" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . (He takes the watch in his hand) This is a watch of my making, it is No. 2066. Upon Mr. Fielding's sending to me I look'd in my book, and found that number was sold to Mrs. Dickson in the year 1740. I have had it since to clean for her, and know it to be her property.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you always register your watches which you sell?</p>
               <p>Ellicote. I do set down the name and number, and the person to whom I sell them; I seldom miss.</p>
               <p>Q. What time do you register them?</p>
               <p>Ellicote. At the time the watch is sold. I was sent for to Mr. Fielding's. I said this was Mrs. Dickson's, before I heard any thing of her being rob'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-31-person330">
                  John 
                  Wilton 
               <interp inst="t17551204-31-person330" type="surname" value="Wilton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-31-person330" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-31-person330" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coachman to this lady. I remember seeing the prisoner at justice Fielding's, but can't say he is the man that rob'd my lady.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a horse did that man ride who rob'd your mistress ?</p>
               <p>Wilton. He rode a black horse.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see a horse at justice Fielding's?</p>
               <p>Wilton. I did. That I believe was the horse the man rode, but I can't swear to him.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see him there?</p>
               <p>Wilton. I saw him there last Monday.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon what ground did you believe that to be the horse ?</p>
               <p>Wilton. Upon the account of his shewing himself when he moved.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was the robbery committed ?</p>
               <p>Wilton. It was committed between four and five o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q Was it day-light ?</p>
               <p>Wilton. It was.</p>
               <p>Q. What were the marks of the horse ?</p>
               <p>Wilton. I observed his tail was sharp cock'd. I had but very little sight of him.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by sharp cock'd?</p>
               <p>Wilton. By carrying his tail pretty high.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-31-person331">
                  Richard 
                  Frost 
               <interp inst="t17551204-31-person331" type="surname" value="Frost"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-31-person331" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-31-person331" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am footman to Mrs. Dickson. I was there at the time she was rob'd. I saw the prisoner since the robbery before justice Fielding. I don't remember he is the person that rob'd my lady.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a horse did the man that rob'd your lady ride?</p>
               <p>Frost. He rode a black horse.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see a horse that was brought to justice Fielding's?</p>
               <p>Frost. I did. He had a sharp cock'd tail, that is, he carried his tail and head pretty high, and his mane was on.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a horse, gelding, or mare the man rode that rob'd your mistress?</p>
               <p>Frost. That I did not observe. I am not positive whether it was that horse I saw, or not; but it look'd much like him.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you at the time of the robbery?</p>
               <p>Frost. I was behind the chariot.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-31-person332">
                  Samuel 
                  Breaden 
               <interp inst="t17551204-31-person332" type="surname" value="Breaden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-31-person332" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-31-person332" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lent the prisoner at the bar a horse on the 4th of November last, he kept him 16 days; he brought him home on the 19th at night. My man carried that horse to justice Fielding's last<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175512040032"></xptr> Monday. I was there when the horse was there.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a horse is he?</p>
               <p>Breaden. A black horse, about 14 hands and a half high, with a cut tail.</p>
               <p>Q. Is there any thing remarkable in his tail and head ?</p>
               <p>Breaden. Nothing, as I know of.</p>
               <p>Q. What condition was he in when brought home ?</p>
               <p>Breaden. He was spur'd pretty much.</p>
               <p>Q. What time in the evening was he brought?</p>
               <p>Breaden. A porter brought him home about seven in the evening.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the two last witnesses see that horse?</p>
               <p>Breaden. They did at justice Fielding's.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-31-person333">
                  William 
                  Norden 
               <interp inst="t17551204-31-person333" type="surname" value="Norden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-31-person333" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-31-person333" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This was one of the watches which I took from the prisoner at the bar, at justice Fielding's.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this gold seal fasten'd to the watch at that time ?</p>
               <p>Norden. No, it was wrap'd up in the same paper. Mr. Fielding ask'd him if he was a watch-maker; he said no. He said how came you by so many watches? He could give no answer. At last he said he found them in St. James's-Park, wrap'd up in an old news paper and an old handkerchief.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-31-person334">
                  Henry 
                  Peal 
               <interp inst="t17551204-31-person334" type="surname" value="Peal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-31-person334" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-31-person334" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I arrested the prisoner on Thursday was se'nnight last. When he was in my custody I perceived he had two pistols upon him, seeing the hoses of them stick out. I ask'd him for them, and he gave them me (produced in court).</p>
               <p>Q. Were they loaded ?</p>
               <p>Peal. They were loaded and primed, His relation paid the debt soon after.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I hope, my lord, you will consider when I was carried before justice Fielding a second time, he obliged me to put a blue coat on, and to button up the cape to my eyes, and put a hat on; he suffered some of them to pull up my hat, to see if they knew me, and they did not know me.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17551204-31-verdict172" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17551204-31-verdict172" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
