<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510417-45">
               <interp inst="t17510417-45" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510417-45" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510417-45" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510417"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510417-45" type="date" value="17510417"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510417-45-off221-c304" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510417-45-defend391 t17510417-45-off221 t17510417-45-verdict224"></join>
         
               <p>311. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17510417-45-defend391" type="defendantName">
                     Edward 
                     Ward 
                  <interp inst="t17510417-45-defend391" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-45-defend391" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-45-defend391" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted, for that <rs id="t17510417-45-off221" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510417-45-off221" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-45-off221" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               he on the <rs id="t17510417-45-cd222" type="crimeDate">second of November</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510417-45-off221 t17510417-45-cd222"></join>, about the hour of three in the night on the same day, the dwelling house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17510417-45-victim393" type="victimName">
                           Miles 
                           Childery 
                        <interp inst="t17510417-45-victim393" type="surname" value="Childery"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510417-45-victim393" type="given" value="Miles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510417-45-victim393" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did break and enter, nine pewter dishes, value 20 s. the property of the said Miles, and one hat the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17510417-45-victim395" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Narbury 
                        <interp inst="t17510417-45-victim395" type="surname" value="Narbury"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510417-45-victim395" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510417-45-victim395" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , did steal, take, &amp;c
            </rs>. *</p>
               <p>Agnes Taylor. I am Mr. Childery's sister, on the second of November we went to bed at his house, he lives in <placeName id="t17510417-45-crimeloc223">High-street in the parish of Stepney</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17510417-45-crimeloc223" type="placeName" value="High-street in the parish of Stepney"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510417-45-crimeloc223" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510417-45-off221 t17510417-45-crimeloc223"></join>, I was the last of the family that was up, every thing was fast; in the morning I was called up and told the house was broke open; I came down stairs and went into the yard, and found some person had broke into the yard, and then into the kitchen, which was boarded without side and within, but they had contrived it so well as to break a place were was only lath and plaister withinside; they got first into the skittle ground, then out of that they got into the kitchen; there was a pretty large quantity of pewter in the kitchen, I missed nine large dishes; about a fortnight ago there came some people from Bridewell to let us know they had taken the people who had robbed us: I went to see them and so to Justice Fielding; the prisoner apprehended he should have been admitted an evidence, but his worship admitted another who is here, who said they were apprehensive there were some people coming, or they had took more things: I suppose it was the dog might make a noise in another room; the prisoner also told the whole case, what method they took to get in, and how they robbed the house.</p>
               <p>Court. As that was done under an expectation of being admitted an evidence, that cannot be taken as evidence here.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he confess to you before he came to the justices?</p>
               <p>A. Taylor. He did to me in Bridewell, that he took the pewter and carried it away. I went there and asked the people where the man was who robbed me, they brought the two persons to me; I asked the prisoner how he came to be so well acquainted with the house; he told me he knew nothing of the house, it was the other person which brought him there, and that he took the dishes away, this he said voluntary.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510417-45-person396">
                  John 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17510417-45-person396" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-45-person396" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-45-person396" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17510417-45-person397">
                  Edward 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17510417-45-person397" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-45-person397" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-45-person397" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and I went to this house about two or three o'clock in the morning, it was a moon light morning and rained, he lent me a hand over a wall, then I opened the skittle ground window, by making a hole and pushing back the bolt, and he got over a little bank and came and got in: after we were in the skittle ground, the window that is in the kitchen is in the skittle ground. I took a pane of glass out of the window, and unhaspd the casement, and then open'd the window.</p>
         
               <p>N. B. The second part will be published in a few days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17510417-45">
                  <interp inst="t17510417-45" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510417-45" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510417-45" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510417"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510417-45" type="date" value="17510417"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175104170021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX,</p>
                  <p>HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY,</p>
                  <p>On Wednesday the 17th, Thursday the 18th, Friday the 19th, Saturday the 20th, and Monday the 22d of April.</p>
                  <p>In the 24th Year of His MAJESTY's Reign.</p>
                  <p>BEING THE Fourth SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of the</p>
                  <p>Right Honble 
                  <persName id="t17510417-45-person398">
                     Francis 
                     Cokayne 
                  <interp inst="t17510417-45-person398" type="surname" value="Cokayne"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510417-45-person398" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510417-45-person398" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Esq; LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>PART II. of NUMBER IV.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by M. COOPER, at the Globe in Pater-noster Row. 1751.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-Pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175104170022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery held for the City of London, &amp;c.</p>
                  <p>
               
                     <persName id="t17510417-45-person399">
                     John 
                     Robinson 
                  <interp inst="t17510417-45-person399" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510417-45-person399" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510417-45-person399" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               .</p>
               </div1>
               <p>THERE was another shutter within side, I took a knife and cut two of the laths away, then took off the mortar, and put in my hand and unbolted it, so got in, and took out nine pewter dishes, and a hat; then we took them into the skittle ground, put them into a bag we had got, and carried them home. We rented two rooms of 
               <persName id="t17510417-45-person400">
                  Richard 
                  Morris 
               <interp inst="t17510417-45-person400" type="surname" value="Morris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-45-person400" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-45-person400" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , see No 271, who is now in Goal, we gave him fourteen pence per week for them. We doubled them up, and the next day we carried them to one 
               <persName id="t17510417-45-person401">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Brease 
               <interp inst="t17510417-45-person401" type="surname" value="Brease"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-45-person401" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-45-person401" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in Church-lane, about two doors on this side the Ship; she gave us five-pence per pound for them, they came to twenty four shillings, we took twelve shillings then and the other twelve afterwards; she well knew how we came by them, because she dealt with a great many that way; and likewise I told her where we got them; she said, it was very well, and that she would take care they should not be seen; she is fled.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510417-45-person402">
                  Thomas 
                  Ind 
               <interp inst="t17510417-45-person402" type="surname" value="Ind"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-45-person402" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-45-person402" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the taking the prisoner, he, the evidence, and another, all wanted to be admitted evidence; when they came before Justice Fielding, the prisoner began to tell his worship of the robbery. One of the others told his worship, that Ward had been admitted an evidence before, and hanged one Roberson, a black, and two others; then the Justice refused him to be an evidence again.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510417-45-verdict224" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510417-45-verdict224" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510417-45-punish225" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510417-45-punish225" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510417-45-defend391 t17510417-45-punish225"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
