<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17500912-15">
               <interp inst="t17500912-15" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500912-15" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500912-15" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17500912"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500912-15" type="date" value="17500912"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500912-15-off72-c94" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-15-defend122 t17500912-15-off72 t17500912-15-verdict75"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500912-15-off72-c95" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-15-defend124 t17500912-15-off72 t17500912-15-verdict75"></join>
         
               <p>519, 520. 
               
                  <persName id="t17500912-15-defend122" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Theobalds 
                  <interp inst="t17500912-15-defend122" type="surname" value="Theobalds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-15-defend122" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-15-defend122" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17500912-15-defend124" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Dangerfield 
                  <interp inst="t17500912-15-defend124" type="surname" value="Dangerfield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-15-defend124" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-15-defend124" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , were indicted for that <rs id="t17500912-15-off72" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500912-15-off72" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-15-off72" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               they, on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17500912-15-victim126" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Cave 
                        <interp inst="t17500912-15-victim126" type="surname" value="Cave"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500912-15-victim126" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500912-15-victim126" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-15-off72 t17500912-15-victim126"></join>
                     </persName>
                     
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life. 7 s. and 6 d. in money, numbered from his person, and against his will, did steal, take, and carry away
            </rs>, <rs id="t17500912-15-cd73" type="crimeDate">Aug. 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-15-off72 t17500912-15-cd73"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-15-person127">
                  William 
                  Cave 
               <interp inst="t17500912-15-person127" type="surname" value="Cave"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-15-person127" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-15-person127" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 12th of Aug. about 9 at night, there were I, and 
               <persName id="t17500912-15-person128">
                  Thomas 
                  Hammond 
               <interp inst="t17500912-15-person128" type="surname" value="Hammond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-15-person128" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-15-person128" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and three women, in a four wheel chaise, with a back seat to it ; and 
               <persName id="t17500912-15-person129">
                  Thomas 
                  Snow 
               <interp inst="t17500912-15-person129" type="surname" value="Snow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-15-person129" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-15-person129" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             drove it. Coming along <placeName id="t17500912-15-crimeloc74">Bethnal Green back road</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17500912-15-crimeloc74" type="placeName" value="Bethnal Green back road"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17500912-15-crimeloc74" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-15-off72 t17500912-15-crimeloc74"></join>, there was a man on horseback rode up to the coachman, and ordered him to stop or he would blow his brains out. After a few words pass'd he came to me, and demanded my money; it was a dark and rainy night; I could not see to swear to the man; I gave him three farthings. He look'd at me and said, d - n your blood what is that for? He demanded more; he call'd out to another man on horseback on the other side, and bid him mind his business. I put my hand in my other pocket and gave him 7 s. 6 d. Then he turned his horse about, and ordered the other man to stop the next coach, calling him Thomas. After he turned his horse about, the coachman said, d - n your body, I know you, I see you almost every day. We all called out and bid him hold his tongue. 
               <persName id="t17500912-15-person130">
                  Thomas 
                  Hammond 
               <interp inst="t17500912-15-person130" type="surname" value="Hammond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-15-person130" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-15-person130" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             lost a shilling and a halfpenny, taken by the man on the other side, but I did not see him do it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-15-person131">
                  Thomas 
                  Snow 
               <interp inst="t17500912-15-person131" type="surname" value="Snow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-15-person131" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-15-person131" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the coachman. As we were coming from Mile-end turnpike to Bethnal Green, two men rode up on the off-side the chaise ; one of them bid me stop, or he would blow my brains out; he had a pistol in his hand. The other rode round on the other side of the chaise : then he who bid me stop, bid me hold my head the other way, or else he'd blow my brains out : (then I knew his voice). He rode up to Mr. Cave, and d - d him, and put the pistol towards him. I heard him ask him for money, saying, money he must have. I turn'd my head round and looked at him. I heard the money chink, but could not see it, it was so dark. Then there came by a coach on the other side; to the best of my knowledge<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175009120007"></xptr> one called out to the other, and bid him stop it; and we went on to London.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the man that stopp'd you?</p>
               <p>Snow. I saw his face and knew him; I believe my face was within a yard and half or two yards of his; I knew his voice and his face at that very time; it was 
               <persName id="t17500912-15-person132">
                  John 
                  Dangerfield 
               <interp inst="t17500912-15-person132" type="surname" value="Dangerfield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-15-person132" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-15-person132" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ; I have drank also with him several times before in Smithfield, and that very night I caused him to be taken up. I have known him three or four years: He was book-keeper to a Waggon on that comes in at the Sarazen's head, on Snow-hill. As to the other prisoner, Theobald, I have nothing against him, but Dangerfield's own words. When he was taken up, he said, he was in company with Theobald's at that time. On thursday was sen'night I was going by the Half-moon in Smithfield, I saw Dangerfield drinking in a public room. I went in, and drank part of one pot of beer with him. I tapp'd him by the shoulder, and called him cut, and asked him, if he remember'd last Sunday-night, about stopping a four-wheel'd chaise near Mile-end turnpike. And he said, did you drive it ? I said yes. Then said he, My dear eyes, be righteous to me, my life lies in your hands. I am sure he is the man that robbed Mr. Cave, if there is a man living in this place.</p>
               <p>On his cross examination he said, it was a dark rainy night; the prisoner's hat was not put down; he had on a neat coat; that he did not think proper to blow it, though he said at that time he knew him, till he could have an opportunity of taking him himself; he believes Dangerfield did not know him when he did the robbery.</p>
               <p>Dangerfield's Defence. I know nothing at all of the matter which this man charges me with.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-15-person133">
                  Robert 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17500912-15-person133" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-15-person133" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-15-person133" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a printer, and live in the Old-Baily; I have seen the two prisoners at the bar twice before, once the 12th of August, the other time in Bridewell: On the 12th of August I saw them at Holloway, at the Horse and Groom; they came in there about a quarter before 7 o'clock in the evening, they got off their horses; whether they came up or down the road thither I know not. The man of the house was fuddled, he brought them out some cold sowl, they call'd for some wine; I remember I had some discourse with them about the Foundling-Hospital, I had been there to see the christening; I came away from thence 17 minutes, by the clock, wanting of 8 o'clock in the evening, and I believe when my wife and I got into the chaise it might be within 10 minutes of 8. I left them there, and their horses were then in the stable.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Walker confirms this account.</p>
               <p>Joseph Cooper I live about a mile and a half on this side the Horse and Groom; Mr. Dangerfield and another man came into my house the 12th of August at night, we had candles lighted; when they came in they call'd for a quartern of rum and milk; there was a heavy shower of rain; I went to bed, they staid drinking their liquor; how long they stay'd I can't tell.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-15-person134">
                  Christiana 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17500912-15-person134" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-15-person134" type="given" value="Christiana"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-15-person134" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live a servant with Mr. Cooper; I remember the prisoners coming into our house, they alighted at the door, and put their horses up themselves; they call'd for sixpeny worth of rum and milk; they ask'd what o'clock it was, I took the candle and saw it wanted 10 minutes of 9, it rained then; they had been in a considerable time before they ask'd what o'clock it was; they did not go away till after 9 o'clock.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-15-person135">
                  Sarah 
                  Sutton 
               <interp inst="t17500912-15-person135" type="surname" value="Sutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-15-person135" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-15-person135" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know Snow the coachman, he was at breakfast with Mr. Hammond at our house, the Half-Moon in Smithfield: Hammond is a coachman, and was robb'd with Cave; Snow said he was very sorry for what he had done in swearing against Dangerfield, and that he had not done it if he had not been advised to it, and that he thought of being a master coachman.</p>
               <p>Job Selby, Mr. Page, Mr. Norton, 
               <persName id="t17500912-15-person136">
                  John 
                  Sibley 
               <interp inst="t17500912-15-person136" type="surname" value="Sibley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-15-person136" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-15-person136" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17500912-15-person137">
                  Francis 
                  Pepworth 
               <interp inst="t17500912-15-person137" type="surname" value="Pepworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-15-person137" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-15-person137" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , all gave Dangerfield a very good character.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17500912-15-verdict75" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500912-15-verdict75" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
