<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510911-48">
               <interp inst="t17510911-48" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510911-48" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510911-48" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510911-48" type="date" value="17510911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510911-48-off225-c310" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-48-defend401 t17510911-48-off225 t17510911-48-verdict230"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510911-48-off225-c311" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-48-defend404 t17510911-48-off225 t17510911-48-verdict232"></join>
         
               <p>522, 523. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17510911-48-defend401" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Benjamin 
                     Smith 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17510911-48-alias-8" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-48-defend401 t17510911-48-alias-8"></join>Grout</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-defend401" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-defend401" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-defend401" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17510911-48-defend404" type="defendantName">
                     Patrick 
                     Berry 
                  <interp inst="t17510911-48-defend404" type="surname" value="Berry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-defend404" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-defend404" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for that they, together with 
               <persName id="t17510911-48-person405">
                  William 
                  Pain 
               <interp inst="t17510911-48-person405" type="surname" value="Pain"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-person405" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-person405" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , not yet taken, <rs id="t17510911-48-off225" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-off225" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-off225" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               did steal two lambs, value 30 s.
            </rs> the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17510911-48-victim407" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Jones 
                  <interp inst="t17510911-48-victim407" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-victim407" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-victim407" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-48-off225 t17510911-48-victim407"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17510911-48-cd226" type="crimeDate">July 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-48-off225 t17510911-48-cd226"></join>. ++.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-48-person408">
                  John 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17510911-48-person408" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-person408" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-person408" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17510911-48-viclabel227" type="occupation">butcher</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-48-victim407 t17510911-48-viclabel227"></join>, and live in <placeName id="t17510911-48-crimeloc228">Wapping</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17510911-48-crimeloc228" type="placeName" value="Wapping"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510911-48-crimeloc228" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-48-off225 t17510911-48-crimeloc228"></join>. On the twelfth of July I bought fifteen lambs of Mr. Saunders in Smithfield, at fifteen shillings each; and I turn'd them down into my fields, at the bottom of <placeName id="t17510911-48-crimeloc229">Bird-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17510911-48-crimeloc229" type="placeName" value="Bird-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510911-48-crimeloc229" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-48-off225 t17510911-48-crimeloc229"></join>, which is about six stones cast from my house, the same day. On the next morning I went down, betwixt four and five o'clock, with one of my men, in order to direct some of them to be killed, and we found but thirteen; but as I could not see any place where they could get out, by looking round, I immediately concluded they were stole. I then called upon one John Brown, a labourer, and ordered him to go and look up and down in the little shops, to see if he could find any large lambs. After this I had word from my drover, about three in the afternoon, that he saw a man dressing two large horn lambs in the morning, about four or five o'clock, at the Queen's Head in Rag-fair, and that there was some of the meat hanging up at the front of the house to be sold. Mine being horn lambs, as described, I went to Justice Manwaring, got a search-warrant, and ordered my drover and another man to go there, and call for a mug of beer, and observe what they could. They went, and when I came, which was after them, I saw two hind quarters of ewe lamb, and one of a weather lamb, hanging at the door; I made a stop, and look'd at them. There was 
               <persName id="t17510911-48-person409">
                  Patrick 
                  Berry 
               <interp inst="t17510911-48-person409" type="surname" value="Berry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-person409" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-person409" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             there, who ask'd me if I would buy the quarters of lamb; I said they were very good, and ask'd if he had more of them. He took me into a back house, or shed, where I saw four quarters of lamb lying, and a hind quarter hanging upon a string in the middle of the place. I asked what I should give for them, and I think he said three pence halfpenny per pound. I said they were very good, and asked who owned them; he said, I own them, and that man, pointing to one Pain, that stood by. I said to Pain, Do you own them? he said Yes, and that<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175109110027"></xptr> man, pointing to Berry. Then I gave a man the warrant, and bid him fetch a constable, and the drover went out with him. As soon as they were gone, Berry endeavour'd to get out, but I stopped him; and when they returned, I went to searching the house. In the vault was found part of the head of a lamb's skin, with my mark upon it, which is a clip down the face. We took Perry before Justice Manwaring ; where we had not been long, before there came a messenger to tell us, that they had taken one of the sheep stealers. I went, and found it was the prisoner Smith, as he called himself, but his proper name is 
               <persName id="t17510911-48-person410">
                  Richard 
                  Grout 
               <interp inst="t17510911-48-person410" type="surname" value="Grout"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-person410" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-person410" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The Justice examined Smith, and he denied it at first, but at last he said he'd tell the truth. He said Pain and he were down at the field - then the Justice made his Mittimus to Bridewell. We took him to my house: there he confessed he stood upon a hog tub without, and the other, Perry, went over and tied the lambs legs, and gave them over the pales; that then Pain and Perry carried them to the end of Virginia-street; there he took the lamb that Berry had, and he and Pain carried them to the Queen's Head door, and knocked up Mr. Hust, that keeps the house ; that they went backwards, and killed them in his shead, and he dressed one lamb, while they took off the skin of the other; that then Pain and Perry carried the skins out, and sold them; that they only gave him some bear; and that he did not know what they sold them for, nor where. I got up on Sunday morning, and went to the Fellmongers, and found the two skins at Mr. Browning's, in Barnaby street, Surry. On the Monday morning I went to my drover, who knows my clip, and took him to Mr. Browning's? where he saw them. There was the grasier's mark, an M, on the near hip, and my mark was a clip on the off hip, about the length of a finger. We carried these two skins to my fell-monger, to compare them with some I had sold there, and they exactly agreed. I also made a clip down the face, but the faces of both these skins were gone. I can swear they are the skins of my lambs by what I saw.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-48-person411">
                  Peter 
                  Strickland 
               <interp inst="t17510911-48-person411" type="surname" value="Strickland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-person411" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-person411" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am foreman to Mr. Browning, a fellmonger in Barnaby-street. I bought them two skins of 
               <persName id="t17510911-48-person412">
                  Benjamin 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17510911-48-person412" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-person412" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-person412" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             on Saturday morning, July 13. He brought them into my master's yard, and asked if my master was at home; I said he was not, but I could buy them all the same. He asked four shillings for them, and I bid him three; then he said three shillings and sixpence, and I bought them for three shillings and two pence; but there was never a head upon thee There was a brand mark, an M, on one hip, and a little clip on the other. Mr. Jones came on the Sunday, but I was not at home; he came again on the Monday, and having left word before of his business, I had looked the skins out, which I bought of this Smith, and I found them out from two or three hundred which I had bought the same day. He said they were his, and desired I would go to his Fellmonger with him, to see them compared, which I did, and they were the same mark and the same clip.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-48-person413">
                  Richard 
                  Brailey 
               <interp inst="t17510911-48-person413" type="surname" value="Brailey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-person413" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-person413" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am drover to Mr. Jones, and drove the lambs to Mr. Jones's field the Friday before; there were 15 of them, who were all branded on the near hip with an M. and clipped on the off hip and down the face; they were all horned lambs. I was going over the water to meet a drove of lambs the same morning they were lost. I came to Mr. Hust's house, and heard a knife and steel whetting, but could not see any thing; Mr. Hust ask'd me to go for a keg of gin for him, which I did, and was gone about three quarters of an hour; then I sat down there again, and heard the knife and steel going again. and asked to go backwards to ease myself in the yard, where I saw the prisoner, Smith, cutting the skin off the head of a lamb. I looked up at the lambs, and said, they are two good lambs; he said, so they are, too good for Rag-fair. I let my master know this, so he sent Brown and I, and gave Brown three half-pence to call for a pint of beer at Mr. Hust's. Q. Did you observe the mark upon the skins then?</p>

               <p>Brailey. No, I did not; I was with my master at Barnaby-street, at Mr. Browning's, and there we saw two skins, the same mark with those I drove into Mr. Jones's field.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-48-person414">
                  Margaret 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17510911-48-person414" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-person414" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-person414" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live facing Mr. Jones's field: on the night before the lambs were stolen, I was up about eleven at night with a neighbour next door, and there came two men, whom I thought might belong to Mr. Jones; I looked at them very narrowly, and they went off from the light of the candle, my house being at the corner, they stood a little time, and leaned over the pales, looking into the fields where the lambs were, They walked from thence towards my house, and I desired my neighbour to let me have a candle to see who they were, one of whom was a poor looking man with a great coat on, and the other white frock. I said to them, who do you want and one of them ask'd, if I knew one Welch, a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175109110028"></xptr> name I knew nothing of; he said he liv'd in the street, and keeps lodgers. I then directed him to a house where they had lodgers, but not of that name, and then they went off.</p>
               <p>Q. Were either of the prisoners the men?</p>
               <p>M. Johnson. I don't pretend to say who they were?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Smith told before the Justice what conversation passed between this woman and himself.</p>
               <p>John Brown. The drover came to me about four o'clock the day the lambs were missing, and told me Mr. Jones had lost two lambs; there having been two lambs seen in this place on the back of Rag-fair, Mr. Jones said, go with the drover, and call for a pint of beer, which we did; I went backwards, and said to Pain who was there, here are two good lambs, I seldom see such kill'd here; says he, we have as good lambs kill'd here, as in other places; I ask'd him, if he had a partner, and he told me he had, and pointed to Smith; there were only them two there. As soon as my master came in, Pain went out and made his escape; I did not see Perry there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-48-person415">
                  John 
                  Hust 
               <interp inst="t17510911-48-person415" type="surname" value="Hust"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-person415" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-person415" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a publick house in Cable-street, the prisoner Smith came to my house, and said, he had some sheep in the country ; (this is about six weeks ago) he ask'd me leave to kill them in my back place, and I gave him leave. I saw him bring in two lambs alive one morning about five o'clock, but did not observe the marks.</p>
               <p>Smith's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was come out of the country, and wanted work; Pain and Perry told me, they could give me a day's work, and bid me come about four o'clock in the morning, saying, they had two lambs to kill ; I came and dressed them, and carried the skins, which I sold for 3 s. 2 d. I came back again, and gave Pain the money, but did not know which way they came by them.</p>
               <p>Perry's Defence.</p>
               <p>These two men, Pain and Smith, happened to come to the door; they had a lamb and a quarter in a basket, and Pain begg'd of me to lend him my things to hang that lamb up; they gave me a pot of beer, and desir'd if any body came while he was cutting the rest up backwards, I would sell it for him; I told him, it was no trouble to me; they both said they bought them at Smithfield. Mr. Jones came and ask'd the price of the lambs, and I said they were three pence halfpenny per pound; he ask'd if there were any more, I told him there was a lamb in the yard, and he went to lock at it; said he, is it yours? I told him no, it belong'd to them two men, and they say they bought them in Smithfield, I have nothing to say to it; then Mr. Jones insisted upon taking hold on me, but they both got away; at last Smith was catch'd, and brought before the Justice. I was in bed about half an hour after nine o'clock, and did not get up till after six; I sell meat at Mr. Hust's door, and have many months.</p>
               <p>To his Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-48-person416">
                  John 
                  Hust 
               <interp inst="t17510911-48-person416" type="surname" value="Hust"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-person416" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-person416" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never knew any thing to the contrary but that Perry was an honest man.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-48-person417">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Golby 
               <interp inst="t17510911-48-person417" type="surname" value="Golby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-person417" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-person417" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know Perry, he is a tenant of mine; he has liv'd under me about half a year, and I never observed but he worked hard for his bread, and behav'd well; I never heard any body challenge him with being a thief in my life; the morning these lambs were found, (being on a Saturday) I got up between six and seven o'clock to see my shop open'd; this Perry came and asked a neighbour to lend him a stick to go to Whitechapel with his tray, as usual; he used to go a peddling with meat.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-48-person418">
                  James 
                  Pendegrest 
               <interp inst="t17510911-48-person418" type="surname" value="Pendegrest"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-person418" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-person418" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Perry some time; he is a butcher, and has bore a very good character ever since he came into our neighbourhood; I live in the house where he does, and the night before the lambs were found at Hust's house, I heard Perry and his wife in his own room about nine o'clock: his wife lock'd the door; my wife had been out, she call'd me to open the street door, and ask'd how it came to be fastened so soon; I let her in, and desir'd her to bolt the door after her. I went to bed a little after ten, and got up about three in the morning, and found the street door bolted; I let a man in about a quarter after five. I am a taylor, and was at work, and nobody could come in or out at the street door, but I must see them, I sat in such a position. The prisoner came to me about half an hour after six, and asked me for a stick to go to market with, and after that went out.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-48-person419">
                  Robert 
                  Reynolds 
               <interp inst="t17510911-48-person419" type="surname" value="Reynolds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-person419" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-person419" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know Grout, he went by that name in the country, that is Smith; I never knew him wrong any body in the would, and I have known him upwards of 20 years; he comes from a place call'd Puckeridge in Hertfordshire.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175109110029"></xptr>Mrs. Bradshaw. I knew Grout, otherwise Smith, at Puckeridge, and I never heard he was guilty of any ill.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has he been come from thence?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Bradshaw. He has been come from thence these four years.</p>
               <p>Smith <rs id="t17510911-48-verdict230" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-verdict230" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510911-48-punish231" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-punish231" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-48-defend401 t17510911-48-punish231"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Perry <rs id="t17510911-48-verdict232" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510911-48-verdict232" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
