<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17581206-22">
               <interp inst="t17581206-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581206-22" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581206-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17581206"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581206-22" type="date" value="17581206"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17581206-22-off110-c160" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-22-defend192 t17581206-22-off110 t17581206-22-verdict113"></join>
         
               <p>24. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17581206-22-defend192" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Torbuck 
                  <interp inst="t17581206-22-defend192" type="surname" value="Torbuck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-defend192" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-defend192" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17581206-22-deflabel109" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-22-defend192 t17581206-22-deflabel109"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17581206-22-off110" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-off110" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-off110" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 20 guineas
            </rs>, the money of 
               
                  <persName id="t17581206-22-victim194" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Goulding 
                  <interp inst="t17581206-22-victim194" type="surname" value="Goulding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-victim194" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-victim194" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-22-off110 t17581206-22-victim194"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17581206-22-cd111" type="crimeDate">Aug. 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-22-off110 t17581206-22-cd111"></join>. *</p>
               <p>John Goulding. The prisoner was my <rs id="t17581206-22-deflabel112" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581206-22-defend192 t17581206-22-deflabel112"></join>, she came first as a chair-woman, and at last I hired her at 3 l. a year; I lost 20 guineas out of a drawer at my bed's feet in our room, in a little green purse.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you seen it last?</p>
               <p>J. Goulding. I saw it last on Friday, the 6th of August, and did not miss it 'till the Tuesday after; then I went up to take it to pay away where I ow'd it, and it was all gone.</p>
               <p>Q. Why do you suspect the prisoner?</p>
               <p>J. Goulding. She would quarrel with us on that Sunday, and would not take dinner up, but went away in an abrupt manner; I went to Mr Fielding, and took out a warrant against her; we could not find her, but we took up her mother, after that we took the prisoner and had her before Mr Fielding, and he committed her: she would not confess any thing.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Did you ever see me in your room?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175812060019"></xptr>J. Goulding. No: We never suffer a servant to go there without our knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Whether my mother was not taken up for stealing this money?</p>
               <p>J. Goulding. No, she was charged with receiving the money, knowing it to have been stolen.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-22-person195">
                  Sarah 
                  Goulding 
               <interp inst="t17581206-22-person195" type="surname" value="Goulding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person195" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person195" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner came very poor into my service, on the Thursday morning my husband went up stairs, the prisoner said, I wonder what my master goes up stairs for! with an oath, I'll go up and peep. On the Saturday morning I call'd her about 5 o'clock; she never answer'd me: after that I call'd her again, she made no answer, presently I goes to the stair-foot, and heard our room door creak.</p>

               <p>Q. Where was your husband then?</p>
               <p>S. Goulding. He was asleep in bed. We lay up one pair of stairs, and she lay in a room opposite, on the same floor; I said nothing to her, nor she to me: on Sunday we had some friends come to see us, and at noon, when we went to dinner, she went up stairs and would eat no victuals; she had quarrel'd with one of the women that had help'd me to dress dinner; she said she would go and see her father and mother: I said pray take your week's wages with you; she had been with me that time. She would not take it, her mother came on the Saturday, and brought her a pair of old shoes; after that a strange man came and brought her some cloaths; I miss'd my money and took her up; in the drawer where this money was, was a small piece of chints, for many years, producing it. This I found in the prisoner's bed-chamber.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Was not you much in liquor; did not you take a half pint pot, and go down into the brandy cellar and get drunk, and then come and give me a slap in the face that Sunday morning?</p>
               <p>S. Goulding. O you wicked girl! I never did such a thing in my life.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. She lock'd up the victuals, and would not let me have any dinner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-22-person196">
                  Stephen 
                  Dupre 
               <interp inst="t17581206-22-person196" type="surname" value="Dupre"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person196" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person196" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was the officer. I served the warrant on the prisoner and her mother; the daughter was taken up for robbing her master of twenty guineas and a purse; the mother was for receiving the same, well knowing it to have been stoln; August the 9th the warrant was deliver'd to me; I went to the mother's house, and ask'd the mother where the daughter was: she said she was gone cross Morefields; we staid there about an hour and a half: she did not come, then we took the old woman, her name is 
               <persName id="t17581206-22-person197">
                  Ann 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17581206-22-person197" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person197" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person197" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; when we were at Justice Fielding's, then the prisoner came; we heard she was at the door, waiting to speak to the old woman; then we went and fetch'd her in. She was ask'd were she bought all her cloaths; she having bought capuchins, and several things of value; she gave a very bad account of that. Justice Fielding ask'd her how she came by the money; she said her brother gave it her; then Mary Peters said, you shew'd me another black petticoat; the prisoner said it was a red one which she had then on; one of the Justice's men look'd at it, and said it was a very good one; it was ordered to be taken off. When she came in again, her mother was coming to speak to her; she shov'd her mother aside, and said, what are you going to turn evidence against me, and hang me? when we found those cloaths of her's, they were conceal'd within the tick of a bed, in a pillowbier, after the tick was ripp'd open.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-22-person198">
                  Mary 
                  Peters 
               <interp inst="t17581206-22-person198" type="surname" value="Peters"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person198" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person198" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was before Justice Fielding when the prisoner was there; there were a very great argument between her mother and she, but Goulding's money was not particularly nam'd; she got up to her mother and said, Go along, now you have got all you can, I may go to the Devil.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-22-person199">
                  Matthew 
                  Eabourn 
               <interp inst="t17581206-22-person199" type="surname" value="Eabourn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person199" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person199" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at Mr. Fielding's when the prisoner was examin'd; her mother said something to her, but what, I can't tell; she draw'd herself from her mother, and said, what are you going to turn evidence against me to hang me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-22-person200">
                  Richard 
                  Pugh 
               <interp inst="t17581206-22-person200" type="surname" value="Pugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person200" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person200" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the searching of the prisoner's room and saw those cloaths found in the tick of the bed.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence. I never saw the money, nor had a farthing of it; there was a gentleman that knew me from a child, and he knows I have had a great many things from the country.</p>
         
               <p>***The Second Part of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17581206-22">
                  <interp inst="t17581206-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17581206-22" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17581206-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17581206"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17581206-22" type="date" value="17581206"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175812060020"></xptr>PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON, And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 6th, Thursday the 7th, and Friday the 8th of DECEMBER, 1758.</p>
                  <p>In the Thirty-second Year of His MAJESTY'S Reign. NUMBER I. PART II. for the YEAR 1759. Being the First SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of The Right Honble Sir 
                  <persName id="t17581206-22-person201">
                     RICHARD 
                     GLYN 
                  <interp inst="t17581206-22-person201" type="surname" value="GLYN"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17581206-22-person201" type="given" value="RICHARD"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17581206-22-person201" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Knt. LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by M. COOPER, at the Globe in Pater-noster-Row. 1758.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175812060021"></xptr>PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery held for the City of LONDON, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>THAT 
               <persName id="t17581206-22-person202">
                  Mary 
                  Peters 
               <interp inst="t17581206-22-person202" type="surname" value="Peters"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person202" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person202" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             told me, that piece of chints lay kick'd about the room where she lay; I never saw it in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17581206-22-person203">
                  Mary 
                  Peters 
               <interp inst="t17581206-22-person203" type="surname" value="Peters"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person203" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person203" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Where did you see that piece of chints?</p>
               <p>M. Peters. I saw it lying in the room where I lay. I was servant to the prosecutor after the prisoner went away; as I was making the bed I saw it lying under the bed.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs Goulding. Where did you see this piece of chints first?</p>
               <p>Mrs Goulding. I first saw it amongst the prisoner's things on the table in her room.</p>
               <p>To her character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-22-person204">
                  James 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17581206-22-person204" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person204" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person204" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17581206-22-person205">
                  Mary 
                  Peters 
               <interp inst="t17581206-22-person205" type="surname" value="Peters"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person205" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person205" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is a woman of no reputation, she said she would swear any thing at all in favour of her master; the mistress had turn'd her away, and since that, has taken her again in order to swear against the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at the buying of the prisoner's cloaths.</p>
               <p>Davis. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not say you knew nothing of the things?</p>
               <p>Davis. I do not know how my wife and daughter came by them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you bring an action against the constable for the things?</p>
               <p>Davis. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Where they bought with your money?</p>
               <p>Davis. No: I could not afford it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-22-person206">
                  Ann 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17581206-22-person206" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person206" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person206" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am mother to the prisoner at the bar. I was taken up instead of her; I have the gentlewoman here that bought almost all the things; she comes out of Buckingham: her name is Mrs Millican.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-22-person207">
                  Ann 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17581206-22-person207" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person207" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person207" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Wing, near Tring. I once kept a good house there, and many servants.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-22-person208">
                  Ann 
                  Millican 
               <interp inst="t17581206-22-person208" type="surname" value="Millican"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person208" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person208" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner first lived with me at her first going out to service.</p>
               <p>Q. When did she come from you?</p>
               <p>A. Millican. She went from me about two years ago; she behav'd very well: she liv'd with me three years, but she had a mind to come to London, like a great many more people, they are very fond of London were there is a great deal of silver; she thought to get all the world by coming here; I have trusted her with all I had; I would take her again did I want a servant, as soon as any body I know.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-22-person209">
                  Robert 
                  Dunbar 
               <interp inst="t17581206-22-person209" type="surname" value="Dunbar"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person209" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person209" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner's parents have been servants to us seventeen years; they are very honest people; I believe the prisoner to be truly honest.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you been acquainted with her?</p>
               <p>Dunbar. I have not been acquainted with her at all, only with her mother and father.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-22-person210">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Waters 
               <interp inst="t17581206-22-person210" type="surname" value="Waters"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person210" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person210" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner going on of six years, she liv'd once at Muzzle-hill; I never heard any harm by her 'till this happen'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-22-person211">
                  John 
                  Rhimes 
               <interp inst="t17581206-22-person211" type="surname" value="Rhimes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person211" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person211" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner and her mother five or six years; I never heard any harm of her 'till now; the mother I always knew to be a very just, honest, sober woman.</p>
               <p>For the prosecution.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581206-22-person212">
                  John 
                  Dean 
               <interp inst="t17581206-22-person212" type="surname" value="Dean"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person212" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-person212" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner at the bar was servant to me in the year 1755; I catch'd her two times in stealing of half-pence, and in two or three days after my drawers were broke open and I miss'd 20 l.</p>
               <p>Q. Only say what is her general character,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175812060022"></xptr> a good or a bad one.</p>
               <p>Dean. Not a good one at all.  <rs id="t17581206-22-verdict113" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581206-22-verdict113" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
