<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17520514-30">
               <interp inst="t17520514-30" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520514-30" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520514-30" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520514"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520514-30" type="date" value="17520514"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520514-30-off158-c240" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-30-defend291 t17520514-30-off158 t17520514-30-verdict163"></join>
         
               <p>316. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17520514-30-defend291" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Carpenter 
                  <interp inst="t17520514-30-defend291" type="surname" value="Carpenter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-30-defend291" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-30-defend291" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-30-defend291" type="age" value="15 years of age"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17520514-30-deflabel157" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-30-defend291 t17520514-30-deflabel157"></join>, was indicted for the <rs id="t17520514-30-off158" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520514-30-off158" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-30-off158" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               murder of William Hill, in mixing vitriol, otherwise white copperas, with water gruel, to be used for the sustenance of the said William
            </rs>, at <rs id="t17520514-30-cd159" type="crimeDate">divers times, as December 1st, February 11th, and March 10th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-30-off158 t17520514-30-cd159"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-30-person292">
                  Eleanor 
                  Woollen 
               <interp inst="t17520514-30-person292" type="surname" value="Woollen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-30-person292" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-30-person292" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I liv'd with the deceased William Hill ; I am his wife's sister's daughter, he lived in <placeName id="t17520514-30-crimeloc160">Long-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17520514-30-crimeloc160" type="placeName" value="Long-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520514-30-crimeloc160" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-30-off158 t17520514-30-crimeloc160"></join>, he was a <rs id="t17520514-30-viclabel161" type="occupation">breeches-maker</rs>.</p>
               <p>Q. How old is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>E. Woollen. She was 15 years of age the 4th of February last, she has been bound <rs id="t17520514-30-deflabel162" type="occupation">apprentice</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-30-defend291 t17520514-30-deflabel162"></join> to my uncle 2 years, this May, to learn the business, and also household work.</p>
               <p>Q. When did William Hill die?</p>
               <p>E. Woollen. He died the first of this month.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had he been ill?</p>
               <p>E. Wollen. He had been ill ever since October.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he in a good state of health before October.</p>
               <p>E. Wollen. He was in good health before, a very healthful man; he said he was taken ill the first of October, with a sad griping in his bowels, and a pinching pain, so that he could hardly stand, he had strong physick that helped him very much; he continued with a sad griping in his bowels, so that he could not lie down in his bed all the winter, and was never well afterwards; he turned yellow, and grew very thin, and fell away from a very lusty man almost to nothing; after he had done with the apothecary, he said he should never overcome it. He had something of the apothecary after he found the poison out.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he find that out?</p>
               <p>E. Woollen. He found that out in March, he often took water-gruel; he was going to eat his breakfast in a hurry, being to go out with some goods, he eat it very hot, he found something of a knob in it; I heard the prisoner say, she saw her master take it out of the gruel, that she stood close by him, he brought it into the shop to me and the journeyman, he said, he believed he had something in his water-gruel, like Mr. Blandy; he said, he believed it had no business there. I tasted it, and said it was very nasty stuff, the prisoner said she had tasted it, and said the same; my uncle asked how it came there? I said, I feared it was a piece of allum, that might come out of the bread. The prisoner stirred the water-gruel over the fire, and my aunt crumbed the bason: the prisoner said, if any thing was done, more than what ought to be, it must be her mistress that did it. My uncle went to Mr. Allen, the apothecary, with it, and was under his hands sometime: the chymist came and said, he believ'd he could let us into the secret, who fetch'd that stuff; the day after he took her and me to let his son see us, to know which of us had fetched it, my uncle was then at the chymist's, he knew the prisoner, and said, she had had white copperas of him. In the evening of the same day my uncle took her out, and when she came back again, she told me, she had fetch'd it. I asked her if she had done such a wicked thing ? she said, she had done it.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175205140033"></xptr>Q. Did you explain it, what wicked thing?</p>
               <p>E. Woollen. No, I did not. I asked her why she did it? she said, she could not tell why: she was sent to the compter, I went to her the next day; she was taken before the Alderman, before whom she said, she had fetch'd two or three penny-worth; he ask'd her how many times she had given it to her master? she said, she could not tell, but she believed about eight times. On the Saturday following, I went to her again, then she said, my aunt had given her the money to fetch the first penny-worth; my uncle insisted upon knowing whether she gave her the second penny, she said, no, she did not know of it: she also told me, she could have poisoned her master with something else, besides white copperas, and that green copperas was poison, as well as white: I asked her how she knew the name of it? she said, she had learned the name of it by her father, and had heard him say it would poison any body by degrees.</p>
               <p>Q. What was he?</p>
               <p>E. Woollen. He was a gardener at Lambeth: my uncle took her out of Lambeth work-house.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-30-person293">
                  James 
                  March 
               <interp inst="t17520514-30-person293" type="surname" value="March"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-30-person293" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-30-person293" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 11th of March last, I, with others, were at the Lock and Key Club ; Mr. Hill there was relating how he had been serv'd in eating his breakfast that morning, or the morning before; he had found a lump of white vitriol, about as big as a horse-bean, and he had carried it to Mr. Allen, the apothecary, and he told him it was poison, and after he had made an enquiry, and found his apprentice bought it at Mr. Wetherall's, the chymist, we desired he would bring the girl to us, to hear what she had to say for herself: he went and fetch'd her, there were several of us, we asked her how she could be so wicked to do such a thing? she first of all denied she did it; then I said, what signifies your denying it? the young man knows you; Mr. Wetherall was in company; then she said she did fetch it: I asked her who told her it was poison? she said, she did not know it was poison: said I, what did you do it for? she said, she did not know: by asking her several times, she said, she was perswaded to do it by an old woman at Lambeth, but she did not know her, nor where she lived, but had seen her when she was at the work-house.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she bid her do with it?</p>
               <p>March. She only told her that such a thing was poison.</p>
               <p>Q. When did she tell her so?</p>
               <p>March. Last Christmas, when she went over there ; she own'd she had given him some in October: we asked her how she came to give him some before Christmas? she said, she could not tell: we asked her, what she had given it him in! she said in water-gruel and broth; we asked her for what intent? the reason she gave, was, that she heard it would kill her master, and that she should be out of her time.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known the deceased ?</p>
               <p>March. I have known him fifteen years, I live opposite against him; he was as clever a portly man as most to be seen, a very healthy man ; I don't remember him to have had a day's illness before this.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he at the time you speak of, at the club, as to health?</p>
               <p>March. He was wasted, and looked like a shadow : I had said to my family, I can't think what is the matter with Mr. Hill, he looks as if he was going into a consumption: I had observ'd it two months before this I believe, or more; after this she was committed. The deceased had the advice of Dr. Shambrook; the day after this, as soon as he saw the doctor, I remember he said, he should never be able to go through a deal of physick, the doses will be too strong, I am afraid they'll kill me: the morning after he had taken one dose, he said, I have had such a night, I never knew a poor creature have; after that he was seemingly a little better, but said he was never free from pain in his bowels and stomach, and that he had such pinchings, that he could not sit up-right: once he said, the apothecary had left off giving him things, and he hoped he should get over it; I think this was about the 10th or 11th of April, after we had been to the club again.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he die?</p>
               <p>March. He died of the May day in the morning, after he had lain ill about a week.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he a temperate man in his diet?</p>
               <p>March. I never saw him disguised in liquor in my life, I don't think he was irregular in eating or drinking, the day before he died, he said to me, he hoped I would do my endeavour to see the girl prosecuted, for he believed she had been the cause of his death.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-30-person294">
                  Marmaduke 
                  Wetherall 
               <interp inst="t17520514-30-person294" type="surname" value="Wetherall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-30-person294" type="given" value="Marmaduke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-30-person294" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Smithfield : I am a Chymist. On the 10th of March, Mr. Hill came to my shop, and said, he believed he was poisoned, that he had found something in his gruel; and had carried something to Mr. Allen's, which he said was White<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175205140034"></xptr> copperas, or white vitriol, he shewed it to me, I examined and tasted it, and compared it with other, but do not take upon me to sware it was that, it had something of the taste, but was altered very much from the raw, it was a dark green powder, almost like moist sugar; I judged it to be white vitriol.</p>
               <p>Q. Is vitriol of such a quality that it would occasion the death of a man?</p>
               <p>Wetherall I believe if it was given frequently it would, it is not strong poison, it is used by persons that make eye-water, and glove-washers; we never refuse it to any body, if we know them; we judged her master sent her for it, my lad told me he had served her. He confirmed the account of the last evidence of the prisoner's confession at the club, he being there.</p>
               <p>W. Wetherall. I am son to the last evidence; when I heard Mr. Hill had taken white copperas, I recollected I had served the prisoner with some : I remember I have two or three times, I think it was before Christmas, at a pennyworth a time.</p>
               <p>Q. How much for a penny?</p>
               <p>Wetherall. An ounce and a half; I knew she belonged to Mr. Hill.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-30-person295">
                  Steven 
                  Bearclift 
               <interp inst="t17520514-30-person295" type="surname" value="Bearclift"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-30-person295" type="given" value="Steven"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-30-person295" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Smithfield: I was at the club on Wednesday the 11th of March; he confirmed that of her confession there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-30-person296">
                  Robert 
                  Lilley 
               <interp inst="t17520514-30-person296" type="surname" value="Lilley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-30-person296" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-30-person296" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was there likewise, he confirmed the same account.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-30-person297">
                  Jonathan 
                  Southwell 
               <interp inst="t17520514-30-person297" type="surname" value="Southwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-30-person297" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-30-person297" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was sent for to the Lock and Key, to the club: I am constable: he confirmed the same.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-30-person298">
                  Edward 
                  Allen 
               <interp inst="t17520514-30-person298" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-30-person298" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-30-person298" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was Apothecary to Mr. Hill; on the 18th of February he came to me and made a great many complaints, (he refreshes his Memory with an extract from his shop-book) he said, he had a prodigious griping in his bowels and stomach, and had been so for some months; I asked him, if he had made use of any medicines, he said, he had some purges from the Chymist, but they did him no great service; I apprehended his complaint, from the yellowness of his complexion, proceeded from a fluxion in the Gall-bladder into his stomach ; I asked him, if he ever belched up any thing that was sour: I told him, I would order him a four ounce mixture, which I hoped would give him relief: on the 19th of February I waited upon him and did not find it had opened him (which I intended) as I expected, upon which I increased it and made it more opening a good deal, and the next morning he told me had received much benefit, he had broke a good deal of wind, and his excrement was more liquid, upon which I did not alter it any more till the 22d, then I found him so well and free from any fourness, that I sent him a purge, which he took on the 23d, he was a good deal better, but still in a lower degree; then till March the 2d I gave him nothing at all.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he in that interval?</p>
               <p>Allen. I did not see him in the time, he had the same ugly complaints he had before of gripings, &amp;c. then I ordered him a gally-pot of electuary to take, when he found them gripings, he made use of it till the 7th, then he told me, whenever he was pinched with those sort of pains, it gave him ease in an instant; I gave him another pot; and on the 10th he brought to me a piece of Vitriol in a paper, it was very wet and ting'd, as soon as I cut off the tinctured part, I could see it was white copperas, I was thoroughly persuaded of it; he said he took it out of his gruel, he took it away again, on the 12th he went to Dr. Shambrook, by my persuasion, the Dr. advised him to take two draughts and a glister, which were given him every night to the 15th or 16th; he ordered him an evacuating kind of a medicine, these things relieved him a little, he had still gripings and sensations in his bowels and stomach pretty much, with these medicines as with mine; I bid him look into his excrement to see if it was interspersed with blood, he said it was, these he took day by day till the 4th of April, that was the last.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he then?</p>
               <p>Allen. He left the medicines off for three weeks, but had some little windy complaints, at last they were intirely removed so that he had no complaint at all, and continued so, free from them, till the 25th; then he came to me again and was pretty much the same as before, I told him he must repeat the medicines the Dr. ordered him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find any fresh complaint?</p>
               <p>Allen. I found. none, but much the same; I waited on him that day and found he had a fever, his tongue was very dry with a brown list in the middle of it, and exceeding low and faint; I ordered him to drink largely of barley-water, his pulse was very fast; on the 26th I found him a great deal more dispirited, I ordered him some draughts which he took every six hours, he grew worse and worse every day, and died on the 1st of May.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it the same disease, after the 25th of March, as before?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175205140035"></xptr>Allen. I can't say that; I can't at all find any symptoms that we can build any such opinion upon, that it was owing to the Vitriol, I don't think such a fever could be produced by the effects of any Vitriol whatever.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you apprehend was the occasion of this fever ?</p>
               <p>Allen. He carried a heavy burthen of leather, heated himself, and catched cold, he drank and eat a hearty supper; I impute his having the fever to these causes wholly, for he was well three weeks before, and I don't think it had any connection with it. Mr. Hawkins told me there were no traces or footsteps to be found of poison in his stomach, he was at the opening of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon the whole, do you think his death was occasioned by this vitriol ?</p>
               <p>Allen. Really, I think, that had no regard to it at all, nor the least tendency to procure that fever; I have no reason in the world to believe it was any way productive of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the body after it was dead?</p>
               <p>Allen. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-30-person299">
                  Mark 
                  Hawkins 
               <interp inst="t17520514-30-person299" type="surname" value="Hawkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-30-person299" type="given" value="Mark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-30-person299" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live by Smithfield-bars; I saw the body of the deceased after he was dead, he died in the night, and in the afternoon follow. I was sent for to open it, which I was told was his desire, there were Mr. Allen's servant and several of the neighbours there, I opened the body, and as there had been a report of his taking poison, I was as exact as possible, I did not perceive any thing at all, only his bowels and guts were pretty much distorted with wind; I examined his stomach to see if any thing was excoriated in the inflammation, I found no livid spots, I turn'd his stomach wrong-side out, I opened his bowels in several places; upon the whole there was not any thing that I could imagine occasioned by what he had taken in his stomach, from poison, or any thing of that kind, I examined also his liver and heart.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you look upon white vitriol to be of a poisonous quality ?</p>
               <p>Hawkins. It is of a harsh rugged nature, it is impossible to confine it in the stomach without throwing it up.</p>
               <p>Q. If a person was to take a quantity of it, would it occasion their death?</p>
               <p>Hawkins. I don't know but by taking quantities it might have a bad effect; but I never heard of an instance of any body's taking it.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think, the deceased could be ill of a fever, as Mr. Allen has mentioned, by taking of vitriol ?</p>
               <p>Hawkins. I think not. I saw him about a fortnight, or three weeks before he died, he then seemed to be much better than he had been.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon the whole, what do you think was the occasion of his death?</p>
               <p>Hawkins. I think there is no reason to say he died of that poison.</p>
               <p>The prisoner being asked, what she had to say for herself? answered, Nothing at all.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520514-30-verdict163" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520514-30-verdict163" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>She was detained to be tried for an attempt to poison, &amp;c.</p>
            </div1>
