<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17520914-43">
               <interp inst="t17520914-43" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520914-43" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520914-43" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520914"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520914-43" type="date" value="17520914"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520914-43-off218-c304" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-43-defend391 t17520914-43-off218 t17520914-43-verdict222"></join>
         
               <p>453. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17520914-43-defend391" type="defendantName">
                     Samuel 
                     Watkins 
                  <interp inst="t17520914-43-defend391" type="surname" value="Watkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-43-defend391" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-43-defend391" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for that <rs id="t17520914-43-off218" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520914-43-off218" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-43-off218" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               he on the <rs id="t17520914-43-cd219" type="crimeDate">22nd of August</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-43-off218 t17520914-43-cd219"></join>, about the hour of six in the morning, the dwelling house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17520914-43-victim393" type="victimName">
                           Charles 
                           Povey 
                        <interp inst="t17520914-43-victim393" type="surname" value="Povey"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520914-43-victim393" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520914-43-victim393" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-43-off218 t17520914-43-victim393"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did break and enter, no person being therein; and one gold ring, val. 5 s. one guinea, one half guinea, and thirty shillings and sixpence, in money number'd, did steal, &amp;c
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520914-43-person394">
                  Charles 
                  Povey 
               <interp inst="t17520914-43-person394" type="surname" value="Povey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-43-person394" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-43-person394" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17520914-43-viclabel220" type="occupation">gardener</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-43-victim393 t17520914-43-viclabel220"></join>, and live at <placeName id="t17520914-43-crimeloc221">Hammersmith</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17520914-43-crimeloc221" type="placeName" value="Hammersmith"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520914-43-crimeloc221" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520914-43-off218 t17520914-43-crimeloc221"></join>. The prisoner lodged at my house, with his wife, in ready furnished lodgings, some months; they quitted it two nights before the robbery was done, which was on the 22nd of August; he gave me no warning when he went away. On the Friday night he came again, and desired I'd let him lie there that night; his wife came that day at noon and paid for their lodging, and gave me two-pence for it. He staid there in the former lodging. I called him in the morning, as he had desired, about five, and took my leave of him in the yard ; he went as tho' he was going for London. I have no family at all, there was only he. I, and Jeffery Mills had lain in the house that night; we were all gone out, and I had lock'd the outward door, and my chamber door, and had the keys in my pocket. I have no shutters to my windows, but am sure the casement that he got in at was hasped; I looked out at the window to see what weather it was, and shut and hasped it again; there were no panes broke. I was told the prisoners was seen going in at my window about six o'clock on that morning. I was then in the fields. I came home and unlocked my outward door; the window was shut, not hasped then, and a pane of glass broke in it. I lifted up Baymont to get in at the window; he came down one pair of stairs, and unbolted the door; then Dancer and Baymont went up to this chamber ; I followed them. Then they went up into the garret, and saw nobody there; we then went down again into my chamber. I found the lock of the chamber door broke, and Dancer saw a key lying in the window, which I left in my breeches pocket; that was the key of a trunk where my money was. I took it and unlocked the trunk; there was no money left. There was one guinea, one half guinea, one five shilling piece, and the rest in silver, in all three pounds two shillings. I had one gold ring in the same trunk, that was gone; I saw them all on the Friday morning lying there, but did not tell it. I desired my master to ride after this man, and I'd follow. The prisoner's wife came as I was going out of the house, and asked for her husband; I seized her. I went up to put a coat on in my chamber; there I picked up a handkerchief, produced in court; it belongs to the prisoner who owned it before the justice; and I know it to be his handkerchief. I walked to London with the woman; we took her before the justice. When he found his wife was in confinement, he came to my house on the Sunday night, and threatened me for taking away his good name; then I charged two men with him; carrying him away, he got from us, and ran two hundred yards before taken again. He had parted with his apparel, and bought others. I never saw any of my things again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520914-43-person395">
                  Thomas 
                  Baymont 
               <interp inst="t17520914-43-person395" type="surname" value="Baymont"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-43-person395" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-43-person395" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Saturday morning last was fortnight, about five o'clock. I was going to my master's by the prosecutor's house; it was light. I saw a man creeping in at the prosecutor's chamber window; I was within thirty or forty yards of him. I went on and told my master, and that he looked like the prisoner, but could not be sure. He was in a sort of a dark coloured coat. My master told the prosecutor ; we all went to the house. He unlocked the door, but could not get in. Then he helped me up on a shed, and I got in at the window; I went down and unbolted the door, and master and he went up together.</p>
         
               <p>N. B. In a few days will be published Part II.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17520914-43">
                  <interp inst="t17520914-43" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520914-43" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520914-43" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520914"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520914-43" type="date" value="17520914"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175209140021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Thursday the 14th, Friday the 15th, Saturday the 16th, Monday the 18th, Tuesday the 19th and Wednesday the 20th of September.</p>
                  <p>In the 26th Year of His MAJESTY's Reign. PART II. of NUMBER VII. for the Year 1752. BEING THE Second SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of the Right Honourable 
                  <persName id="t17520914-43-person396">
                     Robert 
                     Alsop 
                  <interp inst="t17520914-43-person396" type="surname" value="Alsop"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520914-43-person396" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520914-43-person396" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Esq; LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by M. COOPER, at the Globe in Pater-noster Row. 1752.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-Pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175209140022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery held for the City of London, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520914-43-person397">
                  Joshua 
                  Harding 
               <interp inst="t17520914-43-person397" type="surname" value="Harding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-43-person397" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520914-43-person397" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>THE prisoner came to my house on Friday morning, about nine o'clock, and call'd for a pint of beer, and pulled out a handful of silver, and said if any body wanted him, he was gone down to Billingsgate.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I went out on the Saturday morning, and left the prosecutor and another man in the house. I heard at Kensington he had got a warrant to take me up, and went to know of him for what. He stopped me. I worked for Mr. Dancer last summer; please to ask him my character.</p>
               <p>Dancer. He and his wife worked with me from three weeks before Easter. I contracted with them for eleven shillings per week. I found him an industrious fellow, so gave him another shilling per week.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520914-43-verdict222" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520914-43-verdict222" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
