<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17541023-6">
               <interp inst="t17541023-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541023-6" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541023-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17541023"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541023-6" type="date" value="17541023"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17541023-6-off26-c44" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-6-defend53 t17541023-6-off26 t17541023-6-verdict29"></join>
         
               <p>471. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17541023-6-defend53" type="defendantName">
                  Margaret 
                  Purser 
               <interp inst="t17541023-6-defend53" type="surname" value="Purser"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-6-defend53" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-6-defend53" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17541023-6-deflabel25" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-6-defend53 t17541023-6-deflabel25"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17541023-6-off26" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17541023-6-off26" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-6-off26" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one silver table spoon, val. 12 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17541023-6-victim55" type="victimName">
                     George 
                     Gill 
                  <interp inst="t17541023-6-victim55" type="surname" value="Gill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-6-victim55" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-6-victim55" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-6-off26 t17541023-6-victim55"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17541023-6-cd27" type="crimeDate">Sept. 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-6-off26 t17541023-6-cd27"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541023-6-person56">
                  John 
                  Meadows 
               <interp inst="t17541023-6-person56" type="surname" value="Meadows"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-6-person56" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-6-person56" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Gill; he is a <rs id="t17541023-6-viclabel28" type="occupation">baker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-6-victim55 t17541023-6-viclabel28"></join>. I was standing at the door about half an hour after one in the morning, waiting to let a gentleman in. The prisoner came and asked me for some small beer; I gave her about half a pint; she asked me for more; I told her if she would hold a candle while I tapt a cask she should have more, which she did; then she asked me for some victuals, I gave her some meat that was laid out for me.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to let a woman in at that time of night?</p>
               <p>J. Meadows. I thought it was charity to give a poor creature a little beer.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you miss the spoon?</p>
               <p>J. Meadows. Our maid mist it the next morning; I went about my business with my bread; the mean while the spoon was offered to be sold, and she was stopt; when I came home my master asked me if I let her in? I said I did. As soon as I came home I saw the spoon.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541023-6-person57">
                  Mary 
                  Reason 
               <interp inst="t17541023-6-person57" type="surname" value="Reason"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-6-person57" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-6-person57" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a silversmith's shop. The prisoner came to me about 8 o'clock in the morning, and asked me if I would buy a spoon? I looked at it, and asked her whose it was? she said she came honestly by it. I said it was not hers, stopt it, and desir'd her to tell the truth and she should have nothing done to her. She told me a man took her down into a cellar, at a baker's, and pull'd off his coat and laid it upon a sack, then pull'd off his breeches, and laid with her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say this at first when you stopt the spoon?</p>
               <p>M. Reason. At first she told me she found it in the dust; I told her it did not look like that. I sent for a constable, and the mean while she said as before, and did not hesitate at all. I sent the constable down to the owner of the spoon, to see if he had lost one. The prisoner said the man was to provide lodging for her, and take her in keeping.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>He took me in the cellar, laid a sack on the ground, and laid with me; he said he had no money in his pocket, so gave me the spoon, telling me to bring it the next night at one o clock.</p>
               <p>Question to Meadows. Upon your oath was you great with this woman?</p>
               <p>J. Meadows. I was not, and my master is here to witness I had half a guinea of my own, and 13 s. of his, at that time.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17541023-6-verdict29" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17541023-6-verdict29" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
