<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17520219-24">
               <interp inst="t17520219-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520219-24" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520219-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520219"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520219-24" type="date" value="17520219"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520219-24-off106-c198" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520219-24-defend242 t17520219-24-off106 t17520219-24-verdict109"></join>
         
               <p>157. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17520219-24-defend242" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Robertson 
                  <interp inst="t17520219-24-defend242" type="surname" value="Robertson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-24-defend242" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-24-defend242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17520219-24-off106" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520219-24-off106" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-24-off106" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing four flannel petticoats, one quilted petticoat, one camblet gown, two linnen aprons, three brass candlesticks, one beaver hat, one silver buckle set with bristol stones, one gridiron, one firest ovel, and seventeen pence in money
            </rs>, the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17520219-24-victim244" type="victimName">
                     James 
                     Cook 
                  <interp inst="t17520219-24-victim244" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-24-victim244" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-24-victim244" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520219-24-off106 t17520219-24-victim244"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17520219-24-cd107" type="crimeDate">Dec. 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520219-24-off106 t17520219-24-cd107"></join>.  *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520219-24-person245">
                  Rebecca 
                  Cook 
               <interp inst="t17520219-24-person245" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-24-person245" type="given" value="Rebecca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-24-person245" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to 
               <persName id="t17520219-24-person246">
                  James 
                  Cook 
               <interp inst="t17520219-24-person246" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-24-person246" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-24-person246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I live in <placeName id="t17520219-24-crimeloc108">Green-Arbour-Court, Golden-Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17520219-24-crimeloc108" type="placeName" value="Green-Arbour-Court, Golden-Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520219-24-crimeloc108" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520219-24-off106 t17520219-24-crimeloc108"></join>; on the 13 th of December last I was taken ill, and went to-bed ; I had a cat that had a bell about her neck, she flew about the pillow and awaked me, she flew to the chair, then the table, then to the chimney, and then on the bed; I saw a little light; I said, cat, what ails you? she still flew about: the light was gone in a moment: presently I heard a root step about the room; there the prisoner was at my bed-side: my gown and apron hung on a chair: I said, Jemmy, what have you stayed a little longer than ordinary? have you a mind to afright me ? (I thinking it had been my husband) said he, it is none of your husband: he put his hand into the bed, and laid hold on me, and said, but I will do so and so to you, make no resistance, your husband will be at home in two minutes: I catched hold on him: he said, be quick, for I will, speaking in a very vulgar manner: I held him fast by the coat; said I, how came you into my house? he said, G - d blast your eyes, you old b - h! I said, Lord, what makes you use me so? who are you? will not you, you old b - h, speaking it out in a vulgar manner: then, said he, go to hell and be d - d for a b - h: then I felt my things going off the bed: I lost three candlesticks from off my mantlepiece, a cheque apron, a cap, a hood that hung on the chair, one brass pepperbox, one gridiron, three brass knobs off a stove, and a fireshovel: he went out and pulled the door after him.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he any instrument in his hands?</p>
               <p>R. Cook. He threatened me and affrighted me so, that I did not see any thing in his hands. I saw the back of him as he went out, and when he was in the street, I saw him out of the window by the light of a brandy-shop. I was drawing on my stockings when my husband came in; he asked me if I was mad; I told him there had been a man, that came once before with a pretence to take a room, (which were all the times I had seen him) and had taken such and such things: my husband looked about to see what was gone: I described him and he went to the alehouses. When he was gone the prisoner came upon me a second time; then I saw his face and his cloaths; he said, G - d d - n you, you old bitch: I said you are the man that<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175202190015"></xptr> robbed me ; then he went like an arrow out of a bow, and turned down Turk's-head-conrt.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you cry out when you were in bed, when became to you?</p>
               <p>R. Cook. He threatened me so that I was affrighted, and had not power,</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain the prisoner is the man?</p>
               <p>R. Cook. I can say, to my great sorrow, that he is the man.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he come into your room?</p>
               <p>R. Cook. The key was left on the outside the door.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you go to bed?</p>
               <p>R. Cook. About seven o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to go to bed so soon?</p>
               <p>R. Cook. I was taken with a great heaviness and was so for some days.</p>
               <p>Clarles Hilton. On the 13th of December, between eight and nine o'clock, as I went out at my own door, which is just by the corner of Green-Artour court, within a door or two of Mr. Cook's, I saw the prisoner, with a candle lighted in his hand, standing as if he was making water; About half an hour after Mrs. Cook came running to me, and said she had been robbed of every thing she had in the world, and that her husband was standing like a man out of his wits.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was drinking at a publick-house that night from six to nine, when I went away; I then went to the sign of the Three Pigeons to ask for my wife; she was not there; I then went to the house I had been drinking at, and when I came home found my door broke open: there were two or three men took told of me, and said I had robbed the prosecutrix; they brought her to me in a ragged gown: said she I am almost sure the prisoner is the man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520219-24-person247">
                  Jonathan 
                  Keath 
               <interp inst="t17520219-24-person247" type="surname" value="Keath"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-24-person247" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-24-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . If common fame speaks truth, the prosecutrix is a woman of very bad character: she is capable of swearing any thing; there is hardly a worse woman living; she has been confined in Newgate for a crime of this nature. I knew nothing of the prisoner nor of this trial before I came here.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520219-24-verdict109" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520219-24-verdict109" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
