<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570526-14">
               <interp inst="t17570526-14" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570526-14" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570526-14" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570526"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570526-14" type="date" value="17570526"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570526-14-off74-c119" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570526-14-defend143 t17570526-14-off74 t17570526-14-verdict75"></join>
         
               <p>227. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17570526-14-defend143" type="defendantName">
                     Terence 
                     Kane 
                  <interp inst="t17570526-14-defend143" type="surname" value="Kane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-14-defend143" type="given" value="Terence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-14-defend143" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17570526-14-off74" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570526-14-off74" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-14-off74" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one piece of gold, value 3 l.
            </rs> the property of persons unknown.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175705260013"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17570526-14-person144">
                  James 
                  Harman 
               <interp inst="t17570526-14-person144" type="surname" value="Harman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-14-person144" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-14-person144" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a working silversmith; this prisoner at the bar brought me two irregular small pieces of gold, at two separate times; I knowing him bought the first and second, which was much the same shape, but the last more in quantity; after that I had some suspicion they were not honestly come by.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner ?</p>
               <p>Harman. He is a milkman. I gave orders to my people, if he should come and offer any more they should not buy it. On the second or third of February last he brought me another piece of gold, which appeared as though it had been turned out of a melting pot, or crucible; then I had a full suspicion that it was dishonestly come by. I ask'd him how he came by it. He told me he sold it for another person. I clap'd it in the scale, talk'd to him a little to amuse him, and then told him I was satisfied it was dishonestly come by, being in such a shape; he said he came honestly by it. I said, I have no reason to distrust you, but you must discover the person you had it of; he told me he had it of a Jew that sold old cloaths; I told him if it was good it might be worth 3 l. 5 s. but desired him to leave it, that I might have a trial made of it; he left it with me, in order to have a trial made of it, which we call an assay. I applied to justice Welch, and told him my sentiments, and how I came by it; he bid me apply to the assay master in the Tower, which I did, and according to that assay it was reported to be a quarter of a grain worse than standard, but they always make some small allowance. I had a warrant from Mr. Welch, in order to apprehend the prisoner. I had given the prisoner a memorandum of my receiving such a bit of gold of him, in order for my delivering it back upon demand. When he came to my house I told him he must produce the person that he had it of, and I privately sent one of my boys for the constable. The prisoner made this excuse, he could not tell who, or where the man was he had it of, and desired to have some time to find him. I gave him opportunity to go and see for him, but did not deliver him the gold. He did not return, and has absconded ever since, till last Monday he was taken. He has prevaricated much in his discourse. He said he had it of a German Jew first, and that he had not paid for it; afterwards that he had paid for it. When I told him it might be worth 3 l. 5 s. he said he gave three guineas for it; but before the justice he said, he did not pay for it till after I had told him what I thought it might be worth, Mr. Welch committed him.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. When did the prisoner first produce this piece of gold to you ?</p>
               <p>Harman. About the second or third of February.</p>
               <p>Q Did you mention any suspicion you had then?</p>
               <p>Harman. At that time I told him I suspected it to have been stoln.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he call again after that?</p>
               <p>Harman. He call'd about two or three days after.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did he abscond ?</p>
               <p>Harman. He absconded after the second time of coming.</p>
               <p>Q Was the warrant taken out before he absconded ?</p>
               <p>Harman. It was, but it was in the constable's hands, and I call'd my boy in order to fetch him to serve it. I told the justice I was apprehensive it was the diminishing of coin.</p>
               <p>Q. What was their opinion who made the assay?</p>
               <p>Harman. They seem'd to be of the same opinion with me.</p>

               <p>Q. Where is the piece of gold?</p>
               <p>Harman. It is here [produced; the jury look at it.]</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I bought this piece of gold of a German Jew, but I don't know his name, nor where he is. I gave him three guineas for it. He wanting to borrow some money of me to buy old cloaths with, I told him I had none, and he took me into a publick house, where he pull'd this piece of gold out of his pocket, and said he would give me that instead of three guineas. I carried it to the gentleman's house, and ask'd him the value of it; he said it was worth 3 l. 5 s. He gave me a note, and I left the piece of gold with him. I went back to the Jew, and paid him the three guineas.</p>
               <p>To his Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570526-14-person145">
                  Thomas 
                  Rhodes 
               <interp inst="t17570526-14-person145" type="surname" value="Rhodes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-14-person145" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-14-person145" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a cowkeeper; the prisoner deals with me for milk.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you apprehend that in the course of his business he gets a sufficient livelihood?</p>
               <p>Rhodes. No doubt but he does, he is a very industrious man.</p>
               <p>Mr. Riley. I have known him about three years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175705260014"></xptr>Riley. I never heard any thing amiss of him, I always took him to be an honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570526-14-person146">
                  John 
                  Ross 
               <interp inst="t17570526-14-person146" type="surname" value="Ross"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-14-person146" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-14-person146" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about three years, has a very honest pains-taking man.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his business?</p>
               <p>Ross. He is a milkman, and lives in Surrey-Street in the Strand.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570526-14-person147">
                  Abraham 
                  Dent 
               <interp inst="t17570526-14-person147" type="surname" value="Dent"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-14-person147" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-14-person147" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him between two and three years, he is a very worthy man; he is a milkman, and deals largely.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570526-14-person148">
                  Charles 
                  Cavaneragh 
               <interp inst="t17570526-14-person148" type="surname" value="Cavaneragh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-14-person148" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-14-person148" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him ten years.</p>
               <p>Q What is his general character ?</p>
               <p>Cavaneragh. He has a very good character, that of a very industrious honest man; he kept a farm in Ireland.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570526-14-person149">
                  John 
                  Mackdonan 
               <interp inst="t17570526-14-person149" type="surname" value="Mackdonan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-14-person149" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-14-person149" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about three years, and he has always behaved like a very industrious honest man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570526-14-verdict75" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570526-14-verdict75" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
