<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17590711-28">
               <interp inst="t17590711-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590711-28" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590711-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17590711"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590711-28" type="date" value="17590711"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17590711-28-off160-c207" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590711-28-defend258 t17590711-28-off160 t17590711-28-verdict161"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907110033"></xptr>242. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17590711-28-defend258" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Dorothy 
                     Jones 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17590711-28-alias-2" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590711-28-defend258 t17590711-28-alias-2"></join>Harris</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-28-defend258" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-28-defend258" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-28-defend258" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17590711-28-off160" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590711-28-off160" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-28-off160" type="offenceSubcategory" value="perjury"></interp>
               wilful and corrupt perjury, in swearing before Dr Ducarrell, Doctor of Laws, that she was the lawful widow of William Harris, deceased
            </rs>. ++</p>
               <p>As the Counsel for the prosecution was proceeding to open the case, the Counsel for the prisoner said, they should make the trial very short, having a witness in court who was at the marriage: then the Counsel for the prosecution, gave liberty for him to be called first.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590711-28-person260">
                  Edward 
                  Simms 
               <interp inst="t17590711-28-person260" type="surname" value="Simms"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-28-person260" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-28-person260" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Mrs Harris about eighteen years.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Simms. I dealt pretty largely in the Distillery; several gentlemen that are here, know me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know Mr Harris?</p>
               <p>Simms. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember Mr Harris being married?</p>
               <p>Simms. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you present at the marriage?</p>
               <p>Simms. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was he married to?</p>
               <p>Simms. He was married to Mrs 
               <persName id="t17590711-28-person261">
                  Dorothy 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17590711-28-person261" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-28-person261" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-28-person261" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the defendant now in court: Pointing to the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know her while she was a widow?</p>

               <p>Simms. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was she married?</p>
               <p>Simms. She was married to Mr Harris, in her own house, in Botolph-lane; right against Mr Harris's house.</p>
               <p>Q. What was her former husband?</p>
               <p>Simms. He was an Orange-Merchant; and so was Mr Harris.</p>
               <p>Q. How were they married?</p>
               <p>Simms. The ceremony according to the Church of England was read over.</p>
               <p>Q. How came it, that you was there?</p>
               <p>Simms. Mr Harris desired me to come there, on a Sunday morning, to Mrs Jones's house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you for what purpose?</p>
               <p>Simms. No, he did not, 'till I came there; then he said, he sent for me to be present at his marriage: he and I were very intimate, as two brothers, for twenty years.</p>
               <p>Q. When you came there, that Sunday morning, who was present?</p>
               <p>Simms. There was nobody there but Mrs Jones, he, and the gentleman that married them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you give her away?</p>
               <p>Simms. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did?</p>
               <p>Simms. The Minister that married them did.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a Clergyman of the Church of England?</p>
               <p>Simms. He was in a Minister's dress.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you account for their being married in private?</p>
               <p>Simms. Mr. Harris's mother had propos'd another marriage for him, was the reason.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this marriage?</p>
               <p>Simms. This was the second of Oct. 1748.</p>
               <p>Q. Was his mother reconciled afterwards?</p>
               <p>Simms. She was, somewhat more: Mrs Jones had two children, by her former husband.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did the mother live afterwards?</p>
               <p>Simms. She lived about two years afterwards: after this, it was very publickly known, the old gentlewoman told me, she was very well satisfied in it, afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they cohabit together, as man and wife?</p>
               <p>Simms. They did, always.</p>
               <p>Q. For how long?</p>
               <p>Simms. For, I believe, about ten years, to the day of his death.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the name of the Clergyman, that married them?</p>
               <p>Simms. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see him since?</p>
               <p>Simms. Not as I remember.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you no discourse with him, where he was Minister?</p>
               <p>Simms. No.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907110034"></xptr>Q. When did she first live publickly with him, as his wife?</p>
               <p>Simms. From that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Where?</p>
               <p>Simms. In Botolph-lane, at her house, directly facing his house; and they had lodgings at Peckham, about that time.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the name she went by?</p>
               <p>Simms. She went by the name of Mrs Harris: he has said to me many a time, when I have gone there, Mr Simms, I'll call Mrs Harris down.</p>
               <p>Mr Balmore. I know the defendant.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know Mr Harris, in his lifetime ?</p>
               <p>Balmore. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you intimate with him?</p>
               <p>Balmore. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember the defendant being delivered of a child ?</p>
               <p>Balmore. I do, I was one of the God-fathers.</p>
               <p>Q. What name was it christened by ?</p>
               <p>Balmore. By the name of 
               <persName id="t17590711-28-person262">
                  William 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17590711-28-person262" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-28-person262" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-28-person262" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any doubt at that time, that that child was the lawful child of Mr Harris ?</p>
               <p>Balmore. No, I had no doubt about it.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether, at that time, it was looked upon as his legitimate child, or not ?</p>
               <p>Balmore. I could think no other of a woman of credit, and he likewise.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you consider her there, as his wife?</p>
               <p>Balmore. I did.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17590711-28-verdict161" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590711-28-verdict161" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
