<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17591205-35">
               <interp inst="t17591205-35" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591205-35" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591205-35" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17591205"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591205-35" type="date" value="17591205"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17591205-35-off178-c314" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-35-defend385 t17591205-35-off178 t17591205-35-verdict179"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17591205-35-off178-c315" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-35-defend387 t17591205-35-off178 t17591205-35-verdict179"></join>
         
               <p>39, 40. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17591205-35-defend385" type="defendantName">
                     Benjamin 
                     Langrin 
                  <interp inst="t17591205-35-defend385" type="surname" value="Langrin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-defend385" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-defend385" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17591205-35-defend387" type="defendantName">
                     Christian 
                     Carter 
                  <interp inst="t17591205-35-defend387" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-defend387" type="given" value="Christian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-defend387" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were <rs id="t17591205-35-off178" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-off178" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-off178" type="offenceSubcategory" value="perjury"></interp>
               indicted on two separate indictments, for wilful and corrupt perjury, on a trial at the last sessions, held by adjournment at Guildhall, &amp;c. ++
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-35-person388">
                  John 
                  Shaw 
               <interp inst="t17591205-35-person388" type="surname" value="Shaw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person388" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person388" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was attorney for Mr. Davis and wife, and 
               <persName id="t17591205-35-person389">
                  John 
                  Griffice 
               <interp inst="t17591205-35-person389" type="surname" value="Griffice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person389" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person389" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at Guildhall, last sessions; it was for an assault committed by them on Langrin, the prisoner at the bar. The two prisoners at the bar gave evidence on that trial against the three defendants I have mentioned.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the prisoners sworn?</p>
               <p>Shaw. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the evidence Langrin gave ?</p>
               <p>Shaw. He swore he went into the house of Davis (who at that time kept the Crown alehouse in Crown Court, Fleet Street) and called for three<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175912050046"></xptr> pints of beer, the first he drank himself, the second he drank part of, and the third pint that was brought him was water; that when he put the pot to his mouth, Davis gave the bottom of the pot a chuck, which threw the water upon him, struck against the side of his face, and knocked out two of his teeth, which he then shewed in his hands: After that Davis knocked him down against the fire place, and as soon as he got up again Mrs. Davis struck him on the back part of his head with a pint pot that she had in her hand, which caused a large swelling, which he then shewed in court, on the back part of his head, and said that he never had that swelling there before; that Davis spoke to Griffice in Welch to beat him, the said Langrin, and that Griffice did knock him down three times in the house; that by reason of this beating, and what happened to him that night, he was obliged to lie by for near three months, and said he was not able at that time [meaning the time of his giving this evidence] of working as before.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the evidence 
               <persName id="t17591205-35-person390">
                  Christian 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17591205-35-person390" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person390" type="given" value="Christian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person390" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave on that trial?</p>
               <p>Shaw. Carter swore he came accidentally into that house, at that time, for a pint of beer, which was brought him; that just after he came in he saw Mr. Davis bring Langrin a pint of water, that he saw Langrin give Mrs. Davis three halfpence for it, and did not see her return it to him again; he said, when Langrin was going to drink the water he saw Mr. Davis chuck the water out of the pot upon Langrin, and struck the pot against his cheek, which knock'd one of his teeth out, and that he saw the tooth afterwards; that afterwards he saw Davis knock Langrin down, and when Langrin got up he saw Mrs. Davis strike Langrin a violent blow on his head with a pint pot, which she had in her hand, and said he saw Griffice knock Langrin down in the house, but did not name the time. I remember Langrin said he had known Carter 11 years, and when Carter was asked how long he had known Langrin he at first said he had known him 2 years, and being asked again that question, then he said he had known him no more than 3 years.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this trial?</p>
               <p>Shaw. It was the first day of last sessions at Guild-hall.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-35-person391">
                  John 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17591205-35-person391" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person391" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person391" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Langrin prosecuted me for an assault.</p>
               <p>Q. Is what Mr. Shaw has said here true or false?</p>
               <p>Davis. He has said the truth; the two prisoners swore what he has related.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember Langrin's coming to your house ?</p>
               <p>Davis. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. When was that?</p>
               <p>Davis. It was the 9th of November was twelve months; I then lived at the Crown in Crown-court, Fleet-Street, but I left that house in January last.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you draw him a pint of water?</p>
               <p>Davis. No, I did not; he began to quarrel, and I did not chuse to draw him any more beer, then he said if I would not, he would draw it himself, and taking a pint pot went down into the cellar; I was afraid of his doing some mischief, in letting the liquor out, so took a candle and went down after him; there was a butt of water stood all the same as a butt of beer, with a cock in it, fronting the cellar stairs; when I saw him going to that, I was very well pleased, and he went up with a pint of water, and I after him. I step'd on one side while he drew it, and he did not see me. I was behind him, and saw him give my wife three half-pence, I whispered her, and said, you should not take it, for it is only water, so she gave it him again; he put the pint to his mouth, and finding it was water said. what have you given me here, d - n you, what have you given me here, and flung it in my face. I had said not a syllable to him, neither did I meddle or make with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you chuck the pot in his face?</p>
               <p>Davis. No I did not, I stood behind him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any of his teeth knock'd out?</p>
               <p>Davis. No, I saw no such thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you knock him down?</p>
               <p>Davis. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Griffice knock him down in your house?</p>
               <p>Davis. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you bid Griffice in Welch to knock him down?</p>
               <p>Davis. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body fling water upon him?</p>
               <p>Davis. No, nobody did in my house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see your wife return him his three-halfpence again?</p>
               <p>Davis. As soon as I had told her, I saw her return it to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you present all the while?</p>
               <p>Davis. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-35-person392">
                  Davis
               <interp inst="t17591205-35-person392" type="given" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person392" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I was as sober as I am now. When he threw the water into my face, my wife went to him and desired him to get out of my house. He then went into a box, aad laid his head down on his arm for 2 or 3 minutes, and nobody minded him; then he jumped up and went out into the court (nobody said any thing) where he cried murder as loud as he could.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175912050047"></xptr>Q. Did your wife cut him on his head with a pot?</p>
               <p>Davis. No, she did not; she had never a pot in her hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Was 
               <persName id="t17591205-35-person393">
                  Christian 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17591205-35-person393" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person393" type="given" value="Christian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person393" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in your house that night?</p>
               <p>Davis. No, he was not; this was 11 o'clock at night, when Langrin was there. I never saw him till I saw him in court at Guildhall.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Had Mr. Griffice and Langrin any quarrel?</p>
               <p>Davis. No, they had not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not Langrin fall near the fire?</p>
               <p>Davis. No, he did not fall at all.</p>
               <p>Q. When he flung the water in your face, did you resent it?</p>
               <p>Davis. I thought, as his master was a very litigious man, I had better say nothing to him, so I only shook my cloaths.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Davis. I remember this affair; it was last Lord-mayor's day was twelvemonth, at night. Langrin gave me three halfpence, and my husband told me he had got only water, so I returned him his three halfpence again, and he flung the water over my husband's face; but my husband never touched him nor the pot while it was in his hand. I took hold of his shoulder to put him out of the house, but I never struck him either with the pot or any thing else.</p>
               <p>Q. Did your husband talk Welch to Mr. Griffice?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Davis. I do not understand Welch. Griffice sat drinking with another man at the time, but he never stirred out of the box, neither did he strike him; and as to 
               <persName id="t17591205-35-person394">
                  Christian 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17591205-35-person394" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person394" type="given" value="Christian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person394" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             he was not at our house that night; there was nobody in the house but whom I knew.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-35-person395">
                  John 
                  Griffice 
               <interp inst="t17591205-35-person395" type="surname" value="Griffice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person395" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person395" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at Mr. Davis's house that night, and saw Langrin go down into the cellar and bring up a pint of water; I saw him give Mrs. Davis three halfpence for it, and I saw her return him it again: He flung the water into Mr. Davis's face, and Davis only shook his coat; he did not touch him nor the pot.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Davis (in Welch) bid you knock Langrin down?</p>
               <p>Griffice. No, he did not; neither did I knock him down, or touch him at all; neither did Mrs. Davis strike him, for I was there all the time.</p>
               <p>Q. Was 
               <persName id="t17591205-35-person396">
                  Christian 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17591205-35-person396" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person396" type="given" value="Christian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person396" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             there?</p>
               <p>Griffice. He was not there that night.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-35-person397">
                  David 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17591205-35-person397" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person397" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person397" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was there that night, and heard Langrin say he would go and draw a pint of beer himself; he went down, came up again, and put the money into Mrs. Davis's hand, which she returned to him again. He tasted the water, and said, d - n you, what have I got here? and turned about, and flung it into Mr. Davis's face. Mr. Davis never meddled with him, only shook his coat. Mr. Griffice never touched him all the time he was in the house, neither did Mrs. Davis strike him over the head with a pot; and as to Carter he was not there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-35-person398">
                  Griffith 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17591205-35-person398" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person398" type="given" value="Griffith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person398" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17591205-35-person399">
                  Thomas 
                  Parry 
               <interp inst="t17591205-35-person399" type="surname" value="Parry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person399" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person399" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             exactly confirmed the account, in every particular, given by the other three witnesses.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-35-person400">
                  Lawrence
                   Sanson Labart
               <interp inst="t17591205-35-person400" type="surname" value="Sanson Labart"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person400" type="given" value="Lawrence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person400" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Langrin between nine and ten years, I work'd with him about that time at one Mr. Levit's, in Salisbury-Court; we used sometimes to fit bare headed, and he had then a bump on the back part of his head, I can't tell how it came. [The prisoner shew'd his naked head, and on the back part of it was a bump about as big as half a middling orange.] That I have seen as it now appears near ten years ago; he always was a quarrelsome man.</p>
               <p>Langrin's Defence.</p>
               <p>What I said before is very true; he would not deliver the water without the money, and then he threw it upon me, and they almost murder'd me.</p>
               <p>Carter's Defence.</p>
               <p>Mr. Langrin told me the trial was to come on. I went to one Gregory at Limehouse, who gave me an order to take 4 s. 6 d. for him at the court of conscience at Guildhall, and going to receive it Langrin met me full-butt; and gave me a subpaena and a shilling. I went to an alehouse, and asked a stranger if I must appear to it, who said I must, or else pay 40 l. or suffer one year's imprisonment. I went out of the way that I might not hear his examination, and when he had done I went into court and gave mine.</p>
               <p>Langrin called Erick his brother, who gave him a good character.</p>
               <p>Carter called Frederick his brother, 
               <persName id="t17591205-35-person401">
                  Thomas 
                  Collier 
               <interp inst="t17591205-35-person401" type="surname" value="Collier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person401" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person401" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17591205-35-person402">
                  John 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17591205-35-person402" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person402" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person402" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17591205-35-person403">
                  James 
                  Gregory 
               <interp inst="t17591205-35-person403" type="surname" value="Gregory"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person403" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-person403" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who all gave him a good character.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17591205-35-verdict179" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-verdict179" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17591205-35-punish180" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-punish180" type="punishmentCategory" value="corporal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-35-punish180" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="pillory"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-35-defend385 t17591205-35-punish180"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-35-defend387 t17591205-35-punish180"></join>
               
                     <note>[Pillory. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
