<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560225-29">
               <interp inst="t17560225-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560225-29" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560225-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560225"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560225-29" type="date" value="17560225"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560225-29-off162-c234" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-29-defend287 t17560225-29-off162 t17560225-29-verdict167"></join>
         
               <p>139. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17560225-29-defend287" type="defendantName">
                     Nathaniel 
                     Harrison 
                  <interp inst="t17560225-29-defend287" type="surname" value="Harrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-29-defend287" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-29-defend287" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17560225-29-off162" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560225-29-off162" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-29-off162" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one silver tankard, value 3 l. three silver castors, value 3 l. and one hat laced with gold, value 10 s.
            </rs> the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17560225-29-victim289" type="victimName">
                     James 
                     Cobb 
                  <interp inst="t17560225-29-victim289" type="surname" value="Cobb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-29-victim289" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-29-victim289" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-29-off162 t17560225-29-victim289"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17560225-29-cd163" type="crimeDate">Feb. 4</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-29-off162 t17560225-29-cd163"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-29-person290">
                  James 
                  Cobb 
               <interp inst="t17560225-29-person290" type="surname" value="Cobb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-29-person290" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-29-person290" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17560225-29-crimeloc164">Brick-lane, Spitalfields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17560225-29-crimeloc164" type="placeName" value="Brick-lane, Spitalfields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17560225-29-crimeloc164" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-29-off162 t17560225-29-crimeloc164"></join>. On the 17th of January last I had occasion for some things that were deposited in an inward room. I went to my wife, who was ill in bed, and asked her for the key, but she refused it me. I then went down stairs, and said to my servant, I wonder'd her mistress refused me the key, desiring her to go up and tell her, that unless she would let me have the key I should break the door open. Presently after she return'd with the key, with this message to me, that my wife desired I would master up all my patience I could, for I should find it exercised. I asked her why, and she told me, when I went into the room I should soon see the plate was taken away. I sent the maid back again, to demand the key of<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175602250020"></xptr> the glass-case, that I might open it, and see whether the plate was gone. She came down with it, I went and open'd it, and found the plate was taken away, a large quantity.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you a silversmith?</p>
               <p>Cobb. No, I am a <rs id="t17560225-29-viclabel165" type="occupation">surgeon</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-29-victim289 t17560225-29-viclabel165"></join>. I went to my wife, and asked her what she had done with the plate. She told me she had pawn'd it. I asked her upon what occasion, and she said it was to supply the prisoner at the bar with money.</p>
               <p>Q What was the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Cobb. He was my <rs id="t17560225-29-deflabel166" type="occupation">apprentice</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-29-defend287 t17560225-29-deflabel166"></join>, and is so now. The prisoner had been absent about ten days, when he return'd about twelve at night.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he been absent about your business that time ?</p>
               <p>Cobb. No, but he absented himself very often from my business. He knock'd at the door, and my servant open'd it. He had fight of me, which caused him to retreat a little, saying he would return again. I stept to the door, and bid him come in. He did so, and went to go up stairs to bed. I went into my wife's chamber, to prepare something for her. He was coming down again. I told him he could not lie in the chamber he used to lie in, because I must lie there myself, and said I had something further to say to him, asking him what he had done with my tankard and plate. He said he would restore the tankard to me again, but the rest he had not, believing his mistress had pawn'd it. I desired him to go down with me to his mistress's chamber, and speak before her, which he did. I then charged him with having the money the plate was pawn'd for, and he did not deny it, but said he was to sell some houses at Bromley in Kent, and then he would redeem all the plate, and restore it to me. I told him I could not rely upon his promise, and asked him what security I should have in the mean time.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he of age?</p>
               <p>Cobb. He is 23 years of age. Accordingly he gave me a note for 63 guineas. I then desired him to take care to do as he had said, and all might be well. He said he would. I ask'd him who was to dispose of these houses. He said one Mr. Langford, under the piazza's in Covent-Garden, and that there was to be a week's notice in the Advertiser, and were to be put up at Bromley; but this I found to be all a fiction. He continued with me till the Tuesday following, being Jan. 20. I call'd upon the pawnbroker where my wife said the plate was, and saw some of it. I return'd, and had occasion to go into the yard; when the prisoner took the opportunity to go off again. Then I went up into my wife's chamber, and told her I had seen the plate at the pawnbroker's, but there wa s not all, and ask'd her where the rest was; she said she believed Natt. had taken away the tankard. I asked her where were the castors; she said she believed he had taken them without her knowledge, if they were not there. I heard no more of the prisoner till the 4th of February, when I had an order from justice Fielding to come to him. I went there, and there was the prisoner taken up on suspicion of robing on the highway, at Turnham-Green, with a brace of pistols upon him; the prisoner then acknowledged he had the tankard and castors, and pawn'd them with one Mr. Fryer, in Wych-Street; upon which the justice sent for him. He came, and brought the tankard and castors; and he and I were bound over to prosecute.</p>
               <p>Q. Does not the note for 63 guineas include the tankard and castors?</p>
               <p>Cobb. No, my Lord. I knew nothing of the castors when I took the note; neither do I remember that the value of the tankard was included in the note; there was plate to the amount of fourscore pounds missing.</p>
               <p>Q. What were the contents of the note ?</p>
               <p>Cobb. It was a promissory note to pay me 63 guineas, for value received, in so many days.</p>
               <p>Q. In what manner did he acknowledge he had taken the tankard and castors?</p>
               <p>Cobb. He said it was by my wife's consent he took the tankard, the castors he did not mention.</p>
         
               <p>The Second Part of these Proccedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17560225-29">
                  <interp inst="t17560225-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17560225-29" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17560225-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560225"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17560225-29" type="date" value="17560225"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175602250021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Goal Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON, And also the Goal Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 25th, Thursday the 26th, Friday the 27th, and Saturday the 28th of FEBRUARY,</p>
                  <p>In the Twenty-ninth Year of His MAJESTY'S Reign. NUMBER III. PART II. for the YEAR 1756. Being the Third SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of The Right Honble SLINGSBY BETHELL, Esq; LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by J. ROBINSON, at the Golden-Lion, in Ludgate-Street. 1756.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-pence. ]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175602250022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery held for the City of LONDON, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Q. HOW came the sum to be fixed at 63 guineas?</p>
               <p>Cobb. Because I did not apprehend all the plate to be gone. He told me he would give me a note for a hundred pounds if I pleas'd, but I fix'd it under the value.</p>
               <p>Q. Did it appear that he had received any particular sum?</p>
               <p>Cobb. The sum was not particular.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take the sum of 63 guineas to be pretty near equivalent to your loss in plate?</p>
               <p>Cobb. No, my lord, I lost a great deal more; I would not touch the life of the delinquent, but he has wrong'd me in the tenderest point I can mention.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he paid the note since?</p>
               <p>Cobb. No, he has not.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you got the plate again?</p>
               <p>Cobb. No, I have not.</p>
               <p>Q. How much is the plate pawned for?</p>
               <p>Cobb. I don't know how much.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you found out where the rest of the plate is?</p>
               <p>Cobb. I have; my wife said she carried it, and he receiv'd the money, and he own'd he received it of her; she died the 29th of January last.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he related to you?</p>
               <p>Cobb. He is not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-29-person291">
                  John 
                  Fryer 
               <interp inst="t17560225-29-person291" type="surname" value="Fryer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-29-person291" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-29-person291" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Wych street, am a pawnbroker. (He produced a tankard and three castors, all silver.) On Wednesday the 30th of December last, the prisoners brought these three castors to pawn, I lent him two guineas and a half upon them; on Thursday the 8th of January he brought the tankard, upon which I lent him 7 guineas.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Fryer. I have known him 3 years, he has brought plate before, and a watch.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know he was an apprentice?</p>
               <p>Fryer. No, I did not: He appeared as a gentleman.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know where he lived?</p>
               <p>Fryer. No, I did not; I know his father kept the Crown, at Seven-oaks in Kent; I believe he has brought a watch forty times to me, and taken it out again.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Cobb. Look at the tankard and castors, do you know them?</p>
               <p>Cobb. It is marked with my name, it is my property; the castors are mark'd the same, they are mine also.</p>
               <p>Q. to Fryer. In whose name did the prisoner pawn them?</p>
               <p>Fryer. In his own name.</p>
               <p>Q. to the prosecutor. Where is the rest of the plate pawn'd?</p>
               <p>Cobb. They are pawned in Wheeler-street; there was a gold laced hat, my property, pawn'd in the prisoner's name, but that is not here. I have lost above 500 l. by the prisoner at the bar.</p>
               <p>As the prosecutor's wife had the keeping the key of the room where the plate used to be, the prisoner could not take it without her privity or consent.</p>
               <p>He was <rs id="t17560225-29-verdict167" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560225-29-verdict167" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
