<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17520219-3">
               <interp inst="t17520219-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520219-3" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520219-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520219"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520219-3" type="date" value="17520219"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520219-3-off12-c43" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520219-3-defend47 t17520219-3-off12 t17520219-3-verdict15"></join>
         
               <p>133. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17520219-3-defend47" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Whitmore 
                  <interp inst="t17520219-3-defend47" type="surname" value="Whitmore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-defend47" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-defend47" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17520219-3-deflabel11" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520219-3-defend47 t17520219-3-deflabel11"></join>, was indicted <rs id="t17520219-3-off12" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-off12" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-off12" type="offenceSubcategory" value="coiningOffences"></interp>
               for making forty false, feigned, and counterfeit pieces of coin of this kingdom, called shillings
            </rs>, <rs id="t17520219-3-cd13" type="crimeDate">July 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520219-3-off12 t17520219-3-cd13"></join>. * </p>
               <p>Matthias Standfast. On the 29th of July, I was sent for by Mr. Jones, in order to detect some coiners, being a constable; he and I, and another Man, went and searched a room in <placeName id="t17520219-3-crimeloc14">Red-lion street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17520219-3-crimeloc14" type="placeName" value="Red-lion street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520219-3-crimeloc14" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520219-3-off12 t17520219-3-crimeloc14"></join>, there we found the prisoner and 
               <persName id="t17520219-3-person48">
                  Mary 
                  Hays 
               <interp inst="t17520219-3-person48" type="surname" value="Hays"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person48" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person48" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; we found forty counterfeit shillings in a cavity under the floor; we found also some implements.</p>
               <p>Q. Who rents the room?</p>
               <p>Standfast. I believe Mary Hays does; she is admitted an Evidence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520219-3-person49">
                  William 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17520219-3-person49" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person49" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person49" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Headborough: 
               <persName id="t17520219-3-person50">
                  Thomas 
                  Trustram 
               <interp inst="t17520219-3-person50" type="surname" value="Trustram"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person50" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person50" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came and told me he had some coiners in Mr. Strinubold's house: on the 29th of July, I and the Constable went with him; we took the prisoner and evidence, and searched the room, (a was 
               <persName id="t17520219-3-person51">
                  Mary 
                  Hays 
               <interp inst="t17520219-3-person51" type="surname" value="Hays"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person51" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person51" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's room) we found these things he produced, plaster of Paris, a knife, a file, a bottle with some quicksilver in it, and forty pieces of coin.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you think that coin is made of?</p>
               <p>Jones. I believe they are made of pewter.</p>
               <p>Q. What do they imitate ?</p>
               <p>Jones. King William's shillings.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520219-3-person52">
                  Thomas 
                  Trustram 
               <interp inst="t17520219-3-person52" type="surname" value="Trustram"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person52" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person52" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodge in the same house 
               <persName id="t17520219-3-person53">
                  Mary 
                  Hays 
               <interp inst="t17520219-3-person53" type="surname" value="Hays"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person53" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person53" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             does; she came into my room the 28th of July, seemingly confus'd, and said she was got into bad company: I said, what company? she said a woman, a corner, and that the money, and other things, were hid in her room; and that the woman was gone out: the next day I went and fetched Mr. Jones and Mr. Standfast: we went into the room, and the two women were there; there was a hole behind the door in the floor; Hays went to it, and covered it with her cloths, as a signal to shew us that the money lay there: Mr. Standfast took this money out, wrap'd up in a rag; they are like shillings, I take them to be pewter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520219-3-person54">
                  Mary 
                  Hays 
               <interp inst="t17520219-3-person54" type="surname" value="Hays"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person54" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person54" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The latter end of last summer I saw 
               <persName id="t17520219-3-person55">
                  Ann 
                  Whitmore 
               <interp inst="t17520219-3-person55" type="surname" value="Whitmore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person55" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person55" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17520219-3-person56">
                  Mary 
                  Baker 
               <interp inst="t17520219-3-person56" type="surname" value="Baker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person56" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person56" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             at work on this money in Hog lane, (for Baker see Numb. 601, in Cokayne's Mayoralty ) I don't know at whose house it was, but I know the house: the prisoner was casting shillings out of a mould; it was the best of pewter, and 
               <persName id="t17520219-3-person57">
                  Mary 
                  Baker 
               <interp inst="t17520219-3-person57" type="surname" value="Baker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person57" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person57" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             finished two of them, and went out and brought in a twopenny loaf, and cheese; this was on a Friday, I don't know the day of the month, nor the month: on the Monday following the prisoner came and knocked at my door; I asked her why she came so early? she said, for me to take a walk in the fields with her, saying, 
               <persName id="t17520219-3-person58">
                  Mary 
                  Baker 
               <interp inst="t17520219-3-person58" type="surname" value="Baker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person58" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person58" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was in some goal, either New-Prison or Clerkenwell Bridewell, and wanted me to go and see which it was: I went, and found her in New-Prison : when I came to my lodgings again, there sat the prisoner with those counterfeit shillings in her lap, finishing them.</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175202190005"></xptr>Q. Are you sure these are the same?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520219-3-person59">
                  M 
                  Hays 
               <interp inst="t17520219-3-person59" type="surname" value="Hays"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person59" type="given" value="M"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person59" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I believe they are the same, I have had a great many of them: upon my word, my Lord, I have seen her begin and finish these sort of things five years ago: she asked me the Saturday before she was taken to go and put some off, and I did; then she wanted me to go again with four or five more: I pretended to go to shops so to do, but put them between my teeth, and bit them, and brought them back, pretending that people had tried them and would not take them : she said, if I would not leave her till such time she saw what would become of Baker, she would see me hang'd; I believe she meant hang'd, she would hold her head on one side, and put her tongue out, and her hand to her neck, saying, I'll see you so; then I was very uneasy, and told this man where I liv'd, and he advis'd me to send for an officer: this was on a Saturday night, and I told him on the Sunday she then lodg'd with me from the Monday to the Monday following.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. By all relations this Mrs. Baker and the evidence were old practitioners ; I was at her house as I work'd plain work for her, that then I had been a cripple for five weeks: I never saw the money till the Constable brought it out of the hole.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520219-3-person60">
                  M 
                  Hays 
               <interp inst="t17520219-3-person60" type="surname" value="Hays"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person60" type="given" value="M"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person60" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About eighteen years ago the Prisoner was cast for her life for such Practices, and her mother was burnt for the same the winter before that; her sister was also cast, and afterwards transported; two years ago last summer I was in the Compter for changing some such shillings.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is it since you put off the first for her?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520219-3-person61">
                  M 
                  Hays 
               <interp inst="t17520219-3-person61" type="surname" value="Hays"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person61" type="given" value="M"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person61" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I believe it is five years ago: I did it for three years running.</p>
               <p>Q. What benefit had you in so doing?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520219-3-person62">
                  M 
                  Hays 
               <interp inst="t17520219-3-person62" type="surname" value="Hays"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person62" type="given" value="M"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person62" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She would give me what she pleas'd.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>This woman came to me on the Monday ; she said will you do me one favour? what is that, said I; she said, you know the old woman nam'd Baker, otherwise Strong, has happen'd into a sad scrape, she is got into either Bridewell or New-Prison ; she ask'd me to go with her there: I told her I was not able to walk so far; then she said she must go herself, but wish'd she had some trusty friend, but she did not know who to trust : she came to me a second time, and said she was in prison; she told me if I would, walk along with her home, she would tell me more of her mind: I went with her, it was on the Saturday, she perswaded me to lie with her that night, on the next morning she said I should stay all day; I did; I had that night in my pocket two six pences which I lost there, I said nobody had been there but she; she said do you accuse me with robbing you, she said she could get six pence and six pence a great many ways, and said don't make words about it you must breakfast with me; she lock'd me into the room for about two hours and went as she said for some chips to make a fire, she returned without any; after that these men rapp'd at the door, she was very ready to open it, one of them said we are come to search for some melted mettle; I did not know what they meant, she look'd at me and I at her, said I what is this about mettle? I don't know she said, the men search'd and pull'd out this money and my two sixpences with it, she turn'd about to me as if she wanted me to go down stairs, I had no dread; we was taken before the Justice, she said to me say you nothing at all I know what to do.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520219-3-person63">
                  M 
                  Hays 
               <interp inst="t17520219-3-person63" type="surname" value="Hays"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person63" type="given" value="M"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person63" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She was going to set stamps with them two six-pences, and to leave off making shillings: she has lived first with one man, then another, she liv'd with 
               <persName id="t17520219-3-person64">
                  Patrick 
                  Riley 
               <interp inst="t17520219-3-person64" type="surname" value="Riley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person64" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person64" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he was made evidence against her, he left me out of his information, thinking to strengthen his evidence more against her.</p>
               <p>(See No. 599, in Cokayne's Mayoralty.)</p>
               <p>Q. from the Prisoner. Did you ever know me put some off?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520219-3-person65">
                  M 
                  Hays 
               <interp inst="t17520219-3-person65" type="surname" value="Hays"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person65" type="given" value="M"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person65" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never saw her.</p>
               <p>Q. from the Prisoner. Did you put all off?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520219-3-person66">
                  M 
                  Hays 
               <interp inst="t17520219-3-person66" type="surname" value="Hays"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person66" type="given" value="M"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person66" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I put a great many off.</p>
               <p>Q. from the Prisoner. What instruments did I use in making this money?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520219-3-person67">
                  M 
                  Hays 
               <interp inst="t17520219-3-person67" type="surname" value="Hays"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person67" type="given" value="M"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person67" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She made them in a wooden instrument which she had made by a Joyner, after which she cut a spout to pour the mettle into it; she told the maker it was to make chocolate in.</p>
               <p>Q. from the Prisoner. Do you know any body that put any off for me?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520219-3-person68">
                  M 
                  Hays 
               <interp inst="t17520219-3-person68" type="surname" value="Hays"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person68" type="given" value="M"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person68" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know no body but my self that did, I had used to go into shops and change them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. London is a large place; it is strange she can't find some person that has seen me with bad money or putting it off?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520219-3-person69">
                  M 
                  Hays 
               <interp inst="t17520219-3-person69" type="surname" value="Hays"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person69" type="given" value="M"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person69" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            : I don't know any body that could see her, she has liv'd in divers places.</p>
               <p>Court. Was you ever tried in this Court yourself for such a fact?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520219-3-person70">
                  M 
                  Hays 
               <interp inst="t17520219-3-person70" type="surname" value="Hays"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person70" type="given" value="M"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person70" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . No, my Lord, I was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever give your evidence here on such an occasion?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520219-3-person71">
                  M 
                  Hays 
               <interp inst="t17520219-3-person71" type="surname" value="Hays"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person71" type="given" value="M"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person71" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . No, my Lord, I never did.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520219-3-verdict15" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-verdict15" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>It does appear by searching the short-hand minutes of the trial of E. Baker, Hays did give her evidence against her as an accomplice, and that one 
               <persName id="t17520219-3-person72">
                  Ann 
                  Knight 
               <interp inst="t17520219-3-person72" type="surname" value="Knight"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person72" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-3-person72" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was concerned with them.</p>
            </div1>
