<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570223-27">
               <interp inst="t17570223-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570223-27" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570223-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570223"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570223-27" type="date" value="17570223"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570223-27-off153-c252" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570223-27-defend306 t17570223-27-off153 t17570223-27-verdict155"></join>
         
               <p>121. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17570223-27-defend306" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Timperly 
                  <interp inst="t17570223-27-defend306" type="surname" value="Timperly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-defend306" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-defend306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was <rs id="t17570223-27-off153" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-off153" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-off153" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               indicted for that 
                     <persName id="t17570223-27-person307">
                        John 
                        Dove 
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person307" type="surname" value="Dove"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570223-27-person307" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570223-27-person307" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   and 
                     <persName id="t17570223-27-person308">
                        Robert 
                        Blyth 
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person308" type="surname" value="Blyth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570223-27-person308" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570223-27-person308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   did steal eleven bags of ginger, weighing 88 lb. and one firkin of butter, weighing 56 lb. in the county of Surry, the goods of 
                     <persName id="t17570223-27-victim309" type="victimName">
                        Valentine 
                        Hargrove 
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-victim309" type="surname" value="Hargrove"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570223-27-victim309" type="given" value="Valentine"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570223-27-victim309" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                    and 
                     
                        <persName id="t17570223-27-victim311" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Charlton 
                        <interp inst="t17570223-27-victim311" type="surname" value="Charlton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570223-27-victim311" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570223-27-victim311" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , January 11. and were convicted for the same, and receiv'd sentence of transportation at the general quarter sessions of the peace for the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175702230026"></xptr> county of Surry, on Thursday <rs id="t17570223-27-cd154" type="crimeDate">Feb. 17</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570223-27-off153 t17570223-27-cd154"></join>. and that the said Timperly did receive the same, well knowing it to have been stolen
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570223-27-person312">
                  John 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17570223-27-person312" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person312" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person312" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             produced a copy of the record of the conviction of Dove and Blyth, which was read.</p>
               <p>Valentine Hargr ove. I am a wharfinger, our wharf did go by the name of Hay's and Cox's, but now Hargrove and Charlton; on the 4th of this instant I catch'd one 
               <persName id="t17570223-27-person313">
                  John 
                  Blail 
               <interp inst="t17570223-27-person313" type="surname" value="Blail"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person313" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person313" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             with a bag of ginger on his back, which I saw him take out of our warehouse; he was admited an evidence, and that very bag I have now in court; it is fellow to two others that we found in the prisoner's custody, produced in court. I had a hundred and fifty bags of that sort with ginger in them in my warehouse.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell what time they were taken away?</p>
               <p>Hargrove. No, I cannot, it was within these three months or thereabouts.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570223-27-person314">
                  John 
                  Charlton 
               <interp inst="t17570223-27-person314" type="surname" value="Charlton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person314" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am partner with the other evidence; after the evidence Blail was taken up and committed, I went to examine him. He confess'd he had sold the prisoner at the bar some bags of ginger, and that the prisoner allowed him 10 s per hundred wt. for them; he gave information against two persons, named 
               <persName id="t17570223-27-person315">
                  John 
                  Dove 
               <interp inst="t17570223-27-person315" type="surname" value="Dove"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person315" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person315" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Robert Blyth, so we took them up, and the prisoner; we got a search warrant and went and search'd his house, and these two bags were found in a little closet turn'd inside out, they smelt much of ginger; he said upon his examination that his daughter bought them to put old cloaths in.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at the trial of Dove and Blyth?</p>
               <p>Charlton. I was, they confess'd the fact laid to their charge; there was no evidence given against them. I gave evidence before the grand jury of the finding the bags, and their confession.</p>
               <p>Q. What were they indicted for?</p>
               <p>Charlton. For stealing eleven bags of ginger and a firkin of butter.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the closet lock'd in which were the bags?</p>
               <p>Charlton. No.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you find these bags?</p>
               <p>Charlton. On the 9th of this instant.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570223-27-person316">
                  John 
                  Blail 
               <interp inst="t17570223-27-person316" type="surname" value="Blail"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person316" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person316" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About three months ago, or something better. I went to the prisoner's house and asked him if he'd buy a bag of ginger.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does he live?</p>
               <p>Blail. In Drury-lane; he asked me what sort of ginger, I said I could not tell; he asked what it might weigh, but he said I might bring it if I would. We went to him with a bag that afternoon. 
               <persName id="t17570223-27-person317">
                  Robert 
                  Blyth 
               <interp inst="t17570223-27-person317" type="surname" value="Blyth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person317" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person317" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17570223-27-person318">
                  John 
                  Dove 
               <interp inst="t17570223-27-person318" type="surname" value="Dove"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person318" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person318" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and I carried it by turns.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you take it from?</p>
               <p>Blail. From that wharf call'd Hay's and Cox's formerly, out of a warehouse; two stood without while the other went in. The prisoner weigh'd it and gave us half a guinea for it; we asked him if he would have any more, and he bid us take care of ourselves. We went about three days after and took a couple more from the same place; he weigh'd them and gave us 20 s. for them; they weigh'd a hundred wt. each. He asked us if we had any more, and bid us take care of ourselves, and bring some more. Dove and I went and took one bag more; two days after that, at about three in the afternoon, we carried it to the prisoner, and gave us 9 s. for it. We asked him if he would have any more; he said, we might bring another bag if we would; he always caution'd us to take care of ourselves; we went down again and got two bags more in about a week after, which we carried to the prisoner, and he gave us 18 s. for them.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you ever tell him where you brought them from?</p>
               <p>Blail. No, never. Then we asked him if he would have any more. He said, we might bring another if we would, and ordered us to take care of ourselves. About three days after that Dove and I went down, and the warehouse was stop'd up with butter, so that we could not come at the ginger. We took a firkin of butter away, carried it to the prisoner, and sold it to him for half a guinea.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever mentioned any thing of butter to him before?</p>
               <p>Blail. No, we had not. We asked him if he would have any more things, if we could get them. He said, yes; but bid us take care of ourselves. About six weeks after we got into another warehouse, belonging to the same people, and took out two bags of ginger.</p>
               <p>Q. to Hargrove. How were they marked in that warehouse ?</p>
               <p>Hargrove. They were not mark'd like the others. These I have brought here were out of the same warehouse which I suppose the butter was taken from; but there is butter in both warehouses.</p>
               <p>Blail. The two warehouses both join together; one is a long one, and the other is a little one. We took all but two out of the little warehouse.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175702230027"></xptr> The prisoner gave us 19 s. for the two last I mentioned. We asked him if we should bring him some more. He said, we might if we would, but we must take care of ourselves. Then we all three of us went down to the long warehouse, and took three bags out, and sold them to the prisoner for 30 s. We went a little after to get another, and I was taken.</p>
               <p>Q. How many bags of ginger did you take in all ?</p>
               <p>Blail. We took eleven in all.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the marks upon these bags ?</p>
               <p>Blail. If I see them I do. (He looks at the two bags.) These are two of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Which warehouse did these come out of?</p>
               <p>Blail. These came out of the long warehouse.</p>
               <p>Q. to Hargrove. What is the value of this ginger?</p>
               <p>Hargrove. It is worth something better than 30 s. per cwt.</p>
               <p>Q. to Hargrove. Which warehouse contains the bags of this mark?</p>
               <p>Hargrove. The long warehouse.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to carry the first bag to the prisoner's house?</p>
               <p>Blail. I went first to ask him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take notice of the marks of each bag ?</p>
               <p>Blail. I did; as we took them out.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see these bags before ?</p>
               <p>Blail. I saw them last the 17th of this month.</p>
               <p>Q. to Hargrove. Did you lose any butter ?</p>

               <p>Hargrove. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. to Charlton. Do you remember losing any butter?</p>
               <p>Charlton. There was butter put into this warehouse in a hurry, and it lay so as we could not come at the ginger sometimes without removing it.</p>
               <p>Q. to Charlton. Did you mention the losing of butter before the grand jury, in Surry ?</p>
               <p>Charlton. I believe I did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570223-27-person319">
                  William 
                  Foster 
               <interp inst="t17570223-27-person319" type="surname" value="Foster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person319" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person319" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was present, on the 8th of this instant, when the prisoner was taken at his house, the White-Hart, in the Coal yard, Drury-Lane. When he saw us come into his house he ran into a shed, at the upper end of the yard. He had his boots on. We brought him to Covent Garden 
               <persName id="t17570223-27-person320">
                  Round
               <interp inst="t17570223-27-person320" type="given" value="Round"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person320" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             house.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Foster. I am a sergeant in the third regiment of foot guards.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you draw your sword when you went into the house ?</p>
               <p>Foster. No, I did not till he got into the shed. I put it through a crack towards him; then he came out.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not your drawing your sword the occasion of his running away?</p>
               <p>Foster. No. It was not drawn a minute.</p>
               <p>Q. to Charlton. At whose house did you find the bags ?</p>
               <p>Charlton. At the White Hart and Ninopin.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570223-27-person321">
                  George 
                  Keep 
               <interp inst="t17570223-27-person321" type="surname" value="Keep"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person321" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person321" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 9th of February. I went with Mr. Charlton to justice Fielding's. The prisoner was then in custody in Mr. Fielding's house. He ordered a search warrant. I went with the constable, Mr. Charlton, and another person, in order to search his house; and in a back room, in a closet on the left hand. I found two bags turn'd the wrong side outwards. These are the two bags here produced. We carried them to the justice. He said, we must keep them in our custody. The prisoner said his girl bought them of an old cloaths woman.</p>
               <p>Q. What girl was that?</p>
               <p>Keep. It is his daughter. I examined the bags in Mr. Charlton's long warehouse. There are the very same marks on these.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find any ginger?</p>
               <p>Keep. No, none at all. The bags smelt very strong of ginger.</p>
               <p>Q. Were not the bags found upon a parcel of old bags ?</p>
               <p>Keep. No, they were not. There were some foul linen, a coat, and a waistcoat, in the same closet.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing at all of buying any thing they accuse me of. My little girl bought the two bags of a woman, that said she found them in the street, and she put them by to put dirty cloaths in.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570223-27-person322">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Steel 
               <interp inst="t17570223-27-person322" type="surname" value="Steel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person322" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person322" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am really what you may call a rag gatherer in the street, which you may properly call a bunter.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the prisoner at the bar?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175702230028"></xptr>E. Steel. His wife buys old cloaths, and he has bought a great many old rags of me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you, at any time, and when, sell any rags to him?</p>
               <p>E. Steel. I have sold rags five or six years, and I have sold rags upwards of three years to them both. I hardly sold him any thing else, except odd things, which you properly call hand-stuff. Sometimes I have found pieces of old bags, like unto this here. (Looking on one of the two found at the prisoner's house.) I never sold him any bags at all, except what I found in the street. I did pick up two little ones, that I sold him, for which I had no more than three halfpence. I think they were something finer than these are. They weighed two pounds and a half. They were wrapped together in a lump. I never opened them any farther than to see they were bags.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you pick them up ?</p>
               <p>E. Steel. They lay as close as close could be to a door in the Strand, betwixt Somerset-house and the new church.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any mark they had ?</p>
               <p>E. Steel. No. I put them all of a lump together in my pocket apron, and went and sold them directly to his daughter, before any of the other people were up.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in company, alone ?</p>
               <p>E. Steel. There was 
               <persName id="t17570223-27-person323">
                  Susannah 
                  Durkin 
               <interp inst="t17570223-27-person323" type="surname" value="Durkin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person323" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person323" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             with me.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was this ago?</p>
               <p>E. Steel. I believe it may be three weeks, or upwards.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570223-27-person324">
                  Susannah 
                  Durkin 
               <interp inst="t17570223-27-person324" type="surname" value="Durkin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person324" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person324" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I carry butter out three days in a week, and Elizabeth Steel and I have commonly a pint of purl together in a morning. We are what you may call poverty struck, and have no money. I'll tell the truth, that is best. I can't say whether it is a month, or more than three weeks, ago, that Steel pick'd up two bags and put them into her pocket apron. She said here is as much as will fetch us a morning's draught. She and, I went together to the prisoner's house. She sold them to his little girl for three halfpence, so we put a halfpenny to it, and had a pint of purl.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any body by at the time ?</p>
               <p>S. Durkin. Yes, there was Charles, a soldier. He is quarter'd upon them.</p>
               <p>Q. What did they weigh?</p>
               <p>S. Durkin. They weighed two pounds and a half. It was what she call'd hand-stuff.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you know them to be bags?</p>
               <p>S. Durkin. Because I saw they were sew'd up, at the bottom, and one was thicker than the other.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see them open'd?</p>
               <p>S. Durkin. How open'd? I saw her take them up, and put them into her pocket. They were open'd at the rag shed.</p>
               <p>Q. Who open'd them?</p>
               <p>S. Durkin. She did. You know she could not help opening them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her open them?</p>
               <p>S. Durkin. I did not see her open them.</p>
               <p>Court. Then you did not see they were bags.</p>
               <p>S. Durkin. I was very well assured they were bags.</p>
               <p>Q. What marks had they upon them?</p>
               <p>S. Durkin. I believe I could tell them again if I saw them. I believe they were black marks.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the bags made of linen or woollen?</p>
               <p>S. Durkin. Neither one nor t'other I believe.</p>
               <p>Q. What were they made of?</p>
               <p>S. Durkin. I really can't say.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they made of leather?</p>
               <p>S. Durkin. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Then tell the court what they were made of.</p>
               <p>S. Durkin. I believe they were made of such stuff that the packthread is made of, indeed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570223-27-person325">
                  Charles 
                  Thirkall 
               <interp inst="t17570223-27-person325" type="surname" value="Thirkall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person325" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person325" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the house of the prisoner, being quarter'd there, and saw two bags brought in by 
               <persName id="t17570223-27-person326">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Steel 
               <interp inst="t17570223-27-person326" type="surname" value="Steel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person326" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person326" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17570223-27-person327">
                  Susannah 
                  Durkin 
               <interp inst="t17570223-27-person327" type="surname" value="Durkin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person327" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person327" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner's daughter bought them. I opened them after the women were gone, and I saw they had square marks upon them; but I can't swear to them.</p>
               <p>Q. What colour were the marks?</p>
               <p>Thirkall. They were black marks. She gave three halfpence for them. They weighed two-pounds and a half.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the women go away immediately?</p>
               <p>Thirkall. They staid; and had a pint of purk.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were the prisoner and his wife?</p>
               <p>Thirkall. They were in bed.</p>
               <p>Q. What size were the bags?</p>
               <p>Thirkall. Perhaps they might hold a bushel.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the bags open or rolled up, when they were weighed?</p>
               <p>Thirkall. They were not open.</p>
               <p>Q. What were they made of?</p>
               <p>Thirkall. They were made of such as twine is made of.</p>
               <p>Q. For what use did he buy such?</p>
               <p>Thirkall. To make paper of.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at these two bags.</p>
               <p>Thirkall. (He looks at them.) I can't swear to the bags. They are the same make, and the same stuff; but to swear to the marks I cannot.</p>
               <p>Q. Are the marks like them?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175702230029"></xptr>Thirkall. They are something like them.</p>
               <p>Q. to S. Durkin. Look at these, are these the same bags ?</p>
               <p>S. Durkin. I believe, by the virtue of my oath, they are the same bags.</p>
               <p>Corn. Ford. The prisoner has been my tenant above three years. He pays me 20 l. per year, and has as good a character as I could wish to hear of a man. He bought old rags and old iron. He is an industrious, sober man. I never went three times for my rent in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Ford. I live in Dean-Street, Red-Lion-Square.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>Ford. I am a bricklayer.</p>
               <p>H. I have known him two years. I never heard any thing dishonest of him. I have had dealings with him, and he always paid me.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business ?</p>
               <p>Hyate. I am an upholsterer.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Hyate. I live just by him. He deals in rags and iron, and keeps an ale house.</p>
               <p>Mr. Lewis. I am a wholesale druggist, and live in Lawrence-Lane. The prisoner lived with me about eleven years as a porter. He was then a very honest, diligent fellow.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you known him lately ?</p>
               <p>Lewis. No, not since he went from me, which is about three years ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Would you employ him now, if he was clear'd ?</p>
               <p>Lewis. I believe I should, but not to take him into my house.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you deal in ginger?</p>
               <p>Lewis. No.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570223-27-person328">
                  John 
                  Foss 
               <interp inst="t17570223-27-person328" type="surname" value="Foss"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person328" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person328" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live by Queen-Hithe, and am a wholesale dealer in rags.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Foss. I believe I have known him about eight months. I have paid him about 50 or 60 l. He always dealt very well and fair with me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever buy such bags as these two here produced of him?</p>
               <p>Foss. No, to my knowledge, I never did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570223-27-person329">
                  Arthur 
                  Vigers 
               <interp inst="t17570223-27-person329" type="surname" value="Vigers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person329" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-person329" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner a dozen years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general reputation ?</p>
               <p>Vigers. It was always very good. He lodged in my house near five years. He is an industrious, quiet, sober man.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you had any acquaintance with him lately?</p>
               <p>Vigers. No, I have not. He lived in our neighbourhood after he went from me.</p>
               <p>Mr. Calvert. I have known him about sixteen years. He always have an unexceptionable character. I never heard any ill of him before.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570223-27-verdict155" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-verdict155" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570223-27-punish156" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570223-27-punish156" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570223-27-defend306 t17570223-27-punish156"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
