<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17540717-45">
               <interp inst="t17540717-45" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540717-45" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540717-45" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540717"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540717-45" type="date" value="17540717"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540717-45-off221-c325" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-45-defend414 t17540717-45-off221 t17540717-45-verdict224"></join>
         
               <p>393. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17540717-45-defend414" type="defendantName">
                     Bernard 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17540717-45-defend414" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-defend414" type="given" value="Bernard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-defend414" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for the <rs id="t17540717-45-off221" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-off221" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-off221" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               wilful murder
            </rs> of 
               
                  <persName id="t17540717-45-victim416" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Povey 
                  <interp inst="t17540717-45-victim416" type="surname" value="Povey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-victim416" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-victim416" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-45-off221 t17540717-45-victim416"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            . He stood likewise charged on the coroner's inquest for the said murder, <rs id="t17540717-45-cd222" type="crimeDate">June 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-45-off221 t17540717-45-cd222"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-45-person417">
                  John 
                  Barret 
               <interp inst="t17540717-45-person417" type="surname" value="Barret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-person417" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-person417" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Sunday the 16th of June, about six in the evening, I was with a neighbour of mine at his door, I heard a noise at the end of the lane; presently they got into <placeName id="t17540717-45-crimeloc223">Salisbury-Court</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17540717-45-crimeloc223" type="placeName" value="Salisbury-Court"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17540717-45-crimeloc223" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-45-off221 t17540717-45-crimeloc223"></join>; there I saw two men fighting. I went; the prisoner and the deceased were both near me. The prisoner said, D - n the scoundrels, we will lick them all round. The deceased would have nothing to say to him, but turned about and crossed the way towards the Swan. The prisoner pulled off his coat and waistcoat, and followed the deceased and gave him two or three knocks in the face. The deceased fell down, and to appearance lay for dead. I said to the prisoner, You are a scoundrel for using the man so ill that did not offend you. Then the prisoner ran away, and was taken near the steps in Bridewell-Lane, and brought to the Swan; the deceased was carried to Mr. Freak's, a surgeon in Salisbury-Court; there he came to himself a little, but was carried there by his arms and legs as a dead man. The gentleman pulled out a tooth or stump that the deceased complained of as either broke or loose.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-45-person418">
                  William 
                  Wootton 
               <interp inst="t17540717-45-person418" type="surname" value="Wootton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-person418" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-person418" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at my door in Shoe-Lane on a Sunday evening, about six o'clock, I saw a crowd of people, and went to them into Salisbury-Court. There were two men fighting: I heard the prisoner at the bar say, D - n the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175407170033"></xptr> scoundrels, we will lick them all round; then he ran to the deceased, and struck him two blows. He fell to the ground; he received a cut in his forehead; it bled very much; he lay as if he was dead; he was carried to Mr. Freak the surgeon; there his wound was dressed. I saw him led home between two to Mr. Took's in Fleet-Street; on the Monday morning he appeared before the sitting alderman at Guild-hall; I was present; the alderman committed the prisoner to the Compter for want of bail.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the prisoner any thing in his hand when he struck the deceased?</p>
               <p>Wootton. I can't say I remember he had, or the deceased either. I believe the prisoner was in liquor.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-45-person419">
                  Mary 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17540717-45-person419" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-person419" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-person419" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The first I saw of it was, the deceased was coming through the crowd, seemingly towards the White Swan, as the other two were fighting, and when he was pretty near the kennel the prisoner at the bar gave him a blow on the left side of his face with his right hand: The second blow brought him to the ground; he was taken up for dead, and carried to a surgeon in Salisbury-Court; then the fighting broke up.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-45-person420">
                  Thomas 
                  Cawley 
               <interp inst="t17540717-45-person420" type="surname" value="Cawley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-person420" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-person420" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The quarrel began with me; I was one of the two men that was fighting; it at first began with the prisoner splashing and jostling against me. I took my hand and just touched my face afterwards. This was in Shoe-Lane. He began to curse and swear. There were about half a dozen of the prisoner's company. Then the others of his company d - d their eyes, and swore they would fight. One d - d my chuckle head, as he was pleased to call it, and swore he would sight me. I never saw him before. I said, Gentlemen, I don't want to fight; I have no concern at all with you. Words ensuing, they followed us over Fleet-Street. We were four of us in our company, but two of them went away when the quarrel began, and left only the deceased and I. One of the other company came into Salisbury-Court, and gave me several blows. I held an oak-stick behind me, and defended myself with my hand as well as I could. Two gentlemen came by, and said, Countryman fight away, you shall have fair play. I dropt my stick and fell to fighting. I was soon knocked down in the kennel. I never saw a blow struck between the deceased and the prisoner. When I got up they told me my partner was killed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-45-person421">
                  Thomas 
                  Hanton 
               <interp inst="t17540717-45-person421" type="surname" value="Hanton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-person421" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-person421" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I dined at the sign of the Two Kings and Key in Fleet-Street on that Sunday. Coming home at night there arose a fraction. The deceased was very much in liquor; I was behind them; 
               <persName id="t17540717-45-person422">
                  Thomas 
                  Cawley 
               <interp inst="t17540717-45-person422" type="surname" value="Cawley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-person422" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-person422" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was fighting; I took hold of the deceased's arm, and said, Let's have no fractions. He went into Salisbury Court; the prisoner followed him and knocked him down in my fight with his fist. Then we took him to the surgeon's, and from thence to his house, and put him to bed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-45-person423">
                  Charles 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17540717-45-person423" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-person423" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-person423" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mr. Freak, and dressed the deceased's wound that night. To the best of my remembrance, it was on the left side of his forehead. He was very bloody. He had two teeth knocked out, one I took out that night, the other was very loose, which came out the next day; he was very much in liquor; the flesh was divided to the skull, about an inch and an half in length. I found no fracture or ill symptoms, and thought it had a very good appearance. I came away, and the next day I went again; the wound looked well then. I continued dressing him for about eight or ten days; after that I heard he carried a load on his head. I had word came he was extreamly ill. I went and found he had a fever upon him; I dressed the wound, and bled him. After that he was willing to get into the hospital, he not having wherewithal to maintain himself. He was taken in the next morning, and died there.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you think was the occasion of his death?</p>
               <p>White. I do believe he died of that accident.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you find bad symptoms first appear?</p>
               <p>White. Not till after eight or nine days.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this wound occasioned by the fall or a blow?</p>
               <p>White. I imagined it to be done by an obtuse stone in the street.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>Three of us were walking together, and three others behind and a quarrel arose by those behind, but I know nothing of the beginning of it. This man came over and d - d me, and asked what I called after him for. He, the deceased struck, at my head with a stick, and after that with his fist. I got out of the way of the stick, and asked him what he struck me for. He said I called after him; then he struck me on the breast. One of my companions was standing by me.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175407170034"></xptr>For the Prisoner</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-45-person424">
                  James 
                  Collingbourn 
               <interp inst="t17540717-45-person424" type="surname" value="Collingbourn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-person424" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-person424" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming down Fleet-street, accidentally when this happened, and saw the deceased cross the way from Salisbury Court to Shoe-Lane, and strike at the prisoner with a stick and knock his hat off. The prisoner said, Pray, Sir, what do you mean by striking me? Said the deceased you scoundrel, you called after me. Then the prisoner said, No, Sir, I did not, for I was calling to the rest of my friends that were with me. I saw no more blows after that. They went over into Salisbury-Court, but I did not follow them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the deceased or the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Collingham. I know the prisoner, but did not know the deceased.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-45-person425">
                  John 
                  Trippet 
               <interp inst="t17540717-45-person425" type="surname" value="Trippet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-person425" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-person425" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the deceased cross the way to Shoe-Lane, and strike the prisoner over the head with a stick: the prisoner was very quiet before. The prisoner called to some boys that were behind him as he was in the middle of the way. I went down a turning and did not see any more of it.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-45-person426">
                  Michael 
                  Bowvell 
               <interp inst="t17540717-45-person426" type="surname" value="Bowvell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-person426" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-person426" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him four years and a half, and have lived with him that time; he has all that time deserved the character of a quiet, sober, inoffensive lad.</p>
               <p>Mr. Jervis. I have known him 6 years; he is a very honest, industrious, sober, quiet lad.</p>
               <p>Mr. Thorp. I live within 5 doors of the prisoner; I have known him about 6 years, and always heard he was a very sober, modest, industrious lad; I never heard he was given to quarrelling before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-45-person427">
                  William 
                  Loveless 
               <interp inst="t17540717-45-person427" type="surname" value="Loveless"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-person427" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-person427" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him 6 years and a half; he is apprentice to my brother; his general character is that of a quiet, honest, sober lad.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-45-person428">
                  William 
                  Haselford 
               <interp inst="t17540717-45-person428" type="surname" value="Haselford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-person428" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-person428" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about 6 years; I never heard any harm of him in my life; he was always a sober lad; he is a bird-cage maker by trade.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540717-45-verdict224" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-verdict224" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-verdict224" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540717-45-punish225" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-punish225" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-45-punish225" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-45-defend414 t17540717-45-punish225"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
