<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17550116-7">
               <interp inst="t17550116-7" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550116-7" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550116-7" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550116-7" type="date" value="17550116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550116-7-off38-c92" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-7-defend101 t17550116-7-off38 t17550116-7-verdict40"></join>
         
               <p>51. (M. 2.) 
               <persName id="t17550116-7-defend101" type="defendantName">
                  Susannah 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17550116-7-defend101" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-7-defend101" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-7-defend101" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17550116-7-deflabel37" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-7-defend101 t17550116-7-deflabel37"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17550116-7-off38" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550116-7-off38" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-7-off38" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one cloth cloak, value 1 s. 6 d. one linen apron, value 9 d. one shirt, value 9 d. one Leghorn hat, value 6 d.
            </rs> the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17550116-7-victim103" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Symonds 
                  <interp inst="t17550116-7-victim103" type="surname" value="Symonds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-7-victim103" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-7-victim103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-7-off38 t17550116-7-victim103"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17550116-7-cd39" type="crimeDate">Jan. 6</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-7-off38 t17550116-7-cd39"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>Mary Symonds. About last Wednesday se'nnight the prisoner desired me to go of an errand for her to her aunt; I went, and left her in my house. When I returned I told her her aunt was gone out. She said, then she is gone about the same errand I wanted her. She went out; after she was gone, I missed the things mentioned in the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175501160008"></xptr> indictment. After some time, I took her with my hat upon her, in Phaenix-street, Spitalfields, and took her before Sir 
               <persName id="t17550116-7-person104">
                  Samuel 
                  Gore 
               <interp inst="t17550116-7-person104" type="surname" value="Gore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-7-person104" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-7-person104" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; there she said she had taken and pawned my cloak for 1 s. 6 d. and my apron for 9 d. and where they were pawned. (The hat produced in court.)</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>When I went out of her house, I took the hat and cloak as usual; she has lent me them many a time. I did want a little money, and pawned them to be sure.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutrix. Did you lend her these things?</p>
               <p>M. Symonds. No, I did not; neither did I know they were gone till I missed them. I never did lend her them in my life.</p>
               <p>Oswald Hill. This morning I went to the prosecutor's house, and asked her how she could be so base to level a felony, where it was but an action of debt? She said, she had sworn it, and that was sufficient. I said, I understood they were only lent. She said, it was a fine thing if she had lent any thing, that it should be paw ned. She did not deny she had lent them to her. I have known the prisoner ever since she was born; she is a simple honest woman, that does not take care of herself; but I never knew any harm of her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-7-person105">
                  Mary 
                  Pinenet 
               <interp inst="t17550116-7-person105" type="surname" value="Pinenet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-7-person105" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-7-person105" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner lived with me four years; I never knew her to do an ill thing. I have known the prosecutrix to lend her aprons, caps, and all things to wear, except gowns. I once heard her say, what a fool I was to lend Taylor my cloak last night, for she has fell down, and all dirtied it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-7-person106">
                  John 
                  Scot 
               <interp inst="t17550116-7-person106" type="surname" value="Scot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-7-person106" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-7-person106" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About eight or nine days ago, Mrs. Symonds came to me crying, and said, Mrs. Taylor had borrowed her cloak and apron of her, to go to a relation, to get some money for her subsistence; but she got none, so she has carried them to pawn. I knew Mrs. Symonds had frequently lent her her things before, and said she was very welcome to those things at any time.</p>
               <p>Q. How came she to tell you?</p>
               <p>J. Scot. She came to my house, I suppose in order to get some money to redeem them. The prisoner has lived in my house; I took upon her to be an honest woman. She has a husband now living; but he lives with another woman.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutrix. Do you now say you never lent her any of the things?</p>
               <p>M. Symonds. I never said I had lent her things in my life. The first and second witnesses I never spoke to but once each. She never went to her relations with my things in her days.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-7-person107">
                  Catharine 
                  Saunders 
               <interp inst="t17550116-7-person107" type="surname" value="Saunders"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-7-person107" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-7-person107" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner three years; she is an honest woman, only will drink a little too much.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-7-person108">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Robertson 
               <interp inst="t17550116-7-person108" type="surname" value="Robertson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-7-person108" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-7-person108" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her three years; she never wronged man, woman, or child of any thing, as ever I heard.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17550116-7-verdict40" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550116-7-verdict40" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
