<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17540911-8">
               <interp inst="t17540911-8" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-8" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-8" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-8" type="date" value="17540911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540911-8-off40-c63" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-8-defend76 t17540911-8-off40 t17540911-8-verdict45"></join>
         
               <p>420. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17540911-8-defend76" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Young 
                  <interp inst="t17540911-8-defend76" type="surname" value="Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-8-defend76" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-8-defend76" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-8-defend76" type="age" value="seventeen years"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17540911-8-off40" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540911-8-off40" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-8-off40" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing two 3 l. 12 s. pieces of gold, two moidores, three guineas, 17 s. 6 d. in money numbered, three gold rings, three silver buckles, and one silver pocket piece, the goods and money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17540911-8-victim78" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Pitten 
                        <interp inst="t17540911-8-victim78" type="surname" value="Pitten"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540911-8-victim78" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540911-8-victim78" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-8-off40 t17540911-8-victim78"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling house
            </rs> of the said John, <rs id="t17540911-8-cd41" type="crimeDate">July 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-8-off40 t17540911-8-cd41"></join>.*.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-8-person79">
                  John 
                  Pitten 
               <interp inst="t17540911-8-person79" type="surname" value="Pitten"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-8-person79" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-8-person79" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . <rs id="t17540911-8-viclabel42" type="occupation">I keep a cook's shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-8-victim78 t17540911-8-viclabel42"></join> in <placeName id="t17540911-8-crimeloc43">King Street, on Tower-hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17540911-8-crimeloc43" type="placeName" value="King Street, on Tower-hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17540911-8-crimeloc43" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-8-off40 t17540911-8-crimeloc43"></join>, and the prisoner was my <rs id="t17540911-8-deflabel44" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-8-defend76 t17540911-8-deflabel44"></join>. I have a chest in my bedchamber in which was money and plate. I found it broke open on Saturday morning the 20th of July, and missed out of it two 3 l. 12 s. pieces, two 27 s. pieces, some 36 s. pieces and guineas, I can't say how many, besides 6 l. and upwards in all to the amount of 40 l. and upwards. The prisoner lay out of my house that night. I had a suspicion of him, and inquiring about for him, he was taken between eleven and twelve that day in Monmouth Street. I was sent for to him in St. Giles's Round-house, and he owned to me he broke the chest open, and took away the money.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you seen the money and rings mentioned before you missed them?</p>
               <p>Pitten. I had seen the rings and buckles about three days before.</p>
               <p>Q. How old is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Pitten. He is about seventeen years of age. I never found any dishonesty of him before this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-8-person80">
                  Henry 
                  Flannegan 
               <interp inst="t17540911-8-person80" type="surname" value="Flannegan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-8-person80" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-8-person80" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable, and was sent for to Monmouth Street to take the prisoner into custody. I brought him to my house, and upon searching him in my back kitchen found two 3 l. 12 s. pieces, two moidores, three guineas, three gold rings, a silver pocket piece, three silver buckles, and to the best of my knowledge 17 s. 6 d. in silver. Produced in court.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I can't swear to the money, but the rings and buckles are my property, and were in my chest before it was broke open.</p>
               <p>Flannegan. I sent the prisoner to the Round-house, where the prosecutor came, and I heard him own to his master, that he broke open the chest either with a poker or tongs, I can't tell which.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear him say any thing about taking the money and rings?</p>
               <p>Flannegan. I did not. I had other business, and so went away, leaving them together.</p>
               <p>Mr. Dorton. I live in Monmouth Street. Mr. Pitten came to my shop and asked me if I had seen such a person, describing the prisoner. I said, I had not; he desired me, if I should, to stop him, and send him word, saying, he had been robbed of upwards of 40 l. In about half an hour after he was gone the prisoner came into the street, and I followed him into a shop where he went in; he had another young fellow along with him. I got another person to go in with me, and said to the prisoner, Young man, I believe you are the young man who have robbed your master of 40 l. He said, he believed it was not above half the money.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he sober?</p>
               <p>Dorton. He was very sober. The other person with him asked what was the matter, and upon my telling him, said, he was afraid he had done some such thing, and that he had lent him a guinea to buy him a coat, which he returned to me. We sent for a constable, and the prisoner was taken into his house and searched, and the money and things found upon him as the constable mentioned, including the guinea that was delivered to me by the other person. He was put into the Roundhouse, and I sent for the prosecutor, who came, and asked him how he came to do so. He answered, he could not tell. His master asked him what he had done with the rest of the money, and he said he had been in a very disorderly house, and had spent it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I had been drinking, and know nothing how I came by the money, but I am sure I did not break the chest.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540911-8-verdict45" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540911-8-verdict45" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17540911-8-punish46" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540911-8-punish46" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-8-defend76 t17540911-8-punish46"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
