<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17550515-20">
               <interp inst="t17550515-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550515-20" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550515-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550515"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550515-20" type="date" value="17550515"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550515-20-off95-c149" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-20-defend185 t17550515-20-off95 t17550515-20-verdict98"></join>
         
               <p>227. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17550515-20-defend185" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Dennison 
                  <interp inst="t17550515-20-defend185" type="surname" value="Dennison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-20-defend185" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-20-defend185" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17550515-20-off95" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550515-20-off95" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-20-off95" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one feather-bed, value 5 s. one feather-bolster, value 6 d. one pair of linen sheets, value 1 s. one blanket, value 1 s. one quilt, value 1 s. one pair of bellows, value 9 d. and one tin kettle, value 3 d. the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17550515-20-victim187" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Nickson 
                        <interp inst="t17550515-20-victim187" type="surname" value="Nickson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550515-20-victim187" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550515-20-victim187" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-20-off95 t17550515-20-victim187"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , the same being in a certain lodging-room lett by contract
            </rs>, &amp;c. <rs id="t17550515-20-cd96" type="crimeDate">Mar. 14</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-20-off95 t17550515-20-cd96"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550515-20-person188">
                  James 
                  Nickson 
               <interp inst="t17550515-20-person188" type="surname" value="Nickson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-20-person188" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-20-person188" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lived at the <placeName id="t17550515-20-crimeloc97">White-hart in White-hart-court, near Newtoner's-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17550515-20-crimeloc97" type="placeName" value="White-hart in White-hart-court, near Newtoner's-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550515-20-crimeloc97" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-20-off95 t17550515-20-crimeloc97"></join>; I lett the prisoner a ready-furnished lodging with the goods mentioned in the indictment. The prisoner locked the door, and took the key with him on the 14th of March, and I heard he was somewhere about Westminster. I looked through the key-hole of the door, last Sunday I found the bedstead was stripped; I took him at the Great Almonary in Westminster on the same day; I brought him home, we went into the room and missed all the goods mentioned in the indictment, and charged the constable with him, who took him before the justice, and he was committed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550515-20-person189">
                  William 
                  Masters 
               <interp inst="t17550515-20-person189" type="surname" value="Masters"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-20-person189" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-20-person189" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 14th of March I took in pawn a bed of the prisoner at the bar; the prisoner gave me authority to sell it at a month's end if he did not fetch it out before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you sell it?</p>
               <p>Masters. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. To who?</p>
               <p>Masters. To a broker, named Abraham, a Jew, he lives facing me.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Masters. I live in Cow-cross; about two or three days after he had brought the bed he brought a bolster and sheet to pawn, and on the 11th of March a tin kettle and a pair of bellows, I lent him a shilling on them.</p>

               <p>Q. Where are these other things?</p>
               <p>Masters. They are all sold, he gave me orders to sell them in a month's time if he did not fetch them; they were all in one bill.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. The bellows had a brand mark on them.</p>
               <p>Q. to Masters. Had the bellows the prisoner brought a brand mark on them?</p>
               <p>Masters. I can't swear to any brand mark on them; they were a pair of ordinary bellows.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any thing remarkable on the tin kettle ?</p>
               <p>Masters. No, there was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever a blanket or quilt of the prisoner ?</p>
               <p>Masters. I had not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550515-20-person190">
                  Isaac 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17550515-20-person190" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-20-person190" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-20-person190" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Sunday last when the prisoner came home with Mr. Nickson, he took the key out of his pocket, and went into the room, and we with him; he acknowledged talking the goods out of the room, but would not acknowledge what he had done with them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550515-20-person191">
                  Thomas 
                  Dann 
               <interp inst="t17550515-20-person191" type="surname" value="Dann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-20-person191" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-20-person191" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the constable; Mr. Nickson came to me last Sunday, and told me he had got a thief at his house; I went along with him, there I found the prisoner, he took the key and opened the room-door, we went in, there was nothing in the room but the bedstead and an old chair; the prisoner owned he had taken away all the goods, but would not say what he had done with them, he was committed. I privately went to him, and told him if he would let me know where they were pawned I would keep it a secret; then he told me he had pawned them to Masters; I went to Masters, he owned he had the bed and some other things, and that the prisoner had given him a bill of sale to sell them in a month or two, in case he did not pay the money.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I lost my left leg at the battle of Culloden, and am an out-pensioner of Chelsea-hospital; I had no pension to take on account of this new Act of Parliament about the usurers being broke this year, so I made use of the goods; I did think to have got them again, that he should not have been the worse for it.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550515-20-person192">
                  Thomas 
                  Turin 
               <interp inst="t17550515-20-person192" type="surname" value="Turin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-20-person192" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-20-person192" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about five years, he has worked for me four years in a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175505150016"></xptr> branch of the watch-business; I have trusted him to take and pay money for me, he never wronged me. I never heard any ill of his character.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17550515-20-verdict98" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550515-20-verdict98" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17550515-20-punish99" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550515-20-punish99" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-20-punish99" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-20-defend185 t17550515-20-punish99"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
