<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510911-43">
               <interp inst="t17510911-43" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510911-43" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510911-43" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510911-43" type="date" value="17510911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510911-43-off198-c258" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-43-defend342 t17510911-43-off198 t17510911-43-verdict202"></join>
         
               <p>516. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17510911-43-defend342" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Bedford 
                  <interp inst="t17510911-43-defend342" type="surname" value="Bedford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-43-defend342" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-43-defend342" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for that he, <rs id="t17510911-43-off198" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510911-43-off198" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-43-off198" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17510911-43-victim344" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Shepherd 
                        <interp inst="t17510911-43-victim344" type="surname" value="Shepherd"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510911-43-victim344" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510911-43-victim344" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-43-off198 t17510911-43-victim344"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear, &amp;c. and taking from his person one hat, value 5 s.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17510911-43-cd199" type="crimeDate">Aug. 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-43-off198 t17510911-43-cd199"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-43-person345">
                  John 
                  Shepherd 
               <interp inst="t17510911-43-person345" type="surname" value="Shepherd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-43-person345" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-43-person345" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 8th of August, between ten and eleven at night, going <placeName id="t17510911-43-crimeloc200">between the Horse<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175109110019"></xptr> guards and the Admiralty-office</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17510911-43-crimeloc200" type="placeName" value="between the Horse175109110019 guards and the Admiralty-office"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510911-43-crimeloc200" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-43-off198 t17510911-43-crimeloc200"></join>, the prisoner was walking along before me; he is a <rs id="t17510911-43-deflabel201" type="occupation">soldier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-43-defend342 t17510911-43-deflabel201"></join>, I knew him before: he stopped till I came even with him, and struck me a blow with his right hand on my forehead, and knocked me down. I then got up on my hands and knees, at which time he put his hand under my wig and hat; I took hold of my wig, and held it: he then hit me another blow, and knocked me down again, and took only my hat away; I got up again, and went towards him; he was standing about a yard distance from me, on the paved stones near the dead wall over the way, with his face towards mine. Then he held up a hanger, and I ran away : when I was got at some distance, I called him by his name, and told him I knew him. I went up to Charing-cross to get something to wash my face, for it was very much swelled, and dirty.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any lamp near?</p>
               <p>Shepherd. There was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you speak to him before he knocked you down ?</p>
               <p>Shepherd. No, I have not spoke a word to him these four months.</p>
               <p>Q. Had not you a quarrel with him?</p>
               <p>Shepherd. No, my Lord, I had not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he speak to you before he knocked you down?</p>
               <p>Shepherd. To the best of my knowledge, he never spoke a word.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any body near you?</p>
               <p>Shepherd. There was a man walked just before, and he walked Westminster way.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you fall backwards or forwards?</p>
               <p>Shepherd. The second time I fell with my face to the ground.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Shepherd. I am a working brazier.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-43-person346">
                  Sarah 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17510911-43-person346" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-43-person346" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-43-person346" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live servant with the prosecutor, he lives in Charles Court in the Strand: my mistress and I were standing at Charing Cross, and saw my master come back; he had been towards the Horse-guards, but I don't know for what.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>S. Wilson. I don't know how long it is ago, but I know it was between ten and eleven o'clock at night ; the left side of his face was cut.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a large wound?</p>
               <p>S. Wilson. It was not very large.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any dirt on his face?</p>
               <p>S. Wilson. No, there was not any.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever take an oath before?</p>
               <p>S. Wilson. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. What day of the week was this?</p>
               <p>S. Wilson. I cannot tell; when he came back, he said he was robbed, and his hat taken away by one Bedford, a soldier.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your master?</p>
               <p>S. Wilson. He is a milkman.</p>
               <p>Q. What was your master's business at Charing-cross at that time?</p>
               <p>S. Wilson. My master ordered us to stay there for him.</p>
               <p>S. Wilson. Were you in a house?</p>
               <p>S. Wilson. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any other company there?</p>
               <p>S. Wilson. There was another young woman standing there?</p>
               <p>Q. Did your master bleed much?</p>
               <p>S. Wilson. No, he did not; but probably he might bleed before he came to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Whereabouts was the wound?</p>
               <p>S. Wilson. It was just above his left eyebrow.</p>
               <p>Q. Were his hands dirty?</p>
               <p>S. Wilson. They were.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what was his business that way?</p>
               <p>S. Wilson. He had some business that way, and we went to fetch him home. my mistress said he was gone to the Cross-keys, to arrest a man that ow'd him some money. We went and found him there; but he went further afterwards and bid us stay there; saying he was going towards the Horse-guards.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had he been gone?</p>
               <p>S. Wilson. Not a quarter of an hour.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I had been at St. James's: coming from thence in company with 
               <persName id="t17510911-43-person347">
                  Mary 
                  Wilkerson 
               <interp inst="t17510911-43-person347" type="surname" value="Wilkerson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-43-person347" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-43-person347" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I saw a mob of people just by the Bagnio near Charing-cross; I went over the way, to see what was the master there. I saw this Shepherd had hold on one Lightfoot, a Brother-soldier, belonging to the Foot-guards; I knowing him, ask'd him what was the matter, that that person held him, in such a manner; and added, if a man held me so, and I was in no fault, I'd kick him up and down the street. 
               <persName id="t17510911-43-person348">
                  Mary 
                  Wilkerson 
               <interp inst="t17510911-43-person348" type="surname" value="Wilkerson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-43-person348" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-43-person348" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said to me, what business have you to embroil yourself with any body's quarrels? Come along about your business; may be you'll be charg'd your self, and you know you must be upon guard to morrow. I went away along with her, till I came down<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175109110020"></xptr> just facing the Admiraltry; then Lightfoot came running down by me, to go towards Westminster ; he cross'd the way, so said I, you are got off; he said yes, he was oblig'd to have a rowl and a tumble for it. We went to King-street; there we had a pint of beer; from thence we went to Charles-street; and from thence to Tuttle-street ; there we parted: Lightfoot went towards Petty-france; and I never turn'd back towards Charing-cross till six o'clock; then I went to my guard.</p>
               <p>Q. To S. Wilson, was it Lightfoot your master went to arrest?</p>
               <p>S. Wilson. It was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Had there been any discourse between your master and Lightfoot?</p>
               <p>S. Wilson. There had been a quarrel over the Haddock's Bagnio; betwixt my master, and another person ; I don't know who.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it with Bedford?</p>
               <p>S. Wilson. It was not.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-43-person349">
                  Robert 
                  Lightfoot 
               <interp inst="t17510911-43-person349" type="surname" value="Lightfoot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-43-person349" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-43-person349" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . As I was going along near Charing-cross this time there was a woman was very troublesome to me; I desir'd her to be quiet; she still kept jawing of me; I said if she did not get out of my way, I'd kick her out; I set my foot on her backside; then Shepherd came and took me by the collar, and said, you raschal how dare you assault my wife? said I, if she is your wife, you might have kept her closer to you; then came the prisoner by, and said, what do you do here? I told him, this man, says I, has used his wife ill, and said I, she stood amongst the rest of the whores; then Bedford said, was it him, he would not be held so; the prosecutor then said, your servant, Mr. Bedford, I know you; what you want to rescue him; Bedford went away; I made a shift to tumble the prosecutor down, and my hat was off in the scuffle; as soon as I got from him, I went towards the Admiralty Coffee-house, and passed the prisoner; he called out to me, and said, Lightfoot, are you got clear of him? I told him, I had: then we went to the Butcher's arms in King-street, and drank a pint of beer; he had neither sword, bayonet, nor stick. Then I went with him into Tothill-street, then the clock struck eleven. I live in Petty-france, am a soldier in the guards, and a house-keeper.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see this woman, Wilson?</p>
               <p>Lightfoot. No, I never saw her.</p>
               <p>Q. to the Prosecutor. Did you see this soldier, Lightfoot, that night?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. As I was coming from Charing-cross, he laid hold on my wife in a rude manner; my wife called him names, and he kicked her.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the skin broke on your face by Light-foot, or Bedford?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. It was by Bedford, Lightfoot never struck me.</p>
               <p>Q. to Lightfoot. Did you strike him?</p>
               <p>Lightfoot. I did not, my Lord, nor he me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-43-person350">
                  Mary 
                  Wilkerson 
               <interp inst="t17510911-43-person350" type="surname" value="Wilkerson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-43-person350" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-43-person350" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the eighth of August, about half an hour after ten at night, the prisoner and I were coming by Charing-cross, where there was a great croud, and a calling out watch; the prisoner went over the way, and said, Hay, Light-foot, is it you? What do you stand there for? said he, this man holds me, and I don't know what for; and I said to Bedford, you are to be upon guard to-morrow, don't meddle in any body's quarrels, you'll get to the Savoy for missing your guard, if you do not take care. Bedford said he would not be held by him, and the like; then he went away with me. Going along, Light-foot came running along full speed, and he passed us; Bedford said, I see you are got off; yes, said he, but I had a rowl and a tumble for it. Bedford went to my house in the Ambury. I wash his shirts for him. I went with him all the way, and had hold on his arm when Lightfoot came running. I never saw him speak to any body but Lightfoot.</p>
               <p>Q. Had Bedford any weapon?</p>
               <p>M. Wilkerson. He had neither stick, sword, nor bayonet.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510911-43-verdict202" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510911-43-verdict202" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The prosecutor was ordered into custody of the keeper of Newgate for perjury.</p>
            </div1>
