<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17500912-16">
               <interp inst="t17500912-16" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500912-16" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500912-16" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17500912"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500912-16" type="date" value="17500912"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500912-16-off76-c108" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-16-defend139 t17500912-16-off76 t17500912-16-verdict79"></join>
         
               <p>521. 
               
                  <persName id="t17500912-16-defend139" type="defendantName">
                     George 
                     Otterton 
                  <interp inst="t17500912-16-defend139" type="surname" value="Otterton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-16-defend139" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-16-defend139" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for that <rs id="t17500912-16-off76" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500912-16-off76" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-16-off76" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he, on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17500912-16-victim141" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Jenkins 
                        <interp inst="t17500912-16-victim141" type="surname" value="Jenkins"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500912-16-victim141" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500912-16-victim141" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-16-off76 t17500912-16-victim141"></join>
                     </persName>
                     
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, one coat for a child, value 2 s. and sixpence in money number'd, from his person did steal, take and carry away
            </rs>, <rs id="t17500912-16-cd77" type="crimeDate">August 26</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-16-off76 t17500912-16-cd77"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-16-person142">
                  Richard 
                  Jenkins 
               <interp inst="t17500912-16-person142" type="surname" value="Jenkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-16-person142" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-16-person142" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I work in London, my family live at Hounslow; I set out from London late on the 25th of August; the prisoner at the bar came up to me betwixt eleven and twelve o'clock, with his soldier's coat turn'd inside out; he said, he was going to take a deserter; this was betwixt the half way house and Kensington. We went in together at the Cock ale-house at Kensington and drank, then I went forward towards Hounslow, he went with me; I went cross <placeName id="t17500912-16-crimeloc78">Turnham-green, there is a lane leads from that green to Branford</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17500912-16-crimeloc78" type="placeName" value="Turnham-green, there is a lane leads from that green to Branford"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17500912-16-crimeloc78" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500912-16-off76 t17500912-16-crimeloc78"></join>, in that lane he made an attack upon me sword in hand, he clapt it to my throat and collar'd me, and demanded my money; I said I had got no more than the change. I had out of a shilling at Kensington, when I paid<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175009120008"></xptr> for a pint of beer. I collar'd him, and we were down in a dry ditch together; we got up again, then I cry'd out thieves, murder, &amp;c. at this time I judg'd it to be between twelve and one o'clock. I was down again, he throatled me, and said if I spoke a word he would murder me outright. I put my hand in my pocket when he was upon me and got my knife; I thought I had done his business for him, I stuck him in two or three places of his body. We got up, he got me down once more; we got up again, then said he to me, you have murder'd me; said I, I believe I have. Said he, notwithstanding I insist upon your money, then I held a sixpence to him and he took it; in the scussle the child's coat that I had on my arm was lying in the middle of the lane, he took that also; he went for London, and I on to Hounslow. I imagined he would drop by the way with the wounds he received, and reported what had happen'd. I returned in the evening, and call'd upon his comrade, where we had drank together at Kensington, he told me the prisoner would be upon guard next morning at ten o'clock, but I found my instructions were false. I went to Captain Salter's and left word what had happen'd, and that the soldier who had attack'd me was dangerously wounded. He took pains to over-hale his men to see who was wounded; it being blown abroad the prisoner was taken; the other witness can give a farther account.</p>
               <p>Richard Nixon. I am Serjeant of the first regiment of guards; about the 27th of last month the prisoner at the bar declar'd he had been in pursuit of a deserter, and had been wounded in two parts of his body; the prosecutor coming and making complaint to the Adjutant of the regiment, and describing the parts of the body he had wounded the soldier in who had robb'd him; the Adjutant sent for me, and said such a man had been wounded, meaning the prisoner, and ordered me to put him in the Savoy. I met with him about ten o'clock at night, I think the 28th of last month. I told him he was charg'd with a highway robbery; he said, he had been wounded in a scuffle with a deserter. I put him into the Savoy, the next morning I took the prosecutor with me, he said the prisoner was the very man. This coat was brought by another soldier before the justice. The prosecutor swore to it as his property, which the prisoner took from him.</p>
               <p>Q. to the prosecutor. Where did you wound the person you say robb'd you?</p>
               <p>Jenkins. About the breast, I believe, in two or three places.</p>
               <p>Nixon. He had a scratch with something like a pin near his right breast, I examined him no farther.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500912-16-person143">
                  John 
                  Hopkins 
               <interp inst="t17500912-16-person143" type="surname" value="Hopkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-16-person143" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500912-16-person143" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prosecutor is a lodger of mine, he told me when he return'd on Sunday night just the same he has now. I went along with him to find out the prisoner, and before the justice I saw two or three little cuts on the prisoner's breast, as large as a knife might be imagined to cut. The little coat is the prosecutor's property.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I drank a pint of beer with that man; we walk'd very lovingly on together till he call'd me thief-taker, to go to take away a man's life for 20 s. as I was going to take a deserter; said I, it is doing the king's duty; he pull'd out his knife and stuck me, than he ran away as fast as he could, and I return'd back to London.</p>
               <p>Nixon, and four other persons, gave the prisoner a good character.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500912-16-verdict79" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500912-16-verdict79" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
