<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17501017-3">
               <interp inst="t17501017-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501017-3" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501017-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17501017"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501017-3" type="date" value="17501017"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17501017-3-off11-c42" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-3-defend48 t17501017-3-off11 t17501017-3-verdict14"></join>
         
               <p>620. 
               
                  <persName id="t17501017-3-defend48" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Price 
                  <interp inst="t17501017-3-defend48" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-3-defend48" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-3-defend48" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17501017-3-off11" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501017-3-off11" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-3-off11" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing a brown gelding, value 10 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17501017-3-victim50" type="victimName">
                     Lewis 
                     Demock 
                  <interp inst="t17501017-3-victim50" type="surname" value="Demock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-3-victim50" type="given" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-3-victim50" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-3-off11 t17501017-3-victim50"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17501017-3-cd12" type="crimeDate">February 11</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-3-off11 t17501017-3-cd12"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501017-3-person51">
                  Lewis 
                  Demock 
               <interp inst="t17501017-3-person51" type="surname" value="Demock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-3-person51" type="given" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-3-person51" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in London. I had a horse of a brown colour, about 14 hands and an inch, at grass at Mr. Glasby's, the <placeName id="t17501017-3-crimeloc13">Rosemary Branch, Islington</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17501017-3-crimeloc13" type="placeName" value="Rosemary Branch, Islington"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17501017-3-crimeloc13" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-3-off11 t17501017-3-crimeloc13"></join>; he was missing some time; I believe in February he was found again, and brought to me; that is all I know of it.</p>
               <p>Mr. Glasby. I live at the Rosemary Branch, Islington. This horse was at grass with me; I had him between six and seven months; he was taken out of my ground either the 10th or 11th of February last; he was in the field the 10th at night; we saw a great deal of corn scattered about, which, we supposed, was to catch him; he was hard to be catched.</p>
               <p>Q. Whhat colour was he?</p>
               <p>Glasby. He was of a mouse-brown colour, about 14 hands and an inch, or rather better; comes five years old.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he a horse, or a gelding?</p>
               <p>Glasby. A gelding; he is in the ground now.</p>
               <p>Q. Why do you charge the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Glasby. I never saw the prisoner before I saw him at the justice's house; he there owned he sold the horse to Mr. Punnet. There was a man came to me about five or six days after the horse was missing, and asked me, if I had lost such a horse, saying, there was such a one offered to sale at the Blue Bell, near Rochester. I went, and found this horse was sold to one Mr. Punnet, an attorney at law, at Maidstone; and that he had bought him of the prisoner at the bar for seven guineas.</p>
               <p>Mr. Punnet. I bought a horse of the prisoner at the bar [he answers to the description before given] for seven guineas; the prisoner was to call on me again; and, if I liked him, I was to give him another guinea.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner before ?</p>
               <p>Punnet. I had heard of his name before, and saw him before; he offered me a horse once before this; he is a Welchman, and used to travel that way with bullocks; and, before this, bore a very good character.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you buy him?</p>
               <p>Punnet. On the 17th of February, my lord; and on the 24th Mr. Glasby came to me, to demand the horse, saying, he was informed I had bought such a horse, and desired to see him. He swore, before the mayor of Rochester, the horse was his property, and also he had been his six months before. But this seems to me to be a mistake, not done with any design; it appears this horse is Mr. Demock's property.</p>
               <p>Q. to Glasby. Is this the horse you say is Mr. Demock's property ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175010170004"></xptr>Glasby. It is, my lord; I brought him to Mr. Demock, at his own door, and he is in my ground now.</p>
               <p>Q. to Demock, Was that your horse Mr. Glasby brought to your door?</p>
               <p>Demock. It was, my lord.</p>
               <p>Q. to Glasby. How came you to swear this horse was yours ?</p>
               <p>Glasby. I did not read the affidavit when it was brought to me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence. I paid 7 l. 4 s. for this horse.</p>
               <p>To his Character:</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501017-3-person52">
                  Richard 
                  Ribalt 
               <interp inst="t17501017-3-person52" type="surname" value="Ribalt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-3-person52" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-3-person52" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an inn-keeper. I have known the prisoner about ten years, he has used my house, coming with Welch cattle backwards and forwards into Kent. His brother is a drover, and this man used to come with him; he and his brother have dealt in horses; they used to bring them up with their beasts often. I never knew, or heard to the contrary, but the prisoner was an honest man before this.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17501017-3-verdict14" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501017-3-verdict14" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17501017-3-punish15" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501017-3-punish15" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-3-defend48 t17501017-3-punish15"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
