<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17550116-12">
               <interp inst="t17550116-12" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550116-12" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550116-12" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550116-12" type="date" value="17550116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550116-12-off60-c122" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-12-defend143 t17550116-12-off60 t17550116-12-verdict65"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550116-12-off62-c124" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-12-defend147 t17550116-12-off62 t17550116-12-verdict67"></join>
         
               <p>60. (M. 2.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17550116-12-defend143" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Gill 
                  <interp inst="t17550116-12-defend143" type="surname" value="Gill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-12-defend143" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-12-defend143" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             was a second time indicted, for <rs id="t17550116-12-off60" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550116-12-off60" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-12-off60" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he together with Burk, on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17550116-12-victim145" type="victimName">
                           Charles 
                           Johnson 
                        <interp inst="t17550116-12-victim145" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550116-12-victim145" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550116-12-victim145" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and taking from his person one pair of silver shoe-buckles, value 7 s. 6 d. one pair of silver knee-buckles, one pair of studs, one hat, one handkerchief, one guinea and three-pence in money
            </rs>, <rs id="t17550116-12-cd61" type="crimeDate">Dec. 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-12-off60 t17550116-12-cd61"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-12-off62 t17550116-12-cd61"></join>. and 
               
                  <persName id="t17550116-12-defend147" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Mayo 
                  <interp inst="t17550116-12-defend147" type="surname" value="Mayo"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-12-defend147" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-12-defend147" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , for <rs id="t17550116-12-off62" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550116-12-off62" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-12-off62" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving the said shoe-buckles, well knowing them to have been stolen
            </rs>, <rs id="t17550116-12-cd63" type="crimeDate">Jan. 6</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-12-off60 t17550116-12-cd63"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-12-off62 t17550116-12-cd63"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-12-person148">
                  Charles 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17550116-12-person148" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-12-person148" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-12-person148" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 10th of last month, about eight at night, I was coming over the new road, leading to Mile-end that is cut through the mount, I saw two men before me; I was going to <placeName id="t17550116-12-crimeloc64">Mile-end-green</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17550116-12-crimeloc64" type="placeName" value="Mile-end-green"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550116-12-crimeloc64" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-12-off60 t17550116-12-crimeloc64"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-12-off62 t17550116-12-crimeloc64"></join>. I went on pretty fast; when I came up with them, which was about twothirds on the road, they called out, stand and deliver. I stood still, and said, search me, search me. It was a fine night, the moon was a quarter old. The m en were Gill the prisoner, and Burk. Gill gave his pistol to Burk, and felt in my breeches pocket, and took two-pence halfpenny and two farthings out, then he took out of my buckles out of my shoes, after that my knee-buckles; then he took off my shoes, and there I had put a guinea for safety, which he took out of my right shoe. Then he said, now, you dog, you shall walk home without shoes. No, no, said the other, give him his shoes. The other saw a handkerchief in my pocket, he took that, and said he wanted a handkerchief to wipe his nose with, and he put it to his nose, and then into his pocket. I said to them several times, gentlemen, I hope you will not use me ill. No, no, they said, we are none of your knockers-down. Then they took me about an hundred yards upon the soil-field, where they took a pair of silver buttons out of my sleeves, and took my hat, and gave me an old slapt one. Then I walked about half way up the field, and said, gentlemen, I shall be obliged to you if you will give me my hat. They said, No, no; go along. They said several times, don't look in our faces; and one said to the other, don't let him look at your face; but walking with them down in the field, I got a good view of their faces. My hat was brought to justice Fielding's when Gill was examined, said to be taken off of Burk's head, and the buckles were found in his pocket. (Produced in court.) These are the buckles they took from me that night; here is my name on them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-12-person149">
                  William 
                  Nordon 
               <interp inst="t17550116-12-person149" type="surname" value="Nordon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-12-person149" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-12-person149" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the Sunday after we had apprehended Burk and Gill, I went to see Burk<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175501160012"></xptr> in the roundhouse, and had a good deal of talk with him. I said, I was very sorry he had not surrendered sooner, and not have suffered himself to be cut and used so. He said he had an English heart in his belly, and that no highwayman will surrender without a blow. I said, all the service you can do for your country is, to let the poor people you have robbed have their things again. Said he, I wish justice Fielding would come here, I would tell him a great deal. I told Mr. Fielding, and he went to him; I was there also. Burk there said, Mayo had got a pair of buckles and they watches; and that Gill and he robbed one gentleman in the Chelsea stage-coach of one watch, and the other they took from a lady in St. George's fields; and a pair of silver buckles we robbed a man of in the new road near Whitechapel-mount; and on Monday Mayo was taken up, and before the justice he produced these buckles the prosecutor has sworn to; and this watch ( producing one) that he said they took from a lady in St. George's-fields.</p>
               <p>Gill. That watch belongs to that lady ( pointing to a lady that had before said she had been robbed of it, before the justice, and to whom it was delivered.)</p>
               <p>W. Nordon. He produced a paper, he said was of Mapo's hand writing, but it was very badly wrote; it was something about borrowing money on a watch; I know it was signed Gill Burk is so very bad with his wounds he received, that he could not be removed to take his trial.</p>

               <p>Gill's defence.</p>
               <p>All I have to say is, I know nothing of the man (meaning Mayo) but what is honest. I came into his house, and had no money to pay him for what liquor I had, so I gave him my watch and things, and gave him from under my hand that he should keep them till I could get the money to redeem them.</p>
               <p>Mayo's defence.</p>
               <p>Gill and Buck ran a reckoning before I would take the things, and when I did, I would not do it without a writing from under Gill's hand.</p>
               <p>For Mayo.</p>
               <p>WilliamLong. About a week ago, Gill and Burk came into my house, the Coach-and-horses in Swan yard, near the Strand; they ran a reckoning of about half a guinea; Gill asked me what was to pay? I told him. He said he had not money enough about him to pay; but he would leave a pledge. I went into the stable, to inform my father-in-law, the prisoner, Mr. Mayo, of it. He came into the house to them, and told them, they ought to have offered their pledge before they had ran their reckoning. They pressed upon him, and rather than I should lose my reckoning, he lent them some money on the watch. They said they belonged to a ship called the Foy, that was going to be paid off, then they would redeem it. My father lent them a guinea and half-upon it, and allowed the half-guinea for the reckoning. As to the buckles, about two days after, Burk came, and a woman along with him, in the afternoon, into our tap-room; he called for a pint of hot; I believe they staid about two hours and a half; they ran to about the tune of two shillings. Burk called, and asked what was to pay? I said, betwixt two and three shillings: Said he, I have no money; but I'll leave my buckles. He stooped down to his shoes, and took them out. I went and called my father-in-law, and told him Burk had no money; but wanted to pawn his shoe-buckles. My father came in, and said, Mr. Burk, how is this? He said, his ship was at Black-wall, and would be paid in two or three days; and said, if you will lead me some more money on them, I'll pay you in that time: upon which he lent him ten shillings, or ten and six-pence, I don't know which. He would not have lent him a farthing upon these things, had it not been that I should not lose my reckoning.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-12-person150">
                  Lucy 
                  Roberts 
               <interp inst="t17550116-12-person150" type="surname" value="Roberts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-12-person150" type="given" value="Lucy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-12-person150" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I happened to go to Mr. Long's house, there was a man and a woman sat drinking in the taphouse.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>L. Roberts. It was about a week before Christmas, to the best of my knowledge, I sat there the drinking of half a pint of hot wine, I can't say but I heard some dispute about the reckoning; the man said he would leave a pair of silver buckles with Mr. Long; Mr. Long said he would not take them, and called his father, then the man took the buckles of his shoes and gave them to Mr. Mayo, and he lent him about ten shillings upon them to the best of my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Mr. West. I have seen the paper they talk of, it was a conditional note given for the payment of two guineas, but he was to redeem the watch in two days, if not, it was to be forfeited.</p>
               <p>Gill <rs id="t17550116-12-verdict65" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550116-12-verdict65" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17550116-12-punish66" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550116-12-punish66" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-12-defend143 t17550116-12-punish66"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Mayo <rs id="t17550116-12-verdict67" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550116-12-verdict67" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>See Mayo tried before, No. 490, in Alderman Blackford's mayoralty.</p>
            </div1>
