<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17511016-24">
               <interp inst="t17511016-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511016-24" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511016-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17511016"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511016-24" type="date" value="17511016"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17511016-24-off116-c167" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-24-defend210 t17511016-24-off116 t17511016-24-verdict120"></join>
         
               <p>571. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17511016-24-defend210" type="defendantName">
                  Elizabeth 
                  <rs id="t17511016-24-deflabel115" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-24-defend210 t17511016-24-deflabel115"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17511016-24-person211">
                        Francis 
                        Medows 
                     <interp inst="t17511016-24-person211" type="surname" value="Medows"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17511016-24-person211" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17511016-24-person211" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17511016-24-alias-4" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-24-defend210 t17511016-24-alias-4"></join>Wills</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-24-defend210" type="surname" value="Medows"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-24-defend210" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-24-defend210" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17511016-24-off116" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17511016-24-off116" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-24-off116" type="offenceSubcategory" value="shoplifting"></interp>
               stealing four yards and three quarters of lawn, value 20 s. 26 yards of printed cotton, value 3 l. the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17511016-24-victim213" type="victimName">
                           Edward 
                           Eyres 
                        <interp inst="t17511016-24-victim213" type="surname" value="Eyres"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17511016-24-victim213" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17511016-24-victim213" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-24-off116 t17511016-24-victim213"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the shop of the said Edward
            </rs>, <rs id="t17511016-24-cd117" type="crimeDate">September 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-24-off116 t17511016-24-cd117"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-24-person214">
                  Edward 
                  Eyres 
               <interp inst="t17511016-24-person214" type="surname" value="Eyres"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-24-person214" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-24-person214" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17511016-24-crimeloc118">York-street, Covent-Garden</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17511016-24-crimeloc118" type="placeName" value="York-street, Covent-Garden"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17511016-24-crimeloc118" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-24-off116 t17511016-24-crimeloc118"></join>, and am a <rs id="t17511016-24-viclabel119" type="occupation">linen draper</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-24-victim213 t17511016-24-viclabel119"></join>. On the 21st of last month I had been into the city; upon my return I found the prisoner in the shop looking at some lawn. As I passed by her, I heard one of my servants tell her, he was surprized she should offer him less than half the value of it. I took notice of her, and apprehended, by her appearance, she could not have occasion for such a thing; and, by her offering so low a price, I thought she could not come to buy, but to steal. This made me determine to watch her; but I had occasion to leave the shop for four or five minutes; and at my return again, I saw between her and the compter, as she was fitting, something that seemed considerable bulky; she was putting it under her petticoats. As soon as she saw me drawing nearer, she lifted up the right side of her gown next me, and covered it. When I came up to her, I could not see what she had got; but upon my passing behind her, and going on the other side, I saw part of a piece of printed cotton; about eight inches of the selvidge lay upon the floor uncovered at her left side, the rest of it was under her petticoats; the piece was folded. I went behind the compter, and looked at her again. I took a book and laid it before me, and with a pen made believe I was<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175110160015"></xptr> writing. At the same time I observed she kept drawing it up under her petticoats. After I was sensible she had drawn the greatest part of it up, I went forwards and spoke to three or four people of mine near the door, and ordered them not to go backwards to prevent what I thought was going forward, and if she took the piece of cotton away they should follow her and bring her back again. Soon after, she came forward, and went out into the street; as she was going out, I saw part of the cotton hang down below her coats. When she was gone 20 or 30 yards, I sent two of my people, Mr. Maycomb and Mr. Boston, who brought her back. They carried her backwards; a mob gathered about the door; I stood there; she dropped the piece of cotton as she stood; I sent for a constable; he searched her; and, in my presence, he found a remnant of lawn upon her, my property, under her petticoats; both produced in court and deposed to</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-24-person215">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Mills 
               <interp inst="t17511016-24-person215" type="surname" value="Mills"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-24-person215" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-24-person215" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live servant with Mr. Eyres; the prisoner has used our shop for six months; she came to look at some lawns on Saturday the 21st of September; I shewed her some; she bought a yard and paid for it, at 6 s. per yard. After that she went out of the shop; I did not see her take the lawn or printed cotton; he looked on the piece of cotton and lawn. These are Mr. Eyres's property; the cotton is worth 3 l. the lawn 10 s. and more. The piece of cotton came from the printer's that morning, and was lying on the compter when she came in.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-24-person216">
                  Henry 
                  Boston 
               <interp inst="t17511016-24-person216" type="surname" value="Boston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-24-person216" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-24-person216" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant with Mr. Eyres. The first time I remember seeing the prisoner was Saturday September 21. I had been out of the shop some little time; when I came in again, Mr. Eyres told me the woman had taken some cotton. After that she came forward; I saw something hang down, it dragged the ground, as Mr. Eyres had described. Then she went out of the shop; so he ordered me and Mr. Maycomb to follow her, and bring her back. We went after her, and took her before she had got far; we brought her back, and placed her in the middle of the shop, I on one side of her and Mr. Maycomb on the other ; he stooped down and picked up the piece of cotton which she let fall to the ground.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see it fall?</p>
               <p>Boston. I did not; but when we brought her into the shop, there was nothing lying upon the ground. I wrote the initial letter of my name, and the initial and final letters of my surname upon the cotton. After that, she complained she was not well, and sat down upon a stool; then the constable came and searched her; I saw him take the piece of lawn from her, on which I wrote my name with a black pencil; it is hardly to be read now, but I am positive it is the same. Then she was committed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-24-person217">
                  William 
                  Newcomb 
               <interp inst="t17511016-24-person217" type="surname" value="Newcomb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-24-person217" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-24-person217" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mr. Eyres. I remember the prisoner coming to our shop a number of times on the 21st of September; I saw this piece of cotton hang down below her clothes when she was buying the lawn.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did not you speak to her then?</p>
               <p>Maycomb. We let her go out of the shop in order to take her. After she bought the lawn she went out of the shop, and we followed her; she had not gone above 20 yards before we apprehended her, brought her back, and placed her in the middle of the shop, where she let the piece of cotton fall from under her petticoat; I took it up and wrote my name upon it; it is Mr. Eyres's cotton; it came that forenoon from the printer, I asked the prisoner how she could do so; she seemed much affrighted, and desired a glass of water, and to sit down. The constable searched her; I saw him pull the lawn from under her gown or petticoat; it is my master's lawn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-24-person218">
                  Thomas 
                  Burton 
               <interp inst="t17511016-24-person218" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-24-person218" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-24-person218" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable. On the 21st of September, about six o'clock in the evening, I was sent for to Mr. Eyres's. The prisoner was sitting upon a stool, complaining she was very ill; she had no mind to get from the stool; I lifted her up, and felt something soft tucked under her stays behind ; I put my hand up under a petticoat or two, I cannot say which, and there found this piece of lawn; I wrote my name upon it; here it is.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I never had sight of the cotton till I saw it in the gentleman's hand.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17511016-24-verdict120" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17511016-24-verdict120" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17511016-24-punish121" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17511016-24-punish121" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-24-punish121" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="respitedForPregnancy"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-24-defend210 t17511016-24-punish121"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>See Number 125.</p>
            </div1>
