<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17540717-23">
               <interp inst="t17540717-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540717-23" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540717-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540717"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540717-23" type="date" value="17540717"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540717-23-off111-c188" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-23-defend234 t17540717-23-off111 t17540717-23-verdict114"></join>
         
               <p>369. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17540717-23-defend234" type="defendantName">
                  Elizabeth 
                  <rs id="t17540717-23-deflabel110" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-23-defend234 t17540717-23-deflabel110"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17540717-23-person235">
                        Charles 
                        Jones 
                     <interp inst="t17540717-23-person235" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540717-23-person235" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540717-23-person235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
                     <interp inst="t17540717-23-defend234" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-23-defend234" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-23-defend234" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17540717-23-off111" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540717-23-off111" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-23-off111" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch, with 2 seals to the same, value 3 l. 20 guineas and 2 shillings in money, the goods and money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17540717-23-victim237" type="victimName">
                           Willis 
                           Farrows 
                        <interp inst="t17540717-23-victim237" type="surname" value="Farrows"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540717-23-victim237" type="given" value="Willis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540717-23-victim237" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-23-off111 t17540717-23-victim237"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  . in the dwelling house
            </rs> of Michael Carrey, <rs id="t17540717-23-cd112" type="crimeDate">June 6</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-23-off111 t17540717-23-cd112"></join> || .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-23-person238">
                  Willis 
                  Farrows 
               <interp inst="t17540717-23-person238" type="surname" value="Farrows"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-23-person238" type="given" value="Willis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-23-person238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had been at the other end of the town with some friends drinking plentifully; the prisoner picked me up in the street, under pretence to see me safe home, and had me first to the Crown in Bread-Street, and made me more in liquor, then she took me to the house of 
               <persName id="t17540717-23-person239">
                  Michael 
                  Cartey 
               <interp inst="t17540717-23-person239" type="surname" value="Cartey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-23-person239" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-23-person239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in <placeName id="t17540717-23-crimeloc113">Parker's-Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17540717-23-crimeloc113" type="placeName" value="Parker's-Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17540717-23-crimeloc113" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-23-off111 t17540717-23-crimeloc113"></join>, there I lay down on the bed with my breeches off, and when I awak'd my watch and money was gone, and so was she.</p>
               <p>Q. What is this house in Parker's Lane, a publick house?</p>
               <p>Farrows. No, my Lord, it is a private lodging house.</p>
               <p>Q. What reason have you to suspect the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Farrows. Because the watch and some money were found upon her.</p>
               <p>Q. from the prisoner. Did not you give them to me?</p>
               <p>Farrows. No, I did not, under no pretence whatsoever ?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-23-person240">
                  Thomas 
                  James 
               <interp inst="t17540717-23-person240" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-23-person240" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-23-person240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I think it was on Monday the 6th of June the prisoner came casually to my shop to buy a pair of shoes: she was in a sad deplorable dress; I told her I believed she had no occasion for shoes, and desired her to go out of my shop. She did, but returned again, and sat down in a chair, and said she had money enough to pay for a pair of shoes, and pull'd out a guinea. I sold her a pair of shoes and gave her change out of a guinea. After that she enquired where she could get some new clothes, and pull'd out a guinea or two more; I said there were clothes enough in the neighbourhood, and a person by my direction brought some clothes to my shop door, she bought a gown and several things. Then she enquired where she could have a lodging to lodge safe; I said you seem to be full of money, I am afraid you have committed something bad; she said, De'el took me if I have, it is a good mons moony, it is my own husbands, then she went away. The next morning I had some business in Cavendish-Square, and when I came back there was the prisoner in my shop again; I asked her what was her business, she said, I was a muckle mon, and she heard I was a constable, and she was come to give me a glass of beer, because she had heard she had been saucy to me the day before, and that I had been so good to her as not to took her to the watch-house. I bid her go about her business, or I'd turn her out; then she said I will gang no farther till I treate you. Then she put her hand in her bosom, and there I saw 2 seals hang out, then I said I am afraid you have done some bad action, for I see you have got a watch there, pray what o'clock is it? She said you have got a watch of your own I courted her a good deal to see it, but she would not let me have it; at last I took hold of it and saw the name upon it; then I said you must give me some farther account before you go any farther; she said it was her husband's, and that he was a perriwig-maker in Brewer-Street at the Coach and Horses; I left her in the custody of my apprentice, and went there to enquire whether such a person did live there. When I came there, I found her sister lived there, but the prisoner did not. Then I came back, and went to justice Bedwell with her; he ordered me to search her, I did, and found 38 shillings and 6 l. in silver in a paper, and 11 guineas and an half n gold, in her bosom; then she was committed. ( The watch and money produced in court.)</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. This watch and seals are my property which I lost that night I was with the prisoner: the money I will not pretend to swear to.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175407170016"></xptr>James. She told me in the coach going along that she picked up a man in Broad-street by Carnaby-Market, and they agreed to go down to her lodgings in Parker's Lane, there they drank together, after that she helped him off with his breeches, and they lay down on the bed together. After that she took his breeches and took out of them 20 golden guineas and some silver, but did not say what quantity of silver, and the watch, and then went away and left him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-23-person241">
                  John 
                  Topham 
               <interp inst="t17540717-23-person241" type="surname" value="Topham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-23-person241" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-23-person241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 8th of June last I happened to be at justice Fielding's, the prisoner was then present, I asked the prisoner how she came to do such a rash action as to take the gentleman's money; she said she took the gentleman's watch and money to keep till he was sober; I asked her why she did not return them, she said she went out and came no more back to the house in Parker's-Lane.</p>
               <p>Q. to James. You say you went before Mr. Bedwell, the last witness talks of being at Justice Fielding's?</p>
               <p>James. Mr. Bedwell was at Justice Fielding's office, they were both together.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she mention the house where she took the watch and money?</p>
               <p>James. She said it was in Mr. Cartey's house in Parker's-Lane, I have been at the house since to search for more money that she says she hid there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-23-person242">
                  Ann 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17540717-23-person242" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-23-person242" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-23-person242" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lived in Cartey's house in Parker's-Lane, up one pair of stairs forwards, she and her husband came and took that lower room on the Tuesday before she did this robbery. My child and I were sitting on the cill of the door when the gentleman and she came in, I said to my child get up and let Mr. Jones and his wife come in, after that she called for me to go and fetch a pot of beer, and said her husband would not go to sleep without it (meaning the gentleman) and came into the entry to me and gave me six-pence to pay for it, I went and fetched it, and gave her the change.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing about taking the things?</p>
               <p>A. Carter. I do not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I had been into the city receiving some money from Edinburgh, as I was coming home I met with this man at the Crown on the top of Broad-street by Golden-Square, he was in liquor, and worried me to drink there; then we went into another house and chang'd a guinea, and paid for a bit of salmon and a pot of beer; after this we came as far as Parker's-Lane, he said he'd have some beer, and got this woman to fetch some; he desir'd I'd take care of his clothes and watch for him. I sat down, he laid down his breeches, after I had help'd to pull them off; I went to see what was become of my child, and when I came back he was gone, and my door padlock'd. Then I went and bought a pair of shoes, and said at that house I wanted other things, the man's wife went and brought in a smock, 2 petticoats and a gown, I bought them. Then because the door was padlock'd he said he'd take me to a very good lodging; he took me to one, I stay'd all night there, but never spent a farthing of the money. I came back to his house again, his wife was washing, then the thief catchers came in, and they have kept all the things I bought.</p>
               <p>James. As she bought these things out of that money I thought proper to detain them for him.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. She says you gave her these things in order for her to keep for you.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I am pretty sure I never gave them to her at all, but believe she did assist me in pulling my breeches off.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540717-23-verdict114" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540717-23-verdict114" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17540717-23-punish115" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540717-23-punish115" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-23-defend234 t17540717-23-punish115"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
