<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17550515-25">
               <interp inst="t17550515-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550515-25" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550515-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550515"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550515-25" type="date" value="17550515"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550515-25-off117-c178" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-25-defend225 t17550515-25-off117 t17550515-25-verdict120"></join>
         
               <p>232. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17550515-25-defend225" type="defendantName">
                     Anne 
                     Goadby 
                  <interp inst="t17550515-25-defend225" type="surname" value="Goadby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-25-defend225" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-25-defend225" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17550515-25-deflabel116" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-25-defend225 t17550515-25-deflabel116"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17550515-25-off117" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550515-25-off117" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-25-off117" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one silk gown, value 6 s. one linen shift, value 2 s. two linen aprons, value 2 s. one lawn apron, and one flanel cloak
            </rs>, the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17550515-25-victim227" type="victimName">
                     George 
                     Colebourne 
                  <interp inst="t17550515-25-victim227" type="surname" value="Colebourne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-25-victim227" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-25-victim227" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-25-off117 t17550515-25-victim227"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17550515-25-cd118" type="crimeDate">April 14</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-25-off117 t17550515-25-cd118"></join>. +</p>
               <p>Isabella Colebourne. My husband's name is George, the goods mentioned in the indictment I lost, but can't say when. I know I had the gown and shift on the 13th of April, but I did not miss them till I missed them all on the 1st of May.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you found any of them again?</p>
               <p>I. Colebourne. I found the gown, shift, and one apron at Mrs. Enderson's; but never found the rest of the things.</p>
         
               <p>The Second Part of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17550515-25">
                  <interp inst="t17550515-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550515-25" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550515-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550515"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550515-25" type="date" value="17550515"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175505150021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Thursday the 15th, Friday the 16th, and Saturday the 17th of MAY.</p>
                  <p>In the Twenty-eighth Year of His MAJESTY'S Reign. NUMBER V. PART II. for the YEAR 1755. Being the Fifth SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of THE RIGHT HONOURABLE 
                  <persName id="t17550515-25-person228">
                     STEPHEN THEODORE 
                     JANSSEN 
                  <interp inst="t17550515-25-person228" type="surname" value="JANSSEN"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550515-25-person228" type="given" value="STEPHEN THEODORE"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550515-25-person228" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Esq; LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON. LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by M. COOPER at the Globe, in Pater-noster Row. 1755.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175505150022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery held for the City of LONDON, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Q. WHAT is your reason for charging the prisoner at the bar?</p>
               <p>I. Colebourne. The prisoner was <rs id="t17550515-25-deflabel119" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550515-25-defend225 t17550515-25-deflabel119"></join> to me in the house; when I missed them she went away, and when I went to her where she lived, she ran away. I went home, suspecting something ill by that, and missed the things. Then I went after her, and she ran away again. She was then taken before Sir 
               <persName id="t17550515-25-person229">
                  Samuel 
                  Gore 
               <interp inst="t17550515-25-person229" type="surname" value="Gore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-25-person229" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-25-person229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , where she owned she had taken the things, and after that she wanted to deny it.</p>
               <p>Q. In what manner did she say she took them?</p>
               <p>I. Colebourne. Sir Samuel asked her if she did take the things? She said she did take them to be sure; then he said, that was justif ication enough.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he mean by that expression?</p>
               <p>I. Colebourne. He meant it was justification enough for him to commit her. After that, she said she might take them when they were given to her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say who gave them to her?</p>
               <p>I. Colebourne. She said I gave them to her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she make use of the word I took them, or I stole them?</p>
               <p>I. Colebourne. She did not say she stole them.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath, did you, or did you not, give her them?</p>
               <p>I. Colebourne. Upon my oath I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Not to pawn?</p>
               <p>I. Colebourne. No, not to pawn; I had no occasion for that.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does Mrs. Enderson live?</p>
               <p>I. Colebourne. She lives in Nightingale-lane.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner go away privately?</p>
               <p>I. Colebourne. I gave her no leave to go; she went without my knowledge; I thought she was coming to work, as usual.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550515-25-person230">
                  Jane 
                  Enderson 
               <interp inst="t17550515-25-person230" type="surname" value="Enderson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-25-person230" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-25-person230" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner brought a gown the 21st of April to me to pawn. I said this gown looks as if it did not belong to you, and asked her whose it was? She said it belonged to her mistress where she worked. I asked her her mistress's name? She told me she made mantuas, and lived in Church-yard-alley, near the Whitehart. I said, I hope what you have said is true. She said, if I pleased to send a servant, I might know it was true. I asked her what she wanted upon it? She said eight shillings. I said I would not lend above six. She said she would go and ask whether she might take it. She went away, and came again, and said she was to take it; so I let her have it, and she went away.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutrix. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. I live in Church-yard-alley.</p>
               <p>Q. How near the White-hart?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. I live facing it.</p>
               <p>Q. to Enderson. Was the prisoner gone long enough from your shop (when she said she would go and ask whether she might take the six shillings) to go so far as the prosecutrix's house?</p>
               <p>J. Enderson. No, she was not gone long enough; I then supposed she spoke to somebody in the street.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her speak to any body?</p>
               <p>J. Enderson. No, I did not. She came on the Friday following with a shift, and said to me, you seemed to be afraid when I came with the gown, that I did not come honestly by it, this belongs to the same person. She said her mistress used the Lane, she asked two shillings on it, saying, she wanted some money to buy things.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she mean by the Lane?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175505150023"></xptr>J. Enderson. Rosemery-Lane. I lent her two shillings; and in the afternoon she came with an apron, and had ten-pence on that. I never saw her again till the Monday following.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. When did Isabella Colebourne come to ask for the things?</p>

               <p>J. Enderson. She came on the Thursday following, and told me I had a gown of hers, and described it, and also told me it was left in a napkin; I readily went and took it down and shewed it her; she told me also I had a shift of hers, and I must know it was hers, for it was wrapped up in an old rag, plaited down the shoulders, and that I had an apron pieced across the bottom; I told her I had them. She asked the name of the person that brought them? I said, 
               <persName id="t17550515-25-person231">
                  Anne 
                  Richards 
               <interp inst="t17550515-25-person231" type="surname" value="Richards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-25-person231" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-25-person231" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; then she told me they were stole; I said, she told me she brought them from a mantuamaker by the White-hart in Churchyard-alley, and said she lived there. She told me the person that brought them had took three gold rings and other things; just as I was taking the gown down she pointed up to it, and said, that was hers.</p>
               <p>Q. Could she see any part of it then?</p>
               <p>J. Enderson. No, I believe she could not. She said, the shirt is pawned for five shillings, the shift for one shilling and six-pence, the apron for six-pence. I said, it is very odd these things should be stolen, and you come for them in this particular manner. I said the gown was pawned for six shillings, the shift two shillings, and the apron nine-pence.</p>

               <p>Q. Did she say the person had told her they were pawned for that money?</p>
               <p>J. Enderson. She said, no; she had it from one Rachel that the other had sold it to; then I shewed her my book; she went away and left them. After this the headborough came and took me up with a warrant, and carried me before justice Manwaring, and I delivered up the goods.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Tell in what manner I came and surrendered myself.</p>
               <p>J. Enderson. The justice told me he hoped I would be vigilant in taking up the person that brought the goods. I heard she was going to work with some person on the other side the water; I went there, the people told me she was not come; I returned, and about eleven o'clock she came into my shop, and said, I hear you have been brought into trouble upon the account of the things I brought, I am come to clear myself, and will go wherever you please. (The goods produced in court, and deposed to by the prosecutrix).</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>The prosecutrix's husband was a little involved in debt; the first thing I carried to pawn for them was a duffel cloak, and I fetched it out again; the silk gown I carried to Mr. Wright in Nightingale-lane, they would let me have but four shillings for it, so I brought it to Mrs. Enderson's, she offered me six shillings on it; I went to ask whether I might take it or not? she said I might pawn it for that; she herself rolled it up in a napkin, and said to me, she had no opportunity of fetching it out till her mother went to the water-cock. She went to the pawnbroker's door, and I went in and carried it, and brought her out the six shillings, she at the same time gave me one shilling for my week's hire. I had of her twelve-pence per week, and victuals and drink. Some time after that she sent me to pawn a shift, which she wrapped up in an old rag, which I pawned for two shillings; after that she sent me out with a check apron, and a white apron, and bid me get the most I could, I carried them to a pawnbroker in East-smithfield, one I got one shilling and six-pence on, the other I carried to Mrs. Enderson, and she lent me nine-pence on it. Please to call Raby, she heard her say I carried these things for her own use, the prosecutrix desired me to lay them in my maiden name, because she had been guilty of pawning things, and her mother would not be ready to find them out.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550515-25-person232">
                  Rachel 
                  Raby 
               <interp inst="t17550515-25-person232" type="surname" value="Raby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-25-person232" type="given" value="Rachel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-25-person232" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prosecutrix came and asked me if the prisoner was gone away? I said, I believed not, but if she was she is gone over the water; she said, if she is gone away she has done a very wrong thing by me, for she may fetch out my things and go and sell them; I said, what has she pawned of yours? she said, she has pawned a gown for a crown, an apron for one shilling and six-pence, and if her mother came to miss them, she said she would swear she had stole them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she mention an apron?</p>
               <p>R. Raby. She did, but I can't remember what she said that was pawned for.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>R. Raby. I wind silk for my living.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known the prisoner?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175505150024"></xptr>R. Raby. I have known her since Christmas last, she has laid with me from that time.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her general character?</p>
               <p>R. Raby. She bears a good character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550515-25-person233">
                  Dorothy 
                  Skayne 
               <interp inst="t17550515-25-person233" type="surname" value="Skayne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-25-person233" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-25-person233" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at work; the prosecutrix came and asked me if I saw any thing of 
               <persName id="t17550515-25-person234">
                  Anne 
                  Goadby 
               <interp inst="t17550515-25-person234" type="surname" value="Goadby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-25-person234" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550515-25-person234" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ? I said, no; she said, I sent some things to pawn by her at a place, and she had carried them to another place, and if she does not come to me before to-morrow morning, my mother would swear I stole them, and she knocked her hand against the boards in a passion.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17550515-25-verdict120" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550515-25-verdict120" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
