<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17590912-38">
               <interp inst="t17590912-38" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590912-38" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590912-38" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17590912"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590912-38" type="date" value="17590912"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17590912-38-off219-c262" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-38-defend333 t17590912-38-off219 t17590912-38-verdict222"></join>
         
               <p>285. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17590912-38-defend333" type="defendantName">
                     Hugh 
                     Cantrell 
                  <interp inst="t17590912-38-defend333" type="surname" value="Cantrell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-38-defend333" type="given" value="Hugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-38-defend333" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for the <rs id="t17590912-38-off219" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590912-38-off219" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-38-off219" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               wilful murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17590912-38-victim335" type="victimName">
                           Philip 
                           Ruskins 
                        <interp inst="t17590912-38-victim335" type="surname" value="Ruskins"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590912-38-victim335" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590912-38-victim335" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-38-off219 t17590912-38-victim335"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>. He stood charg'd on the Coroner's Inquest for Manslaughter, <rs id="t17590912-38-cd220" type="crimeDate">July 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-38-off219 t17590912-38-cd220"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590912-38-person336">
                  Samuel 
                  Tanner 
               <interp inst="t17590912-38-person336" type="surname" value="Tanner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-38-person336" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-38-person336" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at <placeName id="t17590912-38-crimeloc221">the Bull at Tanner's End</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17590912-38-crimeloc221" type="placeName" value="the Bull at Tanner's End"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17590912-38-crimeloc221" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590912-38-off219 t17590912-38-crimeloc221"></join>; on the 23d of July, about 12'clock, Mr Bonner came to me, and said, Ruskins was at the door, abusing a man that had taken my wife's part, whom Ruskins had abus'd before. Ruskins struck Bonner two blows. Then Cantrell came out, and asked Ruskins, If he was not ashamed to beat an old man? upon which words arose between them. Ruskins challeng'd Cantrell, and they agreed to fight. Then Cantrell declined it, and came into the house. Ruskins followed him to the door, and look'd in at the window, and said, I am now ready, and went backwards 7 or 8 yards and stripp'd. Cantrell went out, but I was about my business, and saw no more of it. Ruskins was a very quarrelsome, troublesome fellow, subject to drink, and then would abuse any body. Cantrell always behaved peaceable and sober.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590912-38-person337">
                  William 
                  Bonner 
               <interp inst="t17590912-38-person337" type="surname" value="Bonner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-38-person337" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-38-person337" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at Mr Tanner's, setting on the bench, and had call'd for some beer. Ruskins ask'd me to drink with me; I said he might. He flew in a violent passion at the landlady at the door, and said, he would throw her into the pond. I said, it was unbecoming to use a woman with such words. He gave me a kick on my backside, and struck me on my stomach with his fist. Cantrell came out, and said, it was a pity to use an old man so ill; upon which words arose between them, and there was a challenge made, but I know not which made it. After that, Cantrell went into the house, and Ruskins came, and call'd him out, saying, he was ready; then they went to fighting, and had 3 set-too's; at the 2 d set-too, Cantrell struck Ruskins on the side, and he fell. He was taken up, and a third set-too, but in that I saw no blow at all. The deceased died the day following: he was always a very quarrelsome man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590912-38-person338">
                  Thomas 
                  Nottage 
               <interp inst="t17590912-38-person338" type="surname" value="Nottage"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-38-person338" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-38-person338" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 3 d set-too Cantrell gave the deceased 3 or 4 blows on the body; one blow was on his face, then Ruskins fell and could rise no more. We put on his cloaths, and gave him some water. He could then speak. He was carried to his lodgings, and he died the next day. I saw him dead, but no marks of violence upon him, only a bruise on the left ear, which he got by the fall. He was a very abusive, quarrelsome man: he would quarrel with any body when he got in liquor.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>He challenged me, and I could not avoid encountering him. He us'd the woman of the house, and the other evidence here, very ill, and there was no making him peaceable. I would have avoided fighting if possible.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>Mr Bass. The prisoner was my servant; I have known him about 2 years, he is a very peaceable man, and always behaved well.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590912-38-person339">
                  Richard 
                  Thomson 
               <interp inst="t17590912-38-person339" type="surname" value="Thomson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-38-person339" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590912-38-person339" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about 4 or 5 years; no man behaved better than he did. I never saw him quarrelsome in my life.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17590912-38-verdict222" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590912-38-verdict222" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>. The deceas'd died a natural death.</p>
            </div1>
