<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17550226-53">
               <interp inst="t17550226-53" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550226-53" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550226-53" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550226"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550226-53" type="date" value="17550226"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550226-53-off289-c372" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550226-53-defend474 t17550226-53-off289 t17550226-53-verdict290"></join>
         
               <p>151. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17550226-53-defend474" type="defendantName">
                  John, alias <rs id="t17550226-53-alias-4" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550226-53-defend474 t17550226-53-alias-4"></join>Cuddy Stevens</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-defend474" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-defend474" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17550226-53-off289" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-off289" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-off289" type="offenceSubcategory" value="perjury"></interp>
               wilful and corrupt perjury, in giving false information before the late lord chief justice Lee, Aug. 1, 1753, in swearing to a written affidavit, complaining against 
                     
                        <persName id="t17550226-53-victim476" type="victimName">
                           Isaac 
                           Thorp 
                        <interp inst="t17550226-53-victim476" type="surname" value="Thorp"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550226-53-victim476" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550226-53-victim476" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , 
                     <persName id="t17550226-53-victim477" type="victimName">
                        Edward, otherwise <rs id="t17550226-53-alias-5" type="alias">
                           <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550226-53-victim477 t17550226-53-alias-5"></join>John Rowland</rs>
                        <interp inst="t17550226-53-victim477" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550226-53-victim477" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , and divers others; that they came into the house of 
                     <persName id="t17550226-53-person478">
                        Jane 
                        Blynn 
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person478" type="surname" value="Blynn"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550226-53-person478" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550226-53-person478" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , and made a great riot, and swore they would set her house on fire, and put her in fear of her life, and did beat her and the defendant 
                     <persName id="t17550226-53-person479">
                        John 
                        Stevens 
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person479" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550226-53-person479" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550226-53-person479" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , and raised a mob of two hundred people round her house, and encouraged them with money to abuse her, and him the defendant on the 14th and 17th of July. ++
            </rs> See Blynn's trial, No. 514, in alderman Rawlinson's mayoralty.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550226-53-person480">
                  Benjamin 
                  Thomas 
               <interp inst="t17550226-53-person480" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person480" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person480" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . (He takes the information of Jane Blynn and 
               <persName id="t17550226-53-person481">
                  John 
                  Stevens 
               <interp inst="t17550226-53-person481" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person481" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person481" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in his hand). I remember my swearing this information by two persons, who called themselves one 
               <persName id="t17550226-53-person482">
                  Jane 
                  Blynn 
               <interp inst="t17550226-53-person482" type="surname" value="Blynn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person482" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person482" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the other 
               <persName id="t17550226-53-person483">
                  John 
                  Stevens 
               <interp inst="t17550226-53-person483" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person483" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person483" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , it appears to have been sworn Aug. 1, 1753.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember the prisoner to be one of the persons?</p>
               <p>Thomas. I remember 
               <persName id="t17550226-53-person484">
                  Jane 
                  Blynn 
               <interp inst="t17550226-53-person484" type="surname" value="Blynn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person484" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person484" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and there was a man with her, she called him John Stevens, and he swore to the truth of this information, it was taken at Guild-hall before my lord chief justice Lee.</p>
               <p>John Hill. I am bar-keeper at Guild-hall; I have seen the prisoner there several times, in August 53 I remember there was a man and a woman, I believe she was the woman tried here some time since, and I really believe the prisoner was the man, they came to Mr. Thomas to lodge an information.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner before that?</p>
               <p>Hill. I have seen him hundreds of times, he went by the name of Cuddy Stevens; I have a very ill opinion of him. I remember seeing Mr. Thomas hand a paper to him and ask if it was his hand-writing? and just at that time somebody cried, open the door, officer, and I was obliged to open the door, I was then within three yards of him; I remember also at the same time a man said to me, don't you know that man, that is Cuddy Stevens.</p>
               <p>Q. Then you can't say you saw him sworn?</p>

               <p>Hill. I cannot.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550226-53-person485">
                  William 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17550226-53-person485" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person485" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person485" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was tipstaff to my lord chief justice Lee; I remember there was a warrant dated August 21 1753, to be executed upon 
               <persName id="t17550226-53-person486">
                  Isaac 
                  Thorp 
               <interp inst="t17550226-53-person486" type="surname" value="Thorp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person486" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person486" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and several others, I can't say who brought it to me, but remember the prisoner at the bar came to me as a prosecutor several times along with Blynn, both before and after the execution of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550226-53-person487">
                  Isaac 
                  Thorp 
               <interp inst="t17550226-53-person487" type="surname" value="Thorp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person487" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person487" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner once lived in my neighbourhood about twelve doors from me, but not in the same street, there was 
               <persName id="t17550226-53-person488">
                  Jane 
                  Blynn 
               <interp inst="t17550226-53-person488" type="surname" value="Blynn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person488" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person488" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             lived with him, they had taken in pawns, and as people came to take them out they would not let them have them, and people made complaints, and there used to be mobs about the door.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you near her house on the 14th or 17th of July 1753?</p>
               <p>Thorp. I was not on both days, I was in my own house, the Ship, a public-house; I had had a trial with this prisoner on the 13th, and I heard<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175502260036"></xptr> he had got a judge's warrant against me and ten more, so I kept at home.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever in your life head a mob in order to make a riot at their door?</p>
               <p>Thorp. No, I never did, neither was I ever there in a riot. I never was at their house but once in my life, then I went with a constable to serve a warrant upon the prisoner on an information of a woman who said he offered twenty pounds to have a riot sworn against me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever threaten to murder him or 
               <persName id="t17550226-53-person489">
                  Jane 
                  Blynn 
               <interp inst="t17550226-53-person489" type="surname" value="Blynn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person489" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person489" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Thorp. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever offer a reward to any to do it?</p>
               <p>Thorp. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550226-53-person490">
                  John 
                  Alexander 
               <interp inst="t17550226-53-person490" type="surname" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person490" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person490" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was constable that time; I was at Stevens's house on the 17th of July, 1753, along with one Fitzmorris, to serve a warrant on him, if Mr. Thorp had been there I must have seen him. Stevens made resistance, and I was obliged to charge others to assist me to haul him along.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550226-53-person491">
                  Mary 
                  Turner 
               <interp inst="t17550226-53-person491" type="surname" value="Turner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person491" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person491" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I laid at Mr. Thorp's in August 1753; I remember there was a disturbance in the street, on the 17th of July, before his door some time in the afternoon, and I know my master was in his house with some gentlemen, and was engaged at home till late at night.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550226-53-person492">
                  Patrick 
                  Holborn 
               <interp inst="t17550226-53-person492" type="surname" value="Holborn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person492" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person492" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Thorp is a neighbour of mine; I remember being at his house on the 17th of July; I went there at about five in the afternoon, and staid till half an hour after nine; we were smoking a pipe together in his back room, I remember it by having a warrant in my pocket to take up a woman in that neighbourhood; I never heard of any riots at the prisoner's house, except it was by people whom they would not let have their goods which they had pawned.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550226-53-person493">
                  Hannah 
                  Russel 
               <interp inst="t17550226-53-person493" type="surname" value="Russel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person493" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person493" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was a chair-woman to the prisoner and 
               <persName id="t17550226-53-person494">
                  Jane 
                  Blynn 
               <interp inst="t17550226-53-person494" type="surname" value="Blynn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person494" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person494" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             when they lived in the Broad-way, Westminster; there used to be people continually coming for their goods which they had pawned. I cannot remember any particular day, because every day was alike, by people coming for their goods; but I never saw Mr. Thorp or Mr. Ashmore, or any of the persons charged in the information in any of the disturbances at the door; they used to make me give answers at the door, and they would keep out of sight as much as they could.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550226-53-person495">
                  Sarah 
                  Jacobs 
               <interp inst="t17550226-53-person495" type="surname" value="Jacobs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person495" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person495" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was four months in Stevens's house to my sorrow, when he and Blynn lived in Goswel-street, sometimes they passed for man and wife, sometimes for mistress and servant, because if they passed for man and wife they could not swear for each other. I heard the prisoner say many a time he was forced to come away from the Broad-way, Westminster, on account of the riots by people coming for their goods, and he has often said he would be revenged on Thorp, Ashmore and Rowland, and three parts of the people in the Broad-way, and would go to law with them till he brought them to beggary, and he often said he was then at a great loss for people to swear for him; he was used to have people to swear for him at any time, but said they were all dead; he said several times to me I must swear Thorp and they came to his house and made riots; and he said Jacobs should go and swear likewise, and threatened to have him and Blynn out of the house, life and limb. I said I knew neither of them, and I would not swear any such thing.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550226-53-person496">
                  Elisabeth 
                  Rogers 
               <interp inst="t17550226-53-person496" type="surname" value="Rogers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person496" type="given" value="Elisabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person496" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in 
               <persName id="t17550226-53-person497">
                  Jane 
                  Blynn 
               <interp inst="t17550226-53-person497" type="surname" value="Blynn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person497" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person497" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's house along with Mrs. Jacobs, she was left in possesion for them; I never heard Mrs. Jacobs say the prisoner bid her swear, as she has sworn here; but I once heard Mrs. Jacobs say Mrs. Blynn asked her to swear so.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550226-53-person498">
                  Richard 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17550226-53-person498" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person498" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person498" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 22d of February, 1754, I was employed by Mrs. Jenkins to take an inventory of Mrs. Blynn's goods; when I went to take possession, Mrs. Jacobs and her husband called me, and took and threw my inventory-book away. I went again on the 28th, and took possession with a letter of attorney; she told me then, if swearing would take away Stevens's and Blynn's lives, she would do it.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you, and where do you live?</p>
               <p>King. I am a journeyman upholsterer, and live in Bishopsgate-street.</p>
               <p>John-King. Mrs. Jacobs has come backwards and forwards to my mistress's, she is Stevens's Sister. About the latter-end of February she came and said, for God's sake don't let Mr. Stevens come home to night, for his three enemies have been there, and they will drag him through the kennel.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is your mistress.</p>
               <p>King. Her name is Phillips, she keeps a pewterer's shop in Watling-street; she is sick in bed, and can't come.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550226-53-person499">
                  Mary 
                  Jenkins 
               <interp inst="t17550226-53-person499" type="surname" value="Jenkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person499" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person499" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had a letter of attorney to go into Mrs. Blynn's house, and take possession. I took 
               <persName id="t17550226-53-person500">
                  Richard 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17550226-53-person500" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person500" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person500" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             with me, to take down what goods were in the house. We took<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175502260037"></xptr> with us a new, lock, to put on the back-door. I told Jacobs we had got a letter of attorney; she took the lock, and said, God blast your eyes, you old b - h, I'll knock your brains out: she threw the lock away, and her husband and she took Mr. King by the collar, I thought they would have strangled him. She, Mrs. Jacobs, called me a thousand old bawds, and Stevens a sodomite. I heard her swear, if he did not deliver some money to her, she would keep the feather-bed, bolster, pillow, blankets, sheets, and a parrot in a cage; I was afraid she would take my life away. I have known the prisoner ever since the year 1715, I never knew any harm of him in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>M. Jenkins. By St. Martin's church.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17550226-53-verdict290" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-verdict290" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>See him tried before, No. 474. in Sir 
               <persName id="t17550226-53-person501">
                  William 
                  Calvert 
               <interp inst="t17550226-53-person501" type="surname" value="Calvert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person501" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person501" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's mayoralty; and No. 126. in Sir 
               <persName id="t17550226-53-person502">
                  Samuel 
                  Pennant 
               <interp inst="t17550226-53-person502" type="surname" value="Pennant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person502" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-person502" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17550226-53-punish291" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-punish291" type="punishmentCategory" value="imprison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-punish291" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="newgate"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550226-53-defend474 t17550226-53-punish291"></join>
               
                     <note>[Imprisonment. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17550226-53-punish292" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550226-53-punish292" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550226-53-defend474 t17550226-53-punish292"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
