<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510523-20">
               <interp inst="t17510523-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510523-20" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510523-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510523"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510523-20" type="date" value="17510523"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510523-20-off109-c141" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-20-defend179 t17510523-20-off109 t17510523-20-verdict114"></join>
         
               <p>374. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17510523-20-defend179" type="defendantName">
                  
                     William 
                     Hatton 
                  , || otherwise <rs id="t17510523-20-alias-2" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-20-defend179 t17510523-20-alias-2"></join>Forrister</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-20-defend179" type="surname" value="Hatton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-20-defend179" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-20-defend179" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for that <rs id="t17510523-20-off109" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510523-20-off109" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-20-off109" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               he in company with 
                     <persName id="t17510523-20-person181">
                        David 
                        Jones 
                     <interp inst="t17510523-20-person181" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510523-20-person181" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510523-20-person181" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   on the <rs id="t17510523-20-cd110" type="crimeDate">23d of April</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-20-off109 t17510523-20-cd110"></join>, between the hours of one and two the dwelling house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17510523-20-victim183" type="victimName">
                           David 
                           Paul 
                        <interp inst="t17510523-20-victim183" type="surname" value="Paul"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510523-20-victim183" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510523-20-victim183" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-20-off109 t17510523-20-victim183"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did break and enter, sixty china cups, value twenty shillings, four china saucers, one bow china tea pot, one earthen tea pot, two pickle dishes earthen ware, five fish plates earthen ware, one earthen fish strainer, one show glass and other things, did steal, take, and carry away
            </rs>. +</p>
               <p>|| See No 25. in this mayoralty.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-20-person184">
                  David 
                  Paul 
               <interp inst="t17510523-20-person184" type="surname" value="Paul"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-20-person184" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-20-person184" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17510523-20-viclabel111" type="occupation">taylor</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-20-victim183 t17510523-20-viclabel111"></join> by trade, <rs id="t17510523-20-viclabel112" type="occupation">my wife keeps an earthen ware shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-20-victim183 t17510523-20-viclabel112"></join>, I live in <placeName id="t17510523-20-crimeloc113">Whitechapel</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17510523-20-crimeloc113" type="placeName" value="Whitechapel"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510523-20-crimeloc113" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-20-off109 t17510523-20-crimeloc113"></join>, on the 23d of April there was no body lay in our house but my wife and I, and she was sick, the windows and doors were all fast, and the bolts and keys were so the next morning. A shutter was broke to pieces, and one pane of glass broke; I was called up about two, there was missing the goods mentioned and more, I don't know how many glasses I lost.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-20-person185">
                  James 
                  Brebrook 
               <interp inst="t17510523-20-person185" type="surname" value="Brebrook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-20-person185" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-20-person185" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . George Hall the evidence sent his wife to me, desiring I'd take up this Forrister. I and another went and took him, Hall was along with him; we went by Hall's direction to an empty house in Rag-fair and found some of the goods. The evidence said the prisoner put them there, but he denied it.</p>
               <p>George Hall. The prisoner and I agreed to go out a house breaking, we went out the 23d of April to break open this china shop in Whitechapel, we had things on purpose for such work, we went betwixt twelve and one at night, we first try'd to break the window shutter in halves, we could not take it out at that time, the watchmen were going about; we left it, and came at past one o'clock and broke it and took it out, I put it in the middle of the kennel; the prisoner broke a pane of glass, he first took out three tea pots, I had a bag in my hand to put the things in; then he took out five fish strainers, six tumblers made of glass, and a quantity of china, I cannot say how much, because we broke a good many; there was a china tea-pot, two little china plates, and a square plate; I stood in the path when the watchman was coming by, I carried the bag cross the way and the prisoner followed me so we carried them to our lodgings; we got up about four o'clock next morning, and gave two women sixpence a piece to carry them to a place in Duke's-place where we used to sell our things; they were sold to Minous, a Jew, the prisoner grumbled at the price and would not take the money. After that I heard we were likely to be taken, I had a mind to leave this sort of life off, and hearing he was going to hang me I then thought to hang him, so I came voluntarily and made a discovery. As he would not let the Jew have the things he took and put them into an empty house in Ragfair, then I sent for the people directly; this prisoner has hang'd two men here before. Brebrook carried us before the Justice, the prosecutor came there. I was admitted an evidence against 
               <persName id="t17510523-20-person186">
                  David 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17510523-20-person186" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-20-person186" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-20-person186" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. You have said nothing about Jones, was he with you in this robbery?</p>
               <p>Hall. He was, my Lord, but I thought I was to say nothing against him till he was tried. When the prisoner was committed I went with Brebrook, 
               <persName id="t17510523-20-person187">
                  John 
                  Lecock 
               <interp inst="t17510523-20-person187" type="surname" value="Lecock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-20-person187" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-20-person187" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and the constable, where the goods were, some are here now, and some are in Bridewell.</p>
               <p>Q. to Brebrook. Are these part of the goods you found in Ragfair ?</p>
               <p>Brebrook. They are, my Lord, and there are many more now at Bridewell.</p>
               <p>Q. to the Prosecutor. Are these your property?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Here are the two covers which I brought from home, they belong to the two teapots. He put them on, they sitted, and deposed to the pots, and another china one.</p>

               <p>Q. from the prisoner to Hall. Where did we meet that night?</p>
               <p>Hall. We met at the Coach and Horses in Ragfair, and made a bargain to go out; there came in 
               <persName id="t17510523-20-person188">
                  David 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17510523-20-person188" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-20-person188" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-20-person188" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he had `been out a picking pockets.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175105230014"></xptr>Q. from the prisoner. Has he got any body here that have seen us together?</p>
               <p>Hall. On the Saturday of the last sessions we were together at the Queen's Head in the Old-Baily, and we were in the right hand gallery in this house, and have been together in this way ever since.</p>
               <p>The prisoner being ask'd what he had to say for himself, made answer, nothing at all.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510523-20-verdict114" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510523-20-verdict114" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510523-20-punish115" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510523-20-punish115" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-20-defend179 t17510523-20-punish115"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>There was another indictment against him for burglary.</p>
            </div1>
