<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17511204-21">
               <interp inst="t17511204-21" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511204-21" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511204-21" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17511204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511204-21" type="date" value="17511204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17511204-21-off124-c161" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511204-21-defend198 t17511204-21-off124 t17511204-21-verdict129"></join>
         
               <p>23. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17511204-21-defend198" type="defendantName">
                  Rachel 
                  <rs id="t17511204-21-deflabel123" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511204-21-defend198 t17511204-21-deflabel123"></join> of Joseph Beacham
               <interp inst="t17511204-21-defend198" type="surname" value="Beacham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-21-defend198" type="given" value="Rachel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-21-defend198" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for the <rs id="t17511204-21-off124" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17511204-21-off124" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-21-off124" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               murder
            </rs> of 
               <persName id="t17511204-21-victim199" type="victimName">
                  Henrietta 
                  Dawes 
               <interp inst="t17511204-21-victim199" type="surname" value="Dawes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-21-victim199" type="given" value="Henrietta"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-21-victim199" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511204-21-off124 t17511204-21-victim199"></join>
                  </persName>
             , <rs id="t17511204-21-viclabel125" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511204-21-victim199 t17511204-21-viclabel125"></join>, <rs id="t17511204-21-cd126" type="crimeDate">Oct. 25</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511204-21-off124 t17511204-21-cd126"></join>. She also stood charged on the coroner's inquisition for the said murder. *</p>
               <p>Mary Hyde. I lodge in the prisoner's house in <placeName id="t17511204-21-crimeloc127">Tittymouse-alley</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17511204-21-crimeloc127" type="placeName" value="Tittymouse-alley"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17511204-21-crimeloc127" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511204-21-off124 t17511204-21-crimeloc127"></join>. I am mother of the deceased. Betwixt eleven and twelve, on the 25th of Oct. the prisoner sent me to Mrs. Pollard's for a peck of coals; I was gone about half an hour, when I came back, the prisoner was below, rubbing her hands all over bloody; I ask'd her what she had done? she made me no answer; Mrs. Pollard followed me directly; she asked the prisoner, what she had been doing? she answered, she had kill'd Henney, then I went up into her room, and saw my babe lying all in its gore upon the floor.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon what account did Mrs. Pollard go with you ?</p>
               <p>M. Hyde. I heard a person say in the street, where is Henney's mother, she was murder'd. So Mrs. Pollard hearing it, went with me.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175112040012"></xptr>Q. Did you examine the child?</p>
               <p>M. Hyde. I had not power, Mrs. Pollard went up with me; it was cut round its throat, and a stab on the side of its breast.</p>
               <p>Q. How old was she?</p>
               <p>M. Hyde. She would have been <rs id="t17511204-21-viclabel128" type="occupation">six years old the 12th of next January</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511204-21-victim199 t17511204-21-viclabel128"></join>.</p>
               <p>Isabella Pollard. The child had been at my house about three quarters of an hour before it was murder'd. I sent her to fetch me half a pint of beer, which she did; after which, her mother came for a peck of coals; while she was there, a young woman came, and said, where is the child's mother? it is murdered. I called to the mother, she was gone from my house to the next door. I told her, she ran, and I after her, to the prisoner's house; when I came in, I saw the prisoner rubbing her hands all over blood. I asked her what she had done? she said, she had kil l'd Henney. I ask'd her what she did it for? she said, what was that to me? she went into the yard; I went up stairs, and saw the babe lying dead all in its gore upon the floor; it was cut from ear to ear.</p>
               <p>Q. to M. Hyde. How had she used to behave to the child before this?</p>
               <p>M. Hyde. She behaved in my sight very well to her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she behave amiss to her, out of your sight?</p>
               <p>M. Hyde. I never asked the child any questions about her behaviour to her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511204-21-person200">
                  Sarah 
                  Wickham 
               <interp inst="t17511204-21-person200" type="surname" value="Wickham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-21-person200" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-21-person200" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live over against the prisoner. I was in my own house and heard a great noise. After which the prisoner came out with her right hand above her wrist all bloody; somebody said they thought there was murder committed, I called to Mrs. Pollard, who came with the mother as beforementioned.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511204-21-person201">
                  Sarah 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17511204-21-person201" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-21-person201" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-21-person201" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard a great noise in our back wash-house. My sister and I opened the back gate, there we saw the prisoner almost to the elbows in blood.</p>
               <p>Q. to M. Hyde. Is the prisoner out of her senses at times?</p>
               <p>M. Hyde, I have known her fifteen or sixteen years; I never knowed her any otherwise than in her senses, I wind silk, the prisoner clear'd my bobbin for me that very morning my child was murdered.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you imagine could induce her to do it?</p>
               <p>M. Hyde. I cannot imagine what, no more than any one here.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511204-21-person202">
                  Arthur 
                  Featherly 
               <interp inst="t17511204-21-person202" type="surname" value="Featherly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-21-person202" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-21-person202" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am headborough, I was sent for and told a child's head was cut off. When I came to the house, there were many people there, and the prisoner standing in the yard. I took her before the justice, all she said before and at the justice's was: She did not know. At last she said a man ni black came in and did it. He produced a case knife. This knife was delivered to me all over blood, blade and handle both, the forepart of her gown was as if it had been dipped in a tub of blood.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511204-21-person203">
                  Mary 
                  Deal 
               <interp inst="t17511204-21-person203" type="surname" value="Deal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-21-person203" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511204-21-person203" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I found the knife in the next yard to the prisoner's, at the time she was taken up. There were many people saw it lie.</p>
               <p>The prisoner was called to make her Defence.</p>
               <p>Who said she did kill the child. She was asked if she upon any account bore any grudge or ill-will to it, answered no, she had none against it. She was asked why she did? she answered she was tempted to do it.</p>
               <p>Q. How tempted ?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I don't know.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs. Pollard. Have you ever observed the prisoner to have been out of her senses?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Pollard. I have known her a great many years; I never saw or heard she was any other than in her senses.</p>
               <p>Q. Is she given to drink?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Pollard. I never saw her in liquor in my life.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17511204-21-verdict129" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17511204-21-verdict129" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17511204-21-punish130" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17511204-21-punish130" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511204-21-defend198 t17511204-21-punish130"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
