<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17590117-40">
               <interp inst="t17590117-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590117-40" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590117-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17590117"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590117-40" type="date" value="17590117"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17590117-40-off244-c355" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590117-40-defend437 t17590117-40-off244 t17590117-40-verdict246"></join>
         
               <p>110. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17590117-40-defend437" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Shirley 
                  <interp inst="t17590117-40-defend437" type="surname" value="Shirley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-40-defend437" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-40-defend437" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17590117-40-off244" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590117-40-off244" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-40-off244" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 30 dozen of crystal stones for earrings, value 3 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17590117-40-victim439" type="victimName">
                     Richard 
                     White 
                  <interp inst="t17590117-40-victim439" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-40-victim439" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-40-victim439" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590117-40-off244 t17590117-40-victim439"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17590117-40-cd245" type="crimeDate">Oct. 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590117-40-off244 t17590117-40-cd245"></join>. *</p>
               <p>Richard White. About the Middle of October I imported about two hundred pounds worth of crystal stones for ear-rings, in the Maria Agnette, 
               <persName id="t17590117-40-person440">
                  Henry 
                  Clinkart 
               <interp inst="t17590117-40-person440" type="surname" value="Clinkart"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-40-person440" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-40-person440" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Commander; when I came to the Custom-House to pay the duty there were nine parcels of them, containing several other smaller parcels; after I had paid the duty, I looked at the package and found it had been opened; and out of a parcel No. 9 I missed forty dozen of stones for earrings; in the Christmas week one 
               <persName id="t17590117-40-person441">
                  Moses 
                  Solomon 
               <interp inst="t17590117-40-person441" type="surname" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-40-person441" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-40-person441" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Jew, came and offered a sample of these sort of goods in my shop; I suspecting them to be mine; I told him they were worth more than they really were; and offered him something for himself if he would bring the whole of them, and the person he had them on, that I might buy them. On New-Years-Day he brought thirty dozen, but did not bring the man; I wanted to know who he had them of: (believing them to be mine) I charged the constable with the Jew, to find out the man that sent him; he would not for a good while tell where he had them; but after a good deal to do, he said they were left for him at the Hare and Punch-Bowl in Lime-street, a publick-house; I ask'd him if the man was not waiting there for the money for them; he said he could not tell, but he believ'd he was; I went there with the Jew and constable; the Jew and I agreed, going along, for him to go up to the man and tell him I bid him so much money for the goods; there we found the prisoner by the kitchen fire; the Jew did his message; the prisoner said he could get more money for them; I ask'd him if he was the person that own'd the goods; he answered yes, and he gave them to the Jew to sell; then I charged the constable with him; but withal I told him, if he would tell me where he had the goods I would let him go. He would give no account how he came by them; I took him before the siting Alderman; there he could give no account; so he was committed; they are a very particular sort of goods, and very hard to come at in London; and they were offered to me at a price less than what we sell them at.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you say they are your goods?</p>
               <p>White. I don't swear to them, but I really believe they are mine.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Where had you the goods from?</p>
               <p>White. I had them from Holland.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you seen them before they were lost?</p>
               <p>White. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were they lost from?</p>
               <p>White. They were lost in the passage from the ship to the Custom-house, I imagine.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure they were not lost on board the ship?</p>
               <p>White. I can't tell that; my having lost such goods, and these being brought me to sell, made me desirous to trace it out.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know you lost such goods at all?</p>
               <p>White. I had an envoyce that such goods were shipped on board such a ship; and when I came to examine the goods, I found such good were missing.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it not possible such goods might be lost in Holland?</p>
               <p>White. It is possible, but not likely.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you charge the prisoner with before Mr. Alderman Stevenson?</p>
               <p>White. There I charged him with buying them, knowing them to have been stolen.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any evidence of that?</p>
               <p>White. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you say there you imagined some custom-house officer took them?</p>
               <p>White. I do not charge any body with taking them, though I really think them to be my goods.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175901170038"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17590117-40-person442">
                  Thomas 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17590117-40-person442" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-40-person442" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590117-40-person442" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable; I was charg'd with the Jew, and after that with the prisoner at the bar; I carry'd him before the sitting Alderman; he could give no account; at last, he said he had the goods of a man that was an hundred miles off.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Smith. I do not know: I think he said he deals in buying goods at Exchequer sales.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17590117-40-verdict246" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590117-40-verdict246" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
