<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17591024-12">
               <interp inst="t17591024-12" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591024-12" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591024-12" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17591024"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591024-12" type="date" value="17591024"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17591024-12-off53-c93" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591024-12-defend117 t17591024-12-off53 t17591024-12-verdict55"></join>
         
               <p>311. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17591024-12-defend117" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Gilbert 
                  <interp inst="t17591024-12-defend117" type="surname" value="Gilbert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-12-defend117" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-12-defend117" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17591024-12-deflabel52" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591024-12-defend117 t17591024-12-deflabel52"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17591024-12-off53" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17591024-12-off53" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-12-off53" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               sacrilegiously stealing two silk damask curtains, containing six yards, value 4 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               <persName id="t17591024-12-victim118" type="victimName">
                     <interp inst="t17591024-12-victim118" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591024-12-off53 t17591024-12-victim118"></join>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17591024-12-cd54" type="crimeDate">September 20</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591024-12-off53 t17591024-12-cd54"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591024-12-person119">
                  Edward Robert 
                  Stephenson 
               <interp inst="t17591024-12-person119" type="surname" value="Stephenson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-12-person119" type="given" value="Edward Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-12-person119" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Sexton of the parish of St Martin in the Fields; I was in waiting in the month of September, and on the sixteenth after Evening prayer, at five o'clock, I missed two silk damask curtains from the churchwardens and overseers pews, they had been left safe in the church over-night; on the twenty-second, being the Saturday following, after Evening Prayer, which begins a quarter after three o'clock, I search'd the church over; and, on the top of the gallery-stairs, I found the prisoner lying at full length; I sent for the keeper of the Round-house, in order take her into custody; I went also to the Justice, to enquire what I must do with her; and in the mean time she was searched in the Round-house. The other witness will give an account of what they found upon her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591024-12-person120">
                  Joseph 
                  Cooper 
               <interp inst="t17591024-12-person120" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-12-person120" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-12-person120" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the twenty-second of September, by order of Mr Churchwarden, I was sent to the church to put up an organ curtain to the churchwardens pew, that they should not look naked where the others were stolen from; there Mr Stephenson made a fort of an out-cry on the top of the stairs; I went up, and there I saw the prisoner lying at full length with a little light bundle under her head; she said, she was very sick; I went down stairs again; then came the Round-house-keeper, in order to take her away. I was before Justice Kynaston, where she was examined; there were some binding, and a little slip of damask found upon her; the Justice ask'd her how she came by them; she said she found them in Monmouth-street, at the upper-end, over-against Mr Loader's.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591024-12-person121">
                  William 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17591024-12-person121" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-12-person121" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-12-person121" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I searched the prisoner in the watch-house; in her pocket I found a Prayer-Book and a piece of damask that tallies exactly with one of the curtains, which had been cut off; I ask'd her where she had them; she gave me no account; I took her before the Justice; but was sent for upon other business, so did not hear her examination.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591024-12-person122">
                  George 
                  Caddey 
               <interp inst="t17591024-12-person122" type="surname" value="Caddey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-12-person122" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-12-person122" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was the Constable in this affair; I was sent for to St Martin's Vestry, on the twenty-third of September, in the morning; the prisoner was committed to the Gatehouse; I went with her; on the Monday about noon the Justice sent for me, and desired I would take them slips of damask and go with him; we went to the back side of St Clement's church, to one Cameron, we there found the curtains.</p>
               <p>Q. What is Cameron?</p>
               <p>Caddey. He is a Piecebroker. The curtains produced; one had a slip about two or three inches wide cut off it; the slip found upon the prisoner was put to it; then it made the two curtains of a length; and the slip tallied as to the flowers, length, and in every respect put it beyond all doubt but that it was cut off the curtain.</p>
               <p>Q. to Stephenson. Can you say these are the curtains that belong to your church?</p>
               <p>Stephenson. I believe they are same.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I never touch'd the curtains; I never wrong'd any body of a farthing in my life; I found them pieces in Monmouth-street; I came from Cobham, and had not been in London above a fortnight; I am subject to fits, and I was afraid one of my fits was coming, made me go up stairs in the church.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17591024-12-verdict55" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17591024-12-verdict55" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
