<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17580222-28">
               <interp inst="t17580222-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580222-28" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580222-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580222"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580222-28" type="date" value="17580222"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580222-28-off148-c228" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580222-28-defend273 t17580222-28-off148 t17580222-28-verdict152"></join>
         
               <p>135. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17580222-28-defend273" type="defendantName">
                  
                     William 
                     Page 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17580222-28-alias-5" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580222-28-defend273 t17580222-28-alias-5"></join>Williams</rs>, otherwise <rs id="t17580222-28-alias-6" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580222-28-defend273 t17580222-28-alias-6"></join>Gage</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-28-defend273" type="surname" value="Page"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-28-defend273" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-28-defend273" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicated for <rs id="t17580222-28-off148" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580222-28-off148" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-28-off148" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17580222-28-victim276" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Webb 
                        <interp inst="t17580222-28-victim276" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580222-28-victim276" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580222-28-victim276" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580222-28-off148 t17580222-28-victim276"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17580222-28-viclabel149" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580222-28-victim276 t17580222-28-viclabel149"></join>; did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and stealing two-pistols, value 10 s. one gold watch, value 6 l. one silk purse, value 2 d. and nine guineas, the goods and money of the said John; and against his will
            </rs>, <rs id="t17580222-28-cd150" type="crimeDate">March 26</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580222-28-off148 t17580222-28-cd150"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580222-28-person277">
                  John 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17580222-28-person277" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-28-person277" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-28-person277" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About the 3d or 4th Sunday in the month of March last, at near one o'clock in the day, being in my chaise with 
               <persName id="t17580222-28-person278">
                  John 
                  Gunery 
               <interp inst="t17580222-28-person278" type="surname" value="Gunery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-28-person278" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-28-person278" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a foreigner, my servant, in <placeName id="t17580222-28-crimeloc151">Belfound-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17580222-28-crimeloc151" type="placeName" value="Belfound-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17580222-28-crimeloc151" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580222-28-off148 t17580222-28-crimeloc151"></join>, I heard a voice behind me; presently I saw a man, on a dark colour'd horse, with a pistol in his hand, and a crape over his face, which hung down to his breast. The boy driving very fast, the man galloped by the side of the chaise twenty yards, and when he came against the postillion he stop'd him. I was sitting on the off side. Then I saw a blue great coat sleeve, with a hand and a pistol in it, on that side on which I sat. I found that man also was craped, as the other was. He was on a grey horse. I immediately let down the glass of the chaise, knowing very well what the presenting of a pistol meant. I gave him my money in a purse, about ten or eleven guineas, and my watch, which was a gold one. Presently the man that had stop'd us came to the chaise side. Then the post boy was order'd to drive up a lane on the right hand side, going to Staines. The lane is about three quarters of a mile long. After we were near half way up it, they ordered the cha ise to stop, then they took away my two pistols, and said they were sure I had a great deal more money with me, and began to parley with me. He on the grey horse dismounted. I said in the condition I was, it would be rediculous in me to oppose them, and that I had no more that was sufficient for my travelling expences, I had a trunk with my cloaths behind the chaise, and one of them ordered my servant to give him the key of it. He opened it, and said to them, here is nothing but my master's wearing apparel. They examined it, and found it so. They asked me where I had taken the chaise, I said it was Mr. Day's at the post office. They asked me my name, I told them. Then they asked me if I was brother to a member of parliament of that name, I said no. I having notes about me, and fearing they should search me, I pull'd out about twenty or thirty shillings in silver, and said, I have got some silver if you'll have it. The man on the grey horse said he scorned to take any silver. Then I desired him to take a crown for a bowl of punch, so he took it. After that they desired me to stop a little while, or not to drive too fast. I should know my pistols again, could I see them. They were made by Freeman, his name is on them, mounted with silver screw barrels, but I never saw them since. They were with me twelve minutes, or a quarter of an hour. I can say nothing to the prisoner, having no idea of the men at all, nor even their sizes. I never saw the watch since.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580222-28-person279">
                  John 
                  Gunery 
               <interp inst="t17580222-28-person279" type="surname" value="Gunery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-28-person279" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-28-person279" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Webb. We were travelling last March to Staines. Two men came up, one on a dark horse, the other on a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175802220029"></xptr> grey one, one stop'd the postillion, and the other came up to the chaise; they had crape before their faces, so I could not distinguish their faces. One of them had a blue great coat, the other a light great coat. They took my master's watch and purse, and ordered the postillion to drive up a bye lane. Then one of them ask'd me for my pistols. I told him they were in the chaise. He took them. One of them said my master had more money, but my master said he had no more. I said, Gentlemen, I am but a servant, I have no money. One of them ask'd me for the key of the trunk that was behind the chaise, and bid me open it, which I did, and said there was nothing but my master's cloaths. They look'd in, but took nothing. My master pull'd some silver out, and said, Gentlemen, here it is, if you'll take some silver. One of them said he scorned to take silver. Master persuaded him to take a crown for a bowl of punch. After they had asked my master's name they went away, and ordered the postillion to drive softly. I don't know which way they went when they got into the road. I could not distinguish their faces. I know one was taller than the other.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580222-28-person280">
                  William 
                  Darwell 
               <interp inst="t17580222-28-person280" type="surname" value="Darwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-28-person280" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-28-person280" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner near twenty years. He was born at Hampton. I lived there upwards of three years. In March last, about the latter end, I and the prisoner at the bar set out from London, in order to commit robberies. His horse had been stopt before, and I being quite an unsuspected person, as he was afraid to walk the streets on another affair, I hired horses for us both. This we had agreed upon. I brought the first horse to him between seven and eight o'clock to a publick house at Marybone. He went there to wait for me, and he carried the arms, three brace of pistols. I saw him look out at the window. I went softly on, he came out, and took the horse, which was a blackish one. Then I came back to Mr. Leader's, at the bottom of Red Lion-street, Holbourn. There I took a grey horse for myself. I believe I got to the farthest sign of the Hatts in Oxford Road between ten and eleven o'clock, the prisoner was to stay for me there. I saw him, and he saw me. I call'd for some liquor at the door, and after that rode on. He soon followed me, and took me into Hounslow road. Then we agreed one should go to one inn, and the other to another. These were little inns before we came to Hounslow. I went to that nearest Hounslow. We were to wait till we found something worthy to attack. When he saw such, he was to come out, and I to mount and follow him. I sat forward, so that I could not miss seeing him as he came along. Presently came a post chaise, and soon after I saw him coming along. He passed me about ten minutes after the chaise did. Then I got my horse ready, and rode after him. We followed the chaise over Hounslow Heath. It was I believe between twelve and one o'clock when we set out from those inns. I join'd him on the Heath, and followed the chaise into Belfound-lane. Then he rode up, and ordered the postillion to stop. The gentleman in it pull'd out a small gold watch, and gave it to him. I rode up to the chaise, and demanded the gentleman's money. He gave it me in a green purse, about ten or eleven guineas, I am sure it was one of them. Then the prisoner ordered the postillion to drive up a lane on the right hand, where we ordered the gentleman to deliver the key of his trunk that was behind the chaise. There was another person in the chaise, which I found to be his servant; they got out of the chaise, and loosed the trunk from behind, but did not take it down. They unlock'd it, the prisoner dismounted to look into it; and they assured us there was nothing but wearing apparel. The prisoner asked if it was Day's chaise at Hounslow; they said it was. Then he said to the postillion, You are the sauciest fellow that travels this road. The gentleman offer'd us some silver, but that the prisoner refused. The gentleman forced a crown upon him for a bowl of punch for us to drink at night. The prosecutor is the gentleman.</p>

               <p>Q. Look about for the other?</p>
               <p>Darwell. This is the other (pointing to the servant) The gentleman desired he might have his watch and pistols again, he said the watch cost about ten guineas, and he'd pay us the value of it, as we should order. We left him, and went over Walton Bridge; we stop'd at a little house about an hour, and drank. Then we went to the King's Head at Martin, and there staid all night, and lay together in one bed. We got in there after dark. Next morning I met with 
               <persName id="t17580222-28-person281">
                  Henry 
                  Harvey 
               <interp inst="t17580222-28-person281" type="surname" value="Harvey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-28-person281" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-28-person281" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a discharged dragoon there. I was servant to the major of the same troop, we were all three in company there, and I had a good deal of discourse with him. I remember there was a very fat man, a blacksmith, there at the time. This was about ten the next morning. We staid there so long, in order to wait for carriages out of town, so to go upon the Croydon road. We went away about eleven o'clock, to a publick house, a little on this side Croydon. The prisoner allowed me three guineas, or three guineas and a half for my share of the watch and pistols, and he took them with him, when he embarked on board a ship for Scotland,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175802220030"></xptr> about five or six weeks after. We shared the money that we took in the purse. After the prisoner returned, he and I set out in July last, in order to commit some robberies on the Tunbridge road, and I was taken a little beyond Seven Oaks in Kent, on the road, by several people, and the next day I told Mr. Curtice some few circumstances of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580222-28-person282">
                  William 
                  Philips 
               <interp inst="t17580222-28-person282" type="surname" value="Philips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-28-person282" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-28-person282" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Globe in Pall-Mall. I knew Darwell and the prisoner from children, at Hampton town, who were acquainted like brothers; but I don't know that I have seen them together these ten years.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580222-28-person283">
                  Henry 
                  Harvey 
               <interp inst="t17580222-28-person283" type="surname" value="Harvey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-28-person283" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-28-person283" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was once a dragoon, and am acquainted with Darwell. I saw him at the King's Head at Martin some time in March, 1757, on a forenoon, where was a man with him; but whether the prisoner is the person I don't know. They had both whips in their hands, but I did not see them go away, so can say nothing of the horses.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580222-28-person284">
                  William 
                  Bailey 
               <interp inst="t17580222-28-person284" type="surname" value="Bailey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-28-person284" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-28-person284" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the King's-Head at Martin. I know Henry Harvey, and know he was in company with two men, about the latter end of March, on a forenoon. The two men lay at my house the night before, and, I believe, both in one bed; but I cannot say I recollect the men; I can say nothing of the prisoner. I was at home when they came in on horseback; it was after dark. I did not see their horses, nor see them go away.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember a very fat man being at your house, at the time the two men were there with Harvey?</p>
               <p>Bailey. There was a blacksmith, a very fat man, at our town at that time, but I don't remember his being there then.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580222-28-person285">
                  William 
                  Marsden 
               <interp inst="t17580222-28-person285" type="surname" value="Marsden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-28-person285" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580222-28-person285" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Darwell was in Maidstone-Gaol. I was with Mr. Fielding at Chelmsford, at the last assizes. While we were attending the trial of a man for robbing the mail, there came a letter, giving an account of a robbery committed. After that I heard Darwell was in Maidstone Gaol, where I went to see him, and take his information, concerning what houses Page used on the road; who gave me an account of many. Mr. Barnes took Page about a fortnight after this, at the Golden-Lion, by Grosvenor-Square Gate. There were three pistols loaded about him, two horse pistols and a pocket one. We found also a wig, a cockade, a powder horn full of powder, and about half a dozen balls. ( Note, Page were his own hair.) We took a book from him after we brought him to Mr. Fielding, in which is an account of all the bye roads. He said very little before justice Fielding. (The pistols produced in court.)</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>In regard to the charge that Darwell has given against me, I really know nothing of it. I never had any connection with him in any such circumstances. I own I knew him when I was a boy at school, and had some correspondence with him some years ago; but since that I know nothing of him, and why he should place this matter to my account, I don't know. He has had access to my lodgings, and has had a long connection with Mr. Fielding from his own testimony. He is every thing that is bad and infamous, in declaring himself a highwayman. He would have given testimony against any person that he should happen to fix upon, to save his own life. He glories in his wickedness. I am much confused at this time, and can't speak so freely as I would. Under these circumstances I submit it to the gentlemen to consider of it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17580222-28-verdict152" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580222-28-verdict152" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>[He was detained for several felonies committed in Kent, Surry, Berks, and Hertfordshire.</p>
            </div1>
