<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17541204-17">
               <interp inst="t17541204-17" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541204-17" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541204-17" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17541204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541204-17" type="date" value="17541204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17541204-17-off82-c154" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541204-17-defend189 t17541204-17-off82 t17541204-17-verdict86"></join>
         
               <p>21. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17541204-17-defend189" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Woollet 
                  <interp inst="t17541204-17-defend189" type="surname" value="Woollet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-17-defend189" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-17-defend189" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             was indicted for <rs id="t17541204-17-off82" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17541204-17-off82" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-17-off82" type="offenceSubcategory" value="gameLawOffence"></interp>
               that he, together with one 
                     <persName id="t17541204-17-person190">
                        James 
                        Deadman 
                     <interp inst="t17541204-17-person190" type="surname" value="Deadman"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17541204-17-person190" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17541204-17-person190" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , not yet taken, after the 1st day of June, 1723, to wit, on the <rs id="t17541204-17-cd83" type="crimeDate">28th day of August</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541204-17-off82 t17541204-17-cd83"></join>, 1754, unlawfully and wilfully did wound, kill, destroy, and carry away two fallow deer, value 4 l. 4 s. belonging to 
                     
                        <persName id="t17541204-17-victim192" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Hallet 
                        <interp inst="t17541204-17-victim192" type="surname" value="Hallet"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17541204-17-victim192" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17541204-17-victim192" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541204-17-off82 t17541204-17-victim192"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17541204-17-viclabel84" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541204-17-victim192 t17541204-17-viclabel84"></join>; which were kept in a certain park or ground of him the said William, inclosed within a brick wall, and other fences, where deer then were, and now are kept
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541204-17-person193">
                  William 
                  Hallet 
               <interp inst="t17541204-17-person193" type="surname" value="Hallet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-17-person193" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-17-person193" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; On the 28th day of August last, two deer were killed in my park, which is in the parish of <placeName id="t17541204-17-crimeloc85">Little-Stanmore</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17541204-17-crimeloc85" type="placeName" value="Little-Stanmore"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17541204-17-crimeloc85" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541204-17-off82 t17541204-17-crimeloc85"></join>; the heads were cut off, and the entrails taken out, which were left behind, the bodies were carried away.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you had that park?</p>
               <p>W. Hallet. I have had it two years.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a park before?</p>
               <p>W. Hallet. I believe it was not:</p>
               <p>Q. How many head of deer were there in this park?</p>
               <p>W. Hallet. I had about forty-five head.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of your own knowledge that these deer were taken away, or do you imagine you lost two from your servants telling of you?</p>
               <p>W. Hallet. I saw the heads and the entrails lying, and I missed two of my number; seeing this, I sent to the man who keeps the turnpikegate, to know whether any people had passed through that looked suspicious of having deer? He said, that between one and two o'clock in the morning, there were three men rode through upon horses, they had sacks with them, and gave such a description of one of them, that I had reason to suspect him, he being employed by me as a hay-maker, which is the evidence of Cooper, upon which a search-warrant was got, and the constable is in court that searched the apartment of the evidence; I was not at the searching.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541204-17-person194">
                  Thomas 
                  James 
               <interp inst="t17541204-17-person194" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-17-person194" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-17-person194" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was employed by 'squire Hallet to search for the venison; I went to the apartment of the evidence Cooper and one Coral, there I found this sack and snare, (producing them) he confessed he catched the deer; we put them in a coach; there the prisoner behaved unruly, and said to the evidence, Well, Cooper, we should have Deadman with us; as we are all guilty alike, we ought all to suffer alike.</p>
               <p>Q. Had any body spoke of Deadman before?</p>
               <p>T. James. Not one soul. I told him, I thought he run a great risque to venture his neck for a deer. He said, he wished he had known nothing about the deer, and wished he had been taken about a week before, that he might have known his doom, and not have lain rotting in a gaol.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find any part of the deer in that sack.</p>
               <p>T. James. No, there was nothing in the sack; but it was bloody, and a great deal of the coat of the deer upon it; but we found no part of the venison at all.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541204-17-person195">
                  David 
                  Cooper 
               <interp inst="t17541204-17-person195" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-17-person195" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-17-person195" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . We catched the two deer with this snare; I took one, Deadman the other, and the prisoner, who is the butcher, cut off the heads, and took the entrails out. He was with us in the park; we met at a public-house near Grosvenor-square; this was between seven and eight o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. What day of the month?</p>
               <p>D. Cooper. I cannot tell what day it was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner with you at the alehouse, or only you and Deadman?</p>
               <p>D. Cooper. The prisoner was with us; I was saying I worked there, and there were such things in the park, and we all agreed to go.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you make the proposal at the alehouse, or before you went there?</p>
               <p>D. Cooper. Before: when we got there, the prisoner cut the heads off, and the entrails out.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175412040016"></xptr> and left the heads and entrails behind; we carried them away upon horses; we had three horses.</p>
               <p>Q. Who produced the Snare?</p>
               <p>D. Cooper. Deadman brought the snare to me; I never killed a deer with him before, but I knew he followed that way.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath, was the prisoner with you in the park?</p>
               <p>D. Cooper. He was, and cut the heads off; we all three went together; we got over by the iron spikes; it was very nigh one o'clock in the morning: we put our horses into a lane, and tied them to a hedge; we took a horse's halter and tied it to the deer, and one pulled, and the other heaved them up over the wall.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I never was there in my life, nor don't know the place.</p>
               <p>Q. to Cooper. How long have you known the prisoner?</p>
               <p>D. Cooper. Four or five years; he lived at a place called the Old Ruins, Broad St. Giles's; he is a porter to a market.</p>
               <p>Q. How many horses had you, when you went for the deer.</p>
               <p>D. Cooper. Three, the prisoner brought one of the horses all the way.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was at the alehouse when Deadman was there; they spoke for two horses; I said I would not go with them, I did not want a horse. The evidence told me, he had killed an out-lying deer; that he had been a hunting with this gentleman where he worked, that the deer had got out, and the gentleman had given over looking for it; and then he said they were any bodies: they would have had three horses; but I told them they might have but two, for I would not go; but if they brought them, I would cut them up for them; they gave me some liquor, and a trifle of money. I am innocent.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541204-17-person196">
                  Francis 
                  Parker 
               <interp inst="t17541204-17-person196" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-17-person196" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541204-17-person196" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a baker, and live in Wardour-street, St. Anne's; I have known the prisoner seven years; his character has been extraordinary good as far as ever I heard; I never knew he did any misdemeanor; he is a butcher, and was set up in Newport-market; he was not a shop-keeper when he was taken up; I never heard him charged with deer-stealing before this unfortunate affair.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17541204-17-verdict86" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17541204-17-verdict86" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
