<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570713-30">
               <interp inst="t17570713-30" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570713-30" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570713-30" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570713"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570713-30" type="date" value="17570713"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570713-30-off141-c223" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570713-30-defend273 t17570713-30-off141 t17570713-30-verdict144"></join>
         
               <p>276. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17570713-30-defend273" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Charles 
                     Steward 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17570713-30-alias-2" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570713-30-defend273 t17570713-30-alias-2"></join>Conner</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-30-defend273" type="surname" value="Steward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-30-defend273" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-30-defend273" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17570713-30-off141" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570713-30-off141" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-30-off141" type="offenceSubcategory" value="fraud"></interp>
               that he, together with John Green, not taken, did conspire to cheat and defraud 
                     
                        <persName id="t17570713-30-victim276" type="victimName">
                           Joseph 
                           Hicks 
                        <interp inst="t17570713-30-victim276" type="surname" value="Hicks"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570713-30-victim276" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570713-30-victim276" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570713-30-off141 t17570713-30-victim276"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   of a forrel gelding, value 6 l. by divers arts and pretences
            </rs>, <rs id="t17570713-30-cd142" type="crimeDate">March 31</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570713-30-off141 t17570713-30-cd142"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570713-30-person277">
                  Joseph 
                  Hicks 
               <interp inst="t17570713-30-person277" type="surname" value="Hicks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-30-person277" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-30-person277" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am <rs id="t17570713-30-viclabel143" type="occupation">coachman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570713-30-victim276 t17570713-30-viclabel143"></join> to Mr. Howard in Hatton-Garden. On the 31st of March the prisoner and one Green, not taken, came to me at the George in Leather-Lane, and the prisoner agreed to give me 6 l. for a forrel gelding. He desired I would take him to the Bell Savage-inn on Ludgate-Hill, where I was to be paid; I went. They ordered the hostler to put him into the stable. Then the prisoner said to me, you must go with me to the Temple-Exchange coffee house, and there I will pay you for him. Then we all three went out with an intent to go there, but before we got there Green gave me the slip, and went away. When the prisoner got me to the coffee-house, and had kept me about ten minutes, I desired him to pay me, for I could not stay. He said have a little patience, Green is gone to change a 20 l. bank note. When I began to be impatient he said I believe I can find Green, he is gone to Symond's inn cellar, Chancery-Lane. We set out from thence<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175707130027"></xptr> in order to go there. When we came there he said to the landlord, has Green been here? The landlord said no. Then he said my wife by, and if she is at home I can a will for the horse. I went with him to a place near Fetter-Lane, where a woman said she was gone out. Then he said we must go to Symond's inn-cellar again, which we did. Then he ask'd the landlord if Green had been there since we went out. The landlord said no. Then he said, come coachman let us drink a tankard of beer. I said I could not stay. Said he you think I want to cheat you out of your horse; if I can't pay you, you can but have him again, so you may go and take him. I said, then you must go along with me. He said, I will not. I said, they will not let me have him, for he was delivered in your name. I desired the landlord to get a porter, in order to send to the Bell-Savage-Inn for the horse. A porter came, and I gave him an order to go for the horse; then the prisoner said he'd go along with me, so I call'd the porter back. We went down Chancery-Lane, almost to the bottom of Fleet-street. He said, suppose the horse should be gone from thence. I said, nobody can take a horse of your's or mine without an order. When I got there I inquired of the hostle, who said a porter had been for him, and had taken him away. I ask'd him whose name he came in. He said the prisoner had given a note to him before I went out of the yard: The contents were, to deliver the horse to any man that should come for him.</p>

               <p>Q. Was the prisoner by at this conversation ?</p>
               <p>Hicks. He was. The hostler gave me the note. I said to the prisoner your name is 
               <persName id="t17570713-30-person278">
                  Charles 
                  Steward 
               <interp inst="t17570713-30-person278" type="surname" value="Steward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-30-person278" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-30-person278" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , is it? He said yes. Said I, you remember you have not paid me for it. D - n your horse said he, I know nothing of him, he is gone from hence. I said I shall detain you till you find either money or horse.</p>
               <p>Q. How was the prisoner dressed then?</p>
               <p>Hicks. In a light colour'd coat and waistcoat embroider'd with gold. He was carried to the compter in that dress. I remember he had another coat on the next day, when he came to go before my Lord mayor. Six days after this Green sent me word, by some acquaintance, I might have my horse again. I ordered him to bring him to the Horse and Groom, in Eagle Street, by Red Lion-Square, where he sent him, and I had him again. Since the prisoner has been in Newgate he sent for me, and desired me not to appear against him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570713-30-person279">
                  William 
                  Bretrage 
               <interp inst="t17570713-30-person279" type="surname" value="Bretrage"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-30-person279" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-30-person279" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 31st of March, in the evening, I was at the George in Leather Lane, where I saw Mr. Hicks, the prisoner, and Green bargaining for a chesnut gelding; they agreed for 6 l. The prisoner gave Mr. Hicks a shilling, and bid them take to the Bell Savage Ludgate Hill, and deliver him; and he was to pay the rest of the money. Mr. Hicks took away the horse directly.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570713-30-person280">
                  Alexander 
                  Coning 
               <interp inst="t17570713-30-person280" type="surname" value="Coning"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-30-person280" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-30-person280" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I remember a chestnut-horse being brought to the B age-Inn on the 31st of March, by 
               <persName id="t17570713-30-person281">
                  Joseph 
                  Hicks 
               <interp inst="t17570713-30-person281" type="surname" value="Hicks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-30-person281" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-30-person281" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who said he had sold him to the prisoner at the bar. The prisoner was there, who ordered Hicks to deliver him to me, and the prisoner ordered me to give him a feed of corn, and said he shou'd send for him as soon as he had eat his corn, and delivered me a note. Produced and read.</p>
               <p>'' Hostler, deliver my sorrel horse to the bearer, '' upon paying for his standing, your's,</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570713-30-person282">
                  CHARLES 
                  STEWARD 
               <interp inst="t17570713-30-person282" type="surname" value="STEWARD"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-30-person282" type="given" value="CHARLES"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-30-person282" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .''</p>
               <p>March 3, 1757.</p>
               <p>About half an hour or three quarters after, a porter, named 
               <persName id="t17570713-30-person283">
                  David 
                  Pugh 
               <interp inst="t17570713-30-person283" type="surname" value="Pugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-30-person283" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-30-person283" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , came for him, and I delivered him the horse.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is he?</p>
               <p>Coning. He is not here.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Was it not with Mr. Hick's consent, that I should send for the horse when I thought proper?</p>
               <p>Coning. I know nothing of any consent of Mr. Hicks.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>This horse was brought by Mr. Hicks in order to be delivered to me when I sent for him. Green came to an unfortunate man in the Press yard in Newgate, Mr. Gatewood, who was executed for robbing the mail, about sending money into the country to subpoena witnesses for him, and he ran away from me, and took the horse unknown to me. When I was going to advertise the horse Green got knowledge of it, and he sent the horse to Mr Hicks. If my consinement has not been a sufficient punishment for the crime, and the court find me guilty, I hope I shall be sent on board a ship to serve my king and country.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570713-30-verdict144" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570713-30-verdict144" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570713-30-punish145" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570713-30-punish145" type="punishmentCategory" value="corporal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-30-punish145" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="pillory"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570713-30-defend273 t17570713-30-punish145"></join>
               
                     <note>[Pillory. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570713-30-punish146" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570713-30-punish146" type="punishmentCategory" value="imprison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-30-punish146" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="newgate"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570713-30-defend273 t17570713-30-punish146"></join>
               
                     <note>[Imprisonment. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570713-30-punish147" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570713-30-punish147" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570713-30-punish147" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="sureties"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570713-30-defend273 t17570713-30-punish147"></join>
               
                     <note>[Provide sureties for good behaviour. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
