<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17540717-29">
               <interp inst="t17540717-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540717-29" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540717-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540717"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540717-29" type="date" value="17540717"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540717-29-off139-c224" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-29-defend279 t17540717-29-off139 t17540717-29-verdict142"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540717-29-off143-c224" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-29-defend279 t17540717-29-off143 t17540717-29-verdict142"></join>
         
               <p>375. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17540717-29-defend279" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Hodson 
                  <interp inst="t17540717-29-defend279" type="surname" value="Hodson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-defend279" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-defend279" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for <rs id="t17540717-29-off139" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-off139" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-off139" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he, together with 
                     <persName id="t17540717-29-person280">
                        James 
                        Harding 
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-person280" type="surname" value="Harding"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540717-29-person280" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540717-29-person280" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , not yet taken, on the king's high-way, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17540717-29-victim282" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Saunders 
                        <interp inst="t17540717-29-victim282" type="surname" value="Saunders"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540717-29-victim282" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540717-29-victim282" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and stealing 9 d. 1\2 from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17540717-29-cd140" type="crimeDate">May 28</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-29-off139 t17540717-29-cd140"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-29-off143 t17540717-29-cd140"></join>.* </p>
               <p>Thomas Saunders, On the 28th of May last, about 10 at night, I was going on horseback from London to my home at Barkhamstead in Hertfordshire, there met me two men on horseback, one on my left hand side and the other in the road I was in; I asked them what they wanted; the man on my left hand said to the other, he seems to be an honest man, let him go along; upon that I turned out of the way and rode on, and did not think of any harm at all. I rode slowly on towards a place called <placeName id="t17540717-29-crimeloc141">Stanmore</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17540717-29-crimeloc141" type="placeName" value="Stanmore"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17540717-29-crimeloc141" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-29-off139 t17540717-29-crimeloc141"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-29-off143 t17540717-29-crimeloc141"></join>. I heard a hallowing and a riding fast behind me, as I was going up the hill to Stanmore; they rode past me, there were two of them.</p>
         
               <p>In a few Days Part II. will be published.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17540717-29">
                  <interp inst="t17540717-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17540717-29" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17540717-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540717"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17540717-29" type="date" value="17540717"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175407170021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 17th, Thursday the 18th, Friday the 19th, Saturday the 20th, and Monday the 22nd of JULY.</p>
                  <p>In the 27th Year of His MAJESTY's Reign. PART II. of NUMBER VI. for the Year 1754. BEING THE Sixth SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of the Right Hon. 
                  <persName id="t17540717-29-person283">
                     Thomas 
                     Rawlinson 
                  <interp inst="t17540717-29-person283" type="surname" value="Rawlinson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540717-29-person283" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540717-29-person283" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Esq; LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by M. COOPER, at the Globe in Pater-noster Row. 1754.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175407170022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>Kings Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery held for the City of London, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Q. WERE they the same persons you had met before?</p>
               <p>Saunders. I really can't say they were or not. I went on as before, when I came to the top of Stanmore there was a man stood dismounted with his horse in his hand. I rode about 100 or 150 yards past him, then there was a man on horseback in the highway, with his face towards me. I offered to turn out of the road, and he stopped me; I asked him what he meant, or what he wanted; he said he wanted my money.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any thing in his hand?</p>
               <p>Saunders. No, I did not. Then I told him I had not got any; then he said, d - n your blood I'll blow your brains out, if you don't give me that bag you have got. I told him I had but a few halfpence and a six-pence. Then he asked me for my watch, I told him I did not carry one. He felt on the wasteband of my breeches to see if I had one. Finding I had none, he demanded what money I had, so I gave it him, which was 9 d. 1/2.</p>
               <p>Q. Look upon the prisoner, do you know him ?</p>
               <p>Saunders. I do not, I can't say this is the person. Then he turned out of the road and came towards London, and I went on my way and wished him a good night. As he went to go by me I looked on his mare and saw something of a skin for a housing behind. I rode slowly on; after which I heard a horse follow me pretty swiftly again; I turned my head about and perceived him to be a horse without a rider. I judged it to be one of the highwaymen's horses. I rode as fast as I could towards Bushey, the mare came following me all the way, and when I stopped at Bushey, she came directly up to me; I laid hold of her bridle, which was upon her neck. I considered some time to know what I had best to do. I stood still, and hearing nobody coming, I went to the Red-lion inn, and called the man of the house, whose name is Cook, he came to the window, I told him I had been robbed, and that I had got the man's mare that robbed me, and desired he'd call the ostler immediately, for I looked upon myself to be in danger. The ostler came and let me in at the gate, and fastened it again. I delivered the mare to him, and desired him to take care of her. I staid there all night.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there a saddle and housing behind upon that mare?</p>
               <p>Saunders. There were, but no housing before. It was a hare housing, like that the man rode that robbed me. The next morning I told the man of the house about the mare, and thought it proper to have her cry'd at three market towns. I left her there with the bridle and saddle, and went home. I had not been at home above two or three days before I was sent for to go to Justice Capper's, and I told him all that I knew, the same as I have done here, as near as I can remember.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. When did this happen?</p>
               <p>Saunders. On the 28th of May about half an hour after 11 o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it not dark?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175407170023"></xptr>Saunders. No, it was not, it was pretty clearish.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you see the person's face that robbed you?</p>
               <p>Saunders. I could not, he did what he could to hide that from me.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you call the housing?</p>
               <p>Saunders. I think it is bear skin.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it light enough to distinguish that?</p>
               <p>Saunders. It was, I could see it very plain.</p>
               <p>Q. You call it a mare, did you know it to be a mare when you was robbed?</p>
               <p>Saunders. No, but I found it to be a mare afterwards.</p>

               <p>Q. Can you take upon you to swear it was the same housing that the man had that robbed you?</p>
               <p>Saunders. I can, it was the very same.</p>
               <p>Jeffery Edwards. On the 28th of May the prisoner at the bar hired the mare of me to go out of town.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen her since?</p>
               <p>Edwards. I have at Justice Fieldings.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you deliver the mare to him?</p>
               <p>Edwards. I sent her to him to his master's, Mr. Lebass, in the afternoon of that day, about 4 or 5 o'clock, he hired her for 3 days. She did not come home according to bargain. Then I went to the person that recommended this man to me. The prisoner had sent for me the afternoon of the day he came home, but I could not go to him, but went to him on the Saturday following, (the 28th of May was on a Tuesday.) The prisoner would not tell me where the mare was, but said she was very safe, and he'd pay me for her, which he accordingly did very honestly.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he give you for her?</p>
               <p>Edwards. He gave me 10 guineas for the mare, bridle and saddle.</p>
               <p>Q. Describe the saddle, bridle and housing.</p>
               <p>Edwards. The housing was a hare housing, it is a bear or Leopard's skin, a mixed mottled thing, the saddle was a common one.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you known the prisoner any time?</p>
               <p>Edwards. I have known him by sight.</p>
               <p>Q. What business is he?</p>
               <p>Edwards. He is a cooper by trade, he worked with Mr. Lebass, a brewer, at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. What might he get a year by his business?</p>
               <p>Edwards. I don't know that.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he appear in his business at that time he paid you for the horse?</p>
               <p>Edwards. He did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he continue in his business till he was taken up, which was on the 11th of June?</p>
               <p>Edwards. I don't know that.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he disappear?</p>
               <p>Edwards. I don't know that he did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-29-person284">
                  Robert 
                  Hammond 
               <interp inst="t17540717-29-person284" type="surname" value="Hammond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-person284" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-person284" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Swan the upper end of Oxford road, the prisoner and Harding stopped at my house and had a quartern of brandy or rum. I don't know which.</p>
               <p>Q. What day was it on?</p>
               <p>Hammond. I don't justly know, I believe it was on a Tuesday.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it the Tuesday before the robbery?</p>
               <p>Hammond. I did not hear of the robbery till about a fortnight after; it answered to the time I believe, I imagine it was on that day, but I can't be certain.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was it?</p>
               <p>Hammond. I believe it was about 12 o'clock at noon.</p>
               <p>Q. Recollect whether it was the day before the 29th of May, there are a many oak boughs about then.</p>
               <p>Hammond. I can't recollect oak boughs. Harding left a message with me for his master, Mr. Rocket, a stone-cutter.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known Harding?</p>
               <p>Hammond. I have known him these 2 years.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he in his business now?</p>
               <p>Hammond. No, Sir, not with Mr. Rocket.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he in business any where else?</p>
               <p>Hammond. I don't know that he is.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you heard he is absent?</p>
               <p>Hammond. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take any notice of the saddles or any thing behind them?</p>
               <p>Hammond. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-29-person285">
                  Michael 
                  Timms 
               <interp inst="t17540717-29-person285" type="surname" value="Timms"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-person285" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-person285" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Red-lion at Kilbourne, Harding and another person came on horseback to my house about 7 o'clock in the evening on the 28th of May, and called for a pint of beer.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the other person?</p>
               <p>Timms. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at the prisoner, is that the man?</p>
               <p>Timms. I can't take upon me to say it is. They both alighted from their horses and went into the house, and there called for a quartern of gin; Harding desired I'd drink part of it, I told him I never drank any at all, then he said bring a quartern of rum, which I did. Then he said to my spouse, I suppose you don't know that man (meaning the person that was with him) we both said we<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175407170024"></xptr> did not; then he said it is my brother-in law, he married my sister, and said they were going down to Watford to see his mother, and asked if she could make a bed up for us against we came back, which would be about 11 o'clock, for that they did not purpose to lie at his mother's, and that then they should be fresh to go to work in the morning. I remember when he came up to my house he turned back to the person with him, and said, d - n it, this mare will never do, she is too fat and too heavy for the lay.</p>
               <p>Q. What answer did the other person make to that?</p>
               <p>Timms. He made no answer. In the mean time came Mr. Milking's two daughters from Edger riding by, and Harding went in a doors, and into the parlour, seemingly because he would not see them. They paid for what they had and went away.</p>
               <p>Q. Did your wife make up a bed for them?</p>
               <p>Timms. She did, but they did not come, I have not seen Harding since.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did they go away?</p>
               <p>Timms. They went away about half an hour past 7 o'clock, after, they had staid about half an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe their horses and saddles?</p>
               <p>Timms. I took a great deal of notice of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Had one of them a housing?</p>
               <p>Timms. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Which rode that horse?</p>
               <p>Timms. The person that was with Harding did.</p>
               <p>Q. Had Harding any Housing?</p>
               <p>Timms. No, he had none, to the best of my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a housing was it?</p>
               <p>Timms. It was skin with the hair on.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember the dress the man (he called his brother-in-law) was in?</p>
               <p>Timms. I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure that was the same mare that was stopped at the Red-lion?</p>
               <p>Timms. I am positive it was the same, I have seen her several times since.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Counsel. You say you, remember that Harding said, that man that was with him was his brother-in-law?</p>
               <p>Timms. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see them in company together ?</p>
               <p>Timms. I cannot take upon me to say I have.</p>
               <p>Court. What is your belief as to the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Timms. Dress alters people much; I can't take upon me to swear he is the man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-29-person286">
                  John 
                  Treacher 
               <interp inst="t17540717-29-person286" type="surname" value="Treacher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-person286" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-person286" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the White Hart at Bushey; opposite to the Red Lion; Harding came to my house on the 29th of May, in the morning, between five and six o'clock, and told me he had had a damnable misfortune; he and a companion of his were coming down to see his mother; that they were both got drunk, and his companion's mare had thrown him in Stanmore pond, and was run away.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Harding's mother?</p>
               <p>Treacher. I do, she keeps an inn at Watford; I was born and bred there, and have known him from a child.</p>
               <p>Q. How many sisters has Harding?</p>
               <p>Treacher. I can't say whether there is one or two.</p>
               <p>Q. Are any of them married?</p>
               <p>Treacher. I know one, she is unmarried; and I don't know whether there is another or not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I know myself innocent, and have a great many witnesses to call, which I hope will prove it.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-29-person287">
                  William 
                  Doleman 
               <interp inst="t17540717-29-person287" type="surname" value="Doleman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-person287" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-person287" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner five or six years.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he a married man?</p>
               <p>Dole. He is.</p>
               <p>Q. Whose daughter is she?</p>
               <p>Doleman. I don't know her maiden name.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he been publick in his business since this robbery was committed?</p>
               <p>Doleman. He has; he threw down a butt of beer for me since that.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Doleman. It was never stained as I know of; he bears the character of a very honest man; he maintains his family very well.</p>
               <p>Mr. Herne. I am broad clerk to Mr. Lebass; the prisoner was cooper; I have known him about two years, during which time he has been under my direction.</p>
               <p>Q. Can he get a good livelihood by his business?</p>
               <p>Herne. He is paid 15 s. per week from the counting-house, and he has a shilling a butt for fining it, or 9 d. and a full pot of beer; it is as good as 28 or 30 s. per week.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175407170025"></xptr>Q. Has he a family ?</p>
               <p>Herne. He has.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what was his wife's maiden name ?</p>
               <p>Herne. I don't know whose daughter she was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you look upon him to be honest before this affair?</p>
               <p>Herne. I had a great reason to believe him so; he has seen me receive large sums of money, and I have desired him to attend me home; he never attempted to affront or misuse me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he in his business constantly after the 28th of May?</p>
               <p>Herne. I can't take upon me to say so; I did not observe him.</p>
               <p>Mr. Povey. I am a cooper by trade; the prisoner at the bar was servant to me three years. About five years ago he behaved like a very honest good servant; upon which I recommended him to Mr. Lebass, and he has been advanced by his master since he has been with him; he has made him his broad cooper.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he a married man?</p>
               <p>Povey. He is; I knew his wife from a child.</p>
               <p>Q. What was her maiden name?</p>
               <p>Povey. Her maiden name was 
               <persName id="t17540717-29-person288">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17540717-29-person288" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-person288" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-person288" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Did he attend his master's business after the 28th of May?</p>
               <p>Povey. He never absented from it at all till the time he was taken up. He was in my shop several times after that. Was he this minute clear, I think I could not have a better servant. I believe him to be a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-29-person289">
                  Patrick 
                  Halfpenny 
               <interp inst="t17540717-29-person289" type="surname" value="Halfpenny"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-person289" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-person289" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him seven or eight years; I am a baker; he lodged in my house three years some years ago; he married his wife in the time; her maiden name was Smith.</p>
               <p>Q. What was his general character ?</p>
               <p>Halfpenny. He has the character of a very honest hard-working man, one that takes good care of his family. There has been hardly a day these four or five years but I have seen him. I do really think that I have seen him every day in my life in that time.</p>
               <p>Q. What days did you see him after the 28th of May ?</p>
               <p>Halfpenny. I can't say as to the particular days; I drank with him about an hour before he was taken up; then he was in his business, putting down some beer in a cellar.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-29-person290">
                  Thomas 
                  Pryer 
               <interp inst="t17540717-29-person290" type="surname" value="Pryer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-person290" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-person290" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a bricklayer; I have known the prisoner about nine or ten years; he has lodg'd with me about five years last past; his wife's maiden name was Smith; he behaved as well as any man could do in point of honesty, sobriety and industry. He lived with me down to the time he was taken up.</p>
               <p>Q. What hours did he use to keep?</p>
               <p>Pryer. I never knew any man keep better hours in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he publickly about your house after the 28th of June?</p>
               <p>Pryer. He was. He stood three hours at my door since that with a gentlewoman that lodges in my house, whom he might have robbed of three hundred pounds worth of things, when he would, had he been so minded. He was about his business usually every day till taken up.</p>
               <p>Court. Upon your oath, Where was he on the 28th of May at night?</p>
               <p>Pryer. I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Court. Was he in your house that night?</p>
               <p>Pryer. I can't say he was.</p>
               <p>Court. Did he go out on horseback that night?</p>
               <p>Pryer. I did not know that till afterwards.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-29-person291">
                  John 
                  Lovel 
               <interp inst="t17540717-29-person291" type="surname" value="Lovel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-person291" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-person291" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about five years; he is a very industrious pains-taking man. I look upon him to be a very honest man; I have frequently seen him about his business, and heard him called up all hours of the night, 12, 1, 2, 3, and 4 o'clock.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-29-person292">
                  John 
                  Bell 
               <interp inst="t17540717-29-person292" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-person292" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-person292" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live next house to Mr. Lebass. I have known him about two years; during that time he has bore a very fair honest character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-29-person293">
                  Henry 
                  Goadspeed 
               <interp inst="t17540717-29-person293" type="surname" value="Goadspeed"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-person293" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-person293" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about three years and an half; I have seen him since the time of the robbery in his business; he has a very honest character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-29-person294">
                  Francis 
                  Broad 
               <interp inst="t17540717-29-person294" type="surname" value="Broad"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-person294" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-person294" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him five years, I never knew any thing but that he was an industrious man.</p>
               <p>Mr. Carr. I have known him about two years; he bears the general good character of an honest man. I live near the brewhouse, and have seen him since the 28th of May in his business. I was extremely surprized when I heard of this affair.</p>
               <p>Mr. Field. I have known him 6 or 7 years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Field. It is that of a very honest industrious man?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-29-person295">
                  Samuel 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17540717-29-person295" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-person295" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-person295" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about five years, I take him to be a very honest pains-taking sober man. I never heard any ill of him in my life. I have met him divers times in his business since the 28th of May.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540717-29-verdict142" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-verdict142" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a second time indicted, for <rs id="t17540717-29-off143" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-off143" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-off143" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he, on the King's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17540717-29-victim297" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Wilcox 
                        <interp inst="t17540717-29-victim297" type="surname" value="Wilcox"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540717-29-victim297" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540717-29-victim297" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17540717-29-viclabel144" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-29-victim297 t17540717-29-viclabel144"></join>,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175407170026"></xptr> did make an assault, putting her in corporal fear and danger of her life, and stealing from her person 4 s. 6 d. in money numbered
            </rs>, <rs id="t17540717-29-cd145" type="crimeDate">May 28</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-29-off139 t17540717-29-cd145"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-29-off143 t17540717-29-cd145"></join>.* </p> 
               <p>Mary Wilcox. On the 28th of May I was going from London to my master's country-house, called Bentley-house, near <placeName id="t17540717-29-crimeloc146">Stanmore</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17540717-29-crimeloc146" type="placeName" value="Stanmore"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17540717-29-crimeloc146" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-29-off139 t17540717-29-crimeloc146"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540717-29-off143 t17540717-29-crimeloc146"></join>, in a post-chaise; about the six-mile-stone from London, a man on horse-back bid the boy stop; then he came up to the window and demanded my money; being alone in it, I gave him either 4 s. 6 d. or 5 s. 6 d. I do not know which; but I can't take upon me to swear the prisoner is the man; he has some resemblance.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take any notice of housings to his saddle?</p>
               <p>Wilcox. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What colour was his horse?</p>
               <p>Wilcox. It was a black one.</p>
               <p>Q. A horse or a mare?</p>
               <p>Wilcox. That I can't say.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take any notice of the person's cloaths ?</p>
               <p>Wilcox. He had a dark grey coat and plain hat.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any body in company with him?</p>
               <p>Wilcox. There was a man behind the chaise at the time, a very little distance off, on horseback.</p>
               <p>Q. Which way did the person come up to you?</p>
               <p>Wilcox. He let me pass him, then he rode past me and stop'd us.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the man a mask on?</p>
               <p>Wilcox. No, he had not.</p>
               <p>Q. Which way did he go after you had lost your money?</p>
               <p>Wilcox. He rode towards London.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540717-29-person298">
                  Q.
                   John Barefoot
               <interp inst="t17540717-29-person298" type="surname" value="John Barefoot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-person298" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-person298" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I rode postilion to the chaise. The man rode before me a good way; then he turned out of the way, and I passed him; then he came riding up, and turned upon us, and said, Stop, you Sir, look the other way, or I'll blow your brains out. Then he demanded my fellow servant's money.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at the prisoner, do you know him?</p>
               <p>Barefoot. I don't know the man.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take any notice of the horse he rode?</p>
               <p>Barefoot. It was a black mare.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any thing particular besides the saddle ?</p>
               <p>Barefoot. I did not see the saddle?</p>
               <p>Q. Did yo u see any housing?</p>
               <p>Barefoot. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What were the colour of his cloaths?</p>
               <p>Barefoot. He had a blue grey coat on.</p>
               <p>Jeffery Edwards and 
               <persName id="t17540717-29-person299">
                  Robert 
                  Hammoud 
               <interp inst="t17540717-29-person299" type="surname" value="Hammoud"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-person299" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-person299" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed the same as in the other trial.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540717-29-verdict147" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540717-29-verdict147" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
