<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510703-21">
               <interp inst="t17510703-21" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510703-21" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510703-21" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510703"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510703-21" type="date" value="17510703"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510703-21-off102-c196" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-21-defend238 t17510703-21-off102 t17510703-21-verdict106"></join>
         
               <p>429. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17510703-21-defend238" type="defendantName">
                     Christopher 
                     Larkin 
                  <interp inst="t17510703-21-defend238" type="surname" value="Larkin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-21-defend238" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-21-defend238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for a <rs id="t17510703-21-off102" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510703-21-off102" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-21-off102" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               rape on the body of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17510703-21-victim240" type="victimName">
                           Jane 
                           Gallicote 
                        <interp inst="t17510703-21-victim240" type="surname" value="Gallicote"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510703-21-victim240" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510703-21-victim240" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-21-off102 t17510703-21-victim240"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , spinster, <rs id="t17510703-21-viclabel103" type="occupation">an infant not 11 years of age</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-21-victim240 t17510703-21-viclabel103"></join>
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17510703-21-cd104" type="crimeDate">June 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-21-off102 t17510703-21-cd104"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-21-person241">
                  Sarah 
                  Stevens 
               <interp inst="t17510703-21-person241" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-21-person241" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-21-person241" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am aunt to 
               <persName id="t17510703-21-person242">
                  Jane 
                  Gallicote 
               <interp inst="t17510703-21-person242" type="surname" value="Gallicote"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-21-person242" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-21-person242" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , she is between 10 and 11 years of age, she lives with me, and the prisoner lodg'd in my house two months or thereabouts, he behaved himself very well some t ime; on the 17th of June my husband and I went over the water, and left this child at home, and another of eight years of age came home from school at 12 o'clock; I live in <placeName id="t17510703-21-crimeloc105">Dolphin yard Crutched Friers</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17510703-21-crimeloc105" type="placeName" value="Dolphin yard Crutched Friers"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510703-21-crimeloc105" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-21-off102 t17510703-21-crimeloc105"></join>, and as we went over the hill the clock struck twelve; I left also an old man and two or three more journeymen taylor; when home; my husband is a journeyman taylor; when I came home about eight or nine at night, I found the children at home ; the girl was very well when I went out for what I knew; I observed something the matter by her shift the next day; she told me her private parts smarted like fire.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you know of this affair?</p>
               <p>S. Stevens. I observed her and found the part red and inflamed, it seemed as though the skin was off; the prisoner went to take his chest away, and would not pay me what he owed me, which was half a crown; the next day after this the girl told me what he had done to her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-21-person243">
                  Amy 
                  Saukster 
               <interp inst="t17510703-21-person243" type="surname" value="Saukster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-21-person243" type="given" value="Amy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-21-person243" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I go out a nursing; I came home; I live next door to her; this day fortnight at night I heard a great tumult at Mr. Stevens's house; I heard her call out, go and fetch a constable; I heard her say, are you going to murder me? she let this child out, and she fetched an officer; the prisoner was some time before he'd pay her; at last he did; I went home and fetched the girl, and Mrs. Stevens and I laid the girl on my bed and examined the part; I advised Mrs. Stevens to have a midwife ; the midwife persuaded her to take the prisoner up; I saw something extraordinary was the occasion of desiring the advice of a midwife.</p>
               <p>Q. Could not what you saw come by sweating, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>A. Saukster. No, Sir, it could not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the part torn?</p>
               <p>A. Saukster. I cannot say it was, Sir, it looked very sore, and seemed to have a very great running.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-21-person244">
                  Anne 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17510703-21-person244" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-21-person244" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-21-person244" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the last witness's house; the child came up very much affrighted on Monday was fortnight; I believe about one o'clock, the child desired we'd come down and put the man away; we asked what was the matter? she said, he was very impudent; the prisoner (I think it was) went out of Mrs. Stevens's house in about a quarter of an hour.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-21-person245">
                  Eleanor 
                  Rogers 
               <interp inst="t17510703-21-person245" type="surname" value="Rogers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-21-person245" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-21-person245" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Mrs. Saukster's; last Monday was fortnight the girl came up to the last vidence and I: she went on and confirmed her account.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-21-person246">
                  Henry 
                  Tompson 
               <interp inst="t17510703-21-person246" type="surname" value="Tompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-21-person246" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-21-person246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a surgeon, an apprentice to Mr. Harrison ; this girl was brought to the London hospital to be examined by the surgeons about a week ago; she had been there two or three times before, this was the last time; upon examination<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175107030017"></xptr> we found she had a gonorrhoea, that is what is commonly called a clap; there was no laceration, or any thing else but the running.</p>
               <p>Q. Had there been any penetration?</p>
               <p>Tompson. There had been none, no man could penetrate her body, she is of too tender an age for that; it was the opinion of all the surgeons there had been no penetration.</p>
               <p>Q. Could a gonorrhoea come without a penetration?</p>
               <p>Tompson. It might come by an impure cohesion.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you been apprentice?</p>
               <p>Tompson. I have served six years of my time. Upon this deposition the girl was not admitted to be sworn, the prisoner was <rs id="t17510703-21-verdict106" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510703-21-verdict106" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>, but another bill for a misdemeanour was preferred against him to be tried at Guildhall.</p>
            </div1>
