<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17580913-14">
               <interp inst="t17580913-14" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-14" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-14" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580913"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-14" type="date" value="17580913"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580913-14-off63-c93" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-14-defend117 t17580913-14-off63 t17580913-14-verdict67"></join>
         
               <p>271. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17580913-14-defend117" type="defendantName">
                     George 
                     Babb 
                  <interp inst="t17580913-14-defend117" type="surname" value="Babb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-14-defend117" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-14-defend117" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17580913-14-off63" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580913-14-off63" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-14-off63" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing one sorrel mare, value 6 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17580913-14-victim119" type="victimName">
                     Richard 
                     Davis 
                  <interp inst="t17580913-14-victim119" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-14-victim119" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-14-victim119" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-14-off63 t17580913-14-victim119"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17580913-14-cd64" type="crimeDate">August 14</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-14-off63 t17580913-14-cd64"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-14-person120">
                  Richard 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17580913-14-person120" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-14-person120" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-14-person120" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at <placeName id="t17580913-14-crimeloc65">Hackney</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17580913-14-crimeloc65" type="placeName" value="Hackney"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17580913-14-crimeloc65" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-14-off63 t17580913-14-crimeloc65"></join>, and am an <rs id="t17580913-14-viclabel66" type="occupation">apothecary</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-14-victim119 t17580913-14-viclabel66"></join>, on the 14th of August, in the evening, I left my mare at the rails at Mr. Brooks's at Hackney; while I was visiting a patient, I missed her from the door. I had hung her on the palisade, and in about a quarter of an hour, coming by that place, I saw her again held by the hand of a young man, whom I was informed was the prisoner at the bar, it was so dark I did not observe him so as to know him again; there were two other persons disputing with him, one said the other had no business with her, the other said he had good reason to ask him, being a stranger, what business he had with her, or to that purport; the young man held her while I mounted, and I rode on 2 or 300 yards to another patient; I ride with a double bridle, there I buckled the long rein to a rail. I have a buckle for that purpose about the middle of that rein. I staid in that house about ten or fifteen minutes; when I came out the mare was gone again, and no bridle remaining on the rail. Some time after I found her in the possession of my servant and a gentleman, who had got the prisoner with them; then I sent for an<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175809130010"></xptr> officer, and next day took him before justice Fielding, where he said he was in liquor, and knew little or nothing about the mare.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you find the rein of the bridle?</p>
               <p>Davis. The rein was cut.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-14-person121">
                  Richard 
                  Pettit 
               <interp inst="t17580913-14-person121" type="surname" value="Pettit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-14-person121" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-14-person121" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Davis, I was sent to see for the mare, by my master, when she was lost; I came home again and could not find her. I was sent out with some medicines, and going along the road, I found the prisoner on the back of her.</p>

               <p>Q. How far was this from the place where your master missed her?</p>
               <p>Pettit. It was about half a mile distance.</p>
               <p>Mr. Davis. She was lost from Mare-street Hackney, opposite Mr. Batcheldor's house.</p>
               <p>Pettit. That is about half a mile distance from the place where I found her.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner going towards London or the country?</p>
               <p>Pettit. He was going towards the country, Essex or Hertfordshire; the bridle was cut and hung down. I told him I thought he rode in danger, as his bridle was under the horse's feet. I then did not know it was my master's mare. I went near to him, he said he would satisfy me if I would get him somebody to mend it; when I discovered the mare, I kept him in discourse till I got him to a publick house; there I got a person to assist me, and brought him and the mare to my master's house.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>Pettit. This was very near 10 o'clock at night, my master had been at home then about half an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Pettit. I never saw him before to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. What time was it when you missed the mare the last time?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I apprehend it was more than nine o'clock when I missed her. It was not more than half an hour till she was brought to me, with the prisoner at the bar.</p>
               <p>Pettit. When I got the prisoner to that publick house, and charged him with taking my master's mare; he gave the bridle a snatch and wanted to get away, and then he pretended to be very much in liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he in liquor?</p>
               <p>Pettit. I really think he was not so much in liquor as he pretended to be; before Mr. Fielding he said he did not know how he came by the mare.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-14-person122">
                  William 
                  Covey 
               <interp inst="t17580913-14-person122" type="surname" value="Covey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-14-person122" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-14-person122" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going home the second Monday in August, I saw a man leading Mr. Davis's mare, I call'd to him to know what he was going to do with her; said he, I am leading her about. She having been taken from my door but the Saturday before, made me the more inquisitive about her. He led her from the foot way towards the road. I said to one Simpson that was with me, I fancy that man is going away with her. I ran after him, then he came back with the mare, and began to swear; and was very angry with me for troubling myself about it. Mr. Davis came out, and he held the mare while Mr. Davis mounted; and rode on, and the man followed him. Then I imagined he had come to call Mr. Davis to some patient. Mr. Simpson said to me when we first saw him, this is the man that served his time with Mr. Bosson.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-14-person123">
                  William 
                  Simpson 
               <interp inst="t17580913-14-person123" type="surname" value="Simpson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-14-person123" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-14-person123" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going home at that time with Mr. Covey, when we came to Church-road at Hackney, about nine at night or half an hour after, we saw the prisoner at the bar walking Mr. Davis's horse down the road. Covey desired me to stop a little, and said that mare was stole from his door the Saturday before, he call'd to the prisoner, he returned again with the mare; as he pass'd by me, I said I believe I know the man, he served part of his time with a smith. He walk'd her into Church-road, there the prisoner began to abuse Mr. Covey. Mr. Davis soon came out, and mounted, and rode away. Then I told Mr. Covey, I knew that was the same person, which is the prisoner at the bar.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I had been at Hackney all that afternoon, and was much in liquor; coming down Mare-street, I found the mare loose in the road. I took her by the bridle, and lead her down towards Church-street. I got past Mr. Davis's door; I did not know it was his mare, but when I was told it was his, I was going to bring her back again, and his servant stop'd me.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17580913-14-verdict67" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580913-14-verdict67" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
