<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17500711-53">
               <interp inst="t17500711-53" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-53" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-53" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17500711"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-53" type="date" value="17500711"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500711-53-off236-c337" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-53-defend440 t17500711-53-off236 t17500711-53-verdict239"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500711-53-off240-c337" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-53-defend440 t17500711-53-off240 t17500711-53-verdict239"></join>
         
               <p>479. 
               
                  <persName id="t17500711-53-defend440" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Wilson 
                  <interp inst="t17500711-53-defend440" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-defend440" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-defend440" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted, for that he, with two other persons not yet taken, <rs id="t17500711-53-off236" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-off236" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-off236" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               one silver watch, val. 3 l. one metal watch, val. 4 l. one three pound twelve shill. piece, two thirty six shill. pieces, and three moidores, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17500711-53-victim442" type="victimName">
                           Joseph 
                           Millikin 
                        <interp inst="t17500711-53-victim442" type="surname" value="Millikin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500711-53-victim442" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500711-53-victim442" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling house of 
                     <persName id="t17500711-53-person443">
                        Ann 
                        Glover 
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person443" type="surname" value="Glover"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500711-53-person443" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500711-53-person443" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , did steal, take and carry away
            </rs>, <rs id="t17500711-53-cd237" type="crimeDate">June 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-53-off236 t17500711-53-cd237"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-53-off240 t17500711-53-cd237"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-53-person444">
                  Joseph 
                  Millikin 
               <interp inst="t17500711-53-person444" type="surname" value="Millikin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person444" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person444" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was a stranger in the town, and walking in the Fleet market was asking for one Mr. Clark's house, June 18. about four in the afternoon. I asked a woman, she said she did not know such a man; a boy came to me and said I am going to Mr. Clark's; he carried me into 
               <persName id="t17500711-53-person445">
                  Ann 
                  Glover 
               <interp inst="t17500711-53-person445" type="surname" value="Glover"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person445" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person445" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's house in Chick-lane. I asked him if that was Mr. Clark's house, he said, no; but, said he, I have sold the man a horse for twenty guineas or twenty pounds, and I'll ask the gentlewoman if he has been here to pay the money; he call'd to the landlady and asked if the gentleman had been there to pay the money; she said he had been there five or six times, and she would send for him in a minute; so upon that account I sat down a little Soon after there came in a pretty lusty man and the prisoner at the bar: they set to gaming at something, they called it pricking at the belt; the prisoner first lost a shilling, then a guinea, upon which he asked me to change a five pound, or a 5 guinea piece. I had got a silver watch in my pocket that I had received in lien of some money, that was above my gold. I took that out, and laid it down upon the table, there was a 3 l. 12 s. two 36 s. pieces, and three moidores; I took them out and laid them on the table, upon which, said he, I think you have got a gold watch, I have let mine run down, please to let me regulate mine by yours ; said I, it is but a pinchbeck one. so I took it out; then the lusty man got up and turned me a little about, and carried me out of the door; going out I looked back and saw Wilson clap his handkerchief over the gold and watches, and pull'd them to that side of the table he was on. When I came in again the watches and gold were gone, I did not see him lift them. The prisoner and the boy also were gone. I asked Mrs. Glover what sort of a house she kept, saying. I thought they were robbers. I asked her her name, she was somewhat slow in telling me; there was a gentleman coming by, I was going to ask him, then she told me it was 
               <persName id="t17500711-53-person446">
                  Ann 
                  Glover 
               <interp inst="t17500711-53-person446" type="surname" value="Glover"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person446" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person446" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I asked her the name of the place, she said, <placeName id="t17500711-53-crimeloc238">Chick-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17500711-53-crimeloc238" type="placeName" value="Chick-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17500711-53-crimeloc238" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-53-off236 t17500711-53-crimeloc238"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-53-off240 t17500711-53-crimeloc238"></join>, which I took into my book; it was five minutes after four o'clock when they were gone. I had no acquaintance in town, but one gentleman, I went to his quarters and could not find him; then I went and found Mr. Clark. he took his cane and we went along; I put off my riding coat, and put on another hat, and a long tail wig, and walked to the place; the prisoner was sitting at the door smoaking a pipe with something to drink; said I, you have changed your coat, but you have not changed your face, you are my prisoner: said he, for what? I said I will tell you by and by: I was assisted by some gentlemen that are here.</p>

               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. How many people were there in the house when you was robb'd?</p>
               <p>Millikin. There were only two men and a boy.</p>
               <p>Q. What day was this?</p>
               <p>Millikin. It was the 18th of June.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was you in the room?</p>
               <p>Millikin. I staid there but a very little time, a lusty man pull'd me out of the room after the things were on the table.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know the prisoner took your money and watches?</p>
               <p>Millikin. I saw him put his handkerchief upon them and pull them to him, and it was a fair sign he should take them, I think.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175007110030"></xptr>Q. Was the boy by at that time?</p>
               <p>Millikin. He was.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you and that man been out of the room?</p>
               <p>Millikin. Not so long as I can go out at that door (pointing to a door about five yards from him) if there were no body in my way.</p>
               <p>Q. What door did you go out at?</p>
               <p>Millikin. It was the street door.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body go out by you at that time?</p>
               <p>Millikin. No, they did not, there was another door went out backwards.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you take the prisoner up?</p>
               <p>Millikin. I suppose between six and seven o'clock that evening.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of that lusty man?</p>
               <p>Millikin. He run away like a rogue as the rest did.</p>
               <p>Q. After you missed your money I should be glad to know why you did not apply to some neighbour and relate the affair, in order to secure the people of the house?</p>
               <p>Millikin. I was a stranger in the place and knew nobody, which was the reason I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you find the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Millikin. He was sitting at the door when I came back again.</p>
               <p>Q. How many times did you prick at that belt?</p>
               <p>Millikin. I pricked none, nor did I wager; it was a thing I never saw, and I was ignorant of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-53-person447">
                  John 
                  Grovner 
               <interp inst="t17500711-53-person447" type="surname" value="Grovner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person447" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person447" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Between six and seven, on the 18th of June last, the prosecutor came into Mr. Dickerson's tap-house in Chick-lane, and told the story he has now. Mr. Lane, upon hearing him describe the persons, went out and saw Wilson sitting at 
               <persName id="t17500711-53-person448">
                  Ann 
                  Glover 
               <interp inst="t17500711-53-person448" type="surname" value="Glover"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person448" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person448" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's door; he came and said there is one person you described sitting there now, saying, I wish you'd go up and see if it is him. We prevailed upon the countryman to change his dress, by pulling his great coat off, and I put my hat and wig on his head, and put on the countryman's wig, and walked up after him. We gave him charge if that was the man to give us notice and we would assist him; he went and took a survey of the man, went past him a few yards, I planted myself by the prisoner, the countryman turn'd upon him, and said, '' mon thou '' hast not altered thy heed if thou hast thy dress, '' thou art the mon that robbed me.'' I immediately seized him, jointly with the prosecutor, we brought him down to Mr. Dickerson's tap-house in Chick-lane, the prisoner was very uneasy and wanted to know what he was charged for; he began to be very abusive, and swore he never saw Millikin in his life before. When we came into the tap-house and altered Millikin's dress by putting on his own clothes, the prisoner then said he had seen him about two hours before at the White Hart in Chick-lane; that he went away grumbling, and said somebody had robbed him of six pence; and that the prisoner himself was eating some anchovies and bread and butter for his dinner. He attempted to make his escape. I sent to Newgate and got some hand-cuffs, and secured him, and put him in a coach, and carried him to the Compter, and the next day before alderman Rawlinson.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-53-person449">
                  Anne 
                  Glover 
               <interp inst="t17500711-53-person449" type="surname" value="Glover"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person449" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person449" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep this house, the White Hart in Chick-lane. I remember Millikin coming to my house along with a young man, on the 18th of June, they went into a room that lies even with the common dining room, they had a pot of beer. I believe they had been together near a quarter of an hour; there were two men came in to drink, one of them seemed to stagger like a drunken man. Wilson never was in my parlour; they were two strange men that pushed in at the parlour; I said they must not go in there, there was company; they said, gentlemen, we hope no offence; Mr. Millikin said, no offence. They asked for six pennyworth of bumboe, they drank that and call'd for six pennyworth more. I was going down for some beer, as I came up they passed me; Mr. Wilson was sitting in a box in the other room; he said, he believed they were gone to the door, the gentleman came in again and ask'd me where they were? I said I did not know, but they would come again. I asked whetehr I was not to be paid for my liquor? yes, said he, for what I called for, a pot of beer; he gave me a shilling to change; he said to Mr. Wilson, I believe I have been among a pack of rogues. I gave him nine pence; he did not say he had lost any thing. Wilson was in a box by himself, and the gentleman was on the back of the box talking to him. There was Mrs. Philips drinking in the room.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she there when the prosecutor and boy came in?</p>
               <p>A. Glover. No, she was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she there when the prosecutor said he believed he had been among a parcel of rogues?</p>
               <p>A. Glover. No, she was not then; she sat and drank with Mr. Wilson. They had half a quartern of bumboe or rumboe, at the time the prosecutor and his three companions were in the other room, they were in the parlour, and Wilson and Mrs. Philips in the dining room.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did Wilson continue at your house?</p>
               <p>A. Glover. Till such time as he was taken up, he sat down and smoaked a pipe after he had eat two achovies which I gave him.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175007110031"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-53-person450">
                  Diana 
                  Philips 
               <interp inst="t17500711-53-person450" type="surname" value="Philips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person450" type="given" value="Diana"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person450" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at this house the 18th of June, I called in for a dram; this Mr. Wilson was there, he asked me if I would drink part of a glass of rum. I knew him before, he was in the kitchen, there was a man or two with him, who they were, I don't know, they were neighbours which I had seen there several times. I sat in the box with him, and was with him half an hour. I heard some company there in the parlour.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you there when any complaint was made of being robbed?</p>
               <p>D. Philips. No, I was not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-53-person451">
                  Samuel 
                  Wilcox 
               <interp inst="t17500711-53-person451" type="surname" value="Wilcox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person451" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person451" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 18th of June I was at Mrs. Glover's, I saw the prisoner and some company in the parlour, there was no woman drinking with him when I was there, the prisoner was in a publick room. I believe I staid there best part of an hour, he sat opposite to me. I did not stay till the company went out of the parlour.</p>
               <p>Q. What company was the prisoner in?</p>
               <p>Wilcox. He was in nobody's company while I was there. There was one 
               <persName id="t17500711-53-person452">
                  William 
                  Scarborough 
               <interp inst="t17500711-53-person452" type="surname" value="Scarborough"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person452" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person452" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             there, but he is not in this trial.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-53-person453">
                  George 
                  Hawkins 
               <interp inst="t17500711-53-person453" type="surname" value="Hawkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person453" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person453" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner 13 or 14 years, he is a tallow chandler, I never knew any harm of him in my life, I believe he is an honest man.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see him play at pricking the belt?</p>
               <p>Hawkins. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-53-person454">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Butler 
               <interp inst="t17500711-53-person454" type="surname" value="Butler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person454" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person454" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him these 20 years, he has the character of a very honest man, I never heard to the contrary in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-53-person455">
                  John 
                  Gravenor 
               <interp inst="t17500711-53-person455" type="surname" value="Gravenor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person455" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person455" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             again. Upon my return from the Compter, 
               <persName id="t17500711-53-person456">
                  Anne 
                  Glover 
               <interp inst="t17500711-53-person456" type="surname" value="Glover"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person456" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person456" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             did declare to me, that Wilson was in company with the countryman and two or three more people, but she did not see any transactions, not being in the room at that time; she keeps as infamous a house as may be in London. When we carried him to the Counter I was forced to carry a hanger drawn in my hand they were so troublesome.</p>
               <p>William Lane. I know 
               <persName id="t17500711-53-person457">
                  Anne 
                  Glover 
               <interp inst="t17500711-53-person457" type="surname" value="Glover"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person457" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person457" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , she keeps a publick house in Chick-lane, so do I.</p>
               <p>Court. I hope you have no prejudice against her upon that account?</p>
               <p>Lane. No, I have not. People of ill same often resort to her house. Some people who are cast this sessions used to frequent her house often; Eli Smith and his companions. I have seen the prisoner at the bar go backwards and forwards. It is esteemed by all my neighbours a bad house; there are neighbours in the court will say the same.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-53-person458">
                  William 
                  Doleman 
               <interp inst="t17500711-53-person458" type="surname" value="Doleman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person458" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person458" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Very bad company resort to this house, I have lived in the lane 14 years.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-53-person459">
                  John 
                  Swithin 
               <interp inst="t17500711-53-person459" type="surname" value="Swithin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person459" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person459" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable; it is reported a very bad house. 
               <persName id="t17500711-53-person460">
                  Anne 
                  Glover 
               <interp inst="t17500711-53-person460" type="surname" value="Glover"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person460" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person460" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was turned out of another house by the parish for keeping a bad house there. I believe there is nobody of repute uses the house. She did confess she knew the other man that was concerned in this robbery, but she would not tell me. <rs id="t17500711-53-verdict239" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-verdict239" type="verdictCategory" value="specialVerdict"></interp>
               The verdict was brought in special, to be decided by the twelve judges of England, whether it is a fraud or a felony
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a second time indicted for <rs id="t17500711-53-off240" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-off240" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-off240" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 6 dead pidgeons, value 1 s. one dead hare, value 3 s. one wicker basket, value 1 s.
            </rs> the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17500711-53-victim462" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Clark 
                  <interp inst="t17500711-53-victim462" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-victim462" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-victim462" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17500711-53-cd241" type="crimeDate">November 28, 1748</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-53-off236 t17500711-53-cd241"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-53-off240 t17500711-53-cd241"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-53-person463">
                  Thomas 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17500711-53-person463" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person463" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person463" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . <rs id="t17500711-53-viclabel242" type="occupation">I keep the Ailsbury coach</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-53-victim462 t17500711-53-viclabel242"></join>. I lost a hamper from behind my coach about six weeks before Christmas was twelvemonth. I did not know what was in it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-53-person464">
                  Anne 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17500711-53-person464" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person464" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person464" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to my lady Dormer. I remember there was a hamper came to our house with medlers in it, but who sent them I cannot tell. It came by the Ailsbury coach; the man's name is 
               <persName id="t17500711-53-person465">
                  Thomas 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17500711-53-person465" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person465" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person465" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , but I cannot tell the exact time, I did not see the hamper open.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-53-person466">
                  Thomas 
                  Cook 
               <interp inst="t17500711-53-person466" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person466" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person466" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The hamper was directed to Mrs. Dormer, near Story's Gate, Westminster. I did not see any body take it, nor never saw the prisoner till now.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-53-person467">
                  William 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17500711-53-person467" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person467" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person467" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Some time in November, 1748, about 7 in the evening, as I was going cross Holborn, a little below the bars I saw the prisoner following the stage coach just passing by me; I saw him take the hamper from behind the coach; he carried it to Staple's-inn-gate, and rested it on the rails. I waited till he took it up again and followed him up Middle Row; he went into Tennis Court, near Middle Row, it is a private court, I follow'd him through it, that goes to the back door to the King's Head tavern, there he dropped the hamper (I believe he saw me follow him) he then ran away, I ran and overtook him. Just as he was going into Holborn I laid hold of him, and, with the assistance of some people, brought him back to where the hamper was dropped. We brought him and the hamper into the King's Head tavern, and charged Mr. Marsh the constable with the prisoner. I think there was some direction upon the hamper where it was to go. I went to the Bell Inn, in Holborn, to see for 
               <persName id="t17500711-53-person468">
                  Thomas 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17500711-53-person468" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person468" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person468" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the coachman. When I returned the tavern was all in confusion. The prisoner was rescued by about a dozen fellows all armed.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this hamper the same that was taken from Clark's coach?</p>
               <p>Ward. The man came and owned the hamper.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175007110032"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-53-person469">
                  Thomas 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17500711-53-person469" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person469" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person469" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lost a hamper from behind my coach that night Mr. Ward applied to me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-53-person470">
                  Adrian 
                  Marsh 
               <interp inst="t17500711-53-person470" type="surname" value="Marsh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person470" type="given" value="Adrian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person470" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I then was headborough. I will not take upon me positively to say, but I believe the prisoner is the man. On the 28th of November was twelvemonth I was sent for to the King's Head, Middle Row, Holborn, to take charge of a person who had robbed a stage coach. He was in a room, and three or four persons with him; we tarried there I believe an hour. There was a porter sent to Mrs. Dormer, the person to whom the hamper was directed. While he was gone, came in about ten men; the moment the prisoner saw them, he said, d - n your eyes, fight away. There were about five or six pistols, and about three or four cutlasses. I am sure to three cutlasses. I received a great blow on my right hand. He was rescued when the messenger came back. He said if the hamper belonged to Mrs. Dormer, it came by the Ailsbury stage coach</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask Mr. Gravenor if he did not come to the lodge at Newgate on Wednesday last with three other gentlemen, and when they came he pointed at me, saying, that is the man in the green waistcoat. Ward said, I cannot take upon me to say he is the man.</p>
               <p>Gravenor. I took Mr. Marsh the constable and Mr. Collingsin, and Mr. Ward staid without to make farther discoveries. The prisoner has been an infamous fellow, his character is well known; he came in at 11 o'clock at night to Mr. Clark's house, (the very man Millikin was enquiring for) and was suspected to be a common highwayman. That night he made a bill of sale of his horse for eight pounds. Mr. Collings said he could not swear to him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-53-person471">
                  Adrian 
                  Marsh 
               <interp inst="t17500711-53-person471" type="surname" value="Marsh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person471" type="given" value="Adrian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-person471" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was there likewise, and said I could not swear to him.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500711-53-verdict243" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-verdict243" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-verdict243" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               Guilty of stealing the hamper only
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500711-53-punish244" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-punish244" type="punishmentCategory" value="noPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-53-punish244" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="sentenceRespited"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-53-defend440 t17500711-53-punish244"></join>
               
                     <note>[No punishment. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
