<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17571207-32">
               <interp inst="t17571207-32" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17571207-32" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17571207-32" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17571207"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17571207-32" type="date" value="17571207"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17571207-32-off168-c235" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571207-32-defend287 t17571207-32-off168 t17571207-32-verdict171"></join>
         
               <p>38. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17571207-32-defend287" type="defendantName">
                  Margaret, <rs id="t17571207-32-deflabel167" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571207-32-defend287 t17571207-32-deflabel167"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17571207-32-person288">
                        Daniel 
                        Rose 
                     <interp inst="t17571207-32-person288" type="surname" value="Rose"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17571207-32-person288" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17571207-32-person288" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
                     <interp inst="t17571207-32-defend287" type="surname" value="Rose"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-32-defend287" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-32-defend287" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17571207-32-off168" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17571207-32-off168" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-32-off168" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing three linen shirts, value 20 s. one shirt, value 4 s. four linen aprons, one cambrick handkerchief, one muslin handkerchief, three cambrick caps, one pair of stockings, and one tablecloth
            </rs>, the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17571207-32-victim290" type="victimName">
                     Joshua 
                     Goodwin 
                  <interp inst="t17571207-32-victim290" type="surname" value="Goodwin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-32-victim290" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-32-victim290" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571207-32-off168 t17571207-32-victim290"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17571207-32-cd169" type="crimeDate">Nov. 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571207-32-off168 t17571207-32-cd169"></join> +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571207-32-person291">
                  Ann 
                  Goodwin 
               <interp inst="t17571207-32-person291" type="surname" value="Goodwin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-32-person291" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-32-person291" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to 
               <persName id="t17571207-32-person292">
                  Joshua 
                  Goodwin 
               <interp inst="t17571207-32-person292" type="surname" value="Goodwin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-32-person292" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-32-person292" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; we live in <placeName id="t17571207-32-crimeloc170">Drury-Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17571207-32-crimeloc170" type="placeName" value="Drury-Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17571207-32-crimeloc170" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571207-32-off168 t17571207-32-crimeloc170"></join>. On the 5th of November at night I was gone up stairs, when the prisoner was coming up the lane; I watched to see which way she went, and saw her turn in at our entry; I went down, and saw her with the key of my door in her hand, and her apron full of my cloaths. I spoke to her, but she made me no answer. I then went into my room, and missed the things mentioned in the indictment ( naming them.) Then I followed her to her lodgings. I then called her husband down stairs, and said, Go and follow your wife, for she has rob'd me of all my cloaths. He said, God forbid, but did not go after her. I went round among the pawnbrokers, but could not meet with the things. I took her up, and she was brought before the justice; she was very drunk. I pull'd this cap out of her bosom (producing one) it is my property.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you know it by?</p>
               <p>A. Goodwin. By my own work and cutting out. This is one of the three I lost.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she confess any thing?</p>
               <p>A. Goodwin. No, she did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571207-32-person293">
                  Henry 
                  Adams 
               <interp inst="t17571207-32-person293" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-32-person293" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-32-person293" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner's husband works in the same shop where I do; we are looking-glass polishers. The prosecutrix called him down, and said, your wife has robbed me; he said no, she has not. She staid about five minutes, and insisted on his going to look for his wife; he would not go, but said he was certain she had not got her things.</p>
         
               <p>N.B. The Second Part of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17571207-32">
                  <interp inst="t17571207-32" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17571207-32" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17571207-32" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17571207"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17571207-32" type="date" value="17571207"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175712070021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON, And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 7th, Thursday the 8th, Friday the 9th, and Saturday the 10th of DECEMBER,</p>
                  <p>In the Thirty-first Year of His MAJESTY'S Reign. NUMBER I PART II. for the Year 1758. Being the First SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of THE RIGHT HONOURABLE Sir 
                  <persName id="t17571207-32-person294">
                     CHARLES 
                     ASGILL 
                  <interp inst="t17571207-32-person294" type="surname" value="ASGILL"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17571207-32-person294" type="given" value="CHARLES"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17571207-32-person294" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Knt. LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by M. COOPER, at the Globe, in Paternoster-Row, 1757.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175712070022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, and Oyer and Terminer, for the City of LONDON, and at the General 
                  <persName id="t17571207-32-person295">
                     Sessions
                  <interp inst="t17571207-32-person295" type="given" value="Sessions"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17571207-32-person295" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                     </persName>
                of Gaol Delivery of Newgate, holden for the said City of LONDON, and County of MIDDLESEX, at Justice-Hall in the Old-Bailey, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I AM not guilty of the fact. I know no more of it than the child within me, and I have not three days to go as I know of.</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. She has no more a child within her than I have.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571207-32-person296">
                  Michael 
                  Brumley 
               <interp inst="t17571207-32-person296" type="surname" value="Brumley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-32-person296" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-32-person296" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a gold beater, and have known the prisoner about a week before she was committed. I have known the prosecutrix about as long. Last Saturday was a month the old gentlewoman came into my room, went down stairs, and cried out death alive.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she mean by that?</p>
               <p>Brumley. She is an Irishwoman, and talks pretty much so. She swore she was job'd. Then she came up-stairs, and seemed to suspect a taylor's wife that lodged in the garret. Then she came down again, and said, it must be this Rose, saying, she knew her to be a villain. Then I said, go and look after her, for I don't like you to be here. Then she went and look'd for the prisoner, returned, and said she was absconded from her lodgings; but she had not been come back above ten minutes before Rose came to her. The old woman said she would go and advertise the things, saying nothing to her about her taken them away. She soon returned, and challenged Rose with them. Then Rose went to justice Welch, and took out a warrant against her, for scandalizing her. When she was gone the old woman said to my wife and I, What a bullocking did I make to affrighten that devil, to see if she was the woman or not. Presently a constable came and took this old woman up. If the court pleases to enquire into the two womens characters, I believe the prisoner's is the best; but they are both, as it were, strangers to me: From the character I have had of the prosecutrix, she is a very bad woman.</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. They have kept this man all day, and fed him with beer, in order to swear against me.</p>
               <p>Brumley. I came freely and voluntarily to speak the truth.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17571207-32-verdict171" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17571207-32-verdict171" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
