<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17500711-62">
               <interp inst="t17500711-62" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-62" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-62" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17500711"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-62" type="date" value="17500711"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500711-62-off279-c399" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-62-defend517 t17500711-62-off279 t17500711-62-verdict282"></join>
         
               <p>490. 
               
                  <persName id="t17500711-62-defend517" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Mayo 
                  <interp inst="t17500711-62-defend517" type="surname" value="Mayo"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-62-defend517" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-62-defend517" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for that he, <rs id="t17500711-62-off279" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500711-62-off279" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-62-off279" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17500711-62-victim519" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Smith 
                        <interp inst="t17500711-62-victim519" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500711-62-victim519" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500711-62-victim519" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-62-off279 t17500711-62-victim519"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , spinster, did make an assault, putting her in corporal fear and danger of her life; one gold ring, value 18 s. from her person did steal, take and carry away
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500711-62-cd280" type="crimeDate">June 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-62-off279 t17500711-62-cd280"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-62-person520">
                  Mary 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17500711-62-person520" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-62-person520" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-62-person520" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On June the 21st, I had been to my washer woman in the Haymarket, the prisoner met me betwixt 10 and 11 at night <placeName id="t17500711-62-crimeloc281">in the middle of the Haymarket</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17500711-62-crimeloc281" type="placeName" value="in the middle of the Haymarket"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17500711-62-crimeloc281" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-62-off279 t17500711-62-crimeloc281"></join>; he asked me to go and drink a glass of wine; I refused to go with him; he laid hold of my hand, and said, are you married? I said no; he said, will you go? I said I would not. Then he took me and threw me down, and took my ring, and swored - n your eyes, if you speak I'll murder you. He struck me after he had got the ring. There was a woman came up to me; I told her that man in the laced hat had knocked me down and taken my ring from off my finger; said she, take care, don't go that way, there is a vile gang of rogues, and he is very likely to do it. I went home and told how ill I had been used by this Mayo. The person that came up told me his name.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>M. Smith. I then lived in Covent Garden. It was on the 21st of June, Mr. Noke went with me to the justice the 22d for a warrant. I did not know howto serve it; he put it into the person's hands to serve it. The prisoner (Mayo) did not speak a word for himself when taken up. When I was before the justice they desired me to say he was not the man. One Ridgway said I should have the sum of five guineas if I would say he was not.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Mrs. Eastoff ?</p>
               <p>M. Smith. Yes, her right name is Mears.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know one Noke?</p>
               <p>M. Smith. Yes, I do, he was at Mrs. Eastoff's house; I told him how I was used; I said to him, I should be obliged to him if he would go and see me home; he did, and staid there all night in Covent Garden.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know one 
               <persName id="t17500711-62-person521">
                  Sarah 
                  Tidmarsh 
               <interp inst="t17500711-62-person521" type="surname" value="Tidmarsh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-62-person521" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-62-person521" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>M. Smith. No, I don't, I have not had any conversation about this with any woman at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not Mr. Eastoff arrested in a suit of Mr. Mayo's?</p>
               <p>M. Smith. Yes, he was, and afterwards he said, Eastoff does not owe him any money.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>M. Smith. I am an unfortunate girl of the town.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you give no other account of yourself?</p>
               <p>M. Smith. No, I cannot.</p>
               <p>Q. What was your business at the Haymarket so late?</p>
               <p>M. Smith. I was to have gone out of town with a gentleman that lives in London next day, so I went for a clean shift.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you lie that night you was robb'd?</p>
               <p>M. Smith. At Covent Garden. My landlord's name is Davis, he keeps a gin shop at the end of Phoenix Alley.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know that Mayo had a writ out against Eastoff that night you was robb'd?</p>
               <p>M. Smith. No, I did not know he had.</p>
               <p>Q. When was he arrested?</p>
               <p>M. Smith. He was arrested on the 23d, at the suit of Mr. Mayo.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-62-person522">
                  William 
                  Eastoff 
               <interp inst="t17500711-62-person522" type="surname" value="Eastoff"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-62-person522" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-62-person522" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming into the Haymarket on Thursday the 21st of last month, coming home, a little below St. James's street I saw a man and a woman below the Haymarket. I saw the woman knocked down. Words passed between them; I saw the man running away, I ran after him, and saw him go into a house in St. James's street, it was the prisoner at the bar. Afterwards I was informed this was the woman. I did not see him take any thing from her. I went to that house where he went into, and enquired what sort of a house it was, and was told it was a bad house to go into. I then came back again, and went home. He turned round as he was going off. I saw him perfectly, and know him very well.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see this woman before?</p>
               <p>Eastoff. Yes, where she lodged in Covent Garden.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you rent two rooms of the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Eastoff. Yes, at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not there a dispute about it?</p>
               <p>Eastoff. There was no dispute then, there was afterwards. Mr. Mayo came to me and asked me for his house; I gave him a month's notice, he was to have come at seven o'clock. I looked over the inventory, there were two plates, a flat iron, and a heater missing. I had no key; I desired to go out and leave him in possession of his house, and told him the things that were lost I would make him restitution for. He came the next day, and broke<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175007110037"></xptr> the house open, and desired me to come down if I would; in two or three days after I heard there was an action against me in order that I should not come to this trial.</p>
               <p>Q. Do not you know of any dispute between you and Mayo?</p>
               <p>Eastoff. There was an action brought for 44 s. which I justly owed the man, there was no dispute before. On Friday Mr. Ridgway and one Mr. Noke sent to me, in order that I would take the Prosecutrix out of the way, and they would give me a sum of money.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Ask that witness if he did not rent a house of me at so much a week.</p>
               <p>Eastoff. I rented two rooms of him up two pair of stairs; some of the goods were gone; two blankets, a flat-iron, a heater, and a candlestick, which I offered t o account for.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence. They have contrived to hang me, because I wanted my money that was my just due.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-62-person523">
                  Richard 
                  Noke 
               <interp inst="t17500711-62-person523" type="surname" value="Noke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-62-person523" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-62-person523" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 17th of June last, I went to Mr. Eastoff and Mrs. Mears, who said, the Prisoner at the bar had used him very ill. Mrs. Mears wanted to make the Prisoner give up his title to his effects. They proposed to go to Mr. Drinkwater, and consult means in order to punish him; Eastoff and Mears said he, had been guilty of robbing some Persons so I went to Mr. Drinkwater with them. He bid him go to Mr. Branson, his Grace the Duke of Bedford's Valet de Chamber, and say to him, the person who robbed him was named Mayo, and that the watch was to be found at any time. Upon their request I went to Mr. Branson with Mr. Eastoff, we desired to speak with him in a private apartment. Eastoff told him we understood that he had been robbed on the 17th of Jan. of a gold watch, &amp;c. Mr. Branson told him he had not lost any such thing, and particularly, he never had a gold watch to lose; but he said, if any body in the house had lost such things he would make enquiry, so we waited upon him again the next day; then he said he had made enquiry in the family, and could not find any body had lost any thing of that kind. The next day, which was Friday, Mr. Drinkwater was acquainted he was not robbed at all. Then with the advice of him and Mr. Eastoff it was proposed, a robbery should be alledg'd against him. Mr. Eastoff desired I would go home with him and talk to Mrs. Mears his companion, she knowing I had had some trifling correspondence with the Prosecutrix, that she should say, that she had been robbed by the Prisoner of a ring, value 14 s. Mr. Drinkwater said it must have been a wedding ring, and the posey of it (Love, Virtue) this was agreed upon. I took the girl out with me on Thursday, the 21st after dinner, in order to take her from these persons, and desir'd her by no means to be guilty of this; I provided a lodging for her in Hart street, and took her there about 9 o'clock at night. We continued there about half an hour; she then told me, she wanted some clean linen, and said, she was desirous of having it; I went along with her to the Hay-market, the woman was not at home; I desired her to sit down with me at a publick-house the door on this side her house, till the woman came home, she was not out of my sight, she took the linen; I paid the reckoning, then we went to the lodging I had taken for her, where I continued with her that whole night, this was the night this robbery is said to be committed. I lay along with her. I met with her about 3 o'clock in the afternoon, and dined with her at Mr. Eastoff's house; I went to several places, she was with me the whole time. Finding a thing, and please your Lordship, of this nature going forward, I was willing to see how far they would carry it into execution; this is the fourth robbery sworn by Eastoff against the Prisoner, and made up.</p>
               <p>On Friday I went about my business; I called upon Eastoff in Mrs. Mears's house, I found Mrs. Mears was abroad; I went to the Prosecutrix's lodgings, I was told she was gone to the King's Head, Holbourn; I met them, that is, Mrs. Mears and the Prosecutrix, near Middle-Row, they said no action had been committed; I carried her home and lay with her that night also. The next morning, she acknowledged Mrs. Mears had used her interest and desired her to go and make an information against the Prisoner at the bar, and that Mrs. Mears lent her half a crown to pay for the warrant. I went the next morning to Mr. Eastoff's house, to ask the reason why she should contrive so wicked a scheme, said East-off, that alone will not do, for there were a considerable deal of money due to the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Noke. I am a compositor in the printing-branch. I was offered three guineas last Sunday if I would back a bill against the Prisoner, by Mr. Eastoff.</p>

               <p>- Ridgway. On Thursday the 21st of June, between 8 an 9 o'clock in the evening, the prisoner called upon me and told me he was going in order to take possession of his house in Park street,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175007110038"></xptr> which he had let to this Eastoff; he said he had been there before and found many of his things missing; he advised with me what to do, I advised him to take possession of his house as he could get it, or else I told him they might be wicked enough to make all the things off. We went between 8 and 9 o'clock to another house he had taken in order to go into. There were Eastoff and Mrs. Mears; Mayo asked for the key; there was a good deal of bad language between them. This Mrs. Mears once lived with the prisoner at the bar, and now lives with Eastoff. We staid till past eleven o'clock in order to get possession of the house. Then we went away to the Two Chairmen at the corner of the street, and had some beer. I returned back in order to get the key. She fell down on her knees, and swore she would not give it him. I proposed to her, that I would strive to persuade Mayo to give her half a dozen chairs, and the things they had taken out of the house, if they would quit the house. She still said she would hang him. Then I return'd back to Mr. Mayo at the Two Chairmen; then we came along the Strand homeward; he went to his own house in Goodman's-fields. It was past 12 at night before I parted with him. The next day he came to me in order to know what he could do to get possession; I told him the only way was to get an action against the woman; so she was arrested, and Eastoff too, and he made his escape; he was taken again last Tuesday.</p>
               <p>They did tamper with me. Mr. Eastoff proposed, that if Mr. Mayo would let Mrs. Mears out of goal, he would take care to keep the prosecutrix out of the way, so that she should not prosecute him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-62-person524">
                  Sarah 
                  Tidmash 
               <interp inst="t17500711-62-person524" type="surname" value="Tidmash"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-62-person524" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-62-person524" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the third day Mrs. Eastoff was in the Fleet, as the prosecutrix and I were going along Fleetstreet, she said she was almost mad, said she, what must I do? I must either go to Newgate or be hanged, or be pillory'd, if I do not go through with it. If they had not given me two or three drams I had not done it, and said how her conscience flew in her face when Mr. Mayo looked at her.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500711-62-verdict282" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500711-62-verdict282" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
