<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510116-44">
               <interp inst="t17510116-44" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510116-44" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510116-44" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510116-44" type="date" value="17510116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510116-44-off208-c324" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-44-defend409 t17510116-44-off208 t17510116-44-verdict210"></join>
         
               <p>148. 
               
                  <persName id="t17510116-44-defend409" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Lloyd 
                  <interp inst="t17510116-44-defend409" type="surname" value="Lloyd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-44-defend409" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-44-defend409" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17510116-44-off208" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510116-44-off208" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-44-off208" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               forging a certain false and counterfeit deed called a letter of attorney; and for publishing it with intent to defraud
            </rs>, <rs id="t17510116-44-cd209" type="crimeDate">Dec. 6</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-44-off208 t17510116-44-cd209"></join>*.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-44-person410">
                  Edward 
                  Fazakerly 
               <interp inst="t17510116-44-person410" type="surname" value="Fazakerly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-44-person410" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-44-person410" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had some prize-money to pay to the Swan sloop; there were 2 l. 5 s. and 3 d. due to one 
               <persName id="t17510116-44-person411">
                  Thomas 
                  Picket 
               <interp inst="t17510116-44-person411" type="surname" value="Picket"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-44-person411" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-44-person411" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I had not made up the account of this prize when he came to town, which was Jan. was two years; as it was not made out, and he going out of town, I paid him the money on his receipt, which he was to have taken up, when he came to town, and to have signed a receipt in the prize-book. On the 5th of December last I was out all the morning. I came home about one o'clock, and was inform'd, a woman had been and ask'd for me, with a power of attorney, to receive 
               <persName id="t17510116-44-person412">
                  Thomas 
                  Picket 
               <interp inst="t17510116-44-person412" type="surname" value="Picket"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-44-person412" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-44-person412" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's prize-money. I was very certain, that whoever came with a power of his, it must not be a true one, and I told Mr. Cotes so, who had informed me of the woman's coming; this was on the Wednesday, and I was informed she would come again on the Monday; I did intend to take her up when she came. On the Thursday, the day following, about 11 o'clock, the prisoner at the bar came and brought me this power of attorney, which probably is the same, but I did not see the other. The power produced in court, as set forth in the indictment. Mr. Cotes being in the back-parlour, hearing me mention the Swan sloop, came out; and he and I obliged the prisoner to go into the compting-house, where we took the power of attorney out of his hand. We compared it with the receipt Mr. Picket had given me, and it did not at all resemble it; Mr. Cotes went into the back-parlour, and he brought a gentleman out, to whom, in the presence of the prisoner, he told the same I have told now. The prisoner fell down on his knees, and beg'd I would forgive him; and said, he was innocent of the thing, as to himself, and that a woman had made over this power of attorney to him, to receive it for her use ; I ask'd him, if he knew where the woman was? to which he gave me little or no answer, or what I could make nothing of, something evasive: I told him as he could not, or would not<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175101160023"></xptr> produce the woman, I was obliged to carry him before a justice of peace, and if he was innocent, he might clear himself. Mrs. Cotes came into the room to him, and he fell on his knees to her to intreat forgiveness for him. I was obliged to go into the city, so I left him to the care of Mr. Cotes, and never saw him since, till now.</p>

               <p>The power of attorney read in Court in the common from, made to Eliz. Symonds. Sign'd 
               <persName id="t17510116-44-person413">
                  Thomas 
                  Picket 
               <interp inst="t17510116-44-person413" type="surname" value="Picket"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-44-person413" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-44-person413" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , sealed and delivered in the presence of Jonathan Ledgar City of Rochester, 
               <persName id="t17510116-44-person414">
                  Robert 
                  Bayley 
               <interp inst="t17510116-44-person414" type="surname" value="Bayley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-44-person414" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-44-person414" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , mayor.</p>
               <p>Mr. Cotes. On Wednesday the 5th of Dec. I was told there was a woman at the door, who wanted the prize-money of a sailor belonging to the Swan-sloop of war; I order'd the person to carry her into the compting-house, and I follow'd her, when she produced the letter of attorney which Mr. Fazakerly has mention'd; I looked at the prize-list, and saw the two letters (Pd.) right against the number of the distribution sum of 
               <persName id="t17510116-44-person415">
                  Thomas 
                  Picket 
               <interp inst="t17510116-44-person415" type="surname" value="Picket"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-44-person415" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-44-person415" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , midshipman; and knowing Mr. Fazakerly a very exact man in his business, I declined paying the woman the money. I desired her to call again on the Monday following, when she would be sure to find Mr. Fazakerly at home.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think that was the same power of attorney which is now produced?</p>
               <p>Cotes. I look'd at it several times; I do take it to be the same. Mr. Fazakerly came home about 12 at noon. I acquainted him with the circumstances which had happened; he said he imagined the letter of attorney was a forged one, for he had paid Mr. Picket the prize-money, and immediately shewed me the receipt for it. We then gave orders for the clerks in the compting-house to stop this woman if she should come again to demand the money, and on Thursday following, the prisoner came with the letter of attorney; as soon as I saw it, I immediately took the prisoner into the compting-house, and ask'd him how he came by it; he said, he had it of one Eliz. Symonds. I was called into the back-parlour about some business, and left him in the care of the clerks. I staid there some little time, when I came back again, the prisoner fell down on his knees, and beg'd I would let him go, for he said his life was in my hands: I told him the nature of his crime was of worse consequence to the community, and I thought it a duty incumbent on me to bring him to justice. I carried him before justice Ledger, where he said, he had this letter of attorney, and gave this direction to us.</p>
               <p>For Eliz. Symonds, at the Noah's-ark near Rochester-bridge in Stroud. He told me, she was to be heard of in Ratcliff-highway ; we sent a servant to inquire after her; and we had some account of such a woman; the woman where we inquired at first denied her, but afterwards said she lived in Suffolk: I endeavoured to have taken her if I could.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you send to the Noah's-ark?</p>
               <p>Cotes. No, I did not, my lord.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Please my lord, to ask him what this woman said to him, when she went for this money ?</p>
               <p>Cotes. She said she would come again, and that she came a good way off; but I don't remember she mentioned the country; and she also pressed me a good deal to pay the monoy.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence. When Mr. Cotes brought me before the justice, he told him he was acquainted with this Mr. Picket, and now he observes he was not at the passing the receipt, neither does he know he passed it; I think that is something relating to this affair in my behalf; that he should say one thing before the justice, and another here.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Cotes. Did you say before the justice, you was acquainted with Mr. Picket?</p>
               <p>Cotes. I never said so, my lord.</p>
               <p>Prisoner continues. On the Thursday after the Monday that this woman was at this house, in order to receive this money, she was at the Bell in Ratcliff highway; she said she was going out of town, and had a letter of attorney in order to receive 45 shillings, and could not stay to receive it, and said she should be glad if any body would receive it for her: there was one in the house, knowing I sometimes did do these things, told me of it; I went accordingly to the house, and called for a pint of beer, and sat down by the woman, and asked her what she had to say? She said, she had a letter of attorney for 45 shillings that belonged to the Swan sloop prize money, and that she could not receive it till next day; said I, if you will trust me with it, I will return it safe to you. I gave her a note for 2 l. 2 s. to deliver to the book-keeper at the Spread Eagle in Gracechurch street, to be remitted to her at the Noah's Ark at Stroud. I went on the Thursday to the gentleman, and told him; I had a letter of attorney indorsed to me by a woman; he said, let me look at it; I shewed it him, and said, if any thing is coming to the woman, she gave me this order to receive it for her: he desired me to go into the office along with him; he examined the books, and said, he judged this<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175101160024"></xptr> letter of attorney to be forged, and said to me, you shall go before the justice of peace. Where is the woman ? I told him she was at Noah's Ark in Stroud, where I had directions to send the money; he said he'd send me to prison till I did produce the woman. I begged for liberty, in order to find her ; he said no, but I must go before the justice: the justice examined me; and I told his worship the same I do here: and now I observe in Mr. Cotes's evidence, he says I said before the justice, that this woman was to be found in Ratcliff highway ; I said I had the paper from her there. The people of the house don't know her, they know me; and if your lordship pleases, I will call the woman who keeps a green stall; she will tell what passed between this last evidence and her in that house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-44-person416">
                  Mary 
                  Gold 
               <interp inst="t17510116-44-person416" type="surname" value="Gold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-44-person416" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-44-person416" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . There came a gentleman, I don't know who he was, and asked after the prisoner at the bar; and also asked me, if I knew one 
               <persName id="t17510116-44-person417">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Symonds 
               <interp inst="t17510116-44-person417" type="surname" value="Symonds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-44-person417" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-44-person417" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ? I told him I did; he asked me where she was? I told him, I did not know; her name was not Symonds now; she has been twice married since.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>M. Gold. I don't know the day of the month, it was the same day the prisoner was taken up. I told him I believed she was now in Suffolk; he said she had been with him within this week past; I knew it could not be the same; I made no answer and wondered what it could be upon, and he did not tell me what he came about; only he told me, if I could find her, there was money due to her from on board a ship; that her husband died in the king's service; I said I did not know where to send to her. I have known the prisoner near two years; he always behaved well in my house; he kept good hours, and spent his money with great conduct as the neighbours tell me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-44-person418">
                  Robert 
                  Cofield 
               <interp inst="t17510116-44-person418" type="surname" value="Cofield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-44-person418" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-44-person418" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about 10 months, he always paid me very honestly for whatever I did for him.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510116-44-verdict210" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510116-44-verdict210" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
