<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17550226-46">
               <interp inst="t17550226-46" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550226-46" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550226-46" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550226"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550226-46" type="date" value="17550226"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550226-46-off249-c326" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550226-46-defend410 t17550226-46-off249 t17550226-46-verdict252"></join>
         
               <p>143. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17550226-46-defend410" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Brown 
                  <interp inst="t17550226-46-defend410" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-46-defend410" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-46-defend410" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17550226-46-deflabel248" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550226-46-defend410 t17550226-46-deflabel248"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17550226-46-off249" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550226-46-off249" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-46-off249" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch, value 40 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17550226-46-victim412" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Otway 
                        <interp inst="t17550226-46-victim412" type="surname" value="Otway"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550226-46-victim412" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550226-46-victim412" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550226-46-off249 t17550226-46-victim412"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17550226-46-cd250" type="crimeDate">Jan. 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550226-46-off249 t17550226-46-cd250"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550226-46-person413">
                  Robert 
                  Otway 
               <interp inst="t17550226-46-person413" type="surname" value="Otway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-46-person413" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-46-person413" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I don't know that I ever saw the prisoner before the 21st of January, on which day I had been at Buckingham-street, York-buildings; returning home I accidentally met the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day?</p>
               <p>Otway. It was about one in the morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you meet her?</p>
               <p>Otway. I believe it might be somewhere in <placeName id="t17550226-46-crimeloc251">the Strand</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17550226-46-crimeloc251" type="placeName" value="the Strand"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550226-46-crimeloc251" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550226-46-off249 t17550226-46-crimeloc251"></join>, going up Burleigh-street and Exeter-street she came pretty close to me, and asked me<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175502260030"></xptr> If I would go home with her to her lodgings? At the corner of Burleigh-street she shied away, as if she wanted to get from me. When I found that, I thought she had got something from me.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is your house?</p>
               <p>Otway. I was going to my house in Holborn; I put my hand into my pocket, and missed my watch; she was at a little distance from me, I ran and laid hold of her, and charged her with stealing my watch; she told me she knew nothing of it. I said she must know it, because nobody had been in my company but her. She wanted to get away; I called for assistance; two watchmen came and asked what was the matter? I said, I believed that woman had got my watch. They were going to take her to the watch-house; as we were going along the Strand, she made a full stop, and said she would go no farther; the watchmen said she should. When she found they would not let her go, she said to the watchmen, if they would go into Burleigh street, she thought they might find it; so we went back, and going along Burleigh-street, Allen, one of the watchmen found a watch near a pawnbroker's door; he said to me, I have found a watch, but I don't know whether it is yours or not. I told him if it had not the marks which I should give of it, it was not mine. He put it in his pocket, and when we came with the prisoner to the constable, he delivered it to him. The constable asked me the marks of it. I told him I could not be positive of the No. but believed it to be 1622. I said it was a silver watch, and had Crook, London, on the dial-plate. In the morning we went before Justice Cox, who committed the prisoner to Newgate.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she confess any thing there?</p>
               <p>Otway. No; she told the justice I was in liquor, and might drop the watch there; she said she saw it in my hand.</p>
               <p>Q. When you came from Buckingham-street, was you sober or in liquor?</p>
               <p>Otway. I was a little in liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you had it in your pocket when you came from thence?</p>
               <p>Otway. I am sure I had, because the prisoner saw it.</p>
               <p>Q. You say you met the prisoner in the Strand; how came you to Burleigh-street? Is that the nearest way from Buckingham-street to Holborn?</p>
               <p>Otway. I thought it was that night.</p>
               <p>Q. When you came first into Burleigh-street, had you been as far as where the watch was found?</p>
               <p>Otway. No, I had not; she was gone on there, and might have laid it down.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was you got into Burleigh-street when she wanted to get away from you?</p>
               <p>Otway. I was got just in at the corner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550226-46-person414">
                  John 
                  Allen 
               <interp inst="t17550226-46-person414" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-46-person414" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-46-person414" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Watchman; on the 1st of February last, I had just finished calling the hour one; I came to the Golden-lion tavern, when the prosecutor called watch! I went, and he was at the corner of the street; he told me a woman had robbed him of his watch, and she was just gone up the street; and followed, and caught hold of her, and said this is the woman.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was she got up the street?</p>
               <p>Allen. She was got up about two or three doors; he gave me charge of her, and I was going to take her to St. Martin's round-house; I brought her down Burleigh-street; when we got facing the Globe alehouse by the Savoy-steps, she said, this man has been rude with me; he got me up into a door-way in Burleigh-street; and pulled out what he had, and very possible his watch might drop at that time. She insisted upon going no farther; but said, if we would go back with her to either Burleigh-street or Exeter-street, we should find the watch. We returned back, and going up Burleigh-street, at the sixth door on the left-hand, (a pawnbroker's,) there I picked up the watch.</p>
               <p>Q. Who saw the watch first?</p>
               <p>Allen. I did; the woman having said he had had her up in a door-way, I went on and looked in all the door-ways I came at. The watch lay with the glass downwards; but that was not broke, and the watch was going. I put it in my breeches-pocket, and said to the prosecutor, I have picked up a silver watch, as you say yours is, it may be yours; you must describe the name and the number when you come to the watch-house. We went there, and I delivered it to the constable of the night. The prosecutor described the watch, and told the maker's name, but could not tell the number. The next morning we went before justice Cox, there the prisoner said she did see the watch, and that they would find it either in Burleigh-street or Exeter-street.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550226-46-person415">
                  Martin 
                  Lion 
               <interp inst="t17550226-46-person415" type="surname" value="Lion"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-46-person415" type="given" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-46-person415" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was constable of the night; the prisoner was brought to the watch-house about a quarter after one in the morning by the prosecutor and two watchmen. Allen, one of the watchmen, gave me this watch (producing it ). I put it into my waistcoat pocket, and asked Allen if he had shewn it to the prosecutor after he had picked it up, he said he had not; then I asked the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175502260031"></xptr> prosecutor what the maker's name was on the dial-plate? he told me it was Crook, London; I turned aside and found it so. After that I asked him the number? he said he did not know; I asked what was with inside the case, whether it was a printed bill or plain paper? he said it was a piece of plain paper, I opened the watch and found it so. After that he said, if I pulled that paper out underneath, I should see the name of a person, and Newcastle upon Tyne. I looked, and found a paper, on it was 
               <persName id="t17550226-46-person416">
                  James 
                  Smoak 
               <interp inst="t17550226-46-person416" type="surname" value="Smoak"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-46-person416" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550226-46-person416" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , New-castle upon Tyne, watchmaker; then I kept him and the prisoner both in custody, and took them before justice Cox, there the prisone r said, she thought he might lose the watch in Burleigh-street or Exeter-street, and said they were both there in a door-way.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was coming near the Fountain-tavern, this man, the prosecutor, was very drunk, he came by, and said to me, will you go and drink any thing? I said, no, you have had enough already, friend; he took hold of me and pulled me about, I had but a little way to go; I staid a little, he knocked at a door. I went and turned the corner to go home, he came and began to pull and use me very ill, (this drunken man did,) he said it is not late yet, it is not above eleven o'clock, and pulled out his watch, that was the way I came to know he had one. I went down Burleigh-street, in the middle of it, I stopped at a pawnbroker's door there on purpose to get rid of him, he came there and knocked several times; I went on, and when I was got about two or three doors from him, he said I had robbed him of his watch; then I said, it can't be lost, it must be either in this street or the other; and when he had told the watchman he had lost his watch, I said, go down to Burleigh-street or Exeter-street and you'll find it, because I saw it in his hand.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17550226-46-verdict252" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550226-46-verdict252" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
