<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17580913-40">
               <interp inst="t17580913-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-40" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580913"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580913-40" type="date" value="17580913"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580913-40-off210-c304" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-40-defend381 t17580913-40-off210 t17580913-40-verdict212"></join>
         
               <p>297. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17580913-40-defend381" type="defendantName">
                  Jervas 
                  Shaw 
               <interp inst="t17580913-40-defend381" type="surname" value="Shaw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-defend381" type="given" value="Jervas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-defend381" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for that <rs id="t17580913-40-off210" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-off210" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-off210" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               he did feloniously make, forge, and counterfeit, and cause and procure to be falsely counterfeited, a certain order for the payment of 7 l. 12 s . 6 d. directed to the Right Hon. the paymaster, or deputy paymaster to Chelsea hospital, signed 
                     <persName id="t17580913-40-person382">
                        John 
                        Dunshy 
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-person382" type="surname" value="Dunshy"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580913-40-person382" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580913-40-person382" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , and for uttering it, with intent to defraud 
                     <persName id="t17580913-40-victim383" type="victimName">
                        his 
                        Majesty 
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-victim383" type="surname" value="Majesty"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580913-40-victim383" type="given" value="his"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580913-40-victim383" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-40-off210 t17580913-40-victim383"></join>
                     </persName>
                   
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17580913-40-cd211" type="crimeDate">May 1, 1754</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580913-40-off210 t17580913-40-cd211"></join>.*</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-40-person384">
                  James 
                  Emson 
               <interp inst="t17580913-40-person384" type="surname" value="Emson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-person384" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-person384" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner a great while, he applied to me in the year 1751 for a loan of some money, he wanted 200 l. I knew he was one, amongst the many others, that were permitted to discount the pensions for the pensioners at Chelsea hospital; I let him have 200 l. upon giving me his bond, and indorsing to me such a number of the Chelsea pension orders to the paymaster, or his deputy, rather more than the sum lent; and when they became due at the college, he applied to me for them, to receive the money, and deposited a fresh number in my hands in the room of them; he applied to me several times, I lent him 160 l. at another time to the amount of 690 l. in the whole.</p>
               <p>Court. Look on this order. (He takes one in his hand.)</p>
               <p>Emson. I used to deliver the orders to Mr. Rayment Pain, for him to deliver them to the prisoner, and to take others of equal value of him; this is one that I received of Mr. Pain.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you make any mark upon it?</p>
               <p>Emson. Here is J. E. on it, which I put there.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever applied to any body, to see if it was a good order?</p>
               <p>Emson. No, I did not, till there was an act of parliament made to put it out of the power of those people to proceed as before? and when the prisoner was arrested by Mr. Murry, then I thought to see whether my security was good or not, and I found this with others were forged.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you shew it?</p>
               <p>Emson. I shewed it at the office, and then applied to my attorney, he fought other security of the prisoner for me, which was a mortgage of a place he had purchased of 150 l. a year; but this appeared to be no manner of advantage at all, (I suppose it to be of the same kind) so I left it to my attorney to do as he thought proper.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you lend the money on the security of his bond, or on the credit and security of these notes?</p>
               <p>Emson. I would not have lent him 5 l. on his bond; I had a bond, as is customary, but it was on the security of these notes that I lent him the money.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you bring an action on this account ?</p>
               <p>Emson. I do not know what action was brought, my attorney charged him with a declaration.</p>
               <p>Rayment Pain. I have known the prisoner ten or twelve years, I have been frequently intrusted by Mr. Emson to deliver the Chelsea pensioner's orders to the prisoner, and to receive others in the room of them; I received some from the prisoner in the year 1755, about July, to deliver to Mr. Emson.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you receive this now in question of the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Pain. (He takes it in his hand) I really cannot tell in particular, because he delivered a whole bundle to me. I know I delivered them all to Mr. Emson, which he delivered to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you deliver any papers to any other people at that time?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175809130036"></xptr>Pain. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Have not you other people's papers in your custody?</p>
               <p>Pain. No, none but my own; I lent the prisoner money as well as Mr. Emson.</p>

               <p>Q. When did you deliver these papers to Mr. Emson?</p>
               <p>Pain. I delivered them to him about July 1755.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Emson. When did Mr. Pain deliver to you these papers?</p>
               <p>Emson. It was in the year 1755, I am sure this is one of them, it was not above five minutes distance in his receiving them of Mr. Shaw, and bringing them up to me.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you make this mark upon it?</p>
               <p>Emson. I believe I made it about three or four days after, it is usual for me so to do.</p>
               <p>It is read to this purport;</p>
               <p>December 17, 1754.</p>
               <p>'' Sir, pray pay to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17580913-40-person385">
                  James 
                  Murry 
               <interp inst="t17580913-40-person385" type="surname" value="Murry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-person385" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-person385" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , or order, '' my twelve months petition money, amounting '' to the sum of seven pounds twelve shillings and '' six-pence, which is, or shall become due to me, '' between the 25th of December 1754, and the '' 25th of December 1755, having received the '' full value of the same from the said James '' Murry, whose receipt shall be your discharge. '' From, sir, your humble servant, 
               <persName id="t17580913-40-person386">
                  John 
                  Dunsby 
               <interp inst="t17580913-40-person386" type="surname" value="Dunsby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-person386" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-person386" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , '' his mark + ''</p>
               <p>'' Witness, 
               <persName id="t17580913-40-person387">
                  William 
                  Galley 
               <interp inst="t17580913-40-person387" type="surname" value="Galley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-person387" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-person387" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>'' Directed to the right honourable the pay-master, '' or deputy pay-master of Chelsea-hospital.''</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-40-person388">
                  John 
                  Dunsby 
               <interp inst="t17580913-40-person388" type="surname" value="Dunsby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-person388" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-person388" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an out pensioner to Chelsea hospital, and have been eleven years.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you write?</p>
               <p>Dunsby. I can, I was a corporal to a troop, and used to write the men's names, &amp;c. (He takes two real orders in his hand; the names to these are my hand writing.)</p>
               <p>Q. Here are witnesses to them, call them, 
               <persName id="t17580913-40-person389">
                  John 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17580913-40-person389" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-person389" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-person389" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17580913-40-person390">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Dun 
               <interp inst="t17580913-40-person390" type="surname" value="Dun"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-person390" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-person390" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Counsel for the crown. We cannot produce them.</p>
               <p>Q. Who procures those witnesses?</p>
               <p>Dunsby. Mr. Murry does.</p>
               <p>Counsel for the prisoner. I object to his being asked as to his name on the order in question, he being interested in it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-40-person391">
                  Ann 
                  Dunsby 
               <interp inst="t17580913-40-person391" type="surname" value="Dunsby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-person391" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-person391" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am 
               <persName id="t17580913-40-person392">
                  John 
                  Dunsby 
               <interp inst="t17580913-40-person392" type="surname" value="Dunsby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-person392" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-person392" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's brother's widow, I have known 
               <persName id="t17580913-40-person393">
                  John 
                  Dunsby 
               <interp inst="t17580913-40-person393" type="surname" value="Dunsby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-person393" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-person393" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             thirty two years, he can write very well, I never knew him to make a mark instead of signing his name in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580913-40-person394">
                  John 
                  Wilton 
               <interp inst="t17580913-40-person394" type="surname" value="Wilton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-person394" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-person394" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I pay the cash in the office, under the pay-master general of Chelsea hospital; I know the prisoner, and have frequently seen him write.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you turn to any book where the prisoner has wrote his name?</p>
               <p>Wilton. Here is a book (producing one) here he has wrote his name to the payment of money.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at the filling up of this order that has the mark of 
               <persName id="t17580913-40-person395">
                  John 
                  Dunsby 
               <interp inst="t17580913-40-person395" type="surname" value="Dunsby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-person395" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-person395" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             on it, and see if it agrees with the prisoner's writing in that book. (He compares them.)</p>
               <p>Wilton. I think the prisoner writes better then this body of the order.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17580913-40-verdict212" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580913-40-verdict212" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
