<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17551204-44">
               <interp inst="t17551204-44" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551204-44" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551204-44" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17551204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551204-44" type="date" value="17551204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17551204-44-off233-c413" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-44-defend486 t17551204-44-off233 t17551204-44-verdict236"></join>
         
               <p>52. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17551204-44-defend486" type="defendantName">
                     Christopher 
                     Wade 
                  <interp inst="t17551204-44-defend486" type="surname" value="Wade"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-defend486" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-defend486" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17551204-44-off233" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-off233" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-off233" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17551204-44-victim488" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Hughes 
                        <interp inst="t17551204-44-victim488" type="surname" value="Hughes"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17551204-44-victim488" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17551204-44-victim488" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-44-off233 t17551204-44-victim488"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in fear and danger of his life, and stealing from his person 1 silver watch, value 3 l. and 14 s. in money numbered
            </rs>, his property, <rs id="t17551204-44-cd234" type="crimeDate">Sept. 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-44-off233 t17551204-44-cd234"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-44-person489">
                  John 
                  Hughes 
               <interp inst="t17551204-44-person489" type="surname" value="Hughes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-person489" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-person489" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 27th of Sept. I was riding towards Barnet. The prisoner followed me up <placeName id="t17551204-44-crimeloc235">Highgate hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17551204-44-crimeloc235" type="placeName" value="Highgate hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17551204-44-crimeloc235" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-44-off233 t17551204-44-crimeloc235"></join>, till I got about 200 yards beyond the five-mile stone, when he came on my right hand, and said something. I he'd up my whip, and said, What do you mean? He said, D - n your blood your money in a minute, or else you are a dead man. I said, In a litt'e time he should have it, only give me leave to take off my glove. Then he said, Dispatch (two or three times) or you are a dead man. I pulled out my money, which was about 14 shillings, and gave it to him, thinking he would have gone off. He then said, You have a watch. I then said, I had none. He said, I'll search you. Then I pulled out my watch, and said, If you will have it, take it. It was not quite dark, even when I had reached Whetstone-turnpike. He was not above three quarters of a yard from me. I know the prisoner is the man. I since saw him and the watch at justice Fielding's.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175512040054"></xptr>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Hughes. I can't say I ever saw him before, but very probably I might see him before, because I am in London every day in the week.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see so much of him, as to think you should know him if ever you saw him again?</p>
               <p>Hughes. I said, as soon as I came home, I should know him wherever I saw him; and I verily believe the prisoner to be the man.</p>
               <p>Q. And do you only verily believe he is the man?</p>
               <p>Hughes. That is the man.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he any thing on his face?</p>
               <p>Hughes. No, he had not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he produce any instrument to you?</p>
               <p>Hughes. He produced a horse pistol.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was it from the time of your being lobbed till you saw him again?</p>
               <p>Hughes. I was robbed on the 27th of September, and I did not see him till the 10th of November.</p>
               <p>Q. What condition was he in then?</p>
               <p>Hughes. His head was bound up, but he had the very self same face.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not there appear to be a bruise on his face?</p>
               <p>Hughes. No, there did not to my knowledge?</p>
               <p>Q. At that time was he shewed to you, or did you pitch upon him?</p>
               <p>Hughes. The door was opened, and the moment I saw him I said that was the man.</p>
               <p>Q. How many people were there together?</p>
               <p>Hughes. There were, I believe, 8 or 10 people in the room.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-44-person490">
                  Francis 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17551204-44-person490" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-person490" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-person490" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My boy had been out of an errand on the 20th of October, about nine at night he ran in, and said there was a pistol gone off, and a horse ran along with a man; I ran out, and there lay the prisoner on a bench, bleeding at his temple, and people standing round him; I said, for God's sake let us get him to the hospital. As he lay I saw the head of a pistol under his coat, I took it out and gave it to a gentleman to hold, and looked to see if there were any more. Then we carried him to the hospital, where I took his breeches, and found two half crowns, a bullet and some loose powder.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you first see the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Taylor. He fell from his horse at the corner of Great Russel-Street, adjoining to Tottenham-Court road.</p>
               <p>Q. Which way was he going?</p>
               <p>Taylor. My boy said he was coming to London.</p>
               <p>Q. What account did the prisoner give of himself?</p>
               <p>Taylor. He was not capable of giving any account of himself that night. I went to justice Fielding's the next morning; where was justice Welch, and he went with me to the prisoner, and asked him where he had been; he said he had been at Brentford to see his master where he had worked; he was asked how he came to come down that road; he said he crossed the country for a ride. The next day there was this robbery talked of, and some country farmers came to our door, and said a man had stopped serjeant Draper's man. I had the horse he rode in my stable.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a horse was he ?</p>
               <p>Taylor. A black horse, upwards of fifteen hands high.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. What sort of a horse did the person ride that robbed you?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. He rode a black gelding I believe.</p>
               <p>Taylor. Mr. Welch ordered me to bring the prisoner to him. When he was there Mr. Welch asked him what pistol that was that went off; he said somebody had pursued him to rob him. Mr. Welch asked him if he stood in his own defence; he said no, but he turn'd up a lane, and the highwayman followed and fired at him. Mr. Welch asked him if he himself had any pistols; he said no.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you or Mr. Welch tell him you had found one upon him?</p>
               <p>Taylor. No.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you think he was in his senses ?</p>
               <p>Taylor. I can't really say; he spoke some things sensibly, but he was in a sad case.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that pistol charged which you took from him?</p>
               <p>Taylor. No, it was discharged. Justice Welch and I went to his lodgings, and broke open a little box, and found a brace of balls and two gun flints. He sent us wrong at first to his lodgings, saying he lodged at a place in Westminster; and at last we were informed by his master he lodged at the Dial in Queen-street.</p>
               <p>Q. What is he?</p>
               <p>Taylor. He is a journeyman baker.</p>
               <p>Natious Jourdan. To the best of my knowledge the prisoner is the man that brought a watch to me, which was advertised in Mr. Fielding's paper. ( produced in court.)</p>
               <p>Q. What did you lend him upon it?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175512040055"></xptr>Jourdan. I lent him 35 shillings upon it.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. Look at this watch, do you know it?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. This is the very watch I was robbed of, here is the name 
               <persName id="t17551204-44-person491">
                  Thomas 
                  Pryer 
               <interp inst="t17551204-44-person491" type="surname" value="Pryer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-person491" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-person491" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             on it, and it winds up very weakly.</p>
               <p>Q. to Jourdan. When was this watch brought to your house ?</p>
               <p>Jourdan. It was brought on Tuesday the 17th of October.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the prisoner ever brought any thing to you before?</p>
               <p>Jourdan. No, he had not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he bring it by day light?</p>
               <p>Jourdan. It was, but I can't tell the time to an hour.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you positive the prisoner is the man that brought the watch?</p>
               <p>Jourdan. I don't take upon me to be positive, but I believe him to be the man.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you know him by?</p>
               <p>Jourdan. By his face; he has a remarkable face.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Jourdan. I live in Bedford-street, Red-Lion-square, Holbourn.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the first time you saw him after the watch was brought to you?</p>
               <p>Jourdan. I saw him in New-prison about three weeks after. Mr. Fielding order'd me to go and look among a number of people, to see if I could find him.</p>
               <p>Q. How many people were there?</p>
               <p>Jourdan. There were I believe 15 or 16. I saw no body else like him; so I pick'd him out at once.</p>
               <p>Q. What was there so remarkable in his face?</p>
               <p>Jourdan. A long nose and a down look; and when I heard his voice at Mr. Fielding's, I told Mr. Fielding I thought he spoke like the man; and I told him the prisoner was the same height.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he a cap or a wig on when he brought the watch?</p>
               <p>Jourdan. He had a cap on. Since that at Mr. Fielding's I saw him in a wig.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. Is that watch your own?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No. I borrow'd it; but I was to pay so much money for it. I had that watch 4 months the last year.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>The pistol I took was for my own security, having heard that several robberies had been committed on that road; having a little money about me (but tho' I had not much of that, I had a life ) I thought proper to take sufficient care of myself.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-44-person492">
                  Joanna 
                  Sparrow 
               <interp inst="t17551204-44-person492" type="surname" value="Sparrow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-person492" type="given" value="Joanna"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-person492" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am nurse at the Middlesex-Hospital, in Tottenham-Court road. The prisoner was brought in there on Monday night; he was very much cut, and had lost a great deal of blood. The surgeon was sent for; and to the best of my knowledge he was not in his senses, and could not give reasonable answers.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you recollect what he did not give reasonable answers to?</p>
               <p>Sparrow. If I carried him a mess of water-gruel, he did not know but it was broth.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Adkins. I am a nurse in the womens ward. The prisoner's sister came to see him; after that he desired I would go for her, to come and see him. I said she had been there.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Adkins. This was on the next morning after he was brought into the hospital. I ask'd him how he did? and in the afternoon told him his sister had been there; he said he did not know she had been there. This was after Mr. Welch had been there.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-44-person493">
                  Samuel 
                  Wade 
               <interp inst="t17551204-44-person493" type="surname" value="Wade"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-person493" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-person493" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a baker. The prisoner is my nephew. I have known him ever since he was born; he never committed any thing ill that ever I heard of, till this accident. I have had him under my care these fourteen years. I intended him for my business and shop. He did not work with me at this time; he was gone from me about a year. When he was with me I did not lock up my money; he had an opportunity of doing any thing at my house.</p>
               <p>Q. What was your reason for parting with him?</p>
               <p>Wade. He went away from me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-44-person494">
                  John 
                  Cook 
               <interp inst="t17551204-44-person494" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-person494" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-person494" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner between 7 and 8 years: he always was very honest for what I heard.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-44-person495">
                  Benjamin 
                  Gee 
               <interp inst="t17551204-44-person495" type="surname" value="Gee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-person495" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-person495" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about 6 years: he has been upwards of 2 years a servant with me. He was a very honest good servant; he has had the taking of a good deal of money of mine. I never heard any thing amiss of him till this time. I came here to give him this character without any subpaena.</p>
               <p>Jos. Witicker. I am a smith. I have known him these 8 years: he is a very good honest man to the best of my knowledge.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175512040056"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-44-person496">
                  Edward 
                  Maybow 
               <interp inst="t17551204-44-person496" type="surname" value="Maybow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-person496" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-person496" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a baker. I have known the prisoner about 5 or 6 years: he has worked for me when I have been sick, or my men have been out of the way. He has demeaned himself honestly; he has wrote my books out; and my wife has trusted him with the buroe, where the money was: he might have taken out money, and I never missed it. He has many times wrote bills for me; and he always was a very honest man till this thing happened.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-44-person497">
                  Henry 
                  Hutchens 
               <interp inst="t17551204-44-person497" type="surname" value="Hutchens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-person497" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-person497" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a farmer. I have known the prisoner some time. He always was an honest man; and I never heard any ill of him till this time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-44-person498">
                  William 
                  Collins 
               <interp inst="t17551204-44-person498" type="surname" value="Collins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-person498" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-person498" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a baker. I have known him, I believe, seven years at least. He was servant to me at the time he had this fall. If I had had cool. in my house, my opinion is, I could have left it unlocked. Could he get over this affair, I should have no objection to taking him a gain.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that box the prisoner's where the balls were found?</p>
               <p>Collins. As far as I know it was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that box locked?</p>
               <p>Collins. It was?</p>
               <p>Q. to Taylor. Is this the person that shew'd you the prisoner's box ?</p>
               <p>Taylor. He did; it was in a room up 2 pair of stairs.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-44-person499">
                  Edward 
                  Pool 
               <interp inst="t17551204-44-person499" type="surname" value="Pool"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-person499" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-person499" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a peruke maker. I live in Castle-street, by Leicester-Fields. I believe I have known the prisoner ever since he has been in town; and I never heard any misbehaviour of him till this affair. I always looked upon him to be a very honest fellow; and I came voluntarily here to give him that character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-44-person500">
                  Mathew 
                  Sterne 
               <interp inst="t17551204-44-person500" type="surname" value="Sterne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-person500" type="given" value="Mathew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-person500" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about seven years. He was always a very sober and industrious man: that was his general character. I once lent him 3 l. 18 s. and he paid me, at different times, very honestly.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-44-person501">
                  Richard 
                  Prosser 
               <interp inst="t17551204-44-person501" type="surname" value="Prosser"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-person501" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-person501" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lived very near the prisoner, and have known him a great many years. I always looked upon him to be a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-44-person502">
                  George 
                  Eastman 
               <interp inst="t17551204-44-person502" type="surname" value="Eastman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-person502" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-person502" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a baker. I have known him 8 or 9 years. He is as honest a man as ever I saw in my life; he is as sober a man as ever was born.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. Is it possible you should be mistaken? Or had you a clear sight of him ?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I am not at all mistaken; I am certain he is the man.</p>
               <p>Q. to Pawnbroker. Do you verily believe, or are you mistaken in the person that brought the watch?</p>
               <p>Pawnbroker. I had such a view of him, that I do not think it possible to be mistaken.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17551204-44-verdict236" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-verdict236" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17551204-44-punish237" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17551204-44-punish237" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-44-defend486 t17551204-44-punish237"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
