<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17551204-27">
               <interp inst="t17551204-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551204-27" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551204-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17551204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551204-27" type="date" value="17551204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17551204-27-off140-c186" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-27-defend231 t17551204-27-off140 t17551204-27-verdict143"></join>
         
               <p>33. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17551204-27-defend231" type="defendantName">
                  Isabella 
                  Buckham 
               <interp inst="t17551204-27-defend231" type="surname" value="Buckham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-defend231" type="given" value="Isabella"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-defend231" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             
                  <rs id="t17551204-27-deflabel139" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-27-defend231 t17551204-27-deflabel139"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17551204-27-off140" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-off140" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-off140" type="offenceSubcategory" value="infanticide"></interp>
               the murder of her male bastard child
            </rs>. She like wise stood charged on the coroner's inquest for the midmurder. <rs id="t17551204-27-cd141" type="crimeDate">Nov. 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-27-off140 t17551204-27-cd141"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-27-person232">
                  Ann 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17551204-27-person232" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person232" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person232" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am nurse in <placeName id="t17551204-27-crimeloc142">Faith's ward, Bartholomew's hospital</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17551204-27-crimeloc142" type="placeName" value="Faith's ward, Bartholomew's hospital"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17551204-27-crimeloc142" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-27-off140 t17551204-27-crimeloc142"></join>. The prisoner was a patient there. I was sitting by the fire, she called to me to burg her the bed pan; she was then ill in bed, I did not know she was with child before; she had a loose stool in the pan, I took and emptied it. I went to the fire and heard her puking, I went and held the bed pan to her, and she pulled in it; I went and emptied it again, and put it by her bedside, and went to the fire side again. After that she called me to warm her a flannel petticoat to put round her waist, she desired me to pin it round her waist; told her I could not for fear of pricking her, and she did it on herself. I went and sat by the fire again; 
               <persName id="t17551204-27-person233">
                  Molly 
                  Elger 
               <interp inst="t17551204-27-person233" type="surname" value="Elger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person233" type="given" value="Molly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person233" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             called to 
               <persName id="t17551204-27-person234">
                  Peggy 
                  Bland 
               <interp inst="t17551204-27-person234" type="surname" value="Bland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person234" type="given" value="Peggy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person234" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and said, do you not hear a child cry? Peggy said, yes, I do; the prisoner said, I hear one cry myself.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>A. Smith. On the 20th of Nov. betwixt one and two o'clock. Some time after this the prisoner said, nurse, my sheets are all wet; I turned the cloaths down, and found the sheets all as they are when a woman has had a child. I said, God bless me, here has been a child; she said, nurse do not say such a thing, for I never had a child in my life. She bid me put the sheets out and have them wash'd, and she would pay for them. I took them to M. Elger, and said, look here, she says she never had a child; I said, where the child is I do not know. Then my sister, 
               <persName id="t17551204-27-person235">
                  Mary 
                  Steward 
               <interp inst="t17551204-27-person235" type="surname" value="Steward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person235" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person235" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , told her, you have had a child, pray where is it, and sent for a midwife; she came and cleared her of the after burthen, I carried the bason to put it in. After that her white flannel petticoat was taken out of the bed, and we saw the print of the child in it where it had laid. After sometime she said, the man that drove the stage coach to Bethnal-green was the man, (but did not say he was her husband, or the child's father) and there are none but you (to me) and the people in the ward can save me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see the child afterwards?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-27-person236">
                  Ann 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17551204-27-person236" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person236" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person236" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw a child afterwards in the dead house in the coffin, but I will not swear that was the child.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175512040016"></xptr>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you been mother of children?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-27-person237">
                  Ann 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17551204-27-person237" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person237" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person237" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Yes I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Have not people been in the same condition in miscarriages ?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-27-person238">
                  Ann 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17551204-27-person238" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person238" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person238" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Yes, they have. I don't say that was her child.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any childbed linen among her things ?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-27-person239">
                  Ann 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17551204-27-person239" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person239" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person239" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never looked among her things?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-27-person240">
                  Mary 
                  Elger 
               <interp inst="t17551204-27-person240" type="surname" value="Elger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person240" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person240" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was a patient in the ward at the time. On Thursday the 20th of November between the hours of one and two in the morning, I heard a child cry.</p>
               <p>Q. From whence did it come?</p>
               <p>Elger. From some part of the ward.</p>
               <p>Q. Did it come from where the prisoner lay?</p>
               <p>Elger. I can't say that. I got up right in my bed, and said to 
               <persName id="t17551204-27-person241">
                  Margaret 
                  Bland 
               <interp inst="t17551204-27-person241" type="surname" value="Bland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person241" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person241" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Lord Peggy, don't you hear a child cry? she answered, and said, yes; and the prisoner said, Lord! Polly, so do I hear it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see this child afterwards?</p>
               <p>Elger. Yes, I saw it in the taking in room, when the coroner sat on it; I had seen it first in the dead house.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was you from the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Elger. About the distance of 6 or 7 yards.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you take upon you to say it was the prisoner's child?</p>
               <p>Elger. I would not say so for the world.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not some of the people say they heard some young kittens cry the night before?</p>
               <p>Elger. Some of them did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-27-person242">
                  Margaret 
                  Bland 
               <interp inst="t17551204-27-person242" type="surname" value="Bland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person242" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person242" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 20th of Nov. at half an hour-after one, I sat upon my bed a coughing, and I heard a cry of a child; and 
               <persName id="t17551204-27-person243">
                  Mary 
                  Elger 
               <interp inst="t17551204-27-person243" type="surname" value="Elger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person243" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person243" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             called to me, and said, 
               <persName id="t17551204-27-person244">
                  Peggy 
                  Bland 
               <interp inst="t17551204-27-person244" type="surname" value="Bland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person244" type="given" value="Peggy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person244" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , did not you hear a child cry? I said, yes, I did. Then the prisoner said to 
               <persName id="t17551204-27-person245">
                  Mary 
                  Elger 
               <interp inst="t17551204-27-person245" type="surname" value="Elger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person245" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person245" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Lord, Polly, I think I hear a child cry too. I laid myself down and heard no more.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-27-person246">
                  Mary 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17551204-27-person246" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person246" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person246" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I sent for the midwife, and saw the after burthen taken from the prisoner; and I saw tracks, all bloody, from the bed to the necessary house, but I saw no child till I saw one in the dead house; but I can't swear it to be the prisoner's.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the prisoner go to the necessary house ?</p>
               <p>Lewis. No, I did not. I saw a great deal of blood and matter on the sheets that were taken off her bed, and a round mark in the petticoat as if a child had been there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the sheets taken off the bed ?</p>
               <p>Lewis. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the petticoat taken out of the bed ?</p>
               <p>Lewis. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you see this blood on the sheets?</p>
               <p>Lewis. About five in the morning.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any talk with the prisoner at the bar ?</p>
               <p>Lewis. I asked her where was her child? she said she had never a one.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she appear to be in her senses?</p>
               <p>Lewis. I can't tell, for I was almost out of mine.</p>
               <p>Q. to Ann Smith. Did the prisoner appear to be in or out of her senses at the time?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-27-person247">
                  Ann 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17551204-27-person247" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person247" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person247" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am not able to say which?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-27-person248">
                  Mary 
                  Old 
               <interp inst="t17551204-27-person248" type="surname" value="Old"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person248" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person248" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the hospital at the time; I lay in the next bed to the prisoner I heard her very ill in the night, she groaned violently; I heard her get out of the bed to go to the vault twice, and come in again; I opened my curtain and saw her go to it, and shut the door afterwards. I saw the sheets taken off the bed afterwards; they were like a lying-in woman's sheets. I saw the flannel petticoat taken out of the bed; that was bloody.</p>
               <p>Q. What hour was it you heard her groan first?</p>
               <p>Old. It was very early in the morning; she awaked me out of my sleep, but I don't know the hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear a child cry?</p>
               <p>Old. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. If a child had cry'd in the next bed to you, should you have heard it as soon as the groans of a woman.</p>
               <p>Old. I can't say for that.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you not known people in that extreme pain they are in at such a time, to be put out of their senses?</p>
               <p>Old. I can't say I ever knew such a thing, it may be.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the other women say that they heard a child cry?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175512040017"></xptr>Old. I did not hear them say so then, but I heard them say so afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17551204-27-person249">
                  Ann 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17551204-27-person249" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person249" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person249" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . How often did you hear the child cry ?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-27-person250">
                  Ann 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17551204-27-person250" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person250" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person250" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard but one shriek.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-27-person251">
                  Ann 
                  Wing 
               <interp inst="t17551204-27-person251" type="surname" value="Wing"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person251" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person251" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the same ward with the prisoner; I saw her get out of the bed, and saw her turning from the feet of the bed, going into the vault between one and two in the morning; I did not see her come back again. I saw the sheets taken off the bed, they were very bloody, and so was the prisoner. I saw the flannel petticoat lying on the floor. There were clots of blood fell on the floor, which shook out of the sheets as they were taken out of the bed; there were all the symptoms of her having been delivered of a child. I did not see the child till it was in the hall; it was a fine boy.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Would not she have been in the same condition had she miscarried?</p>
               <p>Wing. She might.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-27-person252">
                  William 
                  Clutterburg 
               <interp inst="t17551204-27-person252" type="surname" value="Clutterburg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person252" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I belong to Bartholomew's hospital. There was a report there had been a child born in the ward where the prisoner lay, and the treasurer gave orders the vault should be searched. There was a piece of heavy iron fixed to a rope and let down; it stopped after it was gone a little way down, but by raising the iron and letting it down several times, the passage was opened; then we went to search the sespool; this vault vented itself on the left side; I ordered them to search, and soon a fine male child was taken out. I observed a wound on the side of the head, which I imagined was given by the iron instrument that was let down. It seemed to be a full grown child.</p>
               <p>Q. Had it nails on its fingers?</p>
               <p>Clutterburg. I think it had; and hair. It was as fine a child as ever I saw. It appeared to have been fresh thrown in.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was not in my senses; I do not know what I said or did. Had I been in my senses I should have been very loth to have parted with it.</p>
               <p>To her character.</p>
               <p>Mr. Avery. The prisoner lived servant with me two years and three months; she believed modest, sober, honest and careful; I never heard her spell an ill word.</p>
               <p>Q. When did she come to live with you?</p>
               <p>Mr. Avery. She came the 4th or 5th of September was two year, and she imagined she had a dropsy, and went from my house to the hospital.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17551204-27-verdict143" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17551204-27-verdict143" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
