<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17500711-28">
               <interp inst="t17500711-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-28" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17500711"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-28" type="date" value="17500711"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500711-28-off125-c180" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-28-defend235 t17500711-28-off125 t17500711-28-verdict130"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500711-28-off125-c181" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-28-defend236 t17500711-28-off125 t17500711-28-verdict130"></join>
         
               <p>447, 448. 
               
                  <persName id="t17500711-28-defend235" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Wallis 
                  <interp inst="t17500711-28-defend235" type="surname" value="Wallis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-28-defend235" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-28-defend235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               <persName id="t17500711-28-defend236" type="defendantName">
                  
                     John 
                     Carrel 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17500711-28-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-28-defend236 t17500711-28-alias-3"></join>Daniel</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-28-defend236" type="surname" value="Carrel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-28-defend236" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-28-defend236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , were indicted for that they, <rs id="t17500711-28-off125" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500711-28-off125" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-28-off125" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               in a certain field, or open place, near the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17500711-28-victim239" type="victimName">
                           Arthur 
                           Gardiner 
                        <interp inst="t17500711-28-victim239" type="surname" value="Gardiner"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500711-28-victim239" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500711-28-victim239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , did make an assault,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175007110013"></xptr> putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, one portmanteau, val. 6 s. one cloth coat, val. 40 s. one cloth wastcoat, val. 20 s. one pair of breeches, six shirts, six cravats, three pair of worsted stocking, two pair of thread, one perriwig, six handkerchiefs, three razors, one penknife, one pair of pumps, and other things, the goods of the <rs id="t17500711-28-viclabel126" type="occupation">Rev. Mr. 
                        <persName id="t17500711-28-victim240" type="victimName">
                           Stephen 
                           Row 
                        <interp inst="t17500711-28-victim240" type="surname" value="Row"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17500711-28-victim240" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17500711-28-victim240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        </persName>
                      
                     </rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-28-victim240 t17500711-28-viclabel126"></join>, from the person of the said 
                     <persName id="t17500711-28-person241">
                        Arthur 
                        Gardner 
                     <interp inst="t17500711-28-person241" type="surname" value="Gardner"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500711-28-person241" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500711-28-person241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , did steal, take, and carry away
            </rs>, <rs id="t17500711-28-cd127" type="crimeDate">June 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-28-off125 t17500711-28-cd127"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-28-person242">
                  Arthur 
                  Gardner 
               <interp inst="t17500711-28-person242" type="surname" value="Gardner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-28-person242" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-28-person242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 21st of June I had my master's portmanteau carrying it home, coming through <placeName id="t17500711-28-crimeloc128">Stepney church-yard</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17500711-28-crimeloc128" type="placeName" value="Stepney church-yard"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17500711-28-crimeloc128" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-28-off125 t17500711-28-crimeloc128"></join> a little after nine at night, I met three fellows, one of them stop'd me and put a hanger to my throat, and seized me by the shoulder : I was in a great surprise, I cannot swear to the prisoners (this witness was very near sighted ) one of them took the portmanteau, the other guarded me. There was in the portmanteau the things mentioned in the indictment. I cried out murder, they swore if I offered to speak they would kill me directly; they made me deliver two penknives which I had in my pocket; I got some assistance and pursued them to Rag fair. We met three men, they had each a bundle, they went into a house; we went for a constable, but not having a warrant he refused going with us. I went to my master and got money for a warrant and got one; then we went to the house and searched it, but found nothing. The portmanteau was broke open in the fields that night and left there.</p>

               <p>The Rev. Mr. Stephen Row. I ordered this witness, my <rs id="t17500711-28-viclabel129" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-28-victim239 t17500711-28-viclabel129"></join>, to go forward with my portmanteau while I discharged the waterman; he did, I followed after; as I came up White Horse street, within sight of the church-yard, I heard an outcry that there was a robbery committed: I saw my servant at the Red cross, making his complaint to three men, saying he was robbed. I desired the men to come along with me and pursue them, which they did.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the things in the portmanteau yours?</p>
               <p>Row. They were, my Lord. There were a cloth coat, a cloth waistcoat, a pair of breeches, 6 shirts, 6 cravats, 1 pair of silk, 3 pair of worsted, and two pair of thread stockings; three razors, six or seven handkerchiefs, a pair of silver buckles, a pair of pumps, one penknife; there were two taken from my servant, one was his own. I put the things in the portmanteau myself; it was brought home the next morning, found broke open in the field; the man is not here who found it. There was a wig of mine found on the accomplice's head, 
               <persName id="t17500711-28-person243">
                  William 
                  Dawson 
               <interp inst="t17500711-28-person243" type="surname" value="Dawson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-28-person243" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-28-person243" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who is here as an evidence against them. I heard there was a person apprehended in the parish of St. John, Wapping, I went to see him, I heard he had confessed robbing my servant, and other robberies, before Justice Manwaring. On Friday last I had word sent me from the beadle, that Dawson, then in Clerkenwel Bridewell, desired I would come to him, and he would give me a farther account of this robbery. I went on Sunday evening, he told me of a woman, whom he had informed against before, for receiving part of the goods, and had pledged them, and if I would send the beadle after her she was easy to be found. Then I saw my servant talking to some of the prisoners, he was informed by them that Dawson had then my wig on; I made him take it off, and examined it, and knew it to be mine (it was produced in court.) He said he had it of the prisoner Carrel, and that it was the wig they took out of my portmanteau.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-28-person244">
                  William 
                  Dawson 
               <interp inst="t17500711-28-person244" type="surname" value="Dawson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-28-person244" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-28-person244" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The two prisoners at the bar and I stop'd this first witness in Stepney churchyard. We were going towards Limehouse, we went all out of Rag fair together about 8 o'clock; we went over the fields to Stepney, we met the footman in White Horse street; that is about a quarter of a mile from the church-yard. When he came into the church-yard we stop'd him, Wallis held a hanger to his face, and he let the portmanteau fall.</p>
               <p>Q. to Gardner. Did you let it fall, or did they take it from your shoulder?</p>
               <p>Gardner. I believe I let it fall, but I was much surprised.</p>
               <p>Dawson. We took two penknives from him.</p>
               <p>Gardner. They did so, and a penny.</p>
               <p>Dawson. We carried the portmanteau into the fields about half a mile, and broke it open, we did it in a little time, for we were dodged over the fields. We took out the things and threw the portmanteau into the ditch, and left it there. We carried the things to Stitchburn's house where we lodg'd. The things were divided, I had a shirt and a pair of black worsted stockings and some handkerchiefs for my share. The wig I had from Carrel the next day. Carrel had a pair of stockings, a shirt and a pair of new shoes ; Wallis had a new Holland shirt, a pair of white stockings, and two handkerchiefs. The coat, waistcoat and breeches were pawned for nine shillings, I had four shillings and sixpence of the money, but the girl who carried them to pawn would not tell us where she had pawned them; some things we lost ; the house where we lodged was searched the same night, Carrel and I got over a wall into an alley, or we had been taken.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175007110014"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-28-person245">
                  John 
                  Penney 
               <interp inst="t17500711-28-person245" type="surname" value="Penney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-28-person245" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-28-person245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an officer of St. John, Wapping. Since the prisoners have been taken I know them, I was in pursuit of them about the twenty second of June. Dawson the evidence, when taken, had a hanger, a penknife, a half guinea in gold, and three or four shillings in silver, and a new silver buckle, the knife and buckle were produced in court.</p>
               <p>Row. The buckle is not mine. But as far as I can know a knife I take it to be the knife I gave to my servant to make pens with. Gardner deposed the knife was his property, given him by his master.</p>
               <p>Wallis's Defence. I was going through Rag fair a little in liquor: I met this Dawson that night he came home in the same fleet as I did; he desired I would drink a pint of beer, he said, where do you lodge? I said in Wapping: he said, come along with me; so I went along with him till such time he stop'd that first witness, and ran away with the things. I know no more, I am a stranger in the place.</p>
               <p>Carrel's Defence. I know nothing about it, I have not had my health these three or four months. I was at my lodgings and going for a pint of mild porter; I met a man who said I was his prisoner, and took me up upon suspicion, and I went quietly with him.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17500711-28-verdict130" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500711-28-verdict130" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs>  
                  <rs id="t17500711-28-punish131" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500711-28-punish131" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-28-defend235 t17500711-28-punish131"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-28-defend236 t17500711-28-punish131"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
