<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560115-33">
               <interp inst="t17560115-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560115-33" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560115-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560115"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560115-33" type="date" value="17560115"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560115-33-off158-c307" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560115-33-defend372 t17560115-33-off158 t17560115-33-verdict161"></join>
         
               <p>95. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17560115-33-defend372" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Goldbourn 
                  <interp inst="t17560115-33-defend372" type="surname" value="Goldbourn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-33-defend372" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-33-defend372" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17560115-33-deflabel157" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560115-33-defend372 t17560115-33-deflabel157"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17560115-33-off158" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560115-33-off158" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-33-off158" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 12 yards of silk, value 34 s. 18 yards of paduasoy ribbon, value 5 s. 41 yards of other paduasoy ribbon, 7 yards of taffaty, 31 yards of sattin ribbon, 15 yards of figured ribbon, 11 yards of other sattin ribbon, 25 yards of other sattin ribbon, 4 yards of silk lace, 1 yard of sattin, 2 yard of gause, 6 yards of black silk remnants, 1 yard of black sattin, 3 yards of figured silk, 2 yards and a half of cheque gause, 4 pair of scarlet garters, 2 yards of plain gause, 6 oz. and half of sewing silk, 8 oz of other sewing silk, 12 yards of silk, 1 yard of Mechlin lace, 69 yards of shalloon, and 36 yards of black love ribbon, the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17560115-33-victim374" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Hopley 
                        <interp inst="t17560115-33-victim374" type="surname" value="Hopley"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560115-33-victim374" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560115-33-victim374" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560115-33-off158 t17560115-33-victim374"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in his dwelling-house
            </rs>, <rs id="t17560115-33-cd159" type="crimeDate">December 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560115-33-off158 t17560115-33-cd159"></join>. *</p> 
               <p>Amelia Hopley. The prisoner was my <rs id="t17560115-33-deflabel160" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560115-33-defend372 t17560115-33-deflabel160"></join>. On the 13th of Dec. in the morning, between 7 and 8 o'clock, when my husband and I were in bed, she came to the bed-side, and took his breeches from off a chair, and carried them into the dining-room; she then brought them again, and lay'd them on the chair. I was awake at the time.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was she gone with them?</p>
               <p>A. Hopley. She instantly returned. She then came to the feet of the bed, and took off his coat, and carried that into the dining-room; she presently brought it back, and laid it where she took it from.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the waistcoat in the coat?</p>

               <p>A. Hopley. I can't say whether it was or not. As she was spreading the coat smooth as she found it, I stir'd in the bed, as though awaking: She shrunk behind the curtain for some time; then she softly went out of the room, and stay'd till the usual time she used to come up and call Mr. Hopley; then he awaked directly and answered her.</p>
               <p>Q. When he awaked did you acquaint him with what you observed?</p>
               <p>A. Hopley. I did. He got up in about half an hour after that; he went down stairs, and sent for a person to talk to her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he search his breeches?</p>
               <p>A. Hopley. He did, and missed nothing; he happened to have taken out the money over night.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he miss any thing out of his coat pocket?</p>
               <p>A. Hopley. No, nothing at all.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560115-33-person375">
                  John 
                  Hopley 
               <interp inst="t17560115-33-person375" type="surname" value="Hopley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-33-person375" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-33-person375" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When I awaked in the morning, on the 13th of Dec. my spouse related the thing of the maid's having been in the room, as she has now. We both suspected she wanted the key of the buroe out of my pocket. I had put the money out of my pocket over night, except a few halfpence, but whether there were any missing of them I know not. I had before missed money, and that very week a guinea; and the day before 1 s. 6 d. out of a drawer which was lock'd in my warehouse. I thought proper to send for Mr. Newton, when I got up, to hear her examined: She was call'd into a room in my warehouse: he examined her, and she denied every thing; then we open'd her box, in which we found some of<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175601150031"></xptr> the things mentioned in the indictment. After she was committed she sent for her trunk, which was lock'd. I thought it to be empty; but finding it heavy, I refused to send it till it was opened. I had it broke open, and in it we found a deal box, and things conceal'd in it.</p>
               <p>Q. What things?</p>
               <p>Hopley. The following goods:</p>
               <p>Twelve yards of silk</p>
               <p>Eighteen yards of paduasoy ribbon</p>
               <p>Forty-one yards of other paduasoy ribbon</p>
               <p>Seven yards of taffaty</p>
               <p>Thirty-one yards of sattin ribbon</p>
               <p>Fourteen yards of figured ribbon</p>
               <p>Eleven yards of narrow ditto</p>
               <p>Twenty-five yards of narrow shaded ribbon</p>
               <p>Four yards of silk lace</p>
               <p>One yard of black gause</p>
               <p>Six yards of black silk remnants</p>
               <p>One yard of black sattin</p>
               <p>Three yards of figured silk</p>
               <p>Two yards and half of cheque gause</p>
               <p>Four pair of scarlet garters</p>
               <p>Two yards of plain gause</p>
               <p>Six ounces and half of sewing silk</p>
               <p>Eight ounces of black and coloured silk</p>
               <p>Twelve yards of silk</p>
               <p>One yard of Mechlin lace</p>
               <p>Sixty-nine yards of shalloon</p>
               <p>Thirty-six yards of black love ribbon</p>
               <p>The last I can swear to.</p>
               <p>Q. Can't you swear to all the rest?</p>
               <p>Hopley. I can to the first article, the 12 yards of silk, the 18 yards of paduasoy ribbon, and a quarter of a pound of scarlet thread; I can't to the others, but there were private marks to those I swear to.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business ?</p>
               <p>Hopley. I am a haberdasher. These several things were found in a deal box, concealed within her trunk. This trunk was in the garret where she lay. At first she said she could not find the key of it; but when she found we would break it open, then she open'd it; after which, when we found the deal box in it, she owned in the compter, that when she went up stairs to dress herself, to go before a magistrate, she took the box from under the bed there was a padlock upon it) and locked it in the trunk, and took the key to prison with her.</p>
               <p>Q. What was found in the trunk at the first opening it?</p>
               <p>Hopley. There was velvet, and half a yard of black sattin, 3 gause handkerchiefs, a piece of shalloon, 2 yards of muslin, and a ruffled shirt, on which she was committed.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you swear to the shirt?</p>
               <p>Hopley. I know that is mine by the number on it, it being missing, and she owning she took it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she confess any thing?</p>
               <p>Hopley. I heard her say all the things mentioned were mine, and that she was exceedingly sorry for what she had done.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did she say this?</p>
               <p>Hopley. She said this in the Poultry compter.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you make the first search?</p>
               <p>Hopley. On the 13th of Dec. at the time I found the things upon which she was committed to the compter.</p>
               <p>Q. Who unlock'd the trunk?</p>
               <p>Hopley. She herself.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after her opening the trunk was it that she was sent to the compter?</p>
               <p>Hopley. Not till the best part of an hour after.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you miss the goods at different times?</p>
               <p>Hopley. It was impossible to miss every individual; but I missed some.</p>
               <p>Q. When might you lose the twelve yards of black silk?</p>
               <p>Hopley. I cannot say; but I lost it within the time she was my servant.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you lose the 18 yards of paduasoy ? Was it at a different time from the other?</p>
               <p>Hopley. I can't exactly say at what time. To be sure there must be a good deal of time in collecting all these things together.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560115-33-person376">
                  John 
                  Terry 
               <interp inst="t17560115-33-person376" type="surname" value="Terry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-33-person376" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-33-person376" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was the constable. Mr. Hopley sent a servant to me on Saturday morning, the 13th of Dec. When I came there I was desired to go up into the dining-room: there was Mr. Hopley and the prisoner at the bar. He said, I am very sorry to trouble you thus; but I must give you charge of my servant (meaning the prisoner) she has rob'd me. There lay some handkerchiefs and gloves, and other things, on the floor. He was looking at them, and said, These are my property, she has own'd it. I said, You base hussy, have you done this ? Yes, she said, I have, and they are my master's property; I have, continued she, the best of masters: What I did it for I know not! Mr. Hopley came to my house on the 28th of Dec. and said, I have a suspicion of a greater robbery<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175601150032"></xptr> committed by my maid. Is it not right to break open her trunk, for I suspect there are things of mine in it?</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the prisoner then?</p>
               <p>Terry. She was in the Poultry compter. He told me she had sent for her trunk. We broke it open, and there we found some baize and stockings by the side of a box, which was withinside. Mr. Hopley said, What is in this box? There was a padlock hung to it. He said, I insist upon this being broke open, which was done, and there we found the things mentioned. They are all here ( producing a large bundle ) and she owned likewise she took them at different times. I asked her in what manner this box was conveyed into the trunk. She said, When you went home to stay till I had cleaned myself, I took that box from under my bed, and put it into my trunk.</p>
               <p>As it appeared the prisoner had taken these goods at divers times; but no proof that she had at any one time taken goods to the amount of forty shillings value, the jury found her <rs id="t17560115-33-verdict161" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560115-33-verdict161" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-33-verdict161" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder40s"></interp>
               guilty 39 s.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17560115-33-punish162" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560115-33-punish162" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-33-punish162" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560115-33-defend372 t17560115-33-punish162"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
