<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570914-39">
               <interp inst="t17570914-39" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-39" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-39" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570914"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-39" type="date" value="17570914"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570914-39-off258-c402" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-39-defend485 t17570914-39-off258 t17570914-39-verdict260"></join>
         
               <p>347. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17570914-39-defend485" type="defendantName">
                  Mary, <rs id="t17570914-39-deflabel257" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-39-defend485 t17570914-39-deflabel257"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17570914-39-person486">
                        Andrew 
                        Scott 
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-person486" type="surname" value="Scott"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570914-39-person486" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570914-39-person486" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  ,<interp inst="t17570914-39-defend485" type="surname" value="Scott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-defend485" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-defend485" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17570914-39-off258" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-off258" type="offenceCategory" value="miscellaneous"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-off258" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pervertingJustice"></interp>
               endeavouring to facilitate the escape of Andrew her husband, he being at that time committed to Newgate for a felony
            </rs>, <rs id="t17570914-39-cd259" type="crimeDate">September 11</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-39-off258 t17570914-39-cd259"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>Mr. Akerman. (He produces the original detainer.) This was sent to me by Mr. Fielding, which was in order to detain 
               <persName id="t17570914-39-person487">
                  Andrew 
                  Scott 
               <interp inst="t17570914-39-person487" type="surname" value="Scott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-person487" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-person487" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in my custody.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen him write?</p>
               <p>Akerman. I have. I am certain it is his handwriting.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it seal'd?</p>
               <p>Akerman. It is.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175709140048"></xptr>It was read in court to this purport:</p>
               <p>Middlesex, to wit,</p>
               <p>To the keeper of his majesty's gaol of Newgate, or his deputy.</p>
               <p>'' Detain in your custody the body of Andrew '' Scott, charged upon oath of 
               <persName id="t17570914-39-person488">
                  Robert 
                  Drummond 
               <interp inst="t17570914-39-person488" type="surname" value="Drummond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-person488" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-person488" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , '' for publishing as true a forg'd indorsement of a '' promisory note, for the payment of twenty-five '' guineas; drawn by Mr. Drummond and Co. '' payable to 
               <persName id="t17570914-39-person489">
                  Thomas 
                  Boone 
               <interp inst="t17570914-39-person489" type="surname" value="Boone"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-person489" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-person489" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; with an intent '' to defraud the said Mr. Boone, and him safely '' keep in your custody, till he shall be discharged '' by due course of law. Given under my hand '' and seal, September 7, 1737.</p>
               <p>Sign'd Fielding.''</p>
               <p>He was a prisoner before this warrant of detainer came to me, on suspicion of robbing the mail, and is now convicted for the crime here mention'd.</p>
               <p>Q. When was he originally committed?</p>
               <p>Akerman. On the 19th of August.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon whose oath?</p>

               <p>Akerman. Upon the oaths of 
               <persName id="t17570914-39-person490">
                  Robert 
                  Lovelace 
               <interp inst="t17570914-39-person490" type="surname" value="Lovelace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-person490" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-person490" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and another, on suspicion of his having rob'd the Portsmouth mail. He was ordered at first to be kept without any body's seeing him, but his wife took on very much, and I was really sorry to see a woman so unhappy as she appeared to be. I kept him from seeing any body, according to the order that I received from Mr. Fielding and the solicitor of the Post-Office. After he had been examined two or three times, I asked it I might admit his wife to him. They said I might admit whom I thought proper with safety. I really had a good deal of compassion on her, and consented to her being there two or three hours in a day.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-39-person491">
                  Jane 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17570914-39-person491" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-person491" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-person491" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live servant with counsellor Lofts. Last Saturday, in the afternoon, Mrs. Scott came to me, and said Mr. Scott intended to make his escape, by disguising himself, and wanted me to lend her a red cloak. I said, I had no such thing. As she was going out, she saw my master's red roqueleau hanging up behind the door, which she ask'd me to lend her. She took it away with her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know her before?</p>
               <p>J. White. I lived two years and a half with her at Mr. Newman's.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was this?</p>
               <p>J. White. This was about five in the afternoon.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say where he was?</p>
               <p>J. White. No, she did not; I knew he was in Newgate. I saw him there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she know you knew where he was ?</p>
               <p>J. White. Yes, she did; I saw her there with him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-39-person492">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Day 
               <interp inst="t17570914-39-person492" type="surname" value="Day"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-person492" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-person492" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mrs. Scott came to me last Sunday about noon, and desired me to go of an errand for her.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>E. Day. I live in Cock-Alley, Norton-Falgate.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>E. Day. I am a servant out of place, but at that time I was very ill, and she did not tell me her errand till I came into Newgate-Street, which was about seven o'clock. I had got some oysters. She desired me to go to Newgate and enquire for Mr. Graham. [ See his trial, No 252, in last sessions paper.] I went first, as she desired, to her sister in Primrose-Street, named Hays, who gave me a groat, a basket, and a handkerchief; and another of her sisters, named Brown, came to me and brought this bonnet. I bought a groatsworth of oysters in Chiswel-Street. Mrs. Scott put this cardinal on me in Newgate Street. I went and enquired for Mr. Graham, saying, I had some oysters for him. When I came to him I told him they came from Mrs. Hays, in Primrose Street.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was Graham?</p>
               <p>E. Day. He was in a room in Newgate. He desired me to stay the value of five or ten minutes, till Mrs. Scott came. I delivered the oysters to him. While I was there, there was a noise about Mr. Scott making his escape. Mr. Graham went out of the room two or three times, during the little time I was there. I saw Mrs. Scott go into Newgate, but did not take any notice of her, nor she of me. I know no farther. I never saw Mr. Scott.</p>
               <p>Q. Had she any thing with her?</p>
               <p>E. Day. I did not see that she had. I was laid hold on in the press-yard, and have been detained ever since.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-39-person493">
                  Thomas 
                  Eaton 
               <interp inst="t17570914-39-person493" type="surname" value="Eaton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-person493" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-person493" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Akerman. I went up stairs and missed Mr. Scott out of the cell where he lay, about five o'clock last Sunday evening. I was a little affrighted, and thought he had made his escape. I went about the gaol and look'd for him. I went into Mr. Graham's room. I saw this woman there, sitting at a table with some oysters by her. I took her bonnet off, and look'd at her, and found it was not Scott. Then I went and look'd in the yard, and could not see him. I went up to the woman again, and pull'd her about; and after I found she was not he, I went down to the gate, where was a girl that draws beer, who said, Tom, here has been a gentlewoman<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175709140049"></xptr> ringing at the bell to get out this half hour. I said what gentlewoman; she said this, pointing to Scott in women's cloaths; he held down his head, I took hold of his honest and held it up, and laid hold of a cardinal that he had on, and thought I saw a stock buckle on the side of his neck; then I had a great suspicion it was Scott. I pull'd him about, but he never spoke, nor said a word. I took him by the arm and threw him against the wall. Then directly he struck me over the eye with his fist, and the lamp was blown out at the gate; then I laid hold of him, and we had a tustle about a minute in the dark before any body came. When the light came I had hold of him, but he got away from me. I either knock'd or threw him down, I think I knock'd him down and fell over him; he got up and ran to his own apartment, and drop'd the apparel he had on in three or four different places. I went directly up into the place where he lay, where he stood in his own cloaths, with a book in his hand. The cloaths must be but slightly put on over his own cloaths, for he drop'd them as he ran.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was it after the tustle you had, that you saw him with the book in his hand?</p>
               <p>Eaton. It was out about half a quarter of a minute, it was but up fifteen stairs. I took up all the things he had drop'd, and we went and chain'd him down to the floor. He was cloathed just as the woman was that came with the oysters to Graham.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see his face, when at the gate?</p>
               <p>Eaton. I did. His hair was tied behind, and a curl on each ear. I told him he was Scott, but he said not a word. ( The cloaths produced.)</p>
               <p>Q. to E. Day. How was you dress'd?</p>
               <p>E. Day. I had a red cloak, a black cardinal, a black bonnet, and a black quilted petticoat. (They were produc'd and compar'd with what Scott had on, and agreed: he having a red roqueleau instead of a red cloak under his cardinal, which was turn'd in, and stitch'd up to as to be just the length of the oyster woman's cloak.) I saw Mrs. Scott in the gaol about an hour or three quarters of an hour before; she gave two prisoners in the Press yard a glass of red wine each, but she was gone at the time he was ringing the bell at the gate.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any body bring these things into the gaol?</p>
               <p>Eaton. No, I did not. The two glasses that the two men drank had a great effect on them, one of them was very bad for half an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you let in 
               <persName id="t17570914-39-person494">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Day 
               <interp inst="t17570914-39-person494" type="surname" value="Day"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-person494" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-person494" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Eaton. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17570914-39-person495">
                  Jane 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17570914-39-person495" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-person495" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-person495" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Look on this roqueleau?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-39-person496">
                  Jane 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17570914-39-person496" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-person496" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-person496" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This is the same I lent to Mrs. Scott on the Saturday.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-39-person497">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Streeton 
               <interp inst="t17570914-39-person497" type="surname" value="Streeton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-person497" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-person497" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Akerman. I was going to lock up the debtors, and heard it rumour'd that Scott who was committed for robbing the mail, had like to have got out.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Streeton. Last Sunday. Mrs. Day was in the lodge, detected. I went to get a constable in Ivy-lane, in order to carry her before a magistrate. I got Mr. Venables, and coming back there were three women standing together by Gray-Priars Gate in Newgate-street, about forty yards distance from the gaol, and within sight of the door that comes out from the Press-yard. I left the constable and went over the way to see who they were. I saw Mrs. Scott among them. I clasp'd them all three to me, and call'd Mr. Venables. He came, and we took them all three to Newgate. Then there came an order by Mr. Newman from Mr. Fielding to bring them all before him. I went up with the four women, two were sent to the Round-house, that was Mrs. Scott and one of her sisters, Day came back with us to Newgate, and the other was discharged.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I don't know any thing of it, I never brought in any thing but the cloak, that I don't deny; my husband desir'd me to borrow that cloak, but did not tell me for what; I ask'd him for what, he said go and do as I bid you; when I came back I gave it him, he said it was to keep him warm.</p>
               <p>Q. to White. What did she say when she came for this roqueleau?</p>
               <p>J. White. She came and ask'd me for a woman's cloak. I said I knew no body in the world where I could get one. She was going out of the passage and said there is one hangs, I said it is my master's; she said, I'll bring it back again to night as I am a living woman.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say it was for ?</p>
               <p>J. White. She said it was to disguise her husband.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. She had often been with Mr. Scott, they have been together many times, and they would not let me come to them in the cell. When I have gone to go up, he has offer'd me down again; he desir'd I would ask him no questions. He bid me go to Jenny, and ask her for what she had promised him.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17570914-39-person498">
                  Jane 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17570914-39-person498" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-person498" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-person498" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . How often have you been with Scott in Newgate ?</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175709140050"></xptr>J. White. I have been with him twice in the cell. He had sent me a letter, and desir'd to see me, if I could reconcile myself to see him there. When I came it was to go to Mrs. Newman and desire her to contribute to him in his distress. Mrs. Scott was in the room with him when I went both times.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. When they seized me it wanted a quarter of ten, my sisters were with me, we were waiting for 
               <persName id="t17570914-39-person499">
                  Betty 
                  Day 
               <interp inst="t17570914-39-person499" type="surname" value="Day"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-person499" type="given" value="Betty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-person499" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had sent her to Mr. Graham with some oysters.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570914-39-verdict260" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570914-39-verdict260" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
