<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570914-31">
               <interp inst="t17570914-31" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-31" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-31" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570914"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570914-31" type="date" value="17570914"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570914-31-off212-c332" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-31-defend403 t17570914-31-off212 t17570914-31-verdict216"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570914-31-off212-c333" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-31-defend405 t17570914-31-off212 t17570914-31-verdict216"></join>
         
               <p>338, 339. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17570914-31-defend403" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Gibbs 
                  <interp inst="t17570914-31-defend403" type="surname" value="Gibbs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-31-defend403" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-31-defend403" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17570914-31-defend405" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Pearcy 
                  <interp inst="t17570914-31-defend405" type="surname" value="Pearcy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-31-defend405" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-31-defend405" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17570914-31-deflabel211" type="occupation">spinsters</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-31-defend403 t17570914-31-deflabel211"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-31-defend405 t17570914-31-deflabel211"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17570914-31-off212" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570914-31-off212" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-31-off212" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing three pieces of foreign gold coin, call'd 36 s. pieces, three guineas, one half guinea, and 7 s. in money number'd, the property of 
                     <persName id="t17570914-31-victim406" type="victimName">
                        John 
                        Lowe 
                     <interp inst="t17570914-31-victim406" type="surname" value="Lowe"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570914-31-victim406" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17570914-31-victim406" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-31-off212 t17570914-31-victim406"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , privately and secretly from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17570914-31-cd213" type="crimeDate">August 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-31-off212 t17570914-31-cd213"></join>. ++></p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-31-person407">
                  John 
                  Lowe 
               <interp inst="t17570914-31-person407" type="surname" value="Lowe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-31-person407" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-31-person407" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Axe Inn, Aldermanbury.</p>
               <p>Q. In what capacity?</p>
               <p>Lowe. I am an <rs id="t17570914-31-viclabel214" type="occupation">hostler</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-31-victim406 t17570914-31-viclabel214"></join>. I happen'd to be with 
               <persName id="t17570914-31-person408">
                  Mary 
                  Pearcy 
               <interp inst="t17570914-31-person408" type="surname" value="Pearcy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-31-person408" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-31-person408" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             on the 21st of August, at night, who ask'd me to go with her to her lodgings, and she took me to a place where I never was at before, call'd <placeName id="t17570914-31-crimeloc215">Blackboy Alley</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17570914-31-crimeloc215" type="placeName" value="Blackboy Alley"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17570914-31-crimeloc215" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570914-31-off212 t17570914-31-crimeloc215"></join>; there we went to bed together.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in liquor?</p>
               <p>Lowe. Not a great deal in liquor; I had had a pint of beer.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the night did you get there?</p>
               <p>Lowe. It was eleven o'clock when we went into the house. I was awaked at two o'clock by a girl's coming up to ask me whether I had been asleep. I said, yes. She said, what have you done with your bedfellow? I looked and said, here is the nest, but the bird is flown. She said, then, I believe, your money is gone. I made the door fast when we went into the room, so that nobody could get in. I found she had left her stays upon the bed, and my breeches were pull'd from under my head, and part of them hung down on the bedside. When I went to bed I had my money in my pocket; three thirty-six shilling pieces, three guineas, one half guinea, and seven shillings in silver, which I found was all gone. I went down stairs, and there was another young man with another girl in a room there. I call'd him by his name, and said, come get up, for all my money is gone; I have lost more than I ever had in the world, for some of it is not mine. He felt in his pockets, and said his was safe. The people of the house would have turned me out, saying I had no business there. I staid till it was light, between four and five in the morning. Then I went home and told my fellow<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175709140036"></xptr> servants of the misfortune I had had. I got a man to attend in the stable, and took my fellow servants to the house with me, when the people and girls that were there, were for putting us out of the house again; then we inquired where the constable lived. A man opening his shop windows said, what do you want a constable for? I fancy I know your misfortune, you have had your pocket pick'd by two girls; I fancy they are just gone down the street drunk, with two or three thirty-six shilling pieces and some silver, I saw it in one of their hands. We went and inquired about, and found they had been buying some stockings in Field-Lane. I went to the shop, and was there told they had bought two pair of stockings, and that the girls were gone down towards the Fleet-Market but two or three minutes before. We went down the market, some on each side and some in the middle, but we could not find them. Then I went to the stocking shop to know what money they had changed, where the boy said it was half a guinea. I asked him to describe it, which he did, and I knew it to be mine. We went about and found them buying shoes and pattens at a shoemaker's shop on Snow-Hill. We took them, sent for a constable, and carried them before the sitting alderman. In searching them some money was found upon Gibbs, a thirty-six shilling piece, and some silver.</p>
               <p>Q. Which of them went to bed with you?</p>
               <p>Lowe. Pearcy did.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you charge the other with?</p>
               <p>Lowe. All I know against her is, she was with Pearcy when I took her up.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know Pearcy before?</p>
               <p>Lowe. I never saw her before that night.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-31-person409">
                  John 
                  Burton 
               <interp inst="t17570914-31-person409" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-31-person409" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-31-person409" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a hosier. These two prisoners at the bar came to our shop to buy some stockings, on the 22d of August. I chang'd a half guinea for them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570914-31-person410">
                  John 
                  Williamson 
               <interp inst="t17570914-31-person410" type="surname" value="Williamson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-31-person410" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-31-person410" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a corn chandler. I changed half a guinea for John Burton on the 22d of 
               <persName id="t17570914-31-person411">
                  August 
                  After 
               <interp inst="t17570914-31-person411" type="surname" value="After"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-31-person411" type="given" value="August"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-31-person411" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the two girls were secured, the prosecutor came to the hosier's where 
               <persName id="t17570914-31-person412">
                  John 
                  Burton 
               <interp inst="t17570914-31-person412" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-31-person412" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-31-person412" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is servant, and asked to see the money that they changed. I having changed the half guinea for Burton, the prosecutor said he could tell it from a hundred. I desired him to describe it, he said it was a crooked one, and plain on one side. I took out a half guinea, he said that is not it. Then I took out some money with a half guinea amongst it, he said that is it, I can swear that was mine before you turn it; it lay with the head upwards in my hand. He said the scepter side was quite plain, which it was. It is a very remarkable one, (produced in court.)</p>
               <p>Lowe. This half guinea was amongst the other money in my pocket when I went to bed that night. I took it on a Monday in the afternoon of Mr. Scot, a Yorkshire gentleman.</p>
               <p>Q. What are the particulars of it?</p>
               <p>Lowe. It is a king Charles's head, plain on one side, and not a letter to be seen on the other. The bench and jury look upon it. I disputed taking it, and was for returning it, but as my mistress knew the gentleman, I thought there would be no dispute.</p>
               <p>Q. to Burton. Look at this half guinea, is this the half guinea you received of the prisoners to change?</p>
               <p>Burton. This is the same, I received it of Gibbs, and she gave the change to Pearcy. I was very scrupulous of taking it.</p>
               <p>Pearcy's Defence.</p>
               <p>I met this man, he ask'd me to drink; I would not, and he followed me quite home. He carried me into this house, and gave a shilling for a bed, and gave me another. He bid me undress myself, I did so, and went into bed; he sent a woman for a pot of beer, and change for a shilling. I drank a little of the beer, and he went to sleep. About twelve o'clock came in a young woman, and said, here is the watch and constable coming. I got up and dress'd me, but in the fright I left my stays on the bed, and went down stairs. I never saw a farthing of the money, only that shilling he gave me.</p>
               <p>Gibbs's Defence.</p>
               <p>My father sent me up a 36 s. piece, and a golden guinea. I went up the market, and met with 
               <persName id="t17570914-31-person413">
                  Mary 
                  Pearcy 
               <interp inst="t17570914-31-person413" type="surname" value="Pearcy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-31-person413" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570914-31-person413" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I ask'd her to go with me to buy some stockings, and after that a pair of shoes.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17570914-31-verdict216" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570914-31-verdict216" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
