<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17571026-16">
               <interp inst="t17571026-16" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17571026-16" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17571026-16" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17571026"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17571026-16" type="date" value="17571026"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17571026-16-off82-c124" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571026-16-defend149 t17571026-16-off82 t17571026-16-verdict85"></join>
         
               <p>391. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17571026-16-defend149" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Mason 
                  <interp inst="t17571026-16-defend149" type="surname" value="Mason"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-defend149" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-defend149" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , late of the precinct of <placeName id="t17571026-16-defloc80">the Savoy</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17571026-16-defloc80" type="placeName" value="the Savoy"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17571026-16-defloc80" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571026-16-defend149 t17571026-16-defloc80"></join>, in the county of Middlesex, <rs id="t17571026-16-deflabel81" type="occupation">clerk</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571026-16-defend149 t17571026-16-deflabel81"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17571026-16-off82" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-off82" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-off82" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               unlawfully, wilfully, knowingly and feloniously solemnizing matrimony between 
                     
                        <persName id="t17571026-16-victim151" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Gibson 
                        <interp inst="t17571026-16-victim151" type="surname" value="Gibson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17571026-16-victim151" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17571026-16-victim151" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   and 
                     
                        <persName id="t17571026-16-victim153" type="victimName">
                           Elizabeth 
                           Snape 
                        <interp inst="t17571026-16-victim153" type="surname" value="Snape"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17571026-16-victim153" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17571026-16-victim153" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , then a <rs id="t17571026-16-viclabel83" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571026-16-victim153 t17571026-16-viclabel83"></join>, without publishing of banns, or any licence first had or obtained of a person having authority to grant the same, in contempt of our lord the king, and against the statute in that case made and provided
            </rs>, <rs id="t17571026-16-cd84" type="crimeDate">Sept. 4, 1754</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571026-16-off82 t17571026-16-cd84"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571026-16-person154">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Gibson 
               <interp inst="t17571026-16-person154" type="surname" value="Gibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-person154" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-person154" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a widow.</p>
               <p>Q. What was your husband's name?</p>
               <p>E. Gibson. 
               <persName id="t17571026-16-person155">
                  John 
                  Gibson 
               <interp inst="t17571026-16-person155" type="surname" value="Gibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-person155" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-person155" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. What was your name before you was married to him?</p>
               <p>E. Gibson. My name was 
               <persName id="t17571026-16-person156">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Snape 
               <interp inst="t17571026-16-person156" type="surname" value="Snape"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-person156" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-person156" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I was a widow then.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you married?</p>
               <p>E. Gibson. I was married at the Savoy chappel.</p>
               <p>Q. When was you married?</p>
               <p>E. Gibson. I don't know the day of the month, but I have a certificate of the marriage.</p>
               <p>Q. Where had you that?</p>
               <p>E. Gibson. It is sign'd by Mr. 
               <persName id="t17571026-16-person157">
                  John 
                  Wilkinson 
               <interp inst="t17571026-16-person157" type="surname" value="Wilkinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-person157" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-person157" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. How long is it ago since you was married?</p>
               <p>E. Gibson. It is about two years ago; to the best of my remembrance it was on Bartholomew day, in 1755.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was present?</p>
               <p>E. Gibson. There was but one gentlewoman with me, whose name was Ellis, the parson and clerk, and Mr. Gibson; there were two other people in the church, who, I believe, belong'd to the Savoy.</p>
               <p>Q. Who performed the ceremony?</p>
               <p>E. Gibson. The prisoner does not appear to be the gentleman; he that married me had a smoother face, without any pockfrets, but I did not take particular notice of him at that time.</p>
               <p>Court. If you do know him, and say you are not sure, you act contrary to your oath.</p>
               <p>E. Gibson. I know it, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon the oath you have taken, do you believe him to be the man?</p>
               <p>E. Gibson. I don't believe him to be the man; he may, but I have no knowledge of his face.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is the certificate ?</p>
               <p>E. Gibson. I gave it to Mr. Pridle yesterday.</p>
               <p>Council for the prisoner. I believe Mr. Pridle will not appear.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any reason for so believing?</p>
               <p>Council for the prisoner. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. to the clerk of the arraigns. Is Pridle's name on the back of the bill of indictment?</p>
               <p>Clerk of the arraigns. It is.</p>
               <p>[The evidence is ordered out of court, and to be kept alone.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571026-16-person158">
                  Richard 
                  Philips 
               <interp inst="t17571026-16-person158" type="surname" value="Philips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-person158" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-person158" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was clerk of the Savoy chapel about six years, till September last was a twelve-month.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember any marriages solemnized after the late act of parliament?</p>
               <p>Philips. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Grierson officiate there?</p>
               <p>Philips. He did.</p>
               <p>Q. Who solemnized marriages after he was under a prosecution?</p>
               <p>Philips. Mr. Mason, and several others.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was Mr. Wilkinson then?</p>
               <p>Philips. He kept out of the way.</p>
               <p>Q. What number might the prisoner have married there?</p>
               <p>Philips. I can't tell; he married a great number by publication of banns, and some by licence from the Commons.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath, did he marry any without publication of banns, or licence from the Commons?</p>
               <p>Philips. He married by Mr. Wilkinson's licences.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he in the year 1755?</p>
               <p>Philips. He did; sometimes he, and sometimes one Bailey, and another, named Brooks.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember the marriage between 
               <persName id="t17571026-16-person159">
                  John 
                  Gibson 
               <interp inst="t17571026-16-person159" type="surname" value="Gibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-person159" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-person159" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17571026-16-person160">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Snape 
               <interp inst="t17571026-16-person160" type="surname" value="Snape"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-person160" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-person160" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ?</p>
               <p>Philips. I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in court when she was examined ?</p>
               <p>Philips. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you recollect her?</p>
               <p>Philips. I don't remember I ever saw her in my life before.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did the prisoner officiate there?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175710260018"></xptr>Philips. I can't tell exactly.</p>
               <p>Q. Say as near as you can recollect.</p>
               <p>Philips. About half a year; he married none after the trial of Grierson.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he marry there when Grierson was under prosecution?</p>
               <p>Philips. He did.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath, can you or can you not recollect Mrs. Gibson's being married ?</p>
               <p>Philips. I cannot recollect her at all.</p>
               <p>Q. If you had the certificate here, should you know Mr. Wilkinson's hand writing?</p>
               <p>Philips. Yes, I should.</p>
               <p>Q. Is your hand to the certificates, as a witness?</p>
               <p>Philips. Some I fill'd up, and some Mr. Wilkinson himself did, I very seldom sign'd them; some times I did, when desired.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is the attorney that attends this prosecution?</p>
               <p>Council for the prisoner. Mr. Pridle is the attorney.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Within these twelve months it has been six or seven hundred pounds detriment to me: there is a prosecution before your lordship in the King's-bench; he has sent somebody to me almost every day, and promised not to appear against me at the Old-Bailey, if I would forgive him. He likewise would leave it to any two of my acquaintance, and give me 50 l. to make me amends for the injuries I receiv'd from him. I sent this answer, '' That whatever was the consequence of it to me, I had no malice against the man, but owed such justice to society, that if it cost me even my life I would bring him to justice.'' It has cost me near 20 l. to remove myself here. I am informed he has sent one Mrs. Pritchard, otherwise Gordon, otherwise Pridle (she went under three denominations) to Mrs. Gibson, to get her to swear to me as the person that performed the ceremony; but upon her asking her, she said she could not swear that I was the man that married her; then she said to her, write him a letter, and say you can swear to him. The injuries I have received will come before your lordship in your lordship's court the 2d day of next term. It was to have come on before, but he has been always out of the way, and we never could come at him to serve him with the order.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does Pridle live?</p>
               <p>C. for prisoner. He is an attorney in the Temple.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571026-16-person161">
                  Gertrude 
                  Pritchard 
               <interp inst="t17571026-16-person161" type="surname" value="Pritchard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-person161" type="given" value="Gertrude"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-person161" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner two or three years.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know 
               <persName id="t17571026-16-person162">
                  John 
                  Gibson 
               <interp inst="t17571026-16-person162" type="surname" value="Gibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-person162" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-person162" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             that is dead ?</p>
               <p>G. Pritchard. I was acquainted with him and 
               <persName id="t17571026-16-person163">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Snape 
               <interp inst="t17571026-16-person163" type="surname" value="Snape"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-person163" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-person163" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             twenty years.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they married?</p>
               <p>G. Pritchard. They were Mr. Mason used frequently to come to our house, and Mrs. Snape, then a widow, used to come too. I apprehended she and Mr. Gibson were going to be married.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever any conversation with Mr. Mason about the marriage after it was over?</p>
               <p>G. Pritchard. She came and told me she had been married at the Savoy. I used to see Mr. Mason two or three times a week: when he came to my house two or three days after the marriage, I said, So Doctor, you have tacked two old acquaintances of mine together, mentioning them; he said, why don't you come with Mr. Pridle that I may do you the same office? I ask'd Mr. Mason what made him venture to marry, as there were two gentlemen liable to be prosecuted; he said, he had married a great many hundreds of couples, and that Mr. Wilkinson's licences were as good as the archbishop of Canterbury's.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he did marry them?</p>
               <p>G. Pritchard. Yes, he remembered he did marry them, and that by Mr. Wilkinson's licence.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>G. Pritchard. This was at the latter end of the summer, about two years ago last month.</p>
               <p>Q. What month?</p>
               <p>G. Pritchard. About August or September.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>G. Pritchard. I live in Buckingham-Court, Charing-Cross.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you once live with Mr. Pridle?</p>
               <p>G. Pritchard. I did. I tell the truth.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see him last?</p>
               <p>G. Pritchard. I saw him to-day.</p>
               <p>Q. When was you at his chambers?</p>
               <p>G. Pritchard. I called there last night.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never go by the name of Gordon?</p>
               <p>G. Pritchard. I have. I do now.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your real name?</p>
               <p>G. Pritchard. My real name is Pritchard. My father was rector of Spitalfields.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you not once tried in this court?</p>
               <p>G. Pritchard. I was with Mr. Pridle, and the court was very well satisfied that we were used very ill.</p>
               <p>Q. By what name was you indicted?</p>
               <p>G. Pritchard. The prosecutor put in all the names.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he not put in Gertrude wife of 
               <persName id="t17571026-16-person164">
                  William 
                  Pridle 
               <interp inst="t17571026-16-person164" type="surname" value="Pridle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-person164" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-person164" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175710260019"></xptr>G. Pritchard. I always answer'd to that name then.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see Mrs. Gibson last?</p>
               <p>G. Pritchard. I saw her last night.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to see her?</p>
               <p>G. Pritchard. She desired me to call upon her. I have known her from a child.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you no conversation about what was to be done to-day?</p>
               <p>G. Pritchard. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you talk to her about writing a letter?</p>
               <p>G. Pritchard. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never talk to her about this affair?</p>
               <p>G. Pritchard. Yes, she told me she was very sorry her name was brought in question about it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say she knew Mr. Mason ?</p>
               <p>G. Pritchard. She said she did not recollect him.</p>
               <p>Q. from the prisoner. The very day or two before you went in order to obtain this indictment against me, did not you send me a letter that you desired me to come; did I not come, and was not the conversation in regard to the injustice you know I have received from Mr. Pridle; and did not you tell me whenever I should call upon you to give your affidavit, you would make oath of the truth of what you then told me?</p>
               <p>G. Pritchard. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. from the prisoner. Did I not ask you, in order that you might do me that justice that you proposed you would, against Pridle and Hodle, in regard to the injustice I have received from them?</p>
               <p>G. Pritchard. No, Sir, I was out; when I came home I was told there had been two or three constables to take me up, and a gentleman in the appearance of a clergyman was with them. I sent to Mr. Mason to know what he meant by it; he came, and told me he had a warrant against me for taking from him a steel screw (which was my own) to hang a watch on. I said, Mr. Mason you use me vastly ill, but I'll absolutely appear against your; he put me in defiance. Mr. Pridle and he lived together then.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. This cannot be unfolded till the answer is made, whether or no it was not your own motion to me that Pridle and I might make up all matters, if not you knew two persons that could swear to the identity of my person in marrying unlawfully.</p>
               <p>G. Pritchard. That was in regard to myself, but not Mr. Pridle.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this conversation ?</p>
               <p>G. Pritchard. It was a few days before Mr. Mason was indicted. I told him I should be very sorry to appear against him, but he knew he had done it, and that I should appear and give all the evidence I knew.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mrs. Gibson tell you that Mr. Mason had married her ?</p>

               <p>G. Pritchard. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember the prisoner's officiating to marry there?</p>
               <p>G. Pritchard. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you ever in the chapel to see him?</p>
               <p>G. Pritchard. No; I only heard him acknowledge he had done so. He said his profits were about four guineas a week.</p>
               <p>[She is sent out, and Mrs. Gibson call'd in]</p>
               <p>Q. to E. Gibson. Was you acquainted with 
               <persName id="t17571026-16-person165">
                  Gertrude 
                  Pritchard 
               <interp inst="t17571026-16-person165" type="surname" value="Pritchard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-person165" type="given" value="Gertrude"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-person165" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>E. Gibson. I was; I employed this Pridle whom she lived with.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell her anything of your marriage?</p>
               <p>E. Gibson. I don't remember I ever did.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you did not?</p>
               <p>E. Gibson. I am not positive; he and she have been with me several times about this affair, and would have had me go with them in a coach to see the prisoner, but I did not go.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever meet with a parson at her house before your marriage?</p>
               <p>E. Gibson. No; neither before nor after my marriage. I remember Mrs. Pritchard said the certificate was not Mr. Mason's hand-writing; Pridle said, he knew that very well.</p>
               <p>The prisoner's defence consisted of two parts; one, on supposition the facts were proved, regarding the matter of law; and the other, objections to the evidence upon which the charge is supported. He admitted he did officiate and celebrate marriages at the Savoy chapel without publication of banns or licence properly obtained; but that he did not do it knowingly and wilfully, for Mr. Wilkinson had shew'd him a letter from the bishop of London, and told him an instance of his marrying a certain barrister at law. and that he had some opinions that it was lawful for him to celebrate matrimony under the authority of Mr. Wilkinson's licences; that he never married any minor, but always tendered to them an oath, and if they did swear they were under age he refused to marry them. but if they did swear they were of age, he did marry them without either publication of banns or licence.</p>
               <p>He called no body to his character, but desired to ask Mr. Philips some questions.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Did I not, on my first engaging at the Savoy, tell you I never would do any one act inconsistent with my conscience ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175710260020"></xptr>Philips. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Did I not, as often as any persons presented themselves who appear'd to be minors, deny them?</p>
               <p>Philips. Always.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Altho' they said they were not minors, before I proceeded to the marriage, did I not first order a Bible to be sent for, and make them swear that they had no parents, that they were not under the court of chancery, and that they were of age?</p>
               <p>Philips. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he marry them if they said they were of age?</p>
               <p>Philips, Yes.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. If they swore it I did.</p>
               <p>Court. Then you acted contrary to law.</p>
               <p>Q. When was Wilkinson indicted ?</p>
               <p>Philips. I can't tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Who officiated in August, 1755?</p>
               <p>Philips. Mr. Mason and Mr. Brooks.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. We did. I attended the trial of Mr. Grierson, in order to prove the Bishop of London's hand-writing. Ask Philips on his oath whether I married after that.</p>
               <p>Philips. Not once.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17571026-16-verdict85" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-verdict85" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>My Lord mayor issued his warrant during the trial, to apprehend and bring 
               <persName id="t17571026-16-person166">
                  William 
                  Pridle 
               <interp inst="t17571026-16-person166" type="surname" value="Pridle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-person166" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571026-16-person166" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             before his Lordship, who was brought in by a marshal's man before the verdict was given; when Pridle's recognizance was order'd to be estreated, and Mr. Mason was bound in a recognizance of one hundred pounds to appear and give evidence against him at the next sessions.</p>
            </div1>
