<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510703-18">
               <interp inst="t17510703-18" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510703-18" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510703-18" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510703"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510703-18" type="date" value="17510703"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510703-18-off85-c163" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-18-defend201 t17510703-18-off85 t17510703-18-verdict89"></join>
         
               <p>426. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17510703-18-defend201" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Sowle 
                  <interp inst="t17510703-18-defend201" type="surname" value="Sowle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-18-defend201" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-18-defend201" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for that <rs id="t17510703-18-off85" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510703-18-off85" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-18-off85" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               he, not having the fear of God before his eyes, but being moved by the instigation of the devil, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17510703-18-victim203" type="victimName">
                           George 
                           Paschal 
                        <interp inst="t17510703-18-victim203" type="surname" value="Paschal"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510703-18-victim203" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510703-18-victim203" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-18-off85 t17510703-18-victim203"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, and he, the said Richard, with a drawn sword, which he held in his right hand, did strike and stab, giving him on the right side of his belly one mortal wound length half an inch, depth six inches, on the <rs id="t17510703-18-cd86" type="crimeDate">6th of May</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-18-off85 t17510703-18-cd86"></join>, he languished till the 8th, and then died : That he the said George did kill or murder
            </rs>. He likewise stood charged upon the coroner's inquest with manslaughter.*</p>
               <p>John Malcomb. On the 6th of May I saw <rs id="t17510703-18-viclabel87" type="occupation">Capt.</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-18-victim203 t17510703-18-viclabel87"></join> Sowle and the deceased together in <placeName id="t17510703-18-crimeloc88">May-fair</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17510703-18-crimeloc88" type="placeName" value="May-fair"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510703-18-crimeloc88" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510703-18-off85 t17510703-18-crimeloc88"></join>, betwixt the Red-cross and Mr. Norman's, they had both their swords drawn about four or five yards from each other. I went up to them as fast as I could, saying, consider, gentlemen, what you are go ing about is a thing of a very dangerous consequence, and you are both; I suppose, in liquor, and when you are sober you will be sorry for it. Capt. Sowle said he'd take my advice, and so put up his sword. Then the deceased whispered to him, but what they said to each other I cannot tell. Capt. Sowle said to him, as you persist upon it, I'll meet you in Hide-park at four o'clock. The other said, there is no time like the time present, and insisted upon satisfaction then, Capt. Sowle bid him a good morrow, and walk'd away from him, but the other followed him with his sword drawn in his hand, saying, damn your soul, several times, you are a coward like the Core you belong to. They walk'd about sixty or seventy yards from me, and he seem'd to give aggravating language. Then Capt. Sowle drew his sword, and they went to it; I ran up to them as fast as I could, and call'd to them for God Almighty's sake to give over. I saw the captain receive a wound in his left arm.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did not you endeavour to prevent this before?</p>
               <p>Malcomb. I had not my sword or stick with me, the evidence is a soldier. I went in between them, and Capt. Sowle withdrew, I catch'd at their swords, and twisted Paschal's out of his hand, and then going to Capt. Sowle, he let me have his without any resistance. Paschal ask'd me for his sword again, and said, are you going to rob me? I said, no, I had a spirit above that, and that I had a great mind to break both the swords, for I could stand by so doing. He ask'd me for it a second time, and I told him, I took him to be a gentleman of honour, and if he would promise to use it no more at that time I would give it him, which he did, and I put it into his scabbard myself, saying, if he had been kill'd it was his own seeking, because he insisted to fight the gentleman. He said, let the consequence be what it will, I heartily forgive the gentleman. There were then four or five people about them. Capt Sowle ask'd me to help do up his arm, and if I had a room thereabouts.  I carried him to my room, and call'd up my wife, who wash'd him, and tied up his arm. Then he refused me to go and enquire for the deceased, when I did, but he was gone. At that time I did not think he was hurt at all, seeing no blood.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. What size man was Paschal?</p>
               <p>Malcomb. He was a tall, thin gentleman, taller than the prisoner, and seemed a stronger man.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you perceive any other wound the prisoner had, besides that on his arm?</p>
               <p>Malcomb. I did not, sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him lying against the rails of a house ?</p>
               <p>Malcomb. No, I did not, sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he bleed very much?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175107030013"></xptr>Malcomb. He did, sir, as I came in betwixt them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you see a small wound in his neck when your wife dress'd him?</p>
               <p>Malcomb. No, sir, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you think would be the event of it, when you saw the deceased follow the captain with a drawn sword?</p>
               <p>Malcomb. I was really afraid he would run him thro' then.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the deceased after this?</p>
               <p>Malcomb. I did not till he was dead.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see the prisoner after this time?</p>
               <p>Malcomb. Not till to day.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they appear to be sober at that time?</p>
               <p>Malcomb. No, they appeared both to be in liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Paschal put up his sword when the captain did.</p>
               <p>Malcomb. No, sir, he kept his in his hand, and whisper'd to the captain.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-18-person204">
                  John 
                  Joyant 
               <interp inst="t17510703-18-person204" type="surname" value="Joyant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-18-person204" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-18-person204" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Paschal lodg'd at my house. He came home that morning before they fought, I believe it was between four and five in the morning, and Captain 
               <persName id="t17510703-18-person205">
                  Sowle
               <interp inst="t17510703-18-person205" type="given" value="Sowle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-18-person205" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             with him. They went into a parlour in the back part of the house, and stay'd there some little time. While they were there, I went up stairs to put on my coat. I just ask'd Mr. Paschal whether he would have his slippers, and thinking he was going to bed, I did not ask him any farther questions, nor did he say any thing to me. When I came down they were both ready to go out. I heard no words of difference pass, but out they went together. I knew nothing farther of it till Mr. Paschal came back, about half an hour after eight. When he came in I was called down into the fore parlour, where I found him sitting in a chair: he pull'd up the flap of his waistcoat, and said he had a little scratch ; it was in the lower part of the right side of his belly. He said he was in good spirits, and behaved the gentleman. He thought he was not at all hurt, and looked upon it as a thing of no consequence. His shirt was no more bloody than what it might have been by the scratch of a pin, (tho' it bled inwardly we found afterwards.) I prevailed upon him to go up to bed, and desired he would permit me to send for a surgeon, but he would not; notwithstanding that I sent for one Mr. Pinkstone, but when he came, the deceased would not permit him to do any thing to the wound, so he went away again. About one or two o'clock he began to be faint, when he admitted him to be sent for again, but then I was not at home, so can say nothing to it. This was on Monday morning, and he died on the Wednesday following ; There were several other gentlemen that attended him during that time.</p>
               <p>Cross Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the deceased a man fond of drinking to excess?</p>
               <p>Joyant. No, sir, he was not.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he for temper when in his liquor ?</p>
               <p>Joyant. In liquor he was rather rash than otherwise.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you very intimate with him?</p>
               <p>Joyant. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Then you have seen him in liquor, have not you?</p>
               <p>Joyant. I have seen him a little in liquor, but never knew him to have any quarrel since I have known him, which was several years.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any talk with him about this unfortunate affair afterwards?</p>
               <p>Joyant. He several times said he was extremely well pleased to hear that the gentleman was out of any danger; intimating, that he was very happy since he had not kill'd Captain 
               <persName id="t17510703-18-person206">
                  Sowle
               <interp inst="t17510703-18-person206" type="given" value="Sowle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-18-person206" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Did he ever relate any particular circumstance upon which it arose?</p>
               <p>Joyant, No, sir, he never did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-18-person207">
                  Thomas 
                  Roper 
               <interp inst="t17510703-18-person207" type="surname" value="Roper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-18-person207" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-18-person207" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am waiter at St. Alban's tavern, in St. Alban's-street. Mr. Paschal was in a club there on Sunday night, the 5th of May. About 12 o'clock, or a little before, Capt. Sowle came to the same company.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he sober?</p>
               <p>Roper. He was fuddled. The company staid till near four o'clock in the morning, and left Paschal and the captain by themselves. They staid near an hour, and were hiding their money under hand. The door stood a-jar, and I was at it, but hearing them get up to go away I went in, and heard Mr. Paschal say to the captain, I'll go where you dare not go. They went down stairs together, and so out of doors. Capt. Sowle offered to have a chair which was at the door, but Paschal took him by the arm, and they went up the street together. I look'd after them, thinking there was something amiss. I observ'd Capt. Sowle had a sword, the other had not.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175107030014"></xptr>Cross Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they in liquor or sober when they went away?</p>
               <p>Joyant. They were both in liquor, sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen them in that company before?</p>
               <p>Joyant. I have seen Paschal there before in that company, but don't remember I ever saw Capt. Sowle in that company before, sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see them together before?</p>
               <p>Joyant. I don't remember I ever did.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think Capt. Sowle had went in the chair if the other had not prevented him?</p>
               <p>Joyant. I think he would, had not the other took hold of his arm.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Capt. Campbell?</p>
               <p>Joyant. Yes, sir, he was the last person that went out of the room, and left them together.</p>
               <p>Fleming Pinkstone. I attended the deceased on this unhappy occasion. I went to him on Monday about nine in the morning, the gentleman of the house shewed me his bed, and I opened the curtains and said, sir, how do you do? He gave me out his arm, and said, do I want to be let blood? Said I, if you have no complaint, I don't think this pulse will admit of the loss of blood, but, continued I, I hear you have other complaints, if you have, pray shew me. No, said he, if I don't want bleeding I am your humble servant, good morning to you. I went into the next room, and said, what shall I do in this case? The gentlewoman desired me to come again when a friend of his would be there. So I went away, and was sent for again between twelve and one. Then the deceased laid open the bed, and turning up his shirt, I saw a small puncture in the lower part of his belly, on the right side, upon which I took my probe, and found it passed into the cavity quite through. He then complained of a violent pain on the point of his left shoulder, and I found a great anxiety about him. I went into the next room and told the gentlewoman of the house I was afraid it was a thing of great consequence, and desired to have a consultation ; then I went and desired the deceased would name a person; upon which he ask'd me what I thought of Mr. Andrews. I answered I thought very well of him, and should be glad to have him there. Accordingly he was sent for, and came in about 15 or 20 minutes. While he was sent for I sat on the bed-side, and ask'd him how this came; but he seemed to decline that, and turning about said, I don't know who gave it me, but I am sure he is a gentleman. When Mr. Andrews came we consulted what was proper, and dress'd him in the usual manner. Mr. Andrews going out of town, and I finding him worse, called in Mr. Hawkins, but he died on Wednesday in the evening; after which I open'd him, and found the wound had passed through the cavity into the abdomen, and opened the left iliac vein, the consequence of which was a great extravass of blood. I am certain that wound was the occasion of his death.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the deceased say any thing else?</p>
               <p>Pinkstone. I don't recollect he said any thing else.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he lay the blame on any body?</p>
               <p>Pinkstone. If I understood him by his behaviour he seem'd to be extremely chagreen'd with himself, especially when I came first in the morning he seem'd very uneasy, and continued so thro' the whole, being very fullen.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>My lord, the deceased was almost a stranger to me, for I never had seen him but once before. It was by accident I went into that company. I have since heard Mr. Paschal was very unhappy in his liquor, and a very quarrelsome man. The treatment he gave me was very exasperating, following me with a drawn sword, which obliged me to draw in my own defence. I am very sorry for the event. I have a great number of gentlemen here to prove I am no quarrelsome man, or any thing of that sort. I received the first wound on my shoulder which threw me backwards, and I must have been on my back, had it not been for some rails; the second would have been in my body, had I not taken it into my arm; and the third was the unhappy one which I am exceeding sorry for.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510703-18-person208">
                  Alexander 
                  Campbel 
               <interp inst="t17510703-18-person208" type="surname" value="Campbel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-18-person208" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-18-person208" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner some years, and was a little acquainted with the deceased. I was in company with them on the 5th of May at night, at the St. Alban's tavern, St. Alban's-street. I had been in company with Mr. Paschal from eight at night till three in the morning, and the prisoner came in about twelve. I never heard they were together but once before. There was no enmity between them as I saw. I left them about half an hour past three, and was the last that went from them.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175107030015"></xptr>Q. Was the prisoner sober?</p>
               <p>Campbel. I look upon him to have been a good deal in liquor; I begged Mr. Paschal to go home; the next day I had a message from Mr. Paschal, which was, that he says he does not know whether this unhappy affair was with you, or with Captain 
               <persName id="t17510703-18-person209">
                  Sowle
               <interp inst="t17510703-18-person209" type="given" value="Sowle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-18-person209" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , or Mr. Love; I went to Mr. Paschal, he told me he remembered nothing of any quarrel he had with Mr. Sowle; upon which I told him of the provocation Mr. Sowle told me (for I had been there) he gave him; upon which they fought, that is, he insisted upon fighting him, and gave him a great deal of abusive language, which was what a gentleman or officer could not put up with; then he told me, in short I take all that you say for truth, for I think Mr. Sowle is one of the bestnatured men that ever I was in company with, and I dare say it is a thing of my own seeking.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he apt to be a little quarrelsome when in liquor?</p>
               <p>Campbel. I was with him once when he seemed to give a great deal of uneasiness to a company, yet I could not conceive by his speech he was in liquor; I never knew him but that time so quarrelsome.</p>
               <p>Q. What is Captain 
               <persName id="t17510703-18-person210">
                  Sowle
               <interp inst="t17510703-18-person210" type="given" value="Sowle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-18-person210" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's general character?</p>
               <p>Campbel. I have been very often with him, and I never heard or saw he was in the least quarrelsome either sober or in liquor; I have been in company with him when we have drank pretty freely; I went to the deceased a second time; the next day he told me, with a great deal of chearfulness, he had had a fine sweat and was pretty well, and said he had heard from Captain 
               <persName id="t17510703-18-person211">
                  Sowle
               <interp inst="t17510703-18-person211" type="given" value="Sowle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-18-person211" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and that it gave him a great deal of joy to hear he was able to go to his quarters; Captain 
               <persName id="t17510703-18-person212">
                  Sowle
               <interp inst="t17510703-18-person212" type="given" value="Sowle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-18-person212" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             held up his arm on Monday, and it seemed very lame, he could not use it; he also had a little scratch on his collar bone.</p>
               <p>Q. Which of the two seemed to be the strongest man?</p>
               <p>Campbel. Mr. Paschal was stronger and taller a great deal than the Captain.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Paschal's wound?</p>
               <p>Campbel. No, sir.</p>
               <p>Captain Ferguson. I knew Mr. Paschal about two months.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see him in liquor? how is he then?</p>
               <p>Ferguson. I thought him in liquor a little wrong headed; I remember one night at the tavern, about a fortnight or three weeks before this, he had some words with a gentleman, and went down stairs with him and came up again, and asked me to send him a sword; he insisted upon having it' and I would not let him go out of the room for some time; he went and came up again, and asked me to lend him my sword a second time, it was hanging up in the room, I took and put it about me; I have known Captain 
               <persName id="t17510703-18-person213">
                  Sowle
               <interp inst="t17510703-18-person213" type="given" value="Sowle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-18-person213" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             two years, I never saw him the least quarrelsome, I believe him to be a good-tempered gentleman as any I ever was acquainted with.</p>
               <p>Captain English. I have known Captain 
               <persName id="t17510703-18-person214">
                  Sowle
               <interp inst="t17510703-18-person214" type="given" value="Sowle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510703-18-person214" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             three years; he is an extream good-natured man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510703-18-verdict89" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510703-18-verdict89" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
