<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17551022-28">
               <interp inst="t17551022-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551022-28" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551022-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17551022"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551022-28" type="date" value="17551022"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17551022-28-off148-c274" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551022-28-defend327 t17551022-28-off148 t17551022-28-verdict152"></join>
         
               <p>394. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17551022-28-defend327" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Carrol 
                  <interp inst="t17551022-28-defend327" type="surname" value="Carrol"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-28-defend327" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-28-defend327" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17551022-28-off148" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17551022-28-off148" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-28-off148" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing four 36 shilling pieces, one guinea, and a four and sixpenny piece, the monies of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17551022-28-victim329" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Clarkson 
                        <interp inst="t17551022-28-victim329" type="surname" value="Clarkson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17551022-28-victim329" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17551022-28-victim329" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551022-28-off148 t17551022-28-victim329"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling house
            </rs> of 
               <persName id="t17551022-28-person330">
                  Nevil 
                  Henson 
               <interp inst="t17551022-28-person330" type="surname" value="Henson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-28-person330" type="given" value="Nevil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-28-person330" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17551022-28-cd149" type="crimeDate">Sept. 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551022-28-off148 t17551022-28-cd149"></join>.* </p> 
               <p>John Clarkson. <rs id="t17551022-28-viclabel150" type="occupation">I look after the tap, at the Four Swans in Bishopsgate-street</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551022-28-victim329 t17551022-28-viclabel150"></join>. On the 18th of September I was sitting up in the tap room for a gentleman, who was going by the Bury coach. I had seven 36 shilling pieces, and some guineas, and a four and sixpenny piece in my pocket. I fell asleep. About two o'clock in the morning I went to bed.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you had your money when you went to bed?</p>
               <p>Clarkson. I did not feel in my pocket that night. Next morning when I got up about seven o'clock, I miss'd four 36 shilling pieces, a guinea, and a four and sixpenny piece, I then went to the Green dragon next door, and asked if the prisoner had been there, and had some money about him.</p>

               <p>Q. How came you to ask for the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Clarkson. Because I had suspicion of him; he had serv'd me such a trick before. I asked the tapster if had changed any money; he said, the prisoner ask'd him to change a guinea, which one of the book-keeper's did.</p>
               <p>Court. This is what the tapster told you, this is not of your own knowledge.</p>
               <p>Clarkson. The tapster is here.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Clarkson. He was a <rs id="t17551022-28-deflabel151" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551022-28-defend327 t17551022-28-deflabel151"></join> in the yard; when I ask'd the prisoner about it, he denied it; but when I took him up he confess'd he had done so.</p>
               <p>Q. Done how?</p>
               <p>Clarkson. That he took four 36 s. pieces, a guinea, and a little piece, but he did not know what the little piece was; this was in the tap-house, where he was taken up; and before my Lord Mayor, I was present both times.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551022-28-person331">
                  Jeremiah 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17551022-28-person331" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-28-person331" type="given" value="Jeremiah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551022-28-person331" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the tap at the Green-dragon in Bishopsgate-street; I know the prisoner, he has come in often and call'd for a pint of beer, and has paid for it; he came in and called for a shilling's worth of rum and water; he seem'd to be in liquor; he then said, give me change for a guinea; a gentlewoman gave him change, and he paid for the rum and water out of it; then I observ'd, he put down some 36 s. pieces; I saw four, he shoved them towards me; I said, I supposed he wanted me to keep them for him till the morning. In the morning Mr. Clarkson came and inquired if I had seen him, and whether he had any money about him. I told him he had changed a guinea, and had left four 36 s. pieces with me. I have got the money now, and have had it ever since.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner come in the morning for the money?</p>
               <p>White. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was it when the tapster came?</p>
               <p>White. I cannot say.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see the prisoner after this?</p>
               <p>White. I did not see him till after the tapster came for the money.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you find the prisoner afterwards?</p>
               <p>White. I found him at the Four Swans, he did not run away. I went with him before my Lord Mayor, there I heard him confess he robbed the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175510220032"></xptr> tapster, as he lay asleep, of these four 36 s. pieces, (producing them ) and some little piece; I don't remember any thing more.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I found the money upon the floor in the taproom.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17551022-28-verdict152" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17551022-28-verdict152" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17551022-28-punish153" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17551022-28-punish153" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551022-28-defend327 t17551022-28-punish153"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
