<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17500711-60">
               <interp inst="t17500711-60" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-60" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-60" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17500711"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-60" type="date" value="17500711"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500711-60-off272-c388" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-60-defend502 t17500711-60-off272 t17500711-60-verdict274"></join>
         
               <p>488 
               <persName id="t17500711-60-defend502" type="defendantName">
                  Eliz.
                   Preston
               <interp inst="t17500711-60-defend502" type="surname" value="Preston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-60-defend502" type="given" value="Eliz."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-60-defend502" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , spinster, was indicted for <rs id="t17500711-60-off272" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500711-60-off272" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-60-off272" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch, val. 20 s. one silver seal, val. 6 d. two moidores, one thirty six shill. piece, the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17500711-60-victim504" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Skeggs 
                        <interp inst="t17500711-60-victim504" type="surname" value="Skeggs"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500711-60-victim504" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500711-60-victim504" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-60-off272 t17500711-60-victim504"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling house of the said Eliz.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500711-60-cd273" type="crimeDate">July 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-60-off272 t17500711-60-cd273"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-60-person505">
                  Tho 
                  Skeggs 
               <interp inst="t17500711-60-person505" type="surname" value="Skeggs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-60-person505" type="given" value="Tho"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-60-person505" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going to the Greyhound inn, Drury lane, last Monday was seven-night for lodging, I knocked at the door about twelve at night; there was one Ann Hall was walking at the next door to this inn, being the prisoner's house; no body came to let me in, she came and said I might have lodging there, so I went along with her into the house. At going in I had 1 s. 6 d. in punch, then after that I wanted to go to bed; I went to bed; after we went up stairs we had some more punch, till I could drink no longer; then I went to bed, and my companion Ann Hall along with me, but my landlady, the prisoner, came up stairs before Ann Hall was in bed. I asked her what I must give her for the bed, she said two shillings, I gave it her: after that she came up and asked me if I would not have another eighteen penny worth of punch, I had that. When I went to bed I had laid my breeches under my head, I took the money out of my breeches, and paid her for the punch, and put my breeches there again and went to sleep. In the morning when I awaked I went to see what it was o'clock, my watch was gone; I felt for my money; I had two moidores and one thirty six shill. piece and some silver, when I put my breeches there, but it was all gone. Then I asked the girl that lay along with me if she knew any thing what was become of my money and watch, she said she did not know, except my landlady had it. Then she went part of the way down stairs, and asked the prisoner if she had got it; she came back again and told me it was safe. I staid a while, and she did not come so soon as I wanted her, I bid the girl call her again, which she did; then the prisoner came up and brought the watch in her right hand, and sat down on the bed side, and held it out to me, and asked me if it was mine, I said yes, she gave it me; then I asked her where the money was, she said she did not know, I told her somebody in the house must have it, for I lost it there. She said she did not believe any body had it, except her sister; then I asked her where her sister was, she said she was gone out; I asked her how long she would be before she came home, she said, not before dinner, then she expected her. I went away and came again about the time; I asked her if her sister was come in, she said, no, but she expected her every minute. Then I went to an alehouse opposite that house, and got a pint of beer, and went and asked two or three times, and found she was not come. At last I understood she had no sister there, then I told her I would seek a remedy, so I went away on purpose to do it. I was going to get some money, going through St. James's Park I met this Ann Hall along with a drummer, just by the parade, the man came after me and said the prisoner had the money, she took it out of my pocket; that the first thing she took was the watch, then the money. They asked me how long it would be before I came back from Westminster, I said in half an hour, they said they would wait for me, which they did. Then we came almost to Drury-lane, then the drummer went to the house and asked how affairs stood. He came back and said the prisoner said Ann Hall was not to come home till 10 o'clock, but stay at the sign of the Fox, and if things were clear she might come home. I went to Justice Ledger, he granted a warrant, I took Ann Hall with me, the prisoner got out of the coach, and called me and the constable aside, and wanted me to make it up, I told her I would not. After the justice examined her, he committed her to the Gatehouse for farther examination, which was the next day. Before she was brought some of her friends came to the constable and me and offered me the money. The justice committed her there again; before the justice she denied ever seeing me at her house.</p>
               <p>Ann Hall. Betwixt one and two o'clock on Thursday morning was a week I was walking backwards and forwards near the Greyhound, Drury-lane,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175007110035"></xptr> the gentleman asked me if I wanted a careless husband, I told him I could not get one; we went into the prisoner's house and had some punch, he asked for a bed, he gave two shillings, he was not sober, which he owned at his first coming in. After we had been in bed both together for about an hour, my landlady came up and took the breeches from under his head, she pulled out the watch and put it into her bosom; then she pulled out two pieces of gold, and some silver I saw, there was a candle in the room. Said she, if you'll not say any thing of this I'll rub out your score, and buy you a pair of shoes; I said I would not agree to it; she called up another girl, and called for a bottle of wine; she shewed the money to the other girl. In the morning the gentleman put on his waistcoat and other things, he said where are my breeches? then he said, where is my watch? said I, it is all safe, and your money too. I went down and called to the prisoner, she did not come, I called on the stairs again, then she came up and brought the watch in her right hand, and asked if it was his; he asked for the money, she said she knew nothing of it upon her honour. Said he, I had so much money and I lost it in your house; if so, said she, you have given it to my sister, and she is gone out. He went out to the Black Dog and staid there, and came over every now and then. At last she went to Covent Garden market to buy some victuals, and bid me go up and lie down upon the bed, and while I was asleep, the man that goes for her husband came up and awaked me, and asked me for my ring, and bid me go out and stay till every thing was quiet, and then come home. She came home and said, make the best of your way up Drury-lane for the gentleman is gone for a search warrant, and if he should search the house and not find you, we will make oath you was a stranger, and made off with the money. And my landlady was to say if he came to take me up, he wanted to have to do with me in an unhandsome manner. I went directly into St. James's Park, and found an acquaintance, I told him the whole thing; the gentleman was coming by, I was in a surprise; he asked me what was the matter, I told him that was the person; said he, I'll go and speak to him. While he was going after him, I said I would speak to him myself, I'll face him as the d - I did the cat. The gentleman said, if you'll tell me who has got the money I'll make you some recompence; I said my landlady was the person that took it out of his breeches. I went to the justice and took my oath to what I have said now. He was fast asleep when she came up and took it. She took a burning glass out of his pocket, and wanted me to put it in again, and I would not, so she put it in herself.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever frequent a brandy shop in the Butcher-row, near Temple-bar?</p>
               <p>Ann Hall. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you not there the third of July to change a thirty six shill. piece of gold?</p>
               <p>A. Hall. No, I was not, I never was possessed of a piece of gold of that fort ; I know a guinea, and that is all I know of gold coin.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence. I know no more of it than the child unborn. She brought the watch to me and I delivered it to him again in the morning. Because I threatened to trouble her for the money she owes me, she has brought this thing against me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-60-person506">
                  Catharine 
                  Messinger 
               <interp inst="t17500711-60-person506" type="surname" value="Messinger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-60-person506" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-60-person506" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was servant to Mr. Little, a brandy shop in the Butcher-row, by Temple bar, this Ann Hall came to our shop on Friday was seven night betwixt ten and eleven o'clock, and asked for a quartern of gin; there were two women with her, I served her, she wanted me to change a piece of gold, I asked her what it was, she said she could not tell, I took it out of her hand, it was a thirty six shill. piece, the gentlewoman of the shop was asleep and I could not change it, so I returned it again; she offered me another, if I did not like that, and she offered me six-pence to change it; I trusted her for the gin because I could not change it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-60-person507">
                  Hannah 
                  Cordosa 
               <interp inst="t17500711-60-person507" type="surname" value="Cordosa"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-60-person507" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-60-person507" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know Ann Hall, I saw her last Tuesday was seven nights coming out of this gin shop, it is the Black Dog in Butcher-row, I was going in for a half-penny worth of small beer, she had money in her hand, I saw three broad pieces.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Cordosa. I live as far as Westminster. I had been in the city to buy some thread to work with. I am a sempstress.</p>
               <p>Han. Matthews. I go to the house where she lived, next door to the Greyhound, I help the maid there to do the work, I never saw Ann Hall with any money at all.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-60-person508">
                  Mary 
                  Mitchel 
               <interp inst="t17500711-60-person508" type="surname" value="Mitchel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-60-person508" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-60-person508" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never saw Ann Hall with any money, I saw her with the watch in the prisoner's house when the gentleman was in the house. She brought it down to the prisoner between three and four o'clock, and desired her to keep it for him. I am a servant in the house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-60-person509">
                  Patrick 
                  Reynolds 
               <interp inst="t17500711-60-person509" type="surname" value="Reynolds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-60-person509" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-60-person509" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a chandler's shop and sell coals, I have known the prisoner two or three years, she behaved always very honestly, I never heard her charged with theft.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175007110036"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-60-person510">
                  Anne 
                  Callings 
               <interp inst="t17500711-60-person510" type="surname" value="Callings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-60-person510" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-60-person510" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her 15 or 16 years, I never knew her charged with theft before this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-60-person511">
                  Anne 
                  Birk 
               <interp inst="t17500711-60-person511" type="surname" value="Birk"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-60-person511" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-60-person511" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her 11 years, I never knew any harm by her in my life.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500711-60-verdict274" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500711-60-verdict274" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
