<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17540424-46">
               <interp inst="t17540424-46" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540424-46" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540424-46" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540424"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540424-46" type="date" value="17540424"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540424-46-off244-c334" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540424-46-defend415 t17540424-46-off244 t17540424-46-verdict249"></join>
         
               <p>284. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17540424-46-defend415" type="defendantName">
                  Ann
                   the 
                  <rs id="t17540424-46-deflabel243" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540424-46-defend415 t17540424-46-deflabel243"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17540424-46-person416">
                        John 
                        Smith 
                     <interp inst="t17540424-46-person416" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540424-46-person416" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540424-46-person416" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
                     <interp inst="t17540424-46-defend415" type="surname" value="the"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-46-defend415" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-46-defend415" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17540424-46-off244" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540424-46-off244" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-46-off244" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one holland gown, value 2 s. one cotton gown, value 2 s. 6 d. one bed quilt, value 6 s. one linnen sheet, val. 2 d. one pair of laced ruffles, one Dresden handkerchief, two linnen aprons, two dimitty petticoats, two pair of lawn ruffles, one pair of silk stockings, one pair of cotton stockings, a sattin-hat and a pair of paste ear-rings
            </rs>, the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17540424-46-victim418" type="victimName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Ward 
                  <interp inst="t17540424-46-victim418" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-46-victim418" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-46-victim418" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540424-46-off244 t17540424-46-victim418"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17540424-46-viclabel245" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540424-46-victim418 t17540424-46-viclabel245"></join>, <rs id="t17540424-46-cd246" type="crimeDate">April 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540424-46-off244 t17540424-46-cd246"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540424-46-person419">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17540424-46-person419" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-46-person419" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-46-person419" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17540424-46-crimeloc247">Spring-Gardens</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17540424-46-crimeloc247" type="placeName" value="Spring-Gardens"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17540424-46-crimeloc247" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540424-46-off244 t17540424-46-crimeloc247"></join> and keep a house there, the prisoner was my <rs id="t17540424-46-deflabel248" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540424-46-defend415 t17540424-46-deflabel248"></join>, I lost the things mentioned in the indictment, I did not see the prisoner take them, I was at supper when she went away: when I heard where she was, which was in about seven or eight days, I sent a constable, he took her and brought her before the justice; I got all my goods again but a very few.</p>
               <p>Q. How got you your goods again ?</p>
               <p>Ward. The constable got them and kept them in custody; I saw the flowered cotton gown, the laced cap, the cross barred lawn apron, the french dimitty petticoat all upon her, I am very sure they are my property, I was before the justice, there she owned she took them.</p>
               <p>Q. from the prisoner. Did not you give me the clothes to appear in company with?</p>
               <p>Ward. No, my lord, she was with me but two nights, and the third night she robbed me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540424-46-person420">
                  Dorothy 
                  Skelton 
               <interp inst="t17540424-46-person420" type="surname" value="Skelton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-46-person420" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-46-person420" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . A gentlewoman I work for sent the prisoner to me, desiring me to get her a place; I got her this place, I know nothing concerning the fact.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540424-46-person421">
                  Mary 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17540424-46-person421" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-46-person421" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-46-person421" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know nothing but her being hired as a servant to this place.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175404240027"></xptr>Mr. Cuthbert. I am a constable. On the 2d of April I had a warrant brought to me to take up the prisoner, she was charged with stealing the goods mentioned; I carried her before justice Cox who was not then at home; the next morning she was called there again; there she confest having the things; I then had a search warrant and went and found them, and have had them in my custody ever since: the prisoner said, her mistress had lent her some part of the goods to appear in as a lady.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she own the taking of these goods, or whether they were lent her?</p>
               <p>Cuthbert. The night I took her she said she stole them, the next day she said, the Prosecutrix had lent her the things to appear in company with. When she was first taken before the Justice she had the gown, cap, ruffles, and handkerchief on.</p>
               <p>Q. to Ward. Did you lend the prisoner any part of these goods?</p>
               <p>Ward. Upon my oath, my lord, I never did.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>Upon my oath she did, and there is one of the young girls (pointing to Smith) who was in the house with me at the same time, and she has now cloaths on her back that was lent her by 
               <persName id="t17540424-46-person422">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17540424-46-person422" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-46-person422" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-46-person422" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to appear in company.</p>
               <p>Q. to Smith. What is your way of life ?</p>
               <p>Smith. I can do plain work, or go out to plain work.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you maintain yourself by doing plain work?</p>
               <p>Smith. I get my living as I can.</p>
               <p>Q. to Ward. How do you get your living?</p>

               <p>Ward. By plain work, and I take in a little washing.</p>
               <p>Q. Is this finery fit for a washerwoman?</p>
               <p>Ward. My lord, it is all the sinery I had.</p>
               <p>Q. to Smith. Upon the oath you have taken, does this 
               <persName id="t17540424-46-person423">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17540424-46-person423" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-46-person423" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540424-46-person423" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             keep a regular orderly house?</p>
               <p>Smith. I never saw any otherwise.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath are not these goods lent to people in her house?</p>
               <p>Smith. No, they are not.</p>
               <p>Q. She says she gets her living by washing, upon your oath does she, or does she not?</p>
               <p>Smith. Not as I know.</p>
               <p>Q. How does she get it then ?</p>
               <p>Smith. She sells a pint of wine and makes a dish of coffee for gentlemen that come there.</p>
               <p>Q. Does not the cloaths you have on now, belong to Mrs Ward?</p>
               <p>Smith. No, they do not; I paid for them myself; and she is an impudent saucy jade for saying any such thing, for she never saw me in these cloaths I have now got on; I would not take a false oath for the value of all the cloaths.</p>
               <p>Q. to Skelton. What sort of a house does Mrs. Ward keep?</p>
               <p>Skelton. I don't know, I work in making capuchins, bonnets, &amp;c. and when I carried my work home, there was my money; I never saw any thing disorderly.</p>
               <p>Q. from the prisoner to the constable. Do not you know that is a very bad house, for you often frequent it?</p>
               <p>Cuthbert. My lord, if it is a bawdy house I never made one of it.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business ?</p>
               <p>Cuthbert. I keep a grocer's and oyl shop, and live by St. Martin's church.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you acquainted with Mrs. Ward ?</p>
               <p>Cuthbert. I never knew her but since I have been constable.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your reason for your knowing her so much since you have been constable?</p>
               <p>Cuthbert. I believe she keeps a disorderly house, and I going my rounds have taken people from the door when there has been any noise.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540424-46-verdict249" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540424-46-verdict249" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
