<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17540911-31">
               <interp inst="t17540911-31" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-31" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-31" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-31" type="date" value="17540911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540911-31-off173-c231" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-31-defend287 t17540911-31-off173 t17540911-31-verdict177"></join>
         
               <p>446. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17540911-31-defend287" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Heild 
                  <interp inst="t17540911-31-defend287" type="surname" value="Heild"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-defend287" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-defend287" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for <rs id="t17540911-31-off173" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-off173" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-off173" type="offenceSubcategory" value="bigamy"></interp>
               that on the 5th of July, 1747, he did marry, and take to wife, 
                     
                        <persName id="t17540911-31-victim289" type="victimName">
                           Sarah 
                           Mills 
                        <interp inst="t17540911-31-victim289" type="surname" value="Mills"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540911-31-victim289" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540911-31-victim289" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17540911-31-viclabel174" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-31-victim289 t17540911-31-viclabel174"></join>, and, after that, on the <rs id="t17540911-31-cd175" type="crimeDate">29th of Sept. 1753</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-31-off173 t17540911-31-cd175"></join>, he did marry 
                     
                        <persName id="t17540911-31-victim291" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Jenings 
                        <interp inst="t17540911-31-victim291" type="surname" value="Jenings"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540911-31-victim291" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17540911-31-victim291" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17540911-31-viclabel176" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-31-victim291 t17540911-31-viclabel176"></join>, his former wife being then living
            </rs>.*</p> 
               <p>Thomas Russels. I saw the prisoner married to 
               <persName id="t17540911-31-person292">
                  Sarah 
                  Mills 
               <interp inst="t17540911-31-person292" type="surname" value="Mills"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-person292" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-person292" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , but am not positive to the time, nor can I swear to the year, but know it was in the summer time, about 7 years ago.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be there?</p>
               <p>Russel. I gave her away at the time ?</p>
               <p>Q. Were they married in the usual manner?</p>
               <p>Russel. They were.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they live together after ?</p>
               <p>Russel. They did.</p>
               <p>Q. Had she any children by him?</p>
               <p>Russel. I believe she had two.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were they married?</p>
               <p>Russel. In the Fleet.</p>
               <p>Q. By whom?</p>
               <p>Russel. I don't know the gentleman that married them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he appear in the habit of a clergyman ?</p>
               <p>Russel. He did. I think he had a gown on. I very well remember he was in black, and had a band on.</p>
               <p>Q. Is the woman living?</p>
               <p>Russel. She is.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see her?</p>
               <p>Russel. I saw her a little time ago, he looks about, she is now in court.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any acquaintance with the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Russel. I had; he was my bed-fellow at the time he married the woman, and had been for 5 or 6 months.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you recollect the year that the prisoner was first married?</p>
               <p>Russel. I can't be punctual to that.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain whether the person that married them had or had not a gown on?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175409110024"></xptr>Russel. I believe he had a gown on.</p>
               <p>Q. Whereabout is this house, where he was married ?</p>
               <p>Russel. 'Twas in Fleet Market, near Fleet Street, on the right hand side as you go from Holbourn, three or four houses from the corner.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you been to inquire at any house for a register of a marriage with that woman ?</p>
               <p>Russel. I did go by the desire of the mother about a month after they were married, to the same house for a certificate; but they would not let me have one under nine shillings. They thought she had been an heiress, and wanted a good deal of money.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you not been lately ?</p>
               <p>Russel. No, upon my word I have not.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know one Mr. Beech ?</p>
               <p>Russel. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you offer money to a man to insert the register of the prisoner and Mrs. Mills ?</p>
               <p>Russel. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you offer a guinea at any time?</p>
               <p>Russel. No, I never offered a farthing after that first time that I told you of.</p>
               <p>Mary Jennings. I was married to the prisoner at the bar in the year 1753 at May Fair Chapel by Mr. Keith.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you live with him afterwards ?</p>
               <p>Jennings. I did near a twelvemonth.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you worth any thing in money or effects at the time you married him ?</p>
               <p>Jennings. I was worth about 74 l. at the time. I went and received it at the Bank after I was married, and bought me some goods; the rest of the money we spent. I had a little house at the time.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any children by him ?</p>
               <p>Jennings. I had a child by him, of which I lay in within these three weeks.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he know before he married you that you was intitled to something?</p>
               <p>Jennings. Yes, I told him of it.</p>
               <p>Q. to Russel. What was the ceremony that was performed?</p>
               <p>Russel. I believe they were married as usual.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you been married ?</p>
               <p>Russel. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it the same as performed then ?</p>
               <p>Russel. To the best of my knowledge it was in the same manner as mine word for word.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there a ring?</p>
               <p>Russel. There was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear him say he'd have her, and her say she'd have him?</p>
               <p>Russel. I did.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-31-person293">
                  Thomas 
                  Owen 
               <interp inst="t17540911-31-person293" type="surname" value="Owen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-person293" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-person293" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have kept a publick house in the Fleet ever since the 23d of March.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you got any of the books of the marriages that were performed at your house?</p>
               <p>Owen. I have got a pretty many of them.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Look about and see if you can see a man that came to your house about the latter end of March, or beginning of April.</p>
               <p>Owen. I see him; his name, as he told me, is 
               <persName id="t17540911-31-person294">
                  Thomas 
                  Russel 
               <interp inst="t17540911-31-person294" type="surname" value="Russel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-person294" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-person294" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He, and 
               <persName id="t17540911-31-person295">
                  Sarah 
                  Mills 
               <interp inst="t17540911-31-person295" type="surname" value="Mills"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-person295" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-person295" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who pretended to be first wife, came to my house, and going up stairs, called me up, and asked me if they could not have a marriage entered seven years back in the name of Heild and she. I said, there was nothing to be done in that unless I had a mind to be hanged, since the late act of parliament. The man said he would satify me if I would enter it in the book. But I answered him there was no such thing to be done, and that I would not do such a thing unless I would get myself hanged.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How often have you seen that 
               <persName id="t17540911-31-person296">
                  Sarah 
                  Mills 
               <interp inst="t17540911-31-person296" type="surname" value="Mills"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-person296" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-person296" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Owen. I never saw her in my life before that night.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to start that word, the pretended wife ?</p>
               <p>Owen. 'Tis my opinion they never were married.</p>
               <p>Q. Who brought you here ?</p>
               <p>Owen. I was subpoena'd; it was accidental.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever any conversation with Russel till then?</p>
               <p>Owen. No, never. They then drank a pint of wine in my house.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Owen. I have known him seven years.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you been acquainted with him seven years?</p>
               <p>Owen. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you know him when he lived in Spitalfields?</p>
               <p>Owen. I did, and used to recommend him to some jobs.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you then take him to be a married man or a single man ?</p>
               <p>Owen. I used to take him to be a single man till this last marriage at May Fair.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175409110025"></xptr>Q. How came the prisoner to know that such application had been made to you about putting this thing in the book?</p>
               <p>Owen. I let him know it.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to say your coming here was accidental?</p>
               <p>Owen. I can't tell how I came to be subpoena'd here.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath did not you know that 
               <persName id="t17540911-31-person297">
                  Sarah 
                  Mills 
               <interp inst="t17540911-31-person297" type="surname" value="Mills"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-person297" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-person297" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and the prisoner lived together, or that he had children by her?</p>
               <p>Owen. Upon my oath I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. to Russel. When was you in the house of this witness?</p>
               <p>Russel. I believe I have not been in a house in the Fleet these six years.</p>

               <p>Q. When did you see the evidence Owen before ?</p>
               <p>Russel. I never saw him to my knowledge till I saw him at Hicks's Hall when the bill was found.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-31-person298">
                  Mary 
                  Jennings 
               <interp inst="t17540911-31-person298" type="surname" value="Jennings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-person298" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-person298" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner once told me they had put a false certificate in the books, and he wanted a guinea and half of me to go and get the leaf torn out. I told him there was no such thing to be done, and I remember he made me no answer.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember his saying any thing at any time about 
               <persName id="t17540911-31-person299">
                  Thomas 
                  Owen 
               <interp inst="t17540911-31-person299" type="surname" value="Owen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-person299" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-person299" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>M. Jennings. No, except this, he said that he knew him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever mention Owen's name to him?</p>
               <p>M. Jennings. No, never.</p>
               <p>Q. to Russel. Did M. Jennings ever mention Owen's name to you?</p>
               <p>Russel. No, she never did. I have known her but till within these three months.</p>
               <p>Q. to Owen. Was any body by when you had this conversation above stairs ?</p>
               <p>Owen. Yes, one 
               <persName id="t17540911-31-person300">
                  Thomas 
                  Beech 
               <interp inst="t17540911-31-person300" type="surname" value="Beech"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-person300" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-person300" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , whom I called up to hear it repeated, and told him over and over before them what they wanted me for. They offered him a guinea at the same time to prevail upon me to do it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he know them ?</p>
               <p>Owen. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is he ?</p>
               <p>Owen. He is gone to Harly Bush, and is not come up again.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540911-31-verdict177" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-verdict177" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>As 
               <persName id="t17540911-31-person301">
                  Sarah 
                  Mills 
               <interp inst="t17540911-31-person301" type="surname" value="Mills"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-person301" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-person301" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the first wife was in court, and the verdict being given, the gentlemen of the jury desired to know of her whether she was willing to answer the question: Whether or not she went with Russel to the house of Owen as Owen had deposed. She answered she was willing to answer upon oath.</p>
               <p>She was sworn.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go at any time along with 
               <persName id="t17540911-31-person302">
                  Thomas 
                  Russel 
               <interp inst="t17540911-31-person302" type="surname" value="Russel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-person302" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-person302" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to Owen's house?</p>
               <p>S. Mills. No, never since he kept it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you ever in this house with 
               <persName id="t17540911-31-person303">
                  Thomas 
                  Russel 
               <interp inst="t17540911-31-person303" type="surname" value="Russel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-person303" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-person303" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ?</p>
               <p>S. Mills. No, never. Neither was there any such thing offered.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you ever at that house?</p>
               <p>S. Mills. I went there with my brother to have a certificate, and offered 4 s. 6 d. for it. He searched the books, and said, my marriage was not there. I said, I was married there, and saw it registred.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-31-person304">
                  Thomas 
                  Owen 
               <interp inst="t17540911-31-person304" type="surname" value="Owen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-person304" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-31-person304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was committed to Newgate for perjury.</p>
            </div1>
