<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510523-39">
               <interp inst="t17510523-39" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510523-39" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510523-39" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510523"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510523-39" type="date" value="17510523"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510523-39-off217-c306" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-39-defend389 t17510523-39-off217 t17510523-39-verdict222"></join>
         
               <p>393. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17510523-39-defend389" type="defendantName">
                  Edmund
                   otherwise 
                  <rs id="t17510523-39-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-39-defend389 t17510523-39-alias-3"></join>Edward</rs> Wallis<interp inst="t17510523-39-defend389" type="surname" value="otherwise"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-defend389" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-defend389" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted, for <rs id="t17510523-39-off217" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-off217" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-off217" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 19 guineas and 2 half guineas, the money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17510523-39-victim391" type="victimName">
                           David 
                           Commins 
                        <interp inst="t17510523-39-victim391" type="surname" value="Commins"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510523-39-victim391" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510523-39-victim391" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-39-off217 t17510523-39-victim391"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling-house of 
                     <persName id="t17510523-39-person392">
                        Anthony 
                        Powel 
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-person392" type="surname" value="Powel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510523-39-person392" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510523-39-person392" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17510523-39-cd218" type="crimeDate">May 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-39-off217 t17510523-39-cd218"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-39-person393">
                  David 
                  Commins 
               <interp inst="t17510523-39-person393" type="surname" value="Commins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-person393" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-person393" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17510523-39-crimeloc219">Charles Street, Soho Square</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17510523-39-crimeloc219" type="placeName" value="Charles Street, Soho Square"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510523-39-crimeloc219" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-39-off217 t17510523-39-crimeloc219"></join> in the house of 
               <persName id="t17510523-39-person394">
                  Anthony 
                  Powel 
               <interp inst="t17510523-39-person394" type="surname" value="Powel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-person394" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-person394" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and so does the prisoner at the bar. I lost 19 guineas and 2 half guineas the 14th of May; I missed it on the 15th out of my box in the room where I lodge; I had lent my partner (that is the prisoner, we are <rs id="t17510523-39-viclabel220" type="occupation">
                     <rs id="t17510523-39-deflabel221" type="occupation">chairmen</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-39-defend389 t17510523-39-deflabel221"></join>
                  </rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-39-victim391 t17510523-39-viclabel220"></join>) six-pence the 14th at night, he was at play at cards, and had no money he said. I went to bed between 11 and 12 o'clock, he would not go to bed. We used to go to bed by one candle; he lies in the next room to me. The 15th he went out, and did not come nigh me till evening; then he pulled out guineas and silver, and said one Forset a life-guard-man had let him have it. I examined my box, and all my money was gone; I got a warrant for him, and had him before Justice Fielding; the life-guard-man denied he gave him any money. I had a particular mark on one of the guineas, being the first I ever was master of, which I brought from Ireland with me, and had made a scratch cross the nose on it; it was amongst the rest of my money.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to mark that guinea, and when?</p>
               <p>Commins. It is the first I ever had, and I gave it to a friend to keep about three years ago, and he returned it to me when I came to London.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you bring any other with you at that time?</p>
               <p>Commins. I brought about six with me in all.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you come from Ireland?</p>
               <p>Commins. Two years ago last Midsummer, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the figure of the chair your own?</p>
               <p>Commins. One end of the chair was the prisoner's, the other mine.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there other people lodged in the house ?</p>
               <p>Commins. There were, Sir.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-39-person395">
                  Anthony 
                  Powel 
               <interp inst="t17510523-39-person395" type="surname" value="Powel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-person395" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-person395" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . At Michaelmas was 12 months the prosecutor and prisoner came to lodge at my house, the prisoner had 2 guineas of Commins for what they call a colt, that is, to a share the first year. The prisoner owed me some money some time; I used to teize him for it. He gave me a note of hand for 2 l. 14 s. 6 d. he had paid 15 s. of it. The fifteenth of May, he said to me, I'll lay you a pot of beer, I pay you the remainder within an hour; accordingly he came into the tap room with some money in his hand within the hour, one Forset a life-guard-man was with him; said the prisoner you shall not dun me, where is the note? he pulled out a good many guineas, saying, this Mr. Forset would lend him money enough. The life-guard-man passed it on, for my part, I thought he had sold the figure of his chair to him. The prisoner paid me two guineas, out of which I gave him 1 s. 6 d. here they be both, Justice Fielding seald them up; they happened not to be put amongst any other money, one of them is this marked one: the jury examine that.</p>
               <p>Jer. Rapley. I am constable, I carried the prisoner before Justice Fielding. Upon examination he said a gentleman lent him this money (there being 16 guineas and half found upon him before the Justice) the life-guard man denied it; then the prisoner could make no defence. The prisoner said after this, he had lent him some money; the life-guard-man answered he had lent him a shilling or two. The next morning there was a receipt trumped up, as though he received it of his brother.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>My witnesses know every word as well as I do. I have four witnesses that saw me get this money of my brother.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-39-person396">
                  David 
                  Wallis 
               <interp inst="t17510523-39-person396" type="surname" value="Wallis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-person396" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-person396" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Vere Street, Clare-Market, and keep a public house. Last Wednesday was se'nnight about one o'clock, or a little after, I paid my brother the prisoner at the bar, 20 golden guineas in my house, which I had borrowed of him; there were 
               <persName id="t17510523-39-person397">
                  Charles 
                  Finch 
               <interp inst="t17510523-39-person397" type="surname" value="Finch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-person397" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-person397" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17510523-39-person398">
                  William 
                  Battey 
               <interp inst="t17510523-39-person398" type="surname" value="Battey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-person398" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-person398" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Thomas Wilkson, and several others by. I took a receipt of him for it; the prosecutor was always a poor man; he could not pay for his figure, without being indulged by the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. to Powel. How did you know Commins paid the prisoner 2 guineas for learning to carry? &amp;c.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175105230032"></xptr>Powel. I have heard the prisoner say he had them of Commins.</p>
               <p>Q. In what circumstances do you take the prosecutor to be in?</p>
               <p>Powel. He is a close man, and does not let the world know what he is worth. I know he has lent six guineas at a time to a neighbour of ours. I witnessed the note.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-39-person399">
                  Charles 
                  Finch 
               <interp inst="t17510523-39-person399" type="surname" value="Finch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-person399" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-person399" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Wednesday was fortnight coming along, I went into 
               <persName id="t17510523-39-person400">
                  David 
                  Wallis 
               <interp inst="t17510523-39-person400" type="surname" value="Wallis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-person400" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-person400" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's house to drink; I saw the two brothers together; I had been applied to by the prisoner to arrest his brother several times for 20 l. I used to say it is a shame for one brother to arrest another, and endeavoured to hinder that as much as I could. I am an officer of the Marshal's Court.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-39-person401">
                  Thomas 
                  Dwyer 
               <interp inst="t17510523-39-person401" type="surname" value="Dwyer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-person401" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-person401" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a labouring man; I was present at the time, the 15th of this instant, and saw 
               <persName id="t17510523-39-person402">
                  David 
                  Wallis 
               <interp inst="t17510523-39-person402" type="surname" value="Wallis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-person402" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-person402" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             pay the prisoner 20 guineas, there were several people sitting by them. I went there accidentally through to spend a market penny; I have known the prisoner a good while, I never heard him charged with a halfpenny-worth of felony in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-39-person403">
                  William 
                  Battey 
               <interp inst="t17510523-39-person403" type="surname" value="Battey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-person403" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-person403" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I called in at the hole in the wall, the 15th of this instant, about 11 or 12 o' clock, I believe it was the forenoon, I believe it might be one o'clock, I saw the prisoner come in along with a little red-faced man, demanding money of the man of the house, he refused to pay him; said he if you don't I'll arrest you. I understood by that, the other man was an officer.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you know that?</p>
               <p>Battey. Because he said, he'd execute the warrant upon him.</p>
               <p>Q. Which of they two came in first?</p>
               <p>Battey. I can't tell that, I believe they came in together.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you was there before the prisoner was?</p>
               <p>Battey. I think I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you there before the man in the red face came in?</p>
               <p>Battey. I was. I heard the landlord say, I'll pay you, he went and fetched the money, and sat down in the box. I saw it was gold, and a pretty deal of it; as they were going away, said the man that keeps the house, I'll have a receipt.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-39-person404">
                  Thomas 
                  Wilkson 
               <interp inst="t17510523-39-person404" type="surname" value="Wilkson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-person404" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-person404" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the prisoner at the bar, last Wednesday was sen'night just by Clare-Market ; I was walking with Mr. Battey; we called to drink at the hole in the wall, just by Clare-Market, about the middle of the day. We sat down upon the right hand ; there was a little middle sized man and the prisoner at the bar came in, and asked the man of the house for the money that was due ; the man said I have not the money for you at present. This man looked back to the other, and said, come along, I have been here three or four times, I'll come no more, I'll arrest him. The prisoner said to the red faced man, so do; I want the money to set myself in a way of business. Then he and the other went out at the door. The man of the house went to the door, and said, come back you scoundrel, I have the money in the house, I'll pay you. I saw him bring the money in gold, and put it down on the table by them; when it was paid, he demanded a note for 20 pounds or 20 guineas, I don't know which.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-39-person405">
                  Thomas 
                  Forfit 
               <interp inst="t17510523-39-person405" type="surname" value="Forfit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-person405" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-person405" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner three or four years; I am a soldier in the life-guards; I was with him the week before last at Mr. Powel's house; he came to me on the 15th instant about 4 o'clock, and desired me to come there that night. I went there, and one Mac. Daniels along with me; the prisoner came in after I was there; he told me he wanted me about taking up a note of hand, which Mr. Powel had of his of 2 l. 14 s. of which he said he had paid, 17 s. 6 d. saying, he only wanted me, as he could not write or read. He gave me 2 guineas; I held them in my hand; Mr. Powel would not receive it; then I put them into my right-hand pocket, in which I had two guineas and half in gold at that time. Mr. Powel said the prisoner had paid him, but 15 s. At last he took the money and discounted it at 15 s. paid before, giving him 1 s. 6 d. The prisoner said he did not want me to lend him the money, he had money enough.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510523-39-verdict222" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510523-39-verdict222" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acq
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
