<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570526-17">
               <interp inst="t17570526-17" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570526-17" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570526-17" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570526"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570526-17" type="date" value="17570526"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570526-17-off85-c143" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570526-17-defend172 t17570526-17-off85 t17570526-17-verdict90"></join>
         
               <p>230. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17570526-17-defend172" type="defendantName">
                     Nicholas 
                     Hidcloaff 
                  <interp inst="t17570526-17-defend172" type="surname" value="Hidcloaff"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-defend172" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-defend172" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17570526-17-off85" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-off85" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-off85" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one iron coffee pot stake, value 3 s. and one beck iron, value 1 s.
            </rs> the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17570526-17-victim174" type="victimName">
                     George Ebenezer 
                     Pewterers 
                  <interp inst="t17570526-17-victim174" type="surname" value="Pewterers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-victim174" type="given" value="George Ebenezer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-victim174" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570526-17-off85 t17570526-17-victim174"></join>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17570526-17-cd86" type="crimeDate">March 20</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570526-17-off85 t17570526-17-cd86"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570526-17-person175">
                  Mary 
                  Pewterers 
               <interp inst="t17570526-17-person175" type="surname" value="Pewterers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-person175" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-person175" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My husband's name is 
               <persName id="t17570526-17-person176">
                  George Ebenezer 
                  Pewterers 
               <interp inst="t17570526-17-person176" type="surname" value="Pewterers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-person176" type="given" value="George Ebenezer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-person176" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Have you lost any thing?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. I have lost a beck iron and coffee stake.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you lose them?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. Betwixt the 20th of March and the 11th of May.</p>
               <p>Q. What business is your husband?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. He is a <rs id="t17570526-17-viclabel87" type="occupation">brasier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570526-17-victim174 t17570526-17-viclabel87"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is he?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. He is a <rs id="t17570526-17-viclabel88" type="occupation">captain of marines on board a private ship of war</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570526-17-victim174 t17570526-17-viclabel88"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. He was a <rs id="t17570526-17-deflabel89" type="occupation">journeyman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570526-17-defend172 t17570526-17-deflabel89"></join> to my husband.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had he been your journeyman ?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. About four years.</p>
               <p>Q. Why do you charge the prisoner?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. The discovery was made by a person that went to work with the prisoner, who saw the tools there, and knowing them, he came and told me of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he say he saw them?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. At the prisoner's lodgings. So we took the prisoner up.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say for himself?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. He said my husband lent him them before he went away.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know but that is true ?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. I am certain he never lent him them.</p>
               <p>Q. How can you be certain?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. Because it would be against his interest so to do.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he work for you after your husband went away?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. He did.</p>
               <p>Q. How long?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. He work'd for me several weeks after that.</p>
               <p>Q. Is not this a prosecution by way of resentment, on account of his leaving you ?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. No, it is not, it is far from it.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the value of these goods?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. They are of small value, they are not valued at one third of their worth.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he quite quitted your service?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. He had.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he quit your service with or without your consent?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. He gave me no warming, and left my work unfinished.</p>
               <p>Q. How had he behaved in your service?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. He behaved much in the same manner about two years ago. I had not a very great opinion of him.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether during the time he work'd for your husband, there was not a deal of greatness between your husband and the prisoner ?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. Yes, so far as drinking together.</p>
               <p>Q. Had they not used to walk out together on parties of pleasure ?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. Yes, I believe they might two or three times; he earn'd a great deal of money, by<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175705260017"></xptr> which means he could ride when others must walk.</p>
               <p>Q. Did your husband shew him more respect than he did other journeymen?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. He used them all well.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he not discover a greater kindness-towards the prisoner than the other journeymen?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. The other workmen went on parties of pleasure with my husband, as well as the prisoner; but the prisoner might have more money than they.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were the goods found?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. They were found at the prisoner's shop.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not say they were found in the prisoner's lodgings?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. His shop and lodgings are both on one floor; he work'd in the room joining to his bed room.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they concealed or open?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. They were not concealed; he was at work with them.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not there a man that work'd with him, that had work'd with your husband, named Lambert ?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. Yes, there was; at the time the tools were found.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he know the tools ?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. He did very well.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Lambert come and discover it directly, or did he leave the prisoner's service first?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. He left him first.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did Lambert serve his time?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. He served his time with my husband.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had Lambert been gone from you to the prisoner, before he made this discovery?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. He work'd there but about a week or ten days.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of any dispute they had?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. When did Lambert tell you of it?</p>
               <p>M. Pewterers. It was not Lambert that told me; he told one of our journeymen, and he told me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570526-17-person177">
                  Charles 
                  Boucher 
               <interp inst="t17570526-17-person177" type="surname" value="Boucher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-person177" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-person177" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am one of Mrs. Pewterers's journeymen. I and others went in search of these tools, and found them in the possession of the prisoner, in his work shop; I knew them directly.</p>
               <p>Q. What reason did he give for having them in his possession?</p>
               <p>Boucher. He said my master lent him the tools before he went away.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner talk of setting up for himself before your master went away?</p>
               <p>Boucher. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain of that ?</p>
               <p>Boucher. I never heard such a thing mentioned.</p>
               <p>Q. How came he to leave your mistress's service ?</p>
               <p>Boucher. I don't know that.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he work for your mistress after your master was gone away?</p>
               <p>Boucher. He work'd for her three or four weeks after my master went away.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you know whether your mistress and he had any quarrel ?</p>
               <p>Boucher. They had none as I know of.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570526-17-person178">
                  Charles 
                  Lambert 
               <interp inst="t17570526-17-person178" type="surname" value="Lambert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-person178" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-person178" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know these tools to be Mr. 
               <persName id="t17570526-17-person179">
                  George
                   Ebenezer Pewterers
               <interp inst="t17570526-17-person179" type="surname" value="Ebenezer Pewterers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-person179" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-person179" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's property. (The tools produced.)</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutrix. Look at these tools, do you know them ?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. They are my property.</p>
               <p>Q. to Lambert. Did you work with the prisoner at the bar ?</p>
               <p>Lambert. I did work with him a week and 3 days.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to go to work along with him?</p>
               <p>Lambert. I was out of my time, and I had a mind to go to work with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever any conversation with him about the tools?</p>
               <p>Lambert. No, never.</p>
               <p>Q. How came it that you did not tell him they were your mistress's tools ?</p>
               <p>Lambert. There was a man that work'd with him, who said to him, here is a tool that is crack'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Which tool was that?</p>
               <p>Lambert. That tool is not here; he said he bought it, and would have it alter'd. The man answer'd so he might, and it would do very well.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did that tool belong to?</p>
               <p>Lambert. That belongs to my mistress.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutrix. Where is that tool?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. That the prisoner sent home the day after he had the warrant served upon him.</p>
               <p>Q. to Lambert. Why did you not tell him whose tool it was?</p>
               <p>Lambert. I thought my mistress had lent it to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you think so?</p>
               <p>Lambert. Because he used to have more liberty in the shop than any of the other servants.</p>
               <p>Q. What, in your mistress's time?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175705260018"></xptr>Lambert. In my master's time and mistress's too.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he use to follow any separate business in your mistress's time?</p>
               <p>Lambert. He set up about two or three years ago.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say for himself after he was taken up?</p>
               <p>Lambert. He said before justice Fielding his master lent him the tools which he used then.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you say whether your mistress lent him these tools in question now?</p>
               <p>Lambert. No, I can not.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you had any difference with the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Lambert. No, I have not.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to leave him so soon?</p>
               <p>Lambert. He and another man agreed to be partners; they were to give me so much a week, and when I ask'd the prisoner for money, he flew in a passion and bid me go along.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you upon that go and tell Mrs. Pewterers of these things being in his custody?</p>
               <p>Lambert. I did not tell her at all; I told it to Mr. Pearson, and he told her.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutrix. Did not you lend the prisoner the tools yourself, in your husband's time ?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>These tools were lent to me several times, both by Mr. and Mrs. Pewterers.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Conrode Hidcloaff. I remember that when the prisoner work'd with Mr. Pewterers his master used to lend him tools.</p>
               <p>Q. How often have you known him to lend him tools?</p>
               <p>Hidcloaff. Once or twice.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you related to the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Hidcloaff. I am his brother.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the first time you can recollect he lent him tools?</p>
               <p>Hidcloaff. It was about three years ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mrs. Pewterers ever lend him any in the absence of her husband?</p>
               <p>Hidcloaff. She did; I went to her and asked for a tool for my brother, and she lent it me.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Hidcloaff. It was about Christmas last.</p>
               <p>Q. What tool was it Mr. Pewterers lent him?</p>
               <p>Hidcloaff. It was a coffee pot tool.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>Hidcloaff. I am a brasier.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever work for Mr. Pewterers?</p>
               <p>Hidcloaff. I did for about 6 years. I remember my master told him when he lent it him, that he was welcome to what he could spare till business came on again ( business then being very slack) he lent him another tool about the same time.</p>
               <p>Q. What was that?</p>
               <p>Hidcloaff. That was a beck iron.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at the tools produced, whether they are like them ?</p>
               <p>Hidcloaff. These are the same tools; he took them, and brought the beck iron back to me.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutrix. Are you sure you never lent the prisoner any tool?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. I never lent him any tool in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never bid him take a tool?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. No, never.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you heard his brother's evidence?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. I have, and all he says is not true. My husband call'd at his house about three years ago, and saw some of his own tools at his house; he reprimanded him, and desired him to bring them home, which he did; at that time he forgave him, but desired him never to make so free again.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not there an intimacy between your husband and he since that?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. Yes, the same as before at times.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570526-17-person180">
                  John 
                  Wepperman 
               <interp inst="t17570526-17-person180" type="surname" value="Wepperman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-person180" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-person180" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a brasier. I have known the prisoner about twelve years, he has work'd two years with me.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it a common thing in your trade to lend a tool to one another?</p>
               <p>Wepperman. It is.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner's general character?</p>
               <p>Wepperman. So long as I have known him he had a very good character.</p>
               <p>Q. If he was discharg'd now, should you be willing to employ him?</p>
               <p>Wepperman. Yes I should with all my heart.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570526-17-person181">
                  John 
                  Bull 
               <interp inst="t17570526-17-person181" type="surname" value="Bull"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-person181" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-person181" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a brasier.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it a customary thing amongst your trade to lend one another tools ?</p>
               <p>Bull. It is.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175705260019"></xptr>Q. How long have you known the prisoner ?</p>
               <p>Bull. I have known him fifteen years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Bull. He has an exceeding good one, he behaved himself well, and is an exceeding good workman.</p>
               <p>Q. Supposing he should be discharged from this prosecution, and you had an occasion to employ a man, would you employ him?</p>
               <p>Bull. I would.</p>
               <p>Q. What opinion would you have of a man that takes away tools without leave?</p>
               <p>Bull. It is not customary to take tools without leave, but it is not called a crime in the trade.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it customary, at times, to give a general authority, to let a journeyman take a tool if he wants it?</p>
               <p>Bull. When I am not at home I give leave to lend tools, but not to strangers.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570526-17-person182">
                  Christian 
                  Egard 
               <interp inst="t17570526-17-person182" type="surname" value="Egard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-person182" type="given" value="Christian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-person182" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a brasier; I have known the prisoner about five years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Egard. He has a good honest character.</p>
               <p>Q. If he should be discharged, and you had an occasion for a man, would you employ him?</p>
               <p>Egard. I would directly.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570526-17-person183">
                  William 
                  Gesshouse 
               <interp inst="t17570526-17-person183" type="surname" value="Gesshouse"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-person183" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-person183" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him two years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Gesshouse. He has a very good character; he is a very honest industrious man.</p>
               <p>A witness. I have known him about five years; his general character is exceeding good. He is a sober, honest, industrious man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570526-17-person184">
                  John 
                  Dycks 
               <interp inst="t17570526-17-person184" type="surname" value="Dycks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-person184" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-person184" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him four or five years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Dycks. He is a very sober industrious man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570526-17-person185">
                  John 
                  Ring 
               <interp inst="t17570526-17-person185" type="surname" value="Ring"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-person185" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-person185" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him five years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Ring. He is a sober industrious person.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570526-17-person186">
                  Martha 
                  Ford 
               <interp inst="t17570526-17-person186" type="surname" value="Ford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-person186" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-person186" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about two years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>M. Ford. He has as good a character as ever I knew by any man; I have trusted him, and if he had a mind to have rob'd me, he had great opportunities of taking to the value of 20 l.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570526-17-person187">
                  Benjamin 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17570526-17-person187" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-person187" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-person187" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him three years and four months.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Johnson. I took a liking to him as an honest, sober, good man.</p>
               <p>There were two other witnesses appear'd (names not mention'd ) each had known him about five years, and both gave him a good character.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570526-17-verdict90" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570526-17-verdict90" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
