<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17540227-51">
               <interp inst="t17540227-51" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540227-51" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540227-51" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540227"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540227-51" type="date" value="17540227"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540227-51-off269-c377" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540227-51-defend479 t17540227-51-off269 t17540227-51-verdict273"></join>
         
               <p>108. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17540227-51-defend479" type="defendantName">
                     <interp inst="t17540227-51-defend479" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a <rs id="t17540227-51-deflabel268" type="occupation">single woman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540227-51-defend479 t17540227-51-deflabel268"></join>, was indicted for the <rs id="t17540227-51-off269" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540227-51-off269" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540227-51-off269" type="offenceSubcategory" value="infanticide"></interp>
               murder of her female bastard child
            </rs>, <rs id="t17540227-51-cd270" type="crimeDate">Jan. 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540227-51-off269 t17540227-51-cd270"></join>.* </p> 
               <p>John Jones. I live at <placeName id="t17540227-51-crimeloc271">Knightsbridge</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17540227-51-crimeloc271" type="placeName" value="Knightsbridge"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17540227-51-crimeloc271" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540227-51-off269 t17540227-51-crimeloc271"></join>, the prisoner was <rs id="t17540227-51-deflabel272" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540227-51-defend479 t17540227-51-deflabel272"></join> to Dr. Clark who lodged in my house: On the 16th of Jan. about three in the morning. I got up in order to go to brewing; I traced some marks of blood from the kitchen stairs to the necessary house, and seeing much blood there, I put down my lanthorn and candle, and discovered a child lying. I got a chissel and iron crow, and wrenched up the floor, and by the help of a dung hook I got the child up; then I and my servant maid went and washed it at the pump; it was a female child; I observed it lay partly on its back with the head buried in the soil. We could see no cuts, or scars, or marks of violence on it. I then carried it and laid it on a table in the back kitchen, and then sent for Mr. Fisher, a surgeon, and a midwife, who is here to give evidence; they came, and I desired they'd inspect the child to see if there was any thing to be found from whence they might imagine that the child came by its death; they searched it in my sight, and declared they found no marks of violence upon it; it seemed to me to be very near its full time. I thought I had seen children newly born more perfect, there being very little hair on its head, and the nails on its fingers not so big as on newborn children I have seen; it was a small child. By the position the child lay in it might have come from her as she sat on the vault, for the head was downwards, and seemed to be a good deal buried in the soil. I also observed what follows the child lying near its feet, or betwixt the legs, and the navel-string was found to be broke, not cut, about five or six inches from the child's body; a good deal of blood had gone down the vault, more than I perceived any where else.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it drops of blood you had observed on the floor from the stairs?</p>
               <p>Jones. It was rather smear'd blood that seem'd to be done by a woman's bottom of her petticoats, and I am very well assured it was done by a person returning from the vault, for the blood was daubed against the under part of the stairs, which, had it been done by coming down, would have been on the tops of the stairs; I make no doubt but it was done in the return. I went to Dr. Clark and told him what I had seen, and that I thought it was by somebody belonging to him. The prisoner had complained of a purging on her two or three days before this.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any suspicion of the prisoner being big before?</p>
               <p>Jones. No, I had not. My wife went up stairs to the prisoner, and brought down two or three little things for a child, which she said she had been making at different times when her master was out of the way. Produced in court a shirt, some caps, and other things. I had, after this, some talk with my wife, who said it was possible that the child might insensibly slip from her in her pain as she was on the vault, and it is usual for women to want to go to the close-stool oftener at such a Time than usual. She said such accidents had often happened to women where they have had all the help at hand.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Littlewood. I am a midwife, and was sent<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175402270033"></xptr> for upon this occasion on the 16th of January, about six in the morning, I was told how the child was found, and desired to look at it, to see whether it had been thrown in or dropt there accidentally; I observed the navel string to have been broke, I saw no marks of violence on the child; I went up and saw the prisoner, and by examining her found that she had had a child. I asked her if she was married, she said no; my opinion is that the child was at its time. She had a shirt, a cap, and other things for it, which I saw.</p>
               <p>Q Have you heard what Mr. Jones has said as to a conversation with his wife?</p>
               <p>Littlewood. I have, and she is right; such cases often happen to married sober women: a woman who had the same accident sent for me about three months ago. I was satisfied from all I heard or saw, that there was no murder committed in the case.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Clark. When this child was found I went and ask'd the prisoner if she had provided any things for it, and she said I should find some in such a drawer; I went, and taking out a bundle found the little things that have been here produced.</p>

               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540227-51-verdict273" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540227-51-verdict273" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
