<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17590711-6">
               <interp inst="t17590711-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590711-6" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590711-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17590711"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590711-6" type="date" value="17590711"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17590711-6-off32-c54" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590711-6-defend63 t17590711-6-off32 t17590711-6-verdict36"></join>
         
               <p>218. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17590711-6-defend63" type="defendantName">
                     Gilbert 
                     Wright 
                  <interp inst="t17590711-6-defend63" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-6-defend63" type="given" value="Gilbert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-6-defend63" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17590711-6-off32" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590711-6-off32" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-6-off32" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               making an assault upon 
                     
                        <persName id="t17590711-6-victim65" type="victimName">
                           Elizabeth 
                           Larmond 
                        <interp inst="t17590711-6-victim65" type="surname" value="Larmond"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590711-6-victim65" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590711-6-victim65" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590711-6-off32 t17590711-6-victim65"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17590711-6-viclabel33" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590711-6-victim65 t17590711-6-viclabel33"></join>; and against the will of her the said Elizabeth, did ravish and carnally know
            </rs>, <rs id="t17590711-6-cd34" type="crimeDate">June 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590711-6-off32 t17590711-6-cd34"></join>. + </p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590711-6-person66">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Larmond 
               <interp inst="t17590711-6-person66" type="surname" value="Larmond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-6-person66" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-6-person66" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was twelve years of age last January: I live in Drury-lane with my father and mother.</p>
               <p>Q. What business is your father ?</p>
               <p>Larmond. He is a Sword-Cuttler: the prisoner came to Esther Wright's room about two o'clock in the day.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know him before ?</p>
               <p>Larmond. I knew him about four months before; my mother washed for him.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he live?</p>

               <p>Larmond. He lived in Long-Acre, but I do not know at whose house he lodged.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907110006"></xptr>Q. What is his business?</p>
               <p>Larmond. He is a <rs id="t17590711-6-deflabel35" type="occupation">Stay-maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590711-6-defend63 t17590711-6-deflabel35"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does 
               <persName id="t17590711-6-person67">
                  Esther 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17590711-6-person67" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-6-person67" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-6-person67" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             live?</p>
               <p>Larmond. She lives with her father and mother in Drury-lane: her father and mother were gone down to Chatham at the time, and she was alone.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be at that girl's house?</p>
               <p>Larmond. She called Mrs. Larmond, my mother, to come and keep her company; I looked out at the window, and said, my mother was laying down the child to sleep; then she desired me to come and keep her company; I went, and the prisoner was then in the room.</p>
               <p>Q. What room was it?</p>
               <p>Larmond. It was a parlour.</p>
               <p>Q. Were any body else in the room besides the prisoner and 
               <persName id="t17590711-6-person68">
                  Esther 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17590711-6-person68" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-6-person68" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-6-person68" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Larmond. No, nobody else: after I had been a little while in the room he went and lock'd the door, and put the key in his pocket, and shut the windows, and put one hand to my mouth and the other round my back, and throw'd me down on the bed; in struggling I got up, and he took his hand away, and I squalled out, and he clapp'd his hand on my mouth again; I got up again, then he throw'd me down a third time and ravished me.</p>
               <p>Q. Tell what he did to you?</p>
               <p>Larmond. He gave me the foul disease; I am ashamed to mention what he did; - he put his private parts into mine.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the other young woman do at the time ?</p>
               <p>Larmond. She ran out to call my mother.</p>
               <p>Q. How did she get out, you say he had lock'd the door?</p>
               <p>Larmond. She said, 
               <persName id="t17590711-6-person69">
                  Gilbert 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17590711-6-person69" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-6-person69" type="given" value="Gilbert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-6-person69" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , if you will not give me the key, I'll call out at the window to the neighbours, and call them in; then he took and throw'd the key on the bed.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you stay in the room?</p>
               <p>Larmond. I went away directly.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the other girl get any assistance ?</p>
               <p>Larmond. No, she was so much ashamed she went and look'd out at the window.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was you in the room in the whole?</p>
               <p>Larmond. I do not think I was above half an hour in the room.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you get out of the room?</p>
               <p>Larmond. The door was open: he had given 
               <persName id="t17590711-6-person70">
                  Esther 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17590711-6-person70" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-6-person70" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-6-person70" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the key, when she said, she would call out to the neighbours.</p>
               <p>Q. When did she say to him she would call out?</p>
               <p>Larmond. That was when he was going to use me so.</p>
               <p>Q. And did she go to call the neighbours?</p>
               <p>Larmond. Yes: she went to call the neighbours at one house in our yard.</p>
               <p>Q. And did she leave the door open?</p>
               <p>Larmond. She did: but she came in again and shut it; then she went to the window, and open'd the window and call'd, and after I could get liberty I went out at the door.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell your mother of it when you got home?</p>
               <p>Larmond. No, I was asham'd, and I was affrighted; for when she finds any thing amiss she is ready to kill me.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you tell of it?</p>
               <p>Larmond. I never told any body of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your mother at home when you went home?</p>
               <p>Larmond. She was.</p>
               <p>Q. How came it to be known?</p>
               <p>Larmond. On the Sunday morning my mother found it out when I went to clean myself, she was looking over the dirty linnen and found it out.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. Did I not go from 
               <persName id="t17590711-6-person71">
                  Esther 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17590711-6-person71" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-6-person71" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-6-person71" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's to your mother's room?</p>
               <p>Larmond. You did.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. Had we any beer at your mother's?</p>
               <p>Larmond. You drank a full pot of beer with my mother.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was this after you got home?</p>
               <p>Larmond. It was not long after: he came up stairs to my mother when I was in the room, and sent for the full pot; he said, he was going away to his club, and did not stay long.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he stay in the whole?</p>
               <p>Larmond. He stay'd from two o'clock 'till six at night at Wright's house and ours.</p>
               <p>Q. At which house was he longest?</p>
               <p>Larmond. He was longest at Wright's than at our house; he struggled with 
               <persName id="t17590711-6-person72">
                  Esther 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17590711-6-person72" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-6-person72" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-6-person72" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a long while.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907110007"></xptr>Q. Had he use to come often there?</p>
               <p>Larmond. He did: to see his uncle and aunt; her father is his uncle.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had her father and mother been gone out?</p>
               <p>Larmond. This was Tuesday, and they went out the day before.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he use to come there to see her when they were out?</p>
               <p>Larmond. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever been in his company there before?</p>
               <p>Larmond. I have been often in company with him there, and Mr Wright and his wife.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you ever with him at any other place?</p>
               <p>Larmond. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you ever at his lodgings?</p>
               <p>Larmond. No: I have only been with him at my mother's and Mr. Wright's.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590711-6-person73">
                  Esther 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17590711-6-person73" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-6-person73" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-6-person73" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner laid me down three or four times on the bed and used me very ill.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Wright. This was on Whit-Tuesday; he never came to our house when my father and mother were not at home but on that day. I began to squeal out and had a handle-knife in my hand; I said, I would stick the knife through him if he would not let me get up; then he let me get up, and I call'd Mrs. Larmond; her daughter said, she was gone to bed.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he lock'd the door upon you before the girl came in?</p>
               <p>Wright. He had.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. They were both in the room together when I went in.</p>
               <p>Wright. 
               <persName id="t17590711-6-person74">
                  Betty 
                  Larmond 
               <interp inst="t17590711-6-person74" type="surname" value="Larmond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-6-person74" type="given" value="Betty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-6-person74" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said, what do you want; I said, is your mother at home, I should be glad of her company; she said, she is laid down; I said, will you come over; she came directly, and was better than a quarter of an hour in the room; he took and laid her down on the bed, and with struggling she got up twice; he laid her down again; then I said, Gilbert, if you will not give me the key I'll cry out murder; I opened the window and began to cry out, but I got the key from him in struggling with him, as he had the child on the bed; he had got his elbow on the child's breast, and his hand on her mouth, and he gave me the key with his other hand; he then said, if I do not get my ds of you, I will on the other. I open'd the door and went out and left it open; I went up and knock'd at Mrs Larmond's door and found that she was lock'd in, the girl having the key of her mother's room in her pocket; then I came back into the room again, and went and look'd out of the window; and said, Gilbert, Why do not you get off of Betty. He never spoke a word; I was quite ashamed to stay in the room, never seeing such a thing before, I began to call out; then I was going to go out, and he call'd me to come in; then I said, Now you are got off. I wanted to go for some small-beer; then he wanted to lay the girl down on the bed again; when I came back again, the girl and I ran out at the door; I said, for God's sake, call Mrs Hunter in; (that is one of our neighbours) he went out I believe about a quarter of an hour after that; the girl went up into her mother's room directly; when I came back with the small-beer, I contrived to get Gilbert out of the room; and said, Mrs Larmond wants to speak with you; he said, she did not; I made him go out of the room, and he went up there; then I lock'd my own door, fearing he should come over again; after that I went up to Mrs Larmond's room, and she was sent for out to a neighbour that was dying; then I went back to my room again.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Where you not both in the room when I came in?</p>
               <p>Wright. No, we were not; there was nobody but myself in the room when he came first in.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. She never went out of the room while I was there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590711-6-person75">
                  Mary 
                  Larmond 
               <interp inst="t17590711-6-person75" type="surname" value="Larmond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-6-person75" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-6-person75" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am mother to the girl, the first witness; when I was shifting her on Sunday, I said, Betty, my good God, what is this on your shift; come tell me, or I'll be your death; she said, Mother do not strike me, and I'll tell you; I took and turn'd her up on the bed, and saw what a condition she was in; her father came in at the time; then she told me how the prisoner had used her.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907110008"></xptr>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>This is all done out of spight against me. That is my own cousin that swears against me. I know nothing about what they say.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mr Waite. I live in White-Hart yard, Catharine-street, I am a Stay-maker; the prisoner at the bar worked for me from Christmas last 'till he was taken up.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character?</p>
               <p>Waite. I never knew any ill of him; he is one of the quietest, inoffensive, fellows I ever employed; I never had the least suspicion of him of any thing of this sort; he has always behav'd well and industrious; I never heard an ill word come out of his mouth.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590711-6-person76">
                  John 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17590711-6-person76" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-6-person76" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-6-person76" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about three months.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Davis. I keep a Public-house, the Golden-Anchor, in Feathers-Court, Drury-lane, a House of Call for Stay-makers. The prisoner used my house, he always behaved himself very sober and very careful, and paid me for what he had.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17590711-6-verdict36" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590711-6-verdict36" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
