<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17590711-27">
               <interp inst="t17590711-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590711-27" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590711-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17590711"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590711-27" type="date" value="17590711"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17590711-27-off157-c188" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590711-27-defend238 t17590711-27-off157 t17590711-27-verdict159"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17590711-27-off157-c189" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590711-27-defend240 t17590711-27-off157 t17590711-27-verdict159"></join>
         
               <p>240, 241. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17590711-27-defend238" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17590711-27-defend238" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-defend238" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-defend238" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17590711-27-deflabel156" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590711-27-defend238 t17590711-27-deflabel156"></join>; and 
               
                  <persName id="t17590711-27-defend240" type="defendantName">
                     Francis 
                     Hemsworth 
                  <interp inst="t17590711-27-defend240" type="surname" value="Hemsworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-defend240" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-defend240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17590711-27-off157" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-off157" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-off157" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               that at the last sessions, 
                     <persName id="t17590711-27-person241">
                        John 
                        Guest 
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-person241" type="surname" value="Guest"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590711-27-person241" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590711-27-person241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , 
                     <persName id="t17590711-27-person242">
                        Thomas 
                        Henfield 
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-person242" type="surname" value="Henfield"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590711-27-person242" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590711-27-person242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , and 
                     <persName id="t17590711-27-person243">
                        Peter 
                        Mason 
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-person243" type="surname" value="Mason"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590711-27-person243" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590711-27-person243" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , were tried and capitally convicted for stealing 1100 weight of lead from the parish-church of Stepney. They the said 
                     <persName id="t17590711-27-person244">
                        Mary 
                        Smith 
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-person244" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590711-27-person244" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590711-27-person244" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   and 
                     <persName id="t17590711-27-person245">
                        Francis 
                        Hemsworth 
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-person245" type="surname" value="Hemsworth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590711-27-person245" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590711-27-person245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , the same lead so stolen, did receive and have, well knowing it to have been stolen
            </rs>, <rs id="t17590711-27-cd158" type="crimeDate">March 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590711-27-off157 t17590711-27-cd158"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>The record of the trial, and conviction, of 
               <persName id="t17590711-27-person246">
                  John 
                  Guest 
               <interp inst="t17590711-27-person246" type="surname" value="Guest"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-person246" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-person246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17590711-27-person247">
                  Thomas 
                  Henfield 
               <interp inst="t17590711-27-person247" type="surname" value="Henfield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-person247" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17590711-27-person248">
                  Peter 
                  Mason 
               <interp inst="t17590711-27-person248" type="surname" value="Mason"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-person248" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , read in court, wherein the Jury for our Lord the King, upon their oath, present that they were found guilty, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590711-27-person249">
                  James 
                  How 
               <interp inst="t17590711-27-person249" type="surname" value="How"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-person249" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-person249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mr Darking: he is one of Church-Wardens of Stepney Parish. After the church had a second time been robbed I was in Bishopsgate-street.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after the second time the church had been robbed?</p>
               <p>How. The church was robbed on the Wednesday, and I saw the lead on the Friday in Bishopsgate-street.</p>
               <p>Q. What day of the month was the Friday?</p>
               <p>How. That was on the 23d of March: it was in a sand-cart.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day?</p>
               <p>How. It was a little after five in the morning: near the Green-Dragon Inn-door: but when I came back again, after I had been and loaded a cart with dung, then at seven o'clock I saw the cart standing opposite to Mrs Smith's door. I was going by and looked into the cart, and saw it to be sheet-lead, and I had a thought in myself that it was some of Stepney church lead.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any thing over it to conceal it?</p>
               <p>How. There was a little litter and dung-like stuff over it, and the litter had fallen down between it, so that I could see part of the lead; and it being in a sand-cart, made me suspect it to have been stolen. I went home and told my mistress, and she acquainted my master of it, and he came to Mrs Smith's house.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was it you saw this lead in a sand cart by Mrs Smith's door?</p>
               <p>How. It was about seven o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Were not all the shops in the street open?</p>
               <p>How. I can't tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it so openly to be seen that any body by looking into the cart might see it?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907110028"></xptr>How. Any body might see it if they thought proper to look.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it not publickly standing at the door?</p>
               <p>How. It was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it broad day-light?</p>
               <p>How. It was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Mrs Smith's shop open or not?</p>

               <p>How. I cannot tell whether it was or not.</p>
               <p>Q. Some time after this, did not you go with Mr Hemsworth and one of my Lord-Mayor's officers, to look after the men he bought this lead of?</p>
               <p>How. I did: we went to Clerkenwell to examine the man. Mr Hemsworth said, the man had made a mistake in the receipt.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the man you went after?</p>

               <p>How. No: I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you propose to go and see if you could find the two men?</p>
               <p>How. He proposed to go and see for the men, and said, he had made a mistake in the receipt.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr Hemsworth ever advise the men to run away?</p>
               <p>How. No: he bid us go to a publick-house, and said, he would go and see for the men, and then he would come to us.</p>
               <p>Q. Who do you mean?</p>
               <p>How. I mean Child and Guest.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>How. This was on the Saturday, that is, the day after I had seen the lead.</p>
               <p>Q. Who proposed to you to go to see for Guest and Child?</p>
               <p>How. Mr Hemsworth did.</p>
               <p>Q. If he had been desirous that they should have made their escape, would it have been proper to have taken you along with him?</p>
               <p>How. I can't tell that. I don't know what he had in his head; we did not all go into the house together, where one or both were: he bid us go to the publick-house.</p>
               <p>Q. And what was to be done then?</p>
               <p>How. He was to bring Guest and Child to us; he said so; he did not bring them; he said, the man was putting on his coat, and he would soon come to us.</p>
               <p>Q. Was one of my Lord-Mayor's officers with you?</p>
               <p>How. He was.</p>
               <p>Q. How near that house was you?</p>
               <p>How. We went just by the door, and Mr Hemsworth went in and spoke to the man.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him speak to him?</p>
               <p>How. No.</p>

               <p>Counsel for Crown. Where did Mr Hemsworth carry you first of all?</p>
               <p>How. From Mrs Smith's house to Justice Ives's in Spittal-Fields.</p>
               <p>Counsel for Crown. What did you go there for?</p>
               <p>How. To have the warrant backed in Middlesex.</p>
               <p>Counsel for Crown. Where did you go next?</p>
               <p>How. Then we went to Clerkenwell.</p>
               <p>Counsel for Crown. Did not you hear my Lord-Mayor's officer ask him, how he came to carry you about so?</p>
               <p>How. No: I did not.</p>
               <p>Counsel for Prisoners. You say Mr Hemsworth saw the man, how came you not to see him?</p>
               <p>How. He bid us go to a publick-house and call for a tankard of beer, and he went into that house by himself.</p>
               <p>Counsel for Prisoners. What opposition did he make to your going? did he say he would not let you go into that house?</p>
               <p>How. He said, the man was putting his coat on, and he would be there presently.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the agreement (before you came to the house) between the officer, Hemsworth, and you, that you should go to a publick-house, and he should bring the people to you?</p>
               <p>How. No: we made no agreement about it. I thought he would have brought them to us.</p>
               <p>Q. For what purpose did he propose to find out Guest and Child?</p>
               <p>How. He proposed to find them out, he said, they had made a mistake in the receipt that was wrote.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you the lead was brought to his mistress's house by them?</p>
               <p>How. He did.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907110029"></xptr>Q. Did he go to find them out in order to prove from whence they had that lead?</p>
               <p>How. Yes: he said, he would bring them to us.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you he had seen them?</p>
               <p>How. He did.</p>
               <p>Counsel for Crown. Did he bring them?</p>
               <p>How. No: but he told us they would come.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he wait there expecting they would come?</p>
               <p>How. He did. We stay'd there some time and drank a tankard of beer; and then he said he thought they would not come: this was after we had been there half an hour.</p>
               <p>Counsel for Crown. Did he propose your going into that house?</p>
               <p>How. No.</p>
               <p>Counsel for Prisoners. Did he object to your going there?</p>

               <p>How. Yes.</p>
               <p>Counsel for Prisoners. What were his words?</p>
               <p>How. He bid us go to the publick-house and call for a tankard of beer.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is the Green Dragon from Mrs Smith's house?</p>
               <p>How. It is about a hundred yards distance; it is in the same street: I never measured the ground.</p>
               <p>Jos. Darking. I am one of the church-wardens of the parish of Stepney. On the twenty-third of March last I was just come home from the church, and my wife told me, that this witness, How, had told her, he had seen some lead at Mrs Smith's shop in Bishopsgate-street, that he suspected to be the lead that was stolen from off our church. I went there directly, and gave a little knock at the door; nobody coming, I opened it and went in, and asked for Mrs Smith. I went to the counting-house door; there was Mrs Smith. I believe she came up stairs; but I am not sure she came up stairs or down. I still kept going farther up into the shop. I said, I am informed you have bought some lead which was brought in a sand-cart this morning. I am church-warden at Stepney, and our church has been robbed, and I desire to see it. A little farther lay some lead. I said, this is it, She said, this is gutter-lead. I asked her, who she bought it of; she said, she bought it of some Carpenters that were pulling down some old houses, which she said was very often the case. Said I, I am in the building way, and I know it is not gutter-lead, for it is flat lead; and I believed it to be the same lead that came off Stepney church.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it obvious to every discerning eye to know, that was not gutter-lead?</p>
               <p>Darking. To a Plumber it was.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you know it by?</p>
               <p>Darking. I knew it by the spikes that were in it.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>Darking. I am a Bricklayer. After I told her, it was the lead that came off Stepney church. I said, pray, who did you buy it off? She said, the persons names were 
               <persName id="t17590711-27-person250">
                  John 
                  Child 
               <interp inst="t17590711-27-person250" type="surname" value="Child"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-person250" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-person250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17590711-27-person251">
                  John 
                  Guest 
               <interp inst="t17590711-27-person251" type="surname" value="Guest"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-person251" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and shew'd me the receipt for the money which she paid them. I asked her, whether she had bought any lead of them before? And told her, we had lost such a quantity of lead from off the church about three weeks before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you mention the quantity?</p>
               <p>Darking. I did; about 900 weight and upwards.</p>
               <p>Q. What was her answer?</p>
               <p>Darking. She said, she believed she had bought it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say this without any hesitation ?</p>
               <p>Darking. She was seemingly in a flutter. She told me very freely, she believed she had bought it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ask her, or did she tell you she had bought this of the same persons whom she bought the other of.</p>
               <p>Darking. She did not; nor I did not ask her that question, as she had told me she had bought such a quantity.</p>
               <p>Q. When she was before the alderman did she say the same?</p>
               <p>Darking. I believe she was ask'd the question, but I will not be positive.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you advertise the first robbery?</p>
               <p>Darking. We did three times in the Daily Advertiser, Feb. the 9th, and March the 11th, were two of the days; I can't particularly tell the other.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907110030"></xptr>Q. Did you advertise any reward on the discovery ?</p>
               <p>Darking. We did.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. When you first came to Mrs Smith's, you say, you asked for her?</p>
               <p>Darking. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she appear?</p>
               <p>Darking. She did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she, when you ask'd her if she had bought lead that came there that morning in a sand-cart, own she had bought th at?</p>
               <p>Darking. She did without hesitation.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find at that time she was any way wavering?</p>
               <p>Darking. No; I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Were not Child and Guest Carpenters?</p>
               <p>Darking. Child was a Weaver, and Guest was a Carpenter.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you hear Child had been in another business?</p>
               <p>Darking. I have heard he kept a Broker's shop.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she describe them, or tell you their names ?</p>
               <p>Darking. She told me their names; 
               <persName id="t17590711-27-person252">
                  John 
                  Child 
               <interp inst="t17590711-27-person252" type="surname" value="Child"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-person252" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17590711-27-person253">
                  John 
                  Guest 
               <interp inst="t17590711-27-person253" type="surname" value="Guest"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-person253" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-person253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; and told me where they lived; and shewed me the receipt without asking for it.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was it wrote by?</p>
               <p>Darking. It was wrote by Mr Hemsworth.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did she say those persons lived.</p>
               <p>Darking. She said some were in Old-street. Then I went immediately away to Mr Alderman Cokayne.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the lead in very large pieces?</p>
               <p>Darking. It was flat and cut, and thrown all in a heap, and some other lead mixed amongst it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at Mrs Smith's a second time?</p>
               <p>Darking. I was: then there was one Mr Walker there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she give open and free answers to all your questions ?</p>
               <p>Darking. She did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she do the same before the Alderman?</p>
               <p>Darking. That you may ask the Alderman. I was not by all the time.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this receipt - (he takes one in his hand.)</p>
               <p>Darking. This is the receipt which Mrs Smith produced to me. I believe Mr Hemsworth said, if I would go along with him to one Mr 
               <persName id="t17590711-27-person254">
                  Johnson
               <interp inst="t17590711-27-person254" type="given" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-person254" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a Weaver, he said, he belived he could give a good character of Child; and so said Mrs Smith; and Mr Hemsworth went with me to him.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a character did Mr Johnson give him?</p>
               <p>Darking. He said, he had known him six or seven years ago, but could not tell where he lived then, for he had-not worked for him a great while.</p>
               <p>Q. When was Mrs Smith first accused?</p>
               <p>Darking. I cannot tell the day of the month.</p>
               <p>Q. When was Mr Hemsworth first accused?</p>
               <p>Darking. He was not accused 'till after the prisoners were brought to London.</p>
               <p>Q. How came Hemsworth first to be accused, and where?</p>
               <p>Darking. It was by the evidence Child's swearing against him at justice Feilding's; but I was not there.</p>
               <p>Counsel for Crown. When Hemsworth said the persons of whom this lead had been bought lived at such a place, did you find that information to be true or false?</p>
               <p>Darking. I found it to be false.</p>
               <p>Counsel for Prisoners. Did you find they had lived there?</p>
               <p>Darking. They had lived there: they had lived in eight or nine different places. I went with him all the way up Chick-lane, and could not find them.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you since learned that they had lived there?</p>
               <p>Darking. Yes; but not at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you hear that they did live there?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907110031"></xptr>Darking. Somebody told me so, but I do not know who it was.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any reason to believe, that at the time Mr Hemsworth told you those persons lived there, that he himself knew to the contrary of what he had told you?</p>
               <p>Darking. That is too deep a matter to be entered into by me. I cannot tell what he thought.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you did not find, (by enquiring at that very place where Hemsworth said he lived, and the neighbours said he had lived,) the place where he then lived?</p>
               <p>Darking. I did not hear where he lived that day.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not at that place find out where they lived?</p>
               <p>Darking. No; not at that place.</p>

               <p>Q. Whether you did not, by means of the information you received by Hemsworth, find where they lived?</p>
               <p>Darking. No; I did not at that time; nor no other time.</p>
               <p>Q. Then how came you to find them out?</p>
               <p>Darking. By the rest of the gentlemen going. Mr Hemsworth and I went and we could not find them out.</p>
               <p>Q. from Hemsworth. Whether or no we did not get a direction from Mr Johnson.</p>
               <p>Darking. Yes. But we could not find them by that direction.</p>
               <p>Hemsworth. Mr Johnson gave us the direction out of his book; Child having work'd for him: did not we see a man at the place, who said, Child did live there but was removed?</p>
               <p>Darking. That is very true, but we did not find him by that.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell how they were found out?</p>
               <p>Darking. No; I went no farther with them in their inquiry after them, than the first day.</p>
               <p>Q. What did Johnson say, when Hemsworth brought you there?</p>
               <p>Darking. He said Child had work'd for him, four, five, or six years ago; and that he had lived at such and such places; but the man that wrote us the note, told us he could not be certain that he could direct us to him.</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. On the twenty-third of March Mr Darking applyed to me, and said, he had found some lead at Mrs Smith's, a Plumber, in Bishopsgate-street, that he suspected to have been stolen from off Stepney church: I went, and saw the lead, and saw it weighed: I sent for Mr Walker, for his opinion of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mrs Smith insist upon it's being gutter-lead ?</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. No; she did not to me.</p>

               <p>Q. What was the conversation you had with her?</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. It was about who she bought it of, and what she gave for it: she shew'd me her receipt, I think it was to this purport.</p>
               <p>Mrs Smith debtor to 
               <persName id="t17590711-27-person255">
                  John 
                  Child 
               <interp inst="t17590711-27-person255" type="surname" value="Child"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-person255" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-person255" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , for eleven-hundred and one quarter of lead, at twelve shillings per hundred; six pounds, fifteen shillings.</p>
               <p>Receiv'd the contents in full.</p>
               <p>Sign'd with the mark of 
               <persName id="t17590711-27-person256">
                  John 
                  Child 
               <interp inst="t17590711-27-person256" type="surname" value="Child"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-person256" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-person256" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Mr Darking having said they had lost about nine-hundred pounds weight of lead, from off Stepney church before; she said she had bought lead of that same Child before, but could not find the receipt.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she answer freely ?</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. She did, very freely: I told her it would be necessary she should produce this said 
               <persName id="t17590711-27-person257">
                  John 
                  Child 
               <interp inst="t17590711-27-person257" type="surname" value="Child"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-person257" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-person257" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            : she said she was very sorry, and that she believed it was the lead that came from Stepney church.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this at your first discourse with her?</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. No, this was upon our examining the pieces of lead; and finding the nails in it, then she was of the same opinion that I was of.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Mr Walker there, then?</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. Yes, he was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she mention where the man lived?</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. She did mention some where in Chick-lane: I said, she ought to have<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175907110032"></xptr> known this man before she had bought this lead of him: she said, she took him to be a very honest man.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say what business he carried on?</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. She said, he kept a Broker's shop: then they got a warrant, and got it back'd, and went immediately in search of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she mention any thing of Guest?</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. No, she said nothing about him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she speak about the place of Child's residence, as if she was certain of it?</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. No, she did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you had any application to you, from either of the prisoners at the bar, in order to stop this prosecution?</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. No, none at all to me.</p>
               <p>Q. At the Vestry, at Stepney, were there ever any application made of that sort ?</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. There was some application made.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at that Vestry ?</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the application?</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. There was a proposal to put the lead in the same state as it was, provided the prosecution be dropp'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was this made by?</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. This was made by Mrs Smith.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the lead correspond, when weighed, with the receipt?</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. It did.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you say, at that time, you thought she had bought it, knowing it to have been stolen ?</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. I cannot say that I had?</p>
               <p>Q. Do you recollect you made use of such an expression: (it seemed to be a fair bargain.)</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. It was pretty near it, it was within a shilling per hundred weight: Mr Walker told me, he would have given me thirteen-shillings per hundred.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you suppose a credible house-keeper would buy stolen lead, knowing it to be so, for saving one thirteenth part.</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. No, I cannot suppose it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you then make her enter into recognizance?</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Cannot you easily conceive, that a person would rather put as much more lead on a place, rather than to come here to be tried for it?</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. I should easily conceive that.</p>
               <p>Q. Should you, from thence, imagine that the person acknowledged to have received it, knowing it to have been stolen?</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. No, I should not, by that, imagine any such thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Hemsworth attend at the Vestry ?</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Who attended there, for Mrs Smith?</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. She attended personally.</p>
               <p>Q. Supposing you yourself in the situation she was, by buying this lead, under these circumstances, as it appeared to her, when you had examined into it, would not you have proposed to have restated the lead, rather than be brought to a Court about it?</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. I should indeed.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known Mrs Smith?</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. I have known her twenty years, she lived in our neighbourhood.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her character?</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. I never heard any thing ill of her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear she was suspected of buying stolen goods?</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Hemsworth?</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. I do, I have known him a long time.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character?</p>
               <p>Mr Alderman Cokayne. I never heard any ill of him.</p>
               <p>The Court did not think it necessary to call upon the prisoners for their defence; but told them it was an inadvertent act in buying lead of such persons, of whom they had so slender a knowledge; and directed the Jury to acquit them, without summing up the evidence.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17590711-27-verdict159" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-verdict159" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590711-27-verdict159" type="verdictSubcategory" value="directed"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
