<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17591024-25">
               <interp inst="t17591024-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591024-25" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591024-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17591024"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591024-25" type="date" value="17591024"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17591024-25-off125-c245" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591024-25-defend292 t17591024-25-off125 t17591024-25-verdict128"></join>
         
               <p>326. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17591024-25-defend292" type="defendantName">
                     Grace 
                     Haseldine 
                  <interp inst="t17591024-25-defend292" type="surname" value="Haseldine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-25-defend292" type="given" value="Grace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-25-defend292" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17591024-25-deflabel124" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591024-25-defend292 t17591024-25-deflabel124"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17591024-25-off125" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17591024-25-off125" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-25-off125" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one silver spoon, value 5 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17591024-25-victim294" type="victimName">
                     Dennis 
                     Murphy 
                  <interp inst="t17591024-25-victim294" type="surname" value="Murphy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-25-victim294" type="given" value="Dennis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-25-victim294" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591024-25-off125 t17591024-25-victim294"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17591024-25-cd126" type="crimeDate">Oct. 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591024-25-off125 t17591024-25-cd126"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591024-25-person295">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Murphy 
               <interp inst="t17591024-25-person295" type="surname" value="Murphy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-25-person295" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-25-person295" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My husband's name is Dennis; we live in <placeName id="t17591024-25-crimeloc127">Castle-court in the Butcher-row</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17591024-25-crimeloc127" type="placeName" value="Castle-court in the Butcher-row"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17591024-25-crimeloc127" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591024-25-off125 t17591024-25-crimeloc127"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Murphy. I have known her some time; I believe, about four or five years?</p>
               <p>Q. Where does she live.</p>
               <p>Murphy. She lives any where were she can. about the fifth of October, I happened to be out when the prisoner came in; I was fetched home; she having asked for me: when I came home, I saw her in my parlour; she told me she was come to drink a dish of tea with me.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you any acquaintance of her's?</p>
               <p>Murphy. No farther than seeing of her.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you never in her company before?</p>
               <p>Murphy. Never in my life. I have seen her in the street, and she has come to my father; but I never eat nor drank with her in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does your father live?</p>
               <p>Murphy. He lives in the Butcher-row.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she call upon you for?</p>
               <p>Murphy. She called upon me, to ask me how I did.</p>
               <p>Q. How does she get her living?</p>
               <p>Murphy. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ask her to stay to tea?</p>
               <p>Murphy. No.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner do?</p>
               <p>Murphy. I saw her put her hand into the beaufet and take out a spoon; she put it first under her cloak, and then put it into her pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do, when you saw her take the spoon?</p>
               <p>Murphy. Then I desired her to stay.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you send for a constable?</p>
               <p>Murphy. No, I did not; she went out at the door, and up the court, and I desired Mrs Crookshanks to go after her, that I might have time to fetch my husband, least she should be gone out of sight.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you fetch your husband?</p>
               <p>Murphy. He came, and ran after her, and Mrs Crookshanks brought her back.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you when she came back?</p>
               <p>Murphy. I was in the house then; I then charged her.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say upon that?</p>
               <p>Murphy. She said, D - n me, she would stand search; and asked me, If I thought she had the spoon; I told her, That I knew she had it; we took her to Justice Fielding; the spoon was found in the hands of Mr Gaull; he will give an account how he came by it: she said there, If she was transported, she would have the spoon with her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591024-25-person296">
                  Mary 
                  Crookshanks 
               <interp inst="t17591024-25-person296" type="surname" value="Crookshanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-25-person296" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-25-person296" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was asked to drink tea with Mrs Murphy; the prisoner was there when I came into the parlour.</p>
               <p>Q. Who else were there?</p>
               <p>Crookshanks. There were Mrs Murphy and her aunt; the tea things were set, and tea going to be put into the pot.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you invited to drink tea there?</p>
               <p>Crookshanks. I went in as usual, and then she asked me, If I would not drink tea; after a little time, Mrs Murphy said, Where is my spoon? I miss it; she said to the prisoner, Have you got it? having been sitting, when I came into the room, by the beaufet, in a low chair, not by the tea-table.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was Mrs Murphy at that time she asked for the spoon?</p>
               <p>Crookshanks. She was standing up, by the table, and her aunt was putting the tea into the pot, with her back to the beaufet; after that Mrs Murphy said, Haseldine, you shall stay; she answered, She would not; Mrs Murphy said, You shall; for I saw you take my spoon just now, out of the beaufet. Mrs Murphy went to her husband, and I went after the prisoner, and stopped her just by the Black-horse; her husband and another man came after me, and they brought the prisoner back: I first laid my hands on the skirts of her gown, and said, Haseldine, You shall come back.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know her before?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175910240038"></xptr>Crookshanks. I did, and Mrs Murphy. I live in the neighbourhood; she once lived servant at the 
               <persName id="t17591024-25-person297">
                  Robin 
                  Hood 
               <interp inst="t17591024-25-person297" type="surname" value="Hood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-25-person297" type="given" value="Robin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-25-person297" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , just by.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she ever drink tea at your house?</p>
               <p>Crookshanks. No. When Mrs Murphy came up, she d - d and swore that she had not the spoon, and began to strip herself; she was carried to Justice Fielding's; when she was up at the bar, Mr Gaull went up to the prisoner, I saw her put the spoon out of her hand into his hand; then he shewed it directly: then Justice Fielding asked her, If she brought it as a present. She then made him a pretty answer, and a D - n in the bargain.</p>
               <p>- Gaull. I am servant to the keeper of New-prison, and attend at Justice Fielding's; I was by when the prisoner was brought up; I was just opening the door in the office, and she came into the passage and put a silver spoon into my hand directly; she had been in New-prison and knew me, and thought she could put confidence in me; I went and told Justice Fielding of it. The spoon produced in court, and deposed to. There are A B and A D upon it. When the prisoner was brought to the bar, she said, She knew nothing of it; I having before told Justice Fielding of it, then I was sworn.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I lived some years at the 
               <persName id="t17591024-25-person298">
                  Robin 
                  Hood 
               <interp inst="t17591024-25-person298" type="surname" value="Hood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-25-person298" type="given" value="Robin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591024-25-person298" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in the Butcher-row; her father and mother did not lie together for four or five years. I was his bedfellow for eight years; his companion in his naked bed. I have witness in court that he once put me for twenty-seven weeks in the Poultry Compter; they said they would either hang or transport me one time or another; that is the way that she came to know me; she has known me this twenty years, as I lived in the neighbourhood; she knows that her father has been the ruin of me; it is nothing but spite; they want me out of the world: I have disgraced all my friends by my own misconduct.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17591024-25-verdict128" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17591024-25-verdict128" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17591024-25-punish129" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17591024-25-punish129" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591024-25-defend292 t17591024-25-punish129"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
