<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17580113-27">
               <interp inst="t17580113-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580113-27" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580113-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17580113"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17580113-27" type="date" value="17580113"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580113-27-off162-c263" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-27-defend314 t17580113-27-off162 t17580113-27-verdict165"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580113-27-off162-c264" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-27-defend316 t17580113-27-off162 t17580113-27-verdict165"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17580113-27-off162-c265" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-27-defend318 t17580113-27-off162 t17580113-27-verdict165"></join>
         
               <p>90, 91, 92. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17580113-27-defend314" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Morgan 
                  <interp inst="t17580113-27-defend314" type="surname" value="Morgan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-27-defend314" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-27-defend314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17580113-27-defend316" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Newton 
                  <interp inst="t17580113-27-defend316" type="surname" value="Newton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-27-defend316" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-27-defend316" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17580113-27-defend318" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Parsons 
                  <interp inst="t17580113-27-defend318" type="surname" value="Parsons"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-27-defend318" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-27-defend318" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for a <rs id="t17580113-27-off162" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580113-27-off162" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-27-off162" type="offenceSubcategory" value="fraud"></interp>
               conspiracy, in obtaining divers goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17580113-27-victim320" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Townsend 
                        <interp inst="t17580113-27-victim320" type="surname" value="Townsend"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580113-27-victim320" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17580113-27-victim320" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-27-off162 t17580113-27-victim320"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , by false pretences, with intent to cheat and defraud him of the said goods
            </rs>, <rs id="t17580113-27-cd163" type="crimeDate">November 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-27-off162 t17580113-27-cd163"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-27-person321">
                  Richard 
                  Townsend 
               <interp inst="t17580113-27-person321" type="surname" value="Townsend"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-27-person321" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-27-person321" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an <rs id="t17580113-27-viclabel164" type="occupation">ironmonger</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17580113-27-victim320 t17580113-27-viclabel164"></join>, and live in Gracechurch-Street. On Sunday the 27th of November last, in the morning, the prisoner Morgan came to me, and desired to know if I could supply him with such and such goods, which he said he had an order for from the country, and he could not supply them so cheap as I could.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of goods were they?</p>
               <p>Townsend. They were edge tools, and are set forth in the indictment, which goods I told him I had, and he desired I would fix the price to them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you look out the goods for him?</p>
               <p>Townsend. I did; here is the bill of parcels with the prices of each article. ( Producing it.)</p>
               <p>Q. Did he agree to give you your price?</p>
               <p>Townsend. He did; he made no objections.</p>
               <p>Q. Who wrote the bill of parcels?</p>
               <p>Townsend. This is my servant's hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he deal for those goods?</p>
               <p>Townsend. He was to send for them the next day, and to pay ready money for them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know him before?</p>
               <p>Townsend. I have known him some years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is he?</p>
               <p>Townsend He is an edge-tool maker. The next morning a man came for them, and said he was come for the goods that Mr. Morgan bespoke the day before, and that he had left the note behind him. I said, if you have not brought the note, you must go back again. He went away, and came again a second time, and brought a note. I set my servant to look the goods out directly, he look'd out the goods, made the bill of parcels, and pack'd them ready for going away. A friend of mine coming in, and seeing a bill of parcels lying upon the counter, said, is this Morgan the edge tool maker, I said yes, he bid me take care, saying, he is a Sunday man. Then I perceived I was in a way of being trick'd out of my goods. I tore off the receipt from the bill of parcels, and said to my servant, you shall call upon Mr. Morgan with the bill first.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your servant's name?</p>
               <p>Townsend. His name is Hayward, my appren tice. I told him if Mr. Morgan would pay for these goods, I'd send them in, if not to tell him I would not send them. My servant return'd, and told me, he said it did not suit him to pay the money then, but if I'd send them, he would call and pay me in a few days.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17580113-27-person322">
                  John 
                  Hayward 
               <interp inst="t17580113-27-person322" type="surname" value="Hayward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-27-person322" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-27-person322" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am apprentice to Mr. Townsend. I went as my master desired to Mr. Morgan, and delivered the bill of parcels to him, and told him the goods were ready pack'd up, and that they came to 3 l. 2 s. and 8 d.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this bill Mr. Townsend produced. (be takes it in his hand.)</p>
               <p>Haywood. This is the bill, my own hand-writing. I also told him, if he paid the money, I would take off the 2 s. 8 d. for the discount. Mr. Morgan made answer, 'tis very hard I can't be trusted with 3 l. 2 s. and 8 d. I said it was nothing to me, it is my master's pleasure, I must have the money with me, or you are not to have the goods. Mr. Morgan said, he would pay it in a day or two, I said that will not do; then he said, meet me this evening at five or six o'clock, and send the goods to the Saracen's Head, Snow-Hill, or to the Green-Dragon alehouse, and I will pay you. I came home and told my master what he had said. My master sent the porter along with me to carry the goods, and ordered me to take the bill to Morgan, and not to deliver the goods without the money. This charge he also delivered to the porter, and just as we came by the Rainbow Coffee House, I said to the porter, do you carry the goods to the Saracen's Head, Snow-Hill, call for a pint of beer, and set upon the basket, and don't deliver it to any body till I come. Then I went round to Mr. Morgan's house (I had a mind to know whether he was at home, or whether he was gone to Snow-Hill) when his wife told me he had been gone an hour and an half. Then I went to the Saracen's Head, and inquired, and found neither the porter nor he had been there. Then I went to the Green-Dragon alehouse, and there I found the goods all unpack'd into a box, except two parcels of carpenter's heading chissels. There were Mr. Morgan and Newton in the tap-room. I said to Morgan, I ordered these goods to the Saracen's Head, how came you to unpack them; for it was quite contrary to my order, I ordered the porter not to deliver them till I came.</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175801130035"></xptr>Q. Was the porter there?</p>
               <p>Haywood. He was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any talk of paying for the goods?</p>
               <p>Haywood. Morgan said he'd pay me for them, and delivered me the bill of parcels, and bid me write a receipt on it. I had presence of mind not to write it till I had my money. He said step this way and I will pay you, and took me into another room. When I came there, there were 
               <persName id="t17580113-27-person323">
                  William 
                  Newton 
               <interp inst="t17580113-27-person323" type="surname" value="Newton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-27-person323" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-27-person323" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17580113-27-person324">
                  William 
                  Parsons 
               <interp inst="t17580113-27-person324" type="surname" value="Parsons"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-27-person324" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-27-person324" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Morgan said to Newton, do you pay this young man, and let him go about his business. Newton said, Mr. Morgan I will pay you. Then Newton took out of his pocket a handkerchief with some silver in it, I believe there might be 4 l. and told down 7 s. on the table, then he pull'd out a note of hand of William Morgan's, that 
               <persName id="t17580113-27-person325">
                  William 
                  Parsons 
               <interp inst="t17580113-27-person325" type="surname" value="Parsons"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-27-person325" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-27-person325" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had indorsed over to him, that is, to 
               <persName id="t17580113-27-person326">
                  William 
                  Newton 
               <interp inst="t17580113-27-person326" type="surname" value="Newton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-27-person326" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-27-person326" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Morgan said, this note of hand I can't deny, but I don't accept it now, it is my note of hand. Then I said to Mr Morgan, I plainly see that I am to be shuffled out of these goods. Then Mr. Morgan said to Newton, you must pay this young man. No, said he, I have paid you, there is the note of hand and 7 s. in silver, that is sufficient for you, and you must pay the young man.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you ready and desirous to have your goods again?</p>
               <p>Haywood. Yes. I did desire them to let me have them again. Mr. Morgan wrote a receipt for the goods upon the bill of parcels in full.</p>
               <p>Q. As from whom?</p>
               <p>Haywood. As from Mr. Newton. Then I demanded them again.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was then present ?</p>
               <p>Haywood. All the three prisoners.</p>
               <p>Q. What was said to you when you demanded the goods again?</p>

               <p>Haywood. Parsons said no, the goods are in our custody now, and I'll be d - n'd if any body shall have them again. Then I went into the rap-room, and bid the porter to take the goods out of the basket, but Parsons and Newton would not let him. The porter insisted upon having the goods. They said the goods were to go to the Saracen's-Head, to go down into the country in a waggon. When I found they would not let me have them, I sent the porter for a constable, and desired the landlord to keep them in talk till the constable came. When the officer came, I charged him with Newton, because he insisted on having the goods. Then I sent the porter for my master, who came, and two gentlemen along with him. My master asked who demanded the goods. Newton said, I have bought them, and paid for them, and there was a receipt from 
               <persName id="t17580113-27-person327">
                  William 
                  Morgan 
               <interp inst="t17580113-27-person327" type="surname" value="Morgan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-27-person327" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-27-person327" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Parsons detained them.</p>
               <p>Q. How did Parsons detain them?</p>
               <p>Haywood. My master said, let me have my goods, and I'll take them home again, and Parsons said he would not let him have them.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you tell Morgan you'd allow if he paid for the goods?</p>
               <p>Haywood. I told him he should be allow'd the usual discount.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember you said, he should be allow'd the same discount as at Mrs. Crawley's.</p>
               <p>Haywood. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you go to the Saracen's Head?</p>
               <p>Haywood. I had a mind to see if Morgan would be there or not. I had a suspicion he would not.</p>
               <p>Q. What foundation had you for that suspicion?</p>
               <p>Haywood. I heard he had but an indifferent character.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you meet the porter before you got to the Green-Dragon?</p>
               <p>Haywood. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Council. Then Parsons was not at the Green-Dragon when you first came there?</p>
               <p>Haywood. I saw him, but at that time I did not know him.</p>
               <p>Q. Were your's all the goods that they had there ?</p>

               <p>Haywood. No, they had more goods there than mine.</p>
               <p>Q. Whose goods were they?</p>
               <p>Haywood. I can't tell whose goods they were.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Parsons in the room when Newton took out the handkerchief of silver?</p>
               <p>Haywood. He was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not Morgan express some surprise at seeing that note?</p>
               <p>Haywood. He said, this is my note of hand, I can't disown it; I acknowledge it, but you must pay this young man; he did not seem much surprised.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether, from the appearance of the transaction, did Newton think he had any thing to do with you?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175801130036"></xptr>Haywood. Nothing at all.</p>
               <p>Q. When you desired your goods again, what did Morgan say?</p>
               <p>Haywood. Morgan went away.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he not say he would pay you?</p>
               <p>Haywood. He said he would pay me if I would go along with him into Leadenhall-Street.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after that was it that he went away?</p>
               <p>Haywood. He went away immediately, upon my mentioning the constable.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go with him?</p>
               <p>Haywood. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after this was it that you saw Mr. Morgan again?</p>
               <p>Haywood. I saw him the next day, or the day after.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he not tell you then, that he was ready to pay you, if you would give him a receipt.</p>

               <p>Haywood. Yes, he did, but this was after the other two prisoners had been carried before Sir 
               <persName id="t17580113-27-person328">
                  Richard 
                  Glyn 
               <interp inst="t17580113-27-person328" type="surname" value="Glyn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-27-person328" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17580113-27-person328" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>All three <rs id="t17580113-27-verdict165" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17580113-27-verdict165" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
