<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560225-37">
               <interp inst="t17560225-37" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560225-37" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560225-37" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560225"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560225-37" type="date" value="17560225"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560225-37-off209-c274" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-37-defend341 t17560225-37-off209 t17560225-37-verdict212"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560225-37-off209-c275" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-37-defend343 t17560225-37-off209 t17560225-37-verdict212"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560225-37-off209-c276" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-37-defend345 t17560225-37-off209 t17560225-37-verdict212"></join>
         
               <p>147, 148, 149. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17560225-37-defend341" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Boot 
                  <interp inst="t17560225-37-defend341" type="surname" value="Boot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-37-defend341" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-37-defend341" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17560225-37-defend343" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Condict 
                  <interp inst="t17560225-37-defend343" type="surname" value="Condict"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-37-defend343" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-37-defend343" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17560225-37-defend345" type="defendantName">
                     Edward 
                     Shodd 
                  <interp inst="t17560225-37-defend345" type="surname" value="Shodd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-37-defend345" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-37-defend345" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , were indicted <rs id="t17560225-37-off209" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560225-37-off209" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-37-off209" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               for that they, together with another person unknown, did steal one silk handkerchief, value 2 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17560225-37-victim347" type="victimName">
                           Levy 
                           Eeles 
                        <interp inst="t17560225-37-victim347" type="surname" value="Eeles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560225-37-victim347" type="given" value="Levy"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560225-37-victim347" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-37-off209 t17560225-37-victim347"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , and 12 other handkerchiefs, value 5 s. 
            </rs> the goods of persons unknown, <rs id="t17560225-37-cd210" type="crimeDate">Jan. 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-37-off209 t17560225-37-cd210"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-37-person348">
                  Levy 
                  Eeles 
               <interp inst="t17560225-37-person348" type="surname" value="Eeles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-37-person348" type="given" value="Levy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-37-person348" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 18th of Jan. as I was going through Aldgate about 6 o'clock at night, I had my hand in my pocket, and my handkerchief in my hand; I had occasion to blow my nose, I took my handkerchief out, and crossing the way by the corner of <placeName id="t17560225-37-crimeloc211">the Minories</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17560225-37-crimeloc211" type="placeName" value="the Minories"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17560225-37-crimeloc211" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560225-37-off209 t17560225-37-crimeloc211"></join>, after I had put my handkerchief in my pocket, I said to my friend that was along with me, I have not seen you a great while, let's go drink together; then I had occasion to use my handkerchief again, having a cold. I felt in my pocket and missed it, and said I had lost my handkerchief; we were in a publick house then; there came in a gentleman who heard what I said, and said, where did you lose it? I said betwixt here and Aldgate; said he, I just came by there, our neighbours can hardly stir out of an evening without having their pockets picked; there are four of them stand at the end of the school at Houndsditch. I borrowed a great coat to disguise me, and I and my friend went out to see if we could take them. I went first, I saw a Dutchman in liquor and a woman following him; the two prisoners Condict and Shodd followed the man and woman close, when I came through the gate I lost them in a moment, I saw them shoot through and cross over the way, and were standing under the gate where the horses and coaches go, then I went back and saw a coach coming through the gate, after which I saw 4 of the boys; then my friend and I went and took the 3 prisoners at the bar under the school, where I saw them at first; I took 7 handkerchiefs from Boot, and while my friend was gone for a constable, I search'd the other two, they stood shuffling together, I took hold of one and pull'd him from the other, I saw a parcel of handkerchiefs lying on the ground under them; I said, bring a bag, here is a bag full more; we took them up, there were 5 of them and one glove (this was in the watch house) when the constable came to strip them out drop'd the other glove.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find your own handkerchief ?</p>
               <p>Eeles, No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know who the other handkerchiefs belong to?</p>
               <p>Eeles. No, I do not; they are all here in court.</p>
               <p>Q. What did they say for themselves ?</p>
               <p>Eeles. Boot called the other whom we did not take Bogey, and said Bogey had bought them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560225-37-person349">
                  Henry 
                  Mottle 
               <interp inst="t17560225-37-person349" type="surname" value="Mottle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-37-person349" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560225-37-person349" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was along with the other evidence at the crown and Magpie at Aldgate, he had lost his handkerchief and desired me to go along with him to Aldgate to see if we could take the persons that took it; we went, I took Boot, and as soon as I got him to the watch-house I took 7 handkerchiefs from between his coat and waistcoat; I went and fetched a constable, and when I came back again Mr. Eeles said there were five more and a glove on the ground, which he shew'd me, and in searching them I saw another glove fall.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know whom those handkerchiefs belong to ?</p>
               <p>Mottle. No, I do not; I heard there were several people lost their handkerchiefs that night.</p>
               <p>Boot's defence.</p>
               <p>I met a lad, who asked me if I would hold some handkerchiefs for him, and said he would give me a penny or 2 pence; he said he was going to buy some more; and after that a gentleman came and laid hold on me, I said I was waiting for a lad; and because I cried these two lads came to me and they laid hold on them.</p>
               <p>Shodd's defence.</p>
               <p>I was going along and saw this lad, I cross'd the way to speak to him, he was laying his head<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175602250028"></xptr> against the side of a door; I never saw him or the other boy in my life before, I know nothing of the handkerchiefs.</p>
               <p>All three <rs id="t17560225-37-verdict212" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560225-37-verdict212" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
