<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17561208-5">
               <interp inst="t17561208-5" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561208-5" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561208-5" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17561208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17561208-5" type="date" value="17561208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17561208-5-off21-c47" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-5-defend55 t17561208-5-off21 t17561208-5-verdict25"></join>
         
               <p>5. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17561208-5-defend55" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Jolley 
                  <interp inst="t17561208-5-defend55" type="surname" value="Jolley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-5-defend55" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-5-defend55" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17561208-5-off21" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561208-5-off21" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-5-off21" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he on the king's high way, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17561208-5-victim57" type="victimName">
                           Charles 
                           Dyer 
                        <interp inst="t17561208-5-victim57" type="surname" value="Dyer"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17561208-5-victim57" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17561208-5-victim57" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-5-off21 t17561208-5-victim57"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and taking from his person one silver watch and seal, value 4 l. and 20 d. in money
            </rs>, his property, <rs id="t17561208-5-cd22" type="crimeDate">Oct. 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-5-off21 t17561208-5-cd22"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561208-5-person58">
                  Charles 
                  Dyer 
               <interp inst="t17561208-5-person58" type="surname" value="Dyer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-5-person58" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-5-person58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am <rs id="t17561208-5-deflabel23" type="occupation">journeyman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-5-defend55 t17561208-5-deflabel23"></join> to Mr. Godde, his majesty's sadler. I was coming on horseback over <placeName id="t17561208-5-crimeloc24">Hounslow-Heath</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17561208-5-crimeloc24" type="placeName" value="Hounslow-Heath"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17561208-5-crimeloc24" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-5-off21 t17561208-5-crimeloc24"></join> on Saturday the 23d of October, between four and five in the afternoon. Between the powder mills and the eleven mile stone I saw the prisoner at a distance coming towards me. I was on the north side the road coming towards London, and he on the south going from London. He had a handkerchief tied about his head, which hung on one side of his cheek, but did not cover his face.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you a perfect view of his face?</p>
               <p>Dyer. I had. It was a very clear afternoon, as bright as most days in that season of the year. When he came almost opposite me he stop'd. He had a great coat on, that almost cover'd all his other apparel, out of which he pull'd a pistol. He held it up to the side of my head and said, Sir, your money. I gave him what little matter I had, which was about twenty pence; I know it was under two shillings. He palm'd the money in his hand, and said, Sir, this is not all, or to that purpose. I told him it was. Said he it is very little; Then I thought he seem'd inclined to let me go,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175612080004"></xptr> or to return it me again. After some time he said, Sir, your watch. I told him I had none. Then he called his maker to witness, and said I had, that he saw it, and if I would not deliver it he'd blow my brains out, and put the pistol up to my head. I said then you shall have it, and gave it him. Then we parted. He went towards Belsont, and I towards Hounslow. I saw him for some time at a distance from me, as he rode along.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see him again?</p>
               <p>Dyer. I saw him after that in the New-gaol, Surry, about three weeks after. I knew him immediately.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to go there to see him?</p>
               <p>Dyer. Justice Clark had advertised a person taken with a watch, &amp;c. so I went to the justice and he sent me to the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any hint given you which was the person when you came there?</p>
               <p>Dyer. No, none at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you charge him there?</p>
               <p>Dyer. I said nothing to him at all. He had my watch upon him when taken, which I swore to.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I own I am guilty of the fact. I am a young fellow, and leave it to the mercy of the court.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17561208-5-person59">
                  John 
                  Ware 
               <interp inst="t17561208-5-person59" type="surname" value="Ware"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-5-person59" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17561208-5-person59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had been at Wimbleton with a periwig. Coming home, about forty yards on the other side Wandsworth I met a gentleman. He bid me take care of myself, for there was a footpad on the road.</p>
               <p>Court. You are not now to give an account of another robbery, did you see the prisoner secured?</p>
               <p>Ware. I did, and took this watch out of his pocket.</p>
               <p>(Producing one.)</p>
               <p>Q. to the prosecutor. Look on it, do you know it?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. It is the very watch that the prisoner took from me on Hounslow Heath.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17561208-5-verdict25" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561208-5-verdict25" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17561208-5-punish26" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17561208-5-punish26" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17561208-5-defend55 t17561208-5-punish26"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
