<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510116-49">
               <interp inst="t17510116-49" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510116-49" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510116-49" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510116-49" type="date" value="17510116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510116-49-off230-c352" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-49-defend445 t17510116-49-off230 t17510116-49-verdict232"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510116-49-off230-c353" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-49-defend447 t17510116-49-off230 t17510116-49-verdict232"></join>
         
               <p>154. 156. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17510116-49-defend445" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Clements 
                  <interp inst="t17510116-49-defend445" type="surname" value="Clements"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-49-defend445" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-49-defend445" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17510116-49-defend447" type="defendantName">
                     Anthony 
                     Westley 
                  <interp inst="t17510116-49-defend447" type="surname" value="Westley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-49-defend447" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-49-defend447" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were, the first a fourth time, the second, a third time indicted, for <rs id="t17510116-49-off230" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510116-49-off230" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-49-off230" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               breaking and entering the dwelling house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17510116-49-victim449" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Wolley 
                        <interp inst="t17510116-49-victim449" type="surname" value="Wolley"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510116-49-victim449" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510116-49-victim449" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-49-off230 t17510116-49-victim449"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17510116-49-cd231" type="crimeDate">August the 4th</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-49-off230 t17510116-49-cd231"></join>, about two in the morning, and stealing one silver milk-pot, ten linen shirts, value 10 s. two silk handkerchiefs, value 2 s.
            </rs> the property of the said Richard. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-49-person450">
                  James 
                  Bisben 
               <interp inst="t17510116-49-person450" type="surname" value="Bisben"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-49-person450" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-49-person450" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The two Prisoners and I lived with one 
               <persName id="t17510116-49-person451">
                  Sarah 
                  Merrits 
               <interp inst="t17510116-49-person451" type="surname" value="Merrits"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-49-person451" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-49-person451" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in Blue-anchor alley; one day we saw a ladder over in a man's yard, in that alley, we considered it would serve our turns to get into some window by, and about 12 at night we set out with an intent to get into Mrs. Boldridge's a pawnbroker, at a one pair of stairs window; we got the ladder, and carried it there, but could not get in.</p>
               <p>Q. Who carried the ladder?</p>
               <p>Bisben. Clements did. At a room at the sign of the Shears, an alehouse very near where we lived, there was a light, in a one pair of stairs room; Clements said he had a mind to go in there, so we all consented to it.</p>

               <p>Q. What time of the night was this?</p>
               <p>Bisben. This was after one o'clock. We set the ladder against the wall, and Clements went up first, lifted up the sash, and went in; I went up after him and stood on the top of the ladder; Westley stood under the window, there was a bed in the room, and a woman asleep in it; Clements went on the other side of the bed, and brought 131 shirts, and gave them into my hands. I let them fall and Westley did not catch them, but they fell to the ground. There were two silk handkerchiefs hung on the back of a chair on my left hand; I took them, and we went down as fast as we could. I went away as fast as I could by Bunhill-row. They told me they took away the ladder, and put it where they had it; I met them in about 10 minutes time at the end of the court; they brought the shirts between them; we thought we should be found out if we staid there till morning, so we took the things away to Gravel<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175101160027"></xptr> lane, Hounsditch, to one Mrs. Roach who sold them for us, she brought us 15 s. for 12 of them; 
               <persName id="t17510116-49-person452">
                  Thomas 
                  Clements 
               <interp inst="t17510116-49-person452" type="surname" value="Clements"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-49-person452" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-49-person452" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             allowed us two shillings for one, and put it on his back, and we gave the woman one shillings for selling them; we had 4 s. and 8 d. each for them. Then Clements gave us eight-pence each, out of this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-49-person453">
                  Richard 
                  Wolley 
               <interp inst="t17510116-49-person453" type="surname" value="Wolley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-49-person453" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-49-person453" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the sign of the Shears, in Blue-anchor alley. The 4th of August, about two in the morning, somebody got in at a sash-window, up one pair of stairs. I never saw the prisoners before they were taken.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you lose?</p>
               <p>Wolley. I cannot say how many shirts, ten if no more; a silver milk-pot, two silk handkerchiefs. The evidence sent for me to come to him in Bridewell, but I heard him say but little there; I was too late.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see any of your things again?</p>
               <p>Wolley. No, my lord, Clements told me in Newgate, the milk-pot was sold to a Jew that was transported. My mother in law, and a child that had the small-pox, lay in that room that night.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-49-person454">
                  Dorothy 
                  Lawley 
               <interp inst="t17510116-49-person454" type="surname" value="Lawley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-49-person454" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-49-person454" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at my son's house about one o'clock in that very room. I set a lamp burning on the slap of the stove, on the account of the child having the small-pox. I was asleep, and when I awaked, I heard something; I looked up, and saw the sash up, and the prisoner Clements with one hand on one side the sash, and the other on the other side, with his face looking into the room, going as if he was upon a ladder. I saw his face very plain, I am very sure it was he: I said to him, you dog, what are you coming into bed to me? when I saw him go down from the window, I ran to the sash and pull'd it down.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure that sash was not up when you went to bed?</p>
               <p>Lawley. I am very certain it was not; it had not been up for seven days, because of the child being ill; then I ran into the maid's room and call'd her; and by that time my son was got up : we searched, and then missed the things mentioned. I can swear to ten shirts being lost.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see Clements before this time?</p>
               <p>D. Lawley. I don't remember I ever did, my lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Were your Curtains drawn?</p>
               <p>D. Lawley. My bed had a half teaster, and it stood so, that as I lay, I saw the window; the feet of the bed was towards the window, I never draw my curtains.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-49-person455">
                  Samuel 
                  Philipson 
               <interp inst="t17510116-49-person455" type="surname" value="Philipson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-49-person455" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-49-person455" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On this day 7'night I was at justice Fielding's, when the two prisoners were brought there, Clements beg'd to be admitted an evidence. We spoke to Mr. Fielding, and he said, he had admitted the other. Westley cried and begged the same, and said, Clements had got one of the shirts on his back, which were taken out of this house. So I went and took hold of it, and said, Clements, is this one of the shirts you took out of the house? He said, yes.</p>
               <p>Clement's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was not concerned in it.</p>
               <p>Westley's Defence.</p>
               <p>These men took me in Moorfields, and had me to Clerkenwel Bridewel, and kept me there from Monday till Friday, then they carried me before the justice.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17510116-49-verdict232" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510116-49-verdict232" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17510116-49-punish233" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510116-49-punish233" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-49-defend445 t17510116-49-punish233"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-49-defend447 t17510116-49-punish233"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
