<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560915-47">
               <interp inst="t17560915-47" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-47" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-47" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560915"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-47" type="date" value="17560915"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560915-47-off238-c280" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-47-defend370 t17560915-47-off238 t17560915-47-verdict241"></join>
         
               <p>379. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17560915-47-defend370" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Philips 
                  <interp inst="t17560915-47-defend370" type="surname" value="Philips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-47-defend370" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-47-defend370" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17560915-47-off238" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560915-47-off238" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-47-off238" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               forging a certain order for goods
            </rs>, to this purport:</p>
               <p>' Sir, I received the hats, and like the price very ' well, and so long as you use me well I shall continue ' to trade with you. My wife has made out ' the mistake. Please to send me the following ' goods as soon as possible. I shall order a neighbour ' to call for them at your shop to morrow at ' eleven o'clock, but I shall expect three months ' credit for these goods, which I call ready money, ' although six is called good pay.</p>
               <p>' From your humble servant, Richard Hall.</p>
               <p>' <rs id="t17560915-47-cd239" type="crimeDate">June 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-47-off238 t17560915-47-cd239"></join>, 1756.</p>
               <p>' I want no felts, but stiff hats, &amp;c.'</p>
               <p>and for uttering and publishing the same, with intention to defraud 
               
                  <persName id="t17560915-47-victim372" type="victimName">
                     Joseph 
                     Manwaring 
                  <interp inst="t17560915-47-victim372" type="surname" value="Manwaring"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-47-victim372" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-47-victim372" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-47-off238 t17560915-47-victim372"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            .</p>
               <p>Jos. Manwaring. I am a <rs id="t17560915-47-viclabel240" type="occupation">hatter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-47-victim372 t17560915-47-viclabel240"></join>, and live in Bartholomew-Lane, opposite the Bank of England. The prisoner came to me on the 14th of June, and told me he wanted a little fortment of hats to go down to Mr. Hall at Suston, about two miles from Ponders End. He said they were for one Mr. Hall, who lived in repute there, and sold hats and many other things in the haberdashery way, and if I used him well I should have a good customer of him. He appeared as a country farmer. I asked him where he lived; he said he lived next door to the church at Torrenham, that he had a great farm there, and had lived there some time, and kept cows and horses, and should be glad to see me there. I told him I would come down when I had a little time, and in a little time after that I did; but he had got that and also another parcel of goods of me first. The first parcel he received from me on the 14th of June by a verbal order. I received a written order from the prisoner at the bar as a true order from one Richard Hall.</p>
               <p>Q. Whose hand writing was it?</p>
               <p>Manwaring. I know it to be the prisoner's hand writing.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that?</p>
               <p>Manwaring. He owned to me it was his own hand writing, and I have many other letters to compare with it, wrote in the year 1754.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see him write?</p>
               <p>Manwaring. I have, ( be produced a 10 l. bill ) I saw him write his name on this; that is, the indorsement on the back of the bill.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he write this?</p>
               <p>Manwaring. In my house.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175609150029"></xptr>The order read.</p>
               <p>Directed for Mr. Jos. Manwaring, hat-maker, at the Hat and Beaver behind the Royal Exchange, London.</p>
               <p>' Sir, I received the hats, and like them at the ' price very well, and so long as you use me well ' I shall continue to trade with you. My wife has ' found out the mistake.'</p>
               <p>Council. There was a mistake in the first parcel.</p>
               <p>' Please to send me the following goods as soon as ' possible. I shall order a neighbour to call for them ' at your shop to morrow at eleven o'clock, but I ' shall expect three months credit for these goods, ' which I call ready money, although six is called ' good pay.</p>
               <p>' From your humble servant, Richard Hall.'</p>
               <p>' June 7. 1756.</p>
               <p>' I want no felts, but stiff hats and beavers. If ' you have not all these sorts now ready, please ' to send what you can at present, I want them to ' go to a fair in the country immediately. Six at ' 6 s. six at 7 s. six at 8 s. 6 at 9 s. three at 11 s. three ' at 12 s. three at 13 s. three at 14 s. three at 15 s. ' and two small.'</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever any conversation with the prisoner on this letter?</p>
               <p>Manwaring. No farther than reading the letter.</p>
               <p>Q. In pursuance of this did you deliver these goods to him?</p>
               <p>Manwaring. I did, and he received them accordingly. I sent them according to his order to the Black Bull and Bell, in Finsbury, Moorfields, to the prisoner at the bar. I think either he or his son left a direction in writing for me to send them there to them. I think his son came with him, but I know he came on Saturday the 26th of June, the very day the parcel was delivered, and said he'd call at the Bull and Bell, and take them down in his care to Mr. Hall. About the 2d of July I was informed the goods were not carried to Suston, but delivered at another place. Then I began to stir pretty much in it. They were lodged with one Fryer, a man whom the prisoner desired me to go and enquire his character of; he lives in Great Queen Street, Lincoln's Inn Fields, and deals in hats, stockings, and other things. I went to Justice Fielding and told him the case; he directed me to go there, and take another person with me, and see if I could find any of my goods there. I went, and took 
               <persName id="t17560915-47-person373">
                  Thomas 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17560915-47-person373" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-47-person373" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-47-person373" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who lives in Queen Street, with me; there I saw two dozen of my hats with tickets on them on his counter, and all the rest in the box but three, and one at 8 s. I bought one of Fryer for 13 s. 6 d. and carried it to justice Fielding to prove it was my property. He asked 15 s. for it. I would have sold it for 11 s. or 12 s. I told the justice I had seen the principal part of the last box of hats. He would have went with me, but it began to rain, so he sent one of his men, to desire Fryer to come to him, but Fryer disappeared immediately upon it. Then the justice desired me to go and collect all I could swear to by themselves. I went and agreed for three more hats, and when the bill of parcels was brought out, I seized them. I took hold of the young woman's hands that was selling them, and asked her how she came by them. She said a countryman and a young man brought them to their house by night. We carried all the hats to Mr. Fielding's, who had sent a servant there with me and his warrant. Mr. Fielding then ordered me to take them home, and call on Fryer to demand back my 13 s. 6 d. I left word with Mrs. Fryer for him to come to the justice, and tell where the prisoner was, that I might bring him to justice.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the next time you saw the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Manwaring. I believe it was the 18th of July, when I went to Tottenham and Suston. I saw him at the last mentioned place. I enquired for one Hall there, and found a person named Hall, that had lived there forty years. He is now in court. I ask'd him if he sold hats. He said, no. I ask'd him if he knew one Philips. He said, he did not. After that I opened the case, how I had been taken in for hats, to the value of between thirty and forty pounds. His daughter said, there is a parcel of bad fellows about a mile off, so we rode thither, and inquired for one Philips. We were told he was over the way at a little old house. I and the gentleman with me stood a little behind. The officer knock'd at the door, and the prisoner opened it; and I said to the officer, there is your man. We brought him before a justice there, and from thence to justice Fielding, who committed him to Newgate. He desired me to make it up divers times, and wanted to get away. I charged him with being a cheat. He said, he meant nothing but to pay me honestly. He said, Hall of Susion was the man that gave him an order for the goods, and he had delivered the goods to him, and that he had put his hand to a 10 l. note, and I shou'd have the money when it became due. I acquainted him I had been to inquire for Hall at Suston. He laid as had part of my goods again he would pay my expences, and I should have the remaining part of my goods again.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175609150030"></xptr> He wish'd he had never known this Fryer, and likewise he owned to me, he wrote the whole of the order.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Let me see the order, I can tell whether I wrote it or not (it is put into his hand.) This is Mr. Richard Hall's hand-writing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-47-person374">
                  Thomas 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17560915-47-person374" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-47-person374" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-47-person374" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I carried some hats for my master the prosecutor to the Black-Bull and Bell in Finsbury, and delivered them to a short thick man. They were directed to Mr. Richard Hall, at Suston. I saw the prisoner at the bar in Morefields as I was going with them, and ask'd him the way to the inn, and he directed me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know him before?</p>
               <p>Jones. I had seen him once before at my master's house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-47-person375">
                  James 
                  Bedwell 
               <interp inst="t17560915-47-person375" type="surname" value="Bedwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-47-person375" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-47-person375" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Bartholomew-Lane, next door to the prosecutor. When the prisoner came to him about the second parcel of hats I happened to go in, and heard them talking about hats; but I did not observe the particulars. I went in two or three times afterwards, and saw Mr. Manwaring about a parcel of hats. I asked him if they were for that order brought by Philips, and he said, yes.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I saw that man in Mr. Manwaring's shop.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-47-person376">
                  Thomas 
                  Rawlings 
               <interp inst="t17560915-47-person376" type="surname" value="Rawlings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-47-person376" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-47-person376" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Cheapside. The prisoner acknowledged to me, that the goods that he obtained of the prosecutor, he delivered to Fryer in Queen-Street. I had a demand on Fryer at that time, and accidentally hearing Mr. Manwaring had lost a parcel of hats in a fraudulent manner, and Mr. Fryer's name being mentioned, it gave me a suspicion that he and the prisoner were in connection together. I went to Fryer directly, and got what security I could, and in conversing with him he told me he had got a parcel of hats, &amp;c. So it came out.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I own Mr. Hall received the hats at the Bull and Bell, and carried them to Mr. Fryer's. I was there when he brought them in.</p>
               <p>Rawlings. The prisoner acknowledged to me, that he, in company with his son, did deliver the hats to Mr. Fryer, and that he thought it no crime in the course of their proceedings, to take in a man worth 1000 l. for 100 l.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. At the same time the goods were gone down to Mr. Hall, I was gone to Mr. Manwaring, for the bill of parcels.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-47-person377">
                  John 
                  Hide 
               <interp inst="t17560915-47-person377" type="surname" value="Hide"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-47-person377" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-47-person377" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was sent by justice Fielding to Fryer, in Great Queen-Street, with Mr. Manwaring, to keep the peace, and to see if any of his hats were there, and to bring Fryer before him; but when we came there, he was denied. Some time after that, I went with Mr. Manwaring to Suston, where we inquired for one Hall, and there we found an old man of that name, who had lived there thirty or forty years. He said, there were none of that name besides himself. Then we were told, there was a very bad house a little way off, for highwaymen or smuglers. We rode to the place, and inquired for one Hall, when we were told by a gentleman the prisoner lived there, but he knew nothing of any Hall. We went to the house and took the prisoner, and when he was in Newgate I heard him confess he did carry the hats himself to Fryer. He offered to make me a very handsome present to let him go, or, if I would make the thing up for him, he had a horse, which he'd sell, and make me satisfaction for my trouble.</p>
               <p>John Hall. I have lived at Suston upwards of forty years, and never heard of a Richard Hall there.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Have not you heard since, there was a name-sake of your's come to live at that house where I was ?</p>
               <p>Hall. I have seen a woman and children as I went by the gate; but I don't know what name she goes by.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Have not you heard she had a child died, and buried by the name of Hall, since she lived there ?</p>
               <p>Hall. She had a child died, but I know nothing of the name.</p>
               <p>Q. If there had been one named Hall in your parish, just coming into trade, should you not know of it?</p>
               <p>Hall. I think I should.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Have you not heard since, there was a carpenter sitting up a counter, for a person to go into trade?</p>
               <p>Hall. No, I can't say I have. I heard there was going to be a chandler's shop, nothing of hats.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-47-person378">
                  Joseph 
                  Saunders 
               <interp inst="t17560915-47-person378" type="surname" value="Saunders"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-47-person378" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-47-person378" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Black Bull and Bell, in Finsbury, and there was a box directed to my house. I saw a hatter's boy bring it, but I did not see it go. I took no account of it.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Did it not come directed for one 
               <persName id="t17560915-47-person379">
                  Samuel 
                  Roberts 
               <interp inst="t17560915-47-person379" type="surname" value="Roberts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-47-person379" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-47-person379" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Saunders. No, it came directed for one Philips; it was a long box.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Mine was a long box, directed for Richard Hall; and Philips left a written direction to be put upon it, directed to Mr. Philips.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I did not take the box from the inn. Mr. Hall himself took it, and carried it to Mr. Fryer's, to<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175609150031"></xptr> lodge it there till he went down into Cambridgeshire, to fetch his wife and family up.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mr. Peirce. I don't know what I am called upon for; I only came here out of curiosity.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Did not you go into that house opposite your's at Suston, and see one Richard Hall cleaning it out?</p>

               <p>Peirce. No, I live opposite to the house, and was very sorry to have such neighbours by me. As I was going by one day, I heard somebody in it; it is an old ruinated house, and has been uninhabited some time; I knew nobody of credit would come to live there. I ask'd who was there, and a man look'd out at the window. I said, what are you doing there? Said he, I am coming to live here, and am cleaning the house out. Said I, who are you? He said, my name is Hall. I asked him from whence he came, and he said, from out of Cambridge shire. I said, if you come here, I shall insist upon your bringing a certificate. I never saw that man before nor since, and I have lived there forty years. There was a woman with two children lived there, and we wanted to get rid of them. I asked the man what he intended to do there, and he said, to do any thing the people would set him about. There were two or three boards nail'd up, and a pound or two of candles hung up.</p>
               <p>Elizabeth Hall. Richard Hall is my husband. When we were first married we lived at Elsley in Cambridgeshire, but we lived at Suston in Essex last.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you live there?</p>
               <p>E. Hall. I can't tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you live there 12 months ?</p>
               <p>E. Hall. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Half a year?</p>
               <p>E. Hall. No.</p>
               <p>Q. A month?</p>
               <p>E. Hall. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you a housekeeper there?</p>
               <p>E. Hall. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you subsist?</p>
               <p>E. Hall. We had wherewithall then to live upon. We were going into a way of trade, haberdashery and grocery; we had not begun, but had goods bespoke.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you take the house of?</p>
               <p>E. Hall. Of Mr. Gates; it was near Mr. Peirce's.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is your husband now?</p>
               <p>E. Hall. He went down into the country, and is not come back.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know whether your husband bespoke a parcel of hats of Mr. Manwaring?</p>
               <p>E. Hall. He sent me word he had, or I had not come up.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you ever in that way of life before?</p>
               <p>E. Hall. No: We had a farm of 40 l. a year at Elsley, and the prisoner lived next neighbour to us there.</p>
               <p>Q. to Peirce. Did you ever see this woman in your neighbourhood ?</p>
               <p>Peirce. I have seen her several times; I have asked for her husband, and was told he was coming week after week, but he never appear'd since.</p>
               <p>Q. to E. Hall. Had you ever any hats at Suston ?</p>
               <p>E. Hall. No, they did not come, upon the account the gentleman took them out of Mr. Fryer's shop.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Did you not propose to travel the country with hats and stockings, with a licence?</p>
               <p>E. Hall. The prisoner's daughter was to instruct us in it.</p>
               <p>Q. Can your husband write?</p>
               <p>E. Hall. He can.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you swear to his writing?</p>
               <p>E. Hall. I can if I see it ( she is shown the order.)</p>
               <p>Q. Look at the name Richard Hall.</p>
               <p>E. Hall. It is very much like my husband's writing.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath do you believe it is his writing?</p>
               <p>E. Hall. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Look upon the body of the order, whose hand-writing do you take it to be?</p>
               <p>E. Hall. That is not his hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Q. Whose do you think it is?</p>
               <p>E. Hall. It is like Mr. Philips's.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath, whether the name Richard Hall is not Philips's writing?</p>
               <p>E. Hall. No, I don't think it is.</p>
               <p>[The jury compare the body and name, and believe it was all done by one hand.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-47-person380">
                  William 
                  Tossel 
               <interp inst="t17560915-47-person380" type="surname" value="Tossel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-47-person380" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-47-person380" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Richard Hall 12 years, but can't tell whether he can write or not; he has a good character.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner to prosecutor. Did not I say the order was sent by Mr. Hall? and you said you deliver'd the goods upon my credit, you did not know Mr. Hall.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I did not say any such thing.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Did you not come twice to me in Newgate, and desire I would give you general<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175609150032"></xptr> releases, and you would release both me and my son.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I never mention'd such a thing as making it up. There have been many neighbours served in this manner by these sort of fellows, and I was for putting a stop to such practices.</p>
               <p>Q. Would you have deliver'd the goods, if the prisoner had told you the name Hall was wrote by himself?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I believe I should, because he came with so much seeming simplicity and innocence: I thought I could have trusted him with a hundred pounds worth of goods. The prisoner wanted to turn evidence last night.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17560915-47-verdict241" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560915-47-verdict241" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17560915-47-punish242" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560915-47-punish242" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-47-punish242" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="respited"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-47-defend370 t17560915-47-punish242"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
