<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17551204-5">
               <interp inst="t17551204-5" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551204-5" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551204-5" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17551204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17551204-5" type="date" value="17551204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17551204-5-off22-c43" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-5-defend51 t17551204-5-off22 t17551204-5-verdict26"></join>
         
               <p>5. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17551204-5-defend51" type="defendantName">
                     Daniel 
                     Little 
                  <interp inst="t17551204-5-defend51" type="surname" value="Little"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-5-defend51" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-5-defend51" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17551204-5-off22" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17551204-5-off22" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-5-off22" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one silver tankard, value 5 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17551204-5-victim53" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Smither 
                        <interp inst="t17551204-5-victim53" type="surname" value="Smither"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17551204-5-victim53" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17551204-5-victim53" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-5-off22 t17551204-5-victim53"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling house
            </rs> of the said John, <rs id="t17551204-5-cd23" type="crimeDate">Nov. 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-5-off22 t17551204-5-cd23"></join>.* </p> 
               <p>John Smither. <rs id="t17551204-5-viclabel24" type="occupation">I keep the Castle</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-5-victim53 t17551204-5-viclabel24"></join> in <placeName id="t17551204-5-crimeloc25">Portugal-Street, Lincoln's-Inn Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17551204-5-crimeloc25" type="placeName" value="Portugal-Street, Lincoln's-Inn Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17551204-5-crimeloc25" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-5-off22 t17551204-5-crimeloc25"></join>. The prisoner and a woman, whom he calls his wife, were drinking in my house with other company on the 3d of November. The other company went away about three in the afternoon, and left them three halfpence to pay. Some little time after, I look'd in the tap-room, and saw they were gone also. I ask'd my servant if Little had paid the three half-pence. I was told he had not. Then I said, see you tell his wife of it, when she comes at night with her oisters. (I did not then miss the tankard.) The prisoner and his wife used to be at my house most evenings, but they did not come that evening, nor the next day. I missed my tankard, and told 
               <persName id="t17551204-5-person54">
                  William 
                  Hodgen 
               <interp inst="t17551204-5-person54" type="surname" value="Hodgen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-5-person54" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-5-person54" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             of it, and that I suspected the prisoner. He told me he had seen the prisoner and his wife in a silversmith's shop in Cheapside, either buying or selling something. I sent him and one of my daughters to the shop (it was Mr. Briscoe's, at the corner of Friday Street ) to buy a second hand tankard. They were shewn several, but did not see mine. Then I went there with a friend of mine, and asked Mr. Briscoe what the prisoner and his wife were there for; he passed a little, and said he bought the handle of a mug or a tankard of him, and produced it. There was No 2 upon it, the same which I lost; upon which I got a warrant, and took the prisoner up. When I took him before the justice, he did not deny it, but said his wife gave it him. I have four tankards, which are all mark'd with a cypher and number'd; they are No. 1, 2, 3, 4; it was the No. 2 that was missing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-5-person55">
                  Mary 
                  Little 
               <interp inst="t17551204-5-person55" type="surname" value="Little"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-5-person55" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-5-person55" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner is my father's brother's son. On the 3d of November at night he came to<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175512040004"></xptr> my sister's room, and said to me, Molly, I am glad to see you, I want to speak with you in your own room. We went there, when he took from under his coat this body of a tankard ( produced in court) and said let me leave this in your room till Wednesday; Hannah gave it me ( meaning his wife ) and I go upon guard to-morrow (he is a soldier ) and after I come off I will come for it. I had never heard any thing ill of him before, and said to him, Daniel, take care. He said, It will be of no detriment to you; and on the Wednesday morning a man came and knocked at my door, and asked if 
               <persName id="t17551204-5-person56">
                  Mary 
                  Little 
               <interp inst="t17551204-5-person56" type="surname" value="Little"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-5-person56" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-5-person56" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             lived there. I came to him. He said he wanted that which Hannah Little left at my house yesterday. I said, Friend, you must be mistaken; I have not seen her since Monday night. Said he, Good woman make no words, give me what I want; you know what I mean. Friend, said I, what do you mean ? He said, the body of a tankard, Said I, that I have, and gave it to him; after that I saw the thin piece of silver that goes round the body, and that I carry'd to Justice Fielding's.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. She has spoke just what I said to her.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. Look at that body of a tankard.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. This is my property, the same I lost that time I mentioned; here is the cypher on it, and weight at the bottom.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-5-person57">
                  John 
                  Rutter 
               <interp inst="t17551204-5-person57" type="surname" value="Rutter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-5-person57" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-5-person57" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 24th of November, in the evening, Mr. Smither came to me, and said he wanted some assistance. I being beadle of the parish went with him. I took the prisoner's wife, and brought her to the Roundhouse; and after she was lock'd up, she said she would tell me where the tankard was. After she told me, I left her in charge of a watchman, and went for it, and before I returned she had got away. I went to the last evidence by her direction, and she delivered the body of the tankard to me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-5-person58">
                  William 
                  Hodgen 
               <interp inst="t17551204-5-person58" type="surname" value="Hodgen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-5-person58" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-5-person58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going down Cheapside, and saw the prisoner and his wife in Mr. Briscoe's shop, a silversmith there, on the 3d of November, about four in the afternoon. Mr. Smither telling me he had lost a tankard, I told him where I saw the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was only at the door, I was not in the shop.</p>
               <p>Hodgen. They were both in the shop.</p>
               <p>Mr. Briscoe. On the 3d of November, about four in the afternoon, a woman came into my shop with this bit of a handle to a tankard, and asked me whether or not it was silver. I touched it, and told her it was. She asked me whether I would buy it. I asked her how she came by it, and she told me she found it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any body came with her?</p>
               <p>Briscoe. There was a man stood at my door, or in the shop, but whether he was in or not I am not certain: I do not know that I spoke to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he appear to have any concern with the woman in the selling it?</p>
               <p>Briscoe. When I paid the woman, as she was going out, I think she said she was going with her basket to sell oisters; there was something passed between them, but I can't tell what it was.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He has spoke just as the thing was.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I will give a just account of what I know of it: The day the tankard was lost, I, my wife, and two or three more in company, were drinking at the prosecutor's house; after dinner, I said to her, Hannah, if you will go to Billingsgate and buy some oisters, I will go home and fetch my knot and hat. Before I returned again the gentlemen were all gone; my wife had got her sieve upon her head coming out of the house; I said, are you going? she said she had not money enough, but she would go and borrow 6 d. of her landlady. She went and did not return. I went into Chancery-lane, she had not been at home, I staid for her pretty near an hour, she did not come; then I walked down Fleet-street into White-Friars to a house we were just removed from, and there I found her. I asked her if she had borrowed the money, she said no, but she had something that would fetch some money, and pulled out a little bit of silver, and said she found it by St. Dunstan's church among some rubbish; we went to several silversmiths in Fleet-street, she sold it to one on Ludgate-hill, and after she came out of the shop she shewed me four shillings; then we went to St. Paul's church-yard, there she told me she had got something more; then we went to Mr. Briscoe's shop and sold another bit; what she got for that I cannot say. Then, I said, let us go to Billingsgate; she said, she did not purpose to go there to day, so we went to her mother's in Beach-lane, from whence we came back into Fleet-lane, and from thence into White-friars. She went up stairs, and came down in two or three minutes. Then she said we will go as far as my uncle's in Norton-falgate. After we got cross Moorfields she pulled out the body of the tankard from under her cloaths, and said, I have got something that will fetch a good deal of money still. I took it out of her hand, and asked her how she came by it. She said, very honestly; that she found<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175512040005"></xptr> It where she found the other. Then she wanted it out of my hand again. I said, I will not give it you, until I know how you came by it. She d - d me for a scoundrel, and said, if I had a good thing put into my hand I would not make the best of it; and said, if I would carry it among the Jews I might sell it. I said, I will leave it with my cousin until I come from off guard at Kensington, then I should have time to enquire how she came by it. I carried it to my cousin, and told her I had it of my wife, and desired her to let it be there till I came off guard, and then I should know how she came by it.</p>

               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. At what time did the prisoner and his wife go away from your house.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. They staid a little time after the other company. I believe they went away about three o'clock, but I did not see them go away.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17551204-5-person59">
                  William
                   H. I
               <interp inst="t17551204-5-person59" type="surname" value="H. I"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-5-person59" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17551204-5-person59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             am a serjeant in the guards. I have known the prisoner about twelve or thirteen years, he has been about that time in the regiment. I have paid him I believe seven or eight years. I never knew him guilty of any thing bad. He always behaved well. When this unhappy accident happened his discharge was wrote, but the gentlemen postponed giving it him, hoping that as he bore an honest character he would be acquitted. I have lent him money in, and he has always paid me.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17551204-5-verdict26" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17551204-5-verdict26" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17551204-5-punish27" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17551204-5-punish27" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17551204-5-defend51 t17551204-5-punish27"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
