<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17521206-16">
               <interp inst="t17521206-16" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521206-16" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521206-16" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17521206"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17521206-16" type="date" value="17521206"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17521206-16-off66-c100" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-16-defend124 t17521206-16-off66 t17521206-16-verdict69"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175212060007"></xptr>16. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17521206-16-defend124" type="defendantName">
                  Sarah, <rs id="t17521206-16-deflabel65" type="occupation">Wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-16-defend124 t17521206-16-deflabel65"></join> of John Pool, otherwise <rs id="t17521206-16-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-16-defend124 t17521206-16-alias-1"></join>Sarah Pool</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-16-defend124" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-16-defend124" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Widow, was indicted for the <rs id="t17521206-16-off66" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17521206-16-off66" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-16-off66" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17521206-16-victim126" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Pool 
                        <interp inst="t17521206-16-victim126" type="surname" value="Pool"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17521206-16-victim126" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17521206-16-victim126" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-16-off66 t17521206-16-victim126"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , her late husband
            </rs>, <rs id="t17521206-16-cd67" type="crimeDate">Nov. 9</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-16-off66 t17521206-16-cd67"></join>.</p>
               <p>She likewise stood charg'd on the coroner's inquest for the said murder. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521206-16-person127">
                  Henry 
                  Urswell 
               <interp inst="t17521206-16-person127" type="surname" value="Urswell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-16-person127" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-16-person127" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was sent for the 28th of Nov. to take the prisoner up, being constable; I know nothing about the fact.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521206-16-person128">
                  Mary 
                  Oats 
               <interp inst="t17521206-16-person128" type="surname" value="Oats"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-16-person128" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-16-person128" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner and her husband about three years, they lived in <placeName id="t17521206-16-crimeloc68">King's-Head-Yard, Shoreditch</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17521206-16-crimeloc68" type="placeName" value="King's-Head-Yard, Shoreditch"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17521206-16-crimeloc68" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-16-off66 t17521206-16-crimeloc68"></join>; she came to take a room in our house last lord-mayor's day, and took it; they came at night, and went to drinking in our apartments above both together: She went down and he followed her about eight o'clock into their apartment, soon after that I heard a noise as if they were both fighting in their room, I went down to part them, and found them both standing; she said I will not be pull'd about, I will not go up any more, and squatted down on the hearth; he was going to pull her up, saying, she should not sit upon the cold hearth, but before he had laid hold on her, she said, stand away, and took up a piece of brick, about a quarter of one, and threw it at him; he clapp'd up his hand to his forehead and said, I believe you have done it for me now ; she was frightened; he tied his handkerchief about his head; neither of them were right sober ; she got up and said to him, keep it tied up that it may not get cold. I went up then into my apartment again, and so did he, and she followed him, and continued there about an hour, and seemed very agreeable.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any thing mentioned about the blow above stairs?</p>
               <p>M. Oats. No, my lord, there was not ; I went to bed and knew no more of it.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he continue at that apartment after this ?</p>
               <p>M. Oats. He was there but till the Monday following, then he was carried to the Infirmary.</p>
               <p>Q. Between the Wednesday and Monday did you see him?</p>
               <p>M. Oats. I did on the Monday, he went about his business a day and a half.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any blow struck?</p>
               <p>M. Oats. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521206-16-person129">
                  William 
                  Ferrey 
               <interp inst="t17521206-16-person129" type="surname" value="Ferrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-16-person129" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-16-person129" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The deceased and I work'd both in one house, I went to see him on the Saturday after he went into the Infirmary, and ask'd him how it happen'd; he told me his wife had flung a piece of brick at him; I ask'd him no more, nor did he say more.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521206-16-person130">
                  Paul 
                  Boare 
               <interp inst="t17521206-16-person130" type="surname" value="Boare"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-16-person130" type="given" value="Paul"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-16-person130" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the hospital in the next ward to the deceas'd, and have seen the prisoner come to see him; I had us'd frequently to go to see him. On the Sunday our nurse said to me, I heard say his wife did it by slinging a brick. After his wife was gone, I went and ask'd how he did, and desir'd he'd let me know how this affair happened ; he said, that on lord-mayor's day, at night, his wife and others were drinking together, his wife grew drowsy, and laid her head on the table; he would have her get up and lie on the bed, she kick'd him on the private parts, and hurt him, which he resented, and words arose; then the child's godmother came down and took her part, whereupon she took up a brick, flung it at him, and so did it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he struck her?</p>
               <p>Boare. No, he did not,</p>
               <p>Q. Did they seem friendly in the hospital?</p>
               <p>Boare. They did; she came often, and was there on Sunday and on Monday morning; and when she came on Tuesday morning he was dead.</p>
               <p>Jos. Agate. I live in the same house; the Saturday following, at night, after the lord-mayor's day, the deceas'd and his wife went out together, and came home together, and they went to fighting; I heard the man say, Sally, my dear, I want to live in peace, be quiet, I'll never strike you more; she said, D - n you, you dog, I'll cut you down.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17521206-16-person131">
                  Richard 
                  Kentish 
               <interp inst="t17521206-16-person131" type="surname" value="Kentish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-16-person131" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-16-person131" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a surgeon, and was at the London Hospital when the deceas'd was brought in, on the 11th of November, he had a small wound on his forehead; the bone was bare, but not fractured, and in a few days he became exceeding ill; it was the opinion of Mr. Harrison, mi, and others that he should be trapann'd, which he accordingly was; I saw it. The deceas'd complain'd also of a violent pain in his breast, he was blooded, and several other methods made use of to relieve him, but all ineffectual, for he died on the 27th of November.</p>
               <p>Q. What appear'd on your trapanning him?</p>
               <p>Kentish. There was no matter appear'd, but upon opening his head after he was dead, we found it lodg'd under the dura mater; there was a great deal of matter upon the brain under the forehead, and part of the brain was mortified: We opened his body also, and found there was a great inflamation on his stomach, and upon that side of the liver which lies upon it.</p>
               <p>Q. By the symptoms which he had, and the appearances of the bod y after dislocation, what do you think was the occasion of his death?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175212060008"></xptr>Kentish. The violent blow he receiv'd on his head.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think the appearance you saw on his stomach might have occasioned his death if he had not had that wound on his head?</p>
               <p>Kentish. I believe it might.</p>
               <p>Q. Then why do you think his death was owing to that blow he receiv'd on his forehead?</p>
               <p>Kentish. There were two appearances of the cause of his death, it might be from either of them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I never meant to do him any ill in my life, nor did him any to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17521206-16-verdict69" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17521206-16-verdict69" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-16-verdict69" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17521206-16-punish70" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17521206-16-punish70" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17521206-16-punish70" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17521206-16-defend124 t17521206-16-punish70"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
