<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17540530-21">
               <interp inst="t17540530-21" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540530-21" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540530-21" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540530"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540530-21" type="date" value="17540530"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540530-21-off98-c182" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-21-defend214 t17540530-21-off98 t17540530-21-verdict100"></join>
         
               <p>325.(L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17540530-21-defend214" type="defendantName">
                     Charles 
                     Gray 
                  <interp inst="t17540530-21-defend214" type="surname" value="Gray"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-defend214" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-defend214" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17540530-21-off98" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-off98" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-off98" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one piece of superfine woollen cloth of a claret colourcontaining 26 yards, value 18 l.
            </rs> the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17540530-21-victim216" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Dalmear 
                  <interp inst="t17540530-21-victim216" type="surname" value="Dalmear"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-victim216" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-victim216" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-21-off98 t17540530-21-victim216"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            . It was laid over again for stealing 26 yards of woollen cloth, value 18 l. the goods of persons unknown, July 13, 1751. ++.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-21-person217">
                  William 
                  Dalmear 
               <interp inst="t17540530-21-person217" type="surname" value="Dalmear"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-person217" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-person217" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The cloth was assigned to me to sell by commission. I am a <rs id="t17540530-21-viclabel99" type="occupation">Blackwell-Hall factor</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540530-21-victim216 t17540530-21-viclabel99"></join> and it was deposited to us in order to sell it, and Christ's-Hospital is accountable to us for it if it should be lost out of Blackwell-Hallbut I am accountable to the maker. When we missed this piece of cloth we examined our standing over, and could not find it; and am always accountable for it till it is paid for.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you miss it?</p>
               <p>Dalmear. I missed it between the 4th and 11th of July, in the year 1751.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the reason you never prosecuted before?</p>
               <p>Dalmear. The people at Blackwell-Hall had bills printed and dispersed about, that if it was exposed to sale, or the like, it might be stopped; and a pawnbroker came to Blackwell-Hall, and said she believed she had it at her house.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after you dispersed these bills was it that you had intelligence of it ?</p>
               <p>Dalmear. I believe within two months; but that was two yards and a quarter, only part of it, as it appeared by the colour; and as near as I can judge by the manufactory of it, I believe it to be part of what was lost.</p>
               <p>Q. What was that pawned for?</p>
               <p>Dalmear. For eight shillings.</p>
               <p>Q. What was it worth?</p>
               <p>Dalmear. It was worth 30 or 40 shillings.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you hear of it?</p>
               <p>Dalmear. I cannot say whether it was a month or two after I missed it; we cannot prove who stole it. It has remained at Blackwell-Hall ever since, to this time. I have compared it with the pattern, and apprehend it to be part of the same, but how that came to be taken away, I cannot tell: I cannot fix any thing upon the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-21-person218">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Belamy 
               <interp inst="t17540530-21-person218" type="surname" value="Belamy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-person218" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-person218" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . In July, 1751, two yards and a quarter of claret-coloured cloth was brought by one 
               <persName id="t17540530-21-person219">
                  Sarah 
                  Humberston 
               <interp inst="t17540530-21-person219" type="surname" value="Humberston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-person219" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-person219" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to our house. I am a pawnbroker (the cloth produced in court.)</p>
               <p>Q. Is this the piece?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-21-person220">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Belamy 
               <interp inst="t17540530-21-person220" type="surname" value="Belamy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-person220" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-person220" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . It has been out of our care two years and 10 months : I cannot say this is the very cloth.</p>
               <p>Q. Does this piece of cloth answer to that for quantity?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-21-person221">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Belamy 
               <interp inst="t17540530-21-person221" type="surname" value="Belamy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-person221" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-person221" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I cannot say it may, or may not.</p>
               <p>Q. Is this the colour of that you took in?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-21-person222">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Bellamy 
               <interp inst="t17540530-21-person222" type="surname" value="Bellamy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-person222" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-person222" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I believe it is.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you lend upon it?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-21-person223">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Belamy 
               <interp inst="t17540530-21-person223" type="surname" value="Belamy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-person223" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-person223" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lent eight shillings upon it: (she held an advertisement in her hand.) This advertisement was brought to my house, and I went to the Hall, and said, I had taken in a bit of cloth for eight shillingswhich was of a claret-colour. I was asked where I lived; I told them: they came after that, but I was not at home, my husband was: they desired to know whether I would let them have the cloth: they had it, and paid me eight shillings. There was a ticket upon it, put there by a little boy that I had: they took it away with it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you deliver it to Mr. Dalmear?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-21-person224">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Belamy 
               <interp inst="t17540530-21-person224" type="surname" value="Belamy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-person224" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-person224" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . No, I delivered it to Mr. Webb.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-21-person225">
                  Sarah 
                  Humberston 
               <interp inst="t17540530-21-person225" type="surname" value="Humberston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-person225" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-person225" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever carry a piece of cloth to Eliz. Belamy's to pawn?</p>
               <p>S. Humberston. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever pawn any thing with her?</p>
               <p>S. Humberston. No, never in my life, not to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. to E. Belamy. Is this the woman that brought you the cloth?</p>
               <p>E. Belamy. To the best of my knowledge she is: she had been two or three times at my shop before that, but I did not know where she lived.</p>
               <p>Q. to Humberston. Speak the truth, it will not hurt you?</p>
               <p>S. Humberston. I do not remember ever pawning the cloth, or any thing like it, in my life: when Mrs. Belamy first saw me, she could know nothing of menor I of her.</p>

               <p>Q. Look upon the cloth?</p>
               <p>S. Humberston. I have seen it three or four times.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the first time you saw it?</p>
               <p>S. Humberston. When I was last sent for.</p>
               <p>Q. When was that?</p>
               <p>S. Humberston. Last week I believe.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon you oath did you never see that cloth above two years ago?</p>
               <p>S. Humberston. No, Sir, not to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever carry such a piece of cloth as that is to pawn ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175405300013"></xptr>S. Humberston. Not such a colour as that is, but I have carried some to Mr. Wilson's.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath when was the first time you saw that cloth?</p>
               <p>S. Humberston. Last week, when the gentleman sent for me. I never saw it before to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Recollect; you say you never carried any thing to Mr. Belamy's to pawn, is that true or false?</p>
               <p>S. Humberston. No, I never did, to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. to Elizabeth Belamy. Upon your oath has this woman ever pawned any goods at your house ?</p>
               <p>E. Belamy. I believe she pawned this cloak (producing one) for three shillings.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath do you believe she did?</p>
               <p>E. Belamy. I believe she did.</p>
               <p>Q. to S. Humberston. Did you pawn that cloak, upon your oath, to 
               <persName id="t17540530-21-person226">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Belamy 
               <interp inst="t17540530-21-person226" type="surname" value="Belamy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-person226" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-person226" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , or not?</p>
               <p>S. Humberston. I don't know the cloak; I had such a child's cloak, but there was a slit up behind.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of that?</p>
               <p>S. Humberston. It has been to Mr. Wilson's several times, but I don't know whether the cloak is mine or not.</p>
               <p>Q. How can you say so; the woman says you pawned it with her, and you say it is not your cloak?</p>
               <p>S. Humberston. My Lord, I never pawned any thing there as I know of, for Mr. Wilson was the only person that ever I pawned any thing with.</p>
               <p>Court. Regard what you swear; look upon it, and see whether it is your cloak or not.</p>
               <p>S. Humberston. I cannot swear to it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever pawn a child's cloak?</p>
               <p>S. Humberston. Yes, to Mr. Wilson, please your Lordship; though I never went with it myselfbut always sent the girl.</p>
               <p>Court. Mrs. Belamy swears she knows you, and that you have pawned things with her.</p>
               <p>S. Humberston. I cannot help that.</p>
               <p>Q. How can you say the cloak was pawned at Wilson's, if you don't know where the girl went?</p>
               <p>No answer.</p>
               <p>Q. Is that your child's cloak, wherever it was pawned?</p>
               <p>S. Humberston. I cannot swear to the cloak; but if it was my child's cloak, it would have a slit up the back, which this has not, though they say it has been fine drawn.</p>
               <p>Q. How are you certain the cloak was pawned to Mr. Wilson ?</p>
               <p>S. Humberston. I cannot tell any further, than that I sent the child with it.</p>
               <p>Q. How many pieces of cloth have you carried to Wilson's?</p>
               <p>S. Humberston. I do not know; but I carried several remnants.</p>
               <p>Q. Where had you them?</p>
               <p>S. Humberston. From the prisoner at the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever pawn any cloth of this colour?</p>
               <p>S. Humberston. No.</p>
               <p>Q. What business is the prisoner, and how did he get his livelihood?</p>
               <p>S. Humberston. He got his livelihood at Blackwell-Halland was a porter there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever pawn any piece of cloth in your life, but what you had from 
               <persName id="t17540530-21-person227">
                  Charles 
                  Gray 
               <interp inst="t17540530-21-person227" type="surname" value="Gray"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-person227" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-person227" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>S. Humberston. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. How many colours have you ever carried ?</p>
               <p>S. Humberston. I cannot say to any other than claret and scarlet colours.</p>
               <p>Q. I have asked you over and over again, and I desire you will recollect yourself when it was you first saw the cloth? - Take care, and answer upon your oath.</p>
               <p>S. Humberston. On Wednesday was sev'nnight, to the best of my knowledge, I think it was.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-21-person228">
                  Simon 
                  Hobley 
               <interp inst="t17540530-21-person228" type="surname" value="Hobley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-person228" type="given" value="Simon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner at the bar between seven and eight years, and have sold several remnants of cloth for him, but never pawned any.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen this remnant?</p>
               <p>Hobley. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember seeing that before?</p>
               <p>Hobley. I remember seeing something like it, but cannot positively swear to the colour.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember selling two yards and a quarter for him of that kind of cloth?</p>
               <p>Hobley. No; but to the best of my remembrance I sold four yards and a half of that cloth, or a sort much like it.</p>
               <p>Q. Look upon that piece of cloth; when was the first time you saw it?</p>
               <p>Hobley. On Wednesday was sev'nnight.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never see it before?</p>
               <p>Hobley. I cannot positively say that; but what I had from the prisoner I sold.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you swear, that the four yards and a half which you sold were a part of this cloth?</p>
               <p>Hobley. I cannot, but it was very much like it, and to the best of my knowledge I think it of the same.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175405300014"></xptr>Q. to Dalmear. How many yards were there of the cloth you lost?</p>
               <p>Dalmear. There were twenty-six and a quarter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540530-21-person229">
                  Samuel 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17540530-21-person229" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-person229" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-person229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This piece of cloth produced here is the same piece which Elizabeth Belamy delivered to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Does it answer to the descriptions of the advertisement ?</p>
               <p>Webb. It does. She told me it was pawned for eight shillings in the name of 
               <persName id="t17540530-21-person230">
                  Sarah 
                  Humberston 
               <interp inst="t17540530-21-person230" type="surname" value="Humberston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-person230" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-person230" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . It has never been out of my custody since I received it from her.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540530-21-verdict100" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540530-21-verdict100" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
