<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17501205-74">
               <interp inst="t17501205-74" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501205-74" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501205-74" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17501205"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501205-74" type="date" value="17501205"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17501205-74-off366-c437" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501205-74-defend585 t17501205-74-off366 t17501205-74-verdict370"></join>
         
               <p>90. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17501205-74-defend585" type="defendantName">
                     Charles 
                     Speckman 
                  <interp inst="t17501205-74-defend585" type="surname" value="Speckman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-74-defend585" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-74-defend585" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17501205-74-off366" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501205-74-off366" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-74-off366" type="offenceSubcategory" value="shoplifting"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch, value 3 l. the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17501205-74-victim587" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Honychurch 
                        <interp inst="t17501205-74-victim587" type="surname" value="Honychurch"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17501205-74-victim587" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17501205-74-victim587" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501205-74-off366 t17501205-74-victim587"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately out of the Shop of the said John
            </rs>, <rs id="t17501205-74-cd367" type="crimeDate">Nov. 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501205-74-off366 t17501205-74-cd367"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-74-person588">
                  John 
                  Honychurch 
               <interp inst="t17501205-74-person588" type="surname" value="Honychurch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-74-person588" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-74-person588" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17501205-74-crimeloc368">Fleetstreet</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17501205-74-crimeloc368" type="placeName" value="Fleetstreet"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17501205-74-crimeloc368" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501205-74-off366 t17501205-74-crimeloc368"></join>, and am a <rs id="t17501205-74-viclabel369" type="occupation">watchmaker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501205-74-victim587 t17501205-74-viclabel369"></join>, the watch was taken with the prisoner on the 6th of Nov. I lost it on the 5th, here is my name and number upon it, I never had sold it: I advertised it and by that means it was stopped; my servant can give the Court a particular account of the losing it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-74-person589">
                  William 
                  Batersby 
               <interp inst="t17501205-74-person589" type="surname" value="Batersby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-74-person589" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-74-person589" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Honychurch, on the 5th of Nov. in the morning I was alone, the prisoner came into the shop with a watch to have it clean'd, he then appeared in another complection than now, he had on a laced hat, a waistcoat with either gold or silver button holes, he desired me to take his watch to pieces; while I was doing it he said some of the works were drop'd, adding, he was sure some of them were lost. I looked upon the ground, there were none down but all right before me, then he was for taking it to show to some other watchmaker, I said I must not take it to pieces and put it together again for nothing; he said, I'll take it and shew it to another, and if he says there is nothing lost I'll bring it again; he took it not put together, also 2 new wheels, a third and cantrite wheel away with him that lay before me; when he staid longer than I expected I began to suspect him; I looking about saw a hook was empty where a new watch hung just before he came in. I went to the watchmaker, where I supposed he'd go to, and ask'd for him; he told me no such person had been there; then I told my master the affair. Master told me by his book it was a watch he was making for a gentleman in Devonshire. When Mr. Price seat for my master I went with him and knew the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Had there been any body in your shop betwixt the time you last saw the watch and the prisoner coming in?</p>
               <p>Batersby. There was not any body from the time I opened the shop till the watch was lost but him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-74-person590">
                  James 
                  Bruin 
               <interp inst="t17501205-74-person590" type="surname" value="Bruin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-74-person590" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-74-person590" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Price; between 6 and 7 o'clock, on the 6th of November in the evening, I was sitting in the parlour, somebody came and ask'd for Mr. Price; I went into the shop and saw the prisoner, he was drest in a silver-lac'd hat, a green waistcoat with gold button holes: he said, he should be glad to see my master, if he was not engaged; I said, I could do the same; he took a watch out of his pocket, and I saw it was the watch advertised that day; I went and told my master of it, he came down stairs, my master told him he had stole this watch, he denied it; my master sent directly for Mr. Honychurch, his man came, and said, the prisoner was the person that was at his shop yesterday morning. While our man was gone, the prisoner own'd to my master and I, that he had stole it; we went before Justice Fielding the next day, and he was committed to New Prison.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence. What he has said is false; I cannot deny but I carried that watch to be pawn'd; I was coming down Snow Hill, and a well dress'd man ask'd me, if I had a mind to earn a shilling, I said, yes; so I carried it to pawn; then the young gentleman said, there had been a watch stole, so stopt me. See No. 187. 222. in Sir 
               <persName id="t17501205-74-person591">
                  Samuel 
                  Pennant 
               <interp inst="t17501205-74-person591" type="surname" value="Pennant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-74-person591" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-74-person591" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Mayoralty.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17501205-74-verdict370" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501205-74-verdict370" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17501205-74-punish371" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501205-74-punish371" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501205-74-defend585 t17501205-74-punish371"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
