<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17581025-20">
               <interp inst="t17581025-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581025-20" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581025-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17581025"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17581025-20" type="date" value="17581025"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17581025-20-off94-c136" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581025-20-defend175 t17581025-20-off94 t17581025-20-verdict96"></join>
         
               <p>343. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17581025-20-defend175" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Nolan 
                  <interp inst="t17581025-20-defend175" type="surname" value="Nolan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-defend175" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-defend175" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for that he, <rs id="t17581025-20-off94" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-off94" type="offenceCategory" value="breakingPeace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-off94" type="offenceSubcategory" value="wounding"></interp>
               with a certain pistol, loaded with gunpowder, and two leaden slugs, which he had, and held in his right hand, did shoot off, at the person of 
                     <persName id="t17581025-20-victim176" type="victimName">
                        Gustavus 
                        Forshohm 
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-victim176" type="surname" value="Forshohm"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17581025-20-victim176" type="given" value="Gustavus"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17581025-20-victim176" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581025-20-off94 t17581025-20-victim176"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , in the king's highway, against the form of the statute, &amp;c.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17581025-20-cd95" type="crimeDate">Sept. 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581025-20-off94 t17581025-20-cd95"></join>. </p>
               <p>Gustavus Forshohm. On the 23d of September, between the hours of eight and nine in the evening, I was going over Hanover-square, and in a short street, going into Oxford-road, four men came and took hold of my coat, and stopped me, and demanded my money; there was a lamp at the corner just near me; I said gentlemen come to the light, let me look at you, I thought they had been some of my acquaintance; they said they came to rob and murder me; I said I had no money, and bid them go about their business; one of them cried out shoot him; then one of them put a pistol to the side of my head, and shot me; after that I saw another pistol flash in the pan, but it did not go off. I cried Murder! stop thief! They ran away, but in about three minutes time 
               <persName id="t17581025-20-person177">
                  William 
                  Dawson 
               <interp inst="t17581025-20-person177" type="surname" value="Dawson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person177" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person177" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was taken.</p>
               <p>Q. Why do you charge the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Forshohm. He was one of the four, he was at my left hand behind Dawson, who had hold of me, the other two were on the other side of me. (He shewed a wound on his left cheek bone.) Three weeks after the surgeon took out a slug from the wound, (producing one.)</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell which shot off the pistol?</p>
               <p>Forshohm. I then thought it to be Dawson, but he says it was the prisoner that stood behind him, and fired it over his shoulder. For my part I am not positive which did it, but it was one of the two.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Did you ever see me before?</p>

               <p>Forshohm. No, never before that night to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know from your own knowledge who shot off the pistol?</p>
               <p>Forshohm. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain the prisoner was one of the four?</p>
               <p>Forshohm. I am. At first I had two men brought to me; I said they were none of them, then they brought the prisoner; I said he is one of them, I am certain to him and Dawson.</p>
               <p>Q. If you had met the prisoner in the street, should you have known him?</p>
               <p>Forshohm. I should.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not charge Dawson before the justice with firing off the pistol at you?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175810250016"></xptr>Forshohm. I did, I thought it had been he, he being close to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never declare that the prisoner was not there?</p>
               <p>Forshohm. No, never; I said he was there close behind Dawson.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know he was behind Dawson from your own knowledge, or from what Dawson has said?</p>
               <p>Forshohm. I know it from my own knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell the exact time of the night that this happened?</p>
               <p>Forshohm. It was just wanting a quarter of an hour of nine.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it light enough to see their faces?</p>
               <p>Forshohm. It was not very dark, but there was a lamp at the corner within two yards of us.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was the prisoner to you?</p>
               <p>Forshohm. Dawson was close to me, and had hold of me, and the prisoner close to Dawson, within a yard and a half of me.</p>
               <p>Q. Who spoke to you first?</p>
               <p>Forshohm. They all spoke to me.</p>
               <p>Q. What cloaths had the prisoner on?</p>
               <p>Forshohm. He had blue cloaths on.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he a hat on?</p>
               <p>Forshohm. He had.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you distinguish his face with his hat on?</p>
               <p>Forshohm. I could plain, by the light of the lamp, and the flash in the pan; I looked at sharp at them as I could, to know them again, to have them taken.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see them all four?</p>
               <p>Forshohm. I did, before I was shot at, the other two are not taken.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581025-20-person178">
                  William 
                  Dawson 
               <interp inst="t17581025-20-person178" type="surname" value="Dawson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person178" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person178" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . That evening that the prosecutor speaks of, we all four met at the Woolpack in Long-acre.</p>
               <p>Court. Name the persons.</p>
               <p>Dawson. There were Preston, Keaney, Nolan, and I, there we consulted to go a robbing; about seven in the evening we went out, and proceeded to the corner of the street which the prosecutor mentioned, and stopped him, and demanded his money, he made some small resistance, and a noise, but did not speak a word to be understood. [The prosecutor is a foreigner, and did not speak very plain English.] Immediately Preston cried out, shoot him; then the prisoner put the pistol over my shoulder, and fired at the prosecutor. We all dispersed immediately.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there a second pistol fired?</p>
               <p>Dawson. Not as I know of; as I was running, a chairman lay down, and I fell over him, and he and his companion secured me, and a great number of people came round me.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the prisoner taken?</p>
               <p>Dawson. He was taken the next evening, as I was informed, but I was then in prison.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The first commencement of Dawson's and my acquaintance was on board the Antigallican privateer, commanded by capt. Foster.</p>
               <p>Dawson. The prisoner had this coat of mine on at the time we stopped the prosecutor; (it was as the prosecutor said, a blue coat.) I put on another coat, which he left on the bed.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Did I know for what intent you put it on?</p>
               <p>Dawson. Yes, as well as I did.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you shoot at the prosecutor?</p>
               <p>Dawson. No, I never did, it never was my intention to shoot at any man.</p>
         
               <p>N. B. The second part of these proceedings will be published in a few days.</p>
               <p>As a few of the first sheets were printed off before we saw our mistake, the reader is desired to correct the Judges names, page 2, for Mr. 
                  <persName id="t17581025-20-person179">
                     Baron 
                     LEGGE 
                  <interp inst="t17581025-20-person179" type="surname" value="LEGGE"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person179" type="given" value="Baron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person179" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               , read Sir 
                  <persName id="t17581025-20-person180">
                     EDWARD 
                     CLIVE 
                  <interp inst="t17581025-20-person180" type="surname" value="CLIVE"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person180" type="given" value="EDWARD"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person180" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               , Knt.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17581025-20">
                  <interp inst="t17581025-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17581025-20" type="year" value="1758"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17581025-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17581025"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17581025-20" type="date" value="17581025"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175810250017"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 25th, and Thursday the 26th, of OCTOBER.</p>
                  <p>In the Thirty-second Year of his MAJESTY'S Reign. NUMBER VIII. PART II. for the YEAR 1758. Being the Eighth SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of THE RIGHT HONOURABLE Sir 
                  <persName id="t17581025-20-person181">
                     CHARLES 
                     ASGILL 
                  <interp inst="t17581025-20-person181" type="surname" value="ASGILL"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17581025-20-person181" type="given" value="CHARLES"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17581025-20-person181" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Knt. LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed and sold by M. COOPER, at the Globe, in Pater-noster Row. 1758.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175810250018"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, for the City of LONDON, and at the General 
                  <persName id="t17581025-20-person182">
                     Sessions
                  <interp inst="t17581025-20-person182" type="given" value="Sessions"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17581025-20-person182" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                     </persName>
                of Gaol Delivery of Newgate, holden for the said City of LONDON, and County of MIDDLESEX, at Justice-Hall in the Old-Bailey, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581025-20-person183">
                  MARY 
                  PRESTON 
               <interp inst="t17581025-20-person183" type="surname" value="PRESTON"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person183" type="given" value="MARY"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person183" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to 
               <persName id="t17581025-20-person184">
                  Robert 
                  Preston 
               <interp inst="t17581025-20-person184" type="surname" value="Preston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person184" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person184" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Dawson, Keaney, and my husband were all in our room together; Dawson put on a great coat, and they all four went out.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they all go out together?</p>
               <p>Preston. No, they went out two at one time, and two at another, they said they were going to a dancing; they came back again at nine o'clock all but Dawson; this was that night that Dawson was taken. They asked me if he was come home; I said I had not seen him since he went out.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581025-20-person185">
                  John 
                  Ball 
               <interp inst="t17581025-20-person185" type="surname" value="Ball"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person185" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person185" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I picked up a pistol in Hanover-square, the next morning after the prosecutor was shot. (He produced a pocket pistol.) This is it, it was loaded, cock'd, and primed, when I took it up.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581025-20-person186">
                  Adam 
                  Stowars 
               <interp inst="t17581025-20-person186" type="surname" value="Stowars"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person186" type="given" value="Adam"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person186" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was sent for to justice Fielding, to go to look at some prisoners that were in goal; there I saw and knew Dawson, because he bought a pistol of me three or four days before. (He takes the pistol in his hand.) This is the same pistol; there was another man along with him, at the time, in a fustian frock.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any knowledge of the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Stowars. I never saw him till I saw him in goal.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581025-20-person187">
                  John 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17581025-20-person187" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person187" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person187" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am one of the beadles of St. George's, I went in order to apprehend the prisoner, by Dawson's information, to a public-house, joining to the royal Cockpit, St. James's-park. After we had been there some little time, the prisoner came in; the maid-servant of the house, I suppose, suspecting our intent, went to push him out, and we went and laid hold of him.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Did I make any resistance?</p>
               <p>Lewis. He would if he could, but had not time, we put him on his back in a minute.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>Dawson and I being on board the Antigallican privateer, and both suffered much in Spain, we had a resolution to come to England; we came in a small brig to Bristol, and he came to London before me, and he went to the West-Indies, and I never saw him till after he returned; then I met him one Sunday in the afternoon in Covent-garden, he seemed very glad to see me, we went and drank together, I said to him, as you live so far off as the other end of the town, and it is too late to go home, you are extremely welcome to take part of a bed with me; I took him home to the Cockpit alehouse, and treated him with a bottle of wine, and he called for another, and went to bed; the next morning I got up with an intent to go to work at my business, he said he should be obliged to me if I would go along with him to see some of our shipmates, and said he would lose a day or two to oblige me as far; so I went with him to see some of them, and parted with him that night between six and seven o'clock: I never saw him after till such time as I met with him at this woman's<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175810250019"></xptr> house, her name is 
               <persName id="t17581025-20-person188">
                  Mary 
                  Preston 
               <interp inst="t17581025-20-person188" type="surname" value="Preston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person188" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person188" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; he said they lodged together on one floor; I called there out of friendship to see him; I never saw him till a considerable time after that, having a fit of illness. When I got well again, I met him in Long-acre; he asked me where I was going, I said to look for capt. Foster about my prize money; he said I will go along with you, we went to go to the captain's house, and met him by the India-house, we talked with the captain about a quarter of an hour, and then returned home; immediately after I had parted with Dawson, I never was out of my lodgings, only when I work'd for a gentleman at Hammersmith. I have people here, that is Mr. Cranley, 
               <persName id="t17581025-20-person189">
                  Sarah 
                  Holland 
               <interp inst="t17581025-20-person189" type="surname" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person189" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person189" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17581025-20-person190">
                  Edward 
                  Macdonnock 
               <interp inst="t17581025-20-person190" type="surname" value="Macdonnock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person190" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person190" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to prove I was with them that night I am charged with this offence, from seven in the evening, till better than half an hour after nine, and that I was afraid of staying there any longer, fearing I should be locked out from going into the Park.</p>
               <p>[They were ordered to be examined separate, and 
               <persName id="t17581025-20-person191">
                  Mary 
                  Preston 
               <interp inst="t17581025-20-person191" type="surname" value="Preston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person191" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person191" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was ordered out of court likewise, in order to her being examined afterwards.]</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581025-20-person192">
                  Edward 
                  Macdonnock 
               <interp inst="t17581025-20-person192" type="surname" value="Macdonnock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person192" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person192" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On a Saturday night Nolan came to pay me some money for keeping his child; I have it now, his wife having been in the Lying-in-hospital. That night he gave me 3 s. 6 d. towards the maintenance of it; we had some beef stakes for supper, and I parted with him about nine o'clock, to the best of my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Who else was in company with you?</p>
               <p>Macdonnock. There was no one but himself, my wife, and I.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had he been with you?</p>
               <p>Macdonnock. From between six and seven o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure there was no body else with you?</p>
               <p>Macdonnock. There was no body else only a woman that was taking care of my wife, who was not well.</p>
               <p>Q. What is that woman's name ?</p>
               <p>Macdonnock. Her name is 
               <persName id="t17581025-20-person193">
                  Sarah 
                  Holland 
               <interp inst="t17581025-20-person193" type="surname" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person193" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person193" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Macdonnock. I live in Hedge-lane.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581025-20-person194">
                  Sarah 
                  Holland 
               <interp inst="t17581025-20-person194" type="surname" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person194" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person194" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the house of Mr. Macdonnock, taking care of the children, as the woman desired me to come and keep her company, and the prisoner came in; it was on a Saturday night, to the best of my knowledge, between six and seven o'clock, I went over to the dial to see what o'clock it was.</p>
               <p>Q. What else had you besides beef stakes for supper that night?</p>

               <p>Holland. It was dressed with onions and butter, and three pots of beer in all.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you there all the time the prisoner was?</p>
               <p>Holland. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any money paid?</p>
               <p>Holland. He paid some money for taking care of his child, but I cannot say how much it was.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. As I was not well, I was obliged to borrow money of my landlord that Saturday night, before I went, it was 31 s.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581025-20-person195">
                  William 
                  Cranley 
               <interp inst="t17581025-20-person195" type="surname" value="Cranley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person195" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person195" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner lodged at my house about six weeks, he behaved very sober, and very honestly.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Did I not borrow 31 s. of you on the Saturday night?</p>
               <p>Cranley. No, it was one Friday night.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was I not sick in your house?</p>
               <p>Cranley. You was not well to be sure; there were several people came to enquire after him, Dawson, and others.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Give a just testimony of the time I was at home in your house.</p>
               <p>Cranley. He was at home before the shutting up of the gate; I always shut it up at ten o'clock; I did live there then, I do not now, I left it at Michaelmas.</p>
               <p>Q. What gate?</p>
               <p>Cranley. The Park-gate.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is Preston's house?</p>
               <p>Cranley. It is in Glassenbury-court, Long-acre.</p>
               <p>- Lewis. When I went to this man's house, and asked for the prisoner, he declared he had not lodged there for a fortnight.</p>
               <p>Cranley. The reason that I said so was, he was afraid of being pressed, being a seaman, and his having a small family.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581025-20-person196">
                  George 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17581025-20-person196" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person196" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person196" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner four or five years.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175810250020"></xptr>Q. What is his employ?</p>
               <p>Evans. He is a painter, he has worked for me a good deal, but mostly before he belonged to the Antigallican privateer.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you been acquainted with him lately?</p>
               <p>Evans. I have seen him go by about his business this summer.</p>
               <p>Q. What has been his behaviour?</p>
               <p>Evans. While he worked with me, he behaved well, I had a good opinion of him, and put some confidence in him then, he is a very industrious man, and what we call a good hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Why do you lay an emphasis on the word then?</p>
               <p>Evans. Because I have not seen him much since; he has worked in good families, and been respected.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any objection against employing him lately?</p>

               <p>Evans. No, none at all, he is a very active fellow.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581025-20-person197">
                  John 
                  Stanley 
               <interp inst="t17581025-20-person197" type="surname" value="Stanley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person197" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person197" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am clerk to Mr. Clarke, the king's plaisterer, I have known the prisoner about a year ago last August, he did painting work for my master.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Stanley. A very industrious man, I never knew any harm of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581025-20-person198">
                  Walter 
                  Fitzgerald 
               <interp inst="t17581025-20-person198" type="surname" value="Fitzgerald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person198" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person198" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him four or five years, down to the present time, he is industrious in his business, and has a good character, I never heard to the contrary.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17581025-20-verdict96" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-verdict96" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17581025-20-punish97" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-punish97" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17581025-20-defend175 t17581025-20-punish97"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17581025-20-person199">
                  Edward 
                  Macdonnock 
               <interp inst="t17581025-20-person199" type="surname" value="Macdonnock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person199" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person199" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17581025-20-person200">
                  Sarah 
                  Holland 
               <interp inst="t17581025-20-person200" type="surname" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person200" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17581025-20-person200" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , were committed to Newgate to be tried for perjury on this trial.</p>
            </div1>
