<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17570420-9">
               <interp inst="t17570420-9" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570420-9" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570420-9" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17570420"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17570420-9" type="date" value="17570420"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17570420-9-off42-c111" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-9-defend127 t17570420-9-off42 t17570420-9-verdict44"></join>
         
               <p>149. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17570420-9-defend127" type="defendantName">
                  Richard 
                  Perrin 
               <interp inst="t17570420-9-defend127" type="surname" value="Perrin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-9-defend127" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-9-defend127" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17570420-9-off42" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570420-9-off42" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-9-off42" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one wooden cask, call'd a puncheon, value 10 s. and 952 lb. weight of melasses, value 20 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               <persName id="t17570420-9-victim128" type="victimName">
                  his 
                  majesty 
               <interp inst="t17570420-9-victim128" type="surname" value="majesty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-9-victim128" type="given" value="his"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-9-victim128" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-9-off42 t17570420-9-victim128"></join>
                  </persName>
             ; it was laid over again to be the property of persons unknown, <rs id="t17570420-9-cd43" type="crimeDate">Mar. 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17570420-9-off42 t17570420-9-cd43"></join>.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-9-person129">
                  John 
                  Fletcher 
               <interp inst="t17570420-9-person129" type="surname" value="Fletcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-9-person129" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-9-person129" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a labouring man. The prisoner employed me on the 12th of March, about one o'clock in the day, in helping 
               <persName id="t17570420-9-person130">
                  John 
                  Garnsey 
               <interp inst="t17570420-9-person130" type="surname" value="Garnsey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-9-person130" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-9-person130" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to roll a vessel up about five or six yards, from Cox's-Key into the gateway, and after that to load it into a cart.</p>

               <p>Q. What was in it?</p>

               <p>Fletcher. I can't tell that.</p>

               <p>Cross Examination.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you know this Garnsey?</p>

               <p>Fletcher. He works upon the Keys; but I did not know his name before.</p>

               <p>Q. What is your employ?</p>

               <p>Fletcher. I do any thing for a living.</p>

               <p>Q. Are not there some dregs or scrapings of casks, that are the porters perquisites ?</p>

               <p>Fletcher. Yes, there are; that belongs to the wharfinger's men.</p>

               <p>James Dougen. I was a servant to the wharfinger between eight and nine years; there was a man came in the prisoner's place after he was turn'd out. I do not know his name, but we call him Francis.</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200016"></xptr>Q. When was the prisoner turn'd out of his place ?</p>

               <p>Dougen. I can't say when. On the 12th of March I helped to roll a vessel out of the way of the carts, near a door in Fresh-Wharf gateway. I went afterwards to see if it was safe, or not, and this 
               <persName id="t17570420-9-person131">
                  Richard 
                  Perrin 
               <interp inst="t17570420-9-person131" type="surname" value="Perrin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-9-person131" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-9-person131" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was standing in the gateway. He said, '' This is a puncheon of melasses, and I'll load it away presently.'' I thought it was his perquisite. Sometimes we get a good deal of it, and are two or three months in gathering of it.</p>

               <p>Q. How much might there be of it?</p>

               <p>Dougen. About eight hundred and a half, or three quarters.</p>

               <p>Q. What do you sell it for?</p>

               <p>Dougen. For about twelve or thirteen shillings per hundred.</p>

               <p>Cross Examination.</p>

               <p>Q. How long had the prisoner left his place ?</p>

               <p>Dougen. I can't say how long.</p>

               <p>Q. What is that you call perquisites ?</p>

               <p>Dougen. It is the sugar that runs in the buildings, and our master gives us that for keeping the warehouse clean.</p>

               <p>Q. Did not you once send the prisoner of an errand for you?</p>

               <p>Dougen. No, never.</p>

               <p>Q. Did not you send him with a receipt of your's?</p>

               <p>Dougen. He desired me to make a receipt for him.</p>

               <p>Q. Who received the money?</p>

               <p>Dougen. He did.</p>

               <p>Q. What was that receipt for ?</p>

               <p>Dougen. He came and said to me, '' As you are '' a person in our service, and Mr. Featherstone '' knows me to be out of my duty, if you'll make '' the bill he will like it better:'' so I did it, as being of service to him to get the money.</p>

               <p>Q. Was not that for this puncheon ?</p>

               <p>Dougen. I don't know what puncheon it was for.</p>

               <p>Q. Who drew the bill of parcels, and wrote the receipt at bottom?</p>

               <p>Dougen. That was the bill which I wrote in my name, to serve the prisoner at the bar.</p>

               <p>Q. What was that bill for ?</p>

               <p>Dougen. It was for melasses.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you, yourself, write it ?</p>

               <p>Dougen. No, it was wrote by a friend of mine: I can neither write nor read.</p>

               <p>Q. Had you no share of the money he received ?</p>

               <p>Dougen. He came to me, and gave me some of it.</p>

               <p>Q. How much did you receive of it?</p>

               <p>Dougen. I can't say positively how much.</p>

               <p>Q. Did not he bring you 5 l.?</p>

               <p>Dougen. No; he bid me take some off the table for making the bill.</p>

               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>

               <p>Dougen. At the Bull, in Pudding-Lane.</p>

               <p>Q. How much was the receipt for?</p>

               <p>Dougen. For five pounds, nine or ten shillings.</p>

               <p>Q. Did not you give him a guinea on some consideration or other ?</p>

               <p>Dougen. No. I did not.</p>

               <p>Q. Had he any more than a guinea of that money ?</p>

               <p>Dougen. He had the rest of it.</p>

               <p>Q Had you, or he, most of that money ?</p>

               <p>Dougen. I had not; but I don't know justly what I had.</p>

               <p>Q. Did Mr. Featherstone buy that puncheon of melasses ?</p>

               <p>Dougen. I really do not know.</p>

               <p>Q. Was the puncheon full ?</p>

               <p>Dougen. I can't say whether it was full or not.</p>

               <p>Q. Supposing that full of melasses, what is the value ?</p>

               <p>Dougen. We have had about twelve or thirteen shillings per hundred weight.</p>

               <p>- Stoaks. I am a carmin: I carried that puncheon out of Fresh-Water gateway, to Mr. Featherstone's in the Minories.</p>

               <p>Q. Who call'd the cart ?</p>

               <p>Stoaks. I do not know who did.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you see the prisoner when it was lo aded?</p>

               <p>Stoaks. No, I did not.</p>

               <p>Q Did you see Dougen, or Fletcher, there ?</p>

               <p>Stoaks. No; somebody call'd carman down the gateway, so I went down, and followed the cart.</p>

               <p>Q. Who did you see when you came there?</p>

               <p>Stoaks. Nobody: I turn'd about and the puncheon was roll'd up the gateway, and then three men were there, and put it into my cart; they were up at the capstern.</p>

               <p>Q. Who gave you the order to carry it to Mr. Featherstone's ?</p>

               <p>Stoaks. While I was binding my cart Richard Perrin went up the gateway. I asked him where I was to go with it. He said into the Minories. Then I said I know where, for I have carried several there before; it is to Mr. Featherstone's. He said it is.</p>

               <p>Q. How came you to ask the prisoner where to carry it?</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175704200017"></xptr>Stoaks. I seeing him, asked him; I did not know that he was discharged.</p>

               <p>Q. What was in the vessel?</p>

               <p>Stoaks. I do not know; it was bung'd up.</p>

               <p>Q. Was it a melasses puncheon?</p>

               <p>Stoaks. It was. As I was going down the Minories I met the prisoner coming back, who said he had been there.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17570420-9-person132">
                  John 
                  Garnsey 
               <interp inst="t17570420-9-person132" type="surname" value="Garnsey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-9-person132" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17570420-9-person132" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I helped to load the cart at Fresh-Wharf gateway.</p>

               <p>Q. What was in the puncheon?</p>

               <p>Garnsey. I do not know.</p>

               <p>Q. What was the weight of it?</p>

               <p>Garnsey. I do not know that.</p>

               <p>Q. Whose cart did you load it in?</p>

               <p>Garnsey. I do not know.</p>

               <p>
                  <rs id="t17570420-9-verdict44" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17570420-9-verdict44" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
