<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17571207-16">
               <interp inst="t17571207-16" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17571207-16" type="year" value="1757"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17571207-16" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17571207"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17571207-16" type="date" value="17571207"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17571207-16-off85-c147" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571207-16-defend175 t17571207-16-off85 t17571207-16-verdict89"></join>
         
               <p>21. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17571207-16-defend175" type="defendantName">
                     Jeremiah 
                     Bailey 
                  <interp inst="t17571207-16-defend175" type="surname" value="Bailey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-16-defend175" type="given" value="Jeremiah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-16-defend175" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17571207-16-off85" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17571207-16-off85" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-16-off85" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17571207-16-victim177" type="victimName">
                           Ann 
                           Royston 
                        <interp inst="t17571207-16-victim177" type="surname" value="Royston"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17571207-16-victim177" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17571207-16-victim177" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571207-16-off85 t17571207-16-victim177"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17571207-16-viclabel86" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571207-16-victim177 t17571207-16-viclabel86"></join>, did make an assault, putting her in corporal fear and danger of her life, and taking from her person one serge gown, value 5 s. six linen aprons, five linen caps, value 2 s. one ivory comb, two ribbons, two ounces of worstead, two pair of worstead stockings, two pounds weight of sugar, one quarter of a pound of tea, one half pound of butter, two linen handkerchiefs, one half guinea, and 8 s. in money number'd, her property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17571207-16-cd87" type="crimeDate">November 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571207-16-off85 t17571207-16-cd87"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571207-16-person178">
                  Ann 
                  Royston 
               <interp inst="t17571207-16-person178" type="surname" value="Royston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-16-person178" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-16-person178" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Southgate, and knew the prisoner before he rob'd me, and also when he did rob me. On the 18th of November I was going home from Edmonton, about six in the evening. At the upper end of a place call'd <placeName id="t17571207-16-crimeloc88">Hedge Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17571207-16-crimeloc88" type="placeName" value="Hedge Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17571207-16-crimeloc88" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571207-16-off85 t17571207-16-crimeloc88"></join> the prisoner met me; I was going to give him the right hand, to let him pass by me. He went to go by my left side, put his hand up my coats, threw me down, and wanted to lie with me, but I resisted him. He said three or four times over that he would murder me. I beg'd very hard for my life. When he used his pleasure, as far as he thought proper, he rob'd me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he lie with you?</p>
               <p>A. Royston. No. he did not. I had in the bundle the goods mention'd in the indictment ( repeating them all ) which he took, also half a guinea in gold, and 8 s. in silver, that was in my bundle. There were two parcels.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he put you in fear?</p>
               <p>A. Royston. Yes, in a good deal of fear.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he any pistol or sword ?</p>
               <p>A. Royston. No; I saw no such things.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this in the road or fields?</p>
               <p>A. Royston. It was upon the high road. He made towards his own home at Edmonton, and is a day labourer there.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known him?</p>
               <p>A. Royston. These four or five years. I went and told my neighbours of it the same night, at Keys's, but did not tell the man's name that rob'd me, fearing he should go off.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he ask you to deliver the bundles to him?</p>
               <p>A. Royston. No, he did not, but he took them away. I went to Edmonton on the next morning, being Saturday. I ask'd for his christian name, that I did not know. I found he was come to London. I went to Mr. Colebrook on Sunday evening for a warrant.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did not you go before?</p>
               <p>A. Royston. Because the prisoner was not come home; by that warrant he was taken on Monday morning, and brought before the justice. He declared he was innocent there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he own that he had seen you that night?</p>
               <p>A. Royston. No. He said he was that night in Tottenham Street, at a public house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571207-16-person179">
                  William 
                  Weaver 
               <interp inst="t17571207-16-person179" type="surname" value="Weaver"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-16-person179" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-16-person179" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming from my daily labour at night. I live at Palmer's Green, in the parish of Edmonton. I know the prisoner at the bar very well, he lives at Tanner's end, Edmonton. It was moon-light. I heard a woman's voice, but did not know the words. I made up, and saw the prosecutrix stand stamping and crying. I ask'd her what was the matter. She said she was rob'd.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Weaver. On Friday night, the 18th of November. She told me what she was rob'd of, mentioning a gown, aprons, 10 s. 6 d. in gold, and 8 s. She did not tell me who rob'd her. She was going home to Southgate.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she describe what sort of a man he was?</p>
               <p>Weaver. She named no name. She described him.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at the prisoner. Did she describe such a sort of a man as he is.</p>
               <p>Weaver. She did. She said she was afraid to go home. I told her she had better go along with me, which she did, as far as the Fox at Palmer's Green. There we parted.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she tell you the person that rob'd her had made an attempt to lie with her?</p>
               <p>Weaver. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know her before?</p>
               <p>Weaver. I did very well.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571207-16-person180">
                  Thomas 
                  Stanley 
               <interp inst="t17571207-16-person180" type="surname" value="Stanley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-16-person180" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-16-person180" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the prosecutrix to be a very honest woman, she had been nursing my wife, and was going home at this time. I live in Silver Street, Edmonton. She went from my house about half an hour after five o'clock. My wife gave her two half guineas, and would have had<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175712070011"></xptr> her stay all night, but she said she was not afraid, she having gone that road so often.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutrix. Did you ever get your things again?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Stanley. I saw her the next morning about ten o'clock, I had heard before I saw her that she had been rob'd I said I was sorry for her loss. She said she knew the man as well as she did me, that he was about my height, with a flap'd hat on, his eyes a little sunk in his head, a black beard, a great coat, darkish hair or wig. I have known the prisoner about ten years. I never knew him to be deaf before. [The prisoner appear'd very deaf on his trial.]</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Stanley. Within these two months it has not been so good as before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17571207-16-person181">
                  John 
                  Newland 
               <interp inst="t17571207-16-person181" type="surname" value="Newland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-16-person181" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17571207-16-person181" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am headborough of the parish. The prosecutrix came to me on the Saturday, and told me she had been rob'd of two bundles, and about 18 s. in money. I ask'd her if she had got a warrant, she said no. I said do you know the person that rob'd you. She said yes I do, but Mr. Colebrook is not at home. I gave her a great charge to be sure that she knew him. She said she was confident she knew him very well. On the Monday morning the warrant was brought to me, I went and serv'd it on the prisoner, and took him into custody at his own house. He said for what is this warrant. I told him a woman had swore a robbery against him. He asked where the woman was, I said she is behind. The woman came, and the moment she saw him she said that is the man that rob'd me. The prisoner said he was at the Bull at Tanner's End. I took him there to see if any of the people knew him; the people said he came in there about seven o'clock at night, and staid till ten.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is that from the place where the woman was rob'd?</p>
               <p>Newland. It is almost a mile distance. Then we took him to the justice, who examin'd the prisoner. The woman was sworn, and said the same as here. The prisoner said he was at Tottenham in the dusk of the evening, that is about three quarters of a mile from the Bull, on the other side. The justice order'd me to take him there, and inquire, and then bring him before him, or some other justice. I took him there, the people said he was there about five o'clock, and that they lighted the first candles to give him change by. After that I inquir'd about of all I could, to here where he was about six o'clock, but could get no account of that. After that I took him before justice Galiand, he living near. There the woman said the same as now. The justice committed the prisoner. He own'd nothing.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>The woman came to my house on the Monday, and searched my house. I never saw her before in my life.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17571207-16-verdict89" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17571207-16-verdict89" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17571207-16-punish90" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17571207-16-punish90" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17571207-16-defend175 t17571207-16-punish90"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
