<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17550116-33">
               <interp inst="t17550116-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550116-33" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550116-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550116-33" type="date" value="17550116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550116-33-off170-c307" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-33-defend372 t17550116-33-off170 t17550116-33-verdict174"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550116-33-off170-c308" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-33-defend373 t17550116-33-off170 t17550116-33-verdict174"></join>
         
               <p>84, 85. (M. 2.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17550116-33-defend372" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Armstrong 
                  <interp inst="t17550116-33-defend372" type="surname" value="Armstrong"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-33-defend372" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-33-defend372" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               <persName id="t17550116-33-defend373" type="defendantName">
                  John, otherwise <rs id="t17550116-33-alias-6" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-33-defend373 t17550116-33-alias-6"></join>Thomas</rs> Welch<interp inst="t17550116-33-defend373" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-33-defend373" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , were indicted, for <rs id="t17550116-33-off170" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550116-33-off170" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-33-off170" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that they on the king's highway on 
                     <persName id="t17550116-33-victim374" type="victimName">
                        Francis 
                        Hall 
                     <interp inst="t17550116-33-victim374" type="surname" value="Hall"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550116-33-victim374" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550116-33-victim374" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-33-off170 t17550116-33-victim374"></join>
                     </persName>
                    did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and taking from his person 3 s. in money, numbered
            </rs>, <rs id="t17550116-33-cd171" type="crimeDate">Dec. 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-33-off170 t17550116-33-cd171"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>Francis Hall. I was robbed five weeks ago last Tuesday night of three or four shillings, but can't swear to the prisoners; there were three of them that robbed me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-33-person375">
                  John 
                  Courtney 
               <interp inst="t17550116-33-person375" type="surname" value="Courtney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-33-person375" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-33-person375" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 9th of December at night the two prisoners Armstrong and Welch, and I were in company together, and on the next day, being the 10th, we met at the Three Tuns at Aldgate about three o'clock, we had three pots of beer and half a pint of gin, after that we went to <placeName id="t17550116-33-crimeloc172">Islington-road</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17550116-33-crimeloc172" type="placeName" value="Islington-road"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550116-33-crimeloc172" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-33-off170 t17550116-33-crimeloc172"></join>, betwixt there and <placeName id="t17550116-33-crimeloc173">Highgate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17550116-33-crimeloc173" type="placeName" value="Highgate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550116-33-crimeloc173" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-33-off170 t17550116-33-crimeloc173"></join>, about six o'clock, we staid some time at a gate on the left-hand near the two-mile-stone, Armstrong was within-side the gate,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175501160035"></xptr> and Welch and I stopped a farmer that was coming by on horseback, we had him into that field; this was not Mr. Hall.</p>
               <p>J. Armstrong. That fellow will give an account of a dozen robberies, his wife * was hanged amongst the last people here, he has been a thief these seven years.</p>
               <p>*Eleanor Tobin, otherwise Woods.</p>
               <p>J. Courtney. About ten minutes after came the prosecutor Mr. Hall, Welch and I stopped him and brought him to the same place, we stopt the other at coming in at the gate, Armstrong laid hold of his bridle to bring him in, the prosecutor was a little obstropulous, and Welch struck him and laid hold of his bridle, and Armstrong went on the right-side, and I on the left; I took out of his left-pocket nothing but a penknife, Armstrong took out what money there was in his right-pocket, all the money I saw was one shilling and a penny; then I took hold of the bridle and led him to the gate again; I told him to make no words, and bid him a good night; he said, gentlemen, I wish you a good night, and thank you for all favours; then we went to the Thistle-and-crown near Charing-cross, there we had a nogin of rum, a pennyworth of gin and a pot of beer.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Do you remember any such words passing when you was robbed?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. By them words he mentions he must be there, for I repeated those words that he says; the least man struck me, and the tallest took my money away, I suppose that to be Armstrong.</p>
               <p>Note, Armstrong was the tallest man by about two inches, but at the time of these words speaking, he lowered his body down, and the other made the best of his height, so that they seemed much of a size, but in ten minutes time the court perceived the difference, as at first.</p>
               <p>On his cross examination he said, that after the robbery they stopped at a house in Holborn, and had two pots of beer, that he never saw the man at the Thistle-and-crown in his life before, that Armstrong bro ught them there, that he himself was taken up upon another robbery, that Armstrong and he were first acquainted at Bristol.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-33-person376">
                  Samuel 
                  Bromfield 
               <interp inst="t17550116-33-person376" type="surname" value="Bromfield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-33-person376" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-33-person376" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Thistle-and-crown, Charing-cross; I know Armstrong, I never saw the evidence or Welch but once before, the turnkey of Toshil-fields-bridewell was drinking in my house, when they all three came in; he called me to the door, and asked me if I knew them? I said none but Armstrong; he said, take care of them for they all three highwaymen.</p>
               <p>J. Armstrong. That man is a thief-catcher.</p>
               <p>S. Bromfield. I never took a thief in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. What day was it that they came to your house?</p>
               <p>S. Bromfield. I don't know justly, I know it was in December. Armstrong used frequently to come.</p>
               <p>Q. from Armstrong to Courtney. Where did you live in December?</p>
               <p>J. Courtney. I lodged at Welch's house then, I was there five weeks.</p>
               <p>J. Welch. I have no house, nor have had one these three years.</p>
               <p>J. Courtney. He has a house, and wife and children too at Dock-head.</p>
               <p>J. Welch. I have no wife; only the woman that I lodge with.</p>
               <p>Armstrong's defence.</p>
               <p>That evidence has been tried for piracy on the high-seas here, and after he came out, he came to my house (I kept a public house at Bristol) quite naked, and I shipped him to sea; he got in my debt about four or five pounds, and I never saw him till he came to London, at which time I thought I might have a chance to get my money, he told me he had made a very good voyage and would pay me. I lent him money since, and to make me amends he gets acquainted with thief-catchers to take away my life. After I was taken into custody he came to me, I asked him how he came to do this? he said, he did it to save his own life, but he would deny it all in court.</p>
               <p>J. Courtney. I never made such declaration in my life.</p>
               <p>J. Armstrong. He broke Liverpool gaol, and rescued 
               <persName id="t17550116-33-person377">
                  Nell 
                  Tobin 
               <interp inst="t17550116-33-person377" type="surname" value="Tobin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-33-person377" type="given" value="Nell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-33-person377" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and took four men with him to do it, and after that, he turned evidence in Lancaster gaol against them.</p>
               <p>J. Courtney. Those four men turned evidence against me.</p>
               <p>Welch's defence.</p>
               <p>I have no more to say than what I am going to tell you; I met the evidence at the Shepherd and dog below Tower-hill, with three or four men along with him; he had on a new jacket and a new pair of Trousers, singing very merrily. He asked me if I would drink? I said, I did not<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175501160036"></xptr> care if I did. He said, he was just come home from the West-Indies, and that he had got thirty pounds to receive in Broad-street, and he wanted somebody to get his R off. I gave him directions to call at my lodgings the next day, and I never saw him since, till I saw him before justice Fielding. I don't know whether he is a bad or a good man.</p>
               <p>Q. to Courtney. Did you meet Welch as he says.</p>
               <p>J. Courtney. The gentleman that keeps the Shepherd-and-dog knew Mr. Welch and I resorted together at his house more than five or six weeks ago several times. We never went in at his lodgings till dark night, because he did not care to be seen himself.</p>
               <p>For Armstrong.</p>
               <p>William Hailey. Armstrong had lent me four pounds and six pence, he took me up, and sent me to Whitechapel prison. I remained there five days. He wanted the money, and I could not afford it him then; in the mean time, he took compassion on me, and came to the prison and relieved me upon my note, which the gaol-keeper is a witness to. When my lodger came home, I got a little money; I sent him word to come, and I would pay him. He came on the 9th, and remained with me to the 12th of December. I paid him the money upon the nail, and he returned the note; I remember it on account of the date of the note.</p>

               <p>Q. Where is the note?</p>
               <p>W. Hailey. That I have burnt.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you with him every hour of that time?</p>
               <p>W. Hailey. I can't say I was; he lay every night in my house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he not go out in the time?</p>
               <p>W. Hailey. Not above a quarter of a mile in the time, to the best of my knowledge. He told me also he had a pain in his knee, and I had salves from the hospital, which he had applied to it, and thought they did him good.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>W. Hailey. I live in Southwark.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-33-person378">
                  Mary 
                  Cockland 
               <interp inst="t17550116-33-person378" type="surname" value="Cockland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-33-person378" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-33-person378" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I remember Armstrong being at Hailey's house on the 10th, 11th, and 12th of December. He was lame, and could not go out so much as he would. I lived with Hailey eight or nine months.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-33-person379">
                  Barnaby 
                  Horand 
               <interp inst="t17550116-33-person379" type="surname" value="Horand"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-33-person379" type="given" value="Barnaby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-33-person379" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the ship, by the victualling-office; I have known Armstrong four or five years; he behaved very civilly in my house; he was hardly five days absent from my house till this thing happened.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen Welch and Courtney with him?</p>
               <p>B. Horand. I have, at my house, with each of them; but never all three together.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-33-person380">
                  John 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17550116-33-person380" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-33-person380" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-33-person380" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Armstrong was a sergeant under my command, in the year 1745, in the duke of Montague's regiment. He did his duty as a soldier; I never had any complaint against him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550116-33-person381">
                  Thomas 
                  Haines 
               <interp inst="t17550116-33-person381" type="surname" value="Haines"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-33-person381" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-33-person381" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Welch was a ship-mate of mine on board the Crown man of war; he behaved well there, and bore a very good character.</p>
               <p>+ Both <rs id="t17550116-33-verdict174" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550116-33-verdict174" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17550116-33-punish175" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550116-33-punish175" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-33-defend372 t17550116-33-punish175"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550116-33-defend373 t17550116-33-punish175"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>See No. 46, 47. in alderman Rawlinson's mayoralty, in the indictment, 
               <persName id="t17550116-33-person382">
                  John 
                  Welch 
               <interp inst="t17550116-33-person382" type="surname" value="Welch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-33-person382" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550116-33-person382" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the younger.</p>
            </div1>
