<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17550702-1">
               <interp inst="t17550702-1" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550702-1" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550702-1" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550702"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550702-1" type="date" value="17550702"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550702-1-off1-c28" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550702-1-defend29 t17550702-1-off1 t17550702-1-verdict4"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550702-1-off1-c29" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550702-1-defend31 t17550702-1-off1 t17550702-1-verdict4"></join>
         
               <p>251, 252. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17550702-1-defend29" type="defendantName">
                     Susannah 
                     Bird 
                  <interp inst="t17550702-1-defend29" type="surname" value="Bird"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550702-1-defend29" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550702-1-defend29" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17550702-1-defend31" type="defendantName">
                     Hannah 
                     Morris 
                  <interp inst="t17550702-1-defend31" type="surname" value="Morris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550702-1-defend31" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550702-1-defend31" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17550702-1-off1" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550702-1-off1" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550702-1-off1" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one linen handkerchief, value 10 d.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17550702-1-victim33" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Weedon 
                  <interp inst="t17550702-1-victim33" type="surname" value="Weedon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550702-1-victim33" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550702-1-victim33" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550702-1-off1 t17550702-1-victim33"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17550702-1-cd2" type="crimeDate">May 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550702-1-off1 t17550702-1-cd2"></join>.* </p>
               <p>John Weedon. On the 29th of May, I was in <placeName id="t17550702-1-crimeloc3">the King's-bench, Guildhall</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17550702-1-crimeloc3" type="placeName" value="the King's-bench, Guildhall"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550702-1-crimeloc3" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550702-1-off1 t17550702-1-crimeloc3"></join>, to hear a trial; one Mr. Tolderoy told me he saw the prisoner Bird take a handkerchief out of my pocket; I felt, and missed mine; I charged an officer with her; she was taken into another room; and, upon searching her, my handkerchief was found lying underneath her as she stood.</p>
               <p>Q. How come you to charge the other prisoner?</p>
               <p>Weedon. The witness did that; seeing them, as he said, busy together.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550702-1-person34">
                  Thomas 
                  Tolderoy 
               <interp inst="t17550702-1-person34" type="surname" value="Tolderoy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550702-1-person34" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550702-1-person34" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the court of King's-bench, Guildhall, on the 29th of May, being subpoened there on a trial. I saw the two prisoners come, and by their behaviour, I thought them to be pick-pockets; they were very busy about a gentleman's pocket, and I told him to take care, for I thought they had pick'd his pocket; he said he had felt a hand in his pocket, but had lost nothing, having secured his handkerchief before; then they moved to another part of the court. I saw them go to the prosecutor, and as they were both standing together by him, I saw a handerchief lifted up from his pocket; I know not which of the prisoners took it out, but I saw Bird conceal it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Morris make any attempt on the other gentleman's pocket.</p>
               <p>Tolderoy. I can't say I did; Bird seemed to be the busiest; they appeared as companions.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the handkerchief found again?</p>
               <p>Tolderoy. I did; it was found under Bird's cloaths as she was standing.</p>
               <p>Q. Which was nearest the prosecutor when you saw it taken?</p>
               <p>Tolderoy. I can't say which was nearest.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was you to them at the time?</p>
               <p>Tolderoy. I believe I was about ten yards distance.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550702-1-person35">
                  Marmaduke 
                  Gibson 
               <interp inst="t17550702-1-person35" type="surname" value="Gibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550702-1-person35" type="given" value="Marmaduke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550702-1-person35" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 29th of May I was in the King's-bench, Guildhall; the two prisoners were pretty near me, attempting a gentleman's pocket; the last witness and I tap'd him on the shoulder, and ask'd him, if he had not lost any thing; he said he felt a hand in his pocket, but he had secured his handkerchief; then<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175507020003"></xptr> the prisoners removed to where the prosecutor was. I had my eye upon them, and saw the prisoner Morris take a handkerchief from his pocket, the other prisoner was then close by her; they had walk'd round the hall together. After Bird was secured, I saw the handkerchief under her; which the prosecutor swears was his. (The handkerchief produced in court, and deposed to.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550702-1-person36">
                  John 
                  Percifull 
               <interp inst="t17550702-1-person36" type="surname" value="Percifull"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550702-1-person36" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550702-1-person36" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was charged with Bird, and took her into the sitting alderman's room; there searching her, I found the handkerchief under her cloaths. The prosecutor said it was his. After that, I was charged with the other prisoner, and I insisted upon searching her, but she said she would not be searched by me or any body else; but I searched her, and found only one handkerchief upon her (producing it.)</p>
               <p>Morris. That is my own handkerchief.</p>
               <p>Bird's defence.</p>
               <p>I am innocent of the fact.</p>
               <p>Morris's defence.</p>
               <p>I was but just come into the hall as they took me; I know nothing of this woman, ( pointing to her fellow-prisoner.) I was not with her.</p>
               <p>Q. to Tolderoy. Are you sure you saw Morris with Bird when the handkerchief was taken?</p>
               <p>Tolderoy. I am certain of it; and that they were together before that was taken.</p>
               <p>Gibson answered the same to the question.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17550702-1-verdict4" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550702-1-verdict4" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17550702-1-punish5" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550702-1-punish5" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550702-1-defend29 t17550702-1-punish5"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550702-1-defend31 t17550702-1-punish5"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
