<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510116-77">
               <interp inst="t17510116-77" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510116-77" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510116-77" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510116-77" type="date" value="17510116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510116-77-off352-c507" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-77-defend642 t17510116-77-off352 t17510116-77-verdict353"></join>
         
               <p>186 . 
               <persName id="t17510116-77-defend642" type="defendantName">
                  Christopher 
                  Green 
               <interp inst="t17510116-77-defend642" type="surname" value="Green"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-77-defend642" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-77-defend642" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for that <rs id="t17510116-77-off352" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510116-77-off352" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-77-off352" type="offenceSubcategory" value="perjury"></interp>
               he being married to 
                     <persName id="t17510116-77-victim643" type="victimName">
                        Jane 
                        Wilmote 
                     <interp inst="t17510116-77-victim643" type="surname" value="Wilmote"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510116-77-victim643" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510116-77-victim643" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-77-off352 t17510116-77-victim643"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , notwithstanding he came before my lord chief justice Lee, and took an oath, that he never was married to the said Jane
            </rs>. ++</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17510116-77-person644">
                  Benjamin 
                  Thomas 
               <interp inst="t17510116-77-person644" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-77-person644" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-77-person644" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am clerk to my lord chief justice Lee. This is an information made by Christopher Green and 
               <persName id="t17510116-77-person645">
                  William 
                  Richards 
               <interp inst="t17510116-77-person645" type="surname" value="Richards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-77-person645" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-77-person645" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and sworn to by them, as it appears before my lord chief justice Lee. This is his hand-writing, sign'd here. [Holding the paper in his hand.] I have good reason to think my lord chief justice would never have subscribed his hand to it, had it not been administered; but as many people come and make affidavits at my lord chief justice's chambers, I cannot recollect the defendant to be the man that brought this.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-77-person646">
                  William 
                  Richards 
               <interp inst="t17510116-77-person646" type="surname" value="Richards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-77-person646" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-77-person646" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The defendant, Christopher Green and I went to my lord chief justice Lee's chambers to exhibit an information. [The affidavit is put into his hand] This is it, I wrote the name 
               <persName id="t17510116-77-person647">
                  William 
                  Richards 
               <interp inst="t17510116-77-person647" type="surname" value="Richards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-77-person647" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-77-person647" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to it, and it is his name, and what I swear there I now believe is true.</p>
               <p>It is read in Court.</p>
               <p>One part of it is what is contained in the indictment that is, that this informant Christopher Green, maketh oath, that he was never married to 
               <persName id="t17510116-77-person648">
                  Jane 
                  Wilmot 
               <interp inst="t17510116-77-person648" type="surname" value="Wilmot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-77-person648" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-77-person648" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-77-person649">
                  William 
                  Newton 
               <interp inst="t17510116-77-person649" type="surname" value="Newton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-77-person649" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-77-person649" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Christopher Green about two years; about four, five, or six weeks before Christmas 1747. I was then living in Watch-street. he came to my house; he then called himself Hill and said, he lived at Ports-mouth, and had a very considerable estate. He visited my sister-in-law 
               <persName id="t17510116-77-person650">
                  Jane 
                  Wilmot 
               <interp inst="t17510116-77-person650" type="surname" value="Wilmot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-77-person650" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-77-person650" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             at my house; I went into the west of England, and made it my business to enquire at Portsmouth. but could not hear of such a person; my sister in law went into a service, I believe at Chelsea; he came to our house to enquire for her a little before Christmas, the same year; he asked me and my wife what was become of Jenny? After a great many protestations, he was told where she was, then he immediately went away to her: he told me, he courted her for no other end but to make her his wife. I am a taylor ; he gave me orders to make him some cloaths, which I did, almost three suits; when I was measuring him, I said, are these to be your wedding cloaths ? he said, yes. I sent them to him in the county, according to his direction. I did not see him till Midsummer-day. 1748, he came to my house ; she came to him; I cannot say I heard what passed between them, he asked me, if I could take a walk with him that evening? I told him I could not, having some business to do; he and Jenny went out together, and I did not see them till 3 or 4 days after, then he called for his bill; he looked it over; then said he, does my wife owe you any thing? No, said I; then he paid me. I asked him if he was married, he said, yes; they then went to live in Round-court, at one Mr. Humphrys's  he cohabited with her there, as man and wife; I was never there but twice the time they lived there; I now live in Prince's-street by Red-lion-square.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Newton deposed to the same purport, with this addition ; sometimes he would be at our house three or four times a week, and sometimes once in six weeks.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-77-person651">
                  Evan 
                  Humphrys 
               <interp inst="t17510116-77-person651" type="surname" value="Humphrys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-77-person651" type="given" value="Evan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-77-person651" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I did live in Round-court in the Strand; Mr. Green and Mrs. Green came and took a lodging of me, about six weeks before Midsummer, but did not come to live there till Midsummer day ; we agreed at 9 l. a year; he called Mrs. Green, my dear, and Jenny.</p>
               <p>Q. Who do you mean by Mrs. Green?</p>
               <p>Humphrys. The former evidence's sister-in-law, he went down into the country; and what letters he sent up to Jenny, I used to deliver to her; she<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175101160039"></xptr> staid at my house after that about a quarter of a year; and I never saw them together afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live now ?</p>
               <p>Humphrys. That I don't care to tell.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Humphrys deposition was to the same effect with that of her husband.</p>
               <p>[ Jenny produced a writing, which she called a certificate of her marriage at the Fleet.]</p>
               <p>Mrs. Newton. I saw this certificate signed by Boyce and Hammond, taken from the register-book in the liberty of the Fleet, in the custody of Boyce, and that dear Jenny gave a shilling for.</p>
               <p>Boyce and Hammond were called, but neither appeared.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510116-77-verdict353" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510116-77-verdict353" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
