<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17540911-28">
               <interp inst="t17540911-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-28" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-28" type="date" value="17540911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540911-28-off157-c216" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-28-defend267 t17540911-28-off157 t17540911-28-verdict159"></join>
         
               <p>443. (L) 
               <persName id="t17540911-28-defend267" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Thomas 
                     Keel 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17540911-28-alias-2" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-28-defend267 t17540911-28-alias-2"></join>Keen</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-28-defend267" type="surname" value="Keel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-28-defend267" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-28-defend267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17540911-28-off157" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540911-28-off157" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-28-off157" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one silver milk mug, val. 14 s.
            </rs> the property of certain persons unknown, <rs id="t17540911-28-cd158" type="crimeDate">Sept. 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-28-off157 t17540911-28-cd158"></join>.* </p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-28-person269">
                  Levi 
                  Joshua 
               <interp inst="t17540911-28-person269" type="surname" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-28-person269" type="given" value="Levi"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-28-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner came to the Broad court, Duke's place, and offered a milk pot to sell for 3 s. 6 d. about three weeks ago, I don't know the exact time.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he offer it to you?</p>
               <p>Joshua. No, it was to other people near my door. The pot produced in court.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say it was silver?</p>
               <p>Joshua. No, he did not in my hearing. I asked him how he came by it, he said his uncle gave it him, and after that he said he found it.</p>

               <p>Lion Toby. I am constable. This evidence brought the prisoner to my house, and gave me charge of him, and said he had offered a silver chas'd milk pot to sell for 3 s. 6 d. I asked him how he came by it, he said his uncle gave it him, but could not tell where he lived. After that he said he found it on a dunghill, I think somewhere near Croydon.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was in the country about eleven miles from London, I found this mug. Coming by Aldgate there was a Jew standing, who asked me if I would sell it, I said yes: then he said come along with me, and carried me to a publick house, where I gave him two pints of beer. Then he went out a considerable time, and came in again, and said he would go and weigh it. After that came in this man, and a man that had it in his hand flung it away, they took it up and secured me.</p>
               <p>Q. to Joshua. Was there another man with him?</p>
               <p>Joshua. There was, but he ran away, and the prisoner was going to run away too.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540911-28-verdict159" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540911-28-verdict159" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acq.
            </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
