<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17501017-7">
               <interp inst="t17501017-7" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501017-7" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501017-7" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17501017"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501017-7" type="date" value="17501017"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17501017-7-off37-c71" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-7-defend84 t17501017-7-off37 t17501017-7-verdict42"></join>
         
               <p>625. 
               
                  <persName id="t17501017-7-defend84" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Thursel 
                  <interp inst="t17501017-7-defend84" type="surname" value="Thursel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-7-defend84" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-7-defend84" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-7-defend84" type="age" value="14 years of age"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17501017-7-deflabel36" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-7-defend84 t17501017-7-deflabel36"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17501017-7-off37" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501017-7-off37" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-7-off37" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 20 s. in money, numbered
            </rs>, the money of 
               
                  <persName id="t17501017-7-victim86" type="victimName">
                     George 
                     Layland 
                  <interp inst="t17501017-7-victim86" type="surname" value="Layland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-7-victim86" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-7-victim86" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-7-off37 t17501017-7-victim86"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17501017-7-cd38" type="crimeDate">September 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-7-off37 t17501017-7-cd38"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501017-7-person87">
                  George 
                  Layland 
               <interp inst="t17501017-7-person87" type="surname" value="Layland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-7-person87" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-7-person87" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17501017-7-crimeloc39">Clerkenwell</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17501017-7-crimeloc39" type="placeName" value="Clerkenwell"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17501017-7-crimeloc39" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-7-off37 t17501017-7-crimeloc39"></join>. The prisoner was my <rs id="t17501017-7-deflabel40" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-7-defend84 t17501017-7-deflabel40"></join> for about three weeks or a month. My wife and I <rs id="t17501017-7-viclabel41" type="occupation">go with milk into the city</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-7-victim86 t17501017-7-viclabel41"></join>. Last Sunday was fortnight we went out, and left her in charge of our child; coming home between five and six o'clock she was not there; I went to her mother's, her mother said she had not seen her; her mother had got information she was met going towards Newington, and no child with her. I went to break the door open, there I found the key put in on one side the door; when I got up into my room, which was a garret, I found the child crying, all black in the face, weakened very much, and lies in a dangerous way now. I went to my drawer to examine my cow-keeper's money, and I found but 23 s. instead of 45 or 46 s. I pay my cow-man every Monday morning. Besides this, there were 7 l. all but 5 s. two gold rings, and a watch. She took 15 s. out of that, and I believe out of the cow-keeper's money she took upwards of 20 s. then I ran again to her mother, and told her; she said she was told she was gone with two girls to Cold Bath-fields; I went to meet them, and found them; I took hold of her, and said she had robbed me; we brought her towards Bridewell, and near the gate she said she had taken out a handful of all silver, and did not reckon it, and that she had wrapt it in a paper, and hid it under the step that goes up into Faulcon-court. This was a place near our own door; when we came there it was gone.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501017-7-person88">
                  Anne 
                  Abrahams 
               <interp inst="t17501017-7-person88" type="surname" value="Abrahams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-7-person88" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-7-person88" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live next door to the prosecutor. I have known the prisoner something above five years, she is about 14 years of age. I keep a chandler's shop. On Sunday was fortnight I was sitting by my own fire, I heard a noise, and got up to hear what was the matter; the prosecutor said the girl had robbed him; we took her into a neighbour's house, the girl very much denied it; we all thought to make it up, he said he was willing to make it up, if he could tell where to have his money. Then they took the girl away towards Bridewell; the prisoner's mother was there, she much desired her mother to pay the money, but still said she was quite innocent of it. Her mother said it was not in her power, and bid the girl tell where it was, if she had it. When we came to Bridewell-gate, she said, master, if you will not put me to Bridewell, I will confess what I have done with it. She said she drew the staple and took the money out, and was afraid it would be found upon her; so she put it under a post at the steps going down Faulcon-court on the right hand side. I did not go along with them to look for it, but they came back again, and said it was gone.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Woodward Harlow. The prosecutor had got hold of the girl at this time, and sent for me; I came, the girl denied it; at last, by his threatning and her mother persuading her to tell, she did confess; then she was brought back from Bridewell-gate to our shuffleboard-room. I went with the girl to the place where she said it was; we went to the step and could not find it. The girl in coming back said to me, because I was good-natured to him, and would not trouble him, he now would put me to trouble, saying, her master had ravished her, and given her the foul disease. I told him what the girl said; said he, the girl used to lie at the foot of our bed with my wife and I, and that once when she got out of bed he did take hold of her hand, and would have pulled her into bed, but as to ravishing her he never did. At this time the girl indeed confessed it, because her master promised not to send her to gaol if she would; this she said before her master's face.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501017-7-person89">
                  Mary 
                  James 
               <interp inst="t17501017-7-person89" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-7-person89" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-7-person89" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the girl eight or nine years, she has always had a very honest character.</p>
               <p>Isabella Jones. I have known her about five years, she lived with me; my drawers used to be open where she might have taken money out had she been so inclined. I never lost any to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501017-7-person90">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Nightingale 
               <interp inst="t17501017-7-person90" type="surname" value="Nightingale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-7-person90" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-7-person90" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have not lived in the neighbourhood above six months. When she was searched there were three half-pence found in her pocket; she then declared she knew nothing of the money, and said likewise her master had used her<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175010170007"></xptr> very ill, and he bid her say she had stole this money and he would bring her off. I never heard any thing but what was very honest of her. The girl has a very bad distemper on her, and they say he has the same.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501017-7-person91">
                  Mary 
                  House 
               <interp inst="t17501017-7-person91" type="surname" value="House"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-7-person91" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-7-person91" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner two years, she has been often at my house, I never lost any thing by her nor heard ill of her.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Alcock. I have known her these five years and upwards, I never heard any ill of her.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17501017-7-verdict42" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501017-7-verdict42" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquit
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
