<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510116-64">
               <interp inst="t17510116-64" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510116-64" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510116-64" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510116-64" type="date" value="17510116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510116-64-off299-c432" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-64-defend547 t17510116-64-off299 t17510116-64-verdict302"></join>
         
               <p>173. 
               <persName id="t17510116-64-defend547" type="defendantName">
                  William 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17510116-64-defend547" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-64-defend547" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-64-defend547" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , (M.) was indicted for <rs id="t17510116-64-off299" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510116-64-off299" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-64-off299" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing one grey gelding , value 3 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17510116-64-victim549" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Southal 
                  <interp inst="t17510116-64-victim549" type="surname" value="Southal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-64-victim549" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-64-victim549" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-64-off299 t17510116-64-victim549"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17510116-64-cd300" type="crimeDate">Jan. 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-64-off299 t17510116-64-cd300"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-64-person550">
                  John 
                  Southal 
               <interp inst="t17510116-64-person550" type="surname" value="Southal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-64-person550" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-64-person550" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live near <placeName id="t17510116-64-crimeloc301">Rumsey in Hampshire</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17510116-64-crimeloc301" type="placeName" value="Rumsey in Hampshire"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510116-64-crimeloc301" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510116-64-off299 t17510116-64-crimeloc301"></join>; on New years day at night I sent my son out to give the horses some hay, about 10'clock the dog bark'd, I said somebody is about the house; I desired my son to get up, he did; this was about one o'clock; the horse was gone.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Southal. Yes, my lord. I did, his father lives about a mile off from me: this horse had but half a shoe on one of his feet behind; we went out the next morning to see for him about 9 o'clock. I track'd him out through a hurdle, and up a little lane, to a gentleman's wood, and so to a place called Broughton ; when we came there, we traced the half shoe again, and other horses with him, till we came almost to Stone; then we met a road waggoner, and inquired of him, if he met any such horse? I did, he said; said he, you are a long way behind: said I, how far may he be got? said he, as far as Basingstoke, and there were with him a black horse with a hog-mane; then I did not try to track him till I came to Basingstoke ; and I inquired there, whether any body had seen such a horse go by? we were told there was; so we came along for London road: we kept on all night; when we came out into a lane, we met another road waggon about two in the morning, We asked him, he told us he had seen such a horse, saying it was a grey one, about the size of his own, which mine was. Said he, I met him as far off as Blackwater. We kept along all night, and the next morning happened to be very wet, they had put in their horses, and we got before them at Hounslow turnpike. The turnpike man told us no such men were gone by, for we had them described to us before; I said remember if you can, he said indeed he did not remember any such going by; I looked out at his door, and said I think they be coming, and so it was. I peep'd out at the door, when the prisoner came up on my horse; I said, how didst thou come here? I am got here before you; there was another fellow on horseback behind<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175101160032"></xptr> him, he ran down street, and into a gentleman's garden. I ran after and catch'd him; he appeared to be a man he had taken up to carry on the road for a mug or two of drink. The other man on the black horse rode back as hard as he could, we could not catch him, he had a woman behind him, and he threw her down into a pond; she appeared to be wife to the other man, coming to London.</p>
               <p>Said I to the prisoner, how came you by this horse? said he, he had been in a pound, and was brought to me; I took him to a justice near there; the justice ask'd him where he was going; said he, to service: said the justice, how much money hast thou in thy pocket? said he, but six-pence; said the justice, thou settest out very empty; the saddle was mine.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510116-64-person551">
                  Solomon 
                  Southal 
               <interp inst="t17510116-64-person551" type="surname" value="Southal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-64-person551" type="given" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-64-person551" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at my father's house at this time. My father went to bed this night, and I set up with my brother; my younger brother went to serve the horses about 10 o'clock. I was with him with the horses, there were this little grey one and two others, after that we went to bed about one o'clock; the dog barked, I and my brother got up again; we missed this horse out of the stable; the stable door stood open, and one of the other horses was out. We hunted about the garden, but could not find the little horse; and in the morning, we got up and went out at a little back hurdle, where we tracked him; there was a half shoe missing on his near foot behind; the ground being soft where he went out, we could track him along a lane, and by a wood and a back by way, away to Broughton to the Champway ; then we could do nothing till we got up into the fields; there we could track him again out at a hurdle; we went through Stockbridge, there we could do nothing. When we got into the field, there we could track the half shoe again; but when we got to Stone, there we supposed he slung that half shoe, for it seemed to be barefooted. Just before we came to Stone, we met a road waggoner, who told us he met them just on this side Basingstoke: saying there were two fellows, and two horses; one a black horse, a hog-mane, and short cut tail, the other a grey horse. We came on in London road to Brentford ; the moon shone very bright when we came there; when we passed the turnpike, said I, I'll step back and ask this man if he has let any such men through; I did, said he, to the best of my knowledge I have not, in about a minute I saw something like them: my father had got a little hedge stake, and jumped out of the house and hit the prisoner; and I jumped out and ran on the other side the horse; the prisoner had a man behind him; he was surprised and slip'd off the rump of the horse, and ran through the turnpike gate as fast as he could, and my father ran after him; the other man, he had got this man's wife behind him; he pushed her off, and said, I must go back, I have forgot something; I tied the prisoner's hands together and took him to a publick house, and gave him a mug or two of beer, then had him before a justice; the justice asked him how he came by this horse? he said, he was brought to him; said the justice, I think thou hadst very good friends; whither art thou going? he could not tell, then after that he said, he was going to service; the justice ask'd him, how much money he had in his pocket? he said, he had but six pence; he told him, that was but little money to go with, to enter into a service at London.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I never was in the stable in my life; the man's kinsman 
               <persName id="t17510116-64-person552">
                  John 
                  Rug 
               <interp inst="t17510116-64-person552" type="surname" value="Rug"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-64-person552" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-64-person552" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             brought the horse to me.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17510116-64-person553">
                  John 
                  Southal 
               <interp inst="t17510116-64-person553" type="surname" value="Southal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-64-person553" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-64-person553" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Have you a kinsman of that name?</p>
               <p>Southal. Yes, my lord, I have; I am his uncle.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you give him orders to let the prisoner have this horse?</p>
               <p>Southal. No, my lord, I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see him?</p>
               <p>Southal. I have not seen him this never hardly.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he live with you?</p>
               <p>Southal. No, my lord, I live in Hampshire, and he lives in Somersetshire.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think that was your kinsman Rug, who rode back in such haste when you took the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Southal. I don't know, my lord, but it was.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think it was?</p>
               <p>Southal. I did not see his face, but by his back part it was like him.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17510116-64-person554">
                  Solomon 
                  Southal 
               <interp inst="t17510116-64-person554" type="surname" value="Southal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-64-person554" type="given" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510116-64-person554" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Do you believe that man was, or was not your kinsman?</p>
               <p>Southal. My lord, I do believe it was; by all the descriptions we had of him it was.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510116-64-verdict302" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510116-64-verdict302" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
