<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17511016-7">
               <interp inst="t17511016-7" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511016-7" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511016-7" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17511016"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17511016-7" type="date" value="17511016"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17511016-7-off33-c63" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-7-defend75 t17511016-7-off33 t17511016-7-verdict36"></join>
         
               <p>550. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17511016-7-defend75" type="defendantName">
                     Alice 
                     Nixon 
                  <interp inst="t17511016-7-defend75" type="surname" value="Nixon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-7-defend75" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-7-defend75" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17511016-7-deflabel32" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-7-defend75 t17511016-7-deflabel32"></join>, was indicted for that she, together with 
               <persName id="t17511016-7-person76">
                  James 
                  Drinkwater 
               <interp inst="t17511016-7-person76" type="surname" value="Drinkwater"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-7-person76" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-7-person76" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Anne his wife, not yet taken, <rs id="t17511016-7-off33" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17511016-7-off33" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-7-off33" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               one pair of silver shoe buckles, one watch chain, one guinea, one half guinea, the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17511016-7-victim78" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Savage 
                        <interp inst="t17511016-7-victim78" type="surname" value="Savage"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17511016-7-victim78" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17511016-7-victim78" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-7-off33 t17511016-7-victim78"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , did steal privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17511016-7-cd34" type="crimeDate">Sept. 29. +</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-7-off33 t17511016-7-cd34"></join>
               </p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17511016-7-person79">
                  John 
                  Savage 
               <interp inst="t17511016-7-person79" type="surname" value="Savage"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-7-person79" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-7-person79" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Coming along the fields to go to Old-street church, I struck out at the end of Red Lion-street; at the end of the street I met two or three fellows that had belonged to the ship that I had done; after I had parted from them, a woman that is not here took hold on my arm and said, she would treat me; this was at <placeName id="t17511016-7-crimeloc35">Blackmary's hole</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17511016-7-crimeloc35" type="placeName" value="Blackmary's hole"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17511016-7-crimeloc35" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17511016-7-off33 t17511016-7-crimeloc35"></join>; I went in, and up stairs we had seven or eight bottles of wine and water mixed together, then I had 18 shillings in silver, and a guinea and half by themselves in my sob; my money was soon squandered, I found my head giddy and wanted to lie down, which was granted; I had my silver buckles in my shoes; then there were four of them in the room when I went to sleep, 
               <persName id="t17511016-7-person80">
                  James 
                  Drinkwater 
               <interp inst="t17511016-7-person80" type="surname" value="Drinkwater"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-7-person80" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17511016-7-person80" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , his wife, she that picked me up first, and the prisoner; I had not known the man's name, had I not heard his wife say, Drinkwater, get up,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175110160006"></xptr> after that she called him James; so I thought I'd take notice of that. I lay to sleep on my side to preserve my guinea and half, which I then felt there by putting my thumb down in my pocket. I awaked when the clock strack three, I heard it, there was nobody in the room; I knocked, Drinkwater's wife came up, I said I was very cold; I went down stairs with her, I trod on one of my straps as I was going down, I look'd, my silver buckles were taken out ; when Drinkwater's wife came down I asked her where were my buckles; said she, damning her blood, did not you sell them because you had no money, calling me impudent son of a bitch? I said no, I had no occasion, for I had money about me, going to feel for the guinea, and I found it was gone also; she went to her husband, who came in with a knife in his hand, and said to me, don't play any tricks here, but sign this paper, he had a paper in his hand already wrote; he said I sold them for twelve shillings; I signed the paper, but it was through fear; Drinkwater's wife had the buckles in her hand at that time; then they were very agreeable; I asked if I should stay till quite day, I knew I could lose no more than I had lost, so I staid, I went to bed and lay with the prisoner, I could not sleep, she asked me several times why I did not go to sleep; they asked me to stay breakfast; we had all a dram a-piece at six o'clock, and out of the house I went, and promised them to be there at breakfast; then I went for a warrant, but the justice was not up. The prisoner had nothing to say, nor called any witnesses.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17511016-7-verdict36" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17511016-7-verdict36" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
