<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17501205-60">
               <interp inst="t17501205-60" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501205-60" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501205-60" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17501205"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501205-60" type="date" value="17501205"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17501205-60-off306-c387" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501205-60-defend510 t17501205-60-off306 t17501205-60-verdict309"></join>
         
               <p>75. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17501205-60-defend510" type="defendantName">
                     Henry 
                     Stroud 
                  <interp inst="t17501205-60-defend510" type="surname" value="Stroud"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-60-defend510" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-60-defend510" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for the <rs id="t17501205-60-off306" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501205-60-off306" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-60-off306" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               murder
            </rs> of 
               
                  <persName id="t17501205-60-victim512" type="victimName">
                     Richard 
                     Chamberlain 
                  <interp inst="t17501205-60-victim512" type="surname" value="Chamberlain"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-60-victim512" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-60-victim512" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501205-60-off306 t17501205-60-victim512"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17501205-60-cd307" type="crimeDate">December 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501205-60-off306 t17501205-60-cd307"></join>, and he also stood charged on the coroner's inquisition for slaving the said Richard. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-60-person513">
                  William 
                  Barnwell 
               <interp inst="t17501205-60-person513" type="surname" value="Barnwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-60-person513" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-60-person513" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The deceased lived in <placeName id="t17501205-60-crimeloc308">Kingsland Road</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17501205-60-crimeloc308" type="placeName" value="Kingsland Road"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17501205-60-crimeloc308" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501205-60-off306 t17501205-60-crimeloc308"></join>, and I lodged at his house.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he die?</p>
               <p>Barnwell. Last Saturday was se'nnight, my lord; I happened to come in about nine o'clock that night; he wanted some victuals ; I said he had no occasion to go out for any. I had a piece of a hog's face, so he and I sat down to it; I went and fetched a full pot of beer; after that there were words between his wife and he, but I don't know upon what occasion; at first he threw the candlestick at her, then he took up the box iron, I cannot say he threw that; he rose up in a passion, knock'd her down, and then knock'd her daughter down; the prisoner came in at that time, and endeavoured to prevent him beating his wife; then Chamberlain struck the prisoner several blows with his fist, and tore his coat.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Chamberlain appear to be in liquor?</p>
               <p>Barnwell. He did, my lord, he was disguised when he and I sat down to eat; then Mr. Fishook came in, who is the deceased's wife's brother, and lives at the next door; he struck the deceased over the eye; then he went home again; Chamberlain stripp'd himself to fight Fishook, and went to his house; Fishook's wife was standing by her fire side ; she said, pray, Richard, don't strike my husband, for he has a wound on his head already (that was done a night or two before) then Mr. Stroud came in and said to the deceased, Dick, you have hit me several blows, now I have a great mind to hit you one, so he struck him two or three blows with his fist on his breast, upon which the deceased fell down and never spoke more.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-60-person514">
                  Martha 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17501205-60-person514" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-60-person514" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-60-person514" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was up stairs at this Fishook's house, and heard a great scuffle betwixt Fishook and his brother in law; Mr. Fishook bid him get away, saying, he had got a broken head already; he did not go directly; then the prisoner came in and swung the deceased out of Fishook's arms, saying to him, if you can't manage him, I can; then he clapp'd him up against the closet door, and going to strike the deceased, the deceased ran his head into his bosom; Stroud gave him a blow, and he fell down directly.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you at this time?</p>
               <p>M. Harris. I was standing upon the stairs; I saw but one blow.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-60-person515">
                  Mary 
                  Chamberlain 
               <interp inst="t17501205-60-person515" type="surname" value="Chamberlain"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-60-person515" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-60-person515" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am widow to the deceased; he was a coleheaver; he had some money in his pocket, which I wanted to make up my rent; I shut the door fearing he would spend it, so he struck me over the head; my girl came up and he struck her; then Stroud came up and took him away; he took up a box iron to fling at me, but was prevented by a woman who took it from him; he slung a candlestick but it did not hit me; Fishook my brother came in and they had a hustle at the table, but cannot say there were any blows: my husband pulled off his cloaths after my brother was gone, and ran to his house to fight him: Mrs. Fishook said, for God's sake take care of my husband's head, because that had been cut the Sunday night before; then Henry Stroud came into Fishook's and said to my husband, you have struck me many a blow, I'll now strike you, and went up to him, but indeed I can't say I saw the prisoner strike him, or my husband strike the prisoner; I believe there was no malice between them, not any design for mischief.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-60-person516">
                  Mary 
                  Wake 
               <interp inst="t17501205-60-person516" type="surname" value="Wake"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-60-person516" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-60-person516" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in Chamberlain's house, and saw Mr. Fishook beat the deceased over the face; after that he went into his own apartment ; the deceased<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175012050031"></xptr> stripp'd himself in a minute, and swore he would fight him; Mrs. Chamberlain said to the prisoner, for God's sake, don't let him go out for he is mad, and 
               <persName id="t17501205-60-person517">
                  Henry 
                  Stroud 
               <interp inst="t17501205-60-person517" type="surname" value="Stroud"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-60-person517" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-60-person517" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             followed him in order to part them. I saw no more.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-60-person518">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Millet 
               <interp inst="t17501205-60-person518" type="surname" value="Millet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-60-person518" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-60-person518" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in Mr. Chamberlain's house between seven and eight o'clock that night, his wife came in and set herself down by him; he beat her so that she fell down, and the candle went out; Mr. Stroud came and took him off from her ; Mr. Fishook came in, but I can't say I saw any blows, except what were between the deceased and his wife; when Fishook was gone, Chamberlain stripp'd himself and went out at the door; I did not follow them, so saw no more.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-60-person519">
                  Hannah 
                  Perry 
               <interp inst="t17501205-60-person519" type="surname" value="Perry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-60-person519" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-60-person519" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the same house the deceased did, and saw the beginning of it; I was by when they fell out, and the deceased attempted to fling a box iron at his wife; I took it out of his hand ; Mr. Stroud did whatever lay in his power to keep peace between them. I saw no blows at all.</p>
               <p>Mr. Simpson. I am a surgeon. The accident was on the Saturday, and on Monday I saw the body of the deceased, and there seemed several bruises on his head and his face, but nothing of consequence, they were only in the skin ; I examined the lungs, the heart, the stomach, and all the noble parts of the body, but could not find any bruise or contusion that could be the cause of his death; there was no outward appearance of any blow given that could be the cause of it; it must be something internal; the blood might, by receiving a blow on his stomach, be driven into the brain, and give him an apoplexy; I could not account for his death, so was obliged to enquire if he had not been drinking, which, when I found, can give no other reason for his death than this, but it is impossible to be certain about it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>When I first went in there was murder cried out, the deceased was beating his wife behind the door, so I went to part them, but it was more than I could do; at that time Fishook came in: the deceased struck me several times and tore the cuff of my coat almost off; Fishook went out and came in again, and laid the deceased upon the table; when that was over I went out and brought in a full pot of beer and drank with them; I staid there about half an hour, and then went to Fishook's house, where Fishook and I drank together; soon after I heard a sad noise again, so I ran in, and found them quarrelling; then he stripp'd off his cloaths ; I endeavoured to pacify him, but he ran into Fishook's house, and pulled him out of his chair; I ran in after him to part them, and got Fishook away, so he came and struck me several blows on the side of my neck with his fist, which made me reel against the door, he drew blood from me ; we had a little scuffle together, but how the thing happened the Lord above knows ; I only said, Richard, be easy, and don't be quarrelsome; I did strike him in the scuffle, but there was no malice between us. We have done many a hard day's work together, and drank many a full pot of beer together.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17501205-60-verdict309" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501205-60-verdict309" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-60-verdict309" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17501205-60-punish310" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501205-60-punish310" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-60-punish310" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501205-60-defend510 t17501205-60-punish310"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
