<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560115-24">
               <interp inst="t17560115-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560115-24" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560115-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560115"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560115-24" type="date" value="17560115"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560115-24-off115-c225" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560115-24-defend274 t17560115-24-off115 t17560115-24-verdict117"></join>
         
               <p>86. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17560115-24-defend274" type="defendantName">
                     Andrew 
                     Brinkworth 
                  <interp inst="t17560115-24-defend274" type="surname" value="Brinkworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-24-defend274" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-24-defend274" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17560115-24-off115" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560115-24-off115" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-24-off115" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               feloniously forging a promissory note for the payment of 30 l. and uttering the same, well knowing it to have been forged, with intent to defraud
            </rs> 
            
               
                  <persName id="t17560115-24-victim276" type="victimName">
                     Henry 
                     Hawkins 
                  <interp inst="t17560115-24-victim276" type="surname" value="Hawkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-24-victim276" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-24-victim276" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560115-24-off115 t17560115-24-victim276"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17560115-24-cd116" type="crimeDate">Dec. 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560115-24-off115 t17560115-24-cd116"></join>.* </p> 
               <p>John Cotteridge. I was coming along the Strand one day, and the prisoner overtook me in a poor shabby condition.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know him before?</p>
               <p>Cotteridge. I had seen him before.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this ?</p>
               <p>Cotteridge. It was about 6 weeks ago: he asked me to give him some drink. I asked him how he came in that shabby dress: he said his brother allow'd him but a trifle a week; and he had got a note that he had found, since his wife was dead, in a snuff-box, from one Hawkins, that lived in such a place, and he could not get the money. I said I knew the man, and if I can be of any service to you, to see the note paid, I will. He said he would bring the note to me, which he did, to my house, the Tuesday before Christmas-day. I bid him go to the Three Tuns, and said I would come to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he shew you the note ?</p>
               <p>Cotteridge. He did, and I gave it him again. I went to him and said, Now I will go to Mr. Hawkins. Said he, I will go along with you, and shew you his house. We went, he shewed me the house; then I went in, and he stay'd in the street. Mr. Hawkins was in his shop. I said, Mr. Hawkins here is a note fell into my hands, and I desire you would look upon it. He did, and say'd, This is not my hand writing, this is one Curry's writing, an attorney, that was in the Fleet. Said he, This note has been brought to me twice before, and I am sorry that you should be the messenger to bring it again. I have satisfied the original about a year and an half ago, and, if you will step up stairs, I will shew you my receipt of all demands for this note. I went up, and he shew'd me it, and also a copy of this note. He shew'd me the original note: I compared it, and found there was but one letter different. Then I began to tell him how this came about. He said there were some dealings between the prisoner's wife and he. I said, he tells me he found this note in a snuff-box. He said He is a rogue, But I should have told the court I asked the prisoner before, how this note was given, what valuable considerations he had for this note; because it is Value received: He told me he had sold his estate that lay at a place call'd Ramsey, in Hampshire, to Hawkins, and Hawkins gave him this note for it.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175601150020"></xptr>Q. When did he tell you this?</p>
               <p>Cotteridge. This he told me in the first conversation. I had with him in the street.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Hawkins give you any account how this note came to be given?</p>
               <p>Cotteridge. Mr. Hawkins told me he purchased this thing on the 1st of May, 1754, and after it was all finish'd, the receipt was made, and he paid him his money. Then I said, How came this to pass, if you paid him all the purchase money in the year 1754 (which was on his receipt). What, did he write this himself, or Curry? Said he, Curry was a prisoner in the Fleet, and so was the prisoner; and Curry was going out once on a day rule, and Brinkworth desired him -</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner by when he and you had this conversation?</p>
               <p>Cotteridge. No, he was not.</p>
               <p>Court. Then you must not give an account of it. It is not proper evidence.</p>
               <p>Cotteridge. After I came back from Mr. Hawkins's, the prisoner came to my house. I said, Are not you a villain to send me with a forg'd note? He said, It is the Tentical note that I had for the purchase money, and I'll swear to it. Then said I, You'll be hang'd for it; for I verily believe it is not Mr. Hawkins's hand writing; for I have compared the notes, and the writing is not alike: and another thing is, there is a receipt in hall which the prisoner denied, and swore he would have his money. I told him Hawkins will be here in a day or 2, and if you will call on me just after Christmas, Hawkins will be here, and I will see you both face to face, and I'll keep the note the while. Hawkins came. I believe it was the Sunday after Christmas day. The next day the prisoner met me in Stone-Cutter-Street, and said, D - n you, what do you mean, you are going to sell me. I said, Call on me to morrow, and I will go with you to Mr. Hawkins's house, and then you may take and burn the note, or do what you please with it; I'll see you face to face. I went: when I came there Mr. Hawkins desired me to walk out to the sign of the Golden-Lion. The prisoner soon came, and was sent to me there. I said, I am imformed they have got a warrant against you for that note; if it is a right note you need not be afraid; but, if it is a false one, you have cause to fear. He said he did not care a farthing for it; for it was the identical note he had of Hawkins. Presently the constable came in with a warrant, and he was taken before justice St. Lawrence. There he desired to see the receipt in full, which was produced, and the original note after that; he beg'd pardon, and said he was sorry.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560115-24-person277">
                  Charles 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17560115-24-person277" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-24-person277" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-24-person277" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lived with Mr. Hawkins's father in law.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever seen Mr. Hawkins write?</p>
               <p>Harris. I saw him write daily.</p>
               <p>Q. Look upon this note carefully. Do you take it to be Mr. Hawkins's hand? He took it in his hand.</p>
               <p>Harris. I never saw him write this letter R in Henry in my life. I don't apprehend it is like his writing in any shape.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath do you or do you not take it to be his hand writing?</p>
               <p>Harris. Upon my oath I do not think this is his hand writing.</p>
               <p>Q. to Cotteridge. Is this the note you produced to Mr. Hawkins?</p>
               <p>Cotteridge. I believe it is.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not make a mark on it, so as to know it again?</p>
               <p>Cotteridge. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>The original note produced in court.</p>
               <p>Q. to Harris. Whose hand writing do you look upon this to be?</p>
               <p>Harris. This I take to be Mr. Hawkins's hand writing.</p>
               <p>The forged note read to this purport:</p>
               <p>London, 14 Feb, 1750.</p>
               <p>I promise to pay to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17560115-24-person278">
                  Anthony 
                  Brinkworth 
               <interp inst="t17560115-24-person278" type="surname" value="Brinkworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-24-person278" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-24-person278" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , one month after date, the sum of thirty pounds, for value received.</p>
               <p>Hen Hawkins, Glass-grinder.</p>
               <p>Warder-Court, Soho.</p>
               <p>30 00.00</p>
               <p>Ask for Mr. Chalkley.</p>
               <p>Cotteridge. The prisoner acknowledged the original receipt to be his own hand writing.</p>
               <p>Q. to Harris. Do you know any thing farther concerning this note?</p>
               <p>Harris. On the 28th of Dec. in the afternoon, Mr. Hawkins desired me to take a walk along with him to Mr. Cotteridge's, to enquire after the prisoner at the bar. We went to a house in the neighbourhood for that purpose, and when the prisoner came, I told him I had got a warrant against him. We took him before justice St. Lawrence.</p>
         
               <p>The Second Part of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17560115-24">
                  <interp inst="t17560115-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17560115-24" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17560115-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560115"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17560115-24" type="date" value="17560115"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175601150021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON, And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Thursday the 15th, Friday the 16th, Saturday the 17th, and Monday the 19th of JANUARY.</p>
                  <p>In the Twenty-ninth Year of His MAJESTY'S Reign. NUMBER II. PART II. for the YEAR 1756. Being the Second SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of The Right Honble SLINGSBY BETHELL, Esq; LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by J. ROBINSON, at the Golden-Lion, in Ludgate-Street. 1756.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-pence,]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175601150022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery held for the City of LONDON, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>HE said he would swear to the note, and that it was Mr. Hawkins's hand writeing. The justice examined Mr. Hawkins, after which he call'd for the prisoner, and said, You villain, you are just come out of one trouble, and I must commit you again. He shewed him the original receipt, and said, Pray is not this your own hand writing? He owned it was, and seem'd a great deal concern'd; after which he pull'd Mr. Hawkins by the coat, and desired him to release him, when Mr. Hawkins told him it was not in his power.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I asked Mr. Hawkins to shew me the papers before the justice: Said he, I'll shew no papers, why had not you come to me before? I said I had been, and you promised to come to me at the White-Lion, but you never did. I never saw the receipt that he talks of to this day, neither would they shew it me.</p>
               <p>Q. to Cotteridge. Have you ever seen the prisoner write ?</p>
               <p>Cotteridge. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. to Harris. Did you ever see him write?</p>
               <p>Harris. No.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560115-24-person279">
                  James 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17560115-24-person279" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-24-person279" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560115-24-person279" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the Saturday, when the prisoner was before justice St. Lawrence, I heard Mr. Hawkins say he knew the forgery was not the prisoner's hand writing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see the prisoner write?</p>
               <p>Smith. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>- <rs id="t17560115-24-verdict117" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560115-24-verdict117" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Acquitted of the forgery, guilty of uttering it
            </rs>. <rs id="t17560115-24-punish118" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560115-24-punish118" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560115-24-defend274 t17560115-24-punish118"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
