<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17530718-33">
               <interp inst="t17530718-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530718-33" type="year" value="1753"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530718-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17530718"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530718-33" type="date" value="17530718"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17530718-33-off170-c221" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-33-defend277 t17530718-33-off170 t17530718-33-verdict175"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17530718-33-off170-c222" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-33-defend279 t17530718-33-off170 t17530718-33-verdict175"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17530718-33-off172-c221" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-33-defend277 t17530718-33-off172 t17530718-33-verdict175"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17530718-33-off172-c222" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-33-defend279 t17530718-33-off172 t17530718-33-verdict175"></join>
         
               <p>348, 349. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-defend277" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Stockdale 
                  <interp inst="t17530718-33-defend277" type="surname" value="Stockdale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-defend277" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-defend277" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-defend279" type="defendantName">
                     Christopher 
                     Johnson 
                  <interp inst="t17530718-33-defend279" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-defend279" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-defend279" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , where indicted, for that <rs id="t17530718-33-off170" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-off170" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-off170" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               they on the king's-highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17530718-33-victim281" type="victimName">
                           Zachariah 
                           Gardiner 
                        <interp inst="t17530718-33-victim281" type="surname" value="Gardiner"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530718-33-victim281" type="given" value="Zachariah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530718-33-victim281" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-33-off170 t17530718-33-victim281"></join>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-33-off172 t17530718-33-victim281"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , did make an assault, one silver watch, value 30 s. one silver seal, value 1 s. and 19 d. in money numbered, from his person did steal, &amp;c
            </rs>. <rs id="t17530718-33-cd171" type="crimeDate">June 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-33-off170 t17530718-33-cd171"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-33-off172 t17530718-33-cd171"></join>.</p>
               <p>They were indicted also for that <rs id="t17530718-33-off172" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-off172" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-off172" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               Stockdale discharged a pistol upon the said Zachariah, and gave him a wound on the left side of his belly, of which he died; and that the prisoner Johnson was present, aiding, assisting, and abetting in the same
            </rs>. *</p>
               <p>Ann Coant. I live at <placeName id="t17530718-33-crimeloc173">Edmonton</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17530718-33-crimeloc173" type="placeName" value="Edmonton"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17530718-33-crimeloc173" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-33-off170 t17530718-33-crimeloc173"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-33-off172 t17530718-33-crimeloc173"></join>, on the 18th of June 1 was one of the persons call'd to the assistance of the man that was shot, I went, and knew him to be the <rs id="t17530718-33-viclabel174" type="occupation">postman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-33-victim281 t17530718-33-viclabel174"></join>, I found him tumbling on the ground, he had been a bleeding, but he did not bleed then, he looked at me, and said, I am a dead man, then he asked me if I did not see two persons go by on horse back, I said yes, says he they were the men that robbed and shot me, I asked him whereabouts they met him, he said at the Chace gate, he said he opened the gate for them, and they asked him what it was o'clock; he said he pulled out his watch, and told them a little after two; that after he had told them, they demanded his watch; he said he gave it to one of them, and the other shot him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see this man that was shot, any time before?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-person282">
                  Ann 
                  Coant 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person282" type="surname" value="Coant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person282" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person282" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Yes, I saw him go by about five minutes before.</p>
               <p>Q. After he was gone by, did you see any body else go by?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-person283">
                  Ann 
                  Caunt 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person283" type="surname" value="Caunt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person283" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person283" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Yes, the prisoners and one Mr. Lee.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear a pistol fire?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-person284">
                  Ann 
                  Coant 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person284" type="surname" value="Coant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person284" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person284" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I did.</p>
         
               <p>The SECOND PART of these PROCEEDINGS will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17530718-33">
                  <interp inst="t17530718-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17530718-33" type="year" value="1753"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17530718-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17530718"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17530718-33" type="date" value="17530718"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175307180021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Goal Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the Goal Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 18th, Thursday the 19th, Friday the 20th, and Saturday the 21st, of July,</p>
                  <p>In the 27th Year of His MAJESTY's Reign, BEING THE Sixth SESSION in the MAYORALTY of the Right Honble Sir CRISP GASCOYNE, Knt. LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>NUMBER VI. PART II.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by M. COOPER, at the Globe in Pater-noster Row, 1753.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-Pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175307180022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Goal Delivery held for the City of London, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Q. How long was it after the two men went by?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-person285">
                  Ann 
                  Coant 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person285" type="surname" value="Coant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person285" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person285" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . But a very small time.</p>
               <p>Q. What distance of time might there be between the two prisoners going down the lane, and Mr. Lee's ?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-person286">
                  Ann 
                  Coant 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person286" type="surname" value="Coant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person286" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person286" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . A very little time.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure it was the postman, did you say any thing to him?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-person287">
                  Ann 
                  Coant 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person287" type="surname" value="Coant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person287" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person287" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I did not, but my neighbour Fennelly did, I heard her say postman, what is it o'clock? he said two.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any body else by but your self, during the time he told her this?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-person288">
                  Ann 
                  Coant 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person288" type="surname" value="Coant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person288" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person288" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . There was none but myself and Mrs. Fennelly.</p>
               <p>Q. When Mr. Lee came to you, did he say any thing about the two men?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-person289">
                  Ann 
                  Coant 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person289" type="surname" value="Coant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person289" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person289" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . No, he did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-person290">
                  Mary 
                  Fennelly 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person290" type="surname" value="Fennelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person290" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person290" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live next door to the last witness, we were sitting together at work in my house; the postman ran by very swift, I asked who it was, Mrs. Coant said it was the postman ; I said I would satisfy myself, whether it was or no, I then ran and called post! post ! he turned about, and said yes mistress, I asked him what it was o'clock, he said two; he had not been gone by long, before the two prisoners went after him; the first had a light cloth coat on.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a loose coat, or a straight coat?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-person291">
                  Mary 
                  Fennelly 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person291" type="surname" value="Fennelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person291" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person291" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . A straight coat; the second had a dark colour'd coat, and his wig tied with a black ribbon; they both seemed to be young men, and one was of a very swarthy complexion.</p>
               <p>Q. Which was that, the first or the last?</p>
               <p>M. Fennelly. The last.</p>
               <p>Q. What distance was there between them?</p>
               <p>M. Fennely. About the length of their horses,</p>
               <p>Q. How long after the postman was gone was it before the two men went by?</p>
               <p>M. Fennelly. About two or three minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you say any thing as to their horses.</p>
               <p>M. Fennelly. It was a black one the hinder man rode upon, and it was a mare; they had not been gone long, before a gun or pistol went off, as we thought; I said Mrs. Coant there is a gun gone off.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was you then from the chase.</p>
               <p>M. Fennelly. About a quarter of a mile.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175307180023"></xptr>Q. How long after that was it, before Mr. Lee came to you?</p>
               <p>M. Fennelly. About a quarter of an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Mr. Lee go down, before this accident happen'd ?</p>
               <p>M. Fennelly. No, I did not; the first time I saw him that day, was when he came to us, and said the postman had been murdered.</p>
               <p>Q. Which way did he come?</p>
               <p>M. Fennelly. From the chase gate.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was Mr. Lee's speaking and making this alarm to you, after the two men had past by before?</p>
               <p>M. Fennelly. A very little time, I believe it was about two or three minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go to the postman?</p>
               <p>M. Fennelly. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. What condition did you find him in?</p>
               <p>M. Fennelly. A very deplorable one.</p>
               <p>Q. How near the chase-gate did he lay ?</p>
               <p>M. Fennelly. Very near, not above two or three stones throws.</p>
               <p>Q. Did 
               <persName id="t17530718-33-person292">
                  Ann 
                  Coant 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person292" type="surname" value="Coant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person292" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person292" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             go along with you?</p>
               <p>M. Fennelly. She did, we found him very ill; I said, lord have mercy upon me, postman; who would have thought of this when you went by? he ask'd whether there was not two men gone down the lane; we said yes, he said they have robbed and shot me; we asked him whereabouts it was, he said at the chase-gate, and that he held the gate open for them.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say they did then upon his opening the gate ?</p>
               <p>M. Fennelly. He said they asked him what it was o'clock, that he pulled out his watch and told them; that then they immediately asked him for it, he said he gave it them, and made no delay.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say which of them shot or robbed him?</p>
               <p>M. Fennelly. He did not to us, we never asked him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did all this pass, while he lay on the ground ?</p>
               <p>M. Fennelly. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of him afterwards?</p>
               <p>M. Fennelly. He was carried to the King's-head, to one Mr. Hubbard's, by four men.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was it between the King's head, and the place where he lay ?</p>
               <p>M. Fennelly. About two or three stones throws; he was carried up and put to bed, and we did not see him afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he speak plain, and could you well unstand what he said?</p>
               <p>M. Fennelly. He spoke very plain.</p>
               <p>Cross Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Lee say any thing about the two prisoner's riding away?</p>
               <p>M. Fennelly. No, he did not say any thing about them.</p>
               <p>Q. When you came there did not he ask you whether you had seen two men ride away?</p>
               <p>M. Fennelly. No, he said nothing about it.</p>
               <p>Q. What was it he did ask ?</p>
               <p>M. Fennelly. He said, did not you see two men go down the lane; we said yes, he said they were the men that robbed and shot him.</p>
               <p>Q. Had Mrs. Coant said any thing to the deceased about the two men, before such time as he spoke of them to you?</p>
               <p>M. Fennelly. I do not think she did, I did not hear her.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be so particular about these horses ?</p>
               <p>M. Fennelly. The swarthy man looked in my face very hard, and I look'd at him.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of Mr. Lee?</p>
               <p>M. Fennelly. He went to alarm the people at the King's Head.</p>
               <p>Council for the King.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of Stockdale or Johnson ?</p>
               <p>M. Fennelly. I never saw them before I saw them ride by, and I believe, to the best of my knowledge, Stockdale is one.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him afterwards, at any other time ?</p>
               <p>M. Fennelly. Yes, I saw him before the justice in London.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take any notice of him at that time, whether you knew him or not?</p>
               <p>M. Fennelly. I did, and believe to the best of my knowledge, he is one of them that rode by.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you mean that you are positive to the person, or only to the best of your knowledge ?</p>
               <p>M. Fennelly. I dare say, I can be positive to the person.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175307180024"></xptr>Council for the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. When you saw Stockdale before the justice, was you so positive to him ?</p>
               <p>Fennelly. I was not, but said, to the best of my knowledge he was the man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-person293">
                  John 
                  Holbourn 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person293" type="surname" value="Holbourn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person293" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person293" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Kingsland Road, and was at Mr. Hubbard's, who keeps the King's-head on Winchmore-hill, on Monday the 18th of June, sitting at the door, between one and two o'clock; the postman came, and ask'd Mr. Hubbard if there was any thing for him, who said no, but that there was a let ter over the way; he went there and took the letter, and then turn'd down the lane that leads to the chace gate. About two minutes after I saw two young men on horseback go down after him, one of them had a darkish wig on tied behind; the other was behind when they pass'd by me, they both went down the same lane the postman did, and the first that pass'd had a lightish coloured coat on.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take any notice of his person?</p>
               <p>Holbourn. No, not of his face; they both rode on dark mares, and the last man's was a clumsy dirty one, and had three white feet, I took great notice of him, he wore brown cloaths, and look'd a great deal younger than the other.</p>
               <p>Q. Was either of the prisoners at the bar the persons ?</p>
               <p>He points to Stockdale, and says, He is the man that rode last in the brown cloaths.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure that is the man, did you take more notice of him than the first ?</p>
               <p>Holbourn. I did, for I was sitting at the door, and he was jawing by the door, so took more notice of him, he had a swarthy complection.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any thing particular in his wig?</p>
               <p>Holbourn. Yes, he had a black ribband behind.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any body else follow them?</p>
               <p>Holbourn. No, I did not. After I had drank my beer and was going, a gentleman, with a lac'd hat, came up to Mr. Hubbard's, and said, Mr. Hubbard, for God's sake, go or send somebody down the lane to relieve the poor post-boy for he is shot and robb'd, I ran down the lane, and when I came there, there were two women standing hard by, he lay about 200 yards from the gate in the road.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they the women that have been examin'd ?</p>
               <p>Holbourn. I cannot say, I said to him, Lord have mercy upon me! What is the matter? he said, two men followed him down the lane, and robb'd and shot him at the gate. Then I, and three more took him up, and carried him to Mr. Hubbard's, at the King's-head.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen the mares lately?</p>
               <p>Holbourn. I saw them on Wednesday last, in a stable near Hicks's-hall, they were shewn to me by the hostler, who asked me if I knew them, I said I did, and do really believe they are the same mares the two prisoner's rode on; for one had crop'd ears, and the other had three white feet.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take notice that the mare was crop'd when you saw them go down the lane?</p>
               <p>Holbourn. I did.</p>
               <p>Cross Examin'd.</p>
               <p>Q. What was you doing at the time you saw them go down the lane?</p>
               <p>Holbourn. I was eating my dinner at Hubbard's door.</p>
               <p>Q. You say you never saw Stockdale but at that time, now do you think you should know him if you saw him in any other place?</p>
               <p>Holbourn. Yes, I should.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever take notice to any one that the mare was crop'd, before you saw her on Wednesday?</p>
               <p>Holbourn. I did to several people.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you, without having been shewn the mares again, have swore to them?</p>
               <p>Holbourn. I could have pick'd them out from among a thousand.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-person294">
                  William 
                  Hubbard 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person294" type="surname" value="Hubbard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person294" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person294" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the King's-head on Winchmore-hill ; on the 18th of June the deceased called at my house, to know whether there was any letters for him: I told him no, but that there was one over the way, which he went and took, and then I saw him go down the lane that leads to the chace: I went in, and, looking through the window, saw two men ride down the lane, the last had got a sharp cock'd up hat, and a brown wig, tied up with a black ribband behind in a double knot, and hung down loose. They were about two rods distance from one another. In about ten minutes after they were gone down Mr. Lee<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175307180025"></xptr> came to our house, and told my wife that the post-boy was robb'd and shot; my wife told me, so I went down the lane, and they had got him in a chair just by the bottom of the hill.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you speak to him?</p>
               <p>Hubbard. No, I did not, but heard him say he took on for his poor dear wife; he was carried to my house, where I helped to put him to bed.</p>
               <p>Q. If he had been asked a question could he have given an answer?</p>
               <p>Hubbard. He could and did.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at the prisoners, are you sure they are the men?</p>
               <p>Hubbard points to Stockdale, and says, that is the man that rode last I am very positive.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-person295">
                  John 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person295" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person295" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person295" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a farmer, and live at Winchmore-hill by Endfield chace, next door to Mr. Hubbard's. On Monday the 18th of June, much about two o'clock at noon, as I was standing by my own gate, I saw two men go by me, through Mr. Hubbard's yard, and down the chace lane; one had a brown coat, which was the prisoner Stockdale.</p>
               <p>Q. Which is Stockdale ?</p>
               <p>Jones. That is the man (pointing to him) he was the man that rode last.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take notice of the first man?</p>
               <p>Jones. No, not-so much as I did of the last; for he turned his face over his shoulder twice, so I took particular notice of him, he had got on a brown cloth coat, his wig was tied with a ribband behind, and his hat cock'd up very sharp; but I cannot say any thing to the person that rode foremost.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take any notice of their horses?</p>
               <p>Jones. No, I did not, for I look'd more at them than their horses, and am sure Stockdale is the man that rode last by my gate.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see them afterwards?</p>
               <p>Jones. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any thing of the deceased after he was wounded?</p>
               <p>Jones. Yes, I saw the surgeon dress the wound.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was that?</p>
               <p>Jones. Down in the lane, in the place where he lay.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear him say any thing?</p>
               <p>Jones. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him after he was at the King's head ?</p>
               <p>Jones. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Cross Examin'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you not seen the prisoner Stockdale since he has been taken before now ?</p>
               <p>Jones. Yes, I saw him before Mr. Fielding?</p>
               <p>Q. And was you sure then that he was the person that rode by last?</p>
               <p>Jones. Yes, I said so as soon as ever I saw his face.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any other person go down the lane besides the two prisoners?</p>
               <p>Jones. I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-person296">
                  William 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person296" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person296" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person296" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 18th of June I saw the post-man lay wounded near Endfield chace gate ; he was carried from thence to the King's-head, where I asked him who did it; he said two young men followed him down the lane and robb'd him, and that the man in the brown coat shot him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say how it happen'd?</p>
               <p>Smith. Yes: he said he was at the chace gate and open'd it for them, that they ask'd him what it was o'clock, and he told them; that then they demanded his watch and money, after which the man in the brown coat shot them.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he sensible at that time?</p>
               <p>Smith. I believe he was.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he live after that?</p>
               <p>Smith. He liv'd two hours.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was you with him?</p>
               <p>Smith. About an hour and half?</p>
               <p>Q. Did he always declare the man in the brown coat shot him?</p>
               <p>Smith. Yes, he did.</p>
               <p>Cross Examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you say any thing to him about the description of the people?</p>
               <p>Willm. Smith. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Who told him what cloaths they had on?</p>
               <p>Willm. Smith. Nobody, he told me the man in the brown coat shot him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-person297">
                  Henry 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person297" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person297" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person297" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Southgate, in the parish of Edmonton. On Monday the 18th of June, I went on the chace to look at my horses, and while I was looking, I heard a gun or a pistol go off, I thought somebody had shot at a deer, I thought I would<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175307180026"></xptr> get up into the road as soon as I could, thinking I should see the person that shot the deer. I went out just by Winchmore hill gate, there I saw the two prisoners coming along the road as fast as they could gallop towards Southgate, on the side of the chace.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was it after the report of the pistol before you saw them.</p>
               <p>H. Smith. About a minute.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take any particular notice of their horses?</p>
               <p>H. Smith. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any particular marks on them?</p>
               <p>H. Smith. One of them had two white feet behind, but they gallop'd very fast so that I could not mind the colour of their horses, but I took so much notice of them that I can remember them very well.</p>
               <p>Cross Examin'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen them before now?</p>
               <p>H. Smith. I saw them before justice Fielding.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you satisfied they were the persons then?</p>
               <p>H. Smith. Yes, I was.</p>
               <p>Q. How can you swear to him that is sick, are you sure he is one of the men that were before justice Fielding. (He is sent to look at him).</p>
               <p>H. Smith. He is one, and that is the other, (pointing unto Stockdale).</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-person298">
                  Edmund 
                  Glanister 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person298" type="surname" value="Glanister"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person298" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person298" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Southgate, and am a butcher. On the 18th of June I was going to the West-lodge, to look at some lambs upon the chace; and about five minutes past two as I was crossing the chace into the road, I saw a man come riding by very hard; I believe he might be got about a quarter of a mile, when another came up, he spurr'd the mare and she trip'd several times, I thought she would have fell; and every time he spurr'd she groan'd. I took great notice of the mare, she had a wen on the near leg.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take particular notice of the first man's mare?</p>
               <p>E. Glanister. I saw it was a dark brown one, but did not take much notice of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen the mares since.</p>
               <p>E. Glanister. Yes, they were shewn me by the hostler, I can swear to the last man's mare by the wen, but as for the other I cannot swear to that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-person299">
                  Vincent 
                  Moore 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person299" type="surname" value="Moore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person299" type="given" value="Vincent"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person299" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a surgeon and apothecary, and live at Enfield. On Monday the 18th of June, I was in company with two gentlemen going to Southgate to dinner, and call'd by the way to see a person that was sick; this was about half an hour past two, I then heard that an accident had happen'd, I went to the deceased and found him plac'd upon a chair in the lane in a dying condition, (and could scarce speak) supported by the people that were there, they told me it was the penny post-man, and that two young men just gone by had robb'd and shot him.</p>
               <p>Q. Who told you so?</p>
               <p>V. Moore. 
               <persName id="t17530718-33-person300">
                  William 
                  Hubbard 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person300" type="surname" value="Hubbard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person300" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person300" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was one, and a woman the other. I examin'd the man and ask'd him where he was shot, he said in his belly; then I examin'd and found a wound on the left side of his belly, near the navel, I prob'd the wound and found it was very deep, and went between the skin and the membrane of his belly very deep into his right groin. My probe was not sufficent to tell how deep it was; I therefore drest the wound and desir'd he might be had into a bed, and that I might see him again in an hour or two's time. I waited upon him a second time about two or three hours afterwards, I then found him a dying, and waited there till he did die, but did not see him expire; I was there after he was dead, and by examining his right thigh it had turn'd black: I found a round substance on the right side something like a ball.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you imagine the wound proceeded from?</p>
               <p>V. Moore. I believe it proceeded from either balls or slugs, and that more than one.</p>
               <p>Q. From what you observ'd do you believe the wound was mortal?</p>
               <p>V. Moore. He was sinking and dying when I came, and I look upon it to be a mortal wound.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you believe he died of that wound?</p>
               <p>V. Moore. I believe he did.</p>
               <p>Q. During that little time he did live was he capable of speaking?</p>
               <p>V. Moore. Yes, he was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he speak?</p>
               <p>V. Moore. Yes, he said he was in great pain, and told me he was shot and was a dead man.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175307180027"></xptr>Q. Did you ask him in what manner?</p>
               <p>V. Moore. No, I did not, he declar'd that before I came to other people.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-person301">
                  George 
                  Cook 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person301" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person301" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person301" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Three Cups in Holborn, and lett out horses. I have known Johnson this twelve-month, he us'd to hire horses of me; he came to my house on Sunday evening the 17th of June, to hire a horse, I told him he should have one when it came home, and she came home on Sunday night ; then he went away, and on Monday the 18th he and the prisoner Stockdale came about six in the morning, and Johnson desir'd I would get the mare ready. Then they went away together; and between seven and eight Johnson came by himself and mounted the mare.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a mare was it ?</p>
               <p>G. Cook. It was a dark brown mare with cropp'd ears, and a hog mare.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did the mare return?</p>
               <p>G. Cook. At six o'clock that evening Johnson came in without the mare, and desir'd my lad to go and fetch it, for he had left her at St. Giles's, and that he did not care to ride over the stones. I sent the lad for the mare, when she came home I saw she had been rode very hard, and had sweated very much, and had been rubb'd over. I have shewn the mare to several of the witnesses that have been examin'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-person302">
                  James 
                  Miller 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person302" type="surname" value="Miller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person302" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person302" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Black-Bull, Gray's-inn-lane. On Sunday night was a month, about six o'clock, being the 17th of June, the prisoner Johnson came to me and desir'd to know if I had two horses.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know him before?</p>
               <p>Miller. No, I did not, he told me where he lodg'd at a snuff-shop in Tash-Court, Grays inn-lane; he wanted the horses for the Monday following at nine o'clock; then I went into the stable and shewed him two, he told me he believ'd they would do very well, but the gentleman would be in presently; he went away then, and did not bargain: presently Stockdale and he came together.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you seen the prisoner Stockdale before?</p>
               <p>Miller. No, my lord, not to my knowledge; they went into the stable with me, and Johnson said to Stockdale, do you take this mare, she will do very well for you; I will not have the other, but I'll go to Cook's, at the Three Cups in Holborn, for one for me ; they ask'd what I would have for the mare for the next morning to go to Barnet to see the horses that were to run, I told them 4 s. 6 d. and we agreed the next morning. Johnson came about eight o'clock, they had order'd the mare to be ready at nine; he said he'd go to Cook's and bring his mare and take Stockdale with him. He came again on a crop mare almost black, with a hog mare, and Stockdale on foot with him, and Stockdale mounted my mare in my yard.</p>
               <p>Q. Describe your mare.</p>
               <p>Miller. She is a black one with a wen upon her near leg, as big as my fist, and 3 white feet. The call'd for a pint of beer, and drank it, I ask'd for my money before the mare went out, Stockdale said, he never was ask'd for money before he came home; Johnson said, he always paid when he came home, and he'd be answerable for the money; then they both rode off, and in the evening about six, or rather before, they both of them came to my door, Stockdale was on my mare, he deliver'd her, and said to me if you'll go along with me to Johnson's lodgings he would pay me.</p>
               <p>Q. In what condition was the mare?</p>
               <p>Miller. She was in very bad condition indeed. She came in on but three legs, absolutely tired, and strain'd in the back sinews; she lay down as soon as she came into the stable: I went along with Stockdale to Johnson's lodgings, he ask'd the woman below for Johnson, she said he is just gone out, then he said to the woman be so good as to lend me a crown, I could not justly hear her answer, but she lent him none. We went to a place or two more, but could not find Johnson, then Stockdale said, be so good as to step home, and Johnson shall come and pay you in half an hour; I went and staid about that time, then I went to Johnson's lodgings again, and presently he came in and told me he had paid but 3 s. 6 d. for the other mare, but he paid me 4 s. 6 d. for mine.</p>
               <p>Q. When people, Mr. Smith, and others, came to see the mare that Stockdale rode, did you shew them all that same mare that he rode?</p>
               <p>Miller. I did.</p>
               <p>Mr. Glanister. I went to Mr. Miller, to enquire for this mare; Mr. Miller, and the hostler, shewed me her, she was a black one, and had a wen on one leg.</p>
               <p>Q. to Cook. Did you shew that mare to Glanister, which you let to Johnson?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175307180028"></xptr>Cook. I did.</p>
               <p>Mary Wood. My husband keeps the Fox-alehouse at Palmer's Green, about eight miles from London, near Winchmore-hill ; I remember on Monday, June 18, the two prisoners (She looks at them well, and says she is sure they are the same persons) came to our house a little after one o'clock and baited their horses there; they staid about twenty minutes, they aske d me the time of the day and I went to look, and remember the time they staid was thereabouts.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take any notice of their horses?</p>
               <p>M. Wood. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-person303">
                  Thomas 
                  Briant 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person303" type="surname" value="Briant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person303" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person303" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was hostler at the Fox then ; I observed the two mares the two prisoners rode; I have seen them both since, and know them to be the same; and I know the prisoners again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-person304">
                  Henry 
                  Peal 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person304" type="surname" value="Peal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person304" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Wednesday the 20th of June, being at Mr. Fielding's over night; I was informed a man would shew me, and others, a place in Grays-inn-lane, where a man lived that answered the description in the advertisement, of one of the persons that shot the postman; there were Jones, Philipson, Norden, and I, we went in the morning about four clock; as soon as the street door was open, we went in; we found two women in bed, but no man; I staid in the room till about half an hour after seven; Norden and Jones were gone round Holborn, to see if they could find where the horses were hired; in the mean time I talked with Johnson's wife, she told me that on Tuesday morning her husband and Stockdale had been out together; about half an hour after seven, up came Stockdale with a handkerchief in his hand ; said I, is your name Johnson ; he said no, my name is Middleton, what have you to do with me; I had him by the collar, I put my hand to his pocket, and took out these pair of pistols loaded with eight sluggs, four in each, and a seal. (Produced in court.) He immediately said, I wish you'd go and take Johnson, for he has brought me to it, and said he'd tell us where he was; he said he was at a town beyond Hammersmith, at the Led-Lion, but did not know the name of the town; we named Brentford, he said that was it; we went in two chaises, Stockdale and I in one, and the others in the other; and between Knightsbridge and the half-way house, going to Kensington, we met Johnson; Stockdale said that was he, so we took him; Stockdale told us, Johnson had a pistol and hanger about him, Jones took the pistol out of his pocket, and Philipson the/ hanger from under his coat; Stockdale had before told us it was Johnson that shot the postman, and the seal I found in his pocket, Johnson gave to him; when we had them face to face, Johnson said Stockdale shot the man, with bitter wishes; Stockdale owned he got off the horse and took the man's money out of his pocket, and that Johnson demanded the man's watch, and he put it in his hat as he sat on horseback.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-person305">
                  William 
                  Norden 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person305" type="surname" value="Norden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person305" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person305" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went along with the last witness, Jones and Philipson, in order to take Johnson ; I made a stop to talk to the keeper of Tothill-fields-bridewell; that when I came up to them they had taken Johnson as he was coming to town; when we got the prisoners together they upbraided each other with the murder of the man; Johnson wished his eyes might tumble into his hat if Stockdale did not shoot the man, Stockdale denied it and said it was Johnson ; I sat between them to keep them from fighting; Stockdale owned he took the money from the man, and said Johnson held his hat and took the watch, after which Johnson shot the man, Johnson owned he shot at a man near Uxbridge, the next day.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-person306">
                  Samuel 
                  Philipson 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person306" type="surname" value="Philipson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person306" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . After Stockdale was taken I came into the room; he desired we would go and take Johnson, and he went with us; I went with Jones in the first chaise, and Peal with Stockdale, in another; going on this side the half-way house, under the park wall, as Johnson was coming along, Stockdale said that was he; I jumped out of the chaise and got over the ditch and took him by the arm; he asked what it was for, I said I'll tell you presently; under his coat I found this hanger, (produced in court;) and Jones searched his pocket, and in his left hand side found a pistol; then I told him, they say you shot a man: I was tying his hands with his handkerchief, he turned round and saw Stockdale in the chaise; he said that little scoundrel I suppose sent you after me; I said he did; said he, did he say I shot the man; I said he did, he said he is a scoundrel, it was he that shot him; we put him into the chaise and drove to the Red-lion at Brentford, there the two prisoners argued about shooting the postman; Stockdale said, you villian you asked the man what is it o'clock, he pulled out his watch, and you demanded it, he put it in your hat, and you shot him directly, and the man gave a jump, and you laughed; Johnson said to him, you little scoundrel you shot him, and I had a good mind when we were on Hounslow-heath to have shot you, and had my hand on my<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175307180029"></xptr> pistol in my pocket divers time so to do; and am sorry now I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-person307">
                  William 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person307" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person307" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person307" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was present at the taking Johnson; I took a pistol loaded with pebble stones out of his pocket; when we got them to the Red-Lion at Brentford ; they charged each other with doing the murder, also in taking the man's watch.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-person308">
                  John 
                  Ashburner 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person308" type="surname" value="Ashburner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person308" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a pawnbroker, and live at the corner of Half-Moon-street in the Strand. (He produces a watch; ) this I had of the prisoner Johnson, he brought it and had a guinea and half of me for it, he left it in the name of 
               <persName id="t17530718-33-person309">
                  John 
                  Middleton 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person309" type="surname" value="Middleton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person309" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person309" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>Ashburner. It was on Monday the 18th of June in the afternoon, some little time before candlelight.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-person310">
                  John 
                  Stevens 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person310" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person310" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person310" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watch-maker, the deceased married my sister, I have been acquainted with him four or five years.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he used to carry a watch?</p>
               <p>Stevens. He did, I have had it of him to mend several times; (he is shewed the watch and silver seal, found on Stockdale.) This is the watch and seal the deceased used to wear, the seal I gave him, and had an impression taken off from it before I gave it him.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain?</p>
               <p>Stevens. These are the very watch and seal that the deceased used to wear.</p>
               <p>Stockdale's Defence.</p>
               <p>I can call several friends to my character.</p>
               <p>Johnson was very ill the time of trial, and said nothing in his defence, nor called any witness.</p>
               <p>For Stockdale.</p>
               <p>Mr. Dison. I knew Stockdale at Leicester, a lad.</p>
               <p>Q. How old his he?</p>
               <p>Mr. Dison. He is about eighteen years of age; he has been in London about eighteen or nineteen weeks, since which I have been in his company a great many times, I never saw any misbehaviour by him.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Dison. I knew him at Leicester when he lived with his father, I have often been in his company, and cannot suppose he would have been guilty of a crime of this nature, had he not been drawn into it.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Nevil. I have known him ever since he came to London; he was clerk with Mr. Smith in Doctor's-Commons, he has been about three or four months in town, and has behaved extremely well in my sight; he has been backwards and forwards at my house very often.</p>
               <p>Mr. Lilley. I have known him only in town. I live the next door to the house he used, and during the time I knew him he behaved very well, as any person I know, in my company; he is the last person I should have thought on to do such an action, and think he must have been drawn in.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-person311">
                  James 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person311" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person311" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person311" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a clerk in Doctor's-Commons, Stockdale lodged at our house, I always look'd upon him as a very honest young man, and never could have thought him guilty of such a crime had he not been drawn in.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Higgs. I live at Mr. Taylor's, where the prisoner was a clerk, he was regular in his behaviour, I could not have thought him guilty of such an offence had he not been drawn in by somebody.</p>
               <p>Mr. Smith. I am a proctor in the Commons ; his father desired I would take him into my office, in order to qualify him in the business, which I did, and never saw any harm of him during the time I have known him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he live in your house?</p>
               <p>Smith. No, I never take any clerk in my house.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of Johnson, or his coming after Stockdale?</p>
               <p>Smith. I do not: I never saw him, nor heard of his keeping company with him, 'till after he was taken up. I was very much surpriz'd when I heard Stockdale was taken up on this account.</p>
               <p>Q. How old is he?</p>
               <p>Smith. He is turned of seventeen, I should think he must have been drawn in.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-person312">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Gibbs 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person312" type="surname" value="Gibbs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person312" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person312" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him from a child at Leicester, and came up when he did, I never knew any harm by him in my life.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Paget. I have known him from a child, and liv'd some time in the house with him, and never heard any thing ill of him.</p>
               <p>Mr. Philips. I have known him about four months, and took him to be a well-behaved young man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530718-33-person313">
                  John 
                  Philips 
               <interp inst="t17530718-33-person313" type="surname" value="Philips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person313" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-person313" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him ten years, and went to school with him at Leicester eight years, he always behaved extremely well, and was respected as such in the neighbourhood.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17530718-33-verdict175" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-verdict175" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty of the robbery and murder
            </rs>. <rs id="t17530718-33-punish176" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-punish176" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-33-defend277 t17530718-33-punish176"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-33-defend279 t17530718-33-punish176"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175307180030"></xptr>
                  <rs id="t17530718-33-punish177" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-punish177" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530718-33-punish177" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="executed"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-33-defend277 t17530718-33-punish177"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530718-33-defend279 t17530718-33-punish177"></join>
               This being Friday, they received sentence to be executed on the Monday following, and their bodies to be defected and anatomiz'd
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
