<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17530502-20">
               <interp inst="t17530502-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530502-20" type="year" value="1753"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530502-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17530502"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530502-20" type="date" value="17530502"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17530502-20-off100-c187" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530502-20-person228 t17530502-20-off100 t17530502-20-verdict104"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17530502-20-off100-c188" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530502-20-defend229 t17530502-20-off100 t17530502-20-verdict104"></join>
         
               <p>201. (M) 
               <persName id="t17530502-20-victim227" type="victimName">
                  
                     <persName id="t17530502-20-person228" type="defendantName">
                        
                           <persName id="t17530502-20-defend229" type="defendantName">
                              Richard 
                              Jenkins 
                           <interp inst="t17530502-20-defend229" type="surname" value="Jenkins"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17530502-20-defend229" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17530502-20-defend229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        </persName>
                        
                        <interp inst="t17530502-20-person228" type="surname" value="Jenkins"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530502-20-person228" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530502-20-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , <rs id="t17530502-20-deflabel99" type="occupation">Butcher</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530502-20-person228 t17530502-20-deflabel99"></join>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530502-20-defend229 t17530502-20-deflabel99"></join>, was indicted for the <rs id="t17530502-20-off100" type="offenceDescription">
                        <interp inst="t17530502-20-off100" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530502-20-off100" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
                     murder
                  </rs> of Susannah
                   his 
                  <rs id="t17530502-20-viclabel101" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530502-20-victim227 t17530502-20-viclabel101"></join>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-victim227" type="surname" value="his"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-victim227" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-victim227" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530502-20-off100 t17530502-20-victim227"></join>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17530502-20-cd102" type="crimeDate">April 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530502-20-off100 t17530502-20-cd102"></join> ++.</p>
               <p>He also stood charged on the coroner's inquest, for the said murder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530502-20-person230">
                  Sarah 
                  Oxley 
               <interp inst="t17530502-20-person230" type="surname" value="Oxley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-person230" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-person230" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17530502-20-crimeloc103">White-chapel</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17530502-20-crimeloc103" type="placeName" value="White-chapel"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17530502-20-crimeloc103" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530502-20-off100 t17530502-20-crimeloc103"></join> ; the prisoner's wife came to drink a dish of tea at my house, she had been there about half an hour, the prisoner came and knocked at the door, it was lock'd; she got up and opened it, and said, how do you do? he said, d - n your eyes, I'll do for you, you sent the bailiffs after me. She said, indeed I have not. Then he came in, and swore he'd beat her; he offered several blows at her, but did not hurt her; she got up and stood against a chair; he gave her a blow on the side of her face, whether his hand was open or shut, I know not; she took up her apron and held it to her face: I said, don't both back-beat and belly-beat your wife; she cried, he used me with many ill words, and said, d - n your eyes, you have nothing to do with it; and said to her d - n your eyes pull off that pocket, or I'll murder you; she took a pair of scissars off the table, and rip'd her pocket off, and slung it down; he did not touch it; she said, good God what would you have, I have not a farthing in my pocket ; she then sat down in the chair, and seemed ready to saint ; I said, will you have any water; he said, d - n you, you bitch, I had rather see you dead than alive, die and be d - n'd. Then he ran and took her about the back of her neck with one hand, with the other under her chin, as if going to kiss her: I went to put the pot to her mouth to drink some water, her teeth would not go together, her tongue was between, I saw her eyes stare in her face, she could not swallow, he held her head as if hugging her so all the while. He took the pot out of my hand, when she did<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175305020014"></xptr> not swallow, he held one hand at the back of her neck all the time. During all this time I thought he was kissing her. When he held her so, her eyes stared; I said, you Judas son of a bitch, you have murdered your wife; her limbs gave a jerk, and she never stirr'd hand nor foot any more, as I saw. This I made a deposition of before the coroner. He said she was subject to fits, and bid me give him the pot; he tried to power the water into her mouth. She fetched her breath till two o'clock in the morning, and this was between two and three the afternoon before: she remain'd in my house all the time. He tried to give her drops, but could not get it down; he poured hartshorn into her mouth, but that did not move her.</p>
               <p>Q. What state of health was she in before?</p>
               <p>S. Oxley. A very good state. She was blooded, and bled freely. We persuaded the prisoner to send for a surgeon ; he behaved very well, and said she'd be better when she came out of that fit, for she was only drunk. He seemed very much concerned at the last.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530502-20-person231">
                  Samuel 
                  Darkin 
               <interp inst="t17530502-20-person231" type="surname" value="Darkin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-person231" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-person231" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I understood the prisoner sent for me, I only practice bleeding, and operations on the teeth, the woman appeared to be stupified; I understood there had been some words and a blow pass'd, but I heard nothing of the strangling; I bled her, and she bled very free; this was between two and three in the afternoon. She did not speak, and I apprehend she could not; she breathed freely, and I did not apprehend she was a dying woman; there was some talk of drinking, I imagin'd something of that sort might be the cause, and that she was asleep. I did not see her again, till after she was dead, then I observ'd a little black mark just by her ear, near the bottom part. I apprehended it was from the blow.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you apprehend was the cause of her death.</p>
               <p>Darkin. I then could not tell, here are surgeons in court that can give an account, the prisoner paid me for bleeding her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530502-20-person232">
                  Nicholas 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17530502-20-person232" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-person232" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-person232" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a surgeon, at the time the coroner sat on this body, I was sent for to view it, and found the skin a little discolour'd, just below the ear, upon the neck; upon farther enquiry by opening the parts, I did not find any thing that appeared to occasion her death from that part; upon which the jury adjourned, that we might make a farther enquiry. I was call'd upon again, this day fortnight, and another surgeon was sent for, and upon opening the head, and examining the upper part of the brain, we found the brain extended, and a quantity of coagulated blood: we both concluded that that was the cause of her death, without paying any regard to the blow, and which we apprehend was occasioned by suffocation or strangling, which caused the bursting of the blood vessels in the brain.</p>
               <p>Q. You have heard the evidence given by the woman, do you think by the description she has given, whether or no this usage might occasion her death.</p>
               <p>Edwards. From the circumstances it seems to correspond with it.</p>
               <p>Q. If strangling was the cause of her death, could she bleed two or three hours after.</p>
               <p>Edwards. She might bleed whilst she was warm.</p>
               <p>Q. Could a person so suffocated breathe freely as mentioned.</p>
               <p>Edwards. These vessels bursting in the brain might be some time in spewing out the blood. There was the quantity of a turkey's egg-shell full of blood. They may breathe strong at the first, but in time will breathe shorter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530502-20-person233">
                  John 
                  Hunter 
               <interp inst="t17530502-20-person233" type="surname" value="Hunter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-person233" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-person233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was along with Mr. Edwards at the examining the body on the Coroner's inquest ; we found on the left side her head below the ear, the skin a little discolour'd, where Mr. Edwards had made an incision to examine it. I examined it a little farther, and found nothing extraordinary there. I examined the other side much in the same manner, but found nothing there. We went then to the brain, we sawed off the scull, and examin'd it in the substance of the brain, we found a great deal of coagulated blood, which I believe was the cause of her death.</p>
               <p>Q. What was that occasioned by?</p>
               <p>Hunter. I really believe it was by strangulation.</p>
               <p>Q. You have heard the account given by 
               <persName id="t17530502-20-person234">
                  Sarah 
                  Oxley 
               <interp inst="t17530502-20-person234" type="surname" value="Oxley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-person234" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-person234" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in what manner the deceas'd was treated by her husband ; do you believe her death was owing to that.</p>
               <p>Hunter. There is great probability to imagine it was.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I went into Oxley's house and sat down in a chair I asked my wife if she sent the bailiffs after me, she said she did not; she began to abuse me, and bid me go and hang myself; she fell into a sit, and I went and kissed her: she was very subject to fits. I fetched some water, and pour'd some down her throat; after that I sent for some sweet oil and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175305020015"></xptr> some wine, and fed her with it. Then I got some drops, and stroked her temples, and thought to have brought her to again. She has had many children by me; I should be a rogue indeed, to go to put her out of the world. I never touched her throat, no more than I do this minute. I sent for Mr. Darkin, he bled her. 
               <persName id="t17530502-20-person235">
                  Sarah 
                  Oxley 
               <interp inst="t17530502-20-person235" type="surname" value="Oxley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-person235" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-person235" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             would have turned her out of the door, in that condition, and some of the neighbours were much put to it, to persuade her to let her be there. My wife used to have something come up in her throat, I believe it was the rising of the lights; she used to be much affrighted about it.</p>
               <p>Q. to Edwards. Will this occasion a breaking of the blood vessels.</p>
               <p>Edwards. I have known persons in fits to have blood come from their mouth and nose, but I never knew the vessels to burst, except it was apoplectic.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530502-20-person236">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Newton 
               <interp inst="t17530502-20-person236" type="surname" value="Newton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-person236" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-person236" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard the prisoner had struck his wife, I ran to Oxley's house, and was with the deceas'd six hours; I said to the prisoner, what ails your wife, is she in a fit? he said he believed she was, and asked me what I thought of her. I went and fetched a bottle of drops, and gave her some, she struggled a little, and flung up a great deal of froath, she never spoke.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she subject to fits?</p>
               <p>E. Newton. I don't know that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530502-20-person237">
                  Susannah 
                  Dunn 
               <interp inst="t17530502-20-person237" type="surname" value="Dunn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-person237" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-person237" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I hearing there had been words and a blow between the prisoner and his wife, and that the deceas'd was dying, I went to see her a little before six in the afternoon. She was sitting in an arm-chair, quite senseless, and the prisoner had her head leaning against his bosom; I asked him what was the matter with his wife, he said he believed she was in a fit, and desired I would help him, which I did, and gave her some of the drops that 
               <persName id="t17530502-20-person238">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Newton 
               <interp inst="t17530502-20-person238" type="surname" value="Newton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-person238" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-person238" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             brought, and some wine ; then she struggled, and heav'd up froath.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you think was the matter with her?</p>
               <p>S. Dunn. Indeed I thought she was in a fit.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you known her to have fits?</p>
               <p>S. Dunn. No, my lord, I never did. 
               <persName id="t17530502-20-person239">
                  Sarah 
                  Oxley 
               <interp inst="t17530502-20-person239" type="surname" value="Oxley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-person239" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-person239" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was in a violent passion, and said to the prisoner, You rogue, you no nation, Jew-looking son of a bitch, I'll put three spokes in your wheel, I'll hang you by G - d.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530502-20-person240">
                  Abraham 
                  Devass 
               <interp inst="t17530502-20-person240" type="surname" value="Devass"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-person240" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-person240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was once a prisoner for debt, where the prisoner was likewise, he at times behaved much like a mad man, sometimes he'd not go to bed, nor sleep, for 13 or 14 days together.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530502-20-person241">
                  Thomas 
                  Toller 
               <interp inst="t17530502-20-person241" type="surname" value="Toller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-person241" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-person241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner 14 years, he and his wife have lived uneasy together for many years ; I went to see him since he was in confinement, and have talked to him much, and laid it as close to his conscience as I could; he always declared he had no intention to murder her, or any thing like it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17530502-20-verdict104" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-verdict104" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-verdict104" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17530502-20-punish105" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-punish105" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530502-20-punish105" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530502-20-person228 t17530502-20-punish105"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530502-20-defend229 t17530502-20-punish105"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
