<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17501017-20">
               <interp inst="t17501017-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501017-20" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501017-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17501017"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501017-20" type="date" value="17501017"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17501017-20-off104-c141" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-20-defend179 t17501017-20-off104 t17501017-20-verdict107"></join>
         
               <p>638. 
               
                  <persName id="t17501017-20-defend179" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Coppinger 
                  <interp inst="t17501017-20-defend179" type="surname" value="Coppinger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-20-defend179" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-20-defend179" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17501017-20-off104" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501017-20-off104" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-20-off104" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one wooden box, value 2 s. one gold ring, val. 12 s. one stock-buckle, value 5 s. and 40 s. in money numbered, in the dwelling house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17501017-20-victim181" type="victimName">
                           Henry 
                           Flannigin 
                        <interp inst="t17501017-20-victim181" type="surname" value="Flannigin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17501017-20-victim181" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17501017-20-victim181" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-20-off104 t17501017-20-victim181"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, the goods of the said Henry, <rs id="t17501017-20-cd105" type="crimeDate">October 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-20-off104 t17501017-20-cd105"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501017-20-person182">
                  Henry 
                  Flannigin 
               <interp inst="t17501017-20-person182" type="surname" value="Flannigin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-20-person182" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-20-person182" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the <placeName id="t17501017-20-crimeloc106">Hampshire Hog, St. Giles's in-the-fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17501017-20-crimeloc106" type="placeName" value="Hampshire Hog, St. Giles's in-the-fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17501017-20-crimeloc106" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501017-20-off104 t17501017-20-crimeloc106"></join>. The prisoner and others go in a gang together; he resorted to my house with one 
               <persName id="t17501017-20-person183">
                  O'Brian
               <interp inst="t17501017-20-person183" type="given" value="O'Brian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-20-person183" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and a fighting man, named 
               <persName id="t17501017-20-person184">
                  Maine
               <interp inst="t17501017-20-person184" type="given" value="Maine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-20-person184" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; he had used to see me go to this box to change money. Last Friday morning he breakfasted in my house, and he kept close in all day; his partners went out and came in again, one of them called for some beer, I carried them a pot of beer; they began to quarrel; they knocked one another down, and drove one another about. Coppinger, it seems, had got up stairs, and got this box and money away; then he went out and came again with a watchman without his hat, and said he had been knocked down.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him take the box?</p>
               <p>Flannigin. No, my lord, I did not see him take it; the room was broke open, I looked about and found the prisoner; after I found I had been robbed, and charged him with the watchman, he turned out his money, there was a silver 3 d. that was in my box, fell upon the floor; he denied he ever had such a piece in his custody. I took him at the Rose-and-Crown in St. Giles's Church-lane. I never could see O'Brian from that time to this, or any of his gang.</p>
               <p>Q. How much money did you lose?</p>
               <p>Flannigin. I cannot tell, but I know I swear under the sum.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501017-20-person185">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Flannigin 
               <interp inst="t17501017-20-person185" type="surname" value="Flannigin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-20-person185" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-20-person185" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know no more, but I found the silver 3 d. in the prisoner's pocket when he was taken, I saw it drop, and said it was mine; there is a hole in it, I keep it to wear about my child's neck.</p>
               <p>Q. How much money was there in the box?</p>
               <p>E. Flannigin. I am sure there were upwards of 40 s. it used always to be locked up, and it then was in my room, it had been in O'Brian's room, but I removed it; the prisoner had been in my house all day, he and some men had bred a great disturbance; my servant catched him several times on the stairs, and once he went up to O'Brian's room; after he was gone we missed the box, the chamber door was open, some of the wood of the door was broke, but the lock was not.</p>
               <p>Q. How big was this box?</p>
               <p>E. Flannigin. About three quarters of a yard long.</p>
               <p>Eliz. Bull. I live servant with the prosecutor. Last Friday the prisoner was at our house in and out all day; after I had bolted the back door, I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175010170015"></xptr> found the prisoner undoing the bolt; after that I saw him doing so a second time; I spoke to him again; he said he was speaking to an acquaintance; there stood a man in a brown coat; then I went up to make my master's bed, I locked the door and brought down the key, then I went to draw a pot of beer; after that I met the prisoner on the stairs, saying, he was going to O'Brian's room, I told him he had not been at home all day; then he said, there is a man in his room; my master went up, there was nobody there; then after that the prisoner opened the back door again, saying, my dear, I am going to make water. I went to bed about 11. Some time after my master called me and said the box was gone; after this the prisoner was brought into our house, and the 3 d. found, it dropped from him in searching him; my mistress made a 3 or a 4 upon it with a pin because she would know it, when she put it on the child's neck; I fetched this 3 d. from a pawnbroker's once in Denmark-street, it was a King William and Queen Mary's 3 d. I carried it to a pawnbroker with 5 s. in halfpence; after that my mistress said, go back and fetch the 3 d. I'll keep that for the child's neck, he looked into the box and gave it me. They took O'Brian before the justice, and he was discharged because we found nothing upon him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501017-20-person186">
                  Mary 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17501017-20-person186" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-20-person186" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-20-person186" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I work for Mrs. Flannigin in doing plain work. About 10 o'clock that Friday night the prisoner at the bar came out at the back door with the box in his hand, and run against me with it. I knew him then very well. The box was produced in court, found broke open in the street.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501017-20-person187">
                  John 
                  Leveridge 
               <interp inst="t17501017-20-person187" type="surname" value="Leveridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-20-person187" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-20-person187" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . That very night I went to the prosecutor's assistance, the prisoner was brought in, and in searching him this 3 d. fell down, I can swear to it amongst ten thousand. The 3 d. was produced in court and deposed to.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs. Flannigin. Is this your 3 d.?</p>
               <p>E. Flannigin. A man came to me and desired I would lend him 5 s, to fetch a pair of stays out of pawn, I did, and sent this with the halfpence; then I sent the maid to fetch it again; then I marked the figure of 4 with a pin upon it. There was a 4 marked on it as she said.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. That never fell from my pocket.</p>
               <p>[Some of the jury desired 
               <persName id="t17501017-20-person188">
                  Mary 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17501017-20-person188" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-20-person188" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-20-person188" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             might be ask'd if she was not once committed for giving false evidence in this court. To which she replied, she never was in Newgate in her life, and that she never gave evidence in that court in her life.]</p>
               <p>Court. Does any person here know this woman?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501017-20-person189">
                  John 
                  Rogers 
               <interp inst="t17501017-20-person189" type="surname" value="Rogers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-20-person189" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-20-person189" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I do, my lord. I keep the Newfoundland Dog-alehouse Charterhouse-lane.</p>
               <p>He, by the prisoner's desire, was sworn, and deposed he was in court about five or six sessions ago, and heard her give evidence in favour of a prisoner who was for the fact cast and executed, saying, the prisoner bought the tankard he was then trying for somewhere down in Walbrook, and when the trial was over she was committed for perjury; (for which see No. 34 in Sir Samuel Pennant's Mayoralty, the witness 
               <persName id="t17501017-20-person190">
                  Margaret 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17501017-20-person190" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-20-person190" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501017-20-person190" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) He said likewise he knew her husband, [the witness being a drummer now in general Onslow's company of horse grenadiers, but was in the foot in lord Ancram's company, to which her husband belonged] being asked his name, could not immediately say, and after some time said his name was Thompson, and that he had been lately tried in this court for a thief, and is now transported. (For which see No. 25 and No. 344, both in Sir William Calvert's Mayoralty.)</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17501017-20-verdict107" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501017-20-verdict107" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
