<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560603-13">
               <interp inst="t17560603-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560603-13" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560603-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560603"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560603-13" type="date" value="17560603"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560603-13-off67-c105" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560603-13-defend125 t17560603-13-off67 t17560603-13-verdict71"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560603-13-off67-c106" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560603-13-defend127 t17560603-13-off67 t17560603-13-verdict71"></join>
         
               <p>250, 251. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17560603-13-defend125" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Brangham 
                  <interp inst="t17560603-13-defend125" type="surname" value="Brangham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-13-defend125" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-13-defend125" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17560603-13-defend127" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Buckhurst 
                  <interp inst="t17560603-13-defend127" type="surname" value="Buckhurst"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-13-defend127" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-13-defend127" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17560603-13-deflabel66" type="occupation">spinsters</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560603-13-defend125 t17560603-13-deflabel66"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560603-13-defend127 t17560603-13-deflabel66"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17560603-13-off67" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560603-13-off67" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-13-off67" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch, value 52 s. the property of 
                     <persName id="t17560603-13-person128">
                        Edward 
                        West 
                     <interp inst="t17560603-13-person128" type="surname" value="West"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560603-13-person128" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560603-13-person128" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17560603-13-cd68" type="crimeDate">May 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560603-13-off67 t17560603-13-cd68"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560603-13-person129">
                  Edward 
                  West 
               <interp inst="t17560603-13-person129" type="surname" value="West"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-13-person129" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-13-person129" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17560603-13-crimeloc69">Leather Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17560603-13-crimeloc69" type="placeName" value="Leather Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17560603-13-crimeloc69" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560603-13-off67 t17560603-13-crimeloc69"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>West. I am an <rs id="t17560603-13-viclabel70" type="occupation">organ builder</rs>. Last Monday was three weeks I met the two prisoners in George Alley. They ask'd me to go with them, which I did. I took my watch out of my pocket, and laid it upon a table, and Buckhurst took it up, and ran down stairs with it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her take it?</p>
               <p>West. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. What was Brangham doing at the time?</p>
               <p>West. She did nothing at all. I ran down after Buckhurst, but she got away, and when I returned Brangham was gone also.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you find them afterwards?</p>
               <p>West. The constable took them up.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you give intelligence of them?</p>
               <p>West. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. When were they taken?</p>
               <p>West. The same night, but I did not know of it till a good while after. I advertised the watch the next day.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see your watch again?</p>
               <p>West. Yes, I did, at Guildhall. Produced in court and deposed to. The constable advertised it three or four times after I had.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say for themselves?</p>
               <p>West. They said I left it with them for half a crown, and was to have searched it again the next day.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you make such a bargain as that?</p>
               <p>West. No, I never did, I had some money in my pocket at the time.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175606030010"></xptr>Buckhurst. I was not night the watch. They were both on the bed together, and I did not stir from them.</p>
               <p>Brangham. He continued on the bed with me a good while after he miss'd his watch. We had another quartern of brandy brought up after that was gone.</p>
               <p>West. I was not on the bed half a minute after I saw Brangham go away with the watch, but it was ten o'clock at night, and dark, and I could not see her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560603-13-person130">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Normington 
               <interp inst="t17560603-13-person130" type="surname" value="Normington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-13-person130" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-13-person130" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am beadle of St. Andrew's, Holbourn. It was my night to attend at the watch-house. I was gone to an alehouse, and told the watchman if any thing should happen, to come to me. Soon after one came to me, and told me there was a charge brought to the watch-house. I went there and found the two prisoners. They were searched. Buckhurst was ready to undo her bosom to let us see she had no watch; but Carter, a watchman, said he felt it there. I searched Brangham, and found the watch on her left hip; I put my hand down her bosom, and took it out, and delivered it to the constable. This is it that is here produced.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560603-13-person131">
                  John 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17560603-13-person131" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-13-person131" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-13-person131" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The two prisoners were brought to the watch-house by two strange men, who said they had taken a watch from a gentleman, and desired to lodge them there till they could find the man; but they never returned again. I felt about Buckhurst, and felt the watch there, and after that she gave, it to Brangham.</p>
               <p>Brangham's defence. I did not know what she was going to give me in the watch-house. I was on the bed with the gentleman. When he got up, he said where is my watch? I said, I don't know, you know I have not been out of your company. He went down and treated a woman with two pints of beer, who told me so since when I was in the Compter. After that I was going to bed, and met two young men, one of them put his hand into Buckhurst's bosom and felt a watch, and said to the other, she has got a watch. They took us to the watch-house. Whose watch it was I can't tell.</p>
               <p>Buckhurst's defence. This young man came with Brangham, and call'd for a quartern of brandy; I brought a quartern of rasberry; that cost 3 d. They both went up stairs together. A young woman went up and came down again, and said he has left his watch for half a crown, and says he'll fetch it to-morrow. She gave it to me.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17560603-13-verdict71" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560603-13-verdict71" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-13-verdict71" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               guilty of stealing, but not privately from his person
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17560603-13-punish72" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560603-13-punish72" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560603-13-defend125 t17560603-13-punish72"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560603-13-defend127 t17560603-13-punish72"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
