<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17520514-29">
               <interp inst="t17520514-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520514-29" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520514-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520514"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520514-29" type="date" value="17520514"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520514-29-off154-c225" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-29-defend274 t17520514-29-off154 t17520514-29-verdict156"></join>
         
               <p>315. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17520514-29-defend274" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Somers 
                  <interp inst="t17520514-29-defend274" type="surname" value="Somers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-defend274" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-defend274" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , for <rs id="t17520514-29-off154" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-off154" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-off154" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               forging a counterfeit promissory note for the sum of 3 l. 19 s. sign'd 
                     <persName id="t17520514-29-person275">
                        William 
                        Ellis 
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-person275" type="surname" value="Ellis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520514-29-person275" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520514-29-person275" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , with intent to defraud 
                     
                        <persName id="t17520514-29-victim277" type="victimName">
                           Joseph 
                           Ellis 
                        <interp inst="t17520514-29-victim277" type="surname" value="Ellis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520514-29-victim277" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520514-29-victim277" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-29-off154 t17520514-29-victim277"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17520514-29-cd155" type="crimeDate">May 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520514-29-off154 t17520514-29-cd155"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-29-person278">
                  Joseph 
                  Ellis 
               <interp inst="t17520514-29-person278" type="surname" value="Ellis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-person278" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-person278" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . - 
               <persName id="t17520514-29-person279">
                  John 
                  Warner 
               <interp inst="t17520514-29-person279" type="surname" value="Warner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-person279" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-person279" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sent for me to the George alehouse, the corner of Prescot-street, Goodman's fields; he told me he had a note against me for 3 l. 19 s. and produced the note. I told<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175205140031"></xptr> him it could not be upon me, for my name is Joseph, and that was wrote William.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you a brother of that name alive?</p>
               <p>Ellis. I have. Warner told me he was the person intended in that note, and that if he did not pay it it would occasion me trouble. I wrote my name upon a bit of paper, to satisfy him it was neither my name nor hand-writing; he was not satisfied with that. I told him if he'd call at three o'clock I'd consult a gentleman; and after that satisfy him in the affair, accordingly he went away, and call'd at three; but I not being in the way, he offer'd the note in my absence. When I return'd he was charg'd with an officer upon suspicion of forging the note.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is the note?</p>
               <p>Ellis. It is now in the hands of the constable?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-29-person280">
                  Thomas 
                  Henshaw 
               <interp inst="t17520514-29-person280" type="surname" value="Henshaw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-person280" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-person280" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             produces it.</p>
               <p>Ellis. (Look upon it) this is it.</p>
               <p>Q. to Henshaw. How came you by this note?</p>
               <p>Henshaw. I was sent for to the Crown and Magpye in Whitechapal, and one Mr. Duncley gave me charge of Warner, and delivered the note into my hands, which I have kept ever since.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-29-person281">
                  John 
                  Duncley 
               <interp inst="t17520514-29-person281" type="surname" value="Duncley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-person281" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-person281" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Prescott-street, Goodman's-fields. 
               <persName id="t17520514-29-person282">
                  Joseph 
                  Ellis 
               <interp inst="t17520514-29-person282" type="surname" value="Ellis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-person282" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-person282" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is my clerk; he came to me as I was at dinner, and told me there was a note forged upon him in the name of William, and if he did not pay it, the persons insisted upon giving him trouble, and said he never gave such a note. I hearing several persons had been intimidated for small sums that they could get into White-chapel court to make them pay it, I thought proper to charge the two persons that came; so I sent for an officer, that when they came, to take them into custody, which they did on Friday between two and three o'clock. The officer was not at home, and I desired them to stay 'till my clerk came: They were for going, then I asked them if they had any demand upon my clerk? They said yes, and produced this note. Upon seeing it was not his hand writing, I took them into custody, and they were examined before my Lord Mayor, and I gave the note into the constable's hand. They brought the prisoner before my Lord, who examined him about the note; there the prisoner said the note was his note, and Warner said he had it of the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520514-29-person283">
                  John 
                  Warner 
               <interp inst="t17520514-29-person283" type="surname" value="Warner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-person283" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-person283" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This is the note I had of the prisoner, he brought it to me this day 7 weeks.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Warner. I am an officer in White-chapel Court ; the prisoner indors'd the note to me.</p>
               <p>Q. What directions did he give you about it?</p>
               <p>Warner. He told me where the man liv'd, and gave me an order to arrest Mr. Ellis living it merchant Duncley's, and said there were two brothers of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you the christian name?</p>
               <p>Warner. No, he only bid me to arrest him upon this note, he told me likewise he had 50 l. per year, at Mr. Duncley's, and came to me time after time about it; on the 8th of May, I went to the George, and sent for the prosecutor, and acquainted him with it, he told me he was not the person he was sure, and desired to see the note.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you bring an action upon the note?</p>
               <p>Warner. No, I did not, I only shew'd it him, he wrote his name, to shew me the mistake, and desired me to come again at three in the afternoon, and he would talk with the merchant about it, and said it was not his hand writing: I went at three o'clock, and a servant shew'd me where the merchant was, at the Crown and Magpye in Whitechapel ; it being a tavern, I said to the young man that was with me, we'll go to the Coach and horses, and get a pint of beer, then Mr. Duncley and the others came and laid hold on us, I had before given the note into Mr. Duncley's hand, then I was carried to the Compter in the Poultry, and the other man to that in Woodstreet: When we came before my Lord-Mayor, on the Saturday, the prisoner owned it to be his, and said, that I had no concern in it, and I was discharged; he said also, he had indors'd it to me.</p>
               <p>Q. How came the prisoner there?</p>
               <p>Warner. I sent home to Well-close-square to let him know of it.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to go with this note to demand money, without entering an action?</p>
               <p>Warner. I thought as he liv'd with a gentleman, and had so much a Year, he would pay it without an action.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he indorse this note to you?</p>
               <p>Warner. I think it was this day 7 weeks, when he first delivered it to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you pay him the contents?</p>

               <p>Warner. No, I paid him no money for it.</p>
               <p>Q. What is he?</p>
               <p>Warner. He told me, he belong'd to the Deptford Man of War, and that he thought he must be obliged to go aboard, and desired me to get the money.</p>
               <p>Q. How came he to indorse the note to you without receiving the money?</p>
               <p>Warner. He indorsed the note to me, in order for me to bring an action in my own name.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175205140032"></xptr>Q. Are you so desirous to assist strangers, that you will stand plaintiff?</p>
               <p>Warner. No, my Lord, but he told me he would satisfy me; it is a very common thing to have them indorsed to the officer.</p>
               <p>Court. It is a very bad practice.</p>
               <p>Q. to Joseph Ellis. Is this note your brother's writing ?</p>
               <p>Ellis. I believe it is not; I have seen him write often, it is not like his hand writing.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the subscribing witness that is upon it?</p>
               <p>Ellis. No, I know no such person.</p>
               <p>The note is read to this purport:</p>
               <p>'' I Promise to pay unto Mr. 
               <persName id="t17520514-29-person284">
                  Thomas 
                  Somers 
               <interp inst="t17520514-29-person284" type="surname" value="Somers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-person284" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-person284" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , or '' order, upon demand, the Sum of 3 l. 19 s. '' for value receiv'd,</p>
               <p>per 
               <persName id="t17520514-29-person285">
                  William 
                  Ellis 
               <interp inst="t17520514-29-person285" type="surname" value="Ellis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-person285" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-person285" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Indorsed 
               <persName id="t17520514-29-person286">
                  Thomas 
                  Somers 
               <interp inst="t17520514-29-person286" type="surname" value="Somers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-person286" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-person286" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Witness, 
               <persName id="t17520514-29-person287">
                  James 
                  Bedward 
               <interp inst="t17520514-29-person287" type="surname" value="Bedward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-person287" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-person287" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>3 19 0</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>That paper was put into my hands by 
               <persName id="t17520514-29-person288">
                  William 
                  Ellis 
               <interp inst="t17520514-29-person288" type="surname" value="Ellis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-person288" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-person288" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , witnessed by 
               <persName id="t17520514-29-person289">
                  James 
                  Bedward 
               <interp inst="t17520514-29-person289" type="surname" value="Bedward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-person289" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-person289" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , for money he received of me; I heard he lived at No. 26. in Prescot-street, with a merchant, as a clerk; I went to Warner and gave him this note, to get the money for me, he told me, I must indorse the note over to him, and he would endeavour to get the money for me; I directed him to this No. 26. he came and said, he had been there, and no such person lived there, but he was informed that such a person lived with lady Lethgrove, at Stepney, and he would go and enquire there: after which he sent word, that he had some intelligence of him, and desired I would go with him to see the man. The witness Bedworth is gone to sea.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520514-29-verdict156" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520514-29-verdict156" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
