<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560915-42">
               <interp inst="t17560915-42" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-42" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-42" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560915"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560915-42" type="date" value="17560915"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560915-42-off215-c248" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-42-defend327 t17560915-42-off215 t17560915-42-verdict218"></join>
         
               <p>373. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17560915-42-defend327" type="defendantName">
                  
                     George 
                     Langley 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17560915-42-alias-5" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-42-defend327 t17560915-42-alias-5"></join>Playter</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-42-defend327" type="surname" value="Langley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-42-defend327" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-42-defend327" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17560915-42-off215" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560915-42-off215" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-42-off215" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one silk purse, value 6 d. one canvas bag, two gold watches, two Pinchbeck metal watches, two silver watches, two gold seals, one Pinchbeck metal snuff box, one gold medal, two gold rings, one pair of sleeve buttons, 37 pieces of foreign coin call'd 36 s. pieces, twenty-seven moidores, one half moidore, one hundred and twenty guineas, and nine pounds three-shillings in money number'd, the goods and money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17560915-42-victim330" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Price 
                        <interp inst="t17560915-42-victim330" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560915-42-victim330" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560915-42-victim330" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-42-off215 t17560915-42-victim330"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling-house of the said William
            </rs>, <rs id="t17560915-42-cd216" type="crimeDate">August 11</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-42-off215 t17560915-42-cd216"></join> ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-42-person331">
                  William 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17560915-42-person331" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-42-person331" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-42-person331" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the <placeName id="t17560915-42-crimeloc217">Queen of Hungary's Head near Sadler's Wells</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17560915-42-crimeloc217" type="placeName" value="Queen of Hungary's Head near Sadler's Wells"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17560915-42-crimeloc217" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-42-off215 t17560915-42-crimeloc217"></join>. The prisoner at the bar lodged a fortnight at my house.</p>
               <p>Q. How came he first to your house?</p>
               <p>Price. He was brought to my house by Mr. Wilkerson, his wife, and Miss Wilkerson, who dances on the wire at the Wells. On the 11th of August he paid me five pounds eleven shillings and six-pence, being the last day of his being at my house. When he was gone I carried the money to my wife, who keeps my money. She said, I think here is a piece of gold like a thirty six shilling piece.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175609150020"></xptr> She went to put it to the other money, but every shilling was gone. I went in search of him, and being told he was at the Swan in Smithfield I found him there, and charged him with robbing me that morning. He at first denied it, and said, you know I told you I had but two guineas, and now I have but a guinea and half, and said I might search him; I put my hand in his pocket, and pull'd out twenty-four pounds ten shillings, and a Queen-Ann's crown piece that I can swear to, made in the year 1713, and yellow'd over.</p>
               <p>Q. In what coin was this money?</p>
               <p>Price. It was some guineas, some nine-shilling pieces, thirty-six shilling pieces, and moidores. After that he own'd he had rob'd me. I ask'd him if this money I had found upon him was mine ? He said, it was.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you seen that crown piece last?</p>
               <p>Price. I can't tell. I told him that was my crown piece, and that he stole it from me; yes, said he, I did ( produced in court, and deposed to.) I carried him back to my house.</p>
               <p>Q. By what do you know it ?</p>
               <p>Price. There is a little scratch on the face of it, and the yellow is worn off that part by keeping it in my pocket. My predecessor left it me, and I always kept it; was it put among a hundred crown pieces I'd pick it out. He had got a Pinchbeck watch in his pocket. Some of the people pull'd it out, and ask'd me if it was mine? I knew it, and said it was, and that both I and my wife would swear to it; he said, it was mine. I then charged him with stealing 120 l. He said, if I'd go home with him, he'd give me what he had not spent; but what he had spent, he could not give me. I charged him with taking other watches. He denied taking any, except this, and one which he sold in Cheapside, to Mr. Watkinson Wildman; that he said he took out of my house, and that he had changed it with seven guineas for another watch, name Clark.</p>
               <p>Q. What was that, silver or gold?</p>
               <p>Price. Mine was a silver one. My wife knowing best what money was lost, charged him with that in my hearing. He said, he had but so much out of one bag, and so much out of another; not allowing he had taken so much as she said he had.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen any other of the watches since ?</p>
               <p>Price. No, I have not. He was carried before justice Keeling, and there he wrote a confession with his own hands, and sign'd it.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the money taken from?</p>
               <p>Price. From out of a chest or drawers in the chamber I lie in. I never troubled myself with that, but left it with my wife. When I wanted 20 l. or 30 l. I had it from her, and the watches were some in a glass case on the drawers, and some in the drawers.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he come first to lodge with you?</p>
               <p>Price. A fortnight before the 11th of August, but he had used my house a fortnight before that.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he lodge before?</p>
               <p>Price. At the White Lion in Wood's Close, as they tell me.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you take him to be?</p>
               <p>Price. They told me he was an esquire, but I did not believe it.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he himself tell you?</p>
               <p>Price. He told me he was a planter's son in Antigoa; he fell in love with Miss Wilkerson, and was going to make away with himself for her, as I was inform'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Were not Miss Wilkerson and he frequently together at your house?</p>
               <p>Price. They were.</p>
               <p>Q. How much did he run up in that fortnight's time?</p>
               <p>Price. He run most of that score he paid me before he came to lodge with me.</p>
               <p>Q. Can't you tell how much money he spent in that fortnight?</p>
               <p>Price. I cannot. There was once nine or ten of them at supper together.</p>
               <p>Q. How old is he?</p>
               <p>Price. He told me he was very near seventeen years old.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to encourage him to bring Miss Wilkerson to your house?</p>
         
               <p>N. B. The second Part of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17560915-42">
                  <interp inst="t17560915-42" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17560915-42" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17560915-42" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560915"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17560915-42" type="date" value="17560915"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175609150021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON, And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 15th, Thursday the 16th, Friday the 17th, Saturday the 18th and Monday the 20th of SEPTEMBER,</p>
                  <p>In the Thirtieth Year of His MAJESTY'S Reign. NUMBER VII. Part II. for the YEAR 1756. Being the Seventh SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of The Right Honble SLINGSBY BETHELL, Esq; LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by J. ROBINSON, at the Golden-Lion, in Ludgate-Street. 1756.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175609150022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery held for the City of LONDON, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Price. I TOLD him I would trust him no more, and after I was rob'd she never came more.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you have not proposed or told any body, that if he wou'd confess the taking of your money you would not prosecute him.</p>
               <p>Price. There was such a thing mention'd by the gentlemen; they desired him to confess where the money was.</p>
               <p>Q. Name who mention'd that.</p>
               <p>Price. Mr. Rosoman offer'd him 5 guineas to tell where the money was, and said if he would he shou'd go about his business.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this in the presence of the justice?</p>
               <p>Price. I believe it was, but am not sure.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is Mr. Rosoman?</p>
               <p>Price. He keeps Sadler's Wells.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you make him such a promise as to forgive him, if he would tell you where the money was?</p>
               <p>Price. I don't know but I might say, Be so good as to tell me where my money is, and if you lie in gaol, or are sent abroad, and want any money, you shall not starve.</p>
               <p>Q. Let the court know the express terms that any body mention'd to him, about favour being shewn him.</p>
               <p>Price. I know no more than what I have told already; I myself made him no farther promise than what I have said, that he should not want in gaol till he came to be tried.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-42-person332">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17560915-42-person332" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-42-person332" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-42-person332" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the prosecutor. The prisoner came to lodge at our house the latter end of July, and staid a fortnight. He went from our house on the 11th of August, about a quarter after six. I had about 18 watches in my bed room, and upwards of 300 l. in cash, which I missed that same day. My husband came up stairs, and gave me some money he had received of the prisoner, 3 guineas and a 36 s piece. I asked him where he had the 36 s. piece, for it was like my own money. I then took the key of the drawer which lay on the table and open'd it, and all was gone.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is that 36 s. piece?</p>
               <p>E. Price. I forgot to bring it with me; it is at home.</p>
               <p>Q. What coin did your cash that is missing consist of?</p>
               <p>E. Price. There were one hundred pounds tied up in a canvas bag, 5 times nineteen guineas and 5 s. in silver; there was a purse with 48 guineas, and another green silk purse with thirty seven 36 s. pieces, in another old green silk purse there were 27 moidores, and in a piece of paper there were wrap'd up 36 pounds in gold and silver, in order to pay my landlord; there were also eight pounds eight shillings in silver, tied up in a canvas bag, and a quantity of gold in a running cash bag, I don't know how much, but imagine there might be about twenty or thirty pounds of it; it was in a hair bag, and I had taken seven guineas out of it over-night; and there was a particular crown piece lay upon the gold in the same drawer where all the money lay.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the drawer where the money was always kept lock'd?</p>
               <p>E. Price. It was.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were the watches ?</p>
               <p>E. Price. They were in a glass case upon the chest of drawers: There was a bag, in which there was a bond belonging to us, and there was also a 20 l. bank note taken away.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you use to leave that key on the table?</p>
               <p>E. Price. It was often left on the table, but the two room doors were always lock'd. Upon missing the money I call'd my husband up, and ask'd for my money (thinking he had done something with it.) He ask'd me if I was mad. The prisoner was brought back to our house about eleven o'clock that morning. I ask'd him for my own watch. He said, Mrs. Price, I have not your own<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175609150023"></xptr> watch; but if you'll go down stairs into your room I'll give you your watch. When he went into my room I saw a watch hang out of his pocket. I pull'd it out, and said, that is not what I mean by my own watch, but this is one of mine; it is a Pinchbeck meta watch (produced in court, and deposed to.) I said to him, is not this mine? He said, yes madam, it is. I was call'd down stairs, and left my husband and Mr. Rosoman with him. Sometime after that we went up stairs, and on the bed where he lay, there was my watch laid wrap'd up in a dirty piece of paper on the top of a press bed.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is that?</p>
               <p>E. Price. I did not bring that.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was that taken from?</p>
               <p>E. Price. It was in a drawer among my own cloaths, in the same room where I lay. I had wound it up about five o'clock in the afternoon the day before. I charged him at the same time with taking the several sums of money mentioned. He said, he took the money wrap'd up in the paper and the money out of the purse, and put in halfpence.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he own he took all the money?</p>
               <p>E. Price. No, he never owned he took the 100 l. bag.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he own he had taken all the watches which you missed?</p>
               <p>E. Price. No, he said he had taken but two watches; but there were several snuff boxes that he had taken out of the same shew glass. He made a present of one to Miss Wilkerson (a Pinchbeck snuff box, with two gold rings, produced in court.) These were delivered to me by Miss. Wilkerson. The box is mine, and I can swear to one of the rings. The other I cannot, because the stone has been altered.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you lose that ring from?</p>
               <p>E. Price. From out of the glass case.</p>
               <p>Q. What is that worth?</p>
               <p>E. Price. It is not worth above 15 or 16 s. ( Another watch produced.)</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this silver watch, do you k now it?</p>
               <p>E. Price. This is also my property. This was at Mr. Wildman's a goldsmith's, and I lately offered it for four guineas and a half to one of Mr. Rosoman's waiters.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the money that was taken from the prisoner?</p>
               <p>E. Price. I did; there were twenty four guineas or thereabouts. He said he took it out of the drawer. At that time he told us he had sold a watch to Mr. Wildman. My husband was by.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any threats made use of before he acknowledged this ?</p>
               <p>E. Price. The gentlemen said, if he'd give the poor people their money again, things should be made easy.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>E. Price. This was at the justice's, but I was in too great a passion to observe much what was said.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was it before the 11th of August that you saw the ninety-five guineas and five shillings in silver?</p>
               <p>E. Price. Two days before I had it in my hand and tied it up.</p>
               <p>Q. How long before that time did you see the 37 thirty-six shilling pieces?</p>
               <p>E. Price. I saw them on the Monday morning before, and the moidores also. The other money I saw on Wednesday morning</p>
               <p>Q. Were the keys left in the doors?</p>
               <p>E. Price. So he says, but not as I know of.</p>
               <p>Q. Is not your's a publick house?</p>
               <p>E. Price. It is, but nobody goes up there.</p>
               <p>Q. How much of your money have you got again?</p>
               <p>E. Price. About twenty-four pounds ten shillings, and three watches.</p>
               <p>Q. How much money did he acknowledge he took?</p>
               <p>E. Price. He acknowledged he took thirty-six pounds, the running cash, and the forty guineas, and put in halfpence. He said he had paid his taylor and his millener, and had bought I don't know how many things with the money.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-42-person333">
                  Matthew 
                  Wells 
               <interp inst="t17560915-42-person333" type="surname" value="Wells"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-42-person333" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-42-person333" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am shopman to Mr. Wildman, a gold-smith, in Cheapside. On the 19th of July between eight and nine o'clock the youth at the bar came to the shop, and asked to see some stone buckles. I shew'd him some, and he bought a pair of shoe buckles, a pair of knee buckles, a gold watch chain, and key, a gold compass seal, and a case to hold the silver buckles in; in all he paid five pounds four shillings. He came about the Thursday following with the pair of stone shoe buckles, and desired I'd take them again. I told him. I would, but could not allow him so much as he gave for them. I give him thirty-six shillings. Then he desired I'd keep them a few days, and he'd fetch them again; he said his father did not like them. He came on the 31st of July and ask'd for them. I gave him them, and he gave me a thirty-six shilling piece. Pray, said he, have you ever a good plain gold watch? I shew'd him one, and took in<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175609150024"></xptr> exchange between this silver watch here produced, and that, seven guineas.</p>
               <p>Mr. Baileys. I am clerk to justice Keeling. The prisoner was brought before him, and ask'd, if he'd make a voluntary confession? He said, yes. What Mr. Rosoman said to him, was after he had sign'd it. There were no such words said to him before the justice of giving him five guineas. After the confession was made, I read it over to him three times, and each time he was ask'd if he was satisfied; and he answered he was.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is Mr. Rosoman ?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. He is not here.</p>

               <p>Court. We can't suffer this confession to be read under the circumstances of such a promise made, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Isabella Wilkerson. (She takes a Pinchbeck snuff box in her hand, and the ring the prosecutor's wife deposed to.) I know both these, I had them of Mr. Langley.</p>
               <p>Q. What time had you them of him?</p>
               <p>I. Wilkerson. I can't tell.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to part with them?</p>
               <p>I. Wilkerson. I heard he was taken up, so I delivered the box to Mrs. Price on the 11th of August. I don't know who I delivered the ring to.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they given you both at one time?</p>
               <p>I. Wilkerson. No, they were not; the box was given to me first, and I have worn the ring a good many times. I believe pretty near a week.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you been acquainted with Mr. Langley ?</p>
               <p>I. Wilkerson. About a month.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he first become acquainted with you?</p>
               <p>I. Wilkerson. At the Wells.</p>
               <p>Q. What, before he came to lodge at Mr. Price's ?</p>
               <p>I. Wilkerson. Yes, he told my Papa when I had done performing to come and sup with him; but I did not know the gentleman.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever wear that ring in Mr. Price's house ?</p>
               <p>I. Wilkerson. Yes I have, and used the snuff box too, many times.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I made that confession because Mr. Price told me he would set me at liberty. I hope your Lordship will consider my youth. I am not sixteen years of age. I beg to be transported.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-42-person334">
                  William 
                  Roch 
               <interp inst="t17560915-42-person334" type="surname" value="Roch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-42-person334" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-42-person334" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about twelve months. I have trusted him several times in my shop, and I always took him to be a very honest young man. I am a stationer, and he has friends living in great repute in my neighbourhood.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-42-person335">
                  Francis 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17560915-42-person335" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-42-person335" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-42-person335" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a linen-draper in Holbourn. I believe I have known him a year. I have trusted him in my shop, and he is of very reputable parents.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath, what do you think to be his age?</p>
               <p>Williams. I really believe him to be about sixteen.</p>
               <p>Q. to Roch. What do you think to be his age?</p>
               <p>Roch. About sixteen.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560915-42-person336">
                  Philip 
                  Marsh 
               <interp inst="t17560915-42-person336" type="surname" value="Marsh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-42-person336" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560915-42-person336" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him a year or something better. I took him to be a very modest lad, and I never heard a tittle against his honesty.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his age?</p>
               <p>Marsh. I take him to be between sixteen and seventeen.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17560915-42-verdict218" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560915-42-verdict218" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17560915-42-punish219" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560915-42-punish219" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560915-42-defend327 t17560915-42-punish219"></join>
               Death
            </rs>. Recommended.</p>
            </div1>
