<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17520116-34">
               <interp inst="t17520116-34" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520116-34" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520116-34" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520116-34" type="date" value="17520116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520116-34-off176-c256" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520116-34-defend325 t17520116-34-off176 t17520116-34-verdict179"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520116-34-off176-c257" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520116-34-defend327 t17520116-34-off176 t17520116-34-verdict181"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520116-34-off182-c256" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520116-34-defend325 t17520116-34-off182 t17520116-34-verdict179"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520116-34-off182-c257" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520116-34-defend327 t17520116-34-off182 t17520116-34-verdict181"></join>
         
               <p>119, 120. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17520116-34-defend325" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Saunders 
                  <interp inst="t17520116-34-defend325" type="surname" value="Saunders"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-defend325" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-defend325" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17520116-34-defend327" type="defendantName">
                     Jane 
                     Richens 
                  <interp inst="t17520116-34-defend327" type="surname" value="Richens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-defend327" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-defend327" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted, together with 
               <persName id="t17520116-34-person328">
                  Eleanor 
                  Chun 
               <interp inst="t17520116-34-person328" type="surname" value="Chun"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-person328" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-person328" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , not yet taken, for the <rs id="t17520116-34-off176" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-off176" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-off176" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               murder of a person unknown
            </rs>, <rs id="t17520116-34-cd177" type="crimeDate">March 25, in the 22d. year of his present Majesty</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520116-34-off176 t17520116-34-cd177"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520116-34-off182 t17520116-34-cd177"></join>.* </p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520116-34-person329">
                  Rice 
                  Lewis
               <interp inst="t17520116-34-person329" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-person329" type="given" value="Rice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-person329" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             About  three weeks ago, there was a rumour of a person being taken who had murder'd a man on <placeName id="t17520116-34-crimeloc178">Smallbury green</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17520116-34-crimeloc178" type="placeName" value="Smallbury green"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17520116-34-crimeloc178" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520116-34-off176 t17520116-34-crimeloc178"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520116-34-off182 t17520116-34-crimeloc178"></join>, about three years ago; and as I live in the neighbourhood, and had been foreman of the jury upon the coroner's inquisition, I had a desire to see a thing of that nature brought to light; I went to him where he was in custody; there I heard him make confession how the murder was committed; I asked him several questions, backwards and forwards; he said his confession was from a compunction which he still felt ; that he had no rest ; and that he hoped that confession would give him satisfaction and case; I thought he was a little in liquor, and therefore did not give great heed to it; I asked him if he was weary of his life, or did not know how to maintain himself, he said his confession was from another cause, from some uneasiness he felt from within; after this I understood he went before justice Birkhead, and would there make confession of the same; the justice did not think him fit as being in liquor; the next morning he went voluntarily before the justice, he was then entirely sober; I being an officer in the parish where the robbery and murder was committed, I was sent for, but not till after the confession was made: Mr. Birkhead bound me over to appear in this court, on this occasion; I have frequently seen the two women; they have very infamous characters, after the murder, there was a notion prevailed, that the woman untaken was a person suspected to have been concerned in it; the man did confess in my hearing, he was assisted by two women, that the man he met with on Smallbury-green, was on horse-back; and by their assistance he was pulled from his horse, and after that he put his hand into the man's breeches pocket, and took out six shillings; after which they threw him into a pit where gravel had been dug, for mending the road, and in which there was a lodgment of water of sufficient depth to drown a man ; and when he was in, they took up stones out of the highway and paked him as he lay in the pit; after which he alone took the bridle and saddle from the horse and threw them into the same pit: then they went to some houses, and spent that night in revelling with the money they had taken from the man.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there such a person found in a pit?</p>
               <p>Lewis. There was a pit, it is not above a quarter of a mile from the place of my habitation, in Isleworth parish : on viewing the body, which was carried to the Stock house, we observed there was some rufflings on the skin, on the back part of the head, and more particularly a bruise on the side of the temple, the skin was a little raised, but I think not enough to cause a fracture, as the Surgeons call it; this was very particular, the body was found floating, some of my brother jurymen saw it, I did not; it is a particular pleasure to me to find out truth ; I had given my opinion, and we were unanimous before the Coroner, that the man was murdered, from that circumstance of the body floating, which we looked upon must have been committed prior to his being thrown in the water, concluding that where the suction is lost, the water cannot enter the body, from its being clos'd, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the horse?</p>
               <p>Lewis. I did not observe there was a horse found.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the saddle and bridle found ?</p>
               <p>Lewis. No, my Lord, there was no evidence but the body of a man before us.</p>
               <p>Q. Is that pond always full of water?</p>
               <p>Lewis. It is sometimes full, occasioned by the rains, sometimes it is not so.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175201160034"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17520116-34-person330">
                  John 
                  Lighton 
               <interp inst="t17520116-34-person330" type="surname" value="Lighton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-person330" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-person330" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             : I am constable, (he produced the confession of Saunders ) I heard him make this freely before the Justice, here is my name as a witness, which I set to it, and here is Saunders's mark to it, dated Dec. 27, 1751. It is read in court to this purport:</p>
               <p>On Easter evening, two years ago, he was in company with 
               <persName id="t17520116-34-person331">
                  Eleanor 
                  Chun 
               <interp inst="t17520116-34-person331" type="surname" value="Chun"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-person331" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-person331" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17520116-34-person332">
                  Jane 
                  Richens 
               <interp inst="t17520116-34-person332" type="surname" value="Richens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-person332" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-person332" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at the Green Man at Hounslow, from seven till twelve at night; that then he and they went out of the said house to Smallbury Green, where they met a man on horseback, very much in liquor, that they pulled him off his horse, that 
               <persName id="t17520116-34-person333">
                  Jane 
                  Richens 
               <interp inst="t17520116-34-person333" type="surname" value="Richens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-person333" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-person333" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             took out of his pocket 6 s. in silver, and that, with the assistance of him, they threw the man into a pond, and then they took up stones and threw at him, and after that he took the bridle and saddle, and threw them upon him, and that the two women and he went to Brandford to three or four public houses, and continued together till seven in the morning, when they had spent the money, then he went home, and farther faith nor.</p>
               <p>Lighton continues. I took the prisoner up for breaking a man's windows at Hounslow ; he said, if he came again before a Justice of the peace, he'd make a confession of a murder upon Smallbury-Green. The Justice then would not take his examination, thinking he was drunk: I took him to the house, where they gave him some good victuals and small beer, and the next day brought him again to the Justice, where he made the same confession he had the day before, without variation. He said, he was at work at his father's shop on a Saturday night, that he went out and lit of these two women mentioned, that they went to the Green Man at Hounslow, that when they went out there, they had no money amongst them all, that they agreed to rob some people if they could, that they met this man much in liquor, and he laid hold on the horse's bridle with one hand, and helped to pull him off with the other, that 
               <persName id="t17520116-34-person334">
                  Jane 
                  Richens 
               <interp inst="t17520116-34-person334" type="surname" value="Richens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-person334" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-person334" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             took the money out of his pocket, (once he said he took the money) that they dragged him three or four yards from the place where they robbed him, and put him into this pond, then they took stones out of the highway and pelted him; the Justice asked what stones they were? he said, as big some of them as they could get; he was asked, if he thought they hit him? he said, he could not tell, but that they strived to hit him, and he believed they might; then he pulled the bridle and saddle from off the horse, and threw them upon him; the Justice asked, what he did that for? he said, because they were drunk and mad, and did not know what they did; then he said, they went to Brentford and spent the whole six shillings.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you live near the place where the murder was committed ?</p>
               <p>Lighton. I live in the same parish.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the body?</p>
               <p>Lighton. I did not, my Lord.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520116-34-person335">
                  John 
                  Godard 
               <interp inst="t17520116-34-person335" type="surname" value="Godard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-person335" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-person335" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a public house in Hounslow ; I saw the body about a quarter of an hour after it was taken out of the water, which lay close by the pond side; there was no water came out of his mouth: he had an ugly wound near his temple. The prisoner, Saunders, broke my windows, so I had him before the Justice; when he was there, he said, he would confess what he had been guilty of, saying, he was guilty of murder; then I was ordered to take him to my house, where he had nothing but small beer and good victuals: the Justice ordered me to fetch the woman at the bar; I went and took her at the Green Man. At five in the morning I went into Saunder's room, said I, how did you sleep? are you easy in your mind? do you remember what you said? he said, I remember what I said, I have slept very well and am easy, and what I said I'll confess.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you look upon him to be in his senses?</p>
               <p>Godard. I don't think he is mad, he is a very dangerous man, and very wicked.</p>
               <p>Q. to Lighton. How long have you known Saunders?</p>
               <p>Lighton. I have known him between three and four years?</p>
               <p>Q. What do you think of him as to his being in his senses?</p>
               <p>Lighton. I think he is disturbed in his mind, his mother says he is at times, and used to have fits.</p>
               <p>Q. to Godard. What was the occasion of his breaking your windows?</p>
               <p>Godard. He came to my house with her brother-in-law, and had two pots of beer, and he did not chuse to pay for above one, upon which they broke them, and when I desired him to pay for the damage done, he came and broke more; I never knew he was disordered in his mind.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Lewis. What is your opinion of him as to his being out of his mind?</p>
               <p>Lewis. Although he lives in the neighbourhood, I don't remember to have seen him above<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175201160035"></xptr> three times; he is debauch'd in his morals very much.</p>
               <p>Saunders's defence.</p>
               <p>I am very innocent of the murder; I never saw the man in my Life; I am not in my senses, nor know what I speak.</p>
               <p>Saunders, <rs id="t17520116-34-verdict179" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-verdict179" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17520116-34-punish180" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-punish180" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520116-34-defend325 t17520116-34-punish180"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Richens <rs id="t17520116-34-verdict181" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-verdict181" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520116-34-person336">
                  Jane 
                  Richens 
               <interp inst="t17520116-34-person336" type="surname" value="Richens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-person336" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-person336" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was a second time indicted, for that <rs id="t17520116-34-off182" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-off182" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-off182" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               she, together with 
                     <persName id="t17520116-34-person337">
                        Joseph 
                        Saunders 
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-person337" type="surname" value="Saunders"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520116-34-person337" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520116-34-person337" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   and 
                     <persName id="t17520116-34-person338">
                        Eleanor 
                        Chun 
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-person338" type="surname" value="Chun"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520116-34-person338" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520116-34-person338" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , on the King's highway, on a certain person unknown, did make an assault, six shillings in money numbered, from his person did steal, &amp;c
            </rs>. <rs id="t17520116-34-cd183" type="crimeDate">March 25, in the 22d year of his present Majesty</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520116-34-off176 t17520116-34-cd183"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520116-34-off182 t17520116-34-cd183"></join>.</p>
               <p>Here were no other evidence against her than what had been produced on the former trial, she was <rs id="t17520116-34-verdict184" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520116-34-verdict184" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
