<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17500711-65">
               <interp inst="t17500711-65" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-65" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-65" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17500711"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500711-65" type="date" value="17500711"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500711-65-off287-c409" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-65-defend532 t17500711-65-off287 t17500711-65-verdict289"></join>
         
               <p>493. 
               
                  <persName id="t17500711-65-defend532" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Pearson 
                  <interp inst="t17500711-65-defend532" type="surname" value="Pearson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-65-defend532" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-65-defend532" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for the <rs id="t17500711-65-off287" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500711-65-off287" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-65-off287" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17500711-65-victim534" type="victimName">
                           Samuel 
                           Denton 
                        <interp inst="t17500711-65-victim534" type="surname" value="Denton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500711-65-victim534" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500711-65-victim534" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-65-off287 t17500711-65-victim534"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17500711-65-cd288" type="crimeDate">April 20</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500711-65-off287 t17500711-65-cd288"></join>. and likewise stood charged for the same on the coroner's inquisition.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-65-person535">
                  Samuel 
                  Hodges 
               <interp inst="t17500711-65-person535" type="surname" value="Hodges"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-65-person535" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-65-person535" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am uncle to the boy, I believe I should not have known any thing of the affair had not a neighbour informed me of it, in a letter the day after he was buried; then I thought it necessary to come up to London to inquire into the occasion of his death. I inquired and found the lad had been very much abused, as to my own knowledge I know nothing at all of it. I happened providentially to go by the door the very next morning after he had been served so. I live at Richmond, and called to see how he did, the prisoner told me he was a bed sulky, I said I hope you have had no words together, no, not in the least, said he, I only touched him with my finger on his hat or cap, and he is gone to bed sulky. I was going away, he faintly said, will you go up and see him; said I, if he is only sulky let him sleep half an hour. Here is the last letter I received from him, dated the first of May, we suppose he put it in the post on Tuesday night; he died on Friday morning about two o'clock. He was a lively active thing, a colour as fresh as a rose, as any body would desire to be.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence. I have evidence here that he died a natural death.</p>
               <p>Mr. Evans. I am an apothecary, I was sent for by his master, he was in a very restless way when I came, nothing would stay on his stomach; he complained of his bowels, no passage downwards, from some great cold he had catched, and he was attended with a scrophulous humor, which might strike in. I was sent for on Monday April the 23d. he had been ill three or four days before, and had had no stool for five days before. I endeavoured to get a passage through him, by giving him oily medicines with glisters, &amp;c. but could get none. His pains continued, and reaching to vomit he brought up his excrements four or five days before he died. There was no bruises about him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500711-65-person536">
                  Mary 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17500711-65-person536" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-65-person536" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-65-person536" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17500711-65-person537">
                  Mary 
                  Arnold 
               <interp inst="t17500711-65-person537" type="surname" value="Arnold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-65-person537" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500711-65-person537" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the searchers, deposed they saw nothing upon the body but what was common with all other corpses.</p>
               <p>Mr. Bradley, Mr. Carter, Mr. Adison, and Mr. Broughton gave the prisoner the character of a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500711-65-verdict289" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500711-65-verdict289" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
