<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17540911-38">
               <interp inst="t17540911-38" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-38" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-38" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17540911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17540911-38" type="date" value="17540911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17540911-38-off211-c306" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-38-defend373 t17540911-38-off211 t17540911-38-verdict212"></join>
         
               <p>453. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17540911-38-defend373" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Hambleton 
                  <interp inst="t17540911-38-defend373" type="surname" value="Hambleton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-38-defend373" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-38-defend373" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17540911-38-off211" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540911-38-off211" type="offenceCategory" value="miscellaneous"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-38-off211" type="offenceSubcategory" value="returnFromTransportation"></interp>
               returning from transportation before the expiration of his time
            </rs>. +</p>
               <p>The record of the court was read, where it appeared, that one 
               <persName id="t17540911-38-person374">
                  William 
                  Hambleton 
               <interp inst="t17540911-38-person374" type="surname" value="Hambleton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-38-person374" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-38-person374" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was tried in last Feb. sessions, at the Old Bailey, for stealing 50 pound weight of rope, val. 5 s. the property of persons unknown.</p>
               <p>That he was found guilty, and ordered to be transported.</p>
               <p>Richard Jennings. I have known the prisoner 20 years; I am constable of St. Paul's, Shadwell, the watchman came to me on the first of this month and asked me if I had not heard of Hambleton's return from transportation, and of his threatening to kill him and all his brother watchmen. On the second I summoned all the watchmen together, and went in pursuit of him, and took him in Chamber-street, Shadwell, at a house where his mother and wife lived.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of his being tried before?</p>
               <p>Jennings. I did not see him tried.</p>
               <p>Jos. Nicholson. I assisted the constable in taking the prisoner in Chamber-street on the second of September last.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he at large then?</p>
               <p>Nicholson. He was. I had seen him two or three nights before that.</p>
               <p>Ben. Turner. I was one that helped to take the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of his being tried before ?</p>
               <p>Turner. I was at his trial in Feb. last.</p>
               <p>Q. What was he tried for?</p>
               <p>Turner. For stealing of ropes from one Captain Lee. See numb. 182. in this mayoralty.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him receive sentence ?</p>
               <p>Turner. I heard the juryman say guilty, but was not here when he received sentence.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know him before?</p>
               <p>Turner. I had known him some years before that.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>Please to call my commander.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-38-person375">
                  Henry 
                  Carron 
               <interp inst="t17540911-38-person375" type="surname" value="Carron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-38-person375" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-38-person375" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am commander of the vessel called the Concord. I was at Maryland about the latter end of June last, there was great scarcity of men in all parts of Virginia and Maryland; I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175409110033"></xptr> wanted hands, and applied to all people there to get me men.</p>
               <p>Q. How many did you want?</p>
               <p>Carron. I wanted five.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the reason of this scarcity of hands?</p>
               <p>Carron. Most of the ships had their men pressed for the king's service. One Steward, a master of a ship, offered me the prisoner, he was the prisoner's master at that time; he sent him on board my vessel, for which I was to give him a valuable consideration.</p>
               <p>Q. When you set sail from Maryland, did you touch at any other place till you came to England?</p>
               <p>Carron. No, I did not. I was under an absolute necessity of coming to England when we set sail with the ship.</p>
               <p>Q. When was he put on board your vessel?</p>
               <p>Carron. It was on the latter end of June.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner express a desire of returning again, in obedience to his sentence.</p>
               <p>Carron. He said he wished he could get back again, in consequence of his former sentence.</p>
               <p>Q. What part of Maryland was you in when you took him on board?</p>
               <p>Carron. We were in Tucksant river.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is that up land?</p>
               <p>Carron. It is thirty miles from the mouth of the river.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain his master sent him on board?</p>
               <p>Carron. I am, the mate brought him in his boat, from out of ship that lay above me in the river.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know his master gave him orders to come on board?</p>
               <p>Carron. I believe the mate dare not have brought him without his master's orders; but he sent his mate to me, understanding I wanted hands.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you talk with the master about it?</p>
               <p>Carron. No, I never spoke to the master. I knew the mate, and likewise knew that he was Captain Steward's mate.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you know that?</p>
               <p>Carron. The mate told me so.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does that ship trade?</p>
               <p>Carron. It trades from Maryland to London.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had she been in the Tucksant river?</p>
               <p>Carron. I believd he had been in the river about a fortnight, but I cannot say justly as to the time.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her arrive?</p>
               <p>Carron. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell whether the prisoner was on board when she arrived?</p>
               <p>Carron. I can't tell that, I heard the mate and prisoner too say he was on board that ship.</p>
               <p>Q. Is that the transport ship?</p>
               <p>Carron. No, it is not.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the captain of the transport ship?</p>
               <p>Carron. I do, his name is Dobins.</p>
               <p>Q. Who were the owners of this ship?</p>
               <p>Carron. I cannot tell that.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any other prisoners on board this ship, exclusive of the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Carron. I can't tell that, I never understood that there was.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is a vessel going from the port of London to Maryland ?</p>
               <p>Carron. We count 6 weeks.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you set sail for London ?</p>
               <p>Carron. We weighed anchor July the 4th:</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you get down to the mouth of the river?</p>
               <p>Carron. I believe we got down on the 6th of July.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you put the prisoner under any confinement the time you were coming down?</p>
               <p>Carron. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he express a desire not to go with you before you got down to the mouth of the river?</p>
               <p>Carron. I can't say he did; but he frequently, when he was at sea, expressed a desire of going back again.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know he was a transport from England, at the time you took him on board?</p>
               <p>Carron. Really I never considered that.</p>
               <p>Q. If he had insisted to go on shore while you lay in the river, could you have hindered him?</p>
               <p>Carron. No, I could not.</p>
               <p>Q. What was you to give for him?</p>
               <p>Carron. I was to give 8 l. to captain Stewart for him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17540911-38-person376">
                  Daniel 
                  Hide 
               <interp inst="t17540911-38-person376" type="surname" value="Hide"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-38-person376" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-38-person376" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am mate on board the Concord.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the prisoner come on board?</p>
               <p>Hide. No, I did not; I was below at work. We were greatly distressed for seamen at that time. There was an expedition going forward, and most of the seamen which were in the river were pressed.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see him?</p>
               <p>Hide. I saw him the next morning after he came on board.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was it?</p>
               <p>Hide. It was towards the latter end of June.</p>
               <p>Q. From Maryland to England did you touch at any place?</p>
               <p>Hide. No.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175409110034"></xptr>Q. Do you know any thing of Captain 
               <persName id="t17540911-38-person377">
                  Carron
               <interp inst="t17540911-38-person377" type="given" value="Carron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17540911-38-person377" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's purchasing him?</p>
               <p>Hide. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. How many days did you lie in the river after he was on board, before you got to the mouth of the river?</p>
               <p>Hide. Ten or twelve days.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17540911-38-verdict212" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540911-38-verdict212" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17540911-38-punish213" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17540911-38-punish213" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17540911-38-defend373 t17540911-38-punish213"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
