<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17500425-28">
               <interp inst="t17500425-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500425-28" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500425-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17500425"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500425-28" type="date" value="17500425"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500425-28-off146-c161" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500425-28-defend219 t17500425-28-off146 t17500425-28-verdict149"></join>
         
               <p>324. 
               
                  <persName id="t17500425-28-defend219" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Andrews 
                  <interp inst="t17500425-28-defend219" type="surname" value="Andrews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-defend219" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-defend219" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17500425-28-off146" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-off146" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-off146" type="offenceSubcategory" value="coiningOffences"></interp>
               counterfeiting the silver coin of this realm, called shillings
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500425-28-cd147" type="crimeDate">December 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500425-28-off146 t17500425-28-cd147"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500425-28-person220">
                  Thomas 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17500425-28-person220" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-person220" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-person220" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have been acquainted with the Prisoner about two years, at first abroad, and afterwards in <placeName id="t17500425-28-crimeloc148">Old Pye-street Westminster</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17500425-28-crimeloc148" type="placeName" value="Old Pye-street Westminster"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17500425-28-crimeloc148" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500425-28-off146 t17500425-28-crimeloc148"></join>, at the house of serjeant Sage; there I saw the prisoner, and one Davenport, make a shilling, about the middle of October, Davenport held the mould in his hand, while the Prisoner poured the pewter in. The Prisoner shewed me about 15, or 16 of them, they appeared the same as other shillings. After that I saw some in Gardner's-lane at a chandler's shop. About December 14 or 15, I saw the prisoner, along with one Willis, make three of these; there lay 15 on the table all cast. They sist a wooden square frame full of whiting, then cram it down, scrape it off, and lay on a shilling with a sheet of white paper over it, then they put on the other frame were there are four holes and four pegs to fit in; so that those two frames lie true to each other, they having before cut away the paper over, the shilling, they then fill the other frame with this whiting, then take them asunder, the paper being between, take out the shilling: They made a gutter for the mettle to run to the place, and they generally used to melt their pewter in a tobacco pipe to pour it into the mould; there would appear a little roughness upon the edge till they were finished up. At Mr. Harris's at the prince Eugene's head, at Chelsea we once put off some; when we wanted to pass them off, we used to raise a quarrel amongst ourselves; the prisoner, and I was to quarrel at that time, we did so twice that same day. The other time was at the Green-man at Charing-cross, the Prisoner gave the boy a shilling of this sort, he could not change it, and putting it into his mouth to go to change it, he found it was bad, and then I gave a good one in the room of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500425-28-person221">
                  William 
                  Fisher 
               <interp inst="t17500425-28-person221" type="surname" value="Fisher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-person221" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-person221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Stratton's-ground, Westminster; the prisoner came to lodge at my house about four months ago, he staid there about five weeks, I did not mistrust he carried on this business then, till 
               <persName id="t17500425-28-person222">
                  Thomas 
                  Ind 
               <interp inst="t17500425-28-person222" type="surname" value="Ind"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-person222" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-person222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came to apprehend him, upon a suspicion of putting off bad money; he was then in his own room; I, and Mr. Turner, searched his box, we found a pair of wooden flasks, about three inches square, and some powdered whiting, and a bottle of quicksilver.</p>
               <p>Ward. The quicksilver was to rub over the money to make it like silver.</p>
               <p>Fisher. There was a three corner'd file.</p>
               <p>Ward. That was to mill the edges with.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500425-28-person223">
                  John 
                  Turner 
               <interp inst="t17500425-28-person223" type="surname" value="Turner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-person223" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-person223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirmed the Testimony of Fisher.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500425-28-person224">
                  Thomas 
                  Ind 
               <interp inst="t17500425-28-person224" type="surname" value="Ind"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-person224" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-person224" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was employed to search for tools, &amp;c. in Gardner's Lane at a chandler's shop, I found half a sheet of paper on the teaster of the bed, here is the print of a shilling upon it, with four peg holes that shewed it had been pegg'd into the flask.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500425-28-person225">
                  Sarah 
                  Weedon 
               <interp inst="t17500425-28-person225" type="surname" value="Weedon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-person225" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-person225" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Gardner's Lane, Westminster, the prisoner logged at my house the beginning of December. While he was there I lost two pewter spoons. Ward hired the room: I did not know all that used to come, nor did I ever see the prisoner there to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Vere Harris. I keep the Prince Eugene at Chelsea. On Tuesday the 19th of December, the prisoner and 
               <persName id="t17500425-28-person226">
                  Thomas 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17500425-28-person226" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-person226" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-person226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came intomy house along with 
               <persName id="t17500425-28-person227">
                  James 
                  Lampler 
               <interp inst="t17500425-28-person227" type="surname" value="Lampler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-person227" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-person227" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17500425-28-person228">
                  Henry 
                  Wolsington 
               <interp inst="t17500425-28-person228" type="surname" value="Wolsington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-person228" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , they staid there till betwixt five or six o'clock at night; when the reckoning came to be paid, Andrews and Wolfington began to quarrel; I desired them not to quarrel in my house. Lampler and Macdonald threw down sixpence a piece and went out of the house, they came in presently again, and asked for a pint of beer; I draw'd them one; then when that was out, they said,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175004250011"></xptr> they would not pay for that, till they had another. I drew them another, they gave me a shilling, and I gave them six-pence, then Andrews began to quarrel with Wolfington again, then I desired Mary Jenneson to take them out of my house; she desired them to go home with her, saying, she would give them some college loaf and cheese; when Wolfington and Macdonald had done drinking, and had paid me, I found I had received t wo bad shillings, I followed them to Mr. Jenneson's house, I called her out, and said, them soldiers had gave me two bad shillings, she had been and fetched some beer for them, said I, my six-pence is gone for that beer; no, said she, they gave me a shilling to fetch that withal. I went to Firnasses's house were they had the beer, and asked if Mrs. Jenneson had not gave her a bad shilling, which upon enquiry was so. I desired them to secure the men till I went for a constable. Ward there owned giving the money, which was bad: Andrews said to him, d - n you, what do you mean, have you a mind to hang us? See No. 141. of this Mayoralty.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500425-28-person229">
                  Mary 
                  Jenneson 
               <interp inst="t17500425-28-person229" type="surname" value="Jenneson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-person229" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-person229" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirmed the above account.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500425-28-person230">
                  Mary 
                  Curless 
               <interp inst="t17500425-28-person230" type="surname" value="Curless"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-person230" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-person230" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About Christmas day Mrs. Jenneson came to my house for a full pot of beer, she gave me a shilling, I returned Nine-pence : I had no other shilling but that in my pocket at that time. Mr. Harris came into my house and asked me if I had not received bad money of Mrs Jenneson for that pot of beer, &amp;c. I found it so. I went to Mrs. Jenneson's house: Ward owned the bad money, saying, he received it at his quarters. We took them up in the King's name. Andrews slew in a passion, he knocked my son down, and I saw he had a knife in his hand, we brought away the shilling, and I gave it to justice Fielding.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500425-28-person231">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Curless 
               <interp inst="t17500425-28-person231" type="surname" value="Curless"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-person231" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-person231" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at Mrs. Jenneson's house at this time. (The rest as the former witness, with this addition, that she saw a shilling drop out of the Prisoner's hair, it was a bad one, she gave it to Mr. Harris, and he gave it to the Colonel upon guard. The money, that is, the three bad shillings, was in the hands of a justice of peace, but he being engaged, could not be there to prove the identity of the money, it was produced in court by another hand.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500425-28-verdict149" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-verdict149" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17500425-28-punish150" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500425-28-punish150" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500425-28-defend219 t17500425-28-punish150"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
