<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17530906-49">
               <interp inst="t17530906-49" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530906-49" type="year" value="1753"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530906-49" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17530906"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530906-49" type="date" value="17530906"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17530906-49-off259-c377" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530906-49-defend470 t17530906-49-off259 t17530906-49-verdict263"></join>
         
               <p>429 (L.) 
               <persName id="t17530906-49-defend470" type="defendantName">
                  Edward 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17530906-49-defend470" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530906-49-defend470" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530906-49-defend470" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for that <rs id="t17530906-49-off259" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530906-49-off259" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530906-49-off259" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               he, together with 
                     <persName id="t17530906-49-person471">
                        John 
                        Wood 
                     <interp inst="t17530906-49-person471" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530906-49-person471" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530906-49-person471" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , not yet taken, on the <rs id="t17530906-49-cd260" type="crimeDate">5th of September</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530906-49-off259 t17530906-49-cd260"></join>, about the hour of two in the night on the same day, the dwelling-house> of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17530906-49-victim473" type="victimName">
                           Lydia 
                           Cole 
                        <interp inst="t17530906-49-victim473" type="surname" value="Cole"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530906-49-victim473" type="given" value="Lydia"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530906-49-victim473" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530906-49-off259 t17530906-49-victim473"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17530906-49-viclabel261" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530906-49-victim473 t17530906-49-viclabel261"></join>, did break and enter, with intent the goods of the said Lydia to steal, and taking three silver tea spoons, val. 3 s. one copper tea kettle, val. 5 s. one copper saucepan, val. 3 s. the property of the said Lydia
            </rs>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530906-49-person474">
                  Richard 
                  Cole 
               <interp inst="t17530906-49-person474" type="surname" value="Cole"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530906-49-person474" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530906-49-person474" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Seething lane, my mother went out of town, and desir'd that I'd lie at her house on <placeName id="t17530906-49-crimeloc262">Tower-hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17530906-49-crimeloc262" type="placeName" value="Tower-hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17530906-49-crimeloc262" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530906-49-off259 t17530906-49-crimeloc262"></join>; on Wednesday night, Sept. the 4th, my wife and I went there between eleven and twelve o'clock, I took a watchman, whose stand is near, to the door with me to light a candle. I opened the door, got a candle lighted, then shut the door and double lock'd it, and we went to bed. I took the key in my hand. After I was in bed and asleep I was awaked with a sort of a noise that I thought to be the creaking of the hatch at the door; I was in a very great fright, having heard it several times, and once I determined if I heard it any more to get up; but presently I saw a light come into the room, and a man with it.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know that man ?</p>
               <p>Cole. I can't swear to the prisoner's face, he had a whitish coat on such as the prisoner has on now,</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the night was this ?</p>
               <p>Cole. This was between two and three in the morning. I made a motion to arise, but my sear overcame me, so I lay in a violent fright till I saw that the man was going to reach a dish off the table in the room, upon that I jumped out of bed, the man ran down stairs immediately, and I after him; I had an opportunity to have taken him, but I did not care for that, fearing he had got a knife, so I let him get out of the house; he ran down Tower-hill way, and I call'd out, Stop thief! stop thief in a white coat! I went near the ern, where the watchman was, who told me he saw him, so he and another watchman followed him; they secured and brought the prisoner to the watchhouse. I had word brought me they had got him there, so I went, and to the best of my memory he is the man that was in the room, for I lay in bed and look'd at him some time ; he had a blue apron on, which he said belong'd to his wife, and upon observing it, it appeared to be double and was a bag. (produc'd in court. )</p>
               <p>Q. Did you miss any thing about the house?</p>
               <p>Cole. I missed three silver spoons.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see them last?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175309060031"></xptr>Cole. I lay there by myself on Tuesday night; they were there then, and nobody had been there between that time and this night. There was a tea kettle and saucepan before standing on the cistern, which I afterwards found at the street door, in the inside the house. I carried the prisoner the next day before justice Richards, and he was committed.</p>
               <p>Q. Had there been any voilence done to the key hole or lock of the door?</p>

               <p>Cole. No, there were none, the door was opened either by a key or picklock.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you bolt the door ?</p>
               <p>Cole. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530906-49-person475">
                  Thomas 
                  Scruce 
               <interp inst="t17530906-49-person475" type="surname" value="Scruce"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530906-49-person475" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530906-49-person475" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watchman, it was my hour to stand at Postern Row, till three o'clock; while I was there in my stand I heard the cry, Stop thief! I went out of my stand without my lanthorn, and heard a foot come padding in the dark quick towards me, I said, Stop, whoever you be. Then I took the lanthorn out of my box, after which I heard the cry, Stop thief! a man in a white coat. I said I saw such a man running. so I run round the hill after him, he turn'd towards my box again, and I took him near it and secur'd him; he put his hands in his pockets: I said keep your hands out of your pockets, or I'll knock you down, perhaps you have a knife. I call'd to another watchman, there came two, so we carried him to the warehouse. I went to Mr. Cole's house to bring him to give charge of the prisoner to the officer of the night; he told me at his house that the man which was in his room had a white cape coat on. When he saw him in the watch-house he said, that is the man, I'll swear to his coat. He looks on the blue bag, this was found on the prisoner, and a knife we took out of his pocket. Note, the knife was ground at the point, like that of a glazier's, fit to take out a pane of glass. We carried him before justice Ricards, and he committed him. As Mr. Cole said he had had a light, we went to look about where the prisoner had ran for a dark lanthorn, my partner found a bunch of picklock keys, and a wrenching iron, near Mr. Cole's house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530906-49-person476">
                  John 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17530906-49-person476" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530906-49-person476" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530906-49-person476" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watchman, facing alderman Bethell's house, on Great Tower-hill, Mr. Cole and his wife came to his mother's house between eleven and twelve o'clock at night, I was sitting in my box, he borrowed my lanthorn, and I went with him to the door, he opened it with a key, and took a candle and lighted it at mine; he went in and shut the door, I heard it lock, then went to my stand again. When the clock went twelve I went my round, and knock'd at the door, which was fast as usual; a little after two I heard the cry, Stop thief! I went out of my box with my lanthorn and staff, and said, Where! Mr. Cole said, he is just gone out of my house, and gone down the hill in a white coat and coloured handkerchief, I ran directly that way; said another watchman, here he is coming this way: then I saw the glimpse of him running towards the watchman ; I run, and we got him between the watchman and I, with his back towards me. I saw him putting his hand towards his pocket; the other watchman said, if you have got a knife, or offer to draw it, I'll knock you down: then we both secured him, and carried him to the round-house. The watchman said to me, where is the gentleman that call'd out, I said it was Mr. Cole; we went for him, there was a kettle and things standing on the inside the door, he came to the watch-house and said the prisoner at the bar was the man that had been in his room, and said he could swear to his coat.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Mr. Cole's door open when you was with him there to light his candle?</p>
               <p>Jones. I did, there was no kettle there then.</p>
               <p>- Morris. I am a watchman, on that morning after we broke up the watch, I was told this man had a light in the room, so I said, let us look about for a dark lanthorn where he ran, we went and look'd about till day light, we found the picklock keys here produced, and a wrenching iron lying with them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530906-49-person477">
                  Mary 
                  Cole 
               <interp inst="t17530906-49-person477" type="surname" value="Cole"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530906-49-person477" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530906-49-person477" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to 
               <persName id="t17530906-49-person478">
                  Richard 
                  Cole 
               <interp inst="t17530906-49-person478" type="surname" value="Cole"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530906-49-person478" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530906-49-person478" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ; I was asleep when the prisoner came into the room, Mr. Cole jumping out of bed, and calling out stop thief, awakened me, I saw a light go down stairs which Mr. Cole followed, but I saw no man; I was most terribly affrighted.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of the tea spoons being missing?</p>
               <p>Cole. I put three silver tea spoons on the mantle-piece<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175309060032"></xptr> on the Tuesday morning before, and never saw them afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the tea-kettle and saucepan standing before this ?</p>
               <p>Cole. They were standing on the cistern, and when I got up, after the man had been there, I saw them standing at the house door within side.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17530906-49-person479">
                  Richard 
                  Cole 
               <interp inst="t17530906-49-person479" type="surname" value="Cole"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530906-49-person479" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530906-49-person479" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Are you certain as to the prisoner ?</p>
               <p>Cole. I am satisfied he is the man by his wig and coat, and a coloured handkerchief which he had on.</p>

               <p>Q. How far did you see him running after he was out of the house ?</p>
               <p>Cole. I saw him run down the hill and then lost sight of him.</p>
               <p>The watchmen 
               <persName id="t17530906-49-person480">
                  Scruce
               <interp inst="t17530906-49-person480" type="given" value="Scruce"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530906-49-person480" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Jones being asked, if they saw any other man come by that way about that time besides the prisoner, answered they did not.</p>
               <p>Q. to Cole. Could you see the watchman's stand from the house you was at.</p>
               <p>Cole. I could, and the prisoner must go by it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I had been at Bartholomew fair, and happened to meet a small acquaintance, one 
               <persName id="t17530906-49-person481">
                  John 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17530906-49-person481" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530906-49-person481" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530906-49-person481" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , with whom I went and drank a pint of beer; he invited me home to his house, and we went to an alehouse near where he liv'd, at the bottom of Tower-hill, where we stay'd till between 12 and 1 o'clock; he struck a light and went home, and said to me do you intend to go home to-night, I said yes. He said, I believe I can put some money in your pocket; said I how? He said there is a house just by where the people are gone out of town; I said I don't care to be concerned, but he over perswaded me. I said, which way can you open the door; he said he had keys that would open; but I never saw the keys till I was carried before the Justice. Wood went and opened the door, and was gone in some time, he had struck a light. came out again, and said he in bed and desired man's room. which, I got out of bed and <rs id="t17530906-49-verdict263" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530906-49-verdict263" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17530906-49-punish264" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530906-49-punish264" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530906-49-defend470 t17530906-49-punish264"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
