<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17501205-2">
               <interp inst="t17501205-2" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501205-2" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501205-2" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17501205"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17501205-2" type="date" value="17501205"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17501205-2-off7-c34" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501205-2-defend38 t17501205-2-off7 t17501205-2-verdict9"></join>
         
               <p>3. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17501205-2-defend38" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Gordon 
                  <interp inst="t17501205-2-defend38" type="surname" value="Gordon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-2-defend38" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-2-defend38" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17501205-2-off7" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501205-2-off7" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-2-off7" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing one gelding of a chesnut colour, value 5 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17501205-2-victim40" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Philips 
                  <interp inst="t17501205-2-victim40" type="surname" value="Philips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-2-victim40" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-2-victim40" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501205-2-off7 t17501205-2-victim40"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17501205-2-cd8" type="crimeDate">Nov. 4</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17501205-2-off7 t17501205-2-cd8"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-2-person41">
                  Robert 
                  Hore 
               <interp inst="t17501205-2-person41" type="surname" value="Hore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-2-person41" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-2-person41" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a carpenter. Last Saturday was se'nnight I took this gelding of my master's,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175012050003"></xptr> (
               <persName id="t17501205-2-person42">
                  John 
                  Philips 
               <interp inst="t17501205-2-person42" type="surname" value="Philips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-2-person42" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-2-person42" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ) by his order, and rode him to Knightsbridge from Brook street, to carry some linen to be washed to old Mr. Shacksby's; when I came to the gate, I fastened my horse's bridle, by putting it under the rail, and then turned it over the top of a post which was about seven inches above the rail. The prisoner was then at the gate, he said he wanted to speak with one of the footmen; I said, here are no footmen here; I went into the house and delivered my message; they wanted me to do a little jobb in the house; I said I'd go and take care of my horse; I was not a minute in the house; when I returned the horse was gone; I went on to Kensington, a sentinel told me there was a man rode through the town as hard as his horse could go, but it being dark he could not tell the colour of the horse; the horse was left at Hammersmith ; I had him the Tuesday following.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-2-person43">
                  John 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17501205-2-person43" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-2-person43" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-2-person43" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About seven o'clock this night the prisoner at the bar came to the George Inn at Hammersmith ; he put up this horse there, and took a room, saying, there were more people coming, as if there was a family coming; he had a great fire made and a bed sheeted, and said to the landlady, pray give me half a guinea in silver; she had just 7 s. 6 d. in silver, she gave him that; then he went up stairs to see the fire; then the landlord came in, and the landlady told him there was a young man had took a room, and wanted change; so he went to him to give him the rest of the change; the prisoner said he had not half a guinea till his master and mistress came, so he returned the three half crowns; he went down stairs, and away he went, and left the horse in the stable.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-2-person44">
                  John 
                  Tilbury 
               <interp inst="t17501205-2-person44" type="surname" value="Tilbury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-2-person44" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-2-person44" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an hostler at the George in Hammersmith. I took this chesnut coloured gelding of the prisoner, and put him in the stable Nov. 4, about seven at night; he bid me take care of him, and said there were six more a coming, and that they should stay all night.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-2-person45">
                  John 
                  Turner 
               <interp inst="t17501205-2-person45" type="surname" value="Turner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-2-person45" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-2-person45" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner came in at the Bull Head and Three Tuns in Kensington, between 8 and 9 o'clock at night, Nov. 4; he asked my landlady if she could lodge him; he called for two pints of beer and three halfpennyworth of bread and cheese; when he came to pay he pulled out a paper, and, with an oath, swore, as he opened it, he was ruined, he had received a halfpenny instead of a guinea; then he wanted to take lodging there for a week; I thought he had something in his pocket; as he turned himself, I saw a pistol. I took it from him, it was loaded with two balls and prim'd. Produced in court.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17501205-2-person46">
                  Aaron 
                  Cross 
               <interp inst="t17501205-2-person46" type="surname" value="Cross"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-2-person46" type="given" value="Aaron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17501205-2-person46" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I met the prisoner in Kensington; said he, can you get me a lodging? said I, where are you going? said he, to town; I told him it was not so late but he might go to night; said he, I am tired, I came from Reading to day; I went with him to the Thistle and Crown, their beds were all full; then I went to the Bull Head and Three Tuns. He confirmed the last witness.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was coming from Bath, where I was discharged from my master's service (Esq; Carter) he there hired a servant who could talk French, and is gone to Paris; I served him a year and eight months, part in Ireland and part here. This pistol was one of his, the other was broke, and it was my perquisite. Coming along the road I met this horse on the other side Kensington, and no soul with him, about seven o'clock at night; I stopped him and waited to see if any body came up; nobody did, so I brought him to this Inn at Hammersmith and called for the hostler, and delivered the horse to him; there were some post chaises at the door; after I had been in the house, drank half a pint of wine, and paid for it, I went away in haste to get a ride behind one of them chaises. I did design to advertise the horse ; I went to enquire for lodging as I could not get a ride, and met with that soldier, who went with me from one house to another; and when they stopped me, he would have let me go, if I would have given him a piece of money.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17501205-2-verdict9" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17501205-2-verdict9" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
