<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17530111-27">
               <interp inst="t17530111-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530111-27" type="year" value="1753"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530111-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17530111"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17530111-27" type="date" value="17530111"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17530111-27-off133-c275" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530111-27-defend330 t17530111-27-off133 t17530111-27-verdict136"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175301110029"></xptr>87. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17530111-27-defend330" type="defendantName">
                  Joseph 
                  Hall 
               <interp inst="t17530111-27-defend330" type="surname" value="Hall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-defend330" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-defend330" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for that <rs id="t17530111-27-off133" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-off133" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-off133" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               he, together with 
                     <persName id="t17530111-27-person331">
                        Charles 
                        Sickamore 
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person331" type="surname" value="Sickamore"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530111-27-person331" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530111-27-person331" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   and Jonathan Ward, on the <rs id="t17530111-27-cd134" type="crimeDate">first of December</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530111-27-off133 t17530111-27-cd134"></join>, about the hour of seven at night on the same day, the dwelling house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17530111-27-victim333" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Grubb 
                        <interp inst="t17530111-27-victim333" type="surname" value="Grubb"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530111-27-victim333" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17530111-27-victim333" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530111-27-off133 t17530111-27-victim333"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , did break and enter, one cloth coat value 2 s. one flannel waistcoat value 6 d. one pair of leather breeches value 2 s. two linnen gowns, one stuff gown, one camblet gown, two quilted petticoats, and one perriwig, the goods of the said William, in the dwelling house did steal, take, and carry away
            </rs>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530111-27-person334">
                  Mary 
                  Grubb 
               <interp inst="t17530111-27-person334" type="surname" value="Grubb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person334" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person334" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live <placeName id="t17530111-27-crimeloc135">between Pancrass and Kentish Town , just opposite the work-house</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17530111-27-crimeloc135" type="placeName" value="between Pancrass and Kentish Town , just opposite the work-house"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17530111-27-crimeloc135" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530111-27-off133 t17530111-27-crimeloc135"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your husband's name?</p>
               <p>M. Grubb. His name was William, he died since the affair happened; I went to the work-house on the first of December about seven o'clock in the evening, and left my three children in bed in my house; I latched my door (it has a particular latch, which people, who don't know can't open) I put my knee against it and found it was fast. When I returned I found it latched, but the latch was bent, and the candle, which I had left in my bed-chamber, was blown out.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you been gone?</p>
               <p>M. Grubb. I returned in about half an hour, and found the laths broke through on the cieling, and in the morning I saw on the outside that the tiles were taken off, and two bricks were taken out of the wall; I missed four gowns, a coat, waistcoat, and breeches, a child's set of cloaths, that is, a stay and coat, two petticoats and a perriwig; some of them were taken from out of a trunk, some from pins where they hung, and some from off the bed.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the trunk locked?</p>
               <p>M. Grubb. No, it was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure all these things were in your house when you went out?</p>
               <p>M. Grubb. I am sure they were, my lord.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see them last?</p>
               <p>M. Grubb. I saw some of them when I went out, because I could not help going by them.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the cieling whole at the time you went out?</p>
               <p>M. Grubb. It was; the next day there were three men at work in the fields, I told them I had been robbed ; they told me they had seen three men loitering about the fields, and that the prisoner and 
               <persName id="t17530111-27-person335">
                  Charles 
                  Sickamore 
               <interp inst="t17530111-27-person335" type="surname" value="Sickamore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person335" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person335" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             were two of them. I went to London, and got a friend of mine (name Berry) and another person (name Bath) to enquire after them, and in about three days after the robbery the prisoner was taken up and had before justice Fielding, where he said, please to admit an evidence, and I'll tell the w hole truth and be very good, but the justice knowing him to have been an evidence before, would not admit him again. Mr. Berry found out 
               <persName id="t17530111-27-person336">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Wale 
               <interp inst="t17530111-27-person336" type="surname" value="Wale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person336" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person336" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who is come-here to give evidence, he sent for me and told me a gown and coat were at Mr. Hall's, a pawnbroker, in Fox Court: we found some other things stopped on Snow Hill at Mr. Brown's. I have found another gown at another place, but the woman will not let me have it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530111-27-person337">
                  William 
                  Haythorne 
               <interp inst="t17530111-27-person337" type="surname" value="Haythorne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person337" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person337" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the prisoner idling about the fields the first of December at night along with 
               <persName id="t17530111-27-person338">
                  Charles 
                  Sickamore 
               <interp inst="t17530111-27-person338" type="surname" value="Sickamore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person338" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person338" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and another, whom I did not know.</p>
               <p>Q. How near to the prosecutor's house?</p>
               <p>Haythorne. I met them near the turnpike, about a mile from the prosecutor's house, and saw them the day before the robbery about a quarter of a mile from her house. The prisoner wanted to be admitted an evidence before the justice.</p>
               <p>Q. What were his words?</p>
               <p>Haythorne. He said, if the justice would admit him an evidence, he'd tell where all the things were, and how he came by them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530111-27-person339">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Wale 
               <interp inst="t17530111-27-person339" type="surname" value="Wale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person339" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person339" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going home at the top of Field-lane with my child in my arms about seven weeks ago, and met 
               <persName id="t17530111-27-person340">
                  Charles 
                  Sickamore 
               <interp inst="t17530111-27-person340" type="surname" value="Sickamore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person340" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person340" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Joseph Hall, it was in an evening about six o'clock, and Sickamore asked me to carry my child home and go of an errand for him to pawn something, he said he and Hall had been to Rag Fair, and bought them of a woman there; they both said they came honestly by them, and laid this gown and petticoat and other things into my lap; I went and pawned them for 8 s. 6 d. and they gave me a shilling for my trouble.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you deliver the money to?</p>
               <p>E. Wale. I delivered it to Sickamore</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the prisoner at the time you went to pawn the things ?</p>
               <p>E. Wale. Both staid at the pawnbroker's door.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530111-27-person341">
                  William 
                  Knight 
               <interp inst="t17530111-27-person341" type="surname" value="Knight"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person341" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person341" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Hall in Fox Court, Gray's-Inn-lane, he is a pawnbroker; I took in this gown on Friday the first of December about eight o'clock at night of 
               <persName id="t17530111-27-person342">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Wale 
               <interp inst="t17530111-27-person342" type="surname" value="Wale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person342" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person342" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and lent her 8 s. 6 d. upon it.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175301110030"></xptr>Q. Whose did she say they were ?</p>
               <p>Knight. She said they were her property, and that she kept a stall in Fleet market, and wanted money to buy goods.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530111-27-person343">
                  Thomas 
                  Ind 
               <interp inst="t17530111-27-person343" type="surname" value="Ind"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person343" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person343" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I apprehended the prisoner, and carried him to New Prison, and then to justice Fielding; after that we took Sickamore and the woman, and by her directions we found some of the things. The prisoner desired to be admitted an evidence. After the things were found I went to the prison for him; there were he and Wale together. Hall told me first, they gave the woman a shilling and some child-bed linnen for her trouble; he desired me to do what I could for him towards getting him admitted an evidence, but the justice would not admit him. He there confessed that he, Sickamore, and another man (I don't know his name) went out together to a house by Pancrass work-house. Sickamore, being a pan-tile maker, was, by the other two, lifted up on the tiles, then he pulled some off from a place on the house, but the rasters were so close he could not get in, then he got down, and they put their backsides to the door and burst it open, they went in, there was a candle burning; then they took out these things, some from out of a trunk, and at coming out of the room they blew the candle out. I took a wig from Sickamore's head that the prosecutrix owned and said it was her husband's.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17530111-27-person344">
                  Samuel 
                  Watts 
               <interp inst="t17530111-27-person344" type="surname" value="Watts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person344" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person344" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the taking the prisoner; after which justice Fielding ordered him to be brought from New-Prison a second time; going along he asked me if I would get him admitted an evidence ; I said I would do what lay in my power if he would confess the whole truth to me, so he began and told me, that he, 
               <persName id="t17530111-27-person345">
                  Charles 
                  Sickamore 
               <interp inst="t17530111-27-person345" type="surname" value="Sickamore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person345" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person345" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17530111-27-person346">
                  Jonathan 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17530111-27-person346" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person346" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person346" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             went out with an intent either to break some house, or rob somebody, and that they were in Pancrass fields about three o'clock in the afternoon, they met nobody which they thought proper to rob then they concluded to go and rob some house; that they saw a woman go out of this house into the work-house, so they concluded to rob that; then they lifted Sickamore upon the tiles, but he could not get through between the rafters; then they went to the outward door, but could not find any latch, so Sickamore and he put their backs against the door and burst it open; then they went and searched all the rooms, they took a gown, petticoat, pair of breeches, and other things, and brought them away, blew the candle out and gave them to Wale to pawn, which she did, and they gave her a shilling, and that he and Sickamore were with her when she pawned them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>This 
               <persName id="t17530111-27-person347">
                  Charles 
                  Sickamore 
               <interp inst="t17530111-27-person347" type="surname" value="Sickamore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person347" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person347" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had some money sent him out of the country, he said he'd treat me, so I went and drank part of a full pot of beer with him; he bought some things for 18 s. of a person; we met 
               <persName id="t17530111-27-person348">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Wale 
               <interp inst="t17530111-27-person348" type="surname" value="Wale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person348" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-person348" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and he got her to pawn them. These people will take any man's life away for any thing, they are thief-catchers, and have hanged many a man for the lucre of nothing.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17530111-27-verdict136" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-verdict136" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17530111-27-punish137" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17530111-27-punish137" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17530111-27-defend330 t17530111-27-punish137"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
