<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510523-34">
               <interp inst="t17510523-34" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510523-34" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510523-34" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510523"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510523-34" type="date" value="17510523"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510523-34-off194-c227" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-34-defend298 t17510523-34-off194 t17510523-34-verdict196"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510523-34-off194-c228" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-34-defend300 t17510523-34-off194 t17510523-34-verdict196"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510523-34-off194-c229" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-34-defend302 t17510523-34-off194 t17510523-34-verdict196"></join>
         
               <p>388. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17510523-34-defend298" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Reed 
                  <interp inst="t17510523-34-defend298" type="surname" value="Reed"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-34-defend298" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-34-defend298" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17510523-34-defend300" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Limbery 
                  <interp inst="t17510523-34-defend300" type="surname" value="Limbery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-34-defend300" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-34-defend300" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17510523-34-defend302" type="defendantName">
                     Jeremiah 
                     Monk 
                  <interp inst="t17510523-34-defend302" type="surname" value="Monk"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-34-defend302" type="given" value="Jeremiah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-34-defend302" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17510523-34-off194" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510523-34-off194" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-34-off194" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one promissory note, call'd a bank note, for 50 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17510523-34-victim304" type="victimName">
                     Peter 
                     Taylor 
                  <interp inst="t17510523-34-victim304" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-34-victim304" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-34-victim304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-34-off194 t17510523-34-victim304"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17510523-34-cd195" type="crimeDate">May 20</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-34-off194 t17510523-34-cd195"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175105230023"></xptr>Peter Taylor. On Monday last about four o'clock in the afternoon I was at home, the prisoner, Reed, came to me with a note from a gentleman that was then in the house of commons, desiring me to come to him immediately; I went, he came out of the house and told me, there was a matter of consequence in hand and he could not depart the house; that his servant had been with him, telling him, there had been a bill of exchange brought to his house for 85 l. 5 s. He desired I would send my servant to Knight and Jackson, bankers, in Lombard-street, and take up the bill of exchange drawn upon him, it was brought from France and was in their hands, left it should be noted being near five o'clock: He gave me a bank bill of fifty pounds, and said, he would give me the remainder when he saw me: Upon this I ask'd the door-keeper, if he knew an honest porter who I could trust with fifty pounds, so he recommended Reed to me as such. I went into an office just by the door of the house of commons, and ask'd the clerk to lend me some paper, pen and ink, which he did, the porter was behind me. I inclosed the fifty pound bill in a letter to my servant, he saw me inclose it, I also told him what it was. I sealed it up and desired he would make haste with it and leave it at my shop, and that the door keeper would satisfy him. My business kept me out till about eleven o'clock, when I came home I found the account 85 l. 5 s. paid by my servant for the bill of exchange I had wrote to him.</p>
               <p>Make up the inclosed the sum mentioned in the paper, and send immediately and take up the draft.</p>
               <p>Inclosed in it was a paper, wrote</p>
               <p>Mess. Knight and Jackson, Lombard-street, 85 l.</p>
               <p>When I ask'd my servant about the 50 l. note, he said, he received none; that the paper he received was open, with only the bit of paper in it wrote.</p>
               <p>Knight and Jackson, Lombard-street. 85 l.</p>
               <p>I found out where the porter lodged, which was in Thieving-lane, and found he was out; then I went to the house of commons, knowing he was imploy'd there, and found him; I told him, I thought he had made a mistake; he bounced much, and said, he was an honest man; said I, tell me the truth if you have done an imprudent thing. Where did you lie last night? Said he, I lodge at the Shoulder of Mutton in Thieving-lane. Said I, I have been there, and find you do not; then he said, he lay in St. Martin's-lane. Said I, are you married? he said, no, but he kept a whore there. I went there to her, she was alone, told her the affair, and that I would give her five guineas if she wanted any money in her unfortunate circumstances, if she would tell me what was done with it, &amp;c. she declar'd her innocency. I took the prisoner to my house in order to confront my servant about the letter being open; he declared the letter was deliver'd at my house in the same condition it was to him by my hand. I had before sent my servant to stop payment, and the time he was at the Bank the bill came in, which he came and related before the prisoner; then the prisoner trembled, and said, he believ'd it might drop from the letter, and some other persons might take it up. Upon this I went to the Bank in order to see who brought the note there, and found it to be Mr. Pewterer, who is here to give evidence; he described to me two people who had been with him the night before, which was Monday, between seven and eight o'clock, the one in a white apron like a porter, the other said he was chimney sweeper; that they had bought three pair of buckles and a gold ring; I took Mr. Pewterer's servant to see if he knew the person who brought the note; he said, that was none of the man. I took the prisoner, Reed, before Justice Fielding, he was of the opinion he ought to be committed to Newgate. Coming down Southampton-street, I met a man who said, the note was found, and he could help me to the sight of the man who found it, one Limbery in Westminster, who had been all night very drunk, showing a great deal of money, and had been over the water and bought some silver buckles, and things for his wife. I took a hackney-coach to enquire where he lived, for the man could not tell the place. I first saw his wife, she was drunk at the door, and two or three chimney sweepers boys. I ask'd where her husband was, she said, he was not at home. I ran up stairs and found him a bed, his wife awaked him, and said, here is a gentleman wants to speak with you. He gave her a kick, and said, he was not afraid of any gentleman in England, he had committed<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175105230024"></xptr> no robbery, that his character was very good, and that the Duke of Newcastle, and the Duke of Bedford would bail him. I told him, I did not come to charge him with any robbery, but that an innocent man might suffer by what he could explain. He said, he knew 
               <persName id="t17510523-34-person305">
                  Joseph 
                  Reed 
               <interp inst="t17510523-34-person305" type="surname" value="Reed"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-34-person305" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-34-person305" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and that he was an honest man. We took him and his man Monk to Justice Fielding, and examined them a-part. I ask'd Limbery what money he had in his pocket; he answer'd, a meer trifle, about ten or twelve guineas. I took out of his pocket 39 l. 11 s. 6 d. and from his coat pocket two pair of silver buckles. They were produced in court, and very large ones. He then said, he would tell the truth; and said, on Monday about four o'clock in the afternoon, he and his apprentice were going down to purchase some mackreil, his boy kick'd a paper about in the passage leading to New-palace-yard; they went and came back again, then the boy took it up fiauing it still there, and said, I believe I have found a tobacco paper here ; then he gave it to him, and he said, it was a ten pound bank note; then he went home and call'd one Hughs, who went with him into the city and exchang'd the bank note; I can't find that Hughs out; they went to Grace-church street to one Mr. Pewterer's and laid out 5 l. 3 s. in three pair of buckles and a gold ring. This, he said, was on Monday night about two hours after it was found, and that the money taken out of his pocket was the identical money he received of Mr. Pewterer's. I ask'd him what was become of the remainder of the money, to which he gave several answers; sometimes he said, it was all he received; and at other times, he did not know what was become of it.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it not possible you might drop this note instead of sealing it up in the letter?</p>
               <p>Taylor. I am positive I put it into the letter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-34-person306">
                  John 
                  Sirwood 
               <interp inst="t17510523-34-person306" type="surname" value="Sirwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-34-person306" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-34-person306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17510523-34-person307">
                  Peter 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17510523-34-person307" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-34-person307" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-34-person307" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            : 
               <persName id="t17510523-34-person308">
                  Joseph 
                  Reed 
               <interp inst="t17510523-34-person308" type="surname" value="Reed"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-34-person308" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-34-person308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             brought me a letter about five o'clock in the afternoon on Monday last, it was open. Said I, how came this letter open? he said, he did not know, it was as he had it. There was in it a slip of paper, wrote Mess. Knight and Jackson, Lombard-street, 85 l. which I imagined to be what my master mean'd. I went directly to Lombard-street and took up the bill of exchange, and here is a copy of that very day's transactions now in court. I was gone to bed when my master came home, he, in looking over it, found I had made him debtor 85 l. odd money; he ask'd me the reason, I told him as before, the letter came open to me with only that slip of paper in it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there not a waser in the letter?</p>
               <p>Sirwood. There had been a waser in the letter, part of which stuck to it, but it was quite open. I was before the Justice with Reed, there he did not deny my asking him, how the letter came open when I received it of him.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any wax upon the letter?</p>
               <p>Sirwood. No, Sir, none at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the waser appear to be moist?</p>
               <p>Sirwood. I did not examine that.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did he bring it to you?</p>
               <p>Sirwood. As nigh as I can recollect, it was about five o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. to the prosecutor. Did you say any thing to Reed, when you ordered him to carry this letter about a bank note?</p>
               <p>Taylor. I said, take care, there is a bank note in it.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did he come back again to the house of commons?</p>
               <p>Taylor. He was back again in a very little time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-34-person309">
                  Thomas 
                  Pewterer 
               <interp inst="t17510523-34-person309" type="surname" value="Pewterer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-34-person309" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-34-person309" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a goldsmith, and live at the corner of Nag's-head-court, Grace church-street. Last Monday between seven and eight o'clock at night, the prisoner, Limbery, and another man, came to my shop and bought three pair of buckles and a gold ring, for payment he tenderd a bank note of 50 l. I ask'd the other person how he came by it; he said, he had taken it of a person that was with him ; saying, you need not question it, for he is the king's chimney sweeper. I changed it, and gave him forty seven guineas and a half, and half a crown. These are two pair of the buckles ( looking on them produced before) I sent my man to the Bank next morning with this note, the teller was busy and said, he could not change it then. After that one of the tellers sent to me to tell me, that the note was stop'd, and he would be answerable for it, so I delivered it to him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-34-person310">
                  Stephen 
                  Athel 
               <interp inst="t17510523-34-person310" type="surname" value="Athel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-34-person310" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-34-person310" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I happen'd to go to Justice Fielding's about other business, the time the prisoners, Limbery and Monk, were there ; the Justice order'd Limbery to be searched, I saw about twenty guineas and some silver, and two<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175105230025"></xptr> large pair of silver buckles taken out of his pockets; then he order'd Limbery to be taken away, and his man Monk to be brought before him. I went down stairs with Limbery, and sat down by him a good while; said I, is it not a sad thing, to put the poor porter into Newgate upon your account? Said he in answer, it is a juggle, I believe one drop'd the note and the other found it.</p>
               <p>Q. to the prosecutor . Where is the bank bill?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. It is not here, but I have the copy of it here.</p>
               <p>All three <rs id="t17510523-34-verdict196" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510523-34-verdict196" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
