<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17560603-29">
               <interp inst="t17560603-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560603-29" type="year" value="1756"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560603-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17560603"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17560603-29" type="date" value="17560603"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17560603-29-off139-c308" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560603-29-defend360 t17560603-29-off139 t17560603-29-verdict141"></join>
         
               <p>271. 
               <persName id="t17560603-29-defend360" type="defendantName">
                  Robert 
                  Ogle 
               <interp inst="t17560603-29-defend360" type="surname" value="Ogle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-29-defend360" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-29-defend360" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , gent. stood indicted for <rs id="t17560603-29-off139" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560603-29-off139" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-29-off139" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               the wilful murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17560603-29-victim362" type="victimName">
                           Francis 
                           Martin 
                        <interp inst="t17560603-29-victim362" type="surname" value="Martin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560603-29-victim362" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17560603-29-victim362" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560603-29-off139 t17560603-29-victim362"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17560603-29-cd140" type="crimeDate">April 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17560603-29-off139 t17560603-29-cd140"></join>.</p>
               <p>His appearance at the bar seeming to discover he was not right in his senses, the following evidences were sworn, for the Middlesex jury to determine whether he was, or was not of sound mind and memory, fit to take his trial, &amp;c. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560603-29-person363">
                  James 
                  Arlington 
               <interp inst="t17560603-29-person363" type="surname" value="Arlington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-29-person363" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-29-person363" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have attended the prisoner ever since he has been in prison, which is about seven weeks.</p>
               <p>Q. How has he appeared as to his understanding?</p>
               <p>Arlington. Sometimes he has appeared as a madman, and sometimes not quite so bad.</p>
               <p>Q. How have you observed him within this day or two?</p>
               <p>Arlington. His mind changes several times every day, he does not at all seemed settled in his mind. In the morning he was a little flurried in his head.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he yesterday?</p>
               <p>Arlington. Yesterday he was quite mad.</p>
               <p>Q. What has been his general behaviour since he has been in prison?</p>
               <p>Arlington. I take him to have been a man out of his senses chief part of the time. He has very odd actions.</p>
               <p>Q. Do these odd actions seem to be real?</p>
               <p>Arlington. Indeed they are real. He looks out at the window to people in the yard, talks several languages that I do not understand, and points to people, and makes many mad motions.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560603-29-person364">
                  William 
                  Nichols 
               <interp inst="t17560603-29-person364" type="surname" value="Nichols"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-29-person364" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-29-person364" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Mount Street, Grosvenor-Square. The prisoner lodged with me two years and a half last past, and at different times before.</p>
               <p>Q. What has his behaviour been, like a man in his senses, or otherwise?</p>
               <p>Nichols. Not in his senses. I have not thought him so at all, so much as I could wish.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember the time of this fact, for which he was taken up?</p>
               <p>Nichols. He went out of my house about a quarter of an hour before ten, and I did not see him till I saw him in New Prison.</p>
               <p>Q. How was his state of mind then ?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175606030038"></xptr>Nichols. In a very indifferent manner, very bad.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen him often since the time of his confinement ?</p>
               <p>Nichols. I have, I saw him twice yesterday.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he been capable of taking his trial since he has been in confinement ?</p>
               <p>Nichols. No. I have mentioned his case to him several times, of what he is to be tried for; he took no concern about it, not so much as I did. I removed the affair of what was to come on to day, he said it was a day of very great importance. I said, I think of the utmost importance to you; he said, Never mind it, never mind it, and seemed to take no notice of it at all.</p>
               <p>Q. As to his behaviour since he has been in prison, do you think it was counterfeit or real?</p>
               <p>Nichols. Really, my lord, it is real.</p>
               <p>Court. People that counterfeit are very often off their guard, did you see any thing that could induce you to believe that it was put on?</p>
               <p>Nichols. It was real I am sure.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think he has been in a state of mind since his confinement, fit to take his trial, and to attend to a case of this nature?</p>
               <p>Nichols. I think not, by reason he has so little regard about it.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had he lived with you?</p>
               <p>Nichols. From last Michaelmas was two years.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17560603-29-person365">
                  William 
                  Cane 
               <interp inst="t17560603-29-person365" type="surname" value="Cane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-29-person365" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-29-person365" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never knew him before his confinement. I saw him, I believe, two or three days after he was sent to New Prison. I went to him to take instructions relating to his defence; he said he did not know me, therefore would give me no instructions, and that he did not care if he had but an honest jury, for if the man was killed somebody else must kill him. When I told him it was out of dispute who killed him, all he would say to me was, nothing could happen to him if he had but an honest jury. He behaved very decent to me, but rambling in his mind from one thing to another, asking me what became of the French at Minorca. I do not think he behaved like a rational man; a rational man would have been concerned for this person he had killed; but he seemed to have no concern at all. I always found him in bed but once when I went.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon the whole, do you think he is in a proper state of mind to take his trial?</p>
               <p>Cane. I don't think he is capable of attending or minding the evidence, or remembering it when he has heard it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17560603-29-verdict141" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17560603-29-verdict141" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17560603-29-verdict141" type="verdictSubcategory" value="nonComposMentis"></interp>
               The jury found him not of sound mind and memory
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
