<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17590530-6">
               <interp inst="t17590530-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590530-6" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590530-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17590530"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17590530-6" type="date" value="17590530"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17590530-6-off26-c68" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590530-6-defend76 t17590530-6-off26 t17590530-6-verdict28"></join>
         
               <p>183. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17590530-6-defend76" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Curry 
                  <interp inst="t17590530-6-defend76" type="surname" value="Curry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-6-defend76" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-6-defend76" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17590530-6-off26" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590530-6-off26" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-6-off26" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 3 linnen bags, value 3 d. and 300 pounds weight of piemento, value 6 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17590530-6-victim78" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Lesley 
                        <interp inst="t17590530-6-victim78" type="surname" value="Lesley"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590530-6-victim78" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17590530-6-victim78" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590530-6-off26 t17590530-6-victim78"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , the same being in a vessel lying in a certain navigable river, called the the river Thames
            </rs>, <rs id="t17590530-6-cd27" type="crimeDate">May 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17590530-6-off26 t17590530-6-cd27"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590530-6-person79">
                  John 
                  Lesley 
               <interp inst="t17590530-6-person79" type="surname" value="Lesley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-6-person79" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-6-person79" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The piemento was taken out of a lighter lying a-long side my ship, in the Thames; there were seven bags in all, over night, and there were 3 of them about 300 weight, taken away before morning; they were my property.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590530-6-person80">
                  John 
                  Lesby 
               <interp inst="t17590530-6-person80" type="surname" value="Lesby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-6-person80" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-6-person80" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 8th of May, between two and three in the morning; I was watchman in the lighter where the goods were; it was cold, and I was cover'd up; I heard people taking up the tarpauling; I got up, and saw 3 men handing the bags out, and to the best of my knowledge, the prisoner stood upon the gunnel of the lighter, one stood on a cask in the lighter, and the the other was in the boat's bow, (a wherry) they took it from hand to hand. I alarmed the ship, they flew all into the boat, and were shoving the boat off, when I got to the gunnel of the lighter. I call'd to the prisoner by his christian name, to remember I knew him. I threw a hand-spike into the boat, and they took it up and said, d - mn you, kiss my arse, and threw it at me.</p>
               <p>Q. What were your words ?</p>
               <p>Lesby. I said, Bob, remember I know you; he said nothing; we had no conveniency to pursue them, they got away.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to know the prisoner ?</p>
               <p>Lesby. By seeing him work on board our ship; it was moon-light that night.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590530-6-person81">
                  James 
                  Calley 
               <interp inst="t17590530-6-person81" type="surname" value="Calley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-6-person81" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-6-person81" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was on board the ship, and heard the watchman call thieves.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Calley. I am an officer. I went and alarmed the ship's company. I saw one man in the lighter, and another on the lighter's gunnel. After I had call'd the people, I look'd again, and saw four of them. I heard the watchman say, very well, Mr Bob, I know you; and heav'd the hand-spike into the boat; and they d - n'd him, and threw it at him again.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I am as innocent of this as the child unborn. I went to bed between ten and eleven that night; and lay 'till 7 o'clock; then, when I came down stairs, the maid said to me, I hope your early rising will do you no harm. The next day I went to work again, and they charg'd me with it.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590530-6-person82">
                  Ann 
                  Todd 
               <interp inst="t17590530-6-person82" type="surname" value="Todd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-6-person82" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-6-person82" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner lodg'd at my house, and has this year and half. I live at the three cups at Cole-stairs, Shadwell; he always behaved very well; he came in on the 8th of May at ten at night, he had a rasher of bacon for supper, and went to bed; I believe he lay in bed all night; I take the key of the back-door to bed with me, and I lie over the fore-door; and it cannot be open'd without my hearing of it; it is fasten'd with a great bar and bolt, and no lock.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you; a wife, or a single woman?</p>
               <p>Todd. I am a widow.</p>
               <p>Q. Could not a person open that door, and you not hear it?</p>
               <p>Todd. No; the neighbours four houses off might have heard it, it makes a great squeaking; and besides it must have been left unbolted,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175905300008"></xptr> and there is a watchman that knocks every time he comes by the door.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590530-6-person83">
                  Frances 
                  Broad 
               <interp inst="t17590530-6-person83" type="surname" value="Broad"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-6-person83" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-6-person83" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mrs Todd. I saw the prisoner go up to bed that night, and saw him in bed, and took the candle from his bed-side. I saw him the next morning come down about 7 o'clock; I said to him, I hope your early rising will do you no harm.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs Todd. Have you any more lodgers in the house?</p>
               <p>Todd. Yes, the next witness is one.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590530-6-person84">
                  Eleanor 
                  Gascoyne 
               <interp inst="t17590530-6-person84" type="surname" value="Gascoyne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-6-person84" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-6-person84" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodge in Mrs Todd's house. I saw the prisoner come in on the 8th of May, at ten at night, and had a rasher of bacon for supper, and went to bed about eleven; his room door was open, and when I came by his door to go out to work, about a quarter before six, I saw him lying in bed.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17590530-6-person85">
                  Frances 
                  Broad 
               <interp inst="t17590530-6-person85" type="surname" value="Broad"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-6-person85" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-6-person85" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Did you shut the door after you, when you took the candle away?</p>
               <p>F. Broad. The door commonly stands open.</p>
               <p>Q. Does it stand open in the day-time?</p>
               <p>F. Broad. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Who lets him out?</p>
               <p>F. Broad. I do; I always get up by 5 o'clock.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590530-6-person86">
                  Joseph 
                  Fish 
               <interp inst="t17590530-6-person86" type="surname" value="Fish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-6-person86" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-6-person86" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mrs Todd is my daughter; I live just by, and I go for about an hour or two to assist her in her business, in a morning, she keeps a public house; I saw the prisoner come down stairs the morning after the crime was laid to his charge, about 7 o'clock; he is a very honest man.</p>
               <p>Q. to Watchman. What time do the people come to work on board?</p>
               <p>Watchman. Between six and seven o'clock.</p>
               <p>Serjeant Evans. I have known the prisoner ever since the year Fifty-five, he belongs to the Cold-stream regiment, the second regiment of guards. He has behaved himself extreamly well, he is a working man, I never saw him in liquor since I knew him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590530-6-person87">
                  Susannah 
                  Elvey 
               <interp inst="t17590530-6-person87" type="surname" value="Elvey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-6-person87" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-6-person87" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner lodg'd with me two years; he behaved very civil, and very just and sober, and regular as to his hours.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590530-6-person88">
                  Susannah 
                  Elvey 
               <interp inst="t17590530-6-person88" type="surname" value="Elvey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-6-person88" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-6-person88" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am mother to the last witness: he always behaved honest and well, I have trusted him with things, and would again, was he out.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17590530-6-person89">
                  Thomas 
                  Banks 
               <interp inst="t17590530-6-person89" type="surname" value="Banks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-6-person89" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17590530-6-person89" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him many years, he is a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17590530-6-verdict28" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17590530-6-verdict28" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
