<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510523-23">
               <interp inst="t17510523-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510523-23" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510523-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510523"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510523-23" type="date" value="17510523"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510523-23-off127-c170" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-23-defend214 t17510523-23-off127 t17510523-23-verdict132"></join>
         
               <p>377. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17510523-23-defend214" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Cluneys 
                  <interp inst="t17510523-23-defend214" type="surname" value="Cluneys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-23-defend214" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-23-defend214" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17510523-23-off127" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510523-23-off127" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-23-off127" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a gold watch, value 18 l. one silver snuffbox, one silver stock-buckle, and one guinea, the goods and money of 
                     <persName id="t17510523-23-victim215" type="victimName">
                        Jethroe 
                        Weacher 
                     <interp inst="t17510523-23-victim215" type="surname" value="Weacher"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510523-23-victim215" type="given" value="Jethroe"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510523-23-victim215" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-23-off127 t17510523-23-victim215"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , in the dwelling-house of the said Jethroe
            </rs>, <rs id="t17510523-23-cd128" type="crimeDate">Feb. 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-23-off127 t17510523-23-cd128"></join>. *</p>
               <p>Jethroe Weacher. I live now at the king's arms in King's-street, Westminster. In February last I <rs id="t17510523-23-viclabel129" type="occupation">kept the <placeName id="t17510523-23-crimeloc130">Fox ale-house in York-buildings</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-23-crimeloc130" type="placeName" value="Fox ale-house in York-buildings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-23-crimeloc130" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-23-off127 t17510523-23-crimeloc130"></join>
                  </rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-23-victim215 t17510523-23-viclabel129"></join>. The prisoner is a <rs id="t17510523-23-deflabel131" type="occupation">soldier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510523-23-defend214 t17510523-23-deflabel131"></join>, he came to lodge at my house about Christmas, or a little after.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he billeted upon you?</p>
               <p>Weacher. No, my Lord, he was not: He told me his quarters was a long way from the Parade, so he gave me ninepence per week for his lodgings; he staid till he ow'd me six shillings and threepence; I had let this house to another person; I ask'd him for the money the 26th of Feb. he got up Thursday the 27th, saying, he was going to get the money for me, and would be back by ten o'clock but he did not return: I had occasion to go up into the room where I lie to my chest of drawers and found them broke open, I miss'd my wife's gold watch, a silver snuff-box, a silver stock-buckle, and a guinea in gold: I left the house on Saturday morning and went to my lodgings I had taken in Long-Acre: After this I took all the opportunities I could to find the prisoner, about a month after I saw him upon duty at St. James's Gate; I ask'd him when he intended to pay me the money; he said he had been seeking after me, saying, his father had sent him 27 l. and he had received it at Deptford, and that he would come the Saturday after, but did not come: He told me where he lodged, so on the Monday I went there, he was not at home, I told the landlady I had been a great sufferer by him: He deserted, and was taken up as a deserter and sent to the Savoy about three weeks after: I went to him and ask'd him for the things, he told me, if I would pay the money that was taken upon the watch I might have it again, and that it was at the Blue-anchor at Deptford, the man's name 
               <persName id="t17510523-23-person216">
                  William 
                  Liberton 
               <interp inst="t17510523-23-person216" type="surname" value="Liberton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-23-person216" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-23-person216" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; accordingly he gave me a direction to go there for it, I went, the man own'd he had it, but would not let me have it, and said, it cost him 10 l. 1 s. the prisoner said he had sold it for 8 l. I came back to Justice Fielding's and took out a warrant, and brought the prisoner out of the Savoy before him, he was committed to the Gate-house.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Who had the keys of the drawers, your wife or you?</p>
               <p>Weacher. I had.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your wife at home with you then?</p>
               <p>Weacher. She had been gone from me about a week before. I had a room for her in order to go to her when I left the house.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see the watch last before you missed it?</p>
               <p>Weacher. I saw it the Wednesday in the after noon.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you charge the prisoner with the fact when you saw him at St. James's Gate?</p>
               <p>Weacher. No, I did not, because I fear'd he would make off, as he did afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you how he came by the watch?</p>
               <p>Weacher. He told me my wife had made him a present of it, but I told him it was out of her power so to do, as I had the key of the drawers in my pocket, and she had been gone to the lodgings a week.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not your wife absent herself from you?</p>
               <p>Weacher. She went a week before with my consent.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did she live with?</p>
               <p>Weacher. She lodged with a widow woman, and does so now.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never suspect her going away to live with the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Weacher. No, I never did: I have no other reason than to think her a virtuous woman. I liv'd there with her till I took another publick house in Soho, Warder-street, which I enter'd upon about a week after.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is your wife now?</p>
               <p>Weacher. She is still in the lodgings. She was well bred and a publick house is not agreeable to her.</p>
               <p>Q. Are not you separated?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175105230017"></xptr>Weacher. No, we are not, I see her every day.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you get a search warrant at Deptford ?</p>
               <p>Weacher. The Justice there would not grant me one.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-23-person217">
                  William 
                  Leberton 
               <interp inst="t17510523-23-person217" type="surname" value="Leberton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-23-person217" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-23-person217" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Blue-anchor at Deptford, here is the watch. The prosecutor deposed to it. On the 30th of March last there came one John Cockborne to me, and said a friend of his had got into trouble, here is a letter he shewed me wrote by that friend, it is sign'd with the prisoner's name, and that he had pawn'd a gold watch for four pound to Mr. Slaiter, at Deptford. I went with Cockborne's wife, for she pawn'd it, and found there was 4 l. 16 s. upon it with the interest: The man said it had been there five or six weeks: Said I, was it ever advertised? he said, no; the woman desir'd I would pay the money and take the watch out to get it sold to the best advantage; I never saw the prisoner before now to my knowledge. I took it out and carried it to a watchmaker in Deptford, and ask'd him to value it; he said it was very much out of repair, and valued it at 9 l. I gave 10 l. 1 s. for it, and it cost 10 s. 6 d. mending.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-23-person218">
                  Michael 
                  Mayham 
               <interp inst="t17510523-23-person218" type="surname" value="Mayham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-23-person218" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-23-person218" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . After the prisoner was committed to the Savoy, (I belong to the same regiment,) I went to see him, and talking about the watch he desired me to tell the prosecutor the chain and seal were safe, and that no body could come at them unless he was there himself.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510523-23-person219">
                  Mary 
                  Jenkins 
               <interp inst="t17510523-23-person219" type="surname" value="Jenkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-23-person219" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510523-23-person219" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I came into the house the prosecutor went out of, the prisoner had a room of me, he had lodged with me about three weeks when this thing happened. After the prosecutor had been to ask for him after the thing was done, I heard the prisoner say, he never had any thing of the prosecutor's wife in his life; the prisoner had let me look at the snuff-box, and my little boy had once fetch'd a halfpenny worth of snuff in it; the prisoner left the lodgings upon this, and I did not see him after till I saw him in the Gatehouse : I heard him own to the things, and said the prosecutor should have them again. He sent word the chain was buried under ground.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I came a little after Christmas to lodge in the prosecutor's house, the man himself having several times invited me to it; it was my fate to have the landlady to take a regard for me, telling me at different times, that her husband was a very barbarous man, used her ill, and that she could not live in a civil way with him: She made offers to me, and said, it I would go and take private lodgings she would accompany me: I might have agreed to that, but finding her inclinations to drink I took a disgust at her; but on the Sunday in the afternoon before she went away she call'd me up to her own room, and said, I am going away, and shall take one child with me, for I cannot live agreeable with my husband: She said, take you this, and gave me the gold watch and silver snuff box, and said, if I would accept of her invitation her life would be more agreeable to her: After I was in the Savoy the prosecutor sent me word, if I would restore the things he would make it up with me: I told him, I did not think proper to make him restitution for things that were given me as innocent presents: I told him also, the watch was at the Blue-anchor at Deptford, put there by a friend of mine; I gave it to a person as I was upon duty, who gave it to Mrs. Cockborne to sell or pledge it upon my own account, thus it came to the Blue-anchor at Deptford.</p>
               <p>The prisoner had four persons, who had known him above eighteen months, that gave him a good character.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510523-23-verdict132" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510523-23-verdict132" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
