<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510911-25">
               <interp inst="t17510911-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510911-25" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510911-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510911-25" type="date" value="17510911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510911-25-off116-c139" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-25-defend187 t17510911-25-off116 t17510911-25-verdict120"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510911-25-off116-c140" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-25-defend189 t17510911-25-off116 t17510911-25-verdict120"></join>
         
               <p>496, 497. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17510911-25-defend187" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Newman 
                  <interp inst="t17510911-25-defend187" type="surname" value="Newman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-25-defend187" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-25-defend187" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17510911-25-defend189" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     March 
                  <interp inst="t17510911-25-defend189" type="surname" value="March"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-25-defend189" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-25-defend189" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for that they, <rs id="t17510911-25-off116" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510911-25-off116" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-25-off116" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               in a certain passage, or open place, near the King's high-way, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17510911-25-victim191" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Daniel 
                        <interp inst="t17510911-25-victim191" type="surname" value="Daniel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510911-25-victim191" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510911-25-victim191" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-25-off116 t17510911-25-victim191"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, &amp;c. and steal from his person one hat, value 1 s. 6 d. one silk handkerchief, one pair of leather shoes, one pen-knife, and one shilling and sixpence in money
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510911-25-cd117" type="crimeDate">Sept. 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-25-off116 t17510911-25-cd117"></join>. ++ .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-25-person192">
                  James 
                  Daniel 
               <interp inst="t17510911-25-person192" type="surname" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-25-person192" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-25-person192" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an Irishman, and live in the Borough, and am a <rs id="t17510911-25-viclabel118" type="occupation">green grocer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-25-victim191 t17510911-25-viclabel118"></join>. On the second of this month, about nine at night, I was coming home from Islington, having been with a young fellow a big piece of the way to Coventry. I had a pint of beer at <placeName id="t17510911-25-crimeloc119">the Two Brewers in Hockley in the Hole; coming away, about ten yards from the house</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17510911-25-crimeloc119" type="placeName" value="the Two Brewers in Hockley in the Hole; coming away, about ten yards from the house"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510911-25-crimeloc119" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-25-off116 t17510911-25-crimeloc119"></join>, I was stopt.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you alone?</p>
               <p>Daniel. I was all alone, except my shoes tied up in a handkerchief. I saw three men standing by a lamp, two of them had hats, and one a cap: They crossed over to me: then I turned up to make water, in a yard. One of them got hold on my collar, (for they did not give me leave to button up my breeches) the other on my shoulder on the other side. I thought I saw a sword, but it was a long piece of iron. One swore he would knock my brains out if I stir'd, the other came and took off my hat, and put it on March's head; then Newman put his hand in my pocket, and took out one shilling and sixpence. March said, D - n him, he has more money; then the other took out a pen knife, and took from me my handkerchief, and shoes in it. After this they run from me, two one way, and one another; and thinking to catch one of them, I called out, stop! stop! stop! but I saw no more of them that night. I know the two prisoners were two of the men, for I saw their faces by the lamp. The Evidence and March are the two that laid hold on me. The Evidence had the one shilling and sixpence. I met with two men, to whom I related the matter, and they had like to have been taken that night. I likewise told them where I liv'd. The next day I was sent for, and went the day after that to the Horseshoe in Clerkenwell; there I saw the Evidence; then I went to the Justice's, and in going met the two prisoners coming back. I described the penknife, before I saw it, at the Justice's. [ Produced in Court, and deposed to.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-25-person193">
                  Timothy 
                  Brads 
               <interp inst="t17510911-25-person193" type="surname" value="Brads"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-25-person193" type="given" value="Timothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-25-person193" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the second of September, the two prisoner and I set out from an empty house in Black-boy-Alley, about eight o'clock at night, with a full intent to rob. I had been acquainted with March about five weeks, but not so long with Newman. We came up Saffron-hill, and seeing the prosecutor, I walked by him two or three times, and looked him full in the face. I followed him into George-yard, where he was making water, and took him by the collar; Newman had this weapon in his hand; [it was produced in court ; being a piece of iron about twenty inches long, proper to break doors open with,] and March had hold on his coat, not his collar. I took the shoes tied up in his handkerchief, and gave them to Newman; the hat March had, but I took it, and also one shilling and sixpence out of his pocket. March took the pen-knife. This is the very same knife. We were pursued, and March and Newman were taken, but they got away again, and I met March at our place of rendezvous. We went then from Black-boy-Alley to St. Giles's, and I had some victuals out of the money. Next morning we were coming up Purple-lane, and Woodward Harlow laid hold on us. I went and found Newman, after I was admitted an evidence.</p>
               <p>Woodward Harlow. Going into Purple-lane that night, I met one Mr. Burry. I heard a man cry stop; and seeing a lad run along I laid hold of him, crying, I have got you, but he got from me; however, I got his wig, and this piece of iron. I was told at the end of the lane, that Tim the taylor was seen with two more going through such a place. I saw the prosecutor soon after, but he made a more hubble bubble story of it then, than he has now; he was in such a slutter, I could hardly understand him. He told me he lived by the King's Bench, and mentioned the things he had lost. The next day, as I was coming home to dinner, I saw Tim the taylor (that is the evidence) and March coming along, I took them, and brought them to my room. When I told them of this robbery, I took this pen-knife out of March's pocket; upon which he fell a crying, and said if I would let him go to his father, and give him that knife, his father should give me twenty guineas. Tim said, I am a neighbour's child, and,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175109110012"></xptr> if I don't do it, he will. Will you speak to the Justice to get me admitted an evidence? March said, he was out of his senses, or the devil was in him when he did it. I sent for Mr. Burry. Then I left March in my room, and took Tim to shew as where Newman was. He took us to Goswell-street, were we took him, and carried him before the Justice; then we took him to March, and March fell a crying. Said Newman, You whining son of a b - ch, what do you cry for, confess and be hang'd, you can do no more at last? Newman owned the wig, and my having him in my arms the night the robbery was done, but would not own to the iron.</p>
               <p>Newman's Defence.</p>
               <p>Coming along I met Tim the taylor; he stopt me, and said what chear? I knew him by fight, and he asked me to go and drink part of a pint of beer; I reply'd, I don't care if I do. He took me up to a wall, and bid me stay there; then he brought me a hat and a knife; as soon as he had brought them, a man came and called out thief; another man laid hold of me, but I slipped from him, and he got my wig in custody.</p>
               <p>March's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was with the other prisoner. We met Tim the taylor, who said he was going to his master's house, but being afraid to go in, we staid waiting about a good while; at last he came running down from George-yard, and put the hat on my head, and gave me the pen-knife, saying I might keep it, for he did not want it. Then Woodward Harlow came and laid hold of this lad, and called out stop thief; I ran, but did not know what it was for. I met Tim about an hour afterwards, he asked me to go and dine off of a shoulder of mutton and onions; I went, but the woman had none; then she put on a sauce-pan, and boiled a whole breast of mutton. She then sent out a young woman for some strong liquor, and Harlow came in, and said if I would not fit still, he would blow my brains out. He took the knife that Tim gave me directly from my pocket. I did not know he had robbed any body.</p>
               <rs id="t17510911-25-verdict120" type="verdictDescription">
                  <interp inst="t17510911-25-verdict120" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510911-25-verdict120" type="verdictSubcategory" value="withRecommendation"></interp>
            
                  <p>Both Guilty, <rs id="t17510911-25-punish121" type="punishmentDescription">
                        <interp inst="t17510911-25-punish121" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                        <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-25-defend187 t17510911-25-punish121"></join>
                        <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-25-defend189 t17510911-25-punish121"></join>
                     Death
                  </rs>.</p>
                  <p>Recommended to mercy.</p>
            
               </rs>
            </div1>
