<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510417-13">
               <interp inst="t17510417-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510417-13" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510417-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510417"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510417-13" type="date" value="17510417"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510417-13-off65-c86" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510417-13-defend113 t17510417-13-off65 t17510417-13-verdict69"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510417-13-off65-c87" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510417-13-defend115 t17510417-13-off65 t17510417-13-verdict69"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510417-13-off65-c88" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510417-13-defend117 t17510417-13-off65 t17510417-13-verdict69"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510417-13-off65-c89" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510417-13-defend119 t17510417-13-off65 t17510417-13-verdict69"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510417-13-off70-c87" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510417-13-defend115 t17510417-13-off70 t17510417-13-verdict69"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510417-13-off70-c88" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510417-13-defend117 t17510417-13-off70 t17510417-13-verdict69"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510417-13-off70-c89" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510417-13-defend119 t17510417-13-off70 t17510417-13-verdict69"></join>
         
               <p>271, 272, 273, 274. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17510417-13-defend113" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Morris 
                  <interp inst="t17510417-13-defend113" type="surname" value="Morris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-defend113" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-defend113" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17510417-13-defend115" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Commins 
                  <interp inst="t17510417-13-defend115" type="surname" value="Commins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-defend115" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-defend115" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17510417-13-defend117" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Hayes 
                  <interp inst="t17510417-13-defend117" type="surname" value="Hayes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-defend117" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-defend117" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17510417-13-defend119" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Bryan 
                  <interp inst="t17510417-13-defend119" type="surname" value="Bryan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-defend119" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-defend119" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for that <rs id="t17510417-13-off65" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-off65" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-off65" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               they, together with two other persons not taken, on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17510417-13-victim121" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Dudsdon 
                        <interp inst="t17510417-13-victim121" type="surname" value="Dudsdon"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510417-13-victim121" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510417-13-victim121" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, one shagreen case, with six lancets, three half guineas, and 4 s. 6 d. in money number'd, from his person, and against his will, did steal, take and carry away
            </rs>, <rs id="t17510417-13-cd66" type="crimeDate">November 25</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510417-13-off65 t17510417-13-cd66"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510417-13-off70 t17510417-13-cd66"></join>. *</p>
               <p>William Dudsdon. I am an <rs id="t17510417-13-viclabel67" type="occupation">apothecary</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510417-13-victim121 t17510417-13-viclabel67"></join>: On the 25th of November last, returning home from Charing-cross, about a quarter after twelve o'clock at night; as I was in <placeName id="t17510417-13-crimeloc68">Catharine, or Bridges-street, I know not which, not knowing where they end; opposite York-street end</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17510417-13-crimeloc68" type="placeName" value="Catharine, or Bridges-street, I know not which, not knowing where they end; opposite York-street end"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510417-13-crimeloc68" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510417-13-off65 t17510417-13-crimeloc68"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510417-13-off70 t17510417-13-crimeloc68"></join> I was attack'd by seven people armed with pistols and cutlasses; there were two pistols pointed to my head, they told me, if I made any resistance they would blow my brains out; they surrounded me and rifled my pockets; they took from me a shagreen case with six lancets in it, three half guineas, and 4 s. 6 d. in silver; whether my hat fell off I cannot tell, but they put another on my head, and after that cut me through that and my wig, the hat and wig were produced in court with a cut in each, then they left me. I met two gentlemen, of whom I desir'd assistance to take them, but they did not assist me. I went and seized one of the thieves by the arm, and another of them came and struck me over the arm, and rescued him from me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it any of the prisoners do you think you seized?</p>
               <p>Dudsdon. I think it was Morris, and also I think I saw Morris at the time I was surrounded by them, but I do not swear that I think he was one; I saw him before Justice Fielding, and I then thought the same I do now.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell who gave you that blow on your arm?</p>
               <p>Dudsdon. I cannot tell that; then they chas'd me out of the street, with the cry, d - n him, kill him, altho' there were three watchmen, and two chairmen, standing at Drury-lane play-house passage at that time; the watchmen came to my assistance.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you recollect any of the other Prisoners ?</p>
               <p>Dudsdon. I cannot, my Lord, it was pretty dark.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever met with the case and instruments again?</p>
               <p>Dudsdon. No, my Lord.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510417-13-person122">
                  William 
                  Freestone 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person122" type="surname" value="Freestone"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person122" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person122" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About the 24th, or 25th of Nov. on a Saturday, the prisoners, I, 
               <persName id="t17510417-13-person123">
                  Francis 
                  Urwin 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person123" type="surname" value="Urwin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person123" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person123" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17510417-13-person124">
                  James 
                  Field 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person124" type="surname" value="Field"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person124" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person124" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who is since executed, (see No 100 in this mayoralty) and 
               <persName id="t17510417-13-person125">
                  Thomas 
                  Burt 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person125" type="surname" value="Burt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person125" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person125" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , met together at the Fox in Drury-lane; we agreed together in order to go out to rob the first person we met, that we thought worth robbing. We went out about eight o'clock, and came in again a little before nine, having not met with any thing. We drank three full pots standing, and between nine and ten we walk'd out again. We walk'd round Bloomsbury-square, Grosvenor-square, and coming up the Strand we came up Bridges-street, this was about twelve o'clock. Morris swore an oath to 
               <persName id="t17510417-13-person126">
                  James 
                  Field 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person126" type="surname" value="Field"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person126" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person126" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he would not go home without a supper. Just as we came to Vinegar-yard we saw the prosecutor, 
               <persName id="t17510417-13-person127">
                  James 
                  Field 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person127" type="surname" value="Field"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person127" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person127" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             laid hold on his head and squeez'd him to his bosom, and said, d - n your eyes, stand, if you make any resistance you are a dead man, and presented a pistol to the left side of his head; I was very near him, Morris went to rifling his pockets, he had a pistol too when he went out, but I did not see him present it; the hangers were drawn, we had most or all of us hangers.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any other pistol presented besides that of Field's?</p>
               <p>Freestone. No, my Lord, I did not. Morris put the money in his pocket, and gave me the case of lancets, the case was shagreen with a silver edge. Mr. Dudsdon said, gentlemen, I wish there were but three of you, you should not rob me; then I saw Hayes go up to him, and strike him on the head with a hanger; Hayes before, as Morris<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175104170006"></xptr> was rifling him, took off his hat and put his own on the prosecutor. We were going away, I heard a rumble, and I saw Mr. Dudsdon had got Bryan by the hand; I said to Field, he is going to get one of our company away; I went back and laid a stick over his arm, and brought Bryan away; then we went round, and so home to Pendegrast's lodgings, which was on the backside the Fox, and there divided the money. (See No 254 in Sir 
               <persName id="t17510417-13-person128">
                  Samuel 
                  Pennant 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person128" type="surname" value="Pennant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person128" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person128" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's mayoralty) Morris there produced two half guineas, and about four shillings in silver. The next day we saw it advertised three half guineas, and some silver.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510417-13-person129">
                  Susannah 
                  Cooper 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person129" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person129" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person129" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Freestone lodged at my house about ten days, a little before Christmas, and on that time the prisoners used to come to my house to see him, as also did Pendegrast, and Field. 
               <persName id="t17510417-13-person130">
                  William 
                  Woolse 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person130" type="surname" value="Woolse"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person130" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person130" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , son to 
               <persName id="t17510417-13-person131">
                  Susannah 
                  Cooper 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person131" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person131" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person131" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , depos'd the same.</p>
               <p>Morris's Defence. I have some witnesses to call.</p>
               <p>Commins's Defence. I was sick at that time.</p>
               <p>Bryan's Defence. I am a stranger, and have not been long in this country.</p>
               <p>Hayes's Defence. I am ill, and cannot speak.</p>
               <p>For Morris.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510417-13-person132">
                  John 
                  Warner 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person132" type="surname" value="Warner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person132" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person132" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Morris three or four years.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Warner. I am an officer in Whitechappel-court : I had arrested a man, one 
               <persName id="t17510417-13-person133">
                  William 
                  Sadler 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person133" type="surname" value="Sadler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person133" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person133" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who liv'd on Saltpeter-bank, and he was got away. I came to Morris's house, and 
               <persName id="t17510417-13-person134">
                  Alexander 
                  Wells 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person134" type="surname" value="Wells"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person134" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person134" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was there, he was the plaintif, Nov. 24 about five o'clock; we staid there till ten, we had a bit of roast beef hot for supper; we drank to the tune of three or four shillings amongst us, Morris keeps a publick house; at ten o'clock we went away to Saltpeter-bank, and there staid till one; Saltpeter-bank is about three or four stone's cast from Morris's house; we went in at Mr. Scott's on the Bank, and had three full pots there ; we went to re-take the person who had made his escape from me, it was after two o'clock before we got back to Morris's house, where we had a full pot of beer, and then separated, after having agreed to meet again there the next day, to see if we could find this man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510417-13-person135">
                  Alexander 
                  Wells 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person135" type="surname" value="Wells"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person135" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person135" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know Mr. Morris to be a very honest man. Mr. Warner had an action of mine against one Sadler; he and I were at Morris's house on the 24th of Nov. there he had a little supper of beef and pudding, he ask'd me to stay to supper. I came there between five and six o'clock, and said to him, this Warner has lost my prisoner, and takes no care to get him again. Mr. Morris sent for Warner, saying, he was a very good customer to him, and had been there about an hour before; he came between six and seven, and about eight we went to supper. After that Mr. Morris said, I'll go along with you to serve Mr. Warner, to take this person; there was a dispute about taking him without a constable; we went on Saltpeter-bank and watch'd for this Sadler, his time being to be out about one in the morning, he works at the glass-house, so do I: we went into the black Lion and had some beer, but what quantity I cannot tell; we were together till four in the morning.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510417-13-person136">
                  Charles 
                  Shewler 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person136" type="surname" value="Shewler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person136" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person136" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know Freestone, I saw him in Clarkenwel bridewell, and said to him, I am sorry to see you in this condition; he said, he never could sleep in his bed thinking about Morris ; saying, he was innocent as the child unborn; but the thief-takers said, if he did not swear against him, they would hang him.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Shewler. I drive a hackney coach, and live in Whitechappel : I have drank many gallons of beer with Freestone, I have known him some time, and I have known Morris as long, and I respect them both as far as good friendship.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510417-13-person137">
                  John 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person137" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person137" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person137" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Morris fourteen years, he has a very honest character for whatever I heard.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510417-13-person138">
                  Mary 
                  Sampson 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person138" type="surname" value="Sampson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person138" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person138" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him these sixteen years, I never heard he had an ill character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510417-13-person139">
                  Mary 
                  Rogers 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person139" type="surname" value="Rogers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person139" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person139" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Morris between three and four years, I live within three or four doors of him; he always behaved very handsom, and every body gave him a very good character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510417-13-person140">
                  Robert 
                  Pratt 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person140" type="surname" value="Pratt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person140" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person140" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him six or seven years, and never saw any dishonesty by him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510417-13-person141">
                  Roger 
                  Farrel 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person141" type="surname" value="Farrel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person141" type="given" value="Roger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person141" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him six or seven years, I never heard any ill of him.</p>
               <p>For Commins.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510417-13-person142">
                  John 
                  Lang 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person142" type="surname" value="Lang"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person142" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person142" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know 
               <persName id="t17510417-13-person143">
                  John 
                  Commins 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person143" type="surname" value="Commins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person143" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person143" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             very well, I attended him from the 8th of November, in a room of mine, till the 20th of December; he had a nurse which I recommended to attend him also, her name is Connoley; I never found or heard of his going out of the room, till the week before Christmas; he could hardly turn himself in his bed without the help of the nurse; I attended him every day, sometimes twice a day; he came under my hands by the recommendation of a person that I had cured before.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175104170007"></xptr>Pratt. I live in Exeter-change-court, in the Strand, opposite the Running-horse: I laid the prisoner down in a salivation; he, according to agreement, paid me two guineas at first coming, and the other two when he was well.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510417-13-person144">
                  Jane 
                  Connoley 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person144" type="surname" value="Connoley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person144" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person144" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was employ'd to be a nurse-keeper to Mr. Commins, 5 weeks before Christmas, at Exeter-change in the Strand ; I attended him five weeks and three days, I went away the Thursday before Christmas, he never went abroad in that time, for he kept his bed most part of it. Mr. Lang paid me half a guinea a week for my board wages.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510417-13-person145">
                  Esther 
                  Lang 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person145" type="surname" value="Lang"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person145" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person145" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to Mr. Lang. She confirm'd his testimony.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510417-13-person146">
                  William 
                  Floyd 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person146" type="surname" value="Floyd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person146" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person146" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a taylor and staymaker : I work'd with him in one shop about half a year, he is a taylor ; we work'd together for one William Newton, in Crown court, about a year ago.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510417-13-person147">
                  Nicholas 
                  Lenard 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person147" type="surname" value="Lenard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person147" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person147" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a shoemaker: I have known Commins a year and better, his general character is nothing but what is honest, I never heard any ill of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know he was tried for his life last assizes at Kingston ?</p>
               <p>Lenard. I have heard so: But he was honourably acquitted.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you an evidence for him there?</p>
               <p>Lenard. I was not, Sir.</p>
               <p>All <rs id="t17510417-13-verdict69" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-verdict69" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>For Commins see No 641 in Sir 
               <persName id="t17510417-13-person148">
                  William 
                  Calvert 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person148" type="surname" value="Calvert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person148" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person148" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's mayoralty, and also No 13 in the last Kingston paper.</p>
               <p>(M.) 
               <persName id="t17510417-13-person149">
                  James 
                  Hayes 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person149" type="surname" value="Hayes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person149" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person149" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17510417-13-person150">
                  James 
                  Bryan 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person150" type="surname" value="Bryan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person150" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person150" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17510417-13-person151">
                  John 
                  Commins 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person151" type="surname" value="Commins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person151" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person151" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , otherwise <rs id="t17510417-13-alias-1" type="alias">Jack the Taylor</rs>, were a second time indicted, for that <rs id="t17510417-13-off70" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-off70" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-off70" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               they on the king's highway, on 
                     <persName id="t17510417-13-victim152" type="victimName">
                        John 
                        Howard 
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-victim152" type="surname" value="Howard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510417-13-victim152" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510417-13-victim152" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                    did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, one hat, value 1 s. from his person did steal, take and carry away
            </rs>, <rs id="t17510417-13-cd71" type="crimeDate">Dec. 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510417-13-off65 t17510417-13-cd71"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510417-13-off70 t17510417-13-cd71"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510417-13-person153">
                  John 
                  Howard 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person153" type="surname" value="Howard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person153" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person153" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 21st of December, about half an hour after nine o'clock at night, going home to <placeName id="t17510417-13-crimeloc72">Silver-street, Bloomsbury-market</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17510417-13-crimeloc72" type="placeName" value="Silver-street, Bloomsbury-market"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510417-13-crimeloc72" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510417-13-off65 t17510417-13-crimeloc72"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510417-13-off70 t17510417-13-crimeloc72"></join>, I made a stop in that street to make water, at that time five men pass'd by me, I took no farther notice of them ; one of them turn'd upon me, took hold of me, and clap'd a pistol to my face, and said, you are a dead man if you resist or make a noise, repeating it two or three times. I was a little affrignted at first, but my spirits soon arose; they began to rifle my pockets, and tumbled me down; I observed a little fellow very busy about me; I cry'd out thieves and murder, and at the door where I fell the gentleman threw open his parlour window, the neighbourhood was pretty much alarmed; then they ran all, but he that had the pistol, which I believe is 
               <persName id="t17510417-13-person154">
                  James 
                  Hayes 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person154" type="surname" value="Hayes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person154" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person154" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , but I do not swear it; they took my hat away with them, and nothing else, he with the pistol jobb'd the muzzle of it in my face several times, and very narrowly missed my eyes, but he soon made off after the others: I can say nothing to any person but Hayes, when I saw him in Bridewell amongst other people, I then thought him to be the man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510417-13-person155">
                  William 
                  Freestone 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person155" type="surname" value="Freestone"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person155" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person155" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The evidence in the former trial deposed that himself, 
               <persName id="t17510417-13-person156">
                  John 
                  Commins 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person156" type="surname" value="Commins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person156" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person156" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , young 
               <persName id="t17510417-13-person157">
                  George 
                  Hussey 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person157" type="surname" value="Hussey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person157" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person157" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who was executed last Assizes at Reading, and 
               <persName id="t17510417-13-person158">
                  James 
                  Bryne 
               <interp inst="t17510417-13-person158" type="surname" value="Bryne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person158" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-person158" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Hays were the persons that did this robbery, but his testimony not being strengthned by other evidence of credit, they were all 3 <rs id="t17510417-13-verdict73" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510417-13-verdict73" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
