<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17520408-57">
               <interp inst="t17520408-57" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520408-57" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520408-57" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520408"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520408-57" type="date" value="17520408"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520408-57-off293-c360" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520408-57-defend471 t17520408-57-off293 t17520408-57-verdict296"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175204080037"></xptr>274. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17520408-57-defend471" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Darby 
                  <interp inst="t17520408-57-defend471" type="surname" value="Darby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-57-defend471" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-57-defend471" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted <rs id="t17520408-57-off293" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520408-57-off293" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-57-off293" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               as an accessary after a felony committed by his brother, 
                     <persName id="t17520408-57-person472">
                        Robert 
                        Darby 
                     <interp inst="t17520408-57-person472" type="surname" value="Darby"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520408-57-person472" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520408-57-person472" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , in robbing the western Mail, July 29, and was in due form and manner tried and convicted thereof at Kingston upon Thames, March 31; he, the said William, did, on the <rs id="t17520408-57-cd294" type="crimeDate">14th of October</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520408-57-off293 t17520408-57-cd294"></join>, unlawfully and knowingly receive, comfort, aid and abet the said 
                     <persName id="t17520408-57-person473">
                        Robert 
                        Darby 
                     <interp inst="t17520408-57-person473" type="surname" value="Darby"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520408-57-person473" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17520408-57-person473" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , &amp;c
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520408-57-person474">
                  John 
                  Saunderson 
               <interp inst="t17520408-57-person474" type="surname" value="Saunderson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-57-person474" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-57-person474" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             produces the copy of the record of the conviction of 
               <persName id="t17520408-57-person475">
                  Robert 
                  Darby 
               <interp inst="t17520408-57-person475" type="surname" value="Darby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-57-person475" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-57-person475" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; it is read, and compared with the Indictment.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520408-57-person476">
                  Francis
                   Price Newham
               <interp inst="t17520408-57-person476" type="surname" value="Price Newham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-57-person476" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-57-person476" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have been near two years apprentice to the prisoner: he is a <rs id="t17520408-57-deflabel295" type="occupation">chymist</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520408-57-defend471 t17520408-57-deflabel295"></join>, opposite Southampton-street in Holborn: about the latter end of September, he asked me to go with him, he got me a horse, and boots, we took horse about five in the evening, I can't tell the day, we went over Westminster-Bridge, to Kingston, from thence to Edgham, we staid there at the Red-Lion, about half an hour: then we rode across the heath pretty fast, we got to a hedge, it was pretty dark then, it was moon light, the day was shut in, he said he had rather it was dark than light: he got off his horse and went through the hedge, and staid about half an hour, and bro't a coarse linnen bag, tied up together, I think it would hold near a bushel, it was not very heavy in proportion to the bigness : he desired me to buckle it on my saddle, there were things in it, and cover it with my great coat, I did, and we rode directly to London, quite a different way from that we went, we returned through Hounslow, and got to master's house about ten o'clock that night, he took the bag from me and set it down by the door, and when the man open'd the door and was gone, master carried the bag in privately: master sent me away with the horses: I don't know in what manner he disposed of it: 
               <persName id="t17520408-57-person477">
                  Robert 
                  Darby 
               <interp inst="t17520408-57-person477" type="surname" value="Darby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-57-person477" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-57-person477" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's wife was in the house at the time of our going out, and I saw her in the house when we return'd. Master desired me never to speak of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520408-57-person478">
                  Mary 
                  Darby 
               <interp inst="t17520408-57-person478" type="surname" value="Darby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-57-person478" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-57-person478" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the prisoner's house in last September, I can't tell the day particularly; he is brother to my husband, Robert Darby, I was present in Newgate when he gave his directions to go to Core, for the bag that was taken out of the western Mail, which he said was laid in some ditch, and the prisoner said he would go: about five or six weeks after this, he and the apprentice went, I was at his house when they set out, and returned, which was about nine or ten o'clock, I saw nothing that night, the next day there was a particular smell of burnt paper in his own chamber, where I saw the remains of paper that had been burnt ; a few days after that he ordered me to bring a candle and light him in the shop, he took out a coarse sacking bag and brought it into the parlour, I followed him, he sat down by the fire, and took out some papers and letters sealed up, he broke the seals and open'd them, I saw him open to the value of twenty, I believe, they were all very wet, some of them were so wet he could not open them, them he put in the fire without, he might put in the quantity of a peck; in one letter there was two little bits of paper, I asked him what they were? he said they were no bank notes, but notes of hand, them and all the letters he put into the fire: I found some bank notes under 
               <persName id="t17520408-57-person479">
                  Robert 
                  Darby 
               <interp inst="t17520408-57-person479" type="surname" value="Darby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-57-person479" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520408-57-person479" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's bed, I concealed them in a necessary-house at Gravesend, I told the prisoner of them, he said he would go and look for them for the safety of his brother; he went, and returned, and said, he could not find them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I acted a little inadvertently, in order to preserve the reputation of my family, and save my brother's life. I should be glad to know whether or as any one here would not have done the same in such a case.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520408-57-verdict296" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520408-57-verdict296" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>But detained to be tried upon another indictment.</p>
            </div1>
