<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17510911-57">
               <interp inst="t17510911-57" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510911-57" type="year" value="1751"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510911-57" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17510911"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17510911-57" type="date" value="17510911"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17510911-57-off271-c364" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-57-defend471 t17510911-57-off271 t17510911-57-verdict276"></join>
         
               <p>532. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17510911-57-defend471" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Adkins 
                  <interp inst="t17510911-57-defend471" type="surname" value="Adkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-57-defend471" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-57-defend471" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17510911-57-off271" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510911-57-off271" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-57-off271" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               committing a rape upon the body of 
                     <persName id="t17510911-57-victim472" type="victimName">
                        Catharine, <rs id="t17510911-57-viclabel272" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-57-victim472 t17510911-57-viclabel272"></join>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-57-person473 t17510911-57-viclabel272"></join> of 
                           <persName id="t17510911-57-person473" type="victimName">
                              Thomas 
                              Kensey 
                           <interp inst="t17510911-57-person473" type="surname" value="Kensey"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17510911-57-person473" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17510911-57-person473" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                           <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-57-off271 t17510911-57-person473"></join>
                        </persName>
                        
                        <interp inst="t17510911-57-victim472" type="surname" value="Kensey"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510911-57-victim472" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17510911-57-victim472" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-57-off271 t17510911-57-victim472"></join>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17510911-57-cd273" type="crimeDate">July 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-57-off271 t17510911-57-cd273"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17510911-57-person474">
                  Catharine 
                  Kensey 
               <interp inst="t17510911-57-person474" type="surname" value="Kensey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-57-person474" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-57-person474" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a married woman, and my husband's name is 
               <persName id="t17510911-57-person475">
                  Thomas 
                  Kensey 
               <interp inst="t17510911-57-person475" type="surname" value="Kensey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-57-person475" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-57-person475" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My friends are dead, and I came up from the country to live with my aunt, Mrs. Bartlet, in <placeName id="t17510911-57-crimeloc274">Shoreditch</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17510911-57-crimeloc274" type="placeName" value="Shoreditch"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17510911-57-crimeloc274" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-57-off271 t17510911-57-crimeloc274"></join>.</p>
               <p>Counsel. When was you married?</p>
               <p>Kensey. On the second of May last, and we took lodgings in about three weeks time after at Mr. Sturt's, a baker in Shoreditch.</p>
               <p>Counsel. What is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. He is a <rs id="t17510911-57-deflabel275" type="occupation">master carpenter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17510911-57-defend471 t17510911-57-deflabel275"></join>.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Where does he live?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. He lives two doors from where I lodge.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you charge him with?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. On the 18th of July last, between nine and ten at night, I was going by his door from my lodgings; my husband was gone to his work, being a journeyman baker. The prisoner shoved me into his house.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Did he say any thing to you?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. He did not say any thing to me.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Was any body by?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. No, there was no body there but his brother, whom he ordered to shut up the street-door and go to bed; which he did.</p>
               <p>Q. What happened then?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. He blowed out the candle directly.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was he standing when he shoved you in?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. He was standing in the street before his own door. The first place is a carpenter's shop, and he shoved me through that into the kitchen, keeping his hands round my waste till he had got me there. I went backwards all the way.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the middle door shut?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. No, Sir, it was not.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he do to you?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. He - me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he throw you down?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. No.</p>
               <p>Counsel. What, not upon a table?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. No.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Not upon a chair?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. No, neither of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you cry out?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. I did not. I had no power.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was this after you was in his room?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. It was about a quarter of an hour after, for he staid while his brother was got out of the way.</p>
               <p>Q. What was he doing the time before his brother went to bed?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. He was standing by the dresser, where he pushed me first.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Did he undo his breeches?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. He did, in about a quarter of an hour after I was in the kitchen.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say to you?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. He said he would lie with me.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you say?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. I said he should not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you resist him?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. I had not strength to do any thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any marks or bruises?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. I had none.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you hurt?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. I was not hurt at all.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you come away?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. I staid there all night, after he had laid with me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go to bed with him?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. No, Sir, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did not you go home sooner?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. I was afraid to go out, because I heard some people about the door, all night, talking, and he said I should not go whilst they staid there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he aim to lie with you after that?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. No, he did not, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go to sleep there?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. No, Sir, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What time next morning did you go out?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. I did not go out till next morning day light; I believe it was between five and six o'clock.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175109110034"></xptr>Q. How came it you did not call out to them people for help?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. If they had been honest people they would have wanted to open the door.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you go when you went out?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. I went to Mrs. Hyde's, a cook-woman's shop.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell her what he had done to you?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you stay there?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. I staid there three hours. Mrs. Jones, my uncle's servant, came and fetched me home. My husband sent her.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you chuse to go to the cook-woman's house?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. Because I did not like to go to Mr. Sturt's ; for he said I should not come in there. I went to Mrs. Jones's house, and there I told her the prisoner had forcibly lain with me.</p>
               <p>Cross examined.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell her the same day?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. I did, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know 
               <persName id="t17510911-57-person476">
                  Mary 
                  Fox 
               <interp inst="t17510911-57-person476" type="surname" value="Fox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-57-person476" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-57-person476" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. Yes, I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not she in this house that night?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. I will take my oath she was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you tell 
               <persName id="t17510911-57-person477">
                  Mary 
                  Fox 
               <interp inst="t17510911-57-person477" type="surname" value="Fox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-57-person477" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-57-person477" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Mrs. Morse, Mrs. Sturt, and 
               <persName id="t17510911-57-person478">
                  Mary 
                  Hyde 
               <interp inst="t17510911-57-person478" type="surname" value="Hyde"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-57-person478" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17510911-57-person478" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , there was no harm done to you?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not you going up into the prisoner's bed-chamber, had not his brother-in-law pulled you back again?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. He did not make me come down, neither did I attempt to get up.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Where did you sit down after this mighty affair was over?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. I sat down by the dresser in the kitchen, and continued sitting there till I went away in the morning.</p>
               <p>Counsel. How high is the dresser?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. It was not very high.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Was this mischief done as you was standing?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. It was.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Do not you know, that had you made a small resistance in that position you was in, it would have been impossible for him to have committed a rape upon you?</p>
               <p>No Answer.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Is Mr. Adkins a married man?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. He is.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Where was his wife at that time?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. She was gone into the country then.</p>
               <p>Counsel. How do you know that?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. I saw her set out.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Where was the prisoner all night?</p>
               <p>C. Kensey. He was standing against the dresser near me.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Jones. I live across the street from where she lodges; the day after this thing was done, the woman came to my house, after dinner her husband came to my house, and desired I would go to her at the cook's shop, and tell her there was one at my house wanted to speak to her; there I found her crying; and when she came I left her husband and her together; he was very angry with her; presently Mrs. Laurence came, then she and I went in together, she told us she was going for some vinegar, and pepper, to eat with some cucumbers, and he stood at his own door; that he clap'd his two hands upon her, and shov'd her into the kitchen, then he shov'd her up to the dresser, and ordered his brother to go to bed; then he blew the candle out, she told us no more. This I know, it is the parting her husband, and she, and will be for ever.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Laurence. The next day I went to her, where she was at her lodgings, at Mrs. Jones's, about one o'clock; she told me between nine and ten o'clock she was going for some vinegar, and pepper, for some cucumbers, and he shov'd her in, and blow'd the candle out; she did not say a word what he did, after the candle was out; neither did I ask her.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17510911-57-verdict276" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17510911-57-verdict276" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
