<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17541023-12">
               <interp inst="t17541023-12" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541023-12" type="year" value="1754"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541023-12" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17541023"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17541023-12" type="date" value="17541023"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17541023-12-off55-c70" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-12-defend90 t17541023-12-off55 t17541023-12-verdict58"></join>
         
               <p>477. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17541023-12-defend90" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Cottom 
                  <interp inst="t17541023-12-defend90" type="surname" value="Cottom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-12-defend90" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-12-defend90" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17541023-12-off55" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17541023-12-off55" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-12-off55" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing one bay gelding. val. 30 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17541023-12-victim92" type="victimName">
                     Ralph 
                     Burton 
                  <interp inst="t17541023-12-victim92" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-12-victim92" type="given" value="Ralph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-12-victim92" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-12-off55 t17541023-12-victim92"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17541023-12-viclabel56" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-12-victim92 t17541023-12-viclabel56"></join> 
                  <rs id="t17541023-12-cd57" type="crimeDate">July 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-12-off55 t17541023-12-cd57"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541023-12-person93">
                  Thomas 
                  Twells 
               <interp inst="t17541023-12-person93" type="surname" value="Twells"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-12-person93" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-12-person93" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The steward of Major Burton ordered me to take and put in the stable his cropt bay gelding. on the 19th of July, which I did. I am the Major's servant. I entrusted the prisoner with the key of the stable at 11 o'clock, to feed this horse at 12.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you known the prisoner?</p>
               <p>T. Twells. He had been with me three weeks before. I miss'd the prisoner and the key. I was obliged to break open the stable door, and found the horse was gone. I was told by an ass-man that the prisoner was riding on him towards Hounslow; I went, and by making enquiry upon the road found the gelding at Belsound, at the Black Dog, the house of one Pryer. The prisoner was then taken up, and had before a justice of the peace.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17541023-12-person94">
                  Edward 
                  Pryer 
               <interp inst="t17541023-12-person94" type="surname" value="Pryer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-12-person94" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17541023-12-person94" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner came to my house the 20th of July, about six o'clock; he asked for a dram of anniseed, after that he called for a pint of beer; he got off his horse; the ostler cleaned him; the horse sweat prodigiously; I asked him whose horse it was, and he said it was one 'Squire Buckley's, and that he was going to Salsbury to sell him, being ordered by the 'Squire so to do. I asked how the 'Squire came to trust him to sell him? he said he would sell him to me if I would buy him; I examined the horse, to see if he was lame or ailed ought, and found he was in health and sound. I asked him what he asked for the horse? he said 10 guineas; I then thought he stole him; I asked him if he'd take 5, and he said he would take 5 guineas and a half; then I gave him a guinea earnest, and said if he could prove he came honestly by him I would give him the rest, if not, I would take him before a justice of the peace. Then he said he brought him from the stable at the King's Arms in Swallow Street, and (upon my threatening him thus) he said if I would give him another guinea he would grab out his business. Then I charged a constable with him, and had him before 'Squire Goodchild, at legton. He told the justice he brought the horse from the King's Arms in Swallow Street. The justice desired I would go and find if there was any truth in that; and take him back till I returned, and then bring him again for his re-examination. I went; and when I came back again this Twells, the groom, and another man were in pursuit of the prisoner, and had got him at my house. The next day we went with him to the justice's, there the prisoner confess'd the whole of taking the horse out the stable, and I took the key out of his pocket; there his mittimus was made.</p>
               <p>Archiba'd Trumble. I went along with Major Burton's groom to - and was at the taking of the prisoner into custody. on Saturday the 21st of July, and heard him confess taking the horse out of the stable, and riding away with him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I leave it to the mercy of the court.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17541023-12-verdict58" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17541023-12-verdict58" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17541023-12-punish59" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17541023-12-punish59" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17541023-12-defend90 t17541023-12-punish59"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
