<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17591205-32">
               <interp inst="t17591205-32" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591205-32" type="year" value="1759"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591205-32" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17591205"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17591205-32" type="date" value="17591205"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17591205-32-off163-c255" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-32-defend316 t17591205-32-off163 t17591205-32-verdict166"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17591205-32-off163-c256" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-32-defend320 t17591205-32-off163 t17591205-32-verdict166"></join>
         
               <p>35. 36. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17591205-32-defend316" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Mary 
                     Edwards 
                  , otherwise 
                     Sarah 
                     Mac Duel 
                  
               <interp inst="t17591205-32-defend316" type="surname" value="Edwards Mac Duel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-32-defend316" type="given" value="Mary Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-32-defend316" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17591205-32-defend320" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Brown 
                  <interp inst="t17591205-32-defend320" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-32-defend320" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-32-defend320" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for a conspiracy, in <rs id="t17591205-32-off163" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17591205-32-off163" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-32-off163" type="offenceSubcategory" value="extortion"></interp>
               attempting to charge 
                     
                        <persName id="t17591205-32-victim322" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Wintle 
                        <interp inst="t17591205-32-victim322" type="surname" value="Wintle"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17591205-32-victim322" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17591205-32-victim322" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-32-off163 t17591205-32-victim322"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   with the crime of adultery, with an intent to get unlawfully a large sum of money into their hands
            </rs>, <rs id="t17591205-32-cd164" type="crimeDate">Sept. 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-32-off163 t17591205-32-cd164"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17591205-32-person323">
                  Thomas 
                  Wintle 
               <interp inst="t17591205-32-person323" type="surname" value="Wintle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-32-person323" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-32-person323" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the Poultry.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>Wintle. I am a <rs id="t17591205-32-viclabel165" type="occupation">goldsmith</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17591205-32-victim322 t17591205-32-viclabel165"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you a married man?</p>
               <p>Wintle. I am; I have been married these four years.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you live with your wife?</p>
               <p>Wintle. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know either of the prisoners at the bar ?</p>
               <p>Wintle. I never saw either of them till they brought the letters to my shop.</p>
               <p>Q. Who brought them?</p>
               <p>Wintle. Edwards brought the first?</p>
               <p>Q. When?</p>
               <p>Wintle. On the 10th of September last, in the evening, about nine o'clock, but I did not see her face, for she had got a bonnet over her face. She has since acknowledged that she was the person who gave me the letter.</p>
               <p>Q. In what manner did she come?</p>
               <p>Wintle. She rang at the door, to which I went, and she gave me the letter. I said, who is this for? She said, if you open it, you will know, clapped it in my hand, and ran away.</p>
               <p>Q. What direction was on the letter?</p>
               <p>Wintle. There was none at all; this is it. [He delivers in a letter.]</p>
               <p>It is read to this purport:</p>
               <p>"Sir, I should be glad to see you at Mrs. Sherron's,</p>
               <p>"a chandler's shop, in Little NewportStreet,</p>
               <p>"the corner of a court, near Cranbourn Alley,</p>
               <p>"up one pair of stairs, at Mrs. Brown's,</p>
               <p>"Your's, 
               <persName id="t17591205-32-person324">
                  Mary 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17591205-32-person324" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-32-person324" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-32-person324" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ."</p>
               <p>[On one side was wrote 
               <persName id="t17591205-32-person325">
                  Sally 
                  Mac Duel 
               <interp inst="t17591205-32-person325" type="surname" value="Mac Duel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-32-person325" type="given" value="Sally"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-32-person325" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .]</p>
               <p>Wintle. That on the side the constable wrote. After she was taken up, she acknowledged her name was 
               <persName id="t17591205-32-person326">
                  Sally 
                  Mac Duel 
               <interp inst="t17591205-32-person326" type="surname" value="Mac Duel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-32-person326" type="given" value="Sally"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-32-person326" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , so he put it on the same letter.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go in consequence of this letter?</p>
               <p>Wintle. No; I took no notice of it, but shew'd it to several gentlemen who came to my shop. I thought it came from some common prostitute.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you receive any other letter?</p>
               <p>Wintle. I did, on the 18th of September.</p>
               <p>Q. Who brought that?</p>
               <p>Wintle. Brown, otherwise Everitt, brought it; she came into my shop between eight and nine in the evening, and pulled two tea spoons out of her pocket, saying, do you buy old spoons; I said yes, and went to weigh them. She said you need not weigh them, for I have got some other business with you, and gave me this letter (producing one.)</p>
               <p>The letter read to this purport:</p>
               <p>"Sir, I hope you remember the time you met</p>
               <p>"me in Morefields, the time of the princess of</p>
               <p>"Orange's death; that I proved with child, and</p>
               <p>"went into the country to my friends, till I could</p>
               <p>"hide my condition no longer; and as I draw</p>
               <p>"near my time, I hope you will assist me, and I</p>
               <p>"shall for ever be bound to pray for you; if you</p>
               <p>"please, come to Mrs. Sherron's, a chandler's-shop,</p>
               <p>"in Little-Newport-Street, the corner of a</p>
               <p>"court, near Cranbourn Alley, up one pair of</p>
               <p>"stairs, at Mrs. Brown's."</p>
               <p>I read it, and said, what do you mean by bringing me such a letter as this; she said, give yourself no such airs, for there is the girl at the door, that you got with child; upon that I called my wife down stairs, and then said to the prisoner Brown, does this letter belong to you, I know nothing of it; then she said it is Mrs Edwards's, and called her in; I said to my wife, here is a girl come to accuse me of geting her with child, whom I never saw in my life. Then I sent my girl for a constable.</p>
               <p>Q. What did Edwards say when she came in?</p>
               <p>Wintle. She said I was the person that got her with child. The constable came, and I asked him what I must do; he said, take them before my Lord-mayor, but we found he was not in the way; then I told the constable, if he would put them in the compter I'd bear him harmless. The constable asked her her name; she said she was with child by me, and her name was 
               <persName id="t17591205-32-person327">
                  Mac 
                  Duel 
               <interp inst="t17591205-32-person327" type="surname" value="Duel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-32-person327" type="given" value="Mac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17591205-32-person327" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; then he clap'd that down in the letter. Brown said she could get bail. In going to the watch-house a fellow jostled against the constable, and Edwards made her escape. As soon as I had called my wife, Brown said, take notice how long you detain us. Upon this I imagined she pretended to bring an action.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175912050029"></xptr> The other said to the constable, what do you detain me for, I fancy I can find the other at the door. They went, and found the other that had gotten away, opposite the door, on the other side of the way, at the corner of the Old-Jury; then he brought them both to the shop, when Brown said she was not concerned, only in bringing the letter. When we were going to the watch-house, a man jostled the constable and Edwards got away a second time, but we kept the other. About two o'clock came in one Higgins, a lawyer's clerk, who gave bail for Brown's coming in the morning; she was to bring the other with her, but came without her, and said Edwards was waiting at an alehouse in Fleet street, so the constable went and found her there; then they were both brought to my shop, and we went before the present Lord-mayor, who committed them both to the compter, and bound me over to prosecute them.</p>

               <p>Q. Did Edwards say when she was got with child?</p>
               <p>Wintle. She said, that at the time of the princess of Orange's death I met her in Morefields, in the month of February, took her to a tavern, between eight and nine o'clock, was with her an hour and a half, treated her, was concerned with her twice, and gave her four shillings, and that I would have treated her with a coach home; that then she lived with a relation in Chiswell street, and refused the coach, but watched me home, to know where I lived. My Lord-mayor said, it was very odd, if that was true, you should never call upon the gentleman till now, what did you do with yourself before this time. She said that six weeks before she lived in Leicester-street, after that in Kensington, but had been removed into Parliament-street. His lordship asked her where she lived before that, but she made no answer to that. Then the other prisoner Brown was called, and asked how she came to bring such a letter to me; she said she knew the girl two or three years ago, by drawing beer at an alehouse, upon which she brought the letter for her, and that she had helped her to wash for three weeks.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether or no the charge that this letter imports is any part of it truth?</p>
               <p>Wintle. No, it is not, not a word of it; I never saw either of the parties in my life, till they came to my shop, as I have mentioned.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she mention the tavern or sign where she said you were together?</p>
               <p>Wintle. No, she said she did not know the tavern nor the sign.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you ever in Morefields with her?</p>
               <p>Wintle. I never was in Morefields at such time as she speaks of in my life, nor never was in company with her in my life; I never saw either of them before.</p>
               <p>Q. Is this whole accusation, contained in the letter, true or false?</p>
               <p>Wintle. It is every part of it false; I never knew either of them in my life.</p>
               <p>As nothing could be charged upon Brown, otherwise Everitt, but carrying a letter, and the fixing it upon the other, were she ever so guilty, would not be sufficient to prove this indictment, for no person can be said to conspire alone, they were both <rs id="t17591205-32-verdict166" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17591205-32-verdict166" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
