<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17520219-49">
               <interp inst="t17520219-49" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520219-49" type="year" value="1752"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520219-49" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17520219"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17520219-49" type="date" value="17520219"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17520219-49-off241-c365" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520219-49-defend451 t17520219-49-off241 t17520219-49-verdict243"></join>
         
               <p>185. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17520219-49-defend451" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Lewis 
                  <interp inst="t17520219-49-defend451" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-defend451" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-defend451" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17520219-49-deflabel240" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520219-49-defend451 t17520219-49-deflabel240"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17520219-49-off241" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-off241" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-off241" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               making a certain forged and counterfeit power of attorney, and for uttering it knowing it to be forged
            </rs>, <rs id="t17520219-49-cd242" type="crimeDate">Nov. 20</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520219-49-off241 t17520219-49-cd242"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>Mr. Siden. I am clerk to Mess. Masson and Stanhope, they are agents for the Hector man of war, for prizes taken in June 1747, which we call the St. Domingo fleet.</p>
               <p>Q. What money was due to 
               <persName id="t17520219-49-person452">
                  Richard 
                  Tingle 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person452" type="surname" value="Tingle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person452" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person452" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a Marine on board the Exeter?</p>
               <p>Siden. (He produces a book.) There appears to be due to him 25 l. 19 s. on the first dividend; the 2d dividend is 3 s. and 6 d. he is noted dead in the book.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520219-49-person453">
                  Thomas 
                  Bennet 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person453" type="surname" value="Bennet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person453" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person453" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was a warrant-officer on board the Exeter, I knew 
               <persName id="t17520219-49-person454">
                  Richard 
                  Tingle 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person454" type="surname" value="Tingle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person454" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person454" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he was killed in the October fleet 1747.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175202190031"></xptr>Q. How old was he?</p>
               <p>Bennet. He was about 23 or 24 Years of age.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520219-49-person455">
                  Edmund 
                  Mason 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person455" type="surname" value="Mason"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person455" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person455" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am agent for the prize-money for the King's ship the Hector, there came a woman, in the name of 
               <persName id="t17520219-49-person456">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Tingle 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person456" type="surname" value="Tingle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person456" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person456" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , to me at the navy-office, with this administration, ( holding one in his hand) telling me she was the daughter and only surviving child of 
               <persName id="t17520219-49-person457">
                  Richard 
                  Tingle 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person457" type="surname" value="Tingle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person457" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person457" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , late a Marine o n board the Exeter, and that thereby she became entitled to his share of prize-money; upon which I examined the books, and found his money amounted together to the sum of 26 l. but as I observed that share had lain undemanded for three years, I was induced to ask her several questions; one was, how she came not to know of her father's death sooner? she gave me no account of her father's death but this, she said she had met a man in the street, who had told her her father was dead, and that he had paid for the administration, and sent her there; she went away and no claim was made till the September following, then I had a letter from an attorney Mr. Preoham of Barnard's Inn, who made use of her name, and said, unless I paid her the money, he was to file a bill in Chancery against me: I wrote him for answer the reasons I had to suspect it a forgery, so the thing dropt for two or three weeks: in the month of October, Predham's clerk came to me, with the prisoner at the bar, who said she was Aunt to 
               <persName id="t17520219-49-person458">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Tingle 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person458" type="surname" value="Tingle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person458" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person458" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             who was then at Rochester, and that she came to demand the prize-money for her Neice; she called the deceased her brother, told me of his death, and how she came to know of it, and produced a certificate from the commissary: from her account of herself and her Neice I was apt to think the thing was really so; she said her Neice staid at Rochester to look after children, the while she came for her money: I said if her Neice could not come, she should make a power of attorney to her, and get it under the hand of the Mayor of Rochester, and I should make no objection to paying the money; she seem'd satisfied, and went away, I saw her again in a few days with the clerk, and she gave me a sort of a rough draft of an affidavit, describing herself Aunt to 
               <persName id="t17520219-49-person459">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Tingle 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person459" type="surname" value="Tingle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person459" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person459" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and that she was the only child of 
               <persName id="t17520219-49-person460">
                  Richard 
                  Tingle 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person460" type="surname" value="Tingle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person460" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person460" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , deceas'd; and desired to know if that would do; then I alter'd it myself to make it as strong as possible; then she went away determining, as she told me, to go to her Neice at Rochester, and make oath, &amp;c. asI desired her to bring a letter of attorney, she said she could and would, in the beginning of last November she came to me again, with this clerk, and said, now she had brought all the papers, and hoped I should have no objection to the payment of the money : she brought this affidavit ( holding one in his hand ) which she own'd to be her own handwriting, and which she had sworn to; she also produced this letter of attorney; I asked if that was the work of 
               <persName id="t17520219-49-person461">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Tingle 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person461" type="surname" value="Tingle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person461" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person461" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , she said it was, saying it was her Neice's Mark (that is the mark to the letter of attorney ) she said she hoped I'd pay her the money then; I asked her where was her authority from her Neice? she told me the Mayor had promised to write me a private letter, and she left the paper in my hands: she repeated her solicitations frequently from that time, and to know if I had received a letter from the Mayor of Rochester, and was so extreamly solicitous as to say she thought I had received one, and kept it back, because I would not pay the money: then I said I would write a letter to the Mayor, and if I did not receive an answer before the 23d of November, I would pay her the money; I happened to hear it was all a piece of forgery: she came no more, and in two or three days after I found her under another name at the navy-office, and she was detected.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520219-49-person462">
                  Joseph 
                  Harwood 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person462" type="surname" value="Harwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person462" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person462" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am clerk to Mr. Predham: 
               <persName id="t17520219-49-person463">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Tingle 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person463" type="surname" value="Tingle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person463" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person463" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , or a woman in that name, had been at our office to receive prize-money, which she said was due to her father ; she brought an administration, and after that went to Rochester, and the prisoner came to us as her aunt, about the beginning of October, to receive the money for the use of her neice; as she called her, saying, 
               <persName id="t17520219-49-person464">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Tingle 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person464" type="surname" value="Tingle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person464" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person464" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was at her house. I had been at Mr. Mason's, on the 27th of September, to talk with him from 
               <persName id="t17520219-49-person465">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Tingle 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person465" type="surname" value="Tingle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person465" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person465" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , with a letter of attorney, which was brought by one Richardson, a waterman, to empower my master to take the money: the prisoner came the morning after; when she and I went to Mr. Mason's office in Talbot-Court, she said to Mr. Mason, that she hoped he'd pay her the money, for it was due to one 
               <persName id="t17520219-49-person466">
                  Richard 
                  Tingle 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person466" type="surname" value="Tingle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person466" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person466" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , her sister's husband, and that she was aunt to 
               <persName id="t17520219-49-person467">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Tingle 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person467" type="surname" value="Tingle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person467" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person467" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and was ready to make affidavit of it. I saw Mr. Mason correct the affidavit, and the prisoner sign it afterwards, at a publick house near London-bridge.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520219-49-person468">
                  Frederick 
                  Predham 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person468" type="surname" value="Predham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person468" type="given" value="Frederick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person468" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The first time I saw the prisoner was at my chambers, I can't tell the day of the month, some short time after the 18th of November, she said she came from Rochester to<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175202190032"></xptr> receive her Neice, Eliz. Tingle's, prize-money; one Henley, the niece, and a watchman, came together (see No. 392 in Cokayne's Mayoralty) I had received an affidavit also on the 10th of November; they left a letter of administration and a certificate on the 18th of November; the prisoner came about two or three days after, when I sent my servant with her to Mr. Mason's; after they came from Mr. Mason's I saw her sign the affidavit at the Dyer's-arms in Thames-street.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520219-49-person469">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Richardson 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person469" type="surname" value="Richardson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person469" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person469" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Castle-street by Long acre. The prisoner liv'd almost three quarters of a year next door to me: one Henley gave me the power of attorney, I believe it was about four months ago, at my lodgings in Castle-street, they called it an administration, to go to Mr. Mason's; it was on parchment: I went and demanded the money in the name of 
               <persName id="t17520219-49-person470">
                  Richard 
                  Tingle 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person470" type="surname" value="Tingle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person470" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person470" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            : my husband went with me a part of the way to shew me: when I came to the Navy-office I shewed the gentleman the things; he asked me many questions, one was what was my father's name, which I said I had forgot; he then told me if I did not go away about my business he'd charge an office with me. I went back and told Henley, who said he did not know what to do about it. I then told him I would have nothing more to do with the affair: upon which he took the things from me, and said he'd see for somebody to get the money: he came to our house some time after, and told me he had been in company with a lawyer that would take the thing in hand: after that I went with him to Mr. Predham's; he was not at home, but we saw his clerk; in the evening we went again, and found Mr Predham; he asked me if I was the real daughter of 
               <persName id="t17520219-49-person471">
                  Richard 
                  Tingle 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person471" type="surname" value="Tingle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person471" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person471" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I answered yes: then said he, I'll have the money of the gentleman. I never went after I left the things. Mr. Henley ordered the prisoner, I and my husband to go to Rochester about a month after; we were to take a lodging there and stay some time, that we might be known by the Inhabitants, to be able to answer, if there should be any questions about her living there, and then we were to have the power of attorney done. When we were there the prisoner said she would not go to have the Mayor see her face, so she staid at the Blackmoor's head, and my husband and I went; for she was to go after to make an affidavit that she was my aunt. My husband and I carried the letter of attorney to the mayor; it was read there, and I put my mark to it at the bottom before the Mayor: then the prisoner desired me to go no more; my husband put a name to it as a witness, but it was not his own name, it was 
               <persName id="t17520219-49-person472">
                  James 
                  Low 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person472" type="surname" value="Low"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person472" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person472" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; after that the mayor wrote his name. When we came back the prisoner took it and said it would do very well: I believe we came to town that same night: then Richardson and she wrote a letter at home, and put that power in it, as though my aunt had sent it up to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Is the prisoner your aunt?</p>
               <p>E. Richardson. No; she is not a-kin to me: I have been married to Richardson almost three years.</p>
               <p>Q. How old are you?</p>
               <p>E. Richardson. I am twenty-four years of age next 22d of June.</p>
               <p>The power of attorney was read, made to 
               <persName id="t17520219-49-person473">
                  Frederick 
                  Predham 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person473" type="surname" value="Predham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person473" type="given" value="Frederick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person473" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , as her lawful attorney, in the common form, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Signed 
               <persName id="t17520219-49-person474">
                  Andrew 
                  Long 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person474" type="surname" value="Long"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person474" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person474" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Mayor.</p>
               <p>The Mark of Elizabeth + Tingle.</p>
               <p>Witness 
               <persName id="t17520219-49-person475">
                  James 
                  Low 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person475" type="surname" value="Low"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person475" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person475" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Who put the seal near your mark?</p>
               <p>E. Richardson. The mayor put it on, and I took it off.</p>
               <p>The Affidavit read.</p>
               <p>'' 
               <persName id="t17520219-49-person476">
                  Ann 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person476" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person476" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person476" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of the city of Rochester, '' maketh oath, that 
               <persName id="t17520219-49-person477">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Tingle 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person477" type="surname" value="Tingle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person477" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person477" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , now '' with me, is the only administratrix to Richard '' Tingle, late on board, &amp;c. &amp;c.''</p>
               <p>Signed 
               <persName id="t17520219-49-person478">
                  Ann 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person478" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person478" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person478" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Sworn before me Andrew Long, Mayor.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know 
               <persName id="t17520219-49-person479">
                  Richard 
                  Tingle 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person479" type="surname" value="Tingle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person479" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person479" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>E. Richardson. No, I don't know any thing of such a man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17520219-49-person480">
                  Samuel 
                  Jepson 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person480" type="surname" value="Jepson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person480" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person480" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew 
               <persName id="t17520219-49-person481">
                  Richard 
                  Tingle 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person481" type="surname" value="Tingle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person481" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person481" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; he belong'd to the Exeter man of war, and was 'prentice with my brother.</p>
               <p>Q. How old might he be was he now living?</p>
               <p>Jepson. He was about thirteen years of age eight years ago; he is dead; his father is living, and entitled to the money.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think he was old enough to have a daughter as old as the last witness?</p>
               <p>Jepson. It is impossible; besides he never was married.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Richardson told me her father was dead, and she had administered and made a power of attorney to Mr. Predham; that Mr.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175202190033"></xptr> Mason would not be satisfied without an affidavit made; that her father had been dead three years, and there was none left but she.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17520219-49-verdict243" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-verdict243" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17520219-49-punish244" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-punish244" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-punish244" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="respited"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17520219-49-defend451 t17520219-49-punish244"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The prisoner is the same person who appeared an evidence for 
               <persName id="t17520219-49-person482">
                  John 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person482" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person482" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person482" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , by the name of 
               <persName id="t17520219-49-person483">
                  Margaret 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person483" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person483" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person483" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and was committed for perjury, (see No. 14, in Pennant's Mayoralty) and in the name of 
               <persName id="t17520219-49-person484">
                  Mary 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17520219-49-person484" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person484" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17520219-49-person484" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , to swear against J. Coppinger, (see No. 616, in Blachford's Mayoralty.)</p>
            </div1>
