<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17550910-30">
               <interp inst="t17550910-30" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550910-30" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550910-30" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550910"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17550910-30" type="date" value="17550910"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17550910-30-off145-c216" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550910-30-defend271 t17550910-30-off145 t17550910-30-verdict150"></join>
         
               <p>333. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17550910-30-defend271" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Billion 
                  <interp inst="t17550910-30-defend271" type="surname" value="Billion"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-30-defend271" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-30-defend271" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17550910-30-off145" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550910-30-off145" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-30-off145" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one silk-purse, value 6 d. and 200 guineas in gold, the goods and money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17550910-30-victim273" type="victimName">
                           Stephen 
                           Rimbolt 
                        <interp inst="t17550910-30-victim273" type="surname" value="Rimbolt"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550910-30-victim273" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550910-30-victim273" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550910-30-off145 t17550910-30-victim273"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling-house
            </rs> of the said Stephen , <rs id="t17550910-30-cd146" type="crimeDate">July 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550910-30-off145 t17550910-30-cd146"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-30-person274">
                  Stephen 
                  Rimbolt 
               <interp inst="t17550910-30-person274" type="surname" value="Rimbolt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-30-person274" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-30-person274" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . I live in <placeName id="t17550910-30-crimeloc147">Great St. Andrew's-street, Seven-dials</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17550910-30-crimeloc147" type="placeName" value="Great St. Andrew's-street, Seven-dials"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550910-30-crimeloc147" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550910-30-off145 t17550910-30-crimeloc147"></join>, and am a <rs id="t17550910-30-viclabel148" type="occupation">clockmaker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550910-30-victim273 t17550910-30-viclabel148"></join>, the prisoner was my <rs id="t17550910-30-deflabel149" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550910-30-defend271 t17550910-30-deflabel149"></join>. On the third of July, I went into the parlour, I saw my wife in a hurry, she said I am affrighted, I have lost my money. I said be careful, see whether it is not amongst the cloaths; she looked, and said it is gone, the prisoner at the bar absented himself that day. I was in a prodigious dilemma; I took post-chaise about three in the afternoon, and with a friend, went down for Dover, to see for him. I went post to Gravesend , and found when the boat came in, he was not in it. The next morning I took a post-chaise there, and went down to Dover. When I came to Sitingbourne , I had intelligence of him; and when I came to Dover, I found him on board a vessel bound to France. We took him on shore, and brought him to a publick house, where we pulled the prisoner's boots off, there we found part of the money.</p>
               <p>Q. What money did you lose?</p>
               <p>Rimbolt . I lost two hundred and twenty guineas, and found upon the prisoner one hundred and eighty guineas or pounds, I know not which, for I was in a great confusion. We brought him back to London, and as he was a young man, I was tender, and would willingly have forgiven him, and let him go; but after that, I was told I must prosecute.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure it was your money you found upon the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Rimbolt. By the particular pieces, I think it must be mine. I advertised two five guinea pieces, a two guinea piece, two quarters of a guinea, and an old Jacobus. I can sware to the purse the money was in, that I found upon the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was it taken from?</p>
               <p>Rimbolt. I imagin'd it to be in the closet, where the money used to be.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner confess any thing?</p>
               <p>Rimbolt. I charg'd him with taking the money, and he acknowledg'd it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he acknowledge the money was your property?</p>
               <p>Rimbolt . He did, and beg'd I would be favourable to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell him how much money you had lost.</p>
         
               <p>The Second Part of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days .</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17550910-30">
                  <interp inst="t17550910-30" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550910-30" type="year" value="1755"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550910-30" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17550910"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17550910-30" type="date" value="17550910"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175509100021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 10th, Thursday the 11th, Friday the 12th, Saturday the 13th, Monday the 15th, and Tuesday the 16th of SEPTEMBER,</p>
                  <p>In the Twenty-ninth Year of His MAJESTY's Reign. NUMBER VII. PART II. for the YEAR 1755. Being the Seventh SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of THE RIGHT HONOURABLE 
                  <persName id="t17550910-30-person275">
                     STEPHEN THEODORE 
                     JANSSEN 
                  <interp inst="t17550910-30-person275" type="surname" value="JANSSEN"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550910-30-person275" type="given" value="STEPHEN THEODORE"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17550910-30-person275" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Esq; LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by M. COOPER at the Globe, in Pater-noster Row. 1755.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175509100022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery held for the City of LONDON, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Rimbolt . I Did, and he said he had not so much; he said he did not know what was become of the twenty guineas; and when he delivered it up, he said there was all he had left, and the other he had laid out, which he would give me an account of in writing. He said he found it on a pair of breeches, by the side of the trunk; we were moving our goods to another house over the way , when we missed the money; it was lost from out of a trunk.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the trunk appear to have been opened by violence?</p>
               <p>Rimbolt. I cannot say it did; when we were coming with him to London, he came out of the chaise, and rode on horseback to St. George's-fields , there I let him go away; but when I came home, there were a number of people said, if I did not prosecute him, I was liable to be prosecuted, then I went and found him.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you find him?</p>
               <p>Rimbolt. I found him in White-chapel, he told me he should be there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear of the other forty guineas ?</p>
               <p>Rimbolt. No; I never did.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has the lad lived with you?</p>
               <p>Rimbolt . He has lived with me six years next October.</p>
               <p>Q. How has he behaved in the time he was with you?</p>
               <p>Rimbolt. I cannot say he has behav'd so well as I could wish, but he never wrong'd me before .</p>
               <p>Q. How long had this money been in that trunk?</p>
               <p>Rimbolt. It had been there a great many months.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you put it there?</p>
               <p>Rimbolt. No, I did not; I have seen my wife put it in, and take it out several times, she had the care of it; she went to it in my presence , and out of my presence.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you say how much money there was of your own knowledge?</p>
               <p>Rimbolt. I cannot say how much there was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner by, when you missed it?</p>
               <p>Rimbolt. He was in the house just before my wife discovered to me it was lost; he had been employ'd to move some of the things, my wife bid him take my cloaths, and carry them over to the other house that morning.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you say to him, to induce him to say that was your money?</p>
               <p>Rimbolt . He soon own'd it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell him, if he would confess, no harm should come to him?</p>
               <p>Rimbolt . I did tell him, that if he would make a genuine confession, I would forgive him; but when I came to town, I had reason to be more angry with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you sware that money you had from him, is your property?</p>
               <p>Rimbolt . I could know it by a particular guinea, (be produced it ) I think I have seen this guinea a thousand times.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you let him go?</p>
               <p>Rimbolt. Really , when I saw him on shipboard, I was affected at the sight of him. I was more griev'd perhaps than he was. I did<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175509100023"></xptr> say, I will do you no harm, he desir'd he might not be blown about the town as a common thief. Then he wanted to have his boots pull'd off and we found the money in them.</p>
               <p>Q Have not you said since, you did not believe he intended to steal it, and that you would assist him in giving him a character in Holland?</p>
               <p>Rimbolt . I never did tell him, I did not believe he stole it. I told him, if it was possible, I would send him over-sea, and would not prosecute him, without running the hazard of my life; and if he would let me have the other money, I would get him abroad if I could .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never say to any body else, you did not believe he had rob'd you?</p>
               <p>Rimbolt . No; I never did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-30-person276">
                  Frances 
                  Rimbolt 
               <interp inst="t17550910-30-person276" type="surname" value="Rimbolt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-30-person276" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-30-person276" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the prosecutor; there were two hundred and twenty guineas in the trunk with the Jacobus.</p>
               <p>C. Look at this crack'd guinea. (She looks at it.)</p>
               <p>Fr. Rimbolt. I can swear this very guinea was amongst the rest , I have had it thirteen years in the purse, it was amongst the money I lost. We were going out of that house, to a house over the way; he brought a bundle over the way, and ask'd where he must put it; I shew'd him; he put it down, and went back again; and as I was coming over the way, I met him coming again with a bundle of cloaths. I went directly to move my trunk, which was almost the last thing I had to move in the house. To the best of my knowledge I found it lock'd, it open'd as usual; I took out a little trunk, and look'd for my purse to put into it. I missed my purse and my money, the trunk had never been moved this twelve years. I opened all my cloaths, and shook them, but could not find my purse, my husband said, O Lord I am ruin'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether this boy ever saw you put money in it?</p>
               <p>Fr. Rimbolt . Yes; he did once. I have a value for his mother, I have lent her now and then a guinea , he had seen me go to the purse, and take out a guinea, two several times, to send by him to his mother.</p>
               <p>Q. What money was in the purse?</p>
               <p>Fr. Rimbolt. I cannot tell, but I know there was above a hundred pound; I call'd my other servant , and ask'd him if he had taken my purse ; he said he had not; then I said, where is the other? ( meaning the prisoner.) I found he was gone , we sent to his mother, she came and said, she knew nothing of him, and hearing him often say he would go to France, my husband went after him, and brought him home .</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know one 
               <persName id="t17550910-30-person277">
                  Samuel 
                  Foster 
               <interp inst="t17550910-30-person277" type="surname" value="Foster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-30-person277" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-30-person277" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Fr. Rimbolt. Yes; I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember you said to him, very likely you had taken it out and dropt it?</p>
               <p>Fr. Rimbolt. Likely I might.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he had opportunity since the time he saw your money, to go and open the trunk your money was in?</p>
               <p>Fr. Rimbolt. He has.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-30-person278">
                  Peter 
                  Toboyce 
               <interp inst="t17550910-30-person278" type="surname" value="Toboyce"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-30-person278" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-30-person278" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live not a great way from the prosecutor ; when he was rob'd , he came to my house, and told me of it, and desired my assistance. He drew up an advertisement, and left it with some friend to be put into the paper. We took coach, and went to the Borough, there took a post-chaise, and went directly to Gravesend. We staid there, thinking he would come down in the Gravesend-boat, but he did not. We took a post-chaise , and went directly for Dover. At Rochester we described the prisoner , but could not hear of him. When we came to Dover, we found him on board a ship; we took and brought him on shore into a publick house, there I tax'd him about the money; he seemed to deny it at first; after that. I told him his master would not hurt him, in case he would give him the money he had taken away, and his master told him to the same purport. Then the prisoner began to unstrap his boots, and said, he would deliver the money to his master within a trifle, that is ten or twelve pound, I cannot say which; he went to pull his boots off, but could not; then I said I will help you, accordingly I did; when they were off, the money was taken out and deliver'd into his master's possession.</p>
               <p>Q. How much was there of it?</p>
               <p>Toboyce . There were a hundred and fourscore guineas . We went into another room, and took a piece of paper, and I noted it down, and Mr. Rimbolt counted it . I think the prisoner made a little bill of what he had spent coming down to Dover. We brought him to Canterbury : he said I wish you would search me for my master's satisfaction; for there was twenty guineas missing besides what he had spent. I search'd him, but could find no more.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the whole of the money found upon him?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175509100024"></xptr>Toboyce . I did, there was 180 guineas.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe a crooked guinea?</p>
               <p>Toboyce . I cannot say I observed that. We came towards London, and I left them on Black-health . Being on horseback , I came faster than they could in the chaise. The prisoner had got on horseback at Canterbury, and rode from there to a house about six miles on this side Sitting-bourne . It was in the dead of the night, and he might have made his escape if he would.</p>
               <p>Cross examination .</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner acknowledge he had the money at first seeing you?</p>
               <p>Toboyce. At first he seem'd to be surprised, and when we asked him about the money , he said what money?</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body tell him he should not be prosecuted if he would discover where the money was?</p>
               <p>Toboyce . I said he should not be hurt.</p>
               <p>Q. Did his master say the same?</p>
               <p>Toboyce . He did, and the prisoner said upon that consideration he would deliver it up.</p>
               <p>Q. Who counted the money?</p>
               <p>Toboyce . Mr. Rimbolt counted it in his hat by single guineas, and when he came to 20, I noted 20 down, and there was a five guinea piece, and a two guinea piece, two quarters of guineas, and a Jacobus, besides the 180 guineas.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor . In what capacity was the prisoner with you ?</p>
               <p>Rimbolt. He was my apprentice.</p>
               <p>Q. What money had you with him?</p>
               <p>Rimbolt. I had no money with him; his friends were not able to give any. His mother is a poor woman, if she wanted a guinea or two, my wife has lent it her.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>When I had been into the closet, and was carrying these things cross the way, I suppose the purse was amongst the things, and dropt in the street , and at my returning back, I found the purse in the street, and put it in my pocket.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17550910-30-person279">
                  Samuel 
                  Foster 
               <interp inst="t17550910-30-person279" type="surname" value="Foster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-30-person279" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17550910-30-person279" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner 15 or 10 years.</p>
               <p>Q. How old is he?</p>
               <p>Foster. I believe him to be near 20 years of age ; I have known his master and mistress a good many years; the prisoner's character was always reckoned to be very good. I keep a sale shop the corner of Monmouth-street: I have a great many hundred pounds worth of goods in my shop, and the prisoner had egress and regress there. I had some conversation with his mistress the day after the fact was committed. She was at breakfast in her own house. I and another gentleman desired to know how the affair was? I asked her if the chest was broke open? She said no, it was not. She said she well recollected then that she had had a gentleman dined with her a day or two before that time , and that she had put her plate, spoons, and money all in one box in the chest. She went to fetch a silver spoon to use with soup at dinner, and in taking it out she heard the purse fall on the floor; and she went down and left it. So I said to her it was a very weak thing of you not to pick it up then. She said she had locked the closet door, and thought it safe, and a day or two after she gave him the key of the closet door, and sent him to remove the goods there, and to take the cloaths out of the closet.</p>
               <p>Q. How can you account for the prisoner's having 180 guineas about him?</p>
               <p>Foster. I cannot take upon me to say how he came by them.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Did you find the purse in his boots?</p>
               <p>Rimbolt. No, it was in his pocket.</p>
               <p>Knellam Dawson. I know the prisoner very well. I am a salesman in Monmouth-street.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Dawson. It has been that of a sober, sedate, good boy always; I looked upon him to be a good servant to his master. I was with Mr. Foster at his mistress's. Mr. Foster said, for God's sake in what manner was this money taken away? She said, I do not know how it was taken away, but I believe I dropt the purse, but where I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>There appeared 12 other witnesses, who spoke well of his character before this affair.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17550910-30-verdict150" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550910-30-verdict150" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17550910-30-punish151" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17550910-30-punish151" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17550910-30-defend271 t17550910-30-punish151"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
