<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640607-53">
               <interp inst="t17640607-53" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640607-53" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640607-53" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640607"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640607-53" type="date" value="17640607"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640607-53-off300-c347" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-53-defend458 t17640607-53-off300 t17640607-53-verdict304"></join>
         
               <p>379 (L) 
               <persName id="t17640607-53-defend458" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Jane 
                     Faulkner 
                  , <rs id="t17640607-53-deflabel298" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-53-defend458 t17640607-53-deflabel298"></join>, otherwise Jane, <rs id="t17640607-53-deflabel299" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-53-defend458 t17640607-53-deflabel299"></join> of 
                     Robert 
                     <rs id="t17640607-53-alias-7" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-53-defend458 t17640607-53-alias-7"></join>Hanks</rs>
                  
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-defend458" type="surname" value="Faulkner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-defend458" type="given" value="Jane Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-defend458" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17640607-53-off300" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-off300" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-off300" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing one tin box, value 2 d. 5 guineas and a half, and a pair of silver buttons with Mocha stones, value 12 d. the property of 
                     <persName id="t17640607-53-victim461" type="victimName">
                        Humphry 
                        Kelso 
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-victim461" type="surname" value="Kelso"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640607-53-victim461" type="given" value="Humphry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640607-53-victim461" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   , from Mary his wife, privately and secretly from her person
            </rs>. <rs id="t17640607-53-cd301" type="crimeDate">May 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-53-off300 t17640607-53-cd301"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
               
                  <persName id="t17640607-53-victim463" type="victimName">
                     Mary 
                     Kelso 
                  <interp inst="t17640607-53-victim463" type="surname" value="Kelso"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-victim463" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-victim463" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            . My husband's name is Humphry Kelso; we <rs id="t17640607-53-viclabel302" type="occupation">keep a public house</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-53-victim461 t17640607-53-viclabel302"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-53-victim463 t17640607-53-viclabel302"></join> under the <placeName id="t17640607-53-crimeloc303">piazzas at Billingsgate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640607-53-crimeloc303" type="placeName" value="piazzas at Billingsgate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640607-53-crimeloc303" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-53-off300 t17640607-53-crimeloc303"></join>. On the 10th of May the prisoner came to my house, and a beggar-woman along with her; she called for a pint of beer for the woman, and had a groat's worth of salmon to herself, and gave what she did not eat to the woman. She came to me, and asked me to give her change for a 5 s. 3 d. I kept my gold in a tin box; I had at that time 12 guineas in it: after I had put the 5 s. 3 d. in among the rest, I put it in my pocket: this is all that passed that day. She came again on the 16th; then she had a corded striped sack and petticoat, a flounced hat, and black satten cardinal on; she had two pints of beer; I was at dinner; she paid for the two pints of beer; there was nobody in the tap-room but she, and the maid, and I: she went out, and stood on the threshold of the door about a minute: there came a man in, and she followed him; he had a glass of shrub, and gave me a guinea to change; I changed it, and put the guinea in my tin box, and put my box in my pocket. Then she said, Pray, Madam, let me have a little of your good brandy. I said, How much? said she, A quartern; come and bring the bottle and glass, I want to speak to you. She was sitting at the corner of the table, in a corner; she pulled me to her, and got so close to me, close to the side where my pocket hung: she said, she wanted to have a little of my advice; I said, I did not know how to give advice: she got so close, I could not move my hand. I poured her out a glass of brandy; she took it; then she began to talk to me: she told me, one Captain Young, belonging to the Marquis of Granby, that was quartered in the north of Scotland,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176406070033"></xptr> had decoyed a niece of her's, under pretence of marrying her, and had got her with child, and had now married a milliner in Cornhill. She wanted to know if she could sue the captain for half the fortune; she said, she had sent an attorney's letter to him. I told her, as her kinswoman had been so weak as to let him get her with child, I thought she could not avail herself in the affair. She went out, and left me sitting there; she turned round a little table, and went out. I put my hand in my pocket, to put a sixpence in, and missed my box. I asked my girl which way she went, and said she had picked my pocket of my tin box; I was informed, that she turned round upon the quay, and went like lightening.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was this?</p>
               <p>M. Kelso. This was a quarter after f our in the afternoon: she had said to me, the time she was at my house before, that she lived in East-Smithfield. I went in pursuit of her; I enquired about; I was told there was such a woman went along in a black bombazeen sack and petticoat: I offered a guinea reward for taking her: my son-in-law took her in Tooley-street, and brought her into an ale-house there, the sign of the Two Brewers. I was sent for; I asked her, how she could be such a Judas to serve me so? I was there told, she was going into a pawnbroker's with a sack and petticoat, and a white fustian riding-habit, to pawn: I said, These things you bought with my money; She said, I did; and when you come to the Old Bailey, I'll make a fool of you; for I have law at my fingers ends. I said, I could swear to your cloaths you had on when you robbed me, which were a narrow striped sack and petticoat: I have the sack and petticoat here to be produced.</p>
               <p>Q. What day was this that she was taken?</p>
               <p>M. Kelso. She robbed me on the Thursday, and she was not taken till Saturday.</p>
               <p>Q. What money did you lose?</p>
               <p>M. Kelso. I lost five guineas and a half, and a pair of Mocha buttons, all in the tin box.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever get your box or buttons again?</p>
               <p>M. Kelso. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Has not this woman been several times at your house?</p>
               <p>M. Kelso. She has.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was at your house at this last time, besides the prisoner?</p>
               <p>M. Kelso. There was nobody but she, my maid, and myself; my maid was washing the pots; after she was going out of the house, a man came up to the bar, and had half a quartern of rum-shrub, and she followed him.</p>
               <p>Q. What day was she taken up on?</p>
               <p>M. Kelso. On the 19th day.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she not go publicly by your door after this?</p>
               <p>M. Kelso. No, she did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What magistrate did you go before?</p>
               <p>M. Kelso. Before my Lord Mayor.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not say to her, when at the Mansion-house, You b - h, if it costs me all I am worth, I'll have you hanged, or I'll hang you myself?</p>
               <p>M. Kelso. No, I never said such a word in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640607-53-person464">
                  Jane 
                  Brooks 
               <interp inst="t17640607-53-person464" type="surname" value="Brooks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-person464" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-person464" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When the prisoner was taken up in Tooley-street, and was carried into the alehouse, Mrs. Kelso, who is my mother, came; the things were lying on her knee: my mother said, You bought these with my money: the prisoner said, I did. She was in a black bombazeen sack and petticoat; I saw her go by our door; I live in Tooley-street; I said I had seen her at my mother's, and believed that was the woman that had robbed her. My husband watched her into a pawnbroker's shop; she was just going to untie the riding-dress, and he took her to an alehouse, and charged a constable with her, and went for my mother.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640607-53-person465">
                  Mary 
                  Hicks 
               <interp inst="t17640607-53-person465" type="surname" value="Hicks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-person465" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-person465" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live servant with Mrs. Kelso; the prisoner came in, and called for a pint of beer, and paid for it; she sat a little while over it, then called for another; I believe she might stay an hour, or an hour and a half; she arose up to go from the table, and went and stood upon the sill of the door: a gentleman came in, and called for half a gill of rum-shrub; he asked my mistress to change a guinea; my mistress served him, and gave him change, and took her tin box out of her pocket, and put the guinea into it, and put it into her pocket again. The gentleman never spoke to her, nor she to him; she came then to the bar, and said she could drink a little of my mistress's good brandy, and desired my mistress to bring the bottle and glass; she said she had something to say to her; she begged her to sit down. As she was pulling my mistress to her, I saw her hand down at my mistress's pocket: when she came out, she came round the table, not by my mistress: I saw her left hand down by the right side of my mistress's pocket, and she went and flew out at the door, and ran along the Quay like lightening. After that, my mistress went to put a sixpence in her pocket, and cried, O Lord, Mary, that woman has<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176406070034"></xptr> robbed me of my box, and gold in it: I went round the Quay, but could not see her.</p>

               <p>Q. How was she drest?</p>
               <p>M. Hicks. She was drest in a corded sack and petticoat, white and black, with a patch on the belly of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640607-53-person466">
                  Mary 
                  Holford 
               <interp inst="t17640607-53-person466" type="surname" value="Holford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-person466" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-person466" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner came to my shop on the 16th of May, about half an hour after four o'clock, or a quarter more, in the afternoon; she asked me if I had parted with a riding-habit that she had sold me about six months ago? I said no, I had not.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>M. Holford. I live at the Cross-keys on Little Tower-hill; she desired to have it again.</p>
               <p>Q. How was she drest?</p>
               <p>M. Holford. She was drest in a corded sack and coat; here they are; I bought them of her, (Produced in court).</p>
               <p>M. Kelso. This sack and petticoat the prisoner had on when she picked my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did the prisoner go out of your house?</p>
               <p>M. Kelso. She went out about a quarter after four from my house, in these very things.</p>
               <p>M. Holford. She bought the riding-habit of me again, and gave me a guinea and a half for it; then she asked me if I had parted with her bombazeen sack and coat? I said, No. She bought that again; she gave me 28 s. for it. She then bought a riding-shirt for 7 s.</p>
               <p>Q. What money did she pay you in?</p>
               <p>Holford. She paid me in guineas.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see what she took them from, whether a purse, or what?</p>
               <p>Holford. She pulled them loose out of her pocket; I saw neither purse nor box: in the evening the prosecutrix came running to our house, and asked me if I saw such a person? I said, Yes; and I sold her such things, which I had bought of her before.</p>
               <p>Q. How had she used to appear?</p>
               <p>Holford. She always appeared like a gentlewoman.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what way of life she was in?</p>
               <p>Holford. No, I do not; she put the bombazeen sack and coat on in my house; and I gave her 2 s. for her old ones, the same as are here produced, which Mrs. Kelso says she had on at her house.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing at all of the matter of picking her pocket of her money: I went into her house, and eat a lobster there: there was a master of a brig there; he sat on one side the table, and I on the other; and in the mean time I was there, a sailor came in, and drank a pint of beer at the end of the table; the master of the brig's name is George, by that woman calling him Mr. George. I paid for what I had, and went out; I was seized in Tooley-street, going into a pawnbroker's shop; two men came, and said, This is the lady: I asked what they wanted with me? they said, they would let me know by and by. They carried me into a house, till they sent for this woman; when she came, she said, You b - h, I'll have your life, if the judge does not have it: there were two men kept her from beating me at that time; I have a witness in court, that she told she would have my life, and I have witnesses that will prove they never saw me destitute of money or cloaths.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Verner Cappin. I know the prisoner at the bar; I am a habit-maker.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known her?</p>
               <p>Cappin. About eight or nine months; I made her a habit.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her general character?</p>
               <p>Cappin. I never heard but a very good character of her.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you give her a character upon any other foundation than that of buying a habit of you?</p>
               <p>Cappin. Upon no other than that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640607-53-person467">
                  John 
                  Macane 
               <interp inst="t17640607-53-person467" type="surname" value="Macane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-person467" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-person467" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Rotherhithe, by Rotherhithe-wall; some time last summer the prisoner lodged at my house two or three months, at two or three different times; she paid me very honestly; I never saw any thing but honestly and good behaviour by her.</p>
               <p>Q. What way of life was she in?</p>
               <p>Macane. She was a married woman; her husband was at my house along with her.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his name?</p>
               <p>Macane. His name is 
               <persName id="t17640607-53-person468">
                  Robert 
                  Hanks 
               <interp inst="t17640607-53-person468" type="surname" value="Hanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-person468" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-person468" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; her maiden name was 
               <persName id="t17640607-53-person469">
                  Jane 
                  Faulkner 
               <interp inst="t17640607-53-person469" type="surname" value="Faulkner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-person469" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-person469" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; he was mate of a ship.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640607-53-person470">
                  Susannah 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17640607-53-person470" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-person470" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-person470" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her nine or ten months; I first knew her at Mr. Macane's, at Rotherhithe; she lived there some time; I never heard any thing of her but sobriety, honesty, and a good behaviour; that was the opinion of the neighbours of her, as far as I can tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know her husband?</p>
               <p>S. Smith. I do.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640607-53-person471">
                  Thomas 
                  Williamson 
               <interp inst="t17640607-53-person471" type="surname" value="Williamson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-person471" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-person471" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a sea-faring man; I have known the prisoner about 12 months; the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176406070035"></xptr> first of my knowing her was coming to my apartment in Wapping; her husband was come home from a voyage; they went away again; I know nothing but civility and honesty by her; I was acquainted with her no farther than that they only came and went to and from my apartment: her husband is mate of a vessel, very sufficient to maintain her; I do not know what is become of him; I have not seen him these three months; he is mate of a Riga ship.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640607-53-person472">
                  Ann 
                  Mackintosh 
               <interp inst="t17640607-53-person472" type="surname" value="Mackintosh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-person472" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-person472" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her 14 years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her general character?</p>
               <p>A. Mackintosh. It is a very good one, so far as ever I heard; she was away from Edinburgh four or five years; seeing her in London, she has behaved in a very decent manner.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know her husband?</p>
               <p>A. Mackintosh. I do, vastly well; they were married in Wapping-chapel; I never heard any thing amiss of her character in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you known her ever since she has been in London?</p>
               <p>A. Mackintosh. I have; she came to our house the Thursday before she was taken up: I never knew her in distress.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640607-53-verdict304" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-verdict304" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17640607-53-punish305" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-punish305" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-53-defend458 t17640607-53-punish305"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>See No. 11. in Mr. Alderman Beckford's mayoralty. where she and her husband prosecuted Sarah, wife of 
               <persName id="t17640607-53-person473">
                  George 
                  Miers 
               <interp inst="t17640607-53-person473" type="surname" value="Miers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-person473" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-person473" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , for stealing silver spoons; when it appearing to the court a groundless malicious prosecution, a copy of the indictment was granted to 
               <persName id="t17640607-53-person474">
                  Sarah 
                  Meers 
               <interp inst="t17640607-53-person474" type="surname" value="Meers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-person474" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-53-person474" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
            </div1>
