<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660116-22">
               <interp inst="t17660116-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660116-22" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660116-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660116-22" type="date" value="17660116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660116-22-off141-c238" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-22-defend286 t17660116-22-off141 t17660116-22-verdict145"></join>
         
               <p>99. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660116-22-defend286" type="defendantName">
                     Edward 
                     Minot 
                  <interp inst="t17660116-22-defend286" type="surname" value="Minot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-defend286" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-defend286" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for that <rs id="t17660116-22-off141" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-off141" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-off141" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he, together with 
                     <persName id="t17660116-22-person287">
                        John 
                        King 
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person287" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660116-22-person287" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660116-22-person287" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   and 
                     <persName id="t17660116-22-person288">
                        Henry 
                        Payne 
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person288" type="surname" value="Payne"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660116-22-person288" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660116-22-person288" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , not taken, in a certain court near the King's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17660116-22-victim290" type="victimName">
                           Angel 
                           Simonds 
                        <interp inst="t17660116-22-victim290" type="surname" value="Simonds"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660116-22-victim290" type="given" value="Angel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660116-22-victim290" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-22-off141 t17660116-22-victim290"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and violently taking from his person one thickset frock and waistcoat, value 5 s. one cloth coat and waistcoat, value 21 s. six pounds weight of brass, and a linen bag, the property of the said Angel
            </rs>, <rs id="t17660116-22-cd142" type="crimeDate">November 28</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-22-off141 t17660116-22-cd142"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660116-22-person291">
                  Angel 
                  Simonds 
               <interp inst="t17660116-22-person291" type="surname" value="Simonds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person291" type="given" value="Angel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person291" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming home to Hounsditch. When I was in <placeName id="t17660116-22-crimeloc143">Fore-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17660116-22-crimeloc143" type="placeName" value="Fore-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660116-22-crimeloc143" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-22-off141 t17660116-22-crimeloc143"></join>, the man at the bar, and three more, insisted I should deliver what I had. The prisoner took a stick, and knocked me down.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Simonds. This was last Thursday 7 weeks, between 5 and 6 in the evening. They took what I had in my bag, and ran way with it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you meet them, or did they come behind you?</p>
               <p>Simonds. They came behind me.</p>
               <p>Q. What were their words when they first attacked you?</p>
               <p>Simonds. They wanted to know what I had in my bag, and said I should deliver what I had.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner say any thing to you?</p>
               <p>Simonds. He was the first man that spoke to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Now tell the first thing he mentioned.</p>
               <p>Simonds. He asked me whether I had any money about me.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176601160019"></xptr>Q. Were they the first words?</p>
               <p>Simonds. He at first said, what have you in your bag; and whether I had any money.</p>
               <p>Q. You have told it several ways; be careful and tell the words he said, as near as possibly you can recollect.</p>
               <p>Simonds. He asked me what I <rs id="t17660116-22-viclabel144" type="occupation">dealt in, and I said in old cloaths</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-22-victim290 t17660116-22-viclabel144"></join>. Then he said, he should be willing to have what I had in my bag. I said, come in the day-time, and I'll let you see them, and will be willing to sell you them. He would insist upon seeing them directly, and I would not let him. Then he asked me whether I had any money. While he was speaking, there came 3 men behind me; I said, I had no money; then the prisoner knocked me down; then the other 3 took my bag and ran away with it, and the cloaths in it.</p>
               <p>Q. What was in it?</p>
               <p>Simonds. There was a thickset frock and waistcoat, a pair of leather breeches, a pair of buckskin breeches, a single coat, and 6 pounds weight of brass.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Simonds. I never saw him in my life before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they search your pockets?</p>
               <p>Simonds. No. I lay upon the ground 3 or 4 minutes. The blow stunned me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sensible ?</p>
               <p>Simonds. I was quite out of my senses.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know what was done?</p>
               <p>Simonds. It was a violent blow with a great stick. I did not understand what the damage was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in or out of your senses?</p>
               <p>Simonds. I lay about 3 or 4 minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that?</p>
               <p>Simonds. Because they all ran away.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you first see the prisoner after this?</p>
               <p>Simonds. I saw him again last Wednesday was se'nnight.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you find him?</p>
               <p>Simonds. One Mr. Payne, a corn merchant, told me where to find him.</p>
               <p>Q. That is not saying where you found him.</p>
               <p>Simonds. I saw him at 
               <persName id="t17660116-22-person292">
                  Peter 
                  Deschamps 
               <interp inst="t17660116-22-person292" type="surname" value="Deschamps"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person292" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person292" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, and knew him directly. I went in and asked for Mr. 
               <persName id="t17660116-22-person293">
                  Peter 
                  Deschamps 
               <interp inst="t17660116-22-person293" type="surname" value="Deschamps"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person293" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person293" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner said, I suppose you came to seek for me as well as him. We shared the goods between us. He would have given me a note for a guinea, if I would have taken his note, to be paid in a month's time.</p>
               <p>Q. Suppose he would have given you a guinea then, would you have taken it?</p>
               <p>Simonds. No, I would not take no money. I have a witness here that heard him proffer me the note, he was a stranger going by, and I got him to come in.</p>
               <p>Q. What were the words he made use of?</p>
               <p>Simonds. He said it was hard he should give me a note for a guinea, and there were 3 more concerned with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever find your goods again?</p>
               <p>Simonds. No.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you know the prisoner by, when you saw him at Deschamps's ?</p>
               <p>Simonds. I knew him by his face, and he had his own hair.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it not dark?</p>
               <p>Simonds. It was dark.</p>
               <p>Q. Suppose he had denied it, should you have been able to swear to him?</p>
               <p>Simonds. I should have known him.</p>
               <p>Q. Should you know the other three, was you to see them?</p>
               <p>Simonds. No, I could not swear to them, they had not their own hair, and he had.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660116-22-person294">
                  William 
                  Twyman 
               <interp inst="t17660116-22-person294" type="surname" value="Twyman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person294" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person294" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a pipe-maker, and live in Featherstone-street; I never saw the prosecutor with my eyes before this happened. I heard the prisoner offer him a guinea, in case he would take his note for it in a month's time.</p>
               <p>Q. What did Simonds say to that?</p>
               <p>Twyman. He said that would not do.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be there?</p>
               <p>Twyman. I happened to be in a public house where Simonds came, and he asked me to go along with him to Grub-street.</p>
               <p>Q. What public house, and where?</p>
               <p>Twyman. It was a public house in Featherstone-street, at the sign of the Lion.</p>
               <p>Q. How far distant is that from Grub-street.</p>
               <p>Twyman. That is about half a quarter of a mile.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Twyman. To the best of my knowledge it was last Tuesday night was se'nnight.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he want you to go with him for?</p>
               <p>Twyman. He desired me to go down to Grub-street along with him, he said there was an affair in hand; this man had robbed him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he mention his name?</p>
               <p>Twyman. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say he intended to do?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176601160020"></xptr>Twyman. He said if he could light of the man he should chuse to have his goods again, if he could get them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go that night?</p>
               <p>Twyman. We did, the prisoner was not there: the next morning he came to me again at the shop where I work, in Featherstone-street, and begged of me to go again; I did, then the prisoner was in the room, which I thought was the room where he lodged in Grub-street.</p>
               <p>Q. Whole house was it?</p>
               <p>Twyman. That I do not know, it was in an alley.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it above stairs, or below?</p>
               <p>Twyman. It was a lower room.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you along with Simonds when he went in ?</p>
               <p>Twyman. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Then tell the first thing that passed ?</p>
               <p>Twyman. Simonds asked the prisoner about the robbery.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they his words ?</p>
               <p>Twyman. He asked him whether he would produce the things.</p>
               <p>Q. What answer did the prisoner give him?</p>
               <p>Twyman. He asked him whether he would take his note for a guinea, in a month's time; and Simonds said no: I went away immediately.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is this from the place where Simonds came to you?</p>
               <p>Twyman. It is about half a quarter of a mile.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to go along with Simonds ?</p>
               <p>Twyman. Simonds; proposed to satisfy me for my time, if I would go to hear what this man had to say.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not know he was going to take him up?</p>
               <p>Twyman. No, I did not, he left me in the room, and went out, and I went out then.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you first become acquainted with Simonds?</p>
               <p>Twyman. I never was acquainted with him in the world. I never saw him before that night in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. What did Simonds desire you to go with him that night for?</p>
               <p>Twyman. My shopmates thought he wanted to bring me into some premunire, and they followed me: he was talking this over in a public house, to a watch-case maker.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he desire you to go for?</p>
               <p>Twyman. To make up this affair, if possible he could.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you he knew the person that robbed him ?</p>
               <p>Twyman. He did not tell me the man's name.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he tell you he had lost?</p>
               <p>Twyman. He told me he had lost a coat and waistcoat as for the particulars I cannot tell; I know he said there were 6 pounds of brass.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he say he lost it ?</p>
               <p>Twyman. He said he lost it in Fore-street, in an alley.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say how many people there were that robbed him ?</p>
               <p>Twyman. He did not tell me how many.</p>
               <p>Q. Recollect yourself.</p>
               <p>Twyman. I believe he did mention one King, and Peter Deschamps, as having been concerned in the robbery.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know 
               <persName id="t17660116-22-person295">
                  Peter 
                  Deschamps 
               <interp inst="t17660116-22-person295" type="surname" value="Deschamps"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person295" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person295" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ?</p>
               <p>Twyman. I never saw him in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. Nor King?</p>
               <p>Twyman. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure he did not tell you the prisoner's name?</p>
               <p>Twyman. I knew nothing of the prisoner's name till he was taken before my Lord Mayor.</p>
         
               <p>*** The Last part of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17660116-22">
                  <interp inst="t17660116-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660116-22" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660116-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660116"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660116-22" type="date" value="17660116"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176601160021"></xptr>THE WHOLE PROCEEDINGS ON THE KING's COMMISSIONS of the PEACE, OYER and TERMINER, and GOAL DELIVERY FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the GOAL DELIVERY FOR THE COUNTY of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Thursday the 16th, Friday the 17th, Saturday the 18th, and Monday the 20th of JANUARY, 1766.</p>
                  <p>In the Sixth Year of His MAJESTY's Reign. Being the Second SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of THE RIGHT HONOURABLE 
                  <persName id="t17660116-22-person296">
                     GEORGE 
                     NELSON 
                  <interp inst="t17660116-22-person296" type="surname" value="NELSON"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660116-22-person296" type="given" value="GEORGE"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660116-22-person296" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Esq; LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>NUMBER II. PART II.</p>
                  <p>LONDON,</p>
                  <p>Printed for J. WILKIE, at the Bible, in St. Paul's Church-Yard.</p>
                  <p>[Price Six-Pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176601160022"></xptr>THE WHOLE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Goal-Delivery held for the City of LONDON, &amp;c.</p>
                  <p>Continuation of the Trial of 
                  <persName id="t17660116-22-person297">
                     Edward 
                     Minot 
                  <interp inst="t17660116-22-person297" type="surname" value="Minot"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660116-22-person297" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660116-22-person297" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               .</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I Never saw the prosecutor till last Wednesday was se'nnight, when he came in and asked me whether I knew him, he said I had robbed him with the other three. I board at Mr. Deschamps's, he is a pump-maker in Grub-street: said the prosecutor I want restitution for the things I lost; said I do you know me: he said yes. Mrs. Deschamps said if I would make it up with the man, she would be obliged to me: I said I would endeavour to make it up: she asked him if he would take half a guinea; he would not, and went away. He came again, and said he would have more; he wanted a guinea: she said she would endeavour to get him a crown. I did not offer any thing in my own behalf, I said if I was the person, why should he exact more on me than the rest. She went to get him a crown; I went voluntarily with them to my Lord-Mayor, and to the Compter.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660116-22-person298">
                  Hannah 
                  Deschamps 
               <interp inst="t17660116-22-person298" type="surname" value="Deschamps"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person298" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person298" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was taken up in my husband's room; he was at my house on the 15th of November, from about 3 in the afternoon, till after 8 at night; in that time Mr. Payne came and told me such an affair had happened, between 
               <persName id="t17660116-22-person299">
                  Henry 
                  Payne 
               <interp inst="t17660116-22-person299" type="surname" value="Payne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person299" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person299" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17660116-22-person300">
                  Peter 
                  Deschamps 
               <interp inst="t17660116-22-person300" type="surname" value="Deschamps"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person300" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person300" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , my husband, and 
               <persName id="t17660116-22-person301">
                  John 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17660116-22-person301" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person301" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person301" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by an affair?</p>
               <p>H. Deschamps. They were accused with running away with a bag from a Jew. I know this man at the bar is quite innocent, this Jew came to my house, and insisted the prisoner was 
               <persName id="t17660116-22-person302">
                  Peter 
                  Deschamps 
               <interp inst="t17660116-22-person302" type="surname" value="Deschamps"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person302" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person302" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; this was last Friday was fortnight, he asked for Deschamps by name, and by trade; the prisoner said why do you know me; the man said yes Sir, he did, and should know him from an hundred: said the prisoner I never saw you before. The Jew said you have, he came several times, and said he did not desire to hurt me nor my children. We agreed to make it up for half a guinea, then he said if I would give him a crown, he would take a note for the rest of the money.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has the prisoner boarded with you?</p>
               <p>H. Deschamps. He has boarded with me about 3 or 4 weeks.</p>
               <p>Q. Has your husband been at home all that time?</p>
               <p>H. Deschamps. No, he has not been at home much since.</p>
               <p>Q. How is it you recollect the 15th of November?</p>
               <p>H. Deschamps. I was washing that day, and did a particular errand that day, is the reason I remember it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not wash on other days, as well as the 15th of November?</p>
               <p>H. Deschamps. The constable had been at our house to search for 
               <persName id="t17660116-22-person303">
                  Henry 
                  Payne 
               <interp inst="t17660116-22-person303" type="surname" value="Payne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person303" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person303" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and he said he had got 
               <persName id="t17660116-22-person304">
                  John 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17660116-22-person304" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person304" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in custody, and I saw wrote down in a paper 
               <persName id="t17660116-22-person305">
                  John 
                  Deschamps 
               <interp inst="t17660116-22-person305" type="surname" value="Deschamps"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person305" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person305" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17660116-22-person306">
                  Henry 
                  Payne 
               <interp inst="t17660116-22-person306" type="surname" value="Payne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person306" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17660116-22-person307">
                  John 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17660116-22-person307" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person307" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person307" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was in the Compter, and the next day he was cleared; by reason the Jew never answered, and King's father said he gave the Jew 3 guineas and a half to clear his son.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Is that true?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I have not had a farthing of King.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you complain to any body the night you was robbed?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No, I did not; after I went home some people came and told me I must take up John King; the next day the constable came, and said he was out upon bail.</p>
               <p>H. Deschamps. Here is evidence here to prove the agreement between the Jew and the gentleman at the bar.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660116-22-person308">
                  Robert 
                  Eversfield 
               <interp inst="t17660116-22-person308" type="surname" value="Eversfield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person308" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I work in Fore-street, I heard the cry, stop thief; I saw King running.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176601160023"></xptr>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Eversfield. I cannot say how long it was ago, one Mr. 
               <persName id="t17660116-22-person309">
                  Beaumont
               <interp inst="t17660116-22-person309" type="given" value="Beaumont"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person309" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a vintner stopped him, and Hopkins a constable came and laid hold of him; we took him to the Ship, then I went home to my master: this Jew would have made it up, but the constable persuaded him not to do it.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the Jew charge him with?</p>
               <p>Eversfield. He charged him with knocking him down and robbing him, there were King, 
               <persName id="t17660116-22-person310">
                  Harry 
                  Payne 
               <interp inst="t17660116-22-person310" type="surname" value="Payne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person310" type="given" value="Harry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person310" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and Deschamps mentioned.</p>
               <p>Q. Who mentioned them?</p>
               <p>Eversfield: King himself did; he said Payne and Deschamps were the men that were concerned with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he mention any body else?</p>
               <p>Eversfield. No, he did not; the Jew only mentioned three, and he did not know their names, he promised to come to the constable's house, to go before the Court of Alderman; but he did not come.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660116-22-person311">
                  Charles 
                  Ganley 
               <interp inst="t17660116-22-person311" type="surname" value="Ganley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person311" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person311" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Yesterday was fortnight Mr. Deschamps and the prisoner came to my house, he said, he, King, and Payne, were got into a very bad affair; he told it me: I said it is a very bad affair indeed.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know this woman that gave evidence?</p>
               <p>Ganley. I do, she is wife to 
               <persName id="t17660116-22-person312">
                  Peter 
                  Deschamps 
               <interp inst="t17660116-22-person312" type="surname" value="Deschamps"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person312" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-person312" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. What is become of Deschamps and Payne?</p>
               <p>Ganley. I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Ganley. I am a house-keeper, and live in King's Head court, White-Cross-street.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660116-22-verdict145" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660116-22-verdict145" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
