<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610225-16">
               <interp inst="t17610225-16" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610225-16" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610225-16" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610225"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610225-16" type="date" value="17610225"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610225-16-off79-c133" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-16-defend162 t17610225-16-off79 t17610225-16-verdict81"></join>
         
               <p>93 (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610225-16-defend162" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Derbin 
                  <interp inst="t17610225-16-defend162" type="surname" value="Derbin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-16-defend162" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-16-defend162" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17610225-16-off79" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610225-16-off79" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-16-off79" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one cloth coat, value 11 s. and one pair of cloth breeches, value 3 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17610225-16-victim164" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     England 
                  <interp inst="t17610225-16-victim164" type="surname" value="England"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-16-victim164" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-16-victim164" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-16-off79 t17610225-16-victim164"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17610225-16-cd80" type="crimeDate">Jan. 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-16-off79 t17610225-16-cd80"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-16-person165">
                  William 
                  England 
               <interp inst="t17610225-16-person165" type="surname" value="England"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-16-person165" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-16-person165" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lost a coat, waistcoat, a pair of breeches, and a bible, on the 13th of January. I know nothing how they were taken away.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever find them again?</p>
               <p>England. I found them again at Mr. Cook's, in Rosemary-lane. He is a salesman, [The coat and breeches produced in court, and deposed to.]</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you lose them?</p>
               <p>England. Between six and seven o'clock. I bought them for my apprentice.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you bound by article to find your apprentice with cloaths?</p>
               <p>England. I am.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has he had them?</p>
               <p>England. He has had them ever since a week before Whitsuntide last.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his name?</p>
               <p>England. His name is 
               <persName id="t17610225-16-person166">
                  Daniel 
                  Hunson 
               <interp inst="t17610225-16-person166" type="surname" value="Hunson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-16-person166" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-16-person166" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-16-person167">
                  Daniel 
                  Hunson 
               <interp inst="t17610225-16-person167" type="surname" value="Hunson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-16-person167" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-16-person167" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Those cloaths my master bought for me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he deliver them to you?</p>
               <p>Hunson. He did, and I wore them.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you consider these cloaths as your own?</p>
               <p>Hunson. I take them to be my master's property while I am with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Suppose you leave him, do you take the cloaths with you?</p>
               <p>Hunson. No, I think I should leave the cloaths behind me.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is your indenture?</p>
               <p>Hunson. That was in my coat pocket when taken away, and that is lost.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you miss them?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250018"></xptr>Hunson. I missed them on the 13th of Jan. last, from out of my box.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you keep these cloaths?</p>
               <p>Hunson. I kept those cloaths in a two-pair of stairs room.</p>
               <p>Q. Where they under lock and key?</p>
               <p>Hunson. No, they were in my master's box, which he lends me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-16-person168">
                  Henry 
                  Cook 
               <interp inst="t17610225-16-person168" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-16-person168" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-16-person168" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner to come to deal in Rosemary-lane with goods, and I bought these goods of him.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day did you buy them of him?</p>
               <p>Cook. I bought them of him between 10 and 11 in the forenoon, on the 30th of January.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you give him for the coat and waistcoat?</p>
               <p>Cook. He asked 15 s. and I gave him 14 s.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Have I not dealt with you before?</p>
               <p>Cook. Yes, and he has dealt with several others in the Lane.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known him?</p>
               <p>Cook. I have known him 12 months.</p>
               <p>Q. When you charged him with this, did he deny selling them to you?</p>
               <p>Cook. No, he did not; these cloaths had been offered by two women on that same day before, and the prosecutor's wife came and gave an account of what sort of cloaths she had lost; but, as she could not describe them, her husband came, and he described them. I knowing him, I told him, if he would have a little patience, I knew the person that I bought them of, (then I did not know his name, or where he lived). I thought I should soon see him again. The prisoner came the Saturday following to sell an article to me. I took him into my master's house, and told him I bought a blue coat and breeches of him on the last Tuesday, that had been stolen, and to secure myself I must secure him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he make any resistance?</p>
               <p>Cook. No, he did not, neither did he offer to make his escape.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Did you buy these cloaths for your apprentice's use, and as his property?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I did.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610225-16-verdict81" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610225-16-verdict81" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-16-verdict81" type="verdictSubcategory" value="fault"></interp>
               The Indictment being wrong-laid, he was acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
