<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640607-56">
               <interp inst="t17640607-56" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640607-56" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640607-56" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640607"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640607-56" type="date" value="17640607"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640607-56-off320-c385" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-56-defend504 t17640607-56-off320 t17640607-56-verdict323"></join>
         
               <p>382. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17640607-56-defend504" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Henry 
                     Hareman 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17640607-56-alias-8" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-56-defend504 t17640607-56-alias-8"></join>Wilson</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-56-defend504" type="surname" value="Hareman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-56-defend504" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-56-defend504" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for that <rs id="t17640607-56-off320" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640607-56-off320" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-56-off320" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640607-56-victim507" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Openshaw 
                        <interp inst="t17640607-56-victim507" type="surname" value="Openshaw"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640607-56-victim507" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640607-56-victim507" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-56-off320 t17640607-56-victim507"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , on the King's highway, did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and violently taking from his person one hat, value 12 s. one perriwig, value 20 s. one cheque handkerchief, value 4 d. and 6 d. in money
            </rs>, the property of the said James, <rs id="t17640607-56-cd321" type="crimeDate">June 6</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-56-off320 t17640607-56-cd321"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640607-56-person508">
                  James 
                  Openshaw 
               <interp inst="t17640607-56-person508" type="surname" value="Openshaw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-56-person508" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-56-person508" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Saturday I went to the Alphabet in Stanhope-street, Clare-market; and going home, at the bottom of the stable-yard by <placeName id="t17640607-56-crimeloc322">Lincoln's-Inn-fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640607-56-crimeloc322" type="placeName" value="Lincoln's-Inn-fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640607-56-crimeloc322" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-56-off320 t17640607-56-crimeloc322"></join>, there stood up a soldier and another man; they had sticks in their hands; he laid hold of my arm.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober?</p>
               <p>Openshaw. I had been drinking, but was not drunk; the other man stepped back, and gave a bit of a beckon, and said they wanted to speak with me; they both laughed: they got me about six yards up the stable-yard; the soldier had hold of my arm all the way; then he knocked me down with his stick, and after that gave me a punch in my mouth with his fist, when I was upon my back on the ground, and said, if I did not lie still till such time he had searched my pockets, he would murder me. I desired he would not use me ill, and said I had no money of any signification about me: said the other man, See for his watch: that man was dressed in a blue coat. Then the soldier, (which was the prisoner) demanded my watch; I said I had none; he took a cheque handkerchief from my coat pocket, and about six-pennyworth of halfpence. When they could find no more money, he said, D - n you, I'll take your hat and wig. He took the hat from my head, and threw it to the other man, and said, Take that, and I'll take his wig; then they made out of the stable-yard as fast as possible: I got up, and ran, and cried Stop thief. They both of them did the same, as they ran up the street before me: the watchman saw them coming; he struck the prisoner, and put a stop to his running, and I came up. and laid hold of him; he dropped the wig, and the other man threw away the hat, and got away.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>Openshaw. This was a little past two o'clock in the morning; they were not out of my sight before I took the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you take him?</p>
               <p>Openshaw. In Great Queen-street.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure the prisoner is one of the men that robbed you?</p>
               <p>Openshaw. I am very sure he is; the wig was found just by where he was stopped: I had him by the collar when that was found: we took him to St. Gile's round-house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever get your handkerchief again?</p>
               <p>Openshaw. No, nor half-pence neither.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640607-56-person509">
                  Thomas 
                  Neal 
               <interp inst="t17640607-56-person509" type="surname" value="Neal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-56-person509" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-56-person509" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watchman in Queen-street. I saw the prisoner and another man running, on Wednesday morning, between two and three o'clock: the prisoner called Stop thief; as soon as he saw me, he crossed the way; the prosecutor was following him without hat or wig, calling Stop thief: I saw the prisoner throw the wig away, as I came up to him; I struck at him, but he stooped his head, and I hit him cross the back: the prosecutor and I seized him; he kicked us most terribly, and endeavoured to get away; the other got away: the prosecutor said he had lost some halfpence and his hat and wig, and that they swore<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176406070037"></xptr> they would murder me if I made any resistance. The prisoner said he took nothing from him, but he owned he did afterwards. He was taken to the round-house; I saw the wig taken up, and the hat also, about five or six yards from it; the prosecutor has got them both again. The next day, when the prisoner was in the coach, going to Newgate, I was with him, and he said this was not the first time, by two or three, and he would get off from this as well as the rest.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640607-56-person510">
                  William 
                  Standrup 
               <interp inst="t17640607-56-person510" type="surname" value="Standrup"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-56-person510" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-56-person510" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable. Hearing a noise in Queen-street, I went up, and they had hold of the prisoner's collar; I took this stick (producing a long strong stick) out of the prisoner's hand; he was very loath to give it me; we took him to the round-house, and I heard him say he had been tried before at Guildhall, for picking of pockets: he said, he would give them trouble.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I heard them say, they should get the reward, if I was hanged. I was coming home that night from Holborn, from the sign of the Green Man, betwixt twelve and one; I came down the Fleet-market, and then to Temple-bar; I met a young fellow in a grey coat; he said, soldier, where are you going? I said; home. Said he, I am locked out, if you will go with me to some night-house, I will give you a pint of beer: I said, I had no money about me. Going along, I saw a man lying down, in liquor; I took no particular notice of him; I walked on, and this young fellow had hold of my arm: in about five minutes, I heard the cry of Stop thief; I saw a man running by me in soldiers cloaths, and I called Stop thief: I kept walking on, and they catched hold of me. I asked the watchman what he wanted with me? he said, you rascal, you are the thief; there they took me to St. Anne's round-house, where I saw the gentleman; he was very much in liquor; he said, I think you are the man: the man at the round-house said, I don't know what to make of it: he was very much in liquor when he first came in.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640607-56-verdict323" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640607-56-verdict323" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17640607-56-punish324" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640607-56-punish324" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-56-defend504 t17640607-56-punish324"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
