<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680518-23">
               <interp inst="t17680518-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680518-23" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680518-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680518"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680518-23" type="date" value="17680518"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680518-23-off116-c202" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680518-23-defend256 t17680518-23-off116 t17680518-23-verdict119"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176805180014"></xptr>366. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17680518-23-defend256" type="defendantName">
                     Daniel 
                     Saxton 
                  <interp inst="t17680518-23-defend256" type="surname" value="Saxton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-23-defend256" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-23-defend256" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for <rs id="t17680518-23-off116" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680518-23-off116" type="offenceCategory" value="breakingPeace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-23-off116" type="offenceSubcategory" value="riot"></interp>
               that he, together with many others, to the number of 500 or more, being disturbers of the peace, on the <rs id="t17680518-23-cd117" type="crimeDate">28th of March</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680518-23-off116 t17680518-23-cd117"></join>, did assemble near the <placeName id="t17680518-23-crimeloc118">Mansion-house</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-23-crimeloc118" type="placeName" value="Mansion-house"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-23-crimeloc118" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680518-23-off116 t17680518-23-crimeloc118"></join>, in the city of London, there continuing for the space of an hour, and more, making great noise and disturbance; and that he the said Daniel did cast and throw many stones at the windows, and break the same, damage the furniture, and put divers subjects of our Lord the King in the Mansion-house in great fear and danger of their lives
            </rs>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680518-23-person257">
                  William 
                  Pain 
               <interp inst="t17680518-23-person257" type="surname" value="Pain"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-23-person257" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-23-person257" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 28th of March I went about eleven in the night to Mr. Heath's, a fishmonger's at Temple-bar, hearing there was a great disturbance (it was the day of the election at Brentford;) while I was there Mr. Stevenson came; Mr. Manlove, who is partner with Mr. Heath, came and said he was just come from the Mansion-house, and there was a great mob there, and they had done a great deal of mischief; Mr. Stevenson and I proposed to take a walk there, to see if it was so; we went and found the report true; there was a vast number of people, some thousands; I saw several of them throw stones, and break the Mansion-house windows; among them I saw the prisoner at the bar, they were shouting, and crying out, Wilkes for ever! and such like language as that.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you get to the Mansion-house?</p>
               <p>Pain. A very little after eleven; the lamps were most of them broke before I got there, and a great many windows, particularly below stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of stones?</p>
               <p>Pain. Such stones as they could pick up in the streets, being after the new paving was made; and there were a great number of little stones lying about; I saw stones flying may be the bigness of an egg, bigger or lesser, and pieces of brick-bats; I took particular notice of the prisoner, because I looked upon him to be a pickpocket, he had very much the appearance of one, and I think still I am not mistaken in that, from the behaviour which I saw that night; I thought it was my duty, as well as every Englishman, to endeavour to suppress it; I could not attempt to do any thing in the midst of a mob; I showed Stevenson the prisoner, and said, there is that villain, I suspect him to be a pickpocket, you see he is throwing stones; I believe we watched him near half an hour, he threw all the stones he had with him; then he went from the Mansion-house up a passage by the side of a church at the bottom of the Poultry below the Compter, there was a heap of stones, and such things lay; he loaded himself there, we followed him, and saw him come back again to the Mansion-house; he threw and broke several panes of glass on the west side the Mansion-house; I was determined never to leave him till I had taken him, I had hardly patience to forbear taking him in the midst of the mob; my neighbour Stevenson believing I should seize him, said, for God's sake, do not take him, we shall be murdered; I said, if you are afraid go home, for I will never leave him till I take him: the soldiers came, the mob stopped them; there was one more active than the rest, he threw his bayonee about, and made way; they drawed round in a ring, I and the prisoner were in the midst of them; while the soldiers were in that posture, the prisoner threw several stones, and broke several windows in the Mansion-house; my neighbour, according to my advice, and I suppose agreeable to his own inclination, left me: after the prisoner had throwed all the stones he had, then he came out, and went down the west side the Mansion-house, and picked up more stones, and throwed them up to the two pair of stairs windows, and I believe he broke most of the two pair of stairs windows that were broke on that side; I was going to take hold of him several times, but I considered the consequence of the mob, so I waited till about half an hour after twelve; he met with a young man that he knew, they talked together; I took that young man to be one of the same sort; they agreed to go home, they came from the mob a little way; I determined to take him when they got a little way from the mob: to save my own brains, I concluded to take hold of him as a pickpocket; I said, you villain, how dare you come here to pick pockets; I thought in this the mob would rather be on my side than against me; there were no body very near, nor no body assisted me; his companion made off immediately; I got the prisoner into the Poultry Compter, then he was very ready to be searched; I then said no, I do not take you up as a pickpocket, I take you up for breaking the Mansion-house windows.</p>
               <p>Q. How long from first to last might you have kept your eye upon him?</p>
               <p>Pain. I may say a full hour.</p>
               <p>Q. When the lamps were broke how could you see?</p>
               <p>Pain. They did not break the other peoples lamps, and there were candles in every window in all the houses, some out of fear, and some perhaps out of respect, the mob shouting, Wilkes for<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176805180015"></xptr> ever! then a stone went, a number of the mob were throwing and shouting Wilkes: but I believe the prisoner broke more windows after I was there than any ten men, he was remarkable for throwing; when I got him into the inward part of the Compter, we examined his hands, and they were both of them very much soiled, as if handling dirty stones: I should not have mentioned this, had I not heard there are some women would give evidence that his hands were clean.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was it when you put him in the Compter?</p>
               <p>Pain. The watch went half an hour past twelve when I came out of the Compter coming up Cheapside.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was that after you came from the Mansion-house?</p>
               <p>Pain. I suppose it was about a quarter of an hour, that must be the most.</p>
               <p>Q. How was the prisoner dressed?</p>
               <p>Pain. He had his own dark hair, a coloured handkerchief about his neck, and a ragged coat on.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you directly followed him?</p>
               <p>Pain. I did, and took him between the mob and the Poultry Compter; I watched him out of the mob, and just before we got to the Poultry-gate, I went before them to see if there was any body there to assist me; I saw nobody, so I took him myself.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not stop at the Poultry-gate to watch for his coming?</p>
               <p>Pain. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you had not been there five or six minutes watching for him, and then jumped upon him?</p>
               <p>Pain. No, I had not been there half a minute.</p>
               <p>Q. How near the Compter-gate did you seize him?</p>
               <p>Pain. Not ten yards from it I suppose; the mob reached half way up to the gate; they were both walking together a good middling pace, I suppose at the rate of three miles and a half an hour; I was obliged to run to get before them, he was directly fronting the gate when I seized him.</p>
               <p>Q. How near to it?</p>
               <p>Pain. I suppose about twenty feet.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he abide in one place?</p>
               <p>Pain. He shifted about, he was on both sides the Mansion-house and front and all; I was sometimes on one side him, and sometimes behind him; I told my Lord Mayor's porter at the gate, I had got my eye upon a particular person, I meant the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell the man at the Compter the prisoner was a pickpocket?</p>
               <p>Pain. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not say, look at his hands and see they are muddy?</p>
               <p>Pain. I said they were dirty; his hands were both soiled, as if he had been handling dirty stones.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body look at his hands?</p>
               <p>Pain. Nobody but the turnkey looked at them while I was there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680518-23-person258">
                  John 
                  Stevenson 
               <interp inst="t17680518-23-person258" type="surname" value="Stevenson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-23-person258" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-23-person258" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a neighbour to Mr. Pain. On the 28th of March I stood at Temple-bar, there was a great mob of people; I said, what will all this come to; said Mr. Pain, will you take a walk with me into the city, they are breaking the Mansion-house windows; we went; when we came there, there was scarcely a whole window; he and I walked round the Mansion-house; he said, look sharp, I know -; I said, I shall not look about it; he followed some person or other, (the lamps were all broke as I saw,) people were throwing stones, I don't know any one person upon earth that threw a stone; I walked round the Mansion-house with Mr. Pain.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he single out any one particular person?</p>
               <p>Stevenson. He followed a person.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that?</p>
               <p>Stevenson. He turned round and said, I know a person.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the person he mentioned throw a stone?</p>
               <p>Stevenson. I can't remember no person that was there; there were pieces of tiles lying there; said Pain, you'll see if he picks them up; I went off directly, and went over to the left-hand side; there were a great many people walking up and down; said Pain, I shall not go home with you, if you are afraid you may go home, for I will not leave the person; he followed a person that went down on the left-hand side; I went home directly and left him there. He came to me the next morning and said, I have taken him; I said, how can you swear to a person among so many people, I suppose you are going to get 50 l. he said there was no reward offered.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you did not see the person Mr. Pain alluded to throw a stone?</p>
               <p>Stevenson. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any stones thrown while Mr. Pain was with you?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176805180016"></xptr>Stevenson. Yes, three or four,</p>
               <p>Q. Were the persons that throwed them near Mr. Pain?</p>
               <p>Stevenson. They were.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell whether the prisoner was one of the men?</p>
               <p>Stevenson. I cannot tell that, I never saw the prisoner in my life till I saw him here in the court; I took no notice of Mr. Pain after he desired me to look.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you say nothing to Mr. Pain?</p>
               <p>Stevenson. I said, if I had been one of my Lord Mayor's servants at that time, I should certainly have fired at the mob.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was it that you was there?</p>
               <p>Stevenson. It was about 11 o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you stay there?</p>
               <p>Stevenson. All the time I was there was not above 15 minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. What did Mr. Pain say the man was when he came to you next morning?</p>
               <p>Stevenson. He called him a pickpocket, if I remember; he said he followed him till he came to the Compter-gate, and he pushed him in; I said, how could you take him out of the mob; he said, O, I knew him of old.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you and Pain in such a situation in the mob so as to converse together?</p>
               <p>Stevenson. He walked before and I near him behind; we could converse occasionally.</p>
               <p>Council. You say he did take notice of a man?</p>
               <p>Stevenson. He did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he point to him as throwing stones?</p>
               <p>Stevenson. He did.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure the prisoner is not the man that Pain pointed to as throwing stones?</p>
               <p>Stevenson. I will not say he is not the young man that Pain pointed at.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you believe?</p>
               <p>Stevenson. Upon my oath I never saw the prisoner in my life before I saw him now in court.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see that man that Pain pointed throw stones?</p>
               <p>Stevenson. Yes, I did; there were three or four throwing stones together.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you at that time apprehend Pain had some nation of a reward?</p>
               <p>Stevenson. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any?</p>
               <p>Stevenson. No, I had none at all.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you arrive at the Mansion-house?</p>
               <p>Stevenson. About 11 o'clock.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680518-23-person259">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Saxton 
               <interp inst="t17680518-23-person259" type="surname" value="Saxton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-23-person259" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-23-person259" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner is my brother; he came from my mother's house that night about half an hour past ten at night, she lives in Wyld-street, Clare-market; when he has done his business at his master's, he comes and spends his evenings with me and my mother when she is at home; his master lives in Jewin-street, he is a watch-finisher.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he not bailed?</p>
               <p>E. Saxton. He was, by his master and another gentleman.</p>
               <p>Q. Did his bail surrender him up after that?</p>
               <p>E. Saxton. Yes, they did.</p>
               <p>Q. Why so?</p>
               <p>E. Saxton. Because he met with another troublesome affair, of which he was innocent, as well as this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680518-23-person260">
                  Amelia 
                  Waite 
               <interp inst="t17680518-23-person260" type="surname" value="Waite"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-23-person260" type="given" value="Amelia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-23-person260" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the prisoner brought into the Compter that night, my husband is a prisoner there for debt, I live there; I did not see him when he was first laid hold of; when Mr. Pain brought him up the court I was about the middle of it; he said the boy was a pickpocket; then he brought him into the lodge, he asked me where the turnkey was; I rang the bell on the master's side; when he came, Mr. Pain said, he has been throwing stones at the Mansion-house windows, look at his hands; I looked at the m, I saw no dirt; Pain said his hands are all over mud and dirt with flinging stones; Mr. Woolard took the candle and looked at his hands; I looked and said, you cannot say his hands are dirty.</p>
               <p>Pain. If Mr. Woolard was here he would say his hands were dirty.</p>
               <p>Q. to A. Waite. What time did Pain bring him in?</p>
               <p>A. Waite. It was not above a quarter past eleven o'clock.</p>
               <p>Pain. The soldiers did not come till after twelve o'clock.</p>
               <p>A. Waite. We were all in bed by twelve.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you heard the soldiers were come?</p>
               <p>A. Waite. I heard the soldiers were come, but cannot tell whether it was before or after the prisoner was brought.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you judge whether he had not taken hold of bricks, stones, or tiles?</p>
               <p>A. Waite. No, I cannot; but his hands did not appear to be muddy, his hands might be soiled.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176805180017"></xptr>Q. Where did Pain say the prisoner was a pickpocket?</p>
               <p>A. Waite. That was in the lodge.</p>
               <p>Q. When he got him in within the gates what did he say?</p>
               <p>A. Waite. Then he talked about throwing stones.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680518-23-person261">
                  Henrietta 
                  Lawrence 
               <interp inst="t17680518-23-person261" type="surname" value="Lawrence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-23-person261" type="given" value="Henrietta"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-23-person261" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw Mr. Pain stand at the Compter-gate that Monday night; he came up to the gate and opened it, and I believe he might stay there between five and six minutes between the gates, he stood as if he waited for somebody; I remember the prisoner was brought in; I stood looking over the rail close by Mr. Pain; I was there when Mr. Pain came up first; I saw some people walking along the street; Mr. Pain went out and seized the young man by the collar.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner running or walking?</p>
               <p>H. Lawrence. He was walking a common pace as if going home, he was not making any noise; he was going from the Mansion-house, the windows were breaking at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>H. Lawrence. I fancy this might be about 11 or after, it may be before eleven.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it not past twelve?</p>
               <p>H. Lawrence. I am very sure it was not, because I was going to bed when the clock struck twelve; he seized the young man in the street, and said, I have catched you now, he is a pickpocket; he said to me, shut to the gate, and I did, but I did not follow him up into the Compter.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be there?</p>
               <p>H. Lawrence. My father has the care of the Compter.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether Mr. Pain did not address himself to you, and you made some answer to him?</p>
               <p>H. Lawrence. I did not hear him speak a word to any body; he ran up in a great hurry to the gate; and opened the hatch and there he stood.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he there a single minute?</p>
               <p>H. Lawrence. I think he was.</p>
               <p>Q. Will you take upon you to swear he was there two minutes?</p>
               <p>H. Lawrence. I really think he was.</p>
               <p>Q. What was he doing?</p>
               <p>H. Lawrence. He was looking about.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17680518-23-verdict119" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680518-23-verdict119" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acq.
            </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
