<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17620114-23">
               <interp inst="t17620114-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620114-23" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620114-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17620114"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620114-23" type="date" value="17620114"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620114-23-off115-c158" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620114-23-defend196 t17620114-23-off115 t17620114-23-verdict119"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620114-23-off120-c158" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620114-23-defend196 t17620114-23-off120 t17620114-23-verdict119"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620114-23-off125-c158" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620114-23-defend196 t17620114-23-off125 t17620114-23-verdict119"></join>
         
               <p>72. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17620114-23-defend196" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Samuel 
                     Harris 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17620114-23-alias-4" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620114-23-defend196 t17620114-23-alias-4"></join>Watts</rs>, otherwise <rs id="t17620114-23-alias-5" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620114-23-defend196 t17620114-23-alias-5"></join>Jones</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-defend196" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-defend196" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-defend196" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for that <rs id="t17620114-23-off115" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-off115" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-off115" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he, on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17620114-23-victim199" type="victimName">
                           Henry 
                           Kidgell 
                        <interp inst="t17620114-23-victim199" type="surname" value="Kidgell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620114-23-victim199" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620114-23-victim199" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17620114-23-viclabel116" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620114-23-victim199 t17620114-23-viclabel116"></join>; did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and taking from his person one metal watch, val. 40 s. his property, and against his will
            </rs>, <rs id="t17620114-23-cd117" type="crimeDate">Aug. 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620114-23-off115 t17620114-23-cd117"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620114-23-off120 t17620114-23-cd117"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620114-23-off125 t17620114-23-cd117"></join>. *</p>
               <p>Henry Kidgell. On the 15th of August last I had been to the diversion at Sadler's Wells, for the entertainment of a young lady that came to see me from Dublin, she having never been in England before; I presume I might be stopt and robbed about nine o'clock, for I was at home about 20 minutes after nine. We were in a coach, I my wife, a kinsman of mine, 
               <persName id="t17620114-23-person200">
                  William 
                  Horwood 
               <interp inst="t17620114-23-person200" type="surname" value="Horwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-person200" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-person200" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and Miss Clark from Dublin; there came a man up to us on foot, when we were <placeName id="t17620114-23-crimeloc118">a few paces beyond the turning up to Southampton Row, beyond the Bowling Green, by the Long Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17620114-23-crimeloc118" type="placeName" value="a few paces beyond the turning up to Southampton Row, beyond the Bowling Green, by the Long Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17620114-23-crimeloc118" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620114-23-off115 t17620114-23-crimeloc118"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620114-23-off120 t17620114-23-crimeloc118"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620114-23-off125 t17620114-23-crimeloc118"></join>; he ordered the coach to stop, and put a pistol into the coach. I sat on that side next to Bedford-house; he rather presented it at first towards my kinsman, but he did to us all by turns; he said, Your money, your watches, quick, quick, gentlemen, or I'll blow your brains out. I gave him half a guinea and 18 d. He said, More money, your watches, your money, or I'll blow your brains out. I said, You fool, you cannot kill the whole company, you fright the women; here is mine, and gave him my watch; my kinsman gave him 4 s. 6 d. or 5 s. 6 d. and my wife threw a few half-pence into his hand; my watch was a metal watch, with a gold dial-plate, in a shagreen case, it wound up in the dial-plate; then he went off.</p>
               <p>Q. Described what sort of a person he was?</p>
               <p>Kidgell. I had the least sight of him of all the whole company, I can't speak to his person in a satisfactory way; he appeared to have black hair which hung over his forehead, and his eyebrows remarkably black and large; he kept a smart walk before he stopt us, and what view I had of his face was before he stopt us; I looked upon him to be about five feet five inches high.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it light or dark?</p>
               <p>Kidgell. There was a foulness or a mist gathered that evening, it was very hazy. As he went off, I saw him padding along the road: I sent a description of my watch to Sir John Fielding, and so I came by the knowledge of it again; the prisoner was taken up on another account.</p>
               <p>Q. Where are your wife and kinsman?</p>
               <p>Kidgell. My wife is sick in bed, and my kinsman could not swear to the prisoner when he saw him at justice Fielding's.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620114-23-person201">
                  William 
                  Carr 
               <interp inst="t17620114-23-person201" type="surname" value="Carr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-person201" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-person201" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a journeyman taylor; I have known the prisoner four years; I live in Leicester Fields with Mr. Fillico, a watchmaker, and work for Mr. Thomas.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the prisoner any time in August last?</p>
               <p>Carr. I did, he had his own black hair on then: I had some conversation with him about a watch; he went into the country the latter part of that month, and left a watch with me till he came back again.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you how he came by it?</p>
               <p>Carr. He said he had it in part of payment for a suit of cloaths that he had made, and, as I had not a watch, I might keep it till he came out of the country again; and when he came out of the country, I saw him in the park the day the queen came to town; he asked me how the watch went; it was a single case, a metal watch, and a gold dial-plate.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620114-23-person202">
                  William 
                  Partridge 
               <interp inst="t17620114-23-person202" type="surname" value="Partridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-person202" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-person202" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             produced a watch. This I had of the evidence Carr.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. This is the identical watch that I was robbed of that 14th of August, at night.</p>
               <p>Carr. This is the watch that the prisoner at the bar left with me.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. You was mentioning some conversation you had with the prisoner in the park?</p>
               <p>Carr. He said, if I liked it, I might have it at the same price he had it. I told him I would ask advice about it.</p>
               <p>Q. What price did he mention?</p>
               <p>Carr. He mentioned three guineas and a half.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known him?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176201140014"></xptr>Carr. I have known him about four years.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you worked with him?</p>
               <p>Carr. I have; but I seldom saw him except on a Sunday lately, because I was at work.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a character did he bear?</p>
               <p>Carr. While he was at work with me, he seemed very industrious, and worked very close as I did.</p>
               <p>Q. When was his hair cut off?</p>
               <p>Carr. I do not know that.</p>
               <p>Partridge. I searched the prisoner's house in Devereux-court the day he was taken; I found a pistol below-stairs, in a bureau, loaded with powder and ball; it was locke d up; I found also some balls in the same place [Producing pistol and balls.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620114-23-person203">
                  William 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17620114-23-person203" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-person203" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-person203" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I searched the prisoner at Sir 
               <persName id="t17620114-23-person204">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620114-23-person204" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-person204" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-person204" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, and found upon him some gunpowder, two balls, a pistol slint, and a steel seal, all in his left-hand breeches pocket; the balls fit to the same mold, as if made to the pistol found in his bureau. Before the justice, Mr. Carr produced the watch, and gave the same account as now. I heard Sir John ask the prisoner if he knew Mr. Carr? he said, he did. Sir John asked him, if Mr. Carr ever had a watch of him? he answered, No. Said Sir John, No! did you never sell him one? he said, No. Did you never give him one? No. Then Mr. Carr was called into the room, and said, he had that watch of Mr. Harris. Then Sir John said to Harris, Why do you deny it? Harris turned it off, and said, you never asked me if I lent it him. Sir John asked him how he came by that watch? he said, he took it in part of payment for a suit of cloaths, of one James, that was gone abroad.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620114-23-person205">
                  Francis 
                  Tremlet 
               <interp inst="t17620114-23-person205" type="surname" value="Tremlet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-person205" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-person205" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a perriwig-maker; I have known the prisoner five or six years, I cut off his hair I believe about the 12th of December last.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of hair was it?</p>
               <p>Tremlet. It was long black hair.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Tell the plain honest truth, how he came to cut his hair off?</p>
               <p>Tremlet. He was in my shop to have his hair dressed; he told me he was lately got into business for himself. I told him I thought it did not look creditable to a tradesman to wear his own hair, it looked like a gentleman's servant. He said, he should have no objection to cut off his hair, in case a person that cut it off wanted any thing in his way. I said, I had as lieve have part in cloaths, was I do make him some wigs, as not; and on that condition I cut off his hair, and made him two wigs, and he made me a suit of cloaths, and I paid him the balance. I never had any acquaintance with him before, I had seen him at a relation's house of his.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>Last August a gentleman, an acquaintance of mine, met me going to Chelsea; he desired me to steplin at the Cannon, just beyond Buckingham Gate, and drink a glass of wine. I did. He asked me what business I was? I said, A taylor, and I land at Mr. Clackston's. Said he, I want a sut of cloaths, and was going abroad. I told him I was just beginning for myself. He called upon me and I measured him for a coat and waistcoat, the waistcoat trimmed with silver. I made them; he called and put them on, and liked them very well. They came to 8 l. 10 s. He said, I am very sorry I have been disappointed of a bill I was to have received. I said, I am verry sorry, because I do not know much of you. Said he, I have brought two watches, and I'll leave them with you till I pay you the remainder of the money. He had the cloaths on his back, and I was obliged to take them for my security. Some time after that I saw those two watches advertised as stolen on the highway. I went to Mr. Carr, and told him. I had received two watches of a gentleman, and would leave one of them with him, because I was going into the country. He said, if he liked it, he would pay me for it, I said, If you liked it, you shall have it at the same price I gave for it. I said, As for the man I had it of, he would never come again; I had seen him advertised, and I thought him to be a villain; when I came to town, the first day I saw Mr. Carr, he said, you know I have a watch of yours? I said, how does it go? said he, Very well. Said I, Do you chuse to have it? if not, you will do it no harm to keep it in your pocket. I said, If the man comes, I do intend to stop him, for I saw the watch advertised.</p>

               <p>Q. to Carr. Did he declare any thing to you at that time about this watch being advertised?</p>
               <p>Carr. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he mention that he had two watches?</p>
               <p>Carr. I do not remember that he did.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620114-23-person206">
                  John 
                  Clackston 
               <interp inst="t17620114-23-person206" type="surname" value="Clackston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-person206" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-person206" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about nine months; I live in Clare Court, Clare Market; he lodged with me about six months.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did he work with?</p>
               <p>Clackston. Upon my word I do not know that he worked with any body in that time; he behaved very well, very sober, kept very good hours, and very little company came after him except it was about business; he paid me very honestly.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620114-23-person207">
                  William 
                  Piot 
               <interp inst="t17620114-23-person207" type="surname" value="Piot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-person207" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-person207" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him between three and four years; he always bore a very good character,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176201140015"></xptr> and behaved very well. He was a lodger with me between two and three years. He was a very industrious man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17620114-23-verdict119" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-verdict119" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was indicted a Second time; for that <rs id="t17620114-23-off120" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-off120" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-off120" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17620114-23-victim209" type="victimName">
                           Vincent 
                           Durand 
                        <interp inst="t17620114-23-victim209" type="surname" value="Durand"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620114-23-victim209" type="given" value="Vincent"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620114-23-victim209" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , on the king's highway, did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and taking from his person one silver watch, value 40 s. and five shillings in money, numbered, his property, and against his will
            </rs>, <rs id="t17620114-23-cd121" type="crimeDate">August 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620114-23-off115 t17620114-23-cd121"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620114-23-off120 t17620114-23-cd121"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620114-23-off125 t17620114-23-cd121"></join>. * </p>
               <p>Vincent Durand. About the 12th of August, I was returning from Sadler's Wells in a little light cart. I was going home to Hamersmith, and had my wife and two other women with me. I was stopt by a foot-pad <placeName id="t17620114-23-crimeloc122">about a mile from Sadler's Wells on the New Road</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17620114-23-crimeloc122" type="placeName" value="about a mile from Sadler's Wells on the New Road"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17620114-23-crimeloc122" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620114-23-off115 t17620114-23-crimeloc122"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620114-23-off120 t17620114-23-crimeloc122"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620114-23-off125 t17620114-23-crimeloc122"></join>, about 10 o'clock. He walked by the side of the cart a little way. Then he step'd from the rails, and swore he would shoot me through the head if I did not stop directly.</p>
               <p>Q. How many horses had you in the cart?</p>
               <p>Durand. But one. I drove him. The man presented a pistol to me with a very bright barrel. I gave him upwards of 10 s. He swore d - m you. you have more, and demanded my watch. I gave him a silver watch, with a black shagreen case, and a black leather string.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a man was he?</p>
               <p>Durand. I cannot say. I think he had a blue coat on, and his own hair, which looked to be of a dark colour, and seemed to be tied up behind. The moon shone in my face. I went to Mr. Fielding the next day, and described the watch. He sent for me the other day, and gave me orders to go to a pawnbroker's in St.Martin's-lane: there I saw the watch. I was at Mr. Fielding's; but not present when the prisoner was charged with this robbery.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620114-23-person210">
                  Samuel 
                  Hance 
               <interp inst="t17620114-23-person210" type="surname" value="Hance"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-person210" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-person210" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a pawnbroker; I have known the prisoner seven or eight months. I live in St. Martin's-lane. On Saturday morning, the 15th of August, about nine o'clock, the prisoner at the bar brought this silver watch, and pawned it with me. He asked a guinea and half: I lent him 27 s. on it. He said he had it from a man who was going abroad, in part of payment for cloaths.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he then his own hair or a wig?</p>
               <p>Hance. He had his own dark-brown hair. [The watch produced, and deposed to by the prosecutor, and what he was robb'd of the 12th of August, having had it about thirty years].</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see the watch advertised?</p>
               <p>Hance. I was told it was advertised on the 14th of August; but that was after I had taken it in. I was present at the justice's when the watch was shewn to the prisoner. He said, that he neither knew it nor me. Sir John asked me, if I knew the prisoner. I said I did, and pick'd him out from others. I had seen him several times before he pawned the watch; he was a customer.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620114-23-person211">
                  William 
                  Partridge 
               <interp inst="t17620114-23-person211" type="surname" value="Partridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-person211" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-person211" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was present when the prisoner was examined in respect to this robbery. The watch was produced. He said he knew nothing at all of the watch, nor the pawnbroker.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620114-23-person212">
                  William 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17620114-23-person212" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-person212" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-person212" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was present when the prisoner was examined on this robbery. The watch was produced: he said he knew nothing of it not the pawnbroker either. Sir John ordered the pawnbroker to go and pick him out; and he did, from amongst several others. I found, as I mentioned on the other trial, some gun-powder, two balls, a flint, and a steel seal, on the prisoner in searching him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing at all of what I am charged with.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17620114-23-verdict123" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-verdict123" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17620114-23-punish124" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-punish124" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620114-23-defend196 t17620114-23-punish124"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>There was another indictment against him for <rs id="t17620114-23-off125" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-off125" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-off125" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               robbing a clergyman on the highway of a silver watch and steel seal
            </rs>. He was not tried upon that; but the clergyman swore to the watch and steel seal (the latler 
               <persName id="t17620114-23-person213">
                  William 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17620114-23-person213" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-person213" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-23-person213" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             found upon the prisoner) and they were delivered to him in court.</p>
               <p>See him tried for stealing a brown gelding the property of his majesty, No 117, in last mayoralty.</p>
            </div1>
