<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17651016-8">
               <interp inst="t17651016-8" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651016-8" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651016-8" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17651016"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651016-8" type="date" value="17651016"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17651016-8-off40-c78" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651016-8-defend90 t17651016-8-off40 t17651016-8-verdict43"></join>
         
               <p>520. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17651016-8-defend90" type="defendantName">
                  Ann, <rs id="t17651016-8-deflabel39" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651016-8-defend90 t17651016-8-deflabel39"></join> of Thomas Oddy<interp inst="t17651016-8-defend90" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-8-defend90" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17651016-8-off40" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651016-8-off40" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-8-off40" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a blanket, value 4 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17651016-8-victim92" type="victimName">
                           George 
                           Rollos 
                        <interp inst="t17651016-8-victim92" type="surname" value="Rollos"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651016-8-victim92" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651016-8-victim92" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651016-8-off40 t17651016-8-victim92"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in a certain lodging-room, let by contract by the said George, to the said Ann, to be used by the said Ann, &amp;c
            </rs>. <rs id="t17651016-8-cd41" type="crimeDate">August 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651016-8-off40 t17651016-8-cd41"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651016-8-person93">
                  George 
                  Rollos 
               <interp inst="t17651016-8-person93" type="surname" value="Rollos"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-8-person93" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-8-person93" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17651016-8-crimeloc42">Warner-street, Cold-bath-fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17651016-8-crimeloc42" type="placeName" value="Warner-street, Cold-bath-fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17651016-8-crimeloc42" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651016-8-off40 t17651016-8-crimeloc42"></join>. I let my parlour to the prisoner and a man that came with her, as her husband, for 3 s. a week: at that time, I had a very good character of them; but afterwards having reasons to think they were not married, I gave the man warning; (his name was White) but could not get rid of them: he went into the country to see his friends: then she received all sorts of men, as a common prostitute. After that, I was informed she belong'd to a gang of thieves: I gave her warning on a Monday morning, and on the Tuesday I had reason to think my house was beset; there were several fellows came after her. I applied to Justice Girdler for his advice: he told me, the way to get rid of her was by taking the door off the hinges, and the windows out. I went and demanded admittance into her room; she made no answer for some time: then she abused me for coming at that time of the night. The watch going by, I called him; I sent for the constable of the night; he came, and we broke the door open: there were a man and she sitting by the table; they were both conducted to Bridewell: my wife examined the bed, and miss'd a blanket. The under turnkey took her before Justice Girdler, and told him there was nothing against her but an assault: thus by deceiving the Justice, she was discharged. I got a fresh warrant and took her again; and by a search warrant, found the blanket at Mr. William Whitton's, on Hare-street-hill, who told me the prisoner brought it there in the name of White.</p>
               <p>Q. What name did you let the lodging to her in?</p>
               <p>Rollos. In the name of White, as man and wife.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you let it to?</p>
               <p>Rollos. To the supposed husband; she was by at the time; but I afterwards found she has a husband named Oddy.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17651016-8-verdict43" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651016-8-verdict43" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-8-verdict43" type="verdictSubcategory" value="fault"></interp>
               As the indictment mentions it being let to her the said Ann, for her use. she was Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
