<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17651211-10">
               <interp inst="t17651211-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651211-10" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651211-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17651211"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651211-10" type="date" value="17651211"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17651211-10-off59-c103" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-10-defend127 t17651211-10-off59 t17651211-10-verdict63"></join>
         
               <p>(13.) (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17651211-10-defend127" type="defendantName">
                     Catherine, <rs id="t17651211-10-deflabel58" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-10-defend127 t17651211-10-deflabel58"></join> of 
                        <persName id="t17651211-10-person128">
                           Nathaniel 
                           Wilks 
                        <interp inst="t17651211-10-person128" type="surname" value="Wilks"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651211-10-person128" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651211-10-person128" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                     , otherwise <rs id="t17651211-10-alias-2" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-10-defend127 t17651211-10-alias-2"></join>Catherine Bolton</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-defend127" type="surname" value="Wilks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-defend127" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-defend127" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , spinster, was indicted for <rs id="t17651211-10-off59" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-off59" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-off59" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing, in company with 
                     <persName id="t17651211-10-person129">
                        Nathaniel 
                        Wilks 
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-person129" type="surname" value="Wilks"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651211-10-person129" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651211-10-person129" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  ; 100 yards of flowered gauze, value 12 l. 200 yards of striped gauze, 20 yards of plain gauze, 48 gauze handkerchiefs, 6 yards of Scotch lawn, 50 linen handkerchiefs, 30 gauze caps, 50 yards of thread lace, 5 yards of silk ribbon, 5 yards of silk lace, one duffil cloth cardinal, 36 pound weight of butter, and two pieces of serge
            </rs>; the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17651211-10-victim131" type="victimName">
                     Charles 
                     Beal 
                  <interp inst="t17651211-10-victim131" type="surname" value="Beal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-victim131" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-victim131" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-10-off59 t17651211-10-victim131"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17651211-10-cd60" type="crimeDate">October 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-10-off59 t17651211-10-cd60"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-10-person132">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Beal 
               <interp inst="t17651211-10-person132" type="surname" value="Beal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-person132" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-person132" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to 
               <persName id="t17651211-10-person133">
                  Charles 
                  Beal 
               <interp inst="t17651211-10-person133" type="surname" value="Beal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-person133" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-person133" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; we live in Newgate-market, but <rs id="t17651211-10-viclabel61" type="occupation">keep a milliner's shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-10-victim131 t17651211-10-viclabel61"></join> in the <placeName id="t17651211-10-crimeloc62">Fleet-market</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17651211-10-crimeloc62" type="placeName" value="Fleet-market"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17651211-10-crimeloc62" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-10-off59 t17651211-10-crimeloc62"></join>. I left that shop safe on the 4th of October at night, and on the 5th, between 6 and 7 o'clock in the morning I found it broke open in the back part of it; there were a great quantity of goods taken away; all that are mentioned in the indictment. On the Wednesday following Mr. Bruin, a pawn-broker on Snow-hill, sent for me; I went and found the prisoner and two pieces of gauze, but cannot take upon me to sware to them; but recollecting a woman had made some things for me of that gauze, we sent for her, she knew it to be my gauze. The prisoner said she bought the gauze in Rag-fair; we took her before the sitting Alderman, he gave me a warrant to search her house. We found a housewife upon the table, with some of my lace, and two pieces of ribbon, which were my property, also several lappets made of gauze, and several remnants of lace which I can swear to. In a box we found one cap, under the bed another; in the pocket of a blue coat we found some pieces of lace. Under the dresser one plain gauze flowered bordered handkerchief, one gauze laced mob, one queen's mob, one queen's round cap, and about 5 yards of blue ribbon, 5 yards of black edging was found in the room, and the trimmings of my red cardinal, which I can swear to. (The goods produced in court, and deposed to by the prosecutrix.) Mr. Kennet was at the finding the rest. I asked her whose coat that was, in which the piece of lace was, she said it was the man's she lived with. I asked her if it was her husband's, she said no, that she sometimes lived with him, and sometime swent away. There is the mark of a woman's foot on a piece of board, that lay just under the window, where she came into the shop. (Produced in court with a dirty print of a woman's foot upon it. Inspected by the Jury.)</p>
               <p>Mr. Kennet. On the 9th of October in the evening, I was sent for to Mr. Bruin's, he described the woman that had brought the gauze. I said I knew her, and mentioned where she lived; I sent for her, (it was the prisoner.) She said she bought the gauze in Rag-fair; I took her in custody on suspicion of being concerned in this robbery. The next day we took her before Sir 
               <persName id="t17651211-10-person134">
                  John 
                  Cartwright 
               <interp inst="t17651211-10-person134" type="surname" value="Cartwright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-person134" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-person134" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he granted a search-warrant. I went to the house where she lived, and found part of the things; a poor woman came down and said, O sir, I have found the rest of the things, there was a place broke in the garret, up into a cockloft, a hole was broke through, and it had a communication with the next house; then the woman handed the things through a hole out of a room even with the floor I was in. The things she handed through were a sack of butter, and 2 pieces of blue serge, a red cloak, a small piece of cheque, a great number of caps, a large quantity of other gauze, a little box with caps and ribbons. I took them home, and carried the woman at the bar next day to be examined; there was a man appeared in her behalf, and wanted it to be made up, his name was Wilks, he is a kind of a carpenter, and now he is turned quack-doctor, and was going to open a shop in Chick-lane. I have heard nothing of him since.</p>
               <p>Mr. Bruin. I am a pawn-broker on Snow-hill. On the 5th of October Sir 
               <persName id="t17651211-10-person135">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17651211-10-person135" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-person135" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-person135" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sent a warning to acquaint me a shop had been broke open in Fleet-market, and lawns and things taken out. The prisoner that goes by the name of 
               <persName id="t17651211-10-person136">
                  Catherine 
                  Bolton 
               <interp inst="t17651211-10-person136" type="surname" value="Bolton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-person136" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-person136" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , brought a piece of gauze, about enough for an apron and handkerchief; she told me she bought it at a linen-draper's in Cheapside: I said it was very particular for a linen-draper to sell gauze, she said she bought some linen with it. I sent for Mrs. Beal, she said she could not swear<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176512110010"></xptr> to it, but said it was the same pattern; she sent for a woman, that if it was her gauze would know it. I bid the prisoner fetch her husband, she walked out very orderly. The person came and said it was Mrs. Beal's property; after that a warrant was got from Sir 
               <persName id="t17651211-10-person137">
                  John 
                  Cartwright 
               <interp inst="t17651211-10-person137" type="surname" value="Cartwright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-person137" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-person137" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and searched the prisoner's apartment, and some of the things were found. I have known the prisoner a year and a half, she is a woman of the town; she has not lived long with that man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-10-person138">
                  Anne 
                  Hunsdon 
               <interp inst="t17651211-10-person138" type="surname" value="Hunsdon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-person138" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-person138" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I make gauze caps for the shops. I made eight for Mrs. Beal of this piece of gauze found upon the prisoner. (She produced one of them, it matched for quality and colour.)</p>
               <p>Mrs. Beal. The lace that was found in the housewife, in a coat pocket, was my property; the housewife is not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The housewife is mine.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>My husband came home late at night, I chid him for staying out so late. He said he had been at his sister's, and had brought something for me; then I was reconciled: he produced several things. I asked him where he got them, he said of his sister. The next morning when he was sober, he said he bought them in Rag-fair; he went out the next day, and I wanted a little money. I went to the pawn-broker with this housewife and handkerchief. If I had known them to have been stolen, I would not have carried them there.</p>
               <p>She called 
               <persName id="t17651211-10-person139">
                  Jane 
                  Dimson 
               <interp inst="t17651211-10-person139" type="surname" value="Dimson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-person139" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-person139" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17651211-10-person140">
                  Hannah 
                  Bentley 
               <interp inst="t17651211-10-person140" type="surname" value="Bentley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-person140" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-person140" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17651211-10-person141">
                  Catherine 
                  Kingcart 
               <interp inst="t17651211-10-person141" type="surname" value="Kingcart"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-person141" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-person141" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17651211-10-person142">
                  Catherine 
                  Tharrol 
               <interp inst="t17651211-10-person142" type="surname" value="Tharrol"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-person142" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-person142" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who gave her a good character.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17651211-10-verdict63" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-verdict63" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17651211-10-punish64" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651211-10-punish64" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-10-defend127 t17651211-10-punish64"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
