<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17611021-31">
               <interp inst="t17611021-31" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611021-31" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611021-31" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17611021"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611021-31" type="date" value="17611021"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17611021-31-off160-c305" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-31-defend353 t17611021-31-off160 t17611021-31-verdict164"></join>
         
               <p>315. (M) 
               
                  <persName id="t17611021-31-defend353" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Quin 
                  <interp inst="t17611021-31-defend353" type="surname" value="Quin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-defend353" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-defend353" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17611021-31-off160" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-off160" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-off160" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one linnen handkerchief, value 1 s. one towel, value 6 d. and one China-cup, value one penny
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17611021-31-victim355" type="victimName">
                     Georgia 
                     Bellamy 
                  <interp inst="t17611021-31-victim355" type="surname" value="Bellamy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-victim355" type="given" value="Georgia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-victim355" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-31-off160 t17611021-31-victim355"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17611021-31-cd161" type="crimeDate">October 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-31-off160 t17611021-31-cd161"></join>.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-31-person356">
                  Mary 
                  Ellice 
               <interp inst="t17611021-31-person356" type="surname" value="Ellice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person356" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person356" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mrs. Bellamy, she lives in <placeName id="t17611021-31-crimeloc162">Jermin-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17611021-31-crimeloc162" type="placeName" value="Jermin-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17611021-31-crimeloc162" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-31-off160 t17611021-31-crimeloc162"></join>; the prisoner is a <rs id="t17611021-31-deflabel163" type="occupation">journeyman uphosterer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-31-defend353 t17611021-31-deflabel163"></join>; he was at work at my mistress's house, in fitting up some restoon window-curtains, in September last. Two or three days after I missed a handkerchief, two towels, and two tea-cups. We suspected he must take them, and in searching his lodgings, we found the handkerchief. one cup, and one towel. [Produced in court.] These are my mistress's property; here is her name upon the handkerchief. The towel is of a particular sort; I never saw such besides there; my mistress brought them with her from Ireland; they are not made up; here is one of the same sort, I brought from home. [Producing it; they are compared, and correspond.] The tea-cup is part of a set of Drelden-china, [Producing a fellow to it; they correspond,] with a blue stripe down the middle of each.</p>
               <p>Q. When was it that the prisoner worked at you house?</p>
               <p>M. Ellice. About the 3d of October was the last time he worked for my mistress.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-31-person357">
                  John 
                  Kirkwood 
               <interp inst="t17611021-31-person357" type="surname" value="Kirkwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person357" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person357" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner lodged at my house; I have seen that handkerchief, here produced, and two towels, hang up in our yard; this is one of the towels, that is here produced. When the handkerchief was brought home, the woman that the prisoner lives with put it on, and brought it down, and shewed it to my wife; she shewed her the towels and cup also. I did not think he came honestly by them. I found out where he had been at work, and I went and gave information of them. I was with the constable when he was taken up, and before the justice he declared he knew nothing of either of the things.</p>

               <p>Q. from Prisoner. What time did you see the handkerchief?</p>
               <p>Kirkwood. I believe it is better than a month ago; I cannot recollect the day, I believe it was in September.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. Did you ever see the towels hang up in the yard?</p>
               <p>Kirkwood. I never saw such as these, besides this here produced, and the other.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. When I was before the justice I had been drinking, and was not then in a capacity of giving an answer, but I desired to be heard another time; I was sent to Clerkenwell-bridewell, and after that I was sent for again.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176110210057"></xptr>Kirkwood. All he said to Mr. Fielding was, he knew nothing at all of the things he was charged with.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he in liquor?</p>
               <p>Kirkwood. I do not believe he was.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-31-person358">
                  Frances 
                  Kirkwood 
               <interp inst="t17611021-31-person358" type="surname" value="Kirkwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person358" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person358" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the last witness; the woman that the prisoner lives with brought a China tea-cup, and two towels, and shewed them to me, and the handkerchief also. This made me very uneasy. After this, my husband went and informed the prosecutrix, and there was a search-warrant.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner and that woman take the lodgings together?</p>
               <p>F. Kirkwood. They did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-31-person359">
                  James 
                  Rowbottom 
               <interp inst="t17611021-31-person359" type="surname" value="Rowbottom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person359" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person359" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Mason, the prisoner's master, desired me to go and get a warrant from Sir 
               <persName id="t17611021-31-person360">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17611021-31-person360" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person360" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person360" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , to search the prisoner's lodgings. I went with it to the prisoner's lodgings, and told the woman that the prisoner lives with, that there was a handkerchief, marked with the letter B, and I must have it. She declared there was no such thing; but at last she took it off her neck, and delivered it to me, and declared the prisoner gave it her. We found also the other things here produced.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you before the justice when the prisoner was?</p>
               <p>Rowbottom. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he drunk or sober?</p>
               <p>Rowbottom. He was as sober as I am now; he declared he knew nothing of any of the things. On his examination he told Sir John, that he had the towel of his wife's mother, who he said kept an inn in the country. He said he found the handkerchief on the step of the prosecutrix's door.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any other cups in the prisoner's house like this cup?</p>
               <p>Rowbottom. No, there were some others, but none like this; the woman said all the others were her own.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-31-person361">
                  Daniel 
                  Mason 
               <interp inst="t17611021-31-person361" type="surname" value="Mason"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person361" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person361" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was a journeyman to me; he had been at work at the prosecutrix's house, in putting up three festoon window-curtains. I went to her house, and the maid desired me not to send this man any more. I asked her what was the matter? She told me what she had lost, and shewed the fellows to the towel and cup. I got a warrant, and staid in the court while the constable and others went and searched. These things that they found, agree with what the maid had before told me; and she, before the justice, swore to them as her mistress's property.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I found the handkerchief on the step of the door; I have got witnesses.</p>
               <p>Counsel for Prisoner. I will call those witnesses that are to your character, but I do not think the other witnesses will be of any service to you.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Call 
               <persName id="t17611021-31-person362">
                  Mary 
                  Anderson 
               <interp inst="t17611021-31-person362" type="surname" value="Anderson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person362" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person362" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-31-person363">
                  Mary 
                  Anderson 
               <interp inst="t17611021-31-person363" type="surname" value="Anderson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person363" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person363" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I remember this cup being at the prisoner's lodgings, going on between five and six months; I had two, one of them is broke; the prisoner gave them to me; and he gave me two towels, five or six months ago; he told me they were his wife's property.</p>
               <p>Q. Should you know them was you to see them?</p>
               <p>M. Anderson. I should.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at that towel. [Produced; she looks at it.]</p>
               <p>M. Anderson. He gave me this five months ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure of that?</p>
               <p>M. Anderson. I am certain of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Is there any particular mark upon it, so as to know that from the other here produced?</p>
               <p>M. Anderson. The other is a new one.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you live in the same apartment with the prisoner?</p>
               <p>M. Anderson. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Take care, speak the truth, great perils may attend; do not carry your affections to any man, so as to be guilty of swearing falsely. Whether you had the two towels so long as you speak of?</p>
               <p>M. Anderson. I had indeed, indeed I had; and the cup was given me five or six months ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember shewing the cup and handkerchief to Mrs. Kirkwood?</p>
               <p>M. Anderson. I shewed one cup to her.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after he gave it you?</p>
               <p>M. Anderson. He gave it to me a great long while before I shewed it to her.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you say to the handkerchief?</p>
               <p>M. Anderson. He brought it home to me, and told me he found it one evening, and gave it to me.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is that ago?</p>
               <p>M. Anderson. That is going on five or six weeks ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you shew her the handkerchief and cup at the same time?</p>
               <p>M. Anderson. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did those cups use to stand?</p>
               <p>M. Anderson. On the mantle-piece.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176110210058"></xptr>Q. What did you do with the towels?</p>

               <p>M. Anderson. They were in constant use.</p>
               <p>Q. Had they been often washed?</p>
               <p>M. Anderson. They had many times; I washed them every week.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you use to hang them up to dry?</p>
               <p>M. Anderson. In the yard below.</p>
               <p>Q. How long do you say you had them?</p>
               <p>M. Anderson. I had them going on five or six months; he gave me them out of his portmanteau.</p>
               <p>Court. I will caution you once more; do you abide by the account you have given?</p>

               <p>M. Anderson. Yes.</p>
               <p>Court. Are you sure?</p>
               <p>M. Anderson. Yes, I am.</p>
               <p>Q. What is become of the other towel?</p>
               <p>M. Anderson. I do not know, except they took it away; I never saw it since.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you them both together?</p>
               <p>M. Anderson. I had.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in the room when the things were taken away?</p>
               <p>M. Anderson. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. What is become of the pieces of the broken cup?</p>
               <p>M. Anderson. I have not got them.</p>
               <p>Q. By what accident was that cup broke?</p>
               <p>M. Anderson. By washing it one morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mrs. Kirkwood use to drink tea with you?</p>
               <p>M. Anderson. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think she might have seen them cups often?</p>
               <p>M. Anderson. I believe she might.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you believe she might have seen this cup on your mantle-piece?</p>
               <p>M. Anderson. May be she might.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that the place where they were constantly put?</p>
               <p>M. Anderson. It was.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any other cups on the mantlepiece?</p>
               <p>M. Anderson. There were.</p>
               <p>Q. How came it you did not put a mark upon the towel?</p>
               <p>M. Anderson. I do not know why.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is it ago since you broke the other cup?</p>
               <p>M. Anderson. It is about three months ago.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-31-person364">
                  James 
                  Chambers 
               <interp inst="t17611021-31-person364" type="surname" value="Chambers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person364" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person364" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner pretty near 12 months; I have been at his lodgings several times; I remember seeing a remarkable cup there, such as this; [Looking at the cup produced.] it was a China-cup, with a handle to very much like this.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see two such?</p>
               <p>Chambers. I have seen several cups.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see this there, or any like it?</p>
               <p>Chambers. I have seen one of those there, or one very much like it.</p>
               <p>Q. When?</p>
               <p>Chambers. Four or five months ago; a cup of that sort with a handle to it; having handles makes them the more remarkable; I saw one of that shape and make.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember seeing any towels there?</p>
               <p>Chambers. Towels are things a man seldom takes notice of; possibly there might be towels.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner's character?</p>
               <p>Chambers. I have known him to be a man of a very fair character; he is an upholsterer by trade; I have been in his company several times; I always knew him to have an extraordinary good character.</p>
               <p>Court. Take that cup in your hand; have you drank tea out of it?</p>
               <p>Chambers. I have; this cup, or somewhat much like it. when I have drank tea.</p>
               <p>Q. A good handsome set of China?</p>
               <p>Chambers. Not a set of this; this might be an odd cup, the set might be broke before.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any tea-pot, milk-pot, or coffeepot, of the same?</p>
               <p>Chambers. There was no other part of the set but this; I saw one there very much resembling this.</p>
               <p>Q. As there was but one, it was a sort of compliment to put it into a stranger's hand.</p>
               <p>Chambers. I know I have seen such a one there.</p>
               <p>Q. Had any of the others handles to them?</p>
               <p>Chambers. No, only one.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Chambers. I live in Southampton-building, next door to the Grotto.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your y?</p>
               <p>Chambers. I am a taylor.</p>
               <p>Q. Who have you worked with?</p>
               <p>Chambers. I have worked with several.</p>
               <p>Q. Who do you work for at this present time?</p>
               <p>Chambers. I work for nobody now.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is your house of call?</p>
               <p>Chambers. I belong to the Three Castles in Black-friars.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-31-person365">
                  Edward 
                  Thrale 
               <interp inst="t17611021-31-person365" type="surname" value="Thrale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person365" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person365" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner at the bar four or five years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Thrale. I never knew but what he is an honest man; he always behaved himself well; he is a hard working, honest man.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176110210059"></xptr>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Thrale. I am a hatter, a journeyman.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Thrale. I live in Cow-cross.</p>
               <p>Mason. This man swore before the justice he kept ten or a dozen men at work in Cow cross.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-31-person366">
                  Robert 
                  Talbot 
               <interp inst="t17611021-31-person366" type="surname" value="Talbot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person366" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person366" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner I believe ten years; his character was very good; but I have known nothing of him the last four or five years.</p>
               <p>- Delency. I have known him better than twelve months.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character?</p>
               <p>Delency. A very honest industrious man, 'till this affair.</p>

               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17611021-31-person367">
                  John 
                  Kirkwood 
               <interp inst="t17611021-31-person367" type="surname" value="Kirkwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person367" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person367" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When did you first see the cups or towels in the prisoner's room?</p>
               <p>Kirkwood. The cup I never saw; the first time I saw the towels was about a month ago, or a little better; that was the first time they were washed, and hung up in the yard.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever take notice of any other towels hanging there before?</p>
               <p>Kirkwood. There might be a rag or two, but none like these.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether if they had been hanging up there in that manner sooner, should you not have observed them?</p>
               <p>Kirkwood. Yes, I should; I have seen linnen hanging in the yard, but if these towels had been there, I should have seen them; they are remarkable with stripes in the inside of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know 
               <persName id="t17611021-31-person368">
                  James 
                  Chambers 
               <interp inst="t17611021-31-person368" type="surname" value="Chambers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person368" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person368" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Kirkwood. I do; last Sunday night 
               <persName id="t17611021-31-person369">
                  Molly 
                  Anderson 
               <interp inst="t17611021-31-person369" type="surname" value="Anderson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person369" type="given" value="Molly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person369" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and a person that calls herself the prisoner's mother, and Chambers and another man, came to my house; and as soon as the door was opened, they forced in upon me. Chambers struck at me directly, as soon as within the door. I took them both by their collars, and lugged them out into the court. The mother called out at the window, and said she was in danger of her life, and said she would swear the peace against me.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen Chambers there often?</p>
               <p>Kirkwood. I have, especially on a Sunday; he used to come and dine there.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17611021-31-person370">
                  Frances 
                  Kirkwood 
               <interp inst="t17611021-31-person370" type="surname" value="Kirkwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person370" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-person370" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Have you drank tea in Anderson's room?</p>
               <p>F. Kirkwood. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you three or four months ago?</p>
               <p>F. Kirkwood. I think I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you taken notice of china on the mantle-piece?</p>
               <p>F. Kirkwood. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. If there had been ever a fine piece of china on the mantle-piece, three or four months ago, should you have observed it?</p>
               <p>F. Kirkwood. Yes, I should; I have often seen the china taken down, and cleaned.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this cup on the mantle-piece three or four months ago?</p>
               <p>F. Kirkwood. No, not 'till lately.</p>
               <p>Q. How lately?</p>
               <p>F. Kirkwood. Within this month, or five weeks.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the pieces of another cup of this sort?</p>
               <p>F. Kirkwood. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she tell you she had broke one?</p>
               <p>F. Kirkwood. No.</p>
               <p>Q. How often have you seen the towels hang up?</p>
               <p>F. Kirkwood. I have seen them hanging in the yard two or three times.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether they were not better than their ordinary towels?</p>
               <p>F. Kirkwood. They are; she shewed me them when they were first brought home; and she told me, she believed they were cabbage, when she was making them, and putting a piece of tape at the ends.</p>
               <p>Q. At what time was that?</p>
               <p>F. Kirkwood. To the best of my knowledge it was about the 18th or 19th of last month. She told me he brought them home the night before she shewed them to me. They were unwashed when she shewed them to me; that is, they never had been washed. I thought some poor servant might lose their place upon it.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you be certain they never had been washed?</p>
               <p>F. Kirkwood. She gave me them in my hands; I am sure they never had been washed.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17611021-31-verdict164" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-verdict164" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The jury declared they did not believe the evidence given by Anderson and Chambers; they were committed to Newgate for perjury, and Mr. Mason entered into recognizance to prosecuts them for the same next sessions.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17611021-31-punish165" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611021-31-punish165" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-31-defend353 t17611021-31-punish165"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
