<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17630706-13">
               <interp inst="t17630706-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630706-13" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630706-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17630706"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630706-13" type="date" value="17630706"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17630706-13-off68-c102" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-13-defend127 t17630706-13-off68 t17630706-13-verdict71"></join>
         
               <p>273. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17630706-13-defend127" type="defendantName">
                  John 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17630706-13-defend127" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-13-defend127" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-13-defend127" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17630706-13-off68" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630706-13-off68" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-13-off68" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he on the king's highway on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17630706-13-victim129" type="victimName">
                           Edward 
                           Johnson 
                        <interp inst="t17630706-13-victim129" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630706-13-victim129" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630706-13-victim129" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-13-off68 t17630706-13-victim129"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and stealing from his person one linnen purse, val. 3 d. and 3 s. and one halfpenny in money numbered, his property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17630706-13-cd69" type="crimeDate">June 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-13-off68 t17630706-13-cd69"></join> +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630706-13-person130">
                  Edward 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17630706-13-person130" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-13-person130" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-13-person130" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the parish of Wilsdon; on the 16th of June I was riding along the road, in <placeName id="t17630706-13-crimeloc70">Hendon-wood-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17630706-13-crimeloc70" type="placeName" value="Hendon-wood-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17630706-13-crimeloc70" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-13-off68 t17630706-13-crimeloc70"></join>, about 2 in the afternoon, the prisoner met me on foot, he came on the near side my horse, he took hold of my horse with his left hand, and clapped what I thought a pistol to my breast with his right, this is it, (producing a pistol tinder-box) he desired me to deliver my money that minute, or he would blow my brains out; I said, friend, I have but a trifle about me, it is not worth your while: said he, give me your money immediately, why are you so long? I pulled out my purse, and said, friend, here is a little key in my purse, let me take that; I took it out, and gave him my purse with my money in it: then he let my horse go, I watched him, and followed him to Elstrey, and took him there at the sign of the Plough. I asked him how many halfpence he had? he said, one: I said, that is right; I said, how many shillings? he said, three: I said, what did you do with the purse? he said, he threw it away: he said, master, if you'll be kind to me, I believe I can help you to your money again: I said, I'll be as kind to you as I can, you shall have just as much as the law will allow, and no more. 
               <persName id="t17630706-13-person131">
                  John 
                  Nutkin 
               <interp inst="t17630706-13-person131" type="surname" value="Nutkin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-13-person131" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-13-person131" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was with me when I took him, we carried him to the Justice at Barnet; who asked him how he came by this tinder-box? he said he had had it about a week; then he said he found it: the Justice said, how came you to keep it so bright? he could say but very little.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630706-13-person132">
                  John 
                  Nutkin 
               <interp inst="t17630706-13-person132" type="surname" value="Nutkin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-13-person132" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-13-person132" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I joined in the pursuit about 4 o'clock, the prisoner was in at the Plough before me, Mr. Johnson came about half a quarter of<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176307060007"></xptr> an hour after me; he asked the prisoner if he knew him? the prisoner looked at him, and said, yes: Mr. Johnson said, where is your pistol? the prisoner put his hand in his pocket, but pulled nothing out, but colard Mr. Johnson; I took hold of him, and set him in a chair, and kept him till a constable was called; then Mr. Johnson asked him how many halfpence were in the purse? he said, one: then he asked what silver, he said, 3 s. he asked him what he had done with the purse? he said he had thrown it away.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I said I had 3 s. and a halfpenny, and if it was that money I could give him as much.</p>
               <p>Nutkin. He said he had taken it from him, and had thrown the purse away.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Nutkin. I never saw him before.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was going to see for work, but I never robbed him; I happened to go into an alehouse for a pint of small beer, and a pennyworth of bread and cheese, and these men came and laid hold of me; in my fright I owned having this thing, (the tinder-box.) I picked it up in the highway.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17630706-13-verdict71" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630706-13-verdict71" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17630706-13-punish72" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630706-13-punish72" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-13-defend127 t17630706-13-punish72"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
