<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17600521-17">
               <interp inst="t17600521-17" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600521-17" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600521-17" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600521"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600521-17" type="date" value="17600521"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600521-17-off90-c200" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600521-17-defend236 t17600521-17-off90 t17600521-17-verdict93"></join>
         
               <p>190. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17600521-17-defend236" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Hullock 
                  <interp inst="t17600521-17-defend236" type="surname" value="Hullock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-17-defend236" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-17-defend236" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17600521-17-deflabel89" type="occupation">single woman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600521-17-defend236 t17600521-17-deflabel89"></join>, was indicted for the <rs id="t17600521-17-off90" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600521-17-off90" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-17-off90" type="offenceSubcategory" value="infanticide"></interp>
               willful murder of her female bastard infant
            </rs>, <rs id="t17600521-17-cd91" type="crimeDate">April 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600521-17-off90 t17600521-17-cd91"></join>.</p>
               <p>She likewise stood charg'd on the coroner's inquest for the said murder.*</p> 
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600521-17-person237">
                  Susannah 
                  Dorwood 
               <interp inst="t17600521-17-person237" type="surname" value="Dorwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-17-person237" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-17-person237" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a midwife; I was sent for to Mrs. Dudman's; she told me she was afraid that Nanny was brought to bed, and the child was killed; I took a candle and look'd down the vault, and saw a child's feet; I went directly up stairs to the prisoner, and said Nanny, why could you put the child down the vault; she said she did not; this was between 9 and 10 o'clock in the morning; I told her she did, and told her I saw a plain proof that she had been delivered, and had put the child down the vault; then she attempted to make me believe it dropp'd from her body in the vault; I had found she had been delivered on the boards in the vault; at last she told me she did; I went to Mrs. Dudman, and desir'd she would let me take the child out of the soil; she said, she was afraid she should come into trouble; I said, the jury could not sit till it was taken out; I went and took it out; the minute I got it up at the he ad of the vault the blood appear'd: I said here is murder committed, the head is almost off; I laid it down on the boards, and it bled prodigiously.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had it lain in the vault, as near as you can guess?</p>
               <p>S. Dorwood. I believe it might have been born between 3 and 4 in that morning; it stuck in the soil, and the soil kept the place together, so that the blood had no vent; I went up stairs directly; I said Nanny, how could you lay violent hands on it to draw innocent blood, said I, do you consider you soul? she made no answer; I said, where is your pocket? she said it was down stairs; I put my hand under her bed, and found her pocket, but there was no knife in it; then I asked her where the knife was, with which she committed the murder; she said in the knife-box; I ask'd what knife; she said one of her mistress's case knives; I look'd in the box, but looking on the other dresser I found the knife, that I suppose to be the knife with blood upon it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the child appear to you to have come to the birth?</p>
               <p>S. Dorwood. It did.</p>
               <p>Q. In your opinion was the child born alive?</p>
               <p>S. Dorwood. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>S. Dorwood. It was at Paddington.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you examine the body of the prisoner?</p>
               <p>S. Dorwood. No, I did not, because every thing was safe from her body.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a male or female child?</p>
               <p>S. Dorwood. It was a female.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600521-17-person238">
                  Jane 
                  Dudman 
               <interp inst="t17600521-17-person238" type="surname" value="Dudman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-17-person238" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-17-person238" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was <rs id="t17600521-17-deflabel92" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600521-17-defend236 t17600521-17-deflabel92"></join> to a lodger of mine, she seem'd to be big with child; she had been but a fortnight in my house; when she had not been in my house above a week there was some grease upon the floor, I desir'd her to get it up; she down on her knees, and as she stoop'd, I said you are a good servant, but I fear you are spoil'd; I said are you marry'd (she appear'd very big) she said no, she never was married in her life. I was in my bed, and heard a person coming down early in the morning; I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176005210032"></xptr> call'd who is there 2 or 3 times, at last I call'd aloud; she answer'd, it is me; are not you well, said I? no said she I am not well: I heard her go down stairs, and open the yard door; she was out some time. I was very uneasy. She did not come in; I got up and open'd the sash, and call'd to her; she said yes, Madam, I am a great deal better, I will come in presently; I believe she had been in the yard something less than a quarter of an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was she when she answer'd you?</p>
               <p>J. Dudman. She was then in the necessaryhouse; then I went to bed, and did not go to sleep, I was afraid she would fall to pieces there; presently I heard the yard door open, she went into the kitchen, and open'd the window, I went to sleep; when my husband got up, my maid came up to me and said, Madam, I am frighted out of my wits, I am afraid Nanny has miscarry'd, she has mopp'd up the place in the necessaryhouse, and the kitchen too.</p>
               <p>Q. Is you maid here?</p>
               <p>J. Dudman. No, she is not; there was a person that lay in our house that night, and he said to me, there is something that should not be; my husband bid me go and see; I went, and saw a bad thing had been done: then my husband sent for a constable, and order'd me to lend for a midwife, which I did; then I went up stairs to the prisoner's mistress, and begg'd of her to go with me to the maid; she made us believe she was asleep; I shook her, and call'd to her, and ask'd her what wicked deed she had been doing, where is your child? at last she said it was down in the vault. I had seen the child before, but afterwards I saw the child's throat was cut. I said to her, how could you do this, there is an hospital ready, and if you had spoke to me but half an hour before I could have got it in. She never own'd to me that she had laid violent hands on it.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600521-17-person239">
                  John 
                  Gibbs 
               <interp inst="t17600521-17-person239" type="surname" value="Gibbs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-17-person239" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-17-person239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable; I was sent for to the house of Mrs. Dudman. She told me, she was afraid her lodger's servant had been deliver'd of a child in the little house, and that she had made away with it, the child was taken out of the soil, and I saw it with the head almost cut off. I went in, and ask'd where the girl was; I went to her and said, was the child born alive. She said yes. I said, did it cry? she said yes. I said, what could be the reason of your murdering of it? she said, she did not know what to do with it. I said, have you any cloaths for it? she said, no. Said I, you will be hang'd. She said, O Lord, I hope not. Said I, is it your child? she said yes. I said, how did you murder it? with a case knife, said she. I ask'd her where the knife was? she said, in the kitchen. I talk'd to her a good deal, and ask'd her if she was in her senses; she said she was very well for the time, and that she was able to get up and do her business. I went down stairs and ask'd for the knife, and there I was show'd it. The next morning I apply'd to justice Fielding, and ask'd what I should do with her? he said, by all means fetch her, if she is able to be removed, there is one subject lost. don't let another be lost without punishment. I went and fetch'd her, and she confess'd the same before the justice; in the coach between there and justice Fielding's she never denied the fact; but said, she always intended to put it in the necessary. It was a female child (a case knife produc'd with blood upon it)</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I did not intend to do it, I took the knife with me with intent to part the burden from the child; I never heard it cry as I am here alive. When I found what I had done I put it in the vault; I was by myself in the vault.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600521-17-verdict93" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600521-17-verdict93" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17600521-17-punish94" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600521-17-punish94" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-17-punish94" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="deathAndDissection"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600521-17-defend236 t17600521-17-punish94"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600521-17-punish95" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600521-17-punish95" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-17-punish95" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="executed"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600521-17-defend236 t17600521-17-punish95"></join>
               She receiv'd sentence immediately (this being thursday) to be executed on the saturday, and her body to be diffected and anatomis'd.
            </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
