<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17631207-16">
               <interp inst="t17631207-16" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-16" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-16" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17631207"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-16" type="date" value="17631207"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17631207-16-off83-c123" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-16-defend157 t17631207-16-off83 t17631207-16-verdict87"></join>
         
               <p>18. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17631207-16-defend157" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Williams 
                  <interp inst="t17631207-16-defend157" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-16-defend157" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-16-defend157" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for <rs id="t17631207-16-off83" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631207-16-off83" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-16-off83" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he, on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17631207-16-victim159" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Bird 
                        <interp inst="t17631207-16-victim159" type="surname" value="Bird"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17631207-16-victim159" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17631207-16-victim159" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-16-off83 t17631207-16-victim159"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and taking from his person six shillings in money, numbered, his property, and against his will
            </rs>. <rs id="t17631207-16-cd84" type="crimeDate">Nov. 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-16-off83 t17631207-16-cd84"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-16-person160">
                  William 
                  Bird 
               <interp inst="t17631207-16-person160" type="surname" value="Bird"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-16-person160" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-16-person160" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 5th of Nov. at very near 12 at night, I was going from my work, from the <placeName id="t17631207-16-crimeloc85">Hermitage dock</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17631207-16-crimeloc85" type="placeName" value="Hermitage dock"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17631207-16-crimeloc85" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-16-off83 t17631207-16-crimeloc85"></join>, to <placeName id="t17631207-16-crimeloc86">Whitechapel</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17631207-16-crimeloc86" type="placeName" value="Whitechapel"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17631207-16-crimeloc86" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-16-off83 t17631207-16-crimeloc86"></join>: as I came near the Free-School, betwixt the posts, (it was very dark, and it rained) a chap came behind me, and laid hold on me, and tore my shirt collar round, and surprized me very much; after I recovered myself, and spoke to him, another came up directly, and then a third, which I imagine to be the prisoner at the bar. They all came from behind a butt, by a tree: he said, D - n his eyes, knock him down; he never touched me. My money was in my waistcoat pocket, half-pence and silver together; the first man that laid hold of me, searched me; he took and stripped my waistcoat pocket open, and took-out 3 s. 6 d. in silver, and the rest in half-pence, 6 s. and 7 d. 1/2 in all; after that, they took up my apron, and clapt their hand upon each thigh, and asked if I had any more? I said, I had no more in the world. Then one of the men that was going away, said, D - n his eyes, give him 3 d. to carry him home, and instead of that, they gave me a groat, which I carried home in my hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he, which you imagine to be the prisoner, seem to be in their company?</p>
               <p>Bird. He did; and afterwards they went all cross the road together; but it being so dark, I could not be positive of the man's face; I suppose it to be the prisoner, by his frock and his hat, an old cock'd up hat, and a brownish frock, like that he now has on. After this, I was drinking with some coopers, at the Ship ale house, the bottom of Nightingale-lane: they asked me, which way I was robb'd? I told them, and described the prisoner; one of them went out, and fetched him in to me. I said, I believed, when he came in, him to be the man, to the best of my knowledge, but<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176312070015"></xptr> he said, he never saw me that night, and could bring good witnesses where he was at that time, and offered to go to Justice Scott's directly, and went to the door, but Justice Scott was not at home. After this, he was going to work again.</p>
               <p>Q. What trade is he?</p>
               <p>Bird. He is a cooper by trade; he works in the cooperidge near the place where we were: after that, one Newton insisted I should take him up. He was, and the next day taken before Justice Berry, who committed him to Newgate; when he was taken, he had the same sort of a hat on.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any light near where you was robb'd?</p>
               <p>Bird. There was a lamp near me. It was not above 5 yards from me, when I stood between the posts.</p>
               <p>Q. Could that lamp afford you such light, so as to distinguish his person?</p>
               <p>Bird. I did think it was he; I was positive it was the same frock.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you say the prisoner was the man?</p>
               <p>Bird. I would not for all the world swear he was the man.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any other witness?</p>
               <p>Bird. No, I have not.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17631207-16-verdict87" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631207-16-verdict87" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
