<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640912-33">
               <interp inst="t17640912-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-33" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640912"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-33" type="date" value="17640912"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640912-33-off187-c242" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-33-defend301 t17640912-33-off187 t17640912-33-verdict191"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640912-33-off187-c243" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-33-defend304 t17640912-33-off187 t17640912-33-verdict191"></join>
         
               <p>512, 513. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17640912-33-defend301" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Richard 
                     Bond 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17640912-33-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-33-defend301 t17640912-33-alias-3"></join>Clark</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-defend301" type="surname" value="Bond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-defend301" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-defend301" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17640912-33-defend304" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17640912-33-defend304" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-defend304" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-defend304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17640912-33-off187" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-off187" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-off187" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing a promissory note for the payment of 22 l. 8 s. signed by 
                     <persName id="t17640912-33-person305">
                        John 
                        Baker 
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-person305" type="surname" value="Baker"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640912-33-person305" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640912-33-person305" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , by which he promised to pay to 
                     <persName id="t17640912-33-person306">
                        John 
                        Hazard 
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-person306" type="surname" value="Hazard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640912-33-person306" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640912-33-person306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , or order, the said sum; and a leather bill-case, value 2 s. 6 d. from the person of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640912-33-victim308" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Hazard 
                        <interp inst="t17640912-33-victim308" type="surname" value="Hazard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640912-33-victim308" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640912-33-victim308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-33-off187 t17640912-33-victim308"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , his property, privately and secretly
            </rs>, <rs id="t17640912-33-cd188" type="crimeDate">September 6</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-33-off187 t17640912-33-cd188"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-33-person309">
                  John 
                  Hazard 
               <interp inst="t17640912-33-person309" type="surname" value="Hazard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-person309" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-person309" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17640912-33-viclabel189" type="occupation">clerk in the Bank of England</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-33-victim308 t17640912-33-viclabel189"></join>: I have frequently seen the prisoner Clark (for that is his right name) loitering about the Bank-yard, and in the Bow-china passage, which fronts the Bank gates; I never saw him doing business there; I first began to take notice of him about six weeks ago: I suspected by his not having business to do, that he was a bad man; I told several of the clerks I suspected him to be a pickpocket, as numbers of people had lost things. On the 6th of this instant September, I was informed he was in the bank-yard; I went into the bank, and told some of our clerks I would take my pocket-book and go out, and see whether he would attempt to pick my pocket of it: I went out, and pulled my pocket-case out in the yard, as he might see it, and put it in again: I went out, and he followed me into Castle-alley; there was nobody with him then: I stopped at the lottery-office-window, in Castle-alley, and he came and stood by me, on that side the book was: then I came through the alley into Cornhill, and stood at Mr. Kentish's toy shop; he came and stood there by me; then I turned into Pope's-head-alley, and stood at Mr. Shepherd's toy-shop; he followed me there likewise: then I passed him a little way, and stood to make water; then I went on, into Lombard-street, into the shop of Messrs. Breffey Ive, and Co. bankers; he followed me to their door, and staid there, and took notice of what I was doing in the shop; after I came out there, I turned into Lombard-street, and put my hand down by the side of my pocket, with my little finger by the side of it, that I might be able to feel it, if he took my book out of my pocket: I had not gone out at the door above ten or a dozen yards, before I felt him at it; I could almost take my oath that I felt him.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he hold of your pocket-book?</p>
               <p>Hazard. I will not swear that he had hold of it, but I believe he had; I was in some sort of a confussion, and went into the shop of Sir 
               <persName id="t17640912-33-person310">
                  Charles 
                  Asgill 
               <interp inst="t17640912-33-person310" type="surname" value="Asgill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-person310" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-person310" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , for I had between 2 and 300 l. of my own property, in another pocket, which I had forgot to put out, before I went on this affair; I depended on having the heels of him. He came and stood at Sir Charles's door, while I was there; after I came out, he followed me as before, and I imagine, made the same attempt; I went on, farther into Lombard-street, and he still followed me: I took my case out, when by the corner of Birchin-lane, and looked into it; he crossed the way, and looked into it also: then I turned up Birchin-lane, and went into the shop of Vere, Glynn, and Hallifax; he came and stood at the door the space of three minutes, while I was talking to the clerks; then I came out, and crossed the way, and went into 'Change-alley, and away to the bank; he followed me as far as the 'Change, before he dropped me: then I was convinced he was a thief: this was about ten o'clock in the forenoon. Then I told Mr. Carnaby I was very certain that he and I could take him; as he had attempted to pick my pocket once, he would do it again: so we told the gate-porter at the bank, if he saw him, to let us know; the porter knew him, and had told him to keep away before this. About one o'clock the same day, I was informed Clark was there again: I took another pocketbook, rather smaller than the other, that I thought would come out of my pocket easier, and only one note of hand, (the note mentioned in the indictment) and put it into my pocket, and desired Mr. Carnaby to come a little after me upon Change, and watch to see whether Clark saw me. I came out of the bank, and saw Clark and Smith, and another person, standing together, by the corner of Castle-alley.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176409120024"></xptr>Q. Had you seen Smith before?</p>
               <p>Hazard. I had seen him pass the bank gate once before.</p>
               <p>Q. How long before?</p>
               <p>Hazard. Perhaps eight or ten days before. I took out my pocket-case; I had put some blank draughts in it: I just shewed them, that they might imagine they were papers of great consequence, and put my book very carelesly into my pocket, and turned up Castle-alley: I just looked behind me, and saw these three people following me: I went into a little passage, that leads to the Royal Exchange, there is a cane and Toy-shop there; I stood there, with an intent of letting Mr Carnaby come up: I saw him coming; these three men stood behind me: they seemed to decline coming on, and rather drew back. Mr. Carnaby came up, but took no notice of me; I went and stood very near the statue of Sir 
               <persName id="t17640912-33-person311">
                  John 
                  Barnard 
               <interp inst="t17640912-33-person311" type="surname" value="Barnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-person311" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-person311" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , on the <placeName id="t17640912-33-crimeloc190">Royal Exchange</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640912-33-crimeloc190" type="placeName" value="Royal Exchange"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640912-33-crimeloc190" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-33-off187 t17640912-33-crimeloc190"></join>, and in about three seconds after I stopped, they all three came up, on that side where was my pocket-book: the third person began asking me about the inscription over Sir 
               <persName id="t17640912-33-person312">
                  John 
                  Barnard 
               <interp inst="t17640912-33-person312" type="surname" value="Barnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-person312" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-person312" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; Clark stood directly by the side of my pocket, or rather pushed himself against me, and Smith by the side of him. In a little time after we had been there, that third person asked me some insignificant questions; I then put my hand into my bosom, that they might have an opportunity of picking my pocket; and thought, as soon as I found one of them move, I might conclude my book was gone. I soon found 
               <persName id="t17640912-33-person313">
                  Clark
               <interp inst="t17640912-33-person313" type="given" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-person313" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a little upon the move; I put my hand down, and found my book was gone; I saw Mr. Carnaby coming up to him, he laid hold of the prisoners by their collars, and I did the same, and taxed Clark with picking my pocket; at which time, I saw my pocket-case fall from the breast of Smith. I picked it up: here is the case, and the note that was in it, (producing them): the note read to this purport:</p>
               <p>"July 11, 1764.</p>
               <p>"Three months after date, I promise to pay to</p>
               <p>"Mr. 
               <persName id="t17640912-33-person314">
                  John 
                  Hazard 
               <interp inst="t17640912-33-person314" type="surname" value="Hazard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-person314" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-person314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , or order, 22 l. 8 s. for</p>
               <p>"value received.</p>
               <p>"
               <persName id="t17640912-33-person315">
                  John 
                  Baker 
               <interp inst="t17640912-33-person315" type="surname" value="Baker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-person315" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-person315" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ."</p>
               <p>I have witnesses here, to the validity of the note, if it be required.</p>
               <p>Court. It is not to be supposed you would be deficient in that part, considering how well the rest of the scheme was plann'd.</p>
               <p>Hazard. I must say, Clark did it very dexterously, for I did not feel him take the pocket-case out. We took them before my Lord Mayor.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-33-person316">
                  Timothy 
                  Carnaby 
               <interp inst="t17640912-33-person316" type="surname" value="Carnaby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-person316" type="given" value="Timothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-person316" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I followed Mr Hazard out of the bank, and saw him by Sir 
               <persName id="t17640912-33-person317">
                  John 
                  Barnard 
               <interp inst="t17640912-33-person317" type="surname" value="Barnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-person317" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-person317" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's statue; I came about three or four yards behind him; the scheme was laid that I should follow him; Clark stood close by his right hand pocket, and Smith stood on Clark's right hand; he almost touched him; I don't know but what he did. I saw Clark pick Mr. Hazard's pocket of his pocket case, and deliver it to Smith.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know Clark before?</p>
               <p>Carnaby. I had seen him before several times, and knew his person very well.</p>
               <p>Clark's Defence.</p>
               <p>What I am charged with, I am quite innocent of: I was to meet my brother upon 'Change, and did meet him there, about some work. I was there about four or five minutes, and people came and shoved me into a crowd of gentlemen, and said, I had picked his pocket of things that he had lost.</p>
               <p>Smith's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was sent for home into the Borough, about some business: I stopped to see Sir 
               <persName id="t17640912-33-person318">
                  John 
                  Barnard 
               <interp inst="t17640912-33-person318" type="surname" value="Barnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-person318" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-person318" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's statue that was new painted: coming through the 'Change, some of these gentlemen catched hold on me, and accused me with having this man's book; I never saw it, till I saw it before my Lord Mayor.</p>
               <p>As the prosecutor went out with an intent that the prisoners should pick his pocket, it could not be said to be stealing from his person privately and secretly, without his knowledge.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17640912-33-verdict191" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-verdict191" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-verdict191" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               guilty of stealing, but not privately
            </rs>. <rs id="t17640912-33-punish192" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-33-punish192" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-33-defend301 t17640912-33-punish192"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-33-defend304 t17640912-33-punish192"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
