<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17631207-31">
               <interp inst="t17631207-31" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-31" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-31" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17631207"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-31" type="date" value="17631207"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17631207-31-off173-c239" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-31-defend305 t17631207-31-off173 t17631207-31-verdict175"></join>
         
               <p>35. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17631207-31-defend305" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Wilkinson 
                  <interp inst="t17631207-31-defend305" type="surname" value="Wilkinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-31-defend305" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-31-defend305" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17631207-31-off173" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631207-31-off173" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-31-off173" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing ten silver table-spoons, value 15 s. two silver tea-spoons, value 2 s. two pair of silver shoe-buckles, value 10 s. one steel sword, with a silver-hilt, and two linnen aprons
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17631207-31-victim307" type="victimName">
                     Peter 
                     Anderson 
                  <interp inst="t17631207-31-victim307" type="surname" value="Anderson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-31-victim307" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-31-victim307" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-31-off173 t17631207-31-victim307"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17631207-31-cd174" type="crimeDate">November 11</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-31-off173 t17631207-31-cd174"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-31-person308">
                  Hannah 
                  Champion 
               <interp inst="t17631207-31-person308" type="surname" value="Champion"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-31-person308" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-31-person308" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mr. Anderson; he is my uncle. The prisoner came as a lodger to our house; I lay in a first pair of stair's room; the prisoner was gone to bed before I went up; his room was up three pair of stairs; I went to go to bed, and heard a disturbance below stairs; I went down stairs, and saw the prisoner at the bar in the fore-room; I asked him, what he wanted; he told me, he wanted to go out; I told him, there was a door backwards; I did not know that any thing was lost at that time; on turning himself round, I saw an apron hang out of his pocket; I took it out, it was my aunt's apron; I went up stairs to call my uncle, and, in the mean time, he went out at the back door; I had observed, there were more things in his pocket, but could not tell what they were; we missed the buckles and spoons out of the chest of drawers in my uncle's room; he had not been in the house above half an hour, before he came down stairs with the things.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-31-person309">
                  Peter 
                  Anderson 
               <interp inst="t17631207-31-person309" type="surname" value="Anderson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-31-person309" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-31-person309" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner came on the Friday morning, and asked me to lend him a little money, saying, he had money coming from a man of war, which he should take on the Monday. I enquired, and found it was so; and, as the man was a good looking man, I let him have 3 s. and 6 d. he asked me, if I would give him liberty to stay at my house, two or three days, till he took his money. I went out, with my wife, to a friend's to dinner; and, when I came home, my niece told me, the prisoner was gone to bed; we went to bed at about eleven; my niece said, she thought there was something taken out of the room; so she sat up after she had seen the prisoner, as she mentioned; she came up with the apron, and said, the man that we had let to lay there, was a thief, and she believed he had got more things. The prisoner was taken in the little house backwards.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-31-person310">
                  William 
                  Kinton 
               <interp inst="t17631207-31-person310" type="surname" value="Kinton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-31-person310" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-31-person310" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am headborough of St. Catharine's. I was informed, a man, that came from Portsmouth, that had taken a lodging at the prosecutor's, had robbed him, and that he was got out into a back-yard: We went out upon the tiles in search for him, and at last took him in the Necessary-house. It was the prisoner at the bar, with all the things mentioned in the indictment upon him; he had the sword in his hand. (The things produced, and deposed to.)</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was very much in liquor. I have been guilty of taking the things, and I am sorry for it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17631207-31-verdict175" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631207-31-verdict175" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17631207-31-punish176" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631207-31-punish176" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-31-defend305 t17631207-31-punish176"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
