<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640912-51">
               <interp inst="t17640912-51" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-51" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-51" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640912"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-51" type="date" value="17640912"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640912-51-off285-c366" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-51-defend466 t17640912-51-off285 t17640912-51-verdict291"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640912-51-off286-c368" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-51-defend470 t17640912-51-off286 t17640912-51-verdict293"></join>
         
               <p>534, 535. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17640912-51-defend466" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Foster 
                  <interp inst="t17640912-51-defend466" type="surname" value="Foster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-51-defend466" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-51-defend466" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             was indicted for <rs id="t17640912-51-off285" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-51-off285" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-51-off285" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a silver watch, value 40 s. and 140 l. in money, numbered, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640912-51-victim468" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Kennedy 
                        <interp inst="t17640912-51-victim468" type="surname" value="Kennedy"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640912-51-victim468" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640912-51-victim468" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling house of the said Richard
            </rs>, and 
               
                  <persName id="t17640912-51-defend470" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Logan 
                  <interp inst="t17640912-51-defend470" type="surname" value="Logan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-51-defend470" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-51-defend470" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , for <rs id="t17640912-51-off286" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-51-off286" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-51-off286" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving 6 l. 19 s. 9 d. part of the said money, well knowing it to have been stolen
            </rs>, <rs id="t17640912-51-cd287" type="crimeDate">September 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-51-off285 t17640912-51-cd287"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-51-off286 t17640912-51-cd287"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-51-person471">
                  Richard 
                  Kennedy 
               <interp inst="t17640912-51-person471" type="surname" value="Kennedy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-51-person471" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-51-person471" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at <placeName id="t17640912-51-crimeloc288">Cock-hill in the parish of Stepney</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640912-51-crimeloc288" type="placeName" value="Cock-hill in the parish of Stepney"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640912-51-crimeloc288" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-51-off285 t17640912-51-crimeloc288"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-51-off286 t17640912-51-crimeloc288"></join>. I am a <rs id="t17640912-51-viclabel289" type="occupation">cabinet maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-51-victim468 t17640912-51-viclabel289"></join>. 
               <persName id="t17640912-51-person472">
                  Thomas 
                  Foster 
               <interp inst="t17640912-51-person472" type="surname" value="Foster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-51-person472" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-51-person472" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was a <rs id="t17640912-51-deflabel290" type="occupation">journeyman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-51-defend466 t17640912-51-deflabel290"></join> that worked with me: on Monday was se'ennight, about 11 o'clock, he was at work above in the upper shop with me; I sent him down for a tool that I wanted; he staid longer than I thought necessary; I imagined he might have been gone backwards: at the time he was below, a gentleman's servant came and knocked at the door, with a letter for me; but instead of letting him in, he came up with the tool I sent him for: I went down, and took the letter, and looked into it: while I was below, he came down stairs and went out; I had not been below above fifteen minutes, but I missed him; I seeing things in the shop in some disorder, I went into the back-shop, and could not see him; I went down stairs and asked my sister whether she saw him go out? she said, no. Upon the disorder I saw the things in, I ran to my desk, and found it open.</p>
               <p>Q. In what part of your house is your desk?</p>
               <p>Kennedy. It stands in a lower room, just behind my shop; the stairs go down into the room; I looked in it, and missed the drawer where I used to put my money: I ran out directly, and called to some porters that were drinking at a public house, and asked them if they saw him? ( they all knew him) they said, no. He went out with a waistcoat without sleeves: I went to his lodging; the people there said he had not been there: I told the porters what I had lost; they went in pursuit of him.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you miss?</p>
               <p>Kennedy. I missed near 200 l. not above 1 l. or 2 l. more or less, and a silver watch. I went in pursuit of him. I met a little lad, of whom I enquired; he told me he met such a person enquiring for Stepney-fields. Then I took a turn round rag-fair, thinking he would go and buy clothes, and desired the people, if any such person came to buy clothes, to stop him and send for me. I could hear nothing of him: I went to Sir 
               <persName id="t17640912-51-person473">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17640912-51-person473" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-51-person473" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-51-person473" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , but could hear nothing of him: that day. The next day I heard there had been such a man enquiring for the first West-India-man going out; but that I found, upon farther enquiry, not to be him: I took horse, and went down to Gravesend, in order to search all outward bound ships; I could hear nothing of him; I went to bed; in about a quarter of an hour after, a man that I had sent to enquire about, came and told me there had been such a man that had bought slops, shirts, jackets, and things, and was gone down to Chatham. I went down to Chatham immediately. When I came there, the people at the Horn were<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176409120036"></xptr> in bed; I was obliged to inn at the Globe; I told the landlady the reason of my riding so late; she said, she believed she had two such men as I had described that came there and were in bed.</p>

               <p>Q. What other man besides the prisoner did you describe?</p>
               <p>Kennedy. I was told that Logan and he had been seen several times together, and I had enquired at Logan's lodgings, and he was gone. I desired of the landlady to see the men; then it was much about twelve at night. She said I was to lie in the room adjoining to where they lay: I went up; and there I saw the two prisoners in bed together; I seized Foster directly; he was for getting up; he took hold of the knee of his breeches, there tumbled out ten guineas in gold and silver from his pocket: the landlady went and called the hostler; and he called four soldiers that were quartered in the house: I asked Foster, Where was my watch and the rest of my money? he said, D - n you, don't you know your own watch. There was a watch hanging by the bed-side. When he took it there was no string to it, and then it had one, and a silver seal to it. I told the landlord, on the dial-plate was Clay, London; and in the inside was C. Clay, and I believed there was no number: when I looked upon it, it appeared to be my watch: he would not confess to any more money that night. I then applied myself to Logan, and desired to know what money he had got? he put his hand in his pocket and gave me a guinea and a half, and a five and threepenny piece: I said, is that all? he said, yes. We took them to the marine guard, and kept them there till morning. We went to their lodging again; there Foster took a key out and opened a chest, and in the till were eleven half crowns; in another corner of the chest was a bag of gold and silver, which with the other amounted to 86 l. and upwards. They acknowledged it to be my money: then we had them before a Justice at Chatham; the Justice took and sealed up the money, with the watch, and delivered them to the constable, to be brought with the prisoners to London. When we came back to the Globe, we ask'd them if there was any more money? they would not own to any more. The Gentleman searched them separately, and took out of the shirts of Logan's coat two thirty-six shilling-pieces, a guinea, and some silver, which amounted to 5 l. 3 s. I brought them to London, and the watch and money sealed up; and delivered it at the examination before Justice Berry to the constable; they acknowledged before the Justice that the money was mine; and Foster acknowledged there that he took it. I have the key here, that I found in his breeches that he had on when he went off, in his chest that we brought from Chatham; his clothes were in the chest: that key he owned he made use of to open the Lock; I have tried it, and it will lock and unlock my desk.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-51-person474">
                  Walter 
                  Rigby 
               <interp inst="t17640912-51-person474" type="surname" value="Rigby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-51-person474" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-51-person474" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the constable to whom the watch and money were delivered; (producing them in a paper sealed up. The prosecutor takes them in his hand and opens the paper.)</p>
               <p>Prosecuter. This is my watch; this lay in the same drawer where my money lay: Foster acknowledged he took the drawer out; I asked him what he had done with it? he said the drawer was in my own house: I asked him where? he said, in the wash-house. It was found in the wash-house, under the step of the stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. to Rigby. Did you hear the prisoners own to any thing?</p>

               <p>Rigby. I heard Foster confess before Justice Berry that he took the money and watch.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say where he had taken it from?</p>
               <p>Rigby. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Foster's Defence.</p>
               <p>I came down stairs; the watch and money were lying loose in the bureau, and the desk was open.</p>
               <p>Foster <rs id="t17640912-51-verdict291" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-51-verdict291" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17640912-51-punish292" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-51-punish292" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-51-defend466 t17640912-51-punish292"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Logan <rs id="t17640912-51-verdict293" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-51-verdict293" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
