<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640502-80">
               <interp inst="t17640502-80" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640502-80" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640502-80" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640502"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640502-80" type="date" value="17640502"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640502-80-off451-c571" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-80-defend732 t17640502-80-off451 t17640502-80-verdict452"></join>
         
               <p>314. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17640502-80-defend732" type="defendantName">
                  Elizabeth, <rs id="t17640502-80-deflabel450" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-80-defend732 t17640502-80-deflabel450"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17640502-80-person733">
                        John 
                        Dunn 
                     <interp inst="t17640502-80-person733" type="surname" value="Dunn"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640502-80-person733" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640502-80-person733" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17640502-80-alias-9" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-80-defend732 t17640502-80-alias-9"></join>Buck</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-80-defend732" type="surname" value="Dunn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-80-defend732" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-80-defend732" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17640502-80-off451" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640502-80-off451" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-80-off451" type="offenceSubcategory" value="coiningOffences"></interp>
               uttering a counterfeit six-pence, knowing it to be false and a counterfeit
            </rs>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640502-80-person734">
                  Martha 
                  Richards 
               <interp inst="t17640502-80-person734" type="surname" value="Richards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-80-person734" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-80-person734" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the horse-shoe and magpye in Cheapside. I have known the prisoner four years: the first time I saw her, she came in the morning, and called for a pennyworth of beer: she brought me a six-pence that was not a good one; from thence I had a foundation of suspicion of her: the last time I saw her, was the Tuesday before last sessions; she always called for a pennyworth of beer, and gave a bad six-pence. I have taken several, but the last she gave my servant,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176405020045"></xptr> and he brought it to me; his name is 
               <persName id="t17640502-80-person735">
                  Thomas 
                  Tugwell 
               <interp inst="t17640502-80-person735" type="surname" value="Tugwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-80-person735" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-80-person735" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I asked him who he had it of? and went with him to the prisoner, and asked her if it was her six-pence? she said it was: I said it was not a six-pence; she wanted it again, but I would not give it her; then she gave me a penny; (Produced and inspected by the bench and the jury: it appeared to be high tempered pewter.) Mr. Ribright was at my house; and he took it, and nailed it up at the door. I then let her go: the very next Tuesday she came again.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I never saw the woman in all my days: I never was in her house in all my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640502-80-person736">
                  Thomas 
                  Tugwell 
               <interp inst="t17640502-80-person736" type="surname" value="Tugwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-80-person736" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-80-person736" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have lived servant with Mr. Richards three quarters of a year. The prisoner came to our house, and called for a pennyworth of beer; she sat down on the bench: before she drank it, she gave me a sixpence, and said, young man, go and get change. I went with it to my mistress, she looked at it, and said, Tom, where did you get this six-pence? I told her I had it of the prisoner; and my mistress went to her.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure the prisoner is the woman you had the six-pence of?</p>
               <p>Tugwell. I am positive she is the woman,</p>
               <p>Mr. Sayer. I have a six-pence here that the prisoner gave me into my own hand, on a Thursday, about three months ago. I keep the Excise Coffee-house, and sell beer, as well as coffee and tea. She came in, and called for a pennyworth of beer, and sat down in a box in the room; I was then warming some wine, to go to the excise-office; I had taken notice of her before, and said, take notice that woman does not give you bad money: I did not go with the wine, but went to her, and said, Mrs. have you paid? she gave me this sixpence; (producing a pewter one); she pulled out three more at the same time, that were all good. (The jury inspect the six-pence; it appeared the same as the other).</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I went into that house, and called for a pennyworth of beer; I gave the boy a six-pence: the boy staid six or seven minutes from me, and his master came; he said, it was a bad six-pence, and he would take me up; he was near half an hour: he would not give me change till his wife came; then I gave her another six-pence. He said to me, you are the person that has come several times, and brought bad sixpences here; and before God, I never was in that house in my life before. He brought a constable, and seized me. I had four sixpences in my pocket, and did not know it was a bad one.</p>
               <p>Sayer. She gave it to me, and not to the boy; I always took notice, that when this woman came to my house, I always found bad money in my till: she has been in my house. I dare say, a score of times. She never would tell where she lived, or where she got her bread.</p>
               <p>Richards. It was the Tuesday before that she offered me this</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640502-80-verdict452" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640502-80-verdict452" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17640502-80-punish453" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640502-80-punish453" type="punishmentCategory" value="imprison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-80-punish453" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="newgate"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-80-defend732 t17640502-80-punish453"></join>
               Im
            </rs>. </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640502-80-punish454" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640502-80-punish454" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-80-punish454" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="sureties"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-80-defend732 t17640502-80-punish454"></join>
               
                     <note>[Provide sureties for good behaviour. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
