<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17601022-21">
               <interp inst="t17601022-21" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17601022-21" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17601022-21" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17601022"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17601022-21" type="date" value="17601022"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17601022-21-off123-c249" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-21-defend290 t17601022-21-off123 t17601022-21-verdict126"></join>
         
               <p>312. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17601022-21-defend290" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Duprose 
                  <interp inst="t17601022-21-defend290" type="surname" value="Duprose"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-21-defend290" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-21-defend290" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17601022-21-off123" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17601022-21-off123" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-21-off123" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a bank note, value 100 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17601022-21-victim292" type="victimName">
                     Moses 
                     Jacobs 
                  <interp inst="t17601022-21-victim292" type="surname" value="Jacobs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-21-victim292" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-21-victim292" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-21-off123 t17601022-21-victim292"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17601022-21-cd124" type="crimeDate">Oct. 6</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-21-off123 t17601022-21-cd124"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601022-21-person293">
                  Moses 
                  Jacobs 
               <interp inst="t17601022-21-person293" type="surname" value="Jacobs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-21-person293" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-21-person293" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner at the bar was my <rs id="t17601022-21-deflabel125" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-21-defend290 t17601022-21-deflabel125"></join>; on the 12th of October I miss'd a 100 l. bank note; I sent for a constable, and told him, I had a suspicion of my maid. He said, I must advertise it; I advertised it in the paper on the monday, ten guineas reward; a woman came that same day, and told me, she had notice of it; I promised her five guineas for herself, as she said she had not got it, but knew the person that had; I gave her a note for the five guineas.</p>
               <p>Q. What was her name?</p>
               <p>Moses. Her name was Mrs. Hancock. I went to the bank, and slopp'd the payment of the note;<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176010220034"></xptr> she told my brother where it was; he came and told me he must go with me, and carry the money; I went as he directed to a woman nam'd Tompson, in Rosemary lane; she said, are you the man that has lost the back note; I said yes; says she, is your name Moses Jacobs; I said yes; she said, then deposit the money, and I'll give you the note; I deposited the money; my bank note was put upon the table, with my own number, No. 33, letter B. After I had got it. I asked her, if she did not know 
               <persName id="t17601022-21-person294">
                  Mary 
                  Duprose 
               <interp inst="t17601022-21-person294" type="surname" value="Duprose"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-21-person294" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-21-person294" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , that lived with me. She said no; my maid was in the counter, and the constable took her before the alderman. Then we had a warrant for Tompson and Hancock, they both were brought before the alderman, and the next day before my Lord Mayor: there Tompson was in different stories; at first she said, she found it; then she said, another person found it; but at last she said, she had it from my maid, the prisoner at the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. What answer did the prisoner make to that?</p>
               <p>Jacobs. The prisoner said, she gave it her on saturday. Tompson said, she received it of her on the friday.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner own that she took it out of your drawer?</p>
               <p>Jacobs. At that time she did not; I believe she did afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. What were her words?</p>
               <p>Jacobs. I was present, and heard her, but I cannot think directly what she said.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601022-21-person295">
                  Abraham 
                  Abrahams 
               <interp inst="t17601022-21-person295" type="surname" value="Abrahams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-21-person295" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-21-person295" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 12th of October, Mr. Jacobs sent for me to his house, and told me, he had lost a bank note of a hundred pounds, and he suspected his servant to have taken it. I ask'd him where she was; he said, she was gone to Mr. Gregory's, in Crutchet Fryers; he and I went there; when we came there, they said she was not come, but they expected her to drink tea; I staid there, and in about half an hour she came in; her master told her, her mistress was taken ill, and she must come home; I followed her, and when she came there, I desired her to walk up stairs. She went up, then her master charged her with taking the bank note of 100 l. she said, she never had been guilty of any such thing; I being constable, ordered a woman to search her; she was searched, but nothing found upon her. Her master promised her, if she would tell where the note was, he would give her ten guineas, which he had advertised; she persisted in her innocency, and would make no discovery The next morning I was sent for to Mr. Jacobs's house, about eight o'clock, there was Mrs. Hancock; she said, she could give an account about the note: but said, she expected something for her trouble; Mr. Jacobs agreed to give her five guineas, and gave her a note of hand for it, to be paid upon its being produced. The note was produced by Mrs. Townsend; Mr. Jacobs was mistaken in the name, he call'd her Tompson; he gave Townsend ten guineas, and Hancock a note of 5, on her producing the woman with the note; the note was ordered to be returned by my Lord Mayor.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did Mr. Jacobs receive his note again?</p>
               <p>Jacobs. After Hancock had told Townsend's name, Townsend sent word, she would not come; if Mr. Jacobs had a mind to have his note, he might come and fetch it. I went with him to the seven Stars in Rosemary lane; then she said, if Mr. Jacobs would deposit ten guineas in the landlord's hand, she would produce it; and she delivered the note upon her receiving the ten guineas. Then I told her this note had been stolen by a woman that was to be examined before my Lord Mayor to-day; and ask'd her, if she knew the prisoner Duprose; she said, she never heard her name in her life: the next day I took the prisoner before Mr. alderman Alexander; and upon hearing these two womens names, then she said, she found the note at a cheesemonger's door in White Chappel, and that she had given it to Mrs. Townsend for her to see what it was. Upon that Mr. alderman Alexander committed her to the counter, and ordered a warrant to be made out against the other two women; the next day I took them both before my Lord Mayor; and upon his examining Townsend, she own'd she received the bank note of the prisoner at the bar. My Lord Mayor sent for the prisoner; she was ask'd, if she gave it her, and she said she did, for her to tell her what it was.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing of it, or I would have had people to my character.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17601022-21-verdict126" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17601022-21-verdict126" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17601022-21-punish127" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17601022-21-punish127" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-21-punish127" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-21-defend290 t17601022-21-punish127"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
