<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17620224-5">
               <interp inst="t17620224-5" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620224-5" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620224-5" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17620224"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620224-5" type="date" value="17620224"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620224-5-off24-c65" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-5-defend72 t17620224-5-off24 t17620224-5-verdict29"></join>
         
               <p>92. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17620224-5-defend72" type="defendantName">
                     Patrick 
                     Teeling 
                  <interp inst="t17620224-5-defend72" type="surname" value="Teeling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-5-defend72" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-5-defend72" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17620224-5-off24" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620224-5-off24" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-5-off24" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               stealing a firkin of butter and a Gloucester cheese
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17620224-5-victim74" type="victimName">
                     Joseph 
                     Hickman 
                  <interp inst="t17620224-5-victim74" type="surname" value="Hickman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-5-victim74" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-5-victim74" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-5-off24 t17620224-5-victim74"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17620224-5-cd25" type="crimeDate">Jan. 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-5-off24 t17620224-5-cd25"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620224-5-person75">
                  Joseph 
                  Hickman 
               <interp inst="t17620224-5-person75" type="surname" value="Hickman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-5-person75" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-5-person75" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17620224-5-viclabel26" type="occupation">cheesemonger</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-5-victim74 t17620224-5-viclabel26"></join> at East Smith-field, and the day before Christmas-day I missed a cask of west country butter, about 56 lb.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you miss it?</p>
               <p>Hickman. The 24th of December I was down at my warehouse at <placeName id="t17620224-5-crimeloc27">Woolwich</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17620224-5-crimeloc27" type="placeName" value="Woolwich"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17620224-5-crimeloc27" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-5-off24 t17620224-5-crimeloc27"></join>; there were 10 firkins of this sort, and 20 of another; and, upon looking it over, I found one of the ten was missing.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was it you first missed your cheese?</p>
               <p>Hickman. At the same time and place?</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you find this butter and cheese again?</p>
               <p>Hickman. In the hands of Mr. Trumbell, constable. [The case produced, the hoops were stripped off, and just begun to be cut.]</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know this firkin to be yours?</p>
               <p>Hickman. The dairyman cuts the letters I H, and the cooper likewise marks them with this mark. [ Showing it.]</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure, from these marks, that this is your firkin of butter?</p>
               <p>Hickman. Yes, I am sure of it; and by the like marks I know the cheese to be mine, taken out of 15 that I had of the same sort, and I went before the justice to swear to the goods.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner before the justice with you?</p>
               <p>Hickman. Yes; and the justice told him he was very sorry to see a man so capable of getting his bread charged with a thing of that kind. He said he had found them, and that what he thought a fault, he thought none. However, he went away from me at that time, and soon after sent me a letter that he was innocent; that he should attend his business, and would surrender himself to the constable in time, or to the same effect.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620224-5-person76">
                  Richard 
                  Trumbell 
               <interp inst="t17620224-5-person76" type="surname" value="Trumbell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-5-person76" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-5-person76" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , constable. I took the butter and cheese mentioned out of the prisoner's house by a search warrant.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they appear to be concealed when you found them?</p>
               <p>Trumbell. The cask of butter was on the ground floor, and the cheese in a drawer in the room.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find the prisoner at that time?</p>
               <p>Trumbell. No, I did not, he came afterwards, and surrendered himself to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you acquaint his wife that you had a warrant against him?</p>
               <p>Trumbell. Yes, and he came and surrendered to me at my house the 18th day of January; then I took him before justice Scot, after acquainting Mr Hickman of it, who went with us.</p>
               <p>Q. What passed before justice Scot?</p>
               <p>Trumbell. He said he had found the goods in the stern-sheet of a lighter at Bull Wharf stairs, above bridge.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620224-5-person77">
                  Charles 
                  Berry 
               <interp inst="t17620224-5-person77" type="surname" value="Berry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-5-person77" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-5-person77" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I left my boat at Dier's Wharf, on this side Bull Wharf, under the care of the watchman.</p>
               <p>Q. What was there in your boat?</p>
               <p>Berry. Ten firkins of butter, and forty-eight cheese.</p>
               <p>Q. Whose property were they?</p>
               <p>Berry. Mr. Hickman's, delivered by Mr. Hickman's waterman, and I was to take up 20 firkins more at the Three Cranes.</p>
               <p>Q. You staid all night, you say; when did you take in the other 20?</p>
               <p>Berry. The next morning, and carried it from thence to Woolwich.</p>
               <p>Q. What day?</p>
               <p>Berry. The day before Christmas-day.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you miss this firkin of butter?</p>
               <p>Berry. In the morning, before we took in the other 20, and likewise the cheese.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you give Mr. Hickman notice of it?</p>
               <p>Berry. I sent my servant down to Woolwich, and mean while I went and got a search warrant and the constable for to search, and I found them at the prisoner's house, in the manner before-mentioned, and did not go to acquaint Mr. Hickman of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does the prisoner live?</p>
               <p>Berry. At Red-maid Lane.</p>
               <p>Q. How far might that be from the wharf where the goods lay?</p>
               <p>Berry. About a quarter of a mile.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the latest time in the evening when you saw those goods?</p>
               <p>Berry. About 9 o'clock, when I left the boat.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure that when you left the boat yourself, all the butter and cheese was in the boat?</p>
               <p>Berry. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you seen the marks on the butter tub and the cheese when you took them into your boat?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176202240007"></xptr>Berry. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Now, pray, what induced you to get a search warrant to search the prisoner's house?</p>
               <p>Berry. The watchman at the Red Bull wharf said he had seen the prisoner at that wharf about twelve o'clock that night.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I am <rs id="t17620224-5-deflabel28" type="occupation">a lighterman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-5-defend72 t17620224-5-deflabel28"></join>, and it is my business to be out all hours of the night, in order to do my business, and I went up to Red Bull wharf that night, about 12 o'clock, to see if the lighters were safe or in any danger, and my partner was with me, and we saw one lighter that was headmost in some danger, and, wanting a rope to secure it, I went into the other lighter that lay sternmost to get a rope; and I went down, my Lord, and observed a bag containing these things; and I said to my fellow servant, Here is something of a prize; and I handed it from under the lighter's storn sheet, and said I would carry it home to my house for safety, and when inquiry was made, the right owner should have it, there it should be ready for them; which I did. I was obliged to go away again about my business; and before I returned home again, a person told me my house had been searched, and such things found. I said I was innocent as to any theft; but when such things were found, I had carried them home, that the owner, upon inquiry, might have them again. I went home, and out again, as my business called me, till such time as they began to find the bills at Hicks's Hall the last session, then I was less at home; and I sent my wife to Mr. Hickman, to let him know that it was not thro' any fear of coming to him, I knew myself innocent, and he might depend upon it I would appear at the proper time to answer for myself at the court; I was told, my Lord, that if I did, I need not go before the justice. I came and spoke to Mr. Akerman, and said, I came in order to surrender myself; but Mr. Akerman said, there was no bail found, and therefore he could take no surrender; upon that I went into my business again, and I think in two or three days afterwards I went to surrender myself to the constable, with bail for my appearance. At this time, my Lord, I went before the justice, who said, there cannot be any bail for you. I said, that was very hard, for I was very unwilling to injure my family; but that did not avail, I was committed.</p>

               <p>Q. Have you any witnesses to produce in favour of you?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My fellow-servant, who knows that I only carried the things home till a right owner could be found.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620224-5-person78">
                  Samuel 
                  Woodward 
               <interp inst="t17620224-5-person78" type="surname" value="Woodward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-5-person78" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-5-person78" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a lighterman; I live at the Hermitage, servant to one Mr. Staples, and the prisoner was fellow-servant with me a great many years, and was at this time; and it is our business to look after our craft, and to do what business offers, and look out for more; and in the night preceding the 24th of December I was in a lighter at Red Bull wharf, to make it fast, and there was another lighter by, which my partner went into, to get a piece of rope; and, going down into the stern sheet, he found the bag with the things mentioned, and he said, Here is a prize; and I said, Hand it up, which he did; and it was put into the skiff, and he carried it to his house, saying, Somebody may inquire after it, and, if they do, they may have it; and afterwards, on the same day, I heard his house had been searched.</p>
               <p>Q. So you heard him say he would take it home, that if any-body inquired after it they might have it?</p>
               <p>Woodward. Yes, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not look to see what prize this was?</p>
               <p>Woodward. No, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Then you did not inspect it at all, but went down with your lighter, and, upon your return the same day, heard the prisoner's house had been searched. - Did you hear by whom, and on whose behalf?</p>
               <p>Woodward. I think not till the day after.</p>
               <p>Q. As you appear to be acquainted with this affair, did you ever go to acquaint Mr. Hickman with it, or of his character?</p>
               <p>Woodward. No, my lord, I never troubled myself about it; Mr. Hickman had his things, and the prisoner follow'd his business as usual, and continued so to do for two months, so I thought nothing more would come of it.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hickman was asked if the constable endeavoured to take him?</p>
               <p>Mr. Hickman said the constable told him he had.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620224-5-person79">
                  Richard 
                  Trumbell 
               <interp inst="t17620224-5-person79" type="surname" value="Trumbell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-5-person79" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-5-person79" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , constable, called.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you endeavour to take this man?</p>
               <p>Trumbell. I did, I went to find him several times, three or four times to his house; and when ever I enquired for him, I was told he was in his business on board the lighter.</p>
               <p>Mr. Jones. I have known the prisoner these ten years, and have employed him ever since August last; he has done my business very well, he has been intrusted with lighters loaded with linen cloth, and other goods of value, and we never missed any thing from them, and from whatever I know, or ever heard of him, he is an honest man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17620224-5-verdict29" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620224-5-verdict29" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
