<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640502-37">
               <interp inst="t17640502-37" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640502-37" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640502-37" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640502"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640502-37" type="date" value="17640502"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640502-37-off206-c244" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-37-defend309 t17640502-37-off206 t17640502-37-verdict209"></join>
         
               <p>262. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17640502-37-defend309" type="defendantName">
                  Mary, the <rs id="t17640502-37-deflabel205" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-37-defend309 t17640502-37-deflabel205"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17640502-37-person310">
                        John 
                        Hargrove 
                     <interp inst="t17640502-37-person310" type="surname" value="Hargrove"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640502-37-person310" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640502-37-person310" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
                     <interp inst="t17640502-37-defend309" type="surname" value="Hargrove"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-37-defend309" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-37-defend309" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for the <rs id="t17640502-37-off206" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640502-37-off206" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-37-off206" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               wilful murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640502-37-victim312" type="victimName">
                           Anne 
                           Davis 
                        <interp inst="t17640502-37-victim312" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640502-37-victim312" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640502-37-victim312" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-37-off206 t17640502-37-victim312"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , by striking her on the head with an iron poker, on the <rs id="t17640502-37-cd207" type="crimeDate">6th of April</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-37-off206 t17640502-37-cd207"></join>, and giving her a mortal wound; the depth half an inch, and breadth one inch; of which wound she died
            </rs> on the 24th.</p>
               <p>She stood charged on the coroner's inquest for the like murder. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640502-37-person313">
                  Sarah 
                  Littlewood 
               <interp inst="t17640502-37-person313" type="surname" value="Littlewood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-37-person313" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-37-person313" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The deceased, Anne Davis, aggravated the prisoner very much, and she took up the poker, and hit the deceased over the head.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>S. Littlewood. This was about three weeks, or a month ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>S. Littlewood. This was at the prisoner's house, <placeName id="t17640502-37-crimeloc208">the Bull and Butcher, in Brown's Gardens, in the tap-room</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640502-37-crimeloc208" type="placeName" value="the Bull and Butcher, in Brown's Gardens, in the tap-room"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640502-37-crimeloc208" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-37-off206 t17640502-37-crimeloc208"></join>.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176405020019"></xptr>Q. In what manner did the deceased aggravate her?</p>
               <p>S. Littlewood. The deceased said she made a whore of her daughter-in-law.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any thing passed besides words?</p>
               <p>S. Littlewood. No, nothing but words.</p>
               <p>Q. What happened after the blow?</p>
               <p>S. Littlewood. The deceased got up from her seat in the box, and went out of the room.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any wound?</p>
               <p>S. Littlewood. No, I did not see the wound: I saw blood come immediately; she said she had got a cut on her head, and would go for a warrant: I never saw her afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a blow was it?</p>
               <p>S. Littlewood. A small blow: (an iron poker produced.) This is the poker. *</p>
               <p>* Note, it was a common kitchen-poker, the great end pretty weighty.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I struck the woman with that poker, or a bigger, and if the surgeon that opened her, is of opinion that was the cause of her death, I am willing to die for it. It cut her, to be sure, and she bled excessively; if that is the surgeon's opinion, I am willing to lay down my life for her life.</p>
               <p>Joseph Randall. The deceased sent for me, and I dressed her head on the Friday evening; I desired her to go to bed, and apply a warm poultice to it, and if she was not capable to come to me, to send word, and I would wait on her: she came the next two days, which was Saturday and Sunday, I dressed the wound and examined it, but could not find any fracture; she only complained of a little pain in her head. On the Monday, she sent word to my house, she would be glad if I would come to her; I went and enquired for her; I went in at the Bull and Butcher: Mrs. Hargrove asked me who ordered me to attend? I said I had orders from Justice Welch to attend the deceased, and dress the wound; she said, she was to pay for it, and she would employ who she pleased: she would not shew me the room. I enquired, and found her, and dressed her; and after I had dressed her, Mrs. Hargrove came up into the room, and another woman with her; there was another woman before in the room. After I had dressed it, Mrs. Hargrove insisted upon seeing it, I said I had just dressed it, and begged she would not take off the dressings. She attempted to pull the dressings off: I told her it was upon the head, and it might be of dangerous consequence: then I desired her to send for a surgeon from he hospital for fear of he consequence. She said it was no business of mine, she would take care and provide a surgeon. I left the room, and never saw her till I was sent for to open the head after she was dead.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner take the dressings of?</p>
               <p>Randall. I believe she did; I know the cap was off, and she attempted it; but whether she did or not, I am not quite certain. She seemed to be in a passion, and I left the room.</p>
               <p>Q. When was you sent for to open the head?</p>
               <p>Randall. That was on a Thursday, pretty near three weeks after. I opened her head, and found matter under the place where the blow was given upon the brain; I take it to be matter that proceeded from extravased blood: I saw also a black spot between the first and second rib, on the right side, and on the left side there were two broken ribs, the 5th and 6th.</p>
               <p>Q. Had she complained of her ribs to you?</p>
               <p>Randall. No, she never did to me; there was a great inflammation on the right side of the lungs.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon the whole, what was the judgment you formed, as to the cause of her death?</p>
               <p>Randall. I do imagine the blows that were given her, were the cause of her death.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether the blow on the head was the cause of her death?</p>
               <p>Randall. I think that was the principal thing. With proper care, it might not have proved mortal.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. Whether the violent blow she had on the temple might not be more the cause of that matter, than that of the poker? I want no favour.</p>
               <p>Randall. I don't know that I found any bruise on the side of the head.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I offered her Surgeon Watson.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether according to your judgment, what she received on the ribs appeared like to be mortal?</p>
               <p>Randall. No, my lord, they did not: there was no; or a very slight inflammation on her side.</p>
               <p>Mr. Moffet. I was sent for by the prisoner, on the Thursday; I examined the body, and found on the outside a black spot, between the collar-bone and the 2 d rib; there was a small sore on the head: that I was informed was in consequence of a blow she had received on the left side of the head; there was a trifling blackness below the left eye; we proceeded then to open the chest, and the first object of our attention was, to see whether this black spot was nearly more than skin deep; that part appeared quite unhurt: the chest being opened, the right side of the lungs appeared quite black, and quite condensed; they were<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176405020020"></xptr> gathered up into a solid matter; there was about a pint and a half of thin matter, in which the lungs were swiming; we took them out, and put them in water; they readily swam in water; they appeared to have been useless a considerable time before the decease of the person: we then looked into the left side of the body, and found the 5th and 6th ribs broke, but the lungs were not in the least hurt by the broken ribs. These I mention because I would give my opinion clearly. As to that upon the head, I found under the scalp, the bone was bare for a considerable distance, the brain was covered with matter, but this matter would have appeared from the injury without. I gave my opinion before the coroner, that these wounds she had, were the cause of her death; but being acquainted with circumstances since, which I did not know before, that is, that she got cold, and in consequence of that, it settled on her lungs; and I am of opinion, if she had had no blow at all, that would have been sufficient to have brought on her death.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640502-37-person314">
                  Mary 
                  Mills 
               <interp inst="t17640502-37-person314" type="surname" value="Mills"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-37-person314" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-37-person314" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I attended her from the Thursday, she did not appear to have any remarkable drowsiness.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she at any time lose her senses?</p>
               <p>M. Mills. No, she did not.</p>
               <p>Mr. Burgess. I am an apothecary; I was called in three days before she died.</p>
               <p>Q. Who called you in?</p>
               <p>Burgess. The prisoner at the bar: she desired I would take all the pains I could; this was on Easter-Sunday. When I came to her, I understood her disorder was of the pleurisy, and upon the lungs: I thought she was so far gone, that I could not be of much use to her; yet notwithstanding, I tried.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mills. When did the deceased die?</p>
               <p>Mills. She died on the 24th of April.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner do towards taking care of the deceased, after Mr. Randall went away on the Monday?</p>
               <p>Mills. The prisoner would have had the deceased gone to the hospital, but the deceased would not go; her fever began about seven days before she died, and from that time, she grew worse and worse, by going out into the yard one day, about 11 o'clock, all in a wringing sweat.</p>
               <p>Q. to Moffet. What do you think was the cause of her death?</p>
               <p>Moffet. The fracture on her ribs was not; and I cannot think that on her head, without other circumstances, would have been the cause of her death. It did not appear that the bone was broke at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you doubt whether she was struck with the poker?</p>
               <p>Moffet. No; but I doubt whether that was the cause of her death. I rather am of opinion, the cause of her death was the inflammation on her lungs; I believe the wound would have been of no consequence, if she had not catched cold; there was another circumstance, the woman had miscarried about 7 weeks before.</p>
               <p>Q. to Randall. Do you continue in that opinion, that the blow on her head brought on her death?</p>
               <p>Randall. The injury on the brain, must be a considerable part of her death. I saw the deceased's husband, and asked him why they had not got a surgeon? he said he was a poor man, and was indebted to Mrs. Hargrove; and she told him she would give him farther indulgence, in case he would let his wife be without a surgeon.</p>
               <p>Mills. The prisoner sent the deceased victuals and drink till she died.</p>
               <p>Burgess. The first day I was called in, I did not know there was a wound; the second day I was informed there was a wound, but I did not dress it: I attended only as an apothecary.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640502-37-person315">
                  John 
                  Peachey 
               <interp inst="t17640502-37-person315" type="surname" value="Peachey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-37-person315" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-37-person315" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the tap-room; I heard very few words; I saw the blow given with the poker, and I went out of the house directly.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a blow was it?</p>
               <p>Peachey. A small drawing blow, not a violent hard blow.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>If the surgeon thinks I am the cause of her death, I am willing to die; I gave her the blow: though my passion was violent, I stopped my hand, and only let it fall; for as I was standing and she sitting, if I had struck her hard, I must have split her skull: to be sure she had been beat very cruelly; she had a very bad tongue.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640502-37-verdict209" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640502-37-verdict209" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>. </p>
            </div1>
