<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670429-52">
               <interp inst="t17670429-52" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670429-52" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670429-52" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670429"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670429-52" type="date" value="17670429"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670429-52-off285-c365" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-52-defend478 t17670429-52-off285 t17670429-52-verdict287"></join>
         
               <p>250. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17670429-52-defend478" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Hopkins 
                  <interp inst="t17670429-52-defend478" type="surname" value="Hopkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-52-defend478" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-52-defend478" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17670429-52-deflabel284" type="occupation">single woman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-52-defend478 t17670429-52-deflabel284"></join>, was indicted for the <rs id="t17670429-52-off285" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670429-52-off285" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-52-off285" type="offenceSubcategory" value="infanticide"></interp>
               wilful murder of her male bastard child
            </rs>, <rs id="t17670429-52-cd286" type="crimeDate">Feb. 9</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-52-off285 t17670429-52-cd286"></join>.</p>


               <p>She stood charged on the Coroner's inquest for the said murder. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-52-person479">
                  John 
                  Berry 
               <interp inst="t17670429-52-person479" type="surname" value="Berry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-52-person479" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-52-person479" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was employed to get a child out of a vault at Bethnal-green, on a Thursday in the afternoon, I don't know the day of the month.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-52-person480">
                  Ann 
                  Lewland 
               <interp inst="t17670429-52-person480" type="surname" value="Lewland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-52-person480" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-52-person480" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mrs. Scott, the prisoner's mistress, sent for me, and desired I would get somebody to her to know what was the matter with her; I said, Sally are you with child: she said she was not: I said if you are, pray don't destroy it. On the Wednesday after she came to my house, about five doors from her mistress's, I saw an alteration. I said, what have you done, could you deliver yourself; she said she was delivered standing by the bedside, and the child dropped from her, and she took it and wrapt it up, and in the morning threw it down the vault. I went and looked in her box, and found three little shirts, two stays, and a cap for a child</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-52-person481">
                  Mary 
                  Scott 
               <interp inst="t17670429-52-person481" type="surname" value="Scott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-52-person481" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-52-person481" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am daughter to the prisoner's mistress. On the Tuesday night the prisoner looked very bad; I asked her what was the matter, she was silent; I asked her again and again: then I asked her how long she had been with child, she said six or seven months; I said, are you not gone your full time, she said she could not tell; I asked her when she was delivered, she said about twelve on the Saturday night, or one on the Sunday morning; that she kept it that night and flung it down the vault in the morning, and if the child had not been dead she would not have made away with it for the world. She said she made a noise for my mother to come to her; she was often troubled with violent fits of coughing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-52-person482">
                  William 
                  Withers 
               <interp inst="t17670429-52-person482" type="surname" value="Withers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-52-person482" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-52-person482" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a surgeon; I was called in to attend the Coroner. I opened the child, and threw the lungs in water and they swam, from whence I concluded the child had breathed. There was no marks of violence upon it. I observed the navel-string was broke quite close to the navel, so that there could no ligament possibly be made; so that it could not have lived past a minute or two, but must bleed to death; this might happen as she stood erect, and it is more likely to happen by a violent fit of coughing.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17670429-52-verdict287" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670429-52-verdict287" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
