<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660514-23">
               <interp inst="t17660514-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660514-23" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660514-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660514"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660514-23" type="date" value="17660514"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660514-23-off136-c185" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-23-defend234 t17660514-23-off136 t17660514-23-verdict140"></join>
         
               <p>307. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660514-23-defend234" type="defendantName">
                     George 
                     Sutton 
                  <interp inst="t17660514-23-defend234" type="surname" value="Sutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-defend234" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-defend234" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was <rs id="t17660514-23-off136" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-off136" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-off136" type="offenceSubcategory" value="extortion"></interp>
               indicted, for writing and publishing several letters intending to terrify the inhabitants of the ward of Aldersgate, and for devising and intending to obtain from 
                     
                        <persName id="t17660514-23-victim236" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Tyser 
                        <interp inst="t17660514-23-victim236" type="surname" value="Tyser"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660514-23-victim236" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660514-23-victim236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17660514-23-viclabel137" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-23-victim236 t17660514-23-viclabel137"></join>; and 
                     
                        <persName id="t17660514-23-victim238" type="victimName">
                           George Lewis 
                           Carr 
                        <interp inst="t17660514-23-victim238" type="surname" value="Carr"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660514-23-victim238" type="given" value="George Lewis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660514-23-victim238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                     
                  , the sum of 20 l. each, &amp;c
            </rs>. <rs id="t17660514-23-cd138" type="crimeDate">Sept. 25</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-23-off136 t17660514-23-cd138"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-23-person239">
                  William 
                  Tyser 
               <interp inst="t17660514-23-person239" type="surname" value="Tyser"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person239" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner lives in Pelican-Court, Little-Britain. It was understood by the people in general, that the old-beadle in our ward, being a drunken fellow, was intended to be discharged last Christmas; this was talked of 6 or 8 months before Christmas. The prisoner then was a hired Constable in the room of another person; he applied to me, and said he heard the old man was intended to be discharged, and said he should be very glad of my friendship in order to be put in the place, I told him the old one was not to be<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176605140019"></xptr> displaced, and desired him not to think any more of it. I received this letter, dated the first of July by the post, I think the day after the date (producing it.)</p>
               <p>It was read in words and letters following.</p>
               <p>London July 1st 1765</p>
               <p>SIR</p>
               <p>"I send to Let you know that your parrish is</p>
               <p>"thretned with being set a fire in three or fore</p>
               <p>"placeis at once by a set of wikid people in a</p>
               <p>"night or two time so as you have a rite to order</p>
               <p>"your Constables out at eney time I think you</p>
               <p>"a necesity so to doe know for your own safety</p>
               <p>"each to pattrole his own Precint as soon as it is</p>
               <p>"dark I would teel my name but dare not for</p>
               <p>"feare of my Selfe and famely bein destroyd</p>
               <p>"a friend</p>
               <p>Directed to 
               <persName id="t17660514-23-person240">
                  Wm.
                   Tycer Esqur
               <interp inst="t17660514-23-person240" type="surname" value="Tycer Esqur"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person240" type="given" value="Wm."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . in Aldersgate-street London these</p>
               <p>Mr. Tyser. Upon receiving this, I sent an order to the constables to be ready, thinking to have a double watch that night, the fellow meeting with somebody in the street to whom he mentioned the thing, and when I came home the whole neighbourhood was alarmed; I continued this watch several nights; I had a very good opinion then of the prisoner, and desired him to watch the second night, and he should be satisfied for his trouble. In about a week after he brings me a letter directed to himself, which he received by the penny-post, with the post-mark upon it, (produced in court.)</p>
               <p>It is read in court, in words and letters following.</p>
               <p>July 8. 1765</p>
               <p>SIR,</p>
               <p>"Dam youre blud if you Continnew to</p>
               <p>"walk the Streets of youre watch nitte as you</p>
               <p>"Did onn wedsday and thursday Last you and</p>
               <p>"your Debbyty may be asurde of haveing your</p>
               <p>"heds Cut of and your housees set onn fire for</p>
               <p>"Damm your bluds we will lay wate for you be</p>
               <p>"waire of the end of Long Lane</p>
               <p>J, H C, D J, C</p>
               <p>directed For Mr. Sutten in the Court facein the Pump in Little brittin</p>
               <p>Mr. Tyser. I endeavoured to find out where this letter was put into the post; first I went to the General Post-office behind the Change, they apprehended it was put in at an office in Newgate-street; I went there, and there I was told it was put in at the corner of Fleet-ditch, Ludgate-hill. I went there, they told me it was certainly put in there, they knew their own mark upon it, but said it was impossible for them to recollect what sort of a person put it in.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you mention this your enquiry to the prisoner at the bar?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tyser. I think I did. In consequence of this I consulted my Lord-Mayor, and we determined to draw up an advertisement, which we did, and advertised a reward of 50 l. to any person that should discover any person concerned in this affair. After this, the prisoner brought another letter to me, which he pretended was thrown into his shop, and seemed to be very much terrfied, (produced in court.)</p>
               <p>It is read in words and letters following.</p>
               <p>August 6th 1765</p>
               <p>SIR,</p>
               <p>"Mr. constable blast your Eise and lims if you</p>
               <p>"and your debbyty and Carr your Common</p>
               <p>"councel lay Each of you twenty pounds under</p>
               <p>"the Stone faceing the Stone Cutters in goswill</p>
               <p>"Street on thursday nite next dam your Eise and</p>
               <p>"limbs we will murder you all and all little</p>
               <p>"brittin shall be Sett on fire for blast your Eise</p>
               <p>"fifty pounds Shant du for us for dam all your</p>
               <p>"Eise we are detetermd to destroy you all if</p>
               <p>"yo dont comply</p>
               <p>J C C d E C t m</p>
               <p>Directed For Mr. Sutten.</p>
               <p>Mr. Tyser. I had this letter brought me by the prisoner, (produced in court.)</p>
               <p>It is read in words and letters following.</p>
               <p>August 30 1765</p>
               <p>SIR,</p>
               <p>"You nead not think that we had done with</p>
               <p>"you nor the Rest for dam all your Eise and</p>
               <p>"lims ass you did not comply With our former</p>
               <p>"demand blast your Eise We the same people are</p>
               <p>"determd to blow you all up before a week s</p>
               <p>"att an End for blast all your Eise We dont<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176605140020"></xptr> " minde your Watch men So you may depend</p>
               <p>"on What We have said we will doo iff you</p>
               <p>"dont comply we know your nite to watch</p>
               <p>i c c d E C t m</p>
               <p>P S We wont troble the post Office</p>
               <p>Directed For Mr. Sutten</p>
               <p>Mr. Tyser. After this I received another letter from the prisoner, which was directed to him, (produced in court)</p>
               <p>It is read in words and letters following.</p>
               <p>Sept 25 1765</p>
               <p>SIR,</p>
               <p>"Blast your Eise and lims you may depend of</p>
               <p>"having your brains blone out before this day</p>
               <p>"Senit as you did not Comply for dam your</p>
               <p>"Eise whe will performe our promis as you have</p>
               <p>"sent one to the counter we will be revengd of</p>
               <p>"you for it</p>
               <p>i c c d</p>
               <p>Directed to Mr. Sutton These</p>
               <p>Mr. Tyser. The prisoner came to me, and told me, there was a drunken idle fellow had made a disturbance in Aldersgate street, and said he would set the houses on fire; and that he had seized the fellow and carried him to the Compter; I was at the trouble of going to the Compter to this fellow; I desired the keeper to get him to write, which he did; I did not find the least similitude in the writing, and therefore, I did not entertain the least suspicion of him, and he was discharged; this the prisoner pleaded as matter of merit for seizing of him. I began to have a suspicion of the prisoner, and thought of a method to detect him; I do not recollect I had seen any of his hand-writing: I enquired about, and collected five receipts of his writing, which I compared with these letters; I had not compared them two minutes, before I was fully convinced he wrote these letters; I then consulted several friends, and shewed them the letters and receipts, and they were of the same opinion. Then I went to my Lord-Mayor, there was one of the Sheriffs, and Mr. Sclater the chaplain; I laid the letters and receipts on the table for inspection. I took up the prisoner; he was desired to sit down and write as a gentleman dictated to him, sentance for sentence; the words of two of these letters, which was kept from his sight; I have his hand-writing here.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tyser. This was on the 19th of February last: I had not the least doubt but the man that wrote this, wrote the two letters which were dictated to him. I am clear of the opinion that he wrote them.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you made any inspection with regard to the spelling?</p>
               <p>Mr. Tyser. There are many words in the letters spelled very badly, and also, the same in that which he wrote: the letter of the 1st of July, the word parish is spelled Parrish, he wrote the word the same before us; both the first and second letters are liable to the same observations.</p>
               <p>The writing produced in court and compared with the originals, wrote in words and letters as follows.</p>
               <p>London July 1st 1765</p>
               <p>SIR,</p>
               <p>"I send to Let you know that your Parrish is</p>
               <p>"threatned with Being Set on fire in three or</p>
               <p>"four places at once By a Set of wicked people</p>
               <p>"in a Night or twos time So as you have a</p>
               <p>"Right to order your Constables out at Eney</p>
               <p>"Time I think you are Nesessity So to do for</p>
               <p>"your one Saifty Each to pattrole his one precint</p>
               <p>"as soon as it is dark I whould teel my Name</p>
               <p>"But dare Not for fear of My Selfe and family</p>
               <p>"being Destroyd</p>
               <p>"a friend</p>
               <p>The second letter.</p>
               <p>August 6 1765</p>
               <p>"Mr. Constable blast your Eise and limbs if</p>
               <p>"you and youre debity and Car your Common</p>
               <p>"Councell Lay each of you twenty pounds Under</p>
               <p>"the Stone facing the Stone Cutters in Goswell</p>
               <p>"Street on thursday Night Next Dam your</p>
               <p>"Eise and limbs. We will murder you all and all</p>
               <p>"little Brittan shall be Set on fire for Blast fivety</p>
               <p>"pounds shant Due for Us for Dam all your</p>
               <p>"Eise we are Determend to Destroy you all if</p>
               <p>"you Dont Comply</p>
               <p>The letters compared and inspected by the court and jury.</p>
         
               <p>*** The Last Part of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17660514-23">
                  <interp inst="t17660514-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660514-23" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660514-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660514"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660514-23" type="date" value="17660514"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176605140021"></xptr>THE WHOLE PROCEEDINGS ON THE KING's COMMISSION of the PEACE, OYER And TERMINER, and GOAL DELIVERY FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the GOAL DELIVERY FOR THE COUNTY of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 14th, Thursday the 15th, and Friday the 16th, of MAY, 1766.</p>
                  <p>In the Sixth Year of His MAJESTY's Reign. Being the Fifth SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of THE RIGHT HONOURABLE 
                  <persName id="t17660514-23-person241">
                     GEORGE 
                     NELSON 
                  <interp inst="t17660514-23-person241" type="surname" value="NELSON"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660514-23-person241" type="given" value="GEORGE"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660514-23-person241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Esq; LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>NUMBER V. PART II.</p>
                  <p>LONDON,</p>
                  <p>Printed for J. WILKIE, at the Bible, in St. Paul's Church-Yard.</p>
                  <p>[Price Six-Pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176605140022"></xptr>THE WHOLE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commission of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Goal Delivery held for the City of LONDON, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Continuation of the Trial of 
               <persName id="t17660514-23-person242">
                  George 
                  Sutton 
               <interp inst="t17660514-23-person242" type="surname" value="Sutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person242" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Mr. Carr.</p>
               <p>I Was present at the time the prisoner wrote these two papers, as they were dictated to him; I have made the same observations as Mr. Tyser has: I have seen them all, and believe them to be all the same hand-writing, upon my conscience.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-23-person243">
                  John 
                  Duck 
               <interp inst="t17660514-23-person243" type="surname" value="Duck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person243" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person243" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner served <rs id="t17660514-23-deflabel139" type="occupation">constable</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-23-defend234 t17660514-23-deflabel139"></join> for me, (he takes the letters in his hand) I have seen him write one receipt; I am apt to think that in some things, this is very much like his handwriting.</p>
               <p>Mr. Blunt. I have seen the prisoner write, (he takes one of the letters in his hand) on the direction of this, the letters r, t, and d, in the words Aldersgate-street, have a great resemblance to his hand-writing, which I have in my hand.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I never wrote none of them; I know nothing of them indeed.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-23-person244">
                  John 
                  Magriger 
               <interp inst="t17660514-23-person244" type="surname" value="Magriger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person244" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person244" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live upon Lambeth-hill, near Doctors-commons: I am a fan-stick-maker; I have known the prisoner fifteen years; he always bore a very good character; an honest fair dealing man as I ever dealt with in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-23-person245">
                  Richard 
                  Hopkins 
               <interp inst="t17660514-23-person245" type="surname" value="Hopkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person245" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Little Britain, and am in a branch of the buckle-making way; I have known him between 15 and 16 years; his character was never tainted in any shape in the world, till this that he is charged with.</p>
               <p>Q. What business is the prisoner in?</p>
               <p>Hopkins. He is something in the fan way.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-23-person246">
                  Robert 
                  Rigles 
               <interp inst="t17660514-23-person246" type="surname" value="Rigles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person246" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the Borough, and am a taylor: I have known the prisoner near 3 years; I have had opportunities of seeing him pretty often, he is a very honest good natured man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-23-person247">
                  William 
                  Craven 
               <interp inst="t17660514-23-person247" type="surname" value="Craven"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person247" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Black friars, and am a victualler; I have known him about 20 years; he is a very honest industrious man, I never heard to the contrary.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-23-person248">
                  John 
                  Hill 
               <interp inst="t17660514-23-person248" type="surname" value="Hill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person248" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Black-friars; I have known him upwards of 20 years; I never heard any other by him, then that of an honest sober man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-23-person249">
                  Thomas 
                  Cocknell 
               <interp inst="t17660514-23-person249" type="surname" value="Cocknell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person249" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the Borough of Southwark, and am a plaisterer; I have known him ever since the year 1759; I have had dealings with him several times; he is a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-23-person250">
                  John 
                  Kidman 
               <interp inst="t17660514-23-person250" type="surname" value="Kidman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person250" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an oil-man and perfumer, and live in Newgate-street; I have known him 7 years; he has a very good character, I never heard to the contrary.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-23-person251">
                  Hannah 
                  Kempton 
               <interp inst="t17660514-23-person251" type="surname" value="Kempton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person251" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person251" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Barnaby-street, Southwark; I have known him ever since he settled in business, which is 17 years; he always dealt exceeding honest with me, and bears the character of an honest man, I believe him to be such.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-23-person252">
                  Anne 
                  Saunders 
               <interp inst="t17660514-23-person252" type="surname" value="Saunders"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person252" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person252" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about 18 years; he keeps a chandler's shop; I always thought him to be an honest sober man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-23-person253">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Cook 
               <interp inst="t17660514-23-person253" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person253" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person253" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him 20 years; he is an honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-23-person254">
                  Mary 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17660514-23-person254" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person254" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person254" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Pelican-court; I have known him 17 years; he has a very good character, and is willing to work for his living.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-23-person255">
                  Rebeccah 
                  Sears 
               <interp inst="t17660514-23-person255" type="surname" value="Sears"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person255" type="given" value="Rebeccah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person255" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him 17 years; his character is that of an honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-23-person256">
                  John 
                  Stredwell 
               <interp inst="t17660514-23-person256" type="surname" value="Stredwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person256" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-person256" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Pelican-court, and am a spectacle-maker; I have known him four or five years; I believe him to be an honest man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660514-23-verdict140" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-verdict140" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17660514-23-punish141" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-punish141" type="punishmentCategory" value="imprison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-punish141" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="newgate"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-23-defend234 t17660514-23-punish141"></join>
               Imp
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660514-23-punish142" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-punish142" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-punish142" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="fine"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-23-defend234 t17660514-23-punish142"></join>
               
                     <note>[Fine. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660514-23-punish143" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-punish143" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-23-punish143" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="sureties"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-23-defend234 t17660514-23-punish143"></join>
               
                     <note>[Provide sureties for good behaviour. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
