<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640607-43">
               <interp inst="t17640607-43" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640607-43" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640607-43" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640607"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640607-43" type="date" value="17640607"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640607-43-off244-c275" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-43-defend365 t17640607-43-off244 t17640607-43-verdict247"></join>
         
               <p>366. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17640607-43-defend365" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Sarah 
                     Drummond 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17640607-43-alias-4" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-43-defend365 t17640607-43-alias-4"></join>Mary Drummond</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-43-defend365" type="surname" value="Drummond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-43-defend365" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-43-defend365" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17640607-43-off244" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640607-43-off244" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-43-off244" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one silk gown, value 40 s. one long lawn gown, one cotton gown, ten linen shifts, three dimity petticoats, five laced mobbs, two handkerchiefs, five muslin aprons, one flowered gause apron, three laced handkerchiefs, and several plain ditto, one silk bonnet, three yards of silk ribbon, five pair of ruffles, four pair of cotton stockings, and other things, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640607-43-victim368" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Parry 
                        <interp inst="t17640607-43-victim368" type="surname" value="Parry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640607-43-victim368" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640607-43-victim368" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-43-off244 t17640607-43-victim368"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling-house of 
                     <persName id="t17640607-43-person369">
                        Edward 
                        Hodges 
                     <interp inst="t17640607-43-person369" type="surname" value="Hodges"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640607-43-person369" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640607-43-person369" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17640607-43-cd245" type="crimeDate">May 25</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-43-off244 t17640607-43-cd245"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640607-43-person370">
                  Edward 
                  Hodges 
               <interp inst="t17640607-43-person370" type="surname" value="Hodges"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-43-person370" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-43-person370" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17640607-43-crimeloc246">Fleetstreet</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640607-43-crimeloc246" type="placeName" value="Fleetstreet"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640607-43-crimeloc246" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-43-off244 t17640607-43-crimeloc246"></join>, and am a stationer. Mrs. Parry came as a visitor: the prisoner at the bar was a servant of mine: Mrs. Parry came the 23d of May, and the prisoner came the same day: she came from the intelligence office: my wife hired her, and ordered her to come the same evening: she came about 10 o'clock: she said she had lived at one Mr. Hummond's, at Low-Layton: my wife took the direction, and sent to know her character, but she went away before we had an answer; she went away between ten and eleven at night; she brought no cloaths with her, but what she brought on her back. After supper, we were going to bed, and enquired where she was, and found there was a candle left upon the cutting-bench, and the shop door was left upon the single lock. Mrs. Parry walked up stairs, and missed all the things mentioned in the indictment: I took an account from her what things she had lost, and went to Justice Fielding that night; it wanted a quarter of 12 o'clock when I got there: I sent a boy of mine where the prisoner said she lived, but could get no intelligence of her there: the next day she was taken up on another affair, on Ludgate-hill, between five and six o'clock, and was taken before a magistrate. I asked her how she came to take the things, and whether she had any body to assist her? she said, there was nobody to assist her: there were several things found upon her back, a cap and bonnet, a cloak, a laced cap and handkerchief, a shift, stockings, and other things: she owned she had taken these things from my house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640607-43-person371">
                  Batty 
                  Parry 
               <interp inst="t17640607-43-person371" type="surname" value="Parry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-43-person371" type="given" value="Batty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-43-person371" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The things mentioned in the indictment are all mine: they were taken away this day fortnight, from out of a room that I lie in, up two pair of stairs. I had not an opportunity to unpack them; she took this trunk and all; (produced in court); all my cloaths, aprons, ruffles, and them kind of things were in it, (she mentioned by name, the goods mentioned in the indictment) which I lost at that time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640607-43-person372">
                  Anne 
                  Pyke 
               <interp inst="t17640607-43-person372" type="surname" value="Pyke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-43-person372" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-43-person372" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never saw the prisoner before this day fortnight. She was going down Holborn, and I coming home from my business: I met her between Shoe-lane and the New-market, between 10 and 11 o'clock at night; she had a trunk under her arm, and some things in her apron: she asked me if I could tell her of lodgings? I said, I could not. She said she came from Kensington, where she, had lived two years, and had never been in London before; I took compassion on her, and took her to my lodgings; she lay with me that night, but what she had, I know no more than the child unborn.</p>
               <p>The prisoner said nothing in her defence.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640607-43-verdict247" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640607-43-verdict247" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-43-verdict247" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder40s"></interp>
               Guilty, 39 s.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17640607-43-punish248" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640607-43-punish248" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-43-defend365 t17640607-43-punish248"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
