<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17661022-4">
               <interp inst="t17661022-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661022-4" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661022-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17661022"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661022-4" type="date" value="17661022"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17661022-4-off19-c52" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661022-4-defend58 t17661022-4-off19 t17661022-4-verdict23"></join>
         
               <p>475. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17661022-4-defend58" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Griffiths 
                  <interp inst="t17661022-4-defend58" type="surname" value="Griffiths"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-4-defend58" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-4-defend58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17661022-4-off19" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661022-4-off19" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-4-off19" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               that he, on the 15th of October, about the hour of three in the night, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17661022-4-victim60" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Gibson 
                        <interp inst="t17661022-4-victim60" type="surname" value="Gibson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17661022-4-victim60" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17661022-4-victim60" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did break and enter, and stealing one silver table-spoon, value 10 s. three silver tea-spoons, value 6 s. a pair of silver shoe buckles, value 10 s. and one silver knee buckle, the property of the said John; and one hat, the property of 
                     <persName id="t17661022-4-victim61" type="victimName">
                        Frederic 
                        Laber 
                     <interp inst="t17661022-4-victim61" type="surname" value="Laber"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17661022-4-victim61" type="given" value="Frederic"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17661022-4-victim61" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   , <rs id="t17661022-4-viclabel20" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661022-4-victim61 t17661022-4-viclabel20"></join>: in the said dwelling house
            </rs>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661022-4-person62">
                  John 
                  Gibson 
               <interp inst="t17661022-4-person62" type="surname" value="Gibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-4-person62" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-4-person62" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I live facing <placeName id="t17661022-4-crimeloc21">Catharine-street in the Strand</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17661022-4-crimeloc21" type="placeName" value="Catharine-street in the Strand"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17661022-4-crimeloc21" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661022-4-off19 t17661022-4-crimeloc21"></join>; on the 16th of October in the morning, I was called up between three and four, and told my house was broke open; I came down; there were missing three tea-spoons, a table-spoon, a pair of silver shoe-buckles, and one knee buckle; some of them were brought to me by the watchman that morning.</p>
               <p>Frederic Laber, Esq; I lodge at Mr. Gibson's; Mr. Gibson came and knock'd at my chamber-door between three and four that morning; I ask'd what was the matter, and was told the house was robb'd and the door open; I took my sword, and my servant lighted me, and we went about the house, but could find no body.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661022-4-person63">
                  Abraham 
                  Crispin 
               <interp inst="t17661022-4-person63" type="surname" value="Crispin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-4-person63" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-4-person63" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq: I lodge at Mr. Gibson's; on Thursday morning the 10th of this instant October, I came home between three and four in the morning, I found the door a-jar; the watchman was calling half past three, but none near the door; I hesitated a little time to consider what I should do; I call'd watch, but none were in the hearing; I then knock'd very hard at the door; after I had taken my sword out, and held it in my right hand, I still kept knocking hard; I heard a noise in the house, as if some body was walking; I ask'd who was there; nobody answer'd; I endeavour'd to shove the door wide open; I found an opposition, which I believe was the chain of the door, I think I heard it rattle; I hearing a noise again, turned round and saw a man, which was the prisoner; he was in the house, coming out between the door and the post; I put my sword to his breast, and ask'd him what he did there at that time of the morning; I kept him at arms length, and told him if he did not stop till a watchman came I would run him through; he ran out at the door; I made a lunge at him; I did not immediately observe it, but when I looked at it afterwards, I found it bloody, and when the prisoner was examined before the Justice, he had the mark of my sword on his side, and his shirt was bloody; as he ran off I saw a watchman; I ordered him to knock him down; he struck at him, but miss'd him; this was near Exeter-exchange; when he was in Exeter-street, a watchman hit him with his stick and made him reel; he threw down his lanthorn and followed him; when I came up with them, I found them both on the ground together; I told the prisoner, if he offered to make any attempt<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176610220006"></xptr> to get away, I would certainly kill him; we carried him to the Round-house; but before we carried him there, a man brought Capt. Laber's hat to me, and said, Sir, I have brought your hat; I said it was not mine, but I knew it; we searched him at the Round-house, but found nothing about him but a handkerchief or two, not belonging to either of us; upon returning to Mr. Gibson's, they told me they had lost several things out of the house; the watchman was desired to look which way the prisoner had ran; he went, and came back with a silver spoon or two, and a pair of silver shoe buckles, the property of Mr. Gibson.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any thing drop from the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Mr. Crispin. No; except a silver knee-buckle, and that I took up myself (produced and deposed to.)</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Whether I did not run between you and the door in the street, when you struck at me with your sword?</p>
               <p>Mr. Crispin. When I made a lunge at the prisoner, he had come out at the door, and was in the street; I had seen him in the house, and saw him come out.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661022-4-person64">
                  James 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17661022-4-person64" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-4-person64" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-4-person64" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watchman; after I had done calling half an hour after three o'clock, I heard the cry, Stop thief; I ran down from the corner of Russel-court to the bottom of White-hart-yard, there I saw the other watchman's light; he was calling the hour in Exeter-street; I heard stop thief again three or four times. I call'd to the watchman, and said he is coming that way, the prisoner ran by him; that was the time I believe he threw away the buckles; he came running towards me as hard as he could; I put my lanthorn down, and held my stick up, and bid him stop; he ran on the other side of the way; I struck him a blow in Exeter-street; he ran staggering about twenty yards, and then fell down; when I came up to him, he began to turn about and tussel with me; I threw my stick out of my hand, and collared him with both my hands, and threw him down, and kept my knee on his guts, till I had assistance came; when the captain came up, we took the prisoner to the Round-house; going along, he put his hand into his pocket, and threw something down; I said he has throw'd something away, and the captain picked it up, it was this knee-buckle; when the prisoner was lodged in the Round-house, we went to see the gentleman home; when we came to Mr. Gibson's door, Mrs. Gibson said she had lost some silver spoons, and her husband's silver buckles; the gentleman desired me to search, to see if he had dropt any thing as he ran along; I went, and found the silver shoe-buckles and a silver tablespoon in Burleigh-street, and delivered them to Mr. Gibson (produced and deposed to.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661022-4-person65">
                  John 
                  Beasley 
               <interp inst="t17661022-4-person65" type="surname" value="Beasley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-4-person65" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-4-person65" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watchman; I found this hat facing Exeter-exchange in the Strand, between Mr. Gibson's and Burleigh-street (produced and deposed to by Mr. Leaber;) the prisoner came to me about three o'clock that morning, and asked me for a bit of candle; I would not let him have any; he went to another watchman, and got a bit for a penny; I saw him go by with it in his hand towards Mr. Gibson's house; my stand is facing Exeter-exchange.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661022-4-person66">
                  Jane 
                  Gibson 
               <interp inst="t17661022-4-person66" type="surname" value="Gibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-4-person66" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-4-person66" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the prosecutor; I shut up the street-door over night myself, between the hours of eleven and twelve, and locked and bolted and chained it; I think I was more particular in securing the house that night than usual; when we heard the alarm stop thief in the street, it awaked us; then we got up, and missed the things mentioned in the indictment.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>On that night I was drinking with two friends, we staid till the hour of two in the morning; we all three took a walk up the Strand; one of them dropt our company, and the other left me, and went on to St. Clement's church-yard; I went on to my master's house in Fetter-lane; he was gone to bed; then I went back, intending to lodge with a companion at Charing-cross; going by Catharine-street, I met a girl; she gave me ill language; I threw her down; she called watch, watch; I ran away, and rushed by the gentleman, between the house and he, and he picked me with his sword; they secured me, and took me to the Round-house; they found nothing upon me; I imagine the watchman that talk'd of my wanting a candle committed the fact.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661022-4-person67">
                  Dean 
                  Evitt 
               <interp inst="t17661022-4-person67" type="surname" value="Evitt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-4-person67" type="given" value="Dean"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-4-person67" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner is my <rs id="t17661022-4-deflabel22" type="occupation">apprentice</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661022-4-defend58 t17661022-4-deflabel22"></join>; I am a shoemaker, and live at the Golden-fleece in Golden-lane; he always behaved very well; I always found him just and honest to me; he went out that day about dinner-time; I saw him that night about eight o'clock, at a journeyman's house by Hungerford market.</p>
               <p>Mr. Longden. I have known him from a child; I never heard any ill of him in my life before; he was bred and born in Shropthire.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661022-4-person68">
                  Walter 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17661022-4-person68" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-4-person68" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-4-person68" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Queen's-head tavern, Great Queen's-street, Lincoln's-inn-fields;<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176610220007"></xptr> the prisoner was a waiter at my house before he put himself apprentice; I always found him honest.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17661022-4-verdict23" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661022-4-verdict23" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17661022-4-punish24" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661022-4-punish24" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661022-4-defend58 t17661022-4-punish24"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
