<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670429-66">
               <interp inst="t17670429-66" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670429-66" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670429-66" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670429"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670429-66" type="date" value="17670429"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670429-66-off369-c452" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-66-defend595 t17670429-66-off369 t17670429-66-verdict373"></join>
         
               <p>267. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17670429-66-defend595" type="defendantName">
                     Daniel 
                     Hobbs 
                  <interp inst="t17670429-66-defend595" type="surname" value="Hobbs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-66-defend595" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-66-defend595" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for that <rs id="t17670429-66-off369" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670429-66-off369" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-66-off369" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17670429-66-victim597" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Picket 
                        <interp inst="t17670429-66-victim597" type="surname" value="Picket"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670429-66-victim597" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670429-66-victim597" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-66-off369 t17670429-66-victim597"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17670429-66-viclabel370" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-66-victim597 t17670429-66-viclabel370"></join>; did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and violently taking from his person a gold watch, value 20 l. a cornelian seal set in gold, value 2 l. a gold mourning ring, value 10 s. a clasp pocket knife, value 6 d. five guineas and a half, and 13 s. in money numbered
            </rs>, the property of the said John, <rs id="t17670429-66-cd371" type="crimeDate">February 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-66-off369 t17670429-66-cd371"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-66-person598">
                  John 
                  Picket 
               <interp inst="t17670429-66-person598" type="surname" value="Picket"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-66-person598" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-66-person598" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; About a quarter past twelve at night, on the 8th of February, I was on foot alone, <placeName id="t17670429-66-crimeloc372">coming from Ratcliff; and between that and Goodman's-fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17670429-66-crimeloc372" type="placeName" value="coming from Ratcliff; and between that and Goodman's-fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17670429-66-crimeloc372" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-66-off369 t17670429-66-crimeloc372"></join>, I was either pushed down, or knocked down by a man; I believe it was the latter; I cannot swear to the man; I thought there were two men, but am not sure; I saw no arms; I can't remember the man said any thing to me before I was down.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you been drinking?</p>
               <p>Picket. I had.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell whether you was tripped up, or how?</p>
               <p>Picket. I certainly was struck down; I made no resistance.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the man ask you for your money?</p>
               <p>Picket. No, he took it when I was down, without asking; he took my gold watch, and mourning ring, five guineas and a half, and 14 or 15 s. in silver from me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-66-person599">
                  Thomas 
                  Gardner 
               <interp inst="t17670429-66-person599" type="surname" value="Gardner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-66-person599" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-66-person599" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I received a letter from Mr. Alsorth of Isleworth, wherein he acquainted me there was a gold watch with my name, No 334 l. had been offered to a neighbour of his for four guineas and a half, I went there after the watch was delivered into my hand, I knew it, having made it for the prosecutor, and he gave me twenty-six guineas for it; I asked for the man that had it; the woman said he was at her house; we sent for an officer, and he was taken at the Red Lion ther it was the prisoner at the bar he had a cocka in his hat, was a ma; we searched him, the first thing taken from him was a clasp 
               <persName id="t17670429-66-person600">
                  kane
               <interp inst="t17670429-66-person600" type="given" value="kane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-66-person600" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the prisoner was then charged with robbing the prosecutor; it was asked whether he had any body with him in this affair; he said there was nobody but himself, that the gentleman was very much in liquor, and he followed him, and when he attacked him he tell like a log upon his back, and then he took the watch and things from him; I asked him after the ring, he said he had it about him; then he took it out of his pocket in a purse, and delivered it, we took him before Sir 
               <persName id="t17670429-66-person601">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17670429-66-person601" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-66-person601" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-66-person601" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and he committed him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-66-person602">
                  John 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17670429-66-person602" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-66-person602" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-66-person602" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am headborough and beadle of the parish of Isleworth; I took this clasp knife out of the prisoner's pocket on the 18th of February; (the watch, ring, purse, and knife, produced and deposed to by prosecutor) I was sent for to the Red Lion, there was the watchmaker, and they had the prisoner there; they charged him with robbing a captain on the highway; the prisoner said he was the man, and mentioned the several things he had taken from him; but said, the captain may say what he will, I took no more money from him than two guineas, two half guineas, and about 12 or 13 s.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-66-person603">
                  Eleanor 
                  Ansel 
               <interp inst="t17670429-66-person603" type="surname" value="Ansel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-66-person603" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-66-person603" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My mother keeps the Red Lion at Isleworth; the prisoner brought a watch and desired me to say it by for him; (she is shewed the watch) I believe it to be the same but cannot swear to it; I laid it by, and after that delivered it to my sister, the next witness.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-66-person604">
                  Anne Catharine 
                  Pruda 
               <interp inst="t17670429-66-person604" type="surname" value="Pruda"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-66-person604" type="given" value="Anne Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-66-person604" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I received this watch (I believe it to be the same) of my sister, and delivered it to a boy to carry to Mr. Alsorth.</p>
               <p>Mr. Alsorth. Mrs. Ansel sent this watch to me, to get the opinion of a gentleman at Isleworth of the value of it; he informed me it was a gold watch of value, and advised them not to buy it; I saw the knife, purse, and ring taken from the prisoner, which the prosecutor swore to.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I am quite innocent of the affair; I asked liberty of my captain to come to London, he granted me<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176704290036"></xptr> two days. I went into New Gravel-lane, and returned the next morning. I picked these things up upon the road.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17670429-66-verdict373" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670429-66-verdict373" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17670429-66-punish374" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670429-66-punish374" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-66-defend595 t17670429-66-punish374"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
