<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640912-44">
               <interp inst="t17640912-44" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-44" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-44" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640912"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-44" type="date" value="17640912"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640912-44-off249-c320" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-44-defend403 t17640912-44-off249 t17640912-44-verdict252"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640912-44-off249-c321" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-44-defend405 t17640912-44-off249 t17640912-44-verdict252"></join>
         
               <p>526, 527, 
               
                  <persName id="t17640912-44-defend403" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Hands 
                  <interp inst="t17640912-44-defend403" type="surname" value="Hands"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-44-defend403" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-44-defend403" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17640912-44-defend405" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Hands 
                  <interp inst="t17640912-44-defend405" type="surname" value="Hands"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-44-defend405" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-44-defend405" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted, for that <rs id="t17640912-44-off249" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-44-off249" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-44-off249" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               they, on the <rs id="t17640912-44-cd250" type="crimeDate">17th of August</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-44-off249 t17640912-44-cd250"></join>, about the hour of two in the night, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640912-44-victim407" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Whitby 
                        <interp inst="t17640912-44-victim407" type="surname" value="Whitby"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640912-44-victim407" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640912-44-victim407" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did break and enter, and stealing seven linen aprons, value 7 s. five table-cloths, value 12 s. four shifts, value 10 s. five sheets, value 10 s. two damask napkins, value 2 s. one other shift, value 2 s. the property of the said John; and five shirts, value 5 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640912-44-victim409" type="victimName">
                           Joseph 
                           Capareena 
                        <interp inst="t17640912-44-victim409" type="surname" value="Capareena"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640912-44-victim409" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640912-44-victim409" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17640912-44-viclabel251" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-44-victim409 t17640912-44-viclabel251"></join>; in the dwelling-house of the said John
            </rs>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-44-person410">
                  John 
                  Whitby 
               <interp inst="t17640912-44-person410" type="surname" value="Whitby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-44-person410" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-44-person410" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My town-house is in Mount-street, my country-house is at Hammersmith; part of my family reside there. On Saturday, the 18th of last month, my wife told me the room door was broke open, and all the linen the maid had been ironing was gone; I went up to the room, and found the door broke; the staple of the lock was lying on the floor: it appeared to me to have been forced open with an iron bar, or poker; the part was very much bruised: in a day or two after, the landlord of the house where the two brothers at the bar lived, told me he was suspicious his lodgers were the persons that had robbed me: that night<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176409120031"></xptr> they were up and down stairs several times: after that, we got intelligence of a box of linen, sent to a soldier, an acquaintance of theirs, at Westminster. It was found, and my maid swore the linen to be my property.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-44-person411">
                  Mary 
                  Perrin 
               <interp inst="t17640912-44-person411" type="surname" value="Perrin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-44-person411" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-44-person411" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Whitby. On the Friday, I left the door double locked, and in the morning of the 18th, between seven and eight, I found it broke, and standing wide open, and all the linen that I had left on the horse, was taken away. I observed the lock lying broke: I saw the linen at the justice's, about a fortnight after; it is here in court, my master's property.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-44-person412">
                  William 
                  Lock 
               <interp inst="t17640912-44-person412" type="surname" value="Lock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-44-person412" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-44-person412" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Saturday morning, just before two o'clock, I was awake, and heard the clock strike; the two prisoners went down stairs; (they, their father and mother, two sisters, and a younger brother, lodge at my house in two rooms) the two prisoners went out at the fore-door, and pulled the door fast after them: they came in again about ten minutes before three, and their younger brother went down stairs to let them in, (I heard this): they came in, and shut the door after them, and came up stairs; one of them was seemingly heavy loaded; that is the soldier, named Thomas; the other is a cripple: they staid above, till just after three; then they went down again, and went out: one seemed to be heavy loaded, as they went down. The next day, I heard Mr. Whitby's house was broke open; I went, and let him into the light of what had passed: I was before the justice, when the maid swore to the linen.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-44-person413">
                  William 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17640912-44-person413" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-44-person413" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-44-person413" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Long-ditch, Westminster. (A box of linen produced in court.) I believe this box is the same that was brought to me one Saturday morning, about three weeks ago, at a quarter before six o'clock; when the soldier, 
               <persName id="t17640912-44-person414">
                  Thomas 
                  Hands 
               <interp inst="t17640912-44-person414" type="surname" value="Hands"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-44-person414" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-44-person414" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , came to exercise, they were both together, and desired I would put it by for him, till he had done exercise. I took and carried it to my room; after exercise, they did not come for it, which gave me a suspicion; I applied to Serjeant Shaw, belonging to the same company that he did, who desired I would carry it to his house, till farther enquiry could be made. I did, and delivered it to him.</p>
               <p>Serjeant Shaw. The last witness told me of the box on the Monday, and it was brought to me on the Saturday: he said, he suspected it was full of stolen linen, that he could see linen on the top of it, and desired he might leave it at my house, least he should be suspected of receiving stolen goods. I desired him to bring it to my house; (this is the box that is here produced); it has been in my custody ever since.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. There was some of the linen taken out of the box, and pawned, and Justice Welch sent for it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-44-person415">
                  William 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17640912-44-person415" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-44-person415" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-44-person415" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             The prisoner, 
               <persName id="t17640912-44-person416">
                  Thomas 
                  Hand 
               <interp inst="t17640912-44-person416" type="surname" value="Hand"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-44-person416" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-44-person416" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , brought some things to me, and said, his mother was in great necessity, and desired me to take a table-cloth to pawn: I carried that and a shirt to pawn; he wanted me to go with the other things, but I said, I did not care to be concerned with any more things, and desired him to go with me to the pawnbroker, and have every thing wrote down in his own name; this was after he brought the box, these he had loose, which he brought at two or three times, in his pocket: the box was never opened, after it was with me.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he bring loose?</p>
               <p>Thompson. A tea-chest he brought the very day he came with the box; a shirt he brought two days afterwards; and after that, another shirt and a table-cloth: he said, the box of linen was all his own.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you pawn any thing else?</p>
               <p>Thompson. I pawned a shirt.</p>
               <p>Court. You might know that was not his own.</p>
               <p>Thompson. My little girl pawned that. When I desired him to go, and have the things in his own name, he took a shirt away with him then.</p>
               <p>Q. Who had the money that these things were pawned for?</p>
               <p>Thompson. He had every farthing of it: he did not take them in his own name, because he had not money.</p>
               <p>M. Perrin. There is a ruffled shirt of my master's, a shift, three aprons, a stock, and a pair of round robbins missing.</p>
               <p>Q. to Thompson. Upon your oath, do you know any thing of these things, or either of them, that are missing?</p>
               <p>Thompson. Upon my oath, I do not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-44-person417">
                  Thomas 
                  Hands 
               <interp inst="t17640912-44-person417" type="surname" value="Hands"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-44-person417" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-44-person417" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . There was one shirt he said he pawned for 3 s. and when we came to the pawnbroker's, I found it was pawned for 4 s. and he kept one himself.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-44-person418">
                  William 
                  Hands 
               <interp inst="t17640912-44-person418" type="surname" value="Hands"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-44-person418" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-44-person418" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This young woman was ironing of cloaths; I went to bed, and my two brothers went out at the door; it was not two o'clock: they came in again a little after three, and brought in half a bag full of things, and brought them up stairs, and put them in a box, and set off for London in the morning, a little after three.</p>
               <p>Q. What did they bring in the bag?</p>
               <p>W. Hands. It was linen. My brother watched the maid as she was ironing: I saw him watch her, till she had done.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176409120032"></xptr>Q. Where was you then?</p>
               <p>W. Hands. I was then in bed: our house faces the laundry. When they brought the linen in, they said they had it from over the way; the box is my father's box.</p>
               <p>Thomas Hands's Defence.</p>
               <p>I am very sorry for it. Last Saturday 3 weeks, I was ordered for exercise: I got up in the morning, being ordered between two and three: coming along the road, I picked up a bag and some linen in it; I returned back again to my lodgings, and put it all in a box: I nailed it up, and brought it to London, and left it for Thompson to take care of, expecting it to be advertised. I went to my exercise, and bid him not break it open: he said, he would take care of it: I came home in the evening, and my father, mother, and brother were in bed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-44-person419">
                  John 
                  Hands 
               <interp inst="t17640912-44-person419" type="surname" value="Hands"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-44-person419" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-44-person419" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was along with him when he carried the box, but I never touched it all the way: he said, he picked it up in the road; I knew nothing of it before. I said, what will you do with it? said he, I will leave it at a friend's house; perhaps it will be advertised: he said, this Thompson, the soldier, was his friend, and he left it with him; then he went to exercise, and staid all the day, and told the soldier he would come another day for it.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17640912-44-verdict252" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-44-verdict252" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17640912-44-punish253" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-44-punish253" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-44-defend403 t17640912-44-punish253"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-44-defend405 t17640912-44-punish253"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
