<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17641017-27">
               <interp inst="t17641017-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641017-27" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641017-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17641017"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641017-27" type="date" value="17641017"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17641017-27-off151-c256" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641017-27-defend314 t17641017-27-off151 t17641017-27-verdict152"></join>
         
               <p>575. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17641017-27-defend314" type="defendantName">
                     Abraham 
                     Wood 
                  <interp inst="t17641017-27-defend314" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-27-defend314" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-27-defend314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17641017-27-off151" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17641017-27-off151" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-27-off151" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               feloniously forging and counterfeiting, and willingly acting in the same, a promissory note, with the name of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17641017-27-victim316" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Edwards 
                        <interp inst="t17641017-27-victim316" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17641017-27-victim316" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17641017-27-victim316" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641017-27-off151 t17641017-27-victim316"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   subscribed thereunto, purporting to be a promissory note, to pay the sum of 10 l. to him the said Abraham, and 
                     <persName id="t17641017-27-person317">
                        Thomas 
                        Muckle 
                     <interp inst="t17641017-27-person317" type="surname" value="Muckle"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17641017-27-person317" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17641017-27-person317" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  ; and for publishing the same, with intent to defraud the said 
                     <persName id="t17641017-27-person318">
                        Wm 
                        Edwards 
                     <interp inst="t17641017-27-person318" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17641017-27-person318" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17641017-27-person318" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641017-27-person319">
                  William 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17641017-27-person319" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-27-person319" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-27-person319" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 18th of July, there was an advertisement in the news-paper, setting forth, that a man might get an hundred a year, by advancing 40 l. and the person to apply to the Golden Leg, in Long-acre. I went there: there was Muckle, and the prisoner Wood: it was a good while before they would admit me into the room. I asked them, how they could make it appear, that I should get an hundred a year? they said. they would make it appear, or return me my money again. I said, how is it? they said, as the advertisement expresses it. They wanted a partner in an employment, and by his advancing 40 l. as a premium, it would bring them in an hundred per annum, and near half his time to spare; none but principals need apply. and the money ready. I told them, I could not advance the money myself, but I had a friend would lend me a little money: they said, they would go with me to him; I went, but he was not at home. I went back again in about half an hour after, and met my friend, and told him what I had been about; he said, if you engage with them, they are the biggest villains in London, and you will be ruined. I went and told them I could not raise the money, and so could not be engaged: they shook hands with me, and I went back. Three days after, being the 21st of July, there came Muckle, Wood, and another man, to the end of Warwick-court, where I was: they said to me, do you know this man? no, said I, I never saw him before: said they, we have a note against you for 10 l. and you must pay it, or go to gaol. Said I, I made no agreement with you, and I owe you nothing. They were for taking me away, but I begged of them to let me go into a publick-house, and we went into the Griffin, in Holborn. They shewed me a note; my name was in it: I could not deny the name; said I, you are villains, and laid hold of Muckle; Wood and the other ran away; I secured Muckle, with the assistance of the landlord of the house and another person. They said, they had a writ against me, and were going to drag me to gaol. Here is the note. It is read to this purport:</p>
               <p>"I promise to pay to 
               <persName id="t17641017-27-person320">
                  Abraham 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17641017-27-person320" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-27-person320" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-27-person320" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and</p>
               <p>"
               <persName id="t17641017-27-person321">
                  Thomas 
                  Muckle 
               <interp inst="t17641017-27-person321" type="surname" value="Muckle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-27-person321" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-27-person321" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Ten Pounds, upon demand,</p>
               <p>"for value received, this 18th day</p>
               <p>"of July, 1764.</p>
               <p>"
               <persName id="t17641017-27-person322">
                  William 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17641017-27-person322" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-27-person322" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-27-person322" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ."</p>
               <p>Here is another paper which we found upon Muckle. (Producing half a sheet, with a piece of the lower corner on the right hand taken off, about half the breadth, and about four inches deep).</p>
               <p>Edwards. The paper they got me to write my name to, was about the size of this; it was compleat, and I signed no other: they said nothing to me about a promissory note. (The paper inspected. It appeared to be a memorandum of an agreement of a partnership, where Wood and Muckle were to be partners with the person taken in.) They told me the trade was in the brokery way: they drew up a rough draught, as they called it, and I wrote my name at the bottom; if this is the paper, I wrote on that part that is wanting: Wood and Muckle's names were above mine.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they not talk to you about paying ten pounds?</p>
               <p>Edwards. No, they did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Look on this note; is this your name?</p>
               <p>Edwards. (He takes the note in his hand.) It is.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176410170023"></xptr>Q. Did you read what was over it when you signed it?</p>
               <p>Edwards. They said, it was how they bought and sold their goods, and they wanted a sober man that could write; they asked me to write my name, and I wrote my name to such a paper as the large one, not to the promissory note; they called it a rough draught.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641017-27-person323">
                  Thomas 
                  Keyo 
               <interp inst="t17641017-27-person323" type="surname" value="Keyo"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-27-person323" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-27-person323" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner and Muckle came to my house, about a week before this advertisement was put into the paper; they asked me leave to let them make use of my name in an advertisement in the papers: I was part of the time in the room with the prisoner, Muckle, and Mr. Edwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any conversation that pass'd?</p>
               <p>Keyo. I heard them talk of buying and selling of goods, and taking and letting chandler's-shops, and publick-houses. I saw Muckle writing a paper; after he wrote it, he handed it to Mr. Edwards; he put his hand in his waistcoat-pocket, and took out his spectacles and read it: after which, he said it is all well, or all right, or something to that purpose.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him write any thing?</p>
               <p>Keyo. I saw him write his name at the bottom of the paper.</p>
               <p>Q. How big was the paper?</p>
               <p>Keyo. It was a good large sheet of paper.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any other names to it?</p>
               <p>Keyo. I can't say whether there was or not.</p>
               <p>Q. Describe the size of the paper.</p>
               <p>Keyo. It was larger than this promissory note, I really think it was the size of half a sheet of paper.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. How many papers did you sign your name to?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I signed my name to only one.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any notice taken about a forfeiture?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No, there was not.</p>
               <p>Q. What hand had the prisoner at the bar in this affair?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. He and Muckle both told me they were partners.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to write your name?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. They wanted me to write my name, that was all they wanted.</p>
               <p>Q. How came this paper pasted to the back of the note?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. When Muckle found I would take him in custody, he snatched it to get it. and tore a piece off; so Mr. Alderman Dickenson's clerk pasted that paper behind, to stick it together, as it was before,</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I cannot write my name as any body can understand it: I have business enough of my own; I have more business than I can do; I keep a public-house; this man agreed to give us 40 l. I went down stairs, and when I came up again, they had made a little bit of an agreement: after that, it was handed to Mr. Keyo, till the afternoon: after that, the prosecutor would have nothing to do with it.</p>
               <p>Q. to Keyo. Had you the paper in your possession afterwards?</p>
               <p>Keyo. They handed the agreement to me; I believe the note of hand was with it. Muckle called for it in the evening; I had put it into a corner cupboard; I went and delivered it to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this paper whole, or as it appears now?</p>
               <p>Keyo. Muckle tore off some part of it; I cannot say I know a note of hand, because I cannot write.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Muckle told me there was a note of hand at the bottom of it, and the man was to pay 10 l. if he did not come back again, in such a time; he certainly gave that note: I wish I may be hanged in chains if he did not.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17641017-27-verdict152" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17641017-27-verdict152" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>See Muckle tried, No. 454. in July Sessions.</p>
            </div1>
