<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670429-6">
               <interp inst="t17670429-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670429-6" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670429-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670429"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670429-6" type="date" value="17670429"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670429-6-off24-c59" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-6-defend72 t17670429-6-off24 t17670429-6-verdict26"></join>
         
               <p>194. (M.)  
               
                  <persName id="t17670429-6-defend72" type="defendantName">
                     Charles 
                     Manwarring 
                  <interp inst="t17670429-6-defend72" type="surname" value="Manwarring"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-6-defend72" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-6-defend72" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17670429-6-off24" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670429-6-off24" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-6-off24" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a silver watch, value 5 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17670429-6-victim74" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Olive 
                  <interp inst="t17670429-6-victim74" type="surname" value="Olive"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-6-victim74" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-6-victim74" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-6-off24 t17670429-6-victim74"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            . *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-6-person75">
                  William 
                  Olive 
               <interp inst="t17670429-6-person75" type="surname" value="Olive"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-6-person75" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-6-person75" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I wanted a service, and the prisoner picked me up at Charing-cross, to take me to a gentleman; he took me in at an ale-house, this was on Easter Monday; there came two men into the room; they said, here are a couple of gentlemen doing business, and were going out; the prisoner said, we are not about any business; then they sat down; after some little time he handed our rum and water to them, and they their porter to us. I was to meet the gentleman the prisoner said at one o'clock; I was looking at my watch to see the time of the day, he snatched it out of my hand; one of the other men took me to the door, pretending he wanted to speak with me; in the mean time the prisoner and the other man made off, out at another door, the prisoner took my watch with him: I happened to see him on the Wednesday after, peeping into a silversmith's shop in Fleet-street.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-6-person76">
                  Matthew 
                  Yeandle 
               <interp inst="t17670429-6-person76" type="surname" value="Yeandle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-6-person76" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-6-person76" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Wandsworth; I was coming by St. Dunstan's church, there I saw the prosecutor have the prisoner by the collar; he said to him, what have you done with my watch you took from me on Monday; there were another fellow or two began to hustle the countryman about, who had got a bundle in his hand; I thought they wanted that; I said to the prisoner, you shall not go away; the other fellows said, then take him into an ale-house; I said no, he should not; they said he should; I called a coach to take him before a magistrate; the door was open; one of the fellows set himself against the door, and said he should not go in; I said he should; at last with assistance we got him and the other man in, we carried them to the Mansion-house; but my Lord-Mayor being engaged, we carried them to the Compter, and after that before my Lord-Mayor; there I said to the prisoner, it appears you are got into a bad gang, you had better impeach and save yourself; he told me he would, and I acquainted my Lord-Mayor with it; but my Lord would<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176704290005"></xptr> not admit him an evidence, as he was the principal in this affair, after that I went with the countryman to the alehouse; there were two doors, he shewed me which door the prisoner ran out at, while one of the men took him to the other.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I never saw the prosecutor in my life, till I met him in Fleet-street; he said, you defrauded me of my watch; I said you are an impudent rascal, I never saw you before; people came and pulled me about, and forced me into a coach at last; I was with a friend on Easter Monday, the time he says he lost his watch; I was with him till three, then we took a walk up to Marybone.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-6-person77">
                  Charles 
                  Warburton 
               <interp inst="t17670429-6-person77" type="surname" value="Warburton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-6-person77" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-6-person77" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was with me from nine in the morning till eleven at night, on Easter Monday; he went out with me to Marybone, and from thence we came and drank a couple of pots of beer, at the Three Tuns, by the Seven Dials; then we went home to my lodgings, in Crown Court; we staid there till seven, then we went to the Crown, and staid there till between eleven and twelve.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-6-person78">
                  Francis 
                  Richmond 
               <interp inst="t17670429-6-person78" type="surname" value="Richmond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-6-person78" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-6-person78" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was a <rs id="t17670429-6-deflabel25" type="occupation">shoemaker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-6-defend72 t17670429-6-deflabel25"></join>, I worked for him; I never knew any ill of him in my life.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17670429-6-verdict26" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670429-6-verdict26" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17670429-6-punish27" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670429-6-punish27" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-6-defend72 t17670429-6-punish27"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>See him tried before, in company with Trout, for a crime of the same nature, No 23, 24, in this mayoralty.</p>
            </div1>
