<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650227-24">
               <interp inst="t17650227-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650227-24" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650227-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650227"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650227-24" type="date" value="17650227"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650227-24-off141-c188" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-24-defend246 t17650227-24-off141 t17650227-24-verdict145"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650227-24-off141-c189" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-24-defend248 t17650227-24-off141 t17650227-24-verdict145"></join>
         
               <p>184, 185. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17650227-24-defend246" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Wood 
                  <interp inst="t17650227-24-defend246" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-24-defend246" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-24-defend246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17650227-24-defend248" type="defendantName">
                     Humphrey 
                     Harrison 
                  <interp inst="t17650227-24-defend248" type="surname" value="Harrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-24-defend248" type="given" value="Humphrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-24-defend248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17650227-24-off141" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650227-24-off141" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-24-off141" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing twelve pair of women's worsted hose, value 20 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17650227-24-victim250" type="victimName">
                     Moses 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17650227-24-victim250" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-24-victim250" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-24-victim250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-24-off141 t17650227-24-victim250"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17650227-24-cd142" type="crimeDate">February 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-24-off141 t17650227-24-cd142"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650227-24-person251">
                  Moses 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17650227-24-person251" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-24-person251" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-24-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at <placeName id="t17650227-24-crimeloc143">the sign of the Lamb, in Aldersgate-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17650227-24-crimeloc143" type="placeName" value="the sign of the Lamb, in Aldersgate-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17650227-24-crimeloc143" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-24-off141 t17650227-24-crimeloc143"></join>; I am a <rs id="t17650227-24-viclabel144" type="occupation">dyer, and keep a stocking shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-24-victim250 t17650227-24-viclabel144"></join>. Last thursday night, I went out of the shop into the kitchen, and left a paper of stockings out he counter, which I had a little before shewed to a customer: my lodger, 
               <persName id="t17650227-24-person252">
                  Jeremiah 
                  Symonds 
               <interp inst="t17650227-24-person252" type="surname" value="Symonds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-24-person252" type="given" value="Jeremiah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-24-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , went out at the back door, and seeing my shop door open as he came round, he asked how it came to be open; I had left it shut just before. Going on his business, he returned, and said he had seen two boys looking at something under a lamp; he supposed they had got some stockings; I said, I had just missed a paper of stockings; he said he knew where to find them: he and my apprentice went up Maidenhead-court, and I up Aldersgate-street; they took the two prisoners and brought them to my house with the stockings: (produced and deposed to); they had flung the paper away: they are two-threads, sham fine, of a particular fineness, almost as fine as the fine; here are twelve of them. I had seen them, I believe I may say about five minutes before. Wood said the crime was very bad, and hoped I would be merciful to him; he took them out of his pocket, and laid them on the counter, one by one: the other prisoner behaved saucy and rude, and said I had no business with him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650227-24-person253">
                  Jeremiah 
                  Symonds 
               <interp inst="t17650227-24-person253" type="surname" value="Symonds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-24-person253" type="given" value="Jeremiah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-24-person253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodge in the prosecutor's house. I left work about ten minutes after eight, and going to Whitechapel, I went out at the back door; and at the end of the passage, I stood and paused, which way I should go; whether through the city, or over Moorfields: I turned to go over Moorfields, and saw the shop door open; I knocked with my heel, and the housekeeper came and shut it, and seemed surprized: then I went on, and saw two lads standing under a lamp, about twenty yards from Mr. Smith's door; I saw one of them put a white bundle under his arm: I followed them; they went to go into Crowder's-well-alley; Wood said, we will go in here, this will carry us into Jewin-street. I went back, and asked Mr. Smith if he had lost any thing? they were looking for the stockings. Then we went after the boys; he went one way and I went another: I found the prisoners, and laid hold of Wood, and said he must go with me: he said, for what? I said, where are the stockings you have taken? he bid me lay hold of Harrison: after that, he owned he had got them, and would fain have given them to me: I brought them both back: we got a constable: Wood took the stockings out of his pocket, and Harrison said he knew nothing of Wood, and Wood did not own he knew him; they were taken before my Lord Mayor; there Wood said, he picked them up at the door; but over night he owned he had taken them away from the shop.</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176502270019"></xptr>Wood's Defence.</p>
               <p>As I was going by the door, home from work, I kicked a bundle, and picked it up; I saw they were stockings, I put them in my pocket, and was going home; I asked this lad by me, which was the nearest way to the Pye-shop, in Jewin-street? going along, that man came and laid hold of me, and asked what I did with the stockings? I said I had got them. I know no more of this lad (meaning Harrison) than the child unborn: I met him in the Horse-ride, going to Crowder's-well-alley.</p>
               <p>Harrison's Defence.</p>
               <p>I know no more of the thing than the child unborn: he asked me the way to the Pye-shop.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. How old is Harrison?</p>
               <p>Symonds. His mother says he is about thirteen years old.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17650227-24-verdict145" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650227-24-verdict145" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17650227-24-punish146" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650227-24-punish146" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-24-defend246 t17650227-24-punish146"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-24-defend248 t17650227-24-punish146"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>See Harrison tried before, No. 335. in last mayoralty, for picking a gentleman's pocket; for which he was cast and whipped.</p>
            </div1>
