<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640728-39">
               <interp inst="t17640728-39" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640728-39" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640728-39" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640728"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640728-39" type="date" value="17640728"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640728-39-off199-c250" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640728-39-defend338 t17640728-39-off199 t17640728-39-verdict203"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640728-39-off199-c251" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640728-39-defend340 t17640728-39-off199 t17640728-39-verdict203"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176407280017"></xptr>437, 438. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17640728-39-defend338" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Lacey 
                  <interp inst="t17640728-39-defend338" type="surname" value="Lacey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-defend338" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-defend338" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17640728-39-defend340" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Edwards 
                  <interp inst="t17640728-39-defend340" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-defend340" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-defend340" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted, for <rs id="t17640728-39-off199" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-off199" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-off199" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that they, on the King's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640728-39-victim342" type="victimName">
                           Philip 
                           Roper 
                        <interp inst="t17640728-39-victim342" type="surname" value="Roper"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640728-39-victim342" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640728-39-victim342" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640728-39-off199 t17640728-39-victim342"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17640728-39-viclabel200" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640728-39-victim342 t17640728-39-viclabel200"></join>; did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and violently taking from his person one gold watch, value 10 l. two knives, value 6 d. and 2 s. 6 d. in money, numbered, his property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17640728-39-cd201" type="crimeDate">June 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640728-39-off199 t17640728-39-cd201"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640728-39-person343">
                  Philip 
                  Roper 
               <interp inst="t17640728-39-person343" type="surname" value="Roper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person343" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person343" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; On the 27th of June last, I was coming from Sadler's-wells, between nine and ten o'clock: on <placeName id="t17640728-39-crimeloc202">Tottenham-court-road</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640728-39-crimeloc202" type="placeName" value="Tottenham-court-road"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640728-39-crimeloc202" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640728-39-off199 t17640728-39-crimeloc202"></join>, the coach was stopped, and the shutter was up on my side; a person said, Down with the shutter, and knocked at it with a stick: after a little time, I said, Gentlemen, have patience, and I'll let it down to you; I did, and there was a foot-pad on my side, and one on the other: he on my side said, D - n you, give me your watch, or you are a dead man; which, after denying it twice, I gave him; it was a gold watch, the outside case chased: he then demanded my money; I gave him 2 s. 6 d. after that, the other man came from the other side, after he had robbed the ladies, and said to me, D - n you, give me your purse, for I know you have one: I said I had none: he said, Sir, you are a dead man, if you don't give it me; he made me get up, and was going to search me; I said, Sir, I will not give you the trouble, I'll shew you my pockets. I took out of one pocket two penknives and two keys, which I surrendered to him, and said, the keys will be of no service to you, please to give me them again; he said, No, he would not; he would shoot me: then the other man said, Give the gentleman the keys, they will be of no service to us. He gave me one, and dropped the other on the ground; I desired he would pick it up; he said, Drive on, coachman.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you describe the two penknives?</p>
               <p>Roper. One is a buck-horn handle, with a broken point, and the other a tortoise-shell handle. When Lacey was taken, I saw him at Sir 
               <persName id="t17640728-39-person344">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17640728-39-person344" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person344" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person344" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, and he said he was in the robbery, and gave an account of it; he owned he took the penknives from me: (The knives produced and deposed to).</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640728-39-person345">
                  William 
                  Povey 
               <interp inst="t17640728-39-person345" type="surname" value="Povey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person345" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person345" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I happened to be at Sir 
               <persName id="t17640728-39-person346">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17640728-39-person346" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person346" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person346" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, on the 27th of June, in the afternoon, and Sir John's clerk ordered me to call a coach, and drive on; and said, we will come to you: the two Bareav's, (two brothers) were in the coach with me; we went to meet the horse patrole upon the new road to Marybone; we had pistols and hangers: we went up two or three hundred yards beyond the Farthing-pye house; two men came up to the horses heads, and cried, Stop, Stop: they were by the coach door with pistols; Your money, your money; they never stood to see if we would give them any, nor no answer was given them; they fired into the coach directly, yet I received no damage, but Bareav had a ball through his hat; as soon as ever that man fired, I fired at him, and hit him; there was firing on each side the coach in a moment, and away they ran; I fired at Lacey: we jumped out of the coach, and ran after them; I catched him presently; I saw him stagger; we took him into the coach after he had run about two hundred yards. I saw the other man get over a bank, and run cross a field: I saw Bareav take a yellow watch out of Lacey's hands.</p>
               <p>Lacey. I had not opened my mouth before I received a blow out of the coach, which took my right hand to pieces. When we came to the public-house, the Farthing-pye house, I asked for a handkerchief, two of my fingers being loose, and I wanted to wrap them together; the watch was then in my pocket, and I pulled it out immediately before them, but had not an opportunity of speaking, before they snatched it out of my hand, and said here it is.</p>
               <p>Povey. When Lacey was knocked down, this pistol was found under his backside: (Producing a pocket-pistol).</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640728-39-person347">
                  Abraham 
                  Bareav 
               <interp inst="t17640728-39-person347" type="surname" value="Bareav"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person347" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person347" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This gold watch I took from Lacey: (Producing a gold chased watch).</p>
               <p>Roper. This is my watch; the same I lost that night.</p>
               <p>Bareav. On the 27th of June, at night, I was at Sir 
               <persName id="t17640728-39-person348">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17640728-39-person348" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person348" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person348" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's; I went with my brother and Povey, in a coach, as far as Marybone turnpike, to meet the horse-patrole; when, about three hundred yards beyond the Farthing-pye house, I saw Lacey and Edwards come out of the fields, by the side of a rail, to come up to the coach; Edwards damned the coachman, and bid him stand; one came to one side, and the other to the other: he cried, Your money, your money, and immediately fired, and a ball went through my brother's hat: Edwards took a stick, and beat the coachman terribly; my brother put his hand out, and had it almost broke: when they ran away, I slipped down from a bank, and Lacey got upon me, and held a pistol to my head, and said I was a dead man: then assistance came, and he cried, Have mercy, and said, if you go over the ditch, you'll find the other man. We took Lacey to the Farthing-pye house; there he took out the gold watch, and laid it down on the table, and covered it with his handkerchief: I said, hold, there is a watch, and took it out of his hand. Edwards was on my side of the coach; my brother put his<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176407280018"></xptr> pistol close to Edwards, and fired powder in his face. When we were at the round-house, Lacey desired us to go to Tavistock-court, and at a Baker's shop, there we should find Edwards, who kept a whore there, when we came there, the woman said, he had been there, and ran away without his hat; she bid us go to such a place, and we should hear of him: we went to Lacey, and he told us: we found him in bed, and brought him down; this was in Strutton-ground, Westminster. We searched him, and found nothing upon him, but these two penknives here produced: I saw marks of powder on the left side of his face; it was almost full of powder, and his eye was bloodshot; there was a scratch on his face as if done with a shot.</p>
               <p>Q Are you certain that Edwards was one of the two men?</p>
               <p>Bareav. Upon my oath, I am sure he is the man that presented the pistol into the coach.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>Bareav. This was ten at night, or a little after, and a rainy night: it was not so dark, but I could see him very plain, as he came over the fields; and when he came up to the coach, I could see him plain enough: he d - d the coachman, and bid him stop, and fired into the coach, as soon as he got to the door: I fired after he did, and my brother fired in his face; I took particular notice of them both, and did not fire till they had fired.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640728-39-person349">
                  Edward 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17640728-39-person349" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person349" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person349" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am one of the patroles belonging to Sir 
               <persName id="t17640728-39-person350">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17640728-39-person350" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person350" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person350" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When Lacey was taken, he told us where we should find Edwards; we went and waited about till morning; then I went up stairs, and found him in bed; I held a pistol to his head, and said, you must go along with me; before he put on his breeches, I put my hand into his pocket, and took out these two knives here produced: I asked him whose they were? he said, they were his own. I said, what do you do with them? he said, they served to cut his nails. I happened to hear the gentleman talk of knives afterwards, then I told Sir 
               <persName id="t17640728-39-person351">
                  John 
                  I 
               <interp inst="t17640728-39-person351" type="surname" value="I"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person351" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person351" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             took two knives out of Edwards's pocket: Sir John bid me produce them, which I did, and the gentleman said they were his. As soon as I went into the room where Edwards was, I saw his face had powder in it, and his eye was bloodshot, and something had graz'd along his face: the constable was by, when I took the knives out of his pocket. Lacey owned the whole affair, and told us where to find Edwards.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. Did you observe Edwards's face, when you saw him at Sir 
               <persName id="t17640728-39-person352">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17640728-39-person352" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person352" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person352" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. His face was black when I saw him there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640728-39-person353">
                  William 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17640728-39-person353" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person353" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person353" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was sent on this occasion to apprehend those people: on the 27th of June, I went out on horseback, as far as Marybone turnpike, and through Paddington. Before I got to Marybone turnpike, I heard a noise in Marybone fields; I said to the turnpike-ma n, is any thing the matter? he said, I am afraid there is, for I heard three or four pistols go off. Mr. Povey, the constable, came to me, and said, we have got one of the thieves in the coach, which was Lacey; we brought him to the round-house, and he informed us that Edwards kept a girl in Tavistock-court: we went there, and found he was gone; then Lacey told us he lived up two pair of stairs, at the Half-Moon, in Strutton's-ground; we went, and staid till the people got up; then we went into a two pair of stairs room backwards; he bounced out of bed, and we took him directly; one of his eyes was very much bloodshot, and swelled up, and powder was about his face; when he began to dress him, Mr. Wright clapped his hand on his left breeches pocket, and brought out two penknives, and a key; I gave him the key again: he dressed himself: we searched him, and tied his hands, and brought him to the round-house; one of the knives was a buck-horn one, and the other a plainish handle: when we brought him down stairs, he had never a hat on, and he borrowed a hat to come in. (The penknives produced and deposed to by the Prosecutor.</p>
               <p>Lacey's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was so unhappy to be persuaded to go out that night; we met that honourable gentleman in a coach; I stood by the coach, in order to bid them stand: Edwards went up to the coach, and demanded what they had; I went up to one side of the coach, and begged of the gentleman; he said he had given what he had, and the two ladies said they had given what they had. I said to Edwards, for God's sake don't make a noise, but come away: then I believe 'Squire Roper delivered two knives, and a key or two; and said, don't take the keys, they'll be of no service to you; I delivered one key, but could not see the other: then the coachman drove on directly, after I begged of Edwards to come away. The coachman drove on towards the town; then we crossed the fields, in order to go to town; that was my intention; I beg'd of Edwards to go to town. As there had been a great noise and disturbance, I was afraid there would be some pursuit after us; we stood by the farthing pye-house some time:<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176407280019"></xptr> there was a coach went along; we thought it was going to town; we were going the same way: I knew no other than that it was an empty coach, I thought of going to town with it: I no sooner got up to the coach but I received a fire, which tore my hand to pieces. God knows I then thought it was a hard set upon us; I stood a moment or two: they ordered the coachman to drive on; I imagined we were attacked by officers, who were coming to seek for us, to bring us to justice; then I was taken directly and put into the coach, and taken down to the ale-house. I found I was left alone, to the unmerciful weapons they had about them. I could not defend myself in any shape. I voluntarily told where this unhappy young man was: I went to the round-house, a surgeon was sent for, I had two fingers taken off, and my hand drest that night; the next morning I was brought before Sir 
               <persName id="t17640728-39-person354">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17640728-39-person354" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person354" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person354" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            : what I said then, God Almighty knows, I can't remember from the agony I was then in. I beg of the court and judges to be merciful to me, that the latter end of my life may atone for what I acted that unhappy night.</p>
               <p>Edwards's Defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing of the affair, I have some witnesses here.</p>
               <p>For Edwards.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640728-39-person355">
                  Matthias 
                  Darley 
               <interp inst="t17640728-39-person355" type="surname" value="Darley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person355" type="given" value="Matthias"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person355" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Edwards some years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Darley. It is a very good one.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640728-39-person356">
                  James 
                  Balinger 
               <interp inst="t17640728-39-person356" type="surname" value="Balinger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person356" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person356" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him from his infancy; I never know any thing of him but that of a good character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640728-39-person357">
                  Thomas 
                  Field 
               <interp inst="t17640728-39-person357" type="surname" value="Field"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person357" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person357" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him upwards of three years, and always looked on him to be an honest man; he is a sadler, and his wife keeps a hosier's shop.</p>
               <p>Mr. Biffin. I have known him six years and upwards; I always found he bore an exceeding good character; I have trusted him in my shop many times; I never knew any ill by him.</p>

               <p>Mr. Bannister. I am in the tea-way; he often came to our house; we have had, it may be, an hundred pounds on our counter when he has been there; I never knew any ill by him; I never saw him in liquor in all my life.</p>
               <p>Mr. Johnson. I have known him about two or three years; I never heard any ill of him before this, in any respect. I have spent many an evening with him; and I have seen him with people of great reputation and worth; I never suspected any such behaviour as this.</p>
               <p>Mr. Baker. I have known him five years or upwards; he has a very good character, as far as ever I heard or saw.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640728-39-person358">
                  Edward 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17640728-39-person358" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person358" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person358" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him four or five years; I never heard any single fault of him, with regard to his character, but that he was a very honest just man; he is a sadler by trade; his friends are worthy people.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640728-39-person359">
                  Thomas 
                  Hughes 
               <interp inst="t17640728-39-person359" type="surname" value="Hughes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person359" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person359" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him between five and six years; I never heard any thing against his character; he is a free-hearted civil lad.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640728-39-person360">
                  Daniel 
                  Reney 
               <interp inst="t17640728-39-person360" type="surname" value="Reney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person360" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person360" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him several years; he bears a very good character; I have been in company with him several evenings; he always behaved like an honest civil man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640728-39-person361">
                  Robert 
                  Desbrough 
               <interp inst="t17640728-39-person361" type="surname" value="Desbrough"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person361" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-person361" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him better than twelve months; I never heard any harm of him in my life; he has a very good character.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17640728-39-verdict203" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-verdict203" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17640728-39-punish204" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640728-39-punish204" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640728-39-defend338 t17640728-39-punish204"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640728-39-defend340 t17640728-39-punish204"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
