<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610116-24">
               <interp inst="t17610116-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610116-24" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610116-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610116-24" type="date" value="17610116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610116-24-off130-c177" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610116-24-defend222 t17610116-24-off130 t17610116-24-verdict131"></join>
         
               <p>61. (M) Mary, <rs id="t17610116-24-deflabel128" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610116-24-defend222 t17610116-24-deflabel128"></join> of 
               <persName id="t17610116-24-person221">
                  Thomas 
                  Macintear 
               <interp inst="t17610116-24-person221" type="surname" value="Macintear"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610116-24-person221" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610116-24-person221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , otherwise 
               <persName id="t17610116-24-defend222" type="defendantName">
                  Mary 
                  Macintear 
               <interp inst="t17610116-24-defend222" type="surname" value="Macintear"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610116-24-defend222" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610116-24-defend222" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17610116-24-deflabel129" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610116-24-defend222 t17610116-24-deflabel129"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17610116-24-off130" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610116-24-off130" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610116-24-off130" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one linnen shift, value 3 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17610116-24-victim224" type="victimName">
                     Frances 
                     Coffield 
                  <interp inst="t17610116-24-victim224" type="surname" value="Coffield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610116-24-victim224" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610116-24-victim224" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610116-24-off130 t17610116-24-victim224"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            . Dec. 3. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610116-24-person225">
                  Mary 
                  Coffield 
               <interp inst="t17610116-24-person225" type="surname" value="Coffield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610116-24-person225" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610116-24-person225" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had taken my shift from a line, and put it in a basket at my bed's-head: the prisoner came to see me; I asked her to eat some bread and cheese. While we were talking together by the fire-side, there was an odd shift-sleeve hung on the line; I took, and put that in the basket. Then I am sure my shift was there. I was telling her how I had been robbed. I was taken ill, and could talk no more; and said I must lie down on my bed. I lay down, and she put the things about me: she wanted to draw the curtain; but I said I did not chuse that. She pulled the curtain with one hand, and I observed, at the same time, the things in the basket to stir; I looked, and saw her hand in the basket. I was afraid she was not an honest woman. She went away, and said she would bring some warm beer. When she was going out she asked me how she should fasten the door: I bid her fasten it, and put the key through the hole, which she did. As soon as I got a little better, I got up, looked in the basket, and missed my shift: it was a new one. She came to me in two days after; but I concluded not to let her know of it, 'till such time as I had an opportunity of taking her up; and I did not know but she would give me my shift again. At last I took her up, and before the justice she owned she had taken it, and cut it up.</p>
               <p>Q. What was your shift worth?</p>
               <p>M. Coffield. It was worth three shillings.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I never saw the prosecutrix 'till she came to me six weeks ago lask Monday; she was talking of her poverty, and I said I was as poor as she: she told me I should come and live along with her, if I would. I said I should be glad of it: she told me where she lived. I said she might enquire my character at Mr. Prentice's, a cheese-monger, near Smithfield-bars, and a breeches-maker's. She asked me when I would come to see her: I said next Thursday, and I would bring my child. I went, and when I came to the corner of the house, there was a puddle of water, I could not get my child over. I went into her room, and found her sitting by the fireside. She told me she was very bad with her head and eyes, and could not afford t o have any fire at all: she said she was so ill, she could not tell what to do. I perswaded her to lie down on the bed. She said she could not make any<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176101160029"></xptr> money, not having any thing in the room that would fetch her sixpence, except an old gown that she had fetched out of pawn the last week. I said I would give her part of a pint of warm beer. She bid me go to the Eight Bells, and fetch it. I did, and gave her about half of it, as she lay on the bed. Then I covered her up. She asked me to come again the next day. I could not go that day, but went the Saturday following: she seemed to make me very welcome, and gave me the best part of half a peck of flour, and desired to know when I would come and live with her. I said, I was afraid the place would not do for me, it was so dirty, I could not come in with my goods. I went away, and did not see her again 'till the Thursday fortnight after; then she took me up. The constable that had me in charge, paid for a bed for me in Bridewell, for a fortnight and three days, after he heard of my character.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610116-24-verdict131" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610116-24-verdict131" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610116-24-verdict131" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder1s"></interp>
               Guilty 10 d.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610116-24-punish132" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610116-24-punish132" type="punishmentCategory" value="corporal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610116-24-punish132" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="whipping"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610116-24-defend222 t17610116-24-punish132"></join>
               
                     <note>[Whipping. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
