<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610506-17">
               <interp inst="t17610506-17" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610506-17" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610506-17" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610506"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610506-17" type="date" value="17610506"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610506-17-off90-c185" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-17-defend215 t17610506-17-off90 t17610506-17-verdict93"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610506-17-off90-c197" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-17-defend229 t17610506-17-off90 t17610506-17-verdict93"></join>
         
               <p>175 (L) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610506-17-defend215" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Murrill 
                  <interp inst="t17610506-17-defend215" type="surname" value="Murrill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-defend215" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-defend215" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and Elizabeth his <rs id="t17610506-17-deflabel89" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-17-defend229 t17610506-17-deflabel89"></join>, in company with one 
               <persName id="t17610506-17-person216">
                  William 
                  Skettle 
               <interp inst="t17610506-17-person216" type="surname" value="Skettle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-person216" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-person216" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , not taken, were indicted for <rs id="t17610506-17-off90" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-off90" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-off90" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing five remnants of silk, containing four yards, value thirty-six shillings, and 37 silver twist buttons, one guinea, and seven shillings in money numbered
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17610506-17-victim218" type="victimName">
                     Samuel 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17610506-17-victim218" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-victim218" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-victim218" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-17-off90 t17610506-17-victim218"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17610506-17-cd91" type="crimeDate">April 26</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-17-off90 t17610506-17-cd91"></join>.~</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-17-person219">
                  Roger 
                  Preston 
               <interp inst="t17610506-17-person219" type="surname" value="Preston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-person219" type="given" value="Roger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-person219" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am book-keeper to the Norwich coach, which goes out from the <placeName id="t17610506-17-crimeloc92">Bull-inn in Bishopsgate-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17610506-17-crimeloc92" type="placeName" value="Bull-inn in Bishopsgate-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610506-17-crimeloc92" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-17-off90 t17610506-17-crimeloc92"></join>. Last Sunday was se'ennight I was up at supper; when I came down one of my porters told me, he had taken in two parcels,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176105060028"></xptr> and his son had carried them into the warehouse. I was going to enter them. I looked about for them, and could not find one of them. The boy told me he had laid it down on a bale, and shewed me where. I enquired who had been there; they told me only two sailors, and a woman; that which I missed was directed to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17610506-17-person220">
                  John 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17610506-17-person220" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-person220" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-person220" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of Norwich. At night the two prisoners came back again; I asked them if they had not meddled with a paper parcel when they were there before: they both denied it. I sent for a constable, and had them searched, and found in the woman's pocket two pieces of silk. [Produced in court.] I asked her how she came by it; she said her sister had given it to her on the Thursday night before. I charged the constable with them both; and in going with them to my lord-mayor, the man ran away when they got near the 'Change.</p>

               <p>Q. Are they man and wife?</p>
               <p>Preston. They said they were married the Saturday before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find any thing upon the man?</p>
               <p>Preston. No, we did not; my lord-mayor committed the woman for farther examination, till we could get the man. On the Tuesday night following the man was going along the street, and one of our ostlers took him, and he was carried before my lord-mayor, and committed. By enquiring about, I found the person that sent the parcel to go to Norwich, his name is Smith.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-17-person221">
                  Samuel 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17610506-17-person221" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-person221" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-person221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I carried a parcel last Sunday se'ennight, being the 26th of April, to go by the Norwich coach, and delivered it to 
               <persName id="t17610506-17-person222">
                  Jasper 
                  Wrangle 
               <interp inst="t17610506-17-person222" type="surname" value="Wrangle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-person222" type="given" value="Jasper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-person222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the porter to the coach, in the taproom, at the Black Bull, Bishopsgate-street; it contained five remnants of white silk, and three dozen of silver twist buttons, a guinea in gold, and seven shillings in silver; the silk and buttons were mine, and the money belongs to one 
               <persName id="t17610506-17-person223">
                  William 
                  Andrews 
               <interp inst="t17610506-17-person223" type="surname" value="Andrews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-person223" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-person223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , that gave it me to send down. I heard no more of the parcel 'till Mr. Preston called upon me with these two remnants of silk, here produced, which I knew to be part of the parcel I delivered there: I went before my lord-mayor, the prisoners were both present. The silk was produced there. I made oath they were part of the parcel. The woman at the bar said this silk was given her by a young fellow; the man said nothing about it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-17-person224">
                  Jasper 
                  Wrangle 
               <interp inst="t17610506-17-person224" type="surname" value="Wrangle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-person224" type="given" value="Jasper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-person224" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Smith delivered a parcel to me in the tap-room on the Sunday evening; I took money for the carriage, which is a usual custom. The prisoners were both in the room at the same time. They had taken places to go down on the outside of the coach. They had four bundles to put into the warehouse. I gave Mr. Smith's parcel to my boy, and desired him to carry them to the warehouse, which he did. About a quarter of an hour after, master came down stairs to book the things: then the warehouse was locked, and the boy had delivered the key to me. When we went in there was the parcel that Mr. Smith brought missing.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was your boy absent when you sent him with the parcel to the warehouse?</p>
               <p>Wrangle. He came directly to me. Then the two prisoners went out of the yard. They returned, it may be in about an hour and a half. Then we kept them in custody, and got a constable, and were going with them before my lord-mayor, but the man got away.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find any thing on either of the prisoners?</p>
               <p>Wrangle. The prisoners were both sitting on a bench by the tap room door; the woman offered to let drop a little parcel; I stepped up to her, and asked her what that was. She said to her husband, My dear, I had like to have lost the parcel that I had in my pocket. I looked, but saw nothing. In searching of her we found the paper, and two pieces of silk in it.</p>
               <p>Q. How old is your son?</p>
               <p>Wrangle. He is 13 years old. I don't look upon him capable to be examined.</p>
               <p>Q. How near to the warehouse was you when you sent your son with the parcel?</p>
               <p>Wrangle. It may be 20, or 22 or three yards distance.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you sit so as you could see him go to the warehouse-door?</p>
               <p>Wrangle. No, because the way is crooked, and it being night too; I saw him go that way with it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-17-person225">
                  James 
                  Murrill 
               <interp inst="t17610506-17-person225" type="surname" value="Murrill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-person225" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-person225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Defence.</p>
               <p>I went to the inn to go down to see my friends, which I have not seen seven years; I paid ten shillings to go to Norwich on the outside of the coach; the coachman asked me whether I would lie there that night; I said I should. I brought four handkerchiefs with me, and went into the tap-room with them, along with 
               <persName id="t17610506-17-person226">
                  William 
                  Skettle 
               <interp inst="t17610506-17-person226" type="surname" value="Skettle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-person226" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-person226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I had a pint of twopenny', and called to the book-keeper to take care of my things. He sent the lad; I went with him to the warehouse; My wife, and the lad, went both into the warehouse<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176105060029"></xptr> with the things. I was at the outside all the time; after that I went to Skettle's lodgings. I was married but the day before (Skettle gave my wife away.) at Bishopsgate church. There was another brother sailor there at the same time. I was much in liquor when I departed from them. Skettle asked his company-keeper for his parcel; she took it out of a drawer; he opened it, and made my wife a present of a bit of stuff to line her hat with, which he took from the parcel. When we came to the inn, they laid hold of us. If we had known it was dishonestly come by, we would not have come with it to the inn. I am but just come home, having been out of the kingdom seven years. It is a very hard thing a young couple should be drawn in so.</p>
               <p>Preston. The person he speaks of, is the same person that was with them at the inn.</p>
               <p>Elizabeth's Defence.</p>
               <p>I am innocent of it; the silk was made a present of to me to make me a hat.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoners.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-17-person227">
                  Mary 
                  Harrison 
               <interp inst="t17610506-17-person227" type="surname" value="Harrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-person227" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-person227" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the two prisoners about nine weeks. I was in bed with two fatherless children; I saw the silk given to 
               
                  <persName id="t17610506-17-defend229" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Murrill 
                  <interp inst="t17610506-17-defend229" type="surname" value="Murrill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-defend229" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-defend229" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , to make her a hat, that she might remember the person; and 
               <persName id="t17610506-17-person230">
                  Susan 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17610506-17-person230" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-person230" type="given" value="Susan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-person230" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             took a ribbon from off her head, and gave it her to put to the hat; it was a red and white ribbon; the silk was taken out of a piece of brown paper.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>M. Harrison. It was facing the George-ale-house, Whitechapel.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>M. Harrison. I believe it was last Sunday night was a week.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the night?</p>
               <p>M. Harrison. About ten o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you see this as you lay in bed?</p>
               <p>M. Harrison. There was only a bit of wainscot between us.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was it that gave it her?</p>
               <p>M. Harrison. It was 
               <persName id="t17610506-17-person231">
                  William 
                  Skettle 
               <interp inst="t17610506-17-person231" type="surname" value="Skettle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-person231" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-person231" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Could you see through the wainscot?</p>
               <p>M. Harrison. I heard their voices, I could not see them.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know it was taken from a parcel?</p>
               <p>M. Harrison. Skettle said, Give that parcel in a bit of brown paper to Betsy, and that will make her a hat. 
               <persName id="t17610506-17-person232">
                  Susan 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17610506-17-person232" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-person232" type="given" value="Susan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-person232" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             keeps company with Skettle.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you lived there?</p>
               <p>M. Harrison. I have lived there about two months.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be so particular as to the day?</p>
               <p>M. Harrison. Because they came and had a piece of beef and pudding for dinner; they had a half-crown bowl of punch that night, and one pot of beer.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-17-person233">
                  Mary 
                  Landy 
               <interp inst="t17610506-17-person233" type="surname" value="Landy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-person233" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-person233" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to a woman's house, named Wright, I asked her how this thing was, and she told me.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing more than what she told you?</p>
               <p>M. Landy. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know either of the prisoners?</p>
               <p>M. Landy. I have known the woman thirteen years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her character?</p>
               <p>M. Landy. She always bore a good character, she has worked where I do, and behaved herself very well; and I'll tell you who I work for; I work for Mr. Alavine, and all the gentlemen in the city; I'll call in more to her character, if you'll let me go out for an hour.</p>
               <p>Mary Neal. I know the woman at the bar to be a very honest creature.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known her?</p>
               <p>M. Neal. I have known her five years, she is as honest a creature as ever broke the bread of life; I would trust her with untold gold, if I had it to trust her with.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17610506-17-verdict93" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610506-17-verdict93" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
