<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17620526-17">
               <interp inst="t17620526-17" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620526-17" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620526-17" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17620526"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620526-17" type="date" value="17620526"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620526-17-off84-c119" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620526-17-defend143 t17620526-17-off84 t17620526-17-verdict89"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620526-17-off84-c120" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620526-17-defend145 t17620526-17-off84 t17620526-17-verdict91"></join>
         
               <p>169, 170. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17620526-17-defend143" type="defendantName">
                     Henry 
                     Geare 
                  <interp inst="t17620526-17-defend143" type="surname" value="Geare"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-defend143" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-defend143" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17620526-17-defend145" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Walker 
                  <interp inst="t17620526-17-defend145" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-defend145" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-defend145" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17620526-17-deflabel83" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620526-17-defend145 t17620526-17-deflabel83"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17620526-17-off84" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-off84" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-off84" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one pair of silver tea tongs, value 6 s. one piece of lawn, value 5 s. two pieces of lace, value 14 s. one man's hat, value 3 s. one cloth waistcoat, value 2 s. one pair of worsted stockings, value 2 s. one pair of worsted breeches, value 7 s. one piece of cotton cloth, value 6 s. six linen handkerchiefs, value 4 s. one tea-chest, value 10 s. four yards of cotton cloth, value 10 s. four yards of shalloon, value 6 s. one silk and stuff gown, value 10 s. one silk gown, value 36 s. nine yards of camblet, value 9 s. one linen bed-gown, value 3 s. one dimity petticoat, value 2 s. one baize petticoat, value 18 d. four yards and a half of linen cloth, value 6 s. one lawn handkerchief, with thread lace, value 4 s. three silk handkerchiefs, value 4 s. one other silk handkerchief, with silk lace, value 2 s. one cotton handkerchief, value 12 d. one muslin handkerchief, value 12 d. three linen caps, value 5 s. one lawn hood, value 6 d. one gause cap, value 2 s. one muslin cap, value 6 d. one muslin apron, value 4 s. one yard and half of lawn, value 2 s. four pieces of lawn for ruffles, value 4 s. six yards and a half of thread lace, value 9 s. one pair of lawn ruffles, value 12 d. one muslin neckcloth, value 2 s. two muslin stocks, eleven yards of silk ribbon, four yards of silk lace, one tortoiseshell snuff-box, inlaid with silver, one Spanish dollar, one silk cardinal, one silver thimble, one pair of stone and silver studs, two pair of stockings, and one common prayer book
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17620526-17-victim147" type="victimName">
                     Ann 
                     Wybourn 
                  <interp inst="t17620526-17-victim147" type="surname" value="Wybourn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-victim147" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-victim147" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17620526-17-viclabel85" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620526-17-victim147 t17620526-17-viclabel85"></join>, and 
               
                  <persName id="t17620526-17-victim149" type="victimName">
                     Peter 
                     Bushby 
                  <interp inst="t17620526-17-victim149" type="surname" value="Bushby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-victim149" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-victim149" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            .</p>
               <p>It was laid a second time for stealing the goods, the property of 
               <persName id="t17620526-17-person150">
                  Ann 
                  Wybourn 
               <interp inst="t17620526-17-person150" type="surname" value="Wybourn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person150" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person150" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , widow, 
               <persName id="t17620526-17-person151">
                  Peter 
                  Bushby 
               <interp inst="t17620526-17-person151" type="surname" value="Bushby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person151" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person151" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17620526-17-victim153" type="victimName">
                     James 
                     Allen 
                  <interp inst="t17620526-17-victim153" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-victim153" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-victim153" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            .</p>
               <p>It was a third time laid to be the goods of certain persons to the jury unknown, <rs id="t17620526-17-cd86" type="crimeDate">Apr. 28</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620526-17-off84 t17620526-17-cd86"></join>.*</p> 
               <p>James Allen. The two prisoners at the bar came to live with Mr. Wybourn in June last, he in the capacity of a <rs id="t17620526-17-deflabel87" type="occupation">journeyman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620526-17-defend143 t17620526-17-deflabel87"></join>, and she as <rs id="t17620526-17-deflabel88" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620526-17-defend145 t17620526-17-deflabel88"></join> in the house. Mr. Wybourn was a pawnbroker in Fleet-street: he died in July last, and left his widow and 
               <persName id="t17620526-17-person154">
                  Peter 
                  Bushby 
               <interp inst="t17620526-17-person154" type="surname" value="Bushby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person154" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person154" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             executors to his will. He left his whole effects to his wife and three children. Soon after his death I married the daughter. The widow being an elderly woman, and Mr. Bushby an infirm old man in the country, they gave me a power of attorney to settle their effects for them. The shop was continued on, and the two prisoners continued in their places. About a month before the 28th of April, 
               <persName id="t17620526-17-person155">
                  Daniel 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17620526-17-person155" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person155" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person155" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the apprentice gave me information that he suspected the prisoners were robbing of us. Upon which I immediately advertised for a journeyman: as I did not understand the business I thought proper to get a person that did before I parted with Geare. I hired one 
               <persName id="t17620526-17-person156">
                  John 
                  Swinton 
               <interp inst="t17620526-17-person156" type="surname" value="Swinton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person156" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person156" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            : when he came into the shop, which was on the 28th of April, I took Geare into the parlour, and charged him with robbing me. He had by some means got information that I had hired a journeyman, and had made up his account, and delivered it to me, I think, on the 26th. He told me, he heard I had got a journeyman. and he thought I used him ill in not giving him notice of it. When in the parlour, upon his denying it, I said I would send for a constable to take him before my lord mayor; but not knowing where to find a constable I sent for Mr. Ryall, a neighbour. The prisoner down on his knees, and took me round the waist, and said, if I would spare his life he would confess all. He owned he had robb'd me of a very considerable quantity of things, and I should have them all again. I told him to be sure he was a very great rogue, and I had been informed what he had done, and only waited for an opportunity to detect him. I fetch'd him a pen and ink, and desired him to write down what he had robb'd me of. Upon which he wrote a paper: here it is [producing it.] I saw him write part of it; but was not by him all the time. I know it to be his own hand-writing. I said this is not the hundredth part of what you have robb'd me of. Then he added a little more, and so he added till it came to the whole on the paper.</p>
               <p>The paper read.</p>
               <p>One pair of tea-tongs, 6 s. a piece of lawn, 5 s. a piece of lace, 14 s. one hat, 3 s. a handkerchief, 18 d. a pair of stockings, 2 s. one pair of stocking breeches, 7 s. a piece of cotton, 6 s. a piece of linen, 3 l.</p>
               <p>Allen. That linen is not in the indictment.</p>
               <p>A waistcoat, 6 s. another ditto, 5 s.</p>
               <p>Allen. They are not in the indictment; the linen and two waistcoats he had before agreed for, and had made himself debtor for them in his account.</p>
               <p>Three or four pocket handkerchiefs, 9 d. each, a tea-chest half a crown.</p>
               <p>What Nanney had.</p>
               <p>A piece of linen, 5 s. a pair of - [it is wrote so as not to be under stood] price 5 s. a hit of stuff, half a guinea, stuff, 6 s. lace, 10 s. 6 d. a piece of cheque. 18 d. a silk gown, 18 s. a petticoat, 2 s.</p>
               <p>Allen. That is not in the indictment; he confessed he stole all these things, except them that he had put to his account. I know Mr. Wybourn consented he should have the linen for 3 l. I deducted that money and the money for the two waistcoats out of his wages. Then I went up and called 
               <persName id="t17620526-17-person157">
                  Ann
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176205260012"></xptr> Walker<interp inst="t17620526-17-person157" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person157" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             into the dining-room, and examined her. I asked her to bring down her boxes. She did, and opened them; I believe there were three of them. We took the things out; there was a brown silk gown, a purple gown made of silk and stuff, a brown stuff gown (this in the indictment is laid as so much stuff) she had since got it made up, a linen bed gown, a white dimity petticoat, a green baize petticoat, a laced cap, two plain caps, a laced handkerchief, a silk handkerchief, a white apron not made up, a common prayer book, a remnant of long lawn, a black silk laced handkerchief, a body of a shift, two remnants of black lace, one remnant of white lace, a pair of silk hose (an old pair not mentioned in the indictment), another shift body, a white apron, a pair of double ruffles, an old silk handkerchief, some remnants of ribbands, a cotton handkerchief, a neckcloth, a white handkerchief, two stocks, a snuff box, a Spanish dollar, a blue handkerchief, a petticoat (that was made up since she had the stuff), a black cardinal, a silver thimble, and a pair of studs. She said she had them all of the prisoner Geare, and had paid him a guinea and a half in part, and intended to pay him the rest. She had carried a pair of double ruffles to a haberdasher's next door, to be made up, and two pair of silk stockings, a silk handkerchief, and a blue and white handkerchief, she confessed to me, after she was committed, she had carried and left at a neighbour's up the court.</p>

               <p>On his Cross Examination, he said, Geare had a power to receive and deliver goods, and to tell them in the shop: that he apprehended the prisoner put down the figures to the goods, to shew what they lay for in the warehouse: that he never bid him to put the figures down: that he only bid him put down what he had stole from him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620526-17-person158">
                  John 
                  Ryall 
               <interp inst="t17620526-17-person158" type="surname" value="Ryall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person158" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person158" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Allen sent for me on the 28th of April in the morning; I found Geare in the room, seeming very melancholy, and cried several times. Mr. Allen said he had robbed him of a great many things, and was going to discharge him on that account; upon which he begged and prayed of me to intercede with Mr. Allen for him, and said he would make him satisfaction for any injury he had done him. I recommended to him to let Mr. Allen know of every thing that he had done amiss, and then there would be some sort of room to speak in his favour. I said I understood the maid and he had been concerned together in taking the things; and, if his account and hers agreed, it might induce me to speak to his master in his favour. I saw the prisoner begin to write this paper, saying, he would set down the things he had taken upon one side of the paper: he put down things that he said he delivered to Nanny; he said she knew nothing of his taking them without accounting with his master for them, and he said he had received a guinea and half of her, and she was to pay him the rest. His master desired him to tell him what the whole of the things amount to that she had had at different times; he said, about two guineas and a half. Upon this I desired him to shew me his master's books, wherein he had made the maid debtor for the other guinea, and then I should have a better opinion of him: He looked, but could not find such an account; then he looked over a great many tickets, and said he should find a ticket, whereon she was made debtor. After looking a great while, he said she had paid the whole, and the money was in the till. The things he set down on the other side the paper he owned he had taken out of the shop and warehouse, and the price of linen at 3 l. he had accounted for with his master; the other things he could give no account of. I am not quite certain whether he did not except an article or two besides the linen; he owned he had taken them at different times, and many of them he had given to a girl whom he had a great regard for, one Nanny Ford.</p>
               <p>Q. The account of things that Nanny had, did he mean 
               <persName id="t17620526-17-person159">
                  Ann 
                  Ford 
               <interp inst="t17620526-17-person159" type="surname" value="Ford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person159" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person159" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             or 
               <persName id="t17620526-17-person160">
                  Ann 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17620526-17-person160" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person160" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person160" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Ryall. He meant 
               <persName id="t17620526-17-person161">
                  Ann 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17620526-17-person161" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person161" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person161" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I told him I was afraid there were more things that he had taken. Then he said he recollected more, and wrote down one piece of lawn, one guinea, and said that was all he recollected; he owned he had stole these things from his master, and, if he would forgive him, he would make him full satisfaction, and likewise for any thing else that he should afterwards recollect that he had taken.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing as to 
               <persName id="t17620526-17-person162">
                  Ann 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17620526-17-person162" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person162" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person162" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Royall. When Mr. Allen examined her, and she brought her boxes down, I was present. I set down on this paper (holding a paper in his hand), from her own mouth, what she said she had from 
               <persName id="t17620526-17-person163">
                  Harry 
                  Geare 
               <interp inst="t17620526-17-person163" type="surname" value="Geare"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person163" type="given" value="Harry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person163" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She said she bought them at different times of Geare; she had paid him some, and was to pay him the surplus sums as I here put down. I don't recollect what money she said the had paid him.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the Amount of the money that you by her direction put down?</p>
               <p>Ryall. It amounts to about 3 l. 15 s.</p>
               <p>Q. to Allen. How long before this happened was it that you settled accounts with Geare?</p>
               <p>Allen. I never settled with him to this time; he delivered his account the Monday before.</p>
               <p>Q. What wages might be due to him when this happened?</p>
               <p>Allen. Here is his account, he says, coming to him, 8 l. 6 d.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he in that account charge himself with any other goods besides this piece of linen?</p>
               <p>Allen. Yes, the two waistcoats which I mentioned, that is all.</p>
               <p>Q. What was his wages a year?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176205260013"></xptr>Allen. He had 20 l. a year.</p>
               <p>Q. How much is due to him for wages?</p>
               <p>Allen. 17 l. 2 s. deducting the linen and waistcoats; in his account, in all, five guineas he received in cash. He has said at different times, Sir, I want a guinea, and I have given it him. I gave him a strict order never to take any money out of the till for his own use. The linen at 3 l. and two waistcoats at 11 s. the balance is 8 l. 6 d. If he had sold these goods in the shop, it was his business to have put the money into the till; and the rule of the shop is, that he should settle the shop every night, and give me the tickets; they go regularly into books after that.</p>
               <p>Lion Marks. I know this 
               <persName id="t17620526-17-person164">
                  Harry 
                  Geare 
               <interp inst="t17620526-17-person164" type="surname" value="Geare"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person164" type="given" value="Harry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person164" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to be a very honest fellow; he asked me about four months ago if I had a thickset coat for him (I keep a shop, and deal in old cloaths). I sold him one for 14 s. I come to that shop every day in my life; I came two or three times; he did not pay me; at last I bought this piece of linen cloth of him in the shop, and took it at 10 s. in part payment.</p>
               <p>Q. to Allen. Is this in the account Geare has delivered to you?</p>
               <p>Allen. No, it is not; I never had known of it, if the man had not discovered it.</p>
               <p>Marks. He put it down in a little book, and said it was his own account.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this done publicly, or in a whisper?</p>
               <p>Marks. It was not in a whisper, but publicly in the shop; 
               <persName id="t17620526-17-person165">
                  Daniel
               <interp inst="t17620526-17-person165" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person165" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the boy was in the shop at the time. (The linen produced)</p>
               <p>Allen. That Daniel is the apprentice.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620526-17-person166">
                  Daniel 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17620526-17-person166" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person166" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person166" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sent for, and examined.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620526-17-person167">
                  Daniel 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17620526-17-person167" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person167" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person167" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am apprentice at Mr. Allen's.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember this piece of linen in Mr. Allen's shop?</p>
               <p>Brown. I remember it hanging in the shop.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you present when Geare sold it?</p>
               <p>Brown. I do not remember that I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember being in the shop when Marks received any thing of Geare in part of payment for a frock?</p>
               <p>Brown. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. to Marks. Did you not say this lad was in the shop at the time?</p>
               <p>Marks. I think he was, but I can't safely say he was.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620526-17-person168">
                  William 
                  Boddington 
               <interp inst="t17620526-17-person168" type="surname" value="Boddington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person168" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person168" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable. [He produced the goods.] I was sent for, I believe on the 28th of April; there was Geare very melancholy in the room, Mr. Allen gave me charge of him. Geare wrote down several things that he said he had taken from his master.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the word steal?</p>
               <p>Boddington. I can't say I did; he said he made presents to 
               <persName id="t17620526-17-person169">
                  Ann 
                  Ford 
               <interp inst="t17620526-17-person169" type="surname" value="Ford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person169" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person169" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             of a tea chest and a great many things, but she did not know that they were stole.</p>
               <p>Q. to Allen. Look at the things produced; do you know them, or either of them?</p>
               <p>Allen. It is impossible I should swear to them, as the bills were taken off.</p>
               <p>Geare's Defence.</p>
               <p>I am not guilty of any thing that is laid to my charge; I honestly paid for them all.</p>
               <p>Walker's Defence.</p>
               <p>I never had any thing of him but what I always paid for.</p>
               <p>Geare called 
               <persName id="t17620526-17-person170">
                  Henry 
                  Adamson 
               <interp inst="t17620526-17-person170" type="surname" value="Adamson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person170" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person170" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17620526-17-person171">
                  William 
                  Adamson 
               <interp inst="t17620526-17-person171" type="surname" value="Adamson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person171" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person171" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17620526-17-person172">
                  John 
                  Humphrys 
               <interp inst="t17620526-17-person172" type="surname" value="Humphrys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person172" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person172" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who had known him from his birth, 
               <persName id="t17620526-17-person173">
                  Robert 
                  Stone 
               <interp inst="t17620526-17-person173" type="surname" value="Stone"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person173" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person173" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17620526-17-person174">
                  David 
                  Spires 
               <interp inst="t17620526-17-person174" type="surname" value="Spires"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person174" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person174" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             13 years. Thomas Brooks three years, and 
               <persName id="t17620526-17-person175">
                  Ambrose 
                  Stevenson 
               <interp inst="t17620526-17-person175" type="surname" value="Stevenson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person175" type="given" value="Ambrose"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person175" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             14 years, who all gave him a good character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620526-17-person176">
                  Thomas 
                  Trott 
               <interp inst="t17620526-17-person176" type="surname" value="Trott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person176" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person176" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have not known the prisoner a great while.</p>
               <p>Q. How long?</p>
               <p>Trott. I believe eight or nine months.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character?</p>
               <p>Trott. I know nothing of his character.</p>
               <p>Walker called Hannah Osbourn, who had known her four years, 
               <persName id="t17620526-17-person177">
                  Arabella 
                  Wager 
               <interp inst="t17620526-17-person177" type="surname" value="Wager"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person177" type="given" value="Arabella"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-person177" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and Fra. Couche, who had known her a year and half, and gave her a good character.</p>
               <p>Geare <rs id="t17620526-17-verdict89" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-verdict89" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17620526-17-punish90" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-punish90" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620526-17-defend143 t17620526-17-punish90"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Walker <rs id="t17620526-17-verdict91" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620526-17-verdict91" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
