<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670909-82">
               <interp inst="t17670909-82" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670909-82" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670909-82" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670909"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670909-82" type="date" value="17670909"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670909-82-off496-c729" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-82-defend910 t17670909-82-off496 t17670909-82-verdict500"></join>
         
               <p>513. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17670909-82-defend910" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Pentecost 
                  <interp inst="t17670909-82-defend910" type="surname" value="Pentecost"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-82-defend910" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-82-defend910" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17670909-82-off496" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670909-82-off496" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-82-off496" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               forging and counterfeiting a certain promissory note to this purport; I promise to pay to 
                     <persName id="t17670909-82-person911">
                        William 
                        Newcomen 
                     <interp inst="t17670909-82-person911" type="surname" value="Newcomen"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670909-82-person911" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670909-82-person911" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , Esq; or order, thirty-one days after date, the sum of 22 l. 10 s. 6 d. value received, 
                     <persName id="t17670909-82-person912">
                        George 
                        Bowes 
                     <interp inst="t17670909-82-person912" type="surname" value="Bowes"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670909-82-person912" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670909-82-person912" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , directed to Sir 
                     <persName id="t17670909-82-person913">
                        Charles 
                        Asgill 
                     <interp inst="t17670909-82-person913" type="surname" value="Asgill"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670909-82-person913" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670909-82-person913" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   and Co. &amp;c. and for publishing it, with intent to defraud 
                     
                        <persName id="t17670909-82-victim915" type="victimName">
                           Henry 
                           Moreror 
                        <interp inst="t17670909-82-victim915" type="surname" value="Moreror"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670909-82-victim915" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670909-82-victim915" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-82-off496 t17670909-82-victim915"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , knowing it to be false, forged, and counterfeited
            </rs>, dated <rs id="t17670909-82-cd497" type="crimeDate">Nov. 7, 1766</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-82-off496 t17670909-82-cd497"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-82-person916">
                  Henry 
                  Moreror 
               <interp inst="t17670909-82-person916" type="surname" value="Moreror"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-82-person916" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-82-person916" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am in the <rs id="t17670909-82-viclabel498" type="occupation">silk handkerchief manufactory</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-82-victim915 t17670909-82-viclabel498"></join>, and live in <placeName id="t17670909-82-crimeloc499">Prince's-street, Spital-fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17670909-82-crimeloc499" type="placeName" value="Prince's-street, Spital-fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17670909-82-crimeloc499" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-82-off496 t17670909-82-crimeloc499"></join>. On the 4th of December last, about three in the afternoon, the prisoner wrapped pretty hard at the street door; I let him in; he asked if this was not a handkerchief weaver's; I said it was; he desired to look at some; I desired him to walk up with me into the warehouse; I asked him what sort he wanted; there lay some before him, he said such as these; then he said he wanted some curlgees, that is, printed handkerchiefs; I told him we have not made many of that sort lately; he saw another sort; let me look at these, said he, they are very pretty patterns; he looked at them, and said, I have one thing to say to you, I am no judge in the matter, and therefore I shall leave it to you, and I shall pay you ready money, and if you deceive me you deceive yourself, what do<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176709090071"></xptr> you ask a dozen for these; I said fifty shillings; do not you call that a great price, said he; I said no; then I showed him three sorts more of goods, silk and cotton, and said there is a great demand for these at this time of the year; he looked out five dozen; I told him the price was twenty-six shillings a dozen; he said it was a long price; I said I could not abate a farthing; then he made come of more, in all it came to 21 l 10 s. he wanted me to abate; I said I could not; then he said he should enquire in the trade, and if he found I had exacted upon him, he would never deal with me again; and if he found I had not, he should want more goods of me in six weeks; then he said there is a discount always allowed between ready money and credit; I said I had let him have them to follow, that I could not allow one farthing; then he said, make a bill, and write a receipt, and I will pay you. I went to make the bill; he said, I think it is time I had my dinner, having had nothing but two dishes of coffee; I said, if you will walk down with me you are welcome, and take part of such as we have; no, said he, I must make haste to the inn; I said, what is your name; he said, my name is 
               <persName id="t17670909-82-person917">
                  Thomas 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17670909-82-person917" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-82-person917" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-82-person917" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I said, pray do you live in town or in the country; said he, I live at Cowley in Middlesex, I keep the sign of the Cock, and keep a shop there; I made the bill out; he took it in his hand, and looked over it; it was 21 l. 10 s. said he, it is very right, write a receipt, and put the name of the street where you live on it; I did; then he put his hand into his pocket, and gave me this bill; he opened it very gingerly, and said, you must take care of it, it has a little fracture; I looked at it; he mentioned the sum; I said, then you must have twenty shillings and six pence, and gave it him; then I gave him a glass of brandy; he came up to me, and said, Sir, here is success to trade; I said, I am much obliged to you; I said, I was sorry to trouble him to carry his goods, I would send them to the inn; he said, do you think I cannot carry such a little parcel as this, and besides I would not give a pin for that man that is above his business; we parted; he had not been gone above eight or ten minutes before I began to look over the bill; I thought to myself, how do I know that this 
               <persName id="t17670909-82-person918">
                  George 
                  Bowes 
               <interp inst="t17670909-82-person918" type="surname" value="Bowes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-82-person918" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-82-person918" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             keeps cash with Sir Charles Asgill; I ran down to Sir Charles's, and shewed the clerk the bill, and told him the affair; said he, have you got the man in custody; I said, no, I had not; they advised me to go to Sir 
               <persName id="t17670909-82-person919">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17670909-82-person919" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-82-person919" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-82-person919" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             immediately, and give him information of the person; I ran to Sir John's, and gave all the account of the prisoner I was able; while I was describing him, all Sir John's people said, this is Pentecost, as wicked a fellow as any in the world; they said, it is no wonder he had deceived me, for he would deceive the d - l; they said, we shall have him by and by. On the 3d of July, in the evening, I went to take a little walk, I happened to drop in at a house, the Red Lion, the very corner house going into Bunhill-row; I had got a pint mug up drinking, I saw the prisoner; I knew I was in a very honest house, and there were very creditable people in it, I thought I should have enough on my side; as soon as his pint was out, he said to his friend, I suppose we must stand another pint; I thought by the time they drank another pint, I could go to the Admiral Vernon's Head, to a friend of mine; I went, and my friend came with me; I found the prisoner sitting as before; I went up to him, and leaned over the box, and said, how do you do, Sir, I am very glad to see you, I have not seen you since last December, though I assure you I have kept a strict look out for you on each side the way, when I have walked the streets; said he, what does this fellow mean; then I told him of his coming and giving me such a bill, and that I gave him 20 s. and 6 d. change; said he, what impudent fellow are you; said I, you shall soon know; I told the people he was one of those fellows that defrauded tradesmen by false notes; said he, if I do not make you piss on the wrong side the pot, my name is no longer Smith; here, said he, bring me pen, ink, and paper, I will give you an account who I am, meet me here tomorrow; no, no, said I, I do not leave you; I go along with you, said he, you foolish fellow, no, I do not; I ordered a coach, when it came, I said, come, Mr. Pentecost, put down your pipe, you shall go along with me; said he, no, not with twenty such as you; said I, you villain, if you have a mind to put on any manhood, exert it, for you go along with me, dead or alive, to night; we put him in the coach, and got him down with his back to the horses; he got up once, and shoved me down in the coach; we carried him to the Compter, he ran into the lodge, and said, bring me a shilling's worth of punch, and some pipes and tobacco; the next day I took him from thence before Sir John Fielding, there he opened a great deal of villainy, of robbing stage coaches and stage waggons, taking portmanteaus, and the like; Sir John committed him upon this forged bill.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176709090072"></xptr>Q. Do you know any thing of this 
               <persName id="t17670909-82-person920">
                  George 
                  Bowes 
               <interp inst="t17670909-82-person920" type="surname" value="Bowes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-82-person920" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-82-person920" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             mentioned in this paper?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of 
               <persName id="t17670909-82-person921">
                  William 
                  Newcomen 
               <interp inst="t17670909-82-person921" type="surname" value="Newcomen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-82-person921" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-82-person921" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No, I do not; I do not know whether there are such people in the world.</p>
               <p>The bill produced and read in court</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17670909-82-verdict500" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670909-82-verdict500" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was detained to be tried for obtaining goods by false pretences.</p>
               <p>See him tried for defrauding Mr. Warner and Co. of twenty chaldron of coals, No 471, in last Mayoralty; and also for stealing a quantity of wearing apparel, the property of 
               <persName id="t17670909-82-person922">
                  William 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17670909-82-person922" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-82-person922" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-82-person922" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
            </div1>
