<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660903-49">
               <interp inst="t17660903-49" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-49" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-49" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660903"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-49" type="date" value="17660903"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660903-49-off262-c353" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-49-defend451 t17660903-49-off262 t17660903-49-verdict264"></join>
         
               <p>447. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660903-49-defend451" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Newman 
                  <interp inst="t17660903-49-defend451" type="surname" value="Newman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-49-defend451" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-49-defend451" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17660903-49-off262" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660903-49-off262" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-49-off262" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               stealing 37 planes, five saws, an oil-stone, and a hammer, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17660903-49-victim453" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Duck 
                        <interp inst="t17660903-49-victim453" type="surname" value="Duck"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660903-49-victim453" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660903-49-victim453" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  ; seven chisels, a wooden stock, a hammer, and a pair of pincers
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17660903-49-victim455" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Frith 
                  <interp inst="t17660903-49-victim455" type="surname" value="Frith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-49-victim455" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-49-victim455" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17660903-49-cd263" type="crimeDate">June 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-49-off262 t17660903-49-cd263"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-49-person456">
                  John 
                  Duck 
               <interp inst="t17660903-49-person456" type="surname" value="Duck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-49-person456" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-49-person456" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the passage going out of Butcherhall-lane into Little Britain. On the 27th of June in the morning, I went up into my shop and missed several tools; some time afterwards there was an advertisement of these tools being at a broker's shop in St. Giles's; I went and found them to be my property; the broker said he knew the person of whom he bought them; we went before Justice Welch, and he granted a warrant to take up the prisoner: I never saw the prisoner before he was taken.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-49-person457">
                  John 
                  Frith 
               <interp inst="t17660903-49-person457" type="surname" value="Frith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-49-person457" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-49-person457" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am journeyman to 
               <persName id="t17660903-49-person458">
                  John 
                  Duck 
               <interp inst="t17660903-49-person458" type="surname" value="Duck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-49-person458" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-49-person458" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 28th of June in the morning, I saw three saws lying on the top of a book-case, that I was<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176609030040"></xptr> finishing; after that I saw a ripping chisel of mine that had not seen light a great while; then I went to my own bench, and saw three moulding planes lie there; then I went to my chest and found it open, and missed my planes, chisels, and other things; I found them again at Mr. Pickering's, a broker in St. Giles's; he advertised them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-49-person459">
                  Thomas 
                  Pickering 
               <interp inst="t17660903-49-person459" type="surname" value="Pickering"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-49-person459" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-49-person459" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a broker, and live in St. Giles's; I also keep a pawnbroker's shop; the prisoner came to my house the Thursday before the 27th of June; he asked me if I would buy some carpenters tools; I said I would, if I could get any thing by them; (I am a bricklayer by trade) he said his wife was dead, and his uncle had sent for him into the country; he brought two bags full, and six saws, on the 27th, (three saws produced in court) these are three of them; he asked 11 s. for four, I did not chuse to buy them; he went out of the shop, and left his bag in the shop; he told me he could sell them for more money than I would give for them, where he worked; he went out; I followed him unknown to him in the street; I attacked him by Berkley square, and said, I am afraid you do not come honestly by these things; he took me to his own father in Mount-street; his father said the saws were the prisoner's own; I said, I'll take the four saws and go to the shop you mentioned in Tyburn-road, and if they know any thing of them, I'll buy them; he was to follow me, but I could find no such carpenter's shop there, as he had mentioned to me; then I went to Justice Welch, and had the things advertised, and on the Monday morning Mr. Duck came and owned them; here is his name upon them; after that, the prisoner was taken in Smithfield by the description I gave of him; I believe there is a gang of them: (the other tools produced and deposed to by the respective owners.)</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I never was in the shop in my life; I had an action out against me, and was obliged to go to the other end of the town; I met a man with these things on his back; I asked him if he could help me to a job; he desired me to carry them tools for him, and he would do what he could to help me to business; we stopped to have some lop in Holbourn, and while we were there he left me with all these things.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660903-49-verdict264" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660903-49-verdict264" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17660903-49-punish265" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660903-49-punish265" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-49-defend451 t17660903-49-punish265"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
