<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640502-77">
               <interp inst="t17640502-77" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640502-77" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640502-77" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640502"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640502-77" type="date" value="17640502"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640502-77-off434-c548" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-77-defend704 t17640502-77-off434 t17640502-77-verdict438"></join>
         
               <p>311. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17640502-77-defend704" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Davis 
                  <interp inst="t17640502-77-defend704" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-77-defend704" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-77-defend704" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17640502-77-deflabel433" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-77-defend704 t17640502-77-deflabel433"></join>, (together with two others, not yet taken) was indicted for <rs id="t17640502-77-off434" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640502-77-off434" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-77-off434" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing seventy thirty-six shilling pieces, value 126 l. 9 s. and a canvass bag, value 1 d.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17640502-77-victim706" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Morrison 
                  <interp inst="t17640502-77-victim706" type="surname" value="Morrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-77-victim706" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-77-victim706" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-77-off434 t17640502-77-victim706"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17640502-77-cd435" type="crimeDate">April 25</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-77-off434 t17640502-77-cd435"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640502-77-person707">
                  John 
                  Morrison 
               <interp inst="t17640502-77-person707" type="surname" value="Morrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-77-person707" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-77-person707" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 25th of last month I was going up Fleet-street, about half an hour after eight in the evening: I was inquiring my way to my lodgings at Temple-bar.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Morrison. I am an <rs id="t17640502-77-viclabel436" type="occupation">armourer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-77-victim706 t17640502-77-viclabel436"></join>, just come from Antigua. I met with the prisoner and another woman; they told me they would shew me the nearest way: they took me to their lodging, a private room, in <placeName id="t17640502-77-crimeloc437">Ashen-tree court</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640502-77-crimeloc437" type="placeName" value="Ashen-tree court"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640502-77-crimeloc437" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-77-off434 t17640502-77-crimeloc437"></join>, where I sent out for some supper and liquor: I shewed them my money, seventy 36 s. pieces, and about 9 s. in silver. I went to sleep. The prisoner was the last woman I saw when I went to bed: and a little before five in the morning, she burst the door<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176405020043"></xptr> open: I awaked, and saw her come flying into the room: she inquired of me where was the other woman that was at supper with me last night: I said, I did not know: she said, have you got your money, Sir? I felt in my breeches, and my money was gone: no, said I: she ran crying out at the door, making a noise. In about a minute and a half in came Woodward Harlow; he asked me the same questions, and away he ran: he did not stay above half a minute in the room: then the constable came in, and said, I hear you have lost some money in this house: yes, Sir, said I: he said, come along with me, I'll secure this woman till you can find the rest. I dressed myself, and went along with him to the Mansion-house before the alderman. The prisoner confessed she saw the money before I went to sleep, but denied that she took it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever find it.</p>
               <p>Morrison. No, never.</p>
               <p>Q. Did either of the women go to bed with you?</p>
               <p>Morrison. No, neither of them did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640502-77-person708">
                  John 
                  Knapton 
               <interp inst="t17640502-77-person708" type="surname" value="Knapton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-77-person708" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-77-person708" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable. I was on my watch: there came a parcel of people to me, and desired I would come directly, saying, a man was robbed of an hundred pounds: I went: the prosecutor charged the prisoner with stealing the money from out of his breeches under his bed. I searched the prisoner, and found four shillings and two-pence half-penny. She told me, as we were going before the alderman, the first good booty they got, they designed to set out for Bristol.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did she mean by they?</p>
               <p>Knapton. That is, she and 
               <persName id="t17640502-77-person709">
                  Mary 
                  Powlin 
               <interp inst="t17640502-77-person709" type="surname" value="Powlin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-77-person709" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-77-person709" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the other girl, not taken: she said, they had agreed upon that. She said she saw the money before the alderman: she denied having taken it. I have had her sixteen or seventeen times in custody.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>The other girl picked up this man, and carried him home to this room. I had a bad leg, and could not go out. The man sent for five or six quarterns of rum; after that, he sent out for some goose; she brought him some up: after that, he gave her four shillings to go to bed with him: I locked the door, and put the key under it: this was about a quarter before twelve: I went out, and returned about a quarter before five: the door was open, and he awake in bed: he said he was robbed of all but a shilling and some halfpence: after that, the gentleman came and took me to the compter, and took four shillings and two-pence halfpenny from me.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. Had you any women in bed with you?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I cannot recollect I had any.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640502-77-person710">
                  John 
                  Croaker 
               <interp inst="t17640502-77-person710" type="surname" value="Croaker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-77-person710" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-77-person710" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Ashen-tree court: I have two rooms there. The prisoner was coming home from an Irish Wake, in George-alley: said she, there is a woman in the room with the gentleman; he has so much money about him, and if it is lost, I may be hanged instead of her. I went into the room; there lay his watch in the chair: said she, did I rob you? he said, No: this was a quarter after five.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640502-77-person711">
                  Margaret 
                  Bartley 
               <interp inst="t17640502-77-person711" type="surname" value="Bartley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-77-person711" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-77-person711" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live under the place where the robbery was committed, in the same house. All I know, the poor creature, the prisoner, went out about 12 o'clock, and came in about a quarter after five. I was awake, almost all the time: she clapped her hands, and said, she was undone; the man had lost his money, and she should come into trouble: she said, she had been at an Irish wake, in George alley.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640502-77-verdict438" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640502-77-verdict438" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
