<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610625-16">
               <interp inst="t17610625-16" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-16" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-16" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610625"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-16" type="date" value="17610625"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610625-16-off88-c104" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-16-defend129 t17610625-16-off88 t17610625-16-verdict92"></join>
         
               <p>193 (L) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610625-16-defend129" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Hemmings 
                  <interp inst="t17610625-16-defend129" type="surname" value="Hemmings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-16-defend129" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-16-defend129" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17610625-16-off88" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610625-16-off88" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-16-off88" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one leather cloak bag, value 18 d. one rush basket, value 3 d. and 18 dead pigeons, value 4 s. 6 d.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17610625-16-victim131" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Riley 
                  <interp inst="t17610625-16-victim131" type="surname" value="Riley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-16-victim131" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-16-victim131" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-16-off88 t17610625-16-victim131"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17610625-16-cd89" type="crimeDate">April 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-16-off88 t17610625-16-cd89"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-16-person132">
                  William 
                  Riley 
               <interp inst="t17610625-16-person132" type="surname" value="Riley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-16-person132" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-16-person132" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was <rs id="t17610625-16-viclabel90" type="occupation">a porter in Leadenhall-market</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-16-victim131 t17610625-16-viclabel90"></join>, carrying goods for a book-keeper there, I met with the prisoner standing under the gateway, about eight at night.</p>
               <p>Q. What gate-way?</p>
               <p>Riley. <placeName id="t17610625-16-crimeloc91">The Saracen's head on Snow-hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17610625-16-crimeloc91" type="placeName" value="The Saracen's head on Snow-hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610625-16-crimeloc91" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-16-off88 t17610625-16-crimeloc91"></join>; I went there to deliver a parcel; I asked for the book-keeper, he said he was the book-keeper; he desired me to walk as far as the door, and leave the parcel there, and go for a candle; and as soon as I went for the candle, he went away with the goods in the basket.</p>
               <p>Q. What was in the basket?</p>
               <p>Riley. There were cloaths in one of the baskets, which I was to carry to Forster-Lane; the other had 18 dead pigeons, tied up by the legs.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you bring them from?</p>
               <p>Riley. I brought them from Gracechurch-street, near to Leaden-hall.</p>
               <p>Q. What countryman are you?</p>
               <p>Riley. I am an Irishman.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure he is the man that took the basket away?</p>
               <p>Riley. I am. I have seen him often towards Holbourn-bridge: I said to the people, I could swear to him amongst a thousand people. I delivered<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176106250014"></xptr> to him all the goods, and gave him a cloak-bag.</p>
               <p>Q Who did that belong to?</p>
               <p>Riley. That belonged to one Mr. Smith, in Hatton-Garden; there were four guineas in that.</p>
               <p>Q. Were all these in your possession?</p>
               <p>Riley. They were.</p>
               <p>Q Where did you meet with the prisoner afterwards?</p>
               <p>Riley. I saw him since very often.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. How the man came to know me to be the person?</p>
               <p>Riley. I was positive before Mr. Fielding that he was the man that took the things.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you swear to him there?</p>
               <p>Riley. I swore to him twice there.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you lose your things?</p>

               <p>Riley. It was about eight o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. What day?</p>
               <p>Riley. I don't know; only it was on a Friday.</p>
               <p>Q. What week?</p>
               <p>Riley. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. What month?</p>
               <p>Riley. I do not know what month.</p>
               <p>Q. What! cannot you tell the month? Was it April, May, or June?</p>
               <p>Riley. It was in April and May, Sir.</p>
               <p>Court. It cannot be in both.</p>
               <p>Riley. It was about May, Sir.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>All my witnesses were examined before Mr. Fielding on the Monday afterwards, and Mr. Fielding took bail for me upon it.</p>
               <p>Q. to Riley. Was you with the prisoner before justice Fielding?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-16-person133">
                  Riley
               <interp inst="t17610625-16-person133" type="given" value="Riley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-16-person133" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I lost the goods on a Friday; I went to Mr. Fielding, and got an order against the prisoner on the Saturday; but I could not get at him, the door was locked, and he would not come out; and I went for another order to break the door open.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you recollect near the time you lost the goods?</p>
               <p>Riley. It was about May; I cannot say what month.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He accused me with taking these things from him on the 24th of April. He and his master came to me the 25th; I could not understand the odd account he gave; I desired his master to interperet to me what he meant: the master said, If you have no lodgers, it cannot be any body here. They went on farther. After that I went to him, and ask'd him if he had found the man he wanted? he said yes, you are the man, the book-keeper wants you; I went to the publick-house next door, to see where the book-keeper was, and on the Monday following I went and surrendered myself to a constable; they searched my house on the 27th of April, and I was committed to New-prison, and brought up again on the Wednesday, and re-examined before Mr. Fielding; I had four witnesses to prove where I was that night, that he says he lost the things, from four or five in the afternoon, till between ten and eleven o'clock at night.</p>
               <p>Riley. As soon as I went into the prisoner's house, I told the book keeper he was the man that took the goods from me. I went out again, and then I saw the prisoner running along, he went in at a chandler's shop, and out again.</p>
               <p>Counsel for prisoner. The 24th of April was on a Friday, and we have four witnesses to prove he was at Islington; and the Wednesday after, these four people were by when the examination was taken.</p>
               <p>[ The examination produced, dated April 29.]</p>

               <p>Q. to Riley. Did you sign any paper before Mr. Fielding?</p>
               <p>Riley. I put a mark upon a paper before the justice, but upon my shoul, I cannot tell whether this is the paper or no.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know your own mark when you see it?</p>
               <p>Riley. No, I do not; I did nothing upon the paper but only mark a cross upon it.</p>
               <p>Court. Look upon that paper. [He looks at it ]</p>
               <p>Riley. I did not do that at all; I did not mark that paper.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-16-person134">
                  Richard 
                  Dawson 
               <interp inst="t17610625-16-person134" type="surname" value="Dawson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-16-person134" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-16-person134" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know Mr. Fielding's handwriting.</p>
               <p>Q. Look upon this examination.</p>
               <p>Dawson. I believe his name here to be his own hand-writing; it is in the way that he writes.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever seen him write?</p>
               <p>Dawson. I have; upon my oath I believe it to be appertaining to his writing.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by appertaining?</p>
               <p>Dawson. I believe it may be his hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Q. to Riley. Did Mr. Fielding sign that paper you did?</p>
               <p>Riley. He put it down in a book, and desired me to put a cross upon it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it read over to you?</p>
               <p>Riley. It was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear it read?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176106250015"></xptr>Riley. I did.</p>
               <p>Jos. Gibbs. I remember the prisoner being at Mr. Fielding's, on Wednesday the 29th of April. The prosecutor charged him with committing the robbery the Friday before. Then I recollected the prisoner being in company that Friday at the Catharine wheel, in Islington-road. I am the landlord of the house.</p>
               <p>Q. Give an account of the time he came, and how long he staid?</p>
               <p>Gibbs. On the 24th of April last, being Friday, he came to our house, about four in the afternoon, and never went out of the house 'till after ten. The company he was in, was the last company I had in my house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-16-person135">
                  William 
                  Gladman 
               <interp inst="t17610625-16-person135" type="surname" value="Gladman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-16-person135" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-16-person135" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I attended at Mr. Fielding's, at his examination; there was a robbery sworn against him, to have been committed on Friday the 24th of April. I was in company with him that same Friday, at Mr. Gibbs's, from half an hour after five, 'till about half an hour after ten at night: then I parted with him in Bridewell-walk; he went his way, and I mine.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-16-person136">
                  James 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17610625-16-person136" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-16-person136" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-16-person136" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at Mr. Gibbs's, on Friday the 24th of April; I came away with him, and I did not part with him, 'till after one in the morning; for that fire which happened in Swallow-street, that night, we imagined might be about his house, and I went along with him.</p>
               <p>Ratcliff Mosset. The prisoner was at Mr. Gibbs's on that Fri day; I was in company with him from between five and six that evening, and staid with him 'till half an hour after ten. The prosecutor swore he was robbed on that Friday, before the justice, between seven and eight o'clock.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-16-person137">
                  Thomas 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17610625-16-person137" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-16-person137" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-16-person137" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was before justice Fielding at the examination of the prisoner; Riley swore he was robbed on Friday the 24th of April, between eight and nine o'clock.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610625-16-verdict92" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610625-16-verdict92" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
