<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610916-40">
               <interp inst="t17610916-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-40" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610916"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-40" type="date" value="17610916"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610916-40-off210-c317" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-40-defend386 t17610916-40-off210 t17610916-40-verdict214"></join>
         
               <p>260. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610916-40-defend386" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Martin 
                  <interp inst="t17610916-40-defend386" type="surname" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-40-defend386" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-40-defend386" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for <rs id="t17610916-40-off210" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-40-off210" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-40-off210" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               that he on the <rs id="t17610916-40-cd211" type="crimeDate">11th of August</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-40-off210 t17610916-40-cd211"></join>, about three in the night, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17610916-40-victim388" type="victimName">
                           Samuel 
                           Gomley 
                        <interp inst="t17610916-40-victim388" type="surname" value="Gomley"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610916-40-victim388" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610916-40-victim388" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-40-off210 t17610916-40-victim388"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17610916-40-viclabel212" type="occupation">esq</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-40-victim388 t17610916-40-viclabel212"></join>; did break and enter, one half-pint silver mug, value 20 s. and one silver table-spoon, value 5 s. the goods of the said Samuel, and three men's hats, the property of James Simpkins, in the dwelling-house of the said Samuel, did steal
            </rs>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-40-person389">
                  James 
                  Simpkins 
               <interp inst="t17610916-40-person389" type="surname" value="Simpkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-40-person389" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-40-person389" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a servant in the house; our house was broke open, and a silver pint mug, and a silver table-spoon, and three hats, taken out, between the 11th and 12th of Aug.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is Mr. Gomley's house?</p>
               <p>J. Simpkins. At <placeName id="t17610916-40-crimeloc213">Isleworth</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-40-crimeloc213" type="placeName" value="Isleworth"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-40-crimeloc213" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-40-off210 t17610916-40-crimeloc213"></join>: I saw the things safe there over-night. The plate was what we use in the kitchen, and was left there when we went to bed.</p>
               <p>Susanah Jackson. I am servant there, we found the house broke open on the 12th of August in the morning; the kitchen-window was open, and he sash thrown up. The iron bars, on the outside, were wrenched off; the things mentioned in the indictment were taken away from out of the kitchen.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-40-person390">
                  Mary 
                  Chansteene 
               <interp inst="t17610916-40-person390" type="surname" value="Chansteene"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-40-person390" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-40-person390" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Richmond. On the 28th of August last the prisoner at the bar came<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160046"></xptr> and offered some silver to sell to me, about two ounces and a half, all knocked with a hammer, and cut and broke into small pieces. My husband not being at home, I did not buy it, but ordered him to come again on the morrow, but he came no more.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-40-person391">
                  Jonathan 
                  Williamson 
               <interp inst="t17610916-40-person391" type="surname" value="Williamson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-40-person391" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-40-person391" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Richmond: on the 17th of August the beadle and bellman were crying a hatcher at Isleworth; the prisoner was stopped by three gardeners: the bell-man said, there had been a house broke open, and they wanted to know who owned the hatchet. They said they had a suspicion of the prisoner. The week following, the prisoner came to Richmond, I imagined he would go to this house to sell the silver, I saw him knock at the door, and go in and come out again, with a paper with something in it, in his hand. I went, and told the woman, the last witness, my suspicions; she said he had offered some small pieces of silver to sell.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-40-person392">
                  Benjamin 
                  Kitchen 
               <interp inst="t17610916-40-person392" type="surname" value="Kitchen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-40-person392" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-40-person392" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was fellow-servant with me at the George at Hounslow. My master heard there was a warrant out against the prisoner, and he had absconded (he had been gone a half a year from us.) In the morning, about nine o'clock, on the 6th of September, my master and I saw the prisoner: we knowing he was suspected of this robbery, took him: we were going to the justice with him; we came to a dirty lane, the prisoner was for going down that, so I went there with him, and my master went on the outside, in the field; when we were got into the lane, the prisoner said he wanted to stop to ease himself. He went down into a ditch as far as he could for water; he put his hand down among the lappels of his coat: I thought I heard something chink; when he was ready to go again, he went on to Isleworth. When we came to the constable's house, I asked the prisoner, if he did not drop something in that place, saying, I heard something chink; he said, he had not; then it was thought proper I should go back, and search the place. A baker lent me a horse, and I went, and among the weeds I found some small pieces of silver amongst the mud. When I thought I had got it all, I went with it to the constable's house, [ produced in court] After that, there were more such small pieces found in the prisoner's pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. to S. Jackson. Look at these pieces of silver?</p>
               <p>S. Jackson. I have seen them before we came here, I cannot swear they are part of our mug or spoon.</p>
               <p>Q. to Simpkins. Did you ever find your hat since?</p>
               <p>Simpkins. No.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610916-40-verdict214" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-40-verdict214" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
