<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660514-26">
               <interp inst="t17660514-26" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660514-26" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660514-26" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660514"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660514-26" type="date" value="17660514"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660514-26-off156-c233" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-26-defend291 t17660514-26-off156 t17660514-26-verdict160"></join>
         
               <p>310. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660514-26-defend291" type="defendantName">
                     George 
                     Groves 
                  <interp inst="t17660514-26-defend291" type="surname" value="Groves"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-defend291" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-defend291" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for <rs id="t17660514-26-off156" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-off156" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-off156" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               that 
                     <persName id="t17660514-26-person292">
                        David 
                        Jones 
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person292" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660514-26-person292" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660514-26-person292" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , not taken, with a certain gun, loaded with gun-powder and leaden shot, did shoot 
                     
                        <persName id="t17660514-26-victim294" type="victimName">
                           Ezra 
                           Wells 
                        <interp inst="t17660514-26-victim294" type="surname" value="Wells"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660514-26-victim294" type="given" value="Ezra"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660514-26-victim294" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-26-off156 t17660514-26-victim294"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   in the belly, of which wound he did instantly die; and he the said Groves, was present, helping, aiding, assisting, comforting, and abetting the said Jones, the said murder to commit
            </rs> he stood charged on the coroner's inquest for manslaughter, <rs id="t17660514-26-cd157" type="crimeDate">April 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-26-off156 t17660514-26-cd157"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-26-person295">
                  Matthew 
                  Wells 
               <interp inst="t17660514-26-person295" type="surname" value="Wells"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person295" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person295" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17660514-26-person296">
                  Ezra 
                  Wells 
               <interp inst="t17660514-26-person296" type="surname" value="Wells"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person296" type="given" value="Ezra"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person296" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the deceased, was my brother; I am a carpenter, and live at the top of the Hay market; my brother was a <rs id="t17660514-26-viclabel158" type="occupation">carpenter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-26-victim294 t17660514-26-viclabel158"></join> also. On Sunday morning the 13th of April, I called upon him at Marybone to take a walk together in the fields, about six o'clock; we were not determined which way to walk; we were walking beyond <placeName id="t17660514-26-crimeloc159">Primrose-hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17660514-26-crimeloc159" type="placeName" value="Primrose-hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660514-26-crimeloc159" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-26-off156 t17660514-26-crimeloc159"></join>; seeing a field on the left-hand side the way, and some people in it picking turnip-tops, there were some lying on heaps and some growing, we thought it no ill to get a few; the people were all strangers to me; there were eight or ten of them: after we had picked a few, as we might be there eight or ten minutes, or a quarter of an hour, we came out of the field, and were got three fields from it; those men saw us coming along with the tops under our arms, mine were in a little white pillowbear, my brother had his in a little tool-bag all open; this Groves was the very man that met me with the gun, and said, if I offered to move or resist, he would blow my brains out; this was in the pathway, he followed me the space of an hundred yards close to me; I do not know that I saw him, till he ran and hallooed to the other man that is not taken; the other came through the hedge, and ran and met us; he had a gun also; the prisoner desired me to surrender what I had; I told him I had not got his property, and did not know that they belonged to his master, that they had no business with us as we knew of; I refused to surrender them; he presented the gun to me: Jones said, d - n him, knock him down if he will not surrender; upon which, the prisoner up with the butt end of his gun and struck at my brother's head, and struck him on the left shoulder; immediately my brother turned and struck the man on the side of the head with this stick, (producing a large stick) Jones was not then spoke to; he said, d - n you, if you will not fire, I will, and immediately fired his gun at my brother, and shot his bowels out before him as big as my two fists almost; he was about two lengths of his gun from my brother when he fired; then Jones cried out to the prisoner, d - n him, shoot him, shoot him; my brother turned about to me and said, dear brother I am a dead man; I said, I believe my boy thou be'st; I pulled my handkerchief from my neck, clasped my hands round him and put<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176605140027"></xptr> his bowels in, and tied him round, while Groves stood over me with his gun, and said, if I offered to resist he would blow my brains out; I begged of him to let me tie my brother round; then I bussed his cheek, and said, now blow my brains out and let me die with him: seeing some gentlemen, all strangers, coming, I begged of them to help me home with my deceased brother; in the mean time Jones drawed off at a distance and loaded his gun, and came up again; then Groves was gone quite off to farmer Pye's: I shewed the gentlemen Jones, and said, that is the man that killed my brother; Jones made answer again, and said, d - n him, if he speaks two words, I'll blow his brains out; we laid my brother on a small gate, and coming along with him, farmer Pye and three or four more met us, Groves was one of them; the farmer said the turnip-tops were his property, but he denied it afterwards at Sir 
               <persName id="t17660514-26-person297">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17660514-26-person297" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person297" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person297" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's; I shook my head at Groves, and said, you have made a fine job of it; he said, d - n you, you rogue, if you make any words I'll shoot you. He was apprehended the same evening; I have left it to Sir John's people to take Jones; I do not know where he is.</p>
               <p>On his cross examination he said, he and his brother carried the pillow-case and bag, in which the tops were in, out in their pockets. He could not tell whether there was a foot-way through the turnip-field; that his brother was carrying his bag with tops in it on his stick; and to the best of his knowledge his brother hit Jones on the cheek.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-26-person298">
                  Thomas 
                  Grimes 
               <interp inst="t17660514-26-person298" type="surname" value="Grimes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person298" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person298" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who went out the same Sunday morning confirmed his evidence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-26-person299">
                  Richard 
                  Clayton 
               <interp inst="t17660514-26-person299" type="surname" value="Clayton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person299" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person299" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17660514-26-person300">
                  James 
                  Goodwin 
               <interp inst="t17660514-26-person300" type="surname" value="Goodwin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person300" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person300" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , two shopmates, who were taking a walk that way at the time, both deposed they saw the prisoner and another running with each a gun, towards the deceased and his brother; they soon heard a gun go off; they made towards them, and found the deceased dying on the ground, and the brother standing by him; and they heard the deceased say, he never struck the prisoner till the prisoner struck him with the butt end of his gun.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-26-person301">
                  James 
                  Gardner 
               <interp inst="t17660514-26-person301" type="surname" value="Gardner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person301" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person301" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was with the prisoner and the man that is not taken, before this thing happened, in a field joining to the turnip-field; Jones said, the next he met, if he did not deliver what he had he would shoot him, (they had taken some sacks of turnip-tops that morning from other people, that belonged to their masters) the prisoner said, no, do not let us do no such thing as that; while they were talking, two men came into the other side the turnip-field, Groves went round to meet them, to take them while they were there, I saw six or seven men come over the other side the field; they ran towards them, Groves ran first, and called the other to his assistance; we lost sight of them for some time; after which I heard a gun go off; the man with me said, he was afraid something was the matter; we went towards where the noise of the gun was; going over the hedge, I saw a man lying on the ground and another assisting him; I went and asked how it happened; the brother said, it was the man that was standing there shot him; that man was at some distance: after some time, Groves came from towards Mr. Pye's; the brother said, see what you have done; Groves said, you rogue, you ought to be shot, and if you don't hold your tongue I will shoot you, your brother knocked me down with the stick; the brother asked the man on the ground whether he did or not, the deceased said he did not knock him down; then I went to see for something to help bring him home, and know not what passed afterwards.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-26-person302">
                  John 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17660514-26-person302" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person302" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person302" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The turnip-tops belonged to me; I sold half the field to Mrs. Gardner; I have been robbed to the value of 10 or 12 l. my two servants had been drove out of the fields by numbers of people several times; there are two fields; after I sold part of them to Mrs. Gardner, I sent Groves, and she sent her man, named Jones, to watch them; the people had broke down the fences, so that in places a cart might be drove in, and ten or twenty men at a time gathering tops, d - ning my men, saying how they would serve me if I was there: some of the turnips were growing in the ground, and some were pulled up for use: Groves came to me that Sunday morning, and told me there were four bushel sacks full of turnip-tops, which they had got from people that had been taking them, and hand-baskets and bags, and that they were detecting more people; and that these Wells's came by and said, why don't you come and take ours away; if you do, we will souse your heads. He told me a man had been shot, he did not tell me he was killed; when I got there they were gone; after that Sir 
               <persName id="t17660514-26-person303">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17660514-26-person303" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person303" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person303" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sent for Groves to come to him the next day, and he and I went.</p>
               <p>On his cross examination he said, there had been ten, twenty, and thirty people at a time gathering tops; that he ordered Groves not to go away; that he never saw Groves quarrelsome or in liquor; that he was very honest, and he could trust him with thousands<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176605140028"></xptr> of pounds; that he had a black eye, and a stroke cross his cheek and nose.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>When I first went into the field there were a great many men in it, when they saw me, they ran out at the upper end; I went after some, they ran away, and I came back again to my fellow servant; he had taken a sack, a bag, and a basket away from people: we stood a little while in the field; there came five men in the field towards me, we were running after them; the brother said, d - n your blood, don't run after them, run after us, if you come here we will knock your heads; then I said, I will come after you; when they saw me coming, they ran; this man was got to the gate; said I, are not you a pretty fellow, to go steal turnips and abuse us afterwards; his brother was the nearest, I said you shall go along with me before my master; he said he would not; then I called the other man to my assistance; I laid hold of the bag, he turned round and gave me a knock on the side of the head, I fell on one arm and my left knee. I was in a maze, I really did not know whether my head was on or off; he ran at the Welshman, as the Welshman told me, as he had the gun in his hand, and the gun went off, but how he could not tell; when I recovered myself, I was all in a tremble at seeing him lying.</p>
               <p>He called 
               <persName id="t17660514-26-person304">
                  Thomas 
                  Lott 
               <interp inst="t17660514-26-person304" type="surname" value="Lott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person304" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of Acton, with whom he lived servant three years; 
               <persName id="t17660514-26-person305">
                  Francis 
                  Pope 
               <interp inst="t17660514-26-person305" type="surname" value="Pope"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person305" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person305" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , with whom he had lived a year; 
               <persName id="t17660514-26-person306">
                  Ezekiel 
                  Timberly 
               <interp inst="t17660514-26-person306" type="surname" value="Timberly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person306" type="given" value="Ezekiel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17660514-26-person307">
                  Edward 
                  Briggs 
               <interp inst="t17660514-26-person307" type="surname" value="Briggs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person307" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person307" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who had known him seven years; 
               <persName id="t17660514-26-person308">
                  Edward 
                  Lekins 
               <interp inst="t17660514-26-person308" type="surname" value="Lekins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person308" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17660514-26-person309">
                  Robert 
                  Fryer 
               <interp inst="t17660514-26-person309" type="surname" value="Fryer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person309" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-person309" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , several years, who all gave him the character of an honest faithful servant, of a peaceable behaviour, and not given to quarrel.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660514-26-verdict160" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660514-26-verdict160" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
