<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17621208-1">
               <interp inst="t17621208-1" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17621208-1" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17621208-1" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17621208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17621208-1" type="date" value="17621208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17621208-1-off1-c34" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-1-defend34 t17621208-1-off1 t17621208-1-verdict4"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17621208-1-off5-c34" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-1-defend34 t17621208-1-off5 t17621208-1-verdict4"></join>
         
               <p>1. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17621208-1-defend34" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Ann 
                     Ward 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17621208-1-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-1-defend34 t17621208-1-alias-1"></join>Dampier</rs>, otherwise <rs id="t17621208-1-alias-2" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-1-defend34 t17621208-1-alias-2"></join>Lindsey</rs>, otherwise <rs id="t17621208-1-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-1-defend34 t17621208-1-alias-3"></join>Levistone</rs>, otherwise <rs id="t17621208-1-alias-4" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-1-defend34 t17621208-1-alias-4"></join>Nelson</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-defend34" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-defend34" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-defend34" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17621208-1-off1" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-off1" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-off1" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one pair of linnen sheets, value 20 s. one pillow-case, value 1 s. one table-cloth, value 4 s. five silver tea-spoons, value 5 s. one pair of silver tea-tongs, value 1 s. one large table-spoon, value 10 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17621208-1-victim37" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Skryms 
                        <interp inst="t17621208-1-victim37" type="surname" value="Skryms"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17621208-1-victim37" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17621208-1-victim37" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-1-off1 t17621208-1-victim37"></join>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-1-off5 t17621208-1-victim37"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , the same being in a certain lodging room let by contract
            </rs>, &amp;c. <rs id="t17621208-1-cd2" type="crimeDate">July 26</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-1-off1 t17621208-1-cd2"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-1-off5 t17621208-1-cd2"></join>.~</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-1-person38">
                  William 
                  Skryms 
               <interp inst="t17621208-1-person38" type="surname" value="Skryms"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person38" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person38" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17621208-1-crimeloc3">St. James's market</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17621208-1-crimeloc3" type="placeName" value="St. James's market"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17621208-1-crimeloc3" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-1-off1 t17621208-1-crimeloc3"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-1-off5 t17621208-1-crimeloc3"></join>, The prisoner took a lodging of me, she bargained with my wife in my presence; it was ready-furnished.</p>
               <p>Q. What was she to pay a week?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-1-person39">
                  Wm 
                  Skryms 
               <interp inst="t17621208-1-person39" type="surname" value="Skryms"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person39" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person39" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I believe she was to pay 18 s. a week it was a first floor. The things mentioned in the Indictment were part of the furnitures; she pretended, she took them for a gentleman that she resided with, one capt. Dampier. She staid in the lodging six or seven weeks; I cannot exactly tell the time when she came. I remember she gave me a note on the 22d of July, and the Monday following she went out with a pretence to get money, and never returned again. My wife can give the best account of the things.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-1-person40">
                  Susanna 
                  Skryms 
               <interp inst="t17621208-1-person40" type="surname" value="Skryms"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person40" type="given" value="Susanna"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person40" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the prosecutor. The prisoner took the lodging of us on the 10th of June. The things mentioned in the indictment were in the room for her use. When she went away, she took the keys of the apartment with<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176212080003"></xptr> her. I remember, she went away on a Monday, and said she would return in the evening, but did not. She not returning, we waited some time; then we broke open the door, and missed all the things mentioned in the indictment, (mentioning them by name.)</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever find any of your things again?</p>
               <p>S. Skryms. We found three tea spoons in Mr. Brooks's hands in Dean-street, marked, two of them S. W. and one S. B. Part of the five I lost.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-1-person41">
                  William 
                  Skryms 
               <interp inst="t17621208-1-person41" type="surname" value="Skryms"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person41" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person41" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When the prisoner was taken, she told me 
               <persName id="t17621208-1-person42">
                  Eleanor 
                  Mahoney 
               <interp inst="t17621208-1-person42" type="surname" value="Mahoney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person42" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person42" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had pawned things for her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-1-person43">
                  Eleanor 
                  Mahoney 
               <interp inst="t17621208-1-person43" type="surname" value="Mahoney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person43" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person43" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner delivered a gown, a petticoat, three sheets, a damask table cloath, and an apron, in her own apartment, to carry to pawn for her. I did, and brought her the money. I pawned them to Mr. Watson in Coventry-court by the Hay-market.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I sent all these things by that woman, but Mrs. Skryms knew of it, but her husband did not. I was to get them home unknown to him.</p>
               <p>Q. to S. Skryms. If you imprudently have let the prisoner send these things to pawn, you must tell the truth. What say you to it?</p>
               <p>S. Skryms. It is all false. I never pawned a thing, or gave a thing to be pawned to any one, in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-1-person44">
                  James 
                  Brooks 
               <interp inst="t17621208-1-person44" type="surname" value="Brooks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person44" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person44" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a pawnbroker, and live in James-street by the Hay-market. The prisoner at the bar brought 3 tea spoons to me on the 16th of June, and pledged them in the name of Levistone. Two were marked S. W. the other 
               <persName id="t17621208-1-person45">
                  S.
                   B. 
               <interp inst="t17621208-1-person45" type="surname" value="B."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person45" type="given" value="S."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person45" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (produced and deposed to.)</p>
               <p>Jer. Watson. I am a pawnbroker, and live in Coventry-court. (He produced 3 sheets, a table cloth, a pair of tea tongs and 2 tea spoons.) These were brought by Mahoney to my house. (Deposed to by the prosecutor's wife.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-1-person46">
                  Timothy 
                  Dwyre 
               <interp inst="t17621208-1-person46" type="surname" value="Dwyre"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person46" type="given" value="Timothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person46" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . A woman came from the prisoner and wanted one Timothy, a chairman. I said, there was none but me. I went to her lodging. The prisoner desired me to go of a message for her. She sent me with 2 large spoons one time, and a watch another time, which I did. I pawned them at Mr. Watson's, and delivered the money to her.</p>
               <p>Watson. They were pawned at my house, (producing them.)</p>
               <p>S. Skryms. Only one of these spoons was let to her with the lodgings. They are our property.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>She let me send them, and I was to get them again as soon as I could. But I know nothing of the watch: I never know they had a watch.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17621208-1-verdict4" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-verdict4" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>She was a second time indicted by the names for <rs id="t17621208-1-off5" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-off5" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-off5" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one linnen gown, val. 1 one stuff gown, called a sack, val. 1 s one large silver spoon, val. 1 s. one Pinchbook val. 30 s. one steel chain, val. 3 s. one seal and one silver stock buckle, val. 1 s. the property of 
                     <persName id="t17621208-1-person47">
                        William 
                        Skryms 
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person47" type="surname" value="Skryms"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17621208-1-person47" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17621208-1-person47" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , in the dwelling house of the said William
            </rs>, July 26.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-1-person48">
                  William 
                  Skryms 
               <interp inst="t17621208-1-person48" type="surname" value="Skryms"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person48" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person48" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know no more than the things that were found at the pawnbroker's, my property, that is, the 2 large silver spoons and the metale watch.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-1-person49">
                  Timothy 
                  Dwyre 
               <interp inst="t17621208-1-person49" type="surname" value="Dwyre"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person49" type="given" value="Timothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person49" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner employed me to go on errands for her. I can only say, as before she sent me to pawn the 2 spoons and watch.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did she deliver them to you?</p>
               <p>Dwyre. In the prosecutor's passage within the house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she tell you where to pawn them?</p>
               <p>Dwyre. No. I was to go and get as much as I could upon them. I carried them to Mr. Watson's, and pawned them, and gave her the money. When the other things were missing, I went and informed the prosecutor of them.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you get on the spoons and watch?</p>
               <p>Dwyre. I had 9 s. a piece on the spoons, and a guinea on the watch.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-1-person50">
                  William 
                  Dwyre 
               <interp inst="t17621208-1-person50" type="surname" value="Dwyre"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person50" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person50" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last summer the prisoner sent for my partner, the last witness; he was not in the way. (We are chairmen.) Then she sent again for me; I went; I went without my coat; she desired me to send for my coat, or it would not do; I did; then she desired me to go to Mr. Watson's to carry a gown to redeem a large table spoon that lay for 9 s. I went and brought the spoon, as she desired, and left the gown.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-1-person51">
                  Eleanor 
                  Mahoney 
               <interp inst="t17621208-1-person51" type="surname" value="Mahoney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person51" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person51" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I washed for the prisoner; she sent me with a stuff gown to pawn for her. I thought it had been her own. I pawned it at Mr. Watson's. (The gown produced by Mr. Watson, and deposed to by the prosecutor's wife.)</p>
               <p>Q. Where did she deliver the gown to you?</p>
               <p>E. Mahoney. In her own apartment.</p>
               <p>Watson. This is the watch that was pawned by Dwyre; (holding it in his hand) this was brought the 22d of July.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. That watch is my property.</p>
               <p>Watson. This sack and petticoat were brought by Mahoney. (Produced in court, and deposed to by the prosecutor's wife.)</p>
               <p>W. Dwyre. I pawned a gown to Mr. Brooks for the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-1-person52">
                  James 
                  Brooks 
               <interp inst="t17621208-1-person52" type="surname" value="Brooks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person52" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person52" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This it. (producing in court.)<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176212080004"></xptr> 
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-1-person53">
                  William 
                  Dwyre 
               <interp inst="t17621208-1-person53" type="surname" value="Dwyre"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person53" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-person53" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             brought it on the 24th of July. It was pawned in the name of Levistone; he brought a note with it he said from her.</p>
               <p>S. Skryms. That is my property.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were these two gowns taken from, and the watch?</p>
               <p>S. Skryms. One of them was left in a drawer in the dining room, which room she had the use of. I was going to remove it. She said I need not, she had no occasion for that drawer at present. The watch was in a parlour behind the shop, and one of the large spoons was taken out of a cupboard in the same parlour, and the other gown was missing from off the horse, as it hung to dry in the kitchen. All these things were taken away unknown to me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>How could I look for this watch when I did not know that she had one: As to the gown being sent to fetch home the spoon, it was on this account, she had been drinking, and said her husband would miss the spoon, so bid me take that gown and carry it to fetch home the spoon; I remember she had veal that day for dinner: It is very odd I should be called by all these names: I took the lodgings by the name I always went by.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Skryms. She took the house by the name of Wade, and after she was there a person came and asked for Mrs. Lindsey; she came down stairs, and said that was her name. She went sometimes by the name of Levistone, and sometimes by the name of Nelson.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17621208-1-verdict6" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-verdict6" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-verdict6" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder40s"></interp>
               Guilty 39 s.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17621208-1-punish7" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17621208-1-punish7" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-1-defend34 t17621208-1-punish7"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
