<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680224-65">
               <interp inst="t17680224-65" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680224-65" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680224-65" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680224"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680224-65" type="date" value="17680224"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680224-65-off417-c543" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-65-defend688 t17680224-65-off417 t17680224-65-verdict421"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680224-65-off417-c544" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-65-defend691 t17680224-65-off417 t17680224-65-verdict421"></join>
         
               <p>236, 237. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17680224-65-defend688" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Anne 
                     Robinson 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17680224-65-alias-4" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-65-defend688 t17680224-65-alias-4"></join>Anne Cole</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-defend688" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-defend688" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-defend688" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-defend688" type="age" value="20"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17680224-65-defend691" type="defendantName">
                     Sophia 
                     Revell 
                  <interp inst="t17680224-65-defend691" type="surname" value="Revell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-defend691" type="given" value="Sophia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-defend691" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17680224-65-deflabel416" type="occupation">spinsters</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-65-defend688 t17680224-65-deflabel416"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-65-defend691 t17680224-65-deflabel416"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17680224-65-off417" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-off417" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-off417" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 23 guineas, 5 half guineas, and 9 s. in money numbered, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17680224-65-victim693" type="victimName">
                           Dorothy 
                           Foulkes 
                        <interp inst="t17680224-65-victim693" type="surname" value="Foulkes"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680224-65-victim693" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680224-65-victim693" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-65-off417 t17680224-65-victim693"></join>
                     </persName>
                     
                  , in the dwelling-house of 
                     <persName id="t17680224-65-person694">
                        Samuel 
                        Cherry 
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-person694" type="surname" value="Cherry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680224-65-person694" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680224-65-person694" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17680224-65-cd418" type="crimeDate">January 14</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-65-off417 t17680224-65-cd418"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-65-person695">
                  Dorothy 
                  Foulkes 
               <interp inst="t17680224-65-person695" type="surname" value="Foulkes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-person695" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-person695" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had been come out of the country but betwixt three weeks and a month; I lodged in <placeName id="t17680224-65-crimeloc419">Philip-lane, Aldermanbury</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17680224-65-crimeloc419" type="placeName" value="Philip-lane, Aldermanbury"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17680224-65-crimeloc419" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-65-off417 t17680224-65-crimeloc419"></join>, at my uncle's, named 
               <persName id="t17680224-65-person696">
                  Samuel 
                  Cherry 
               <interp inst="t17680224-65-person696" type="surname" value="Cherry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-person696" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-person696" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; the two prisoners went for mistress and maid; I lodged in a two pair of stairs room, they lodged in the same house; there was (I think) 27 l. 17 s. 6 d. locked up in my box; the last money I had out of it was a half-crown piece, five weeks ago last Monday, it was safe then; I missed it the Thursday after, between five and six in the evening; the prisoners went out of town that day, about one in the day; they said they were going into the country, and said they would be back the Monday following; they did not come back till the Tuesday, when I missed my money, I found it locked as usual.</p>
               <p>Q. How many guineas were there of the money?</p>
               <p>D. Foulkes. I cannot justly say, I know it was in gold and silver; I had been working for it fourteen years a servant in the country, thinking to get me some good clothes here, to go into a good service in town; I know there were guineas, half guineas, a crown-piece, and a half crown. I suspected Revell the maid. Two or three days before she had no money, she borrowed 6 d. of me, and was obliged to borrow some halfpence of another lodger in the next room, to buy some coals; but when they returned, they flash'd away; they had got new things, they got gowns out of pawn, and they had got a watch; we got a constable, and took them up; they were searched, they had no money; they were carried to goal that night, the maid denied it; the mistress said she believed the maid had the money out of my box; the next day they were taken before my Lord Mayor, there the maid confessed she had taken the money out of my box; that she owed several debts, and had paid them all, and had bought her mistress that gown she had on; she said, when she brought the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176802240043"></xptr> money down she gave it to her mistress, and her mistress parted it between them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did her mistress hear all this?</p>
               <p>D. Foulkes. She was by, and heard it all.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the mistress say to it?</p>
               <p>D. Foulkes. She denied it.</p>
               <p>Q. How did she say she came to do it?</p>
               <p>D. Foulkes. I had just bought a new hat, and she said she desired me to let her mistress look at it; I went up and unlocked my box, and took the hat and carried it down to her mistress to see it, to have such a one; (this was all true;) the maid went down with me; she said she went up again, and took the money.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you lock the box after you took it out?</p>
               <p>D. Foulkes. I cannot say whether I did or not; I brought it up again after the mistress had looked at it, and put it in the box, and locked it up.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the mistress own she gave the maid orders to fetch it.</p>
               <p>D. Foulkes. No, she denied that, or that she had any hand in it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you get any of your money again?</p>
               <p>D. Foulkes. No, I never got a farthing again.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Is there any lock to your room-door?</p>
               <p>D. Foulkes. No, there is none that will lock.</p>
               <p>Q. How was your money, in any thing, or loose?</p>
               <p>D. Foulkes. It was sewed up in a piece of new leather, and put into a linen purse, and sewed in, and that was put down in a nook of the box.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-65-person697">
                  Martha 
                  Cherry 
               <interp inst="t17680224-65-person697" type="surname" value="Cherry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-person697" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-person697" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mrs. Robinson came with the other prisoner, and called her her maid, and took a lodging of me, she went for a captain's window; they lodged with me between two and three months; they nor only robbed my niece, but they robbed their lodging; the maid had borrowed money on the Monday, and on the Tuesday in the afternoon, after they came home, we saw them in good new clothes they never appeared in before while in my house; the maid had a linen gown, and the mistress a linen one and a bed-gown; I had just before been dunning the mistress for money she owed me at this time; they were in my debt 3 l. or thereabouts; I had seen my kinswoman's money, there were guineas and half guineas, and some silver, but a little silver; it was in a bit of new leather, sewed up in a bit of an old sheet; she had cut a little hole in it, just to take out what she wanted.</p>
               <p>Q. What day did they go away?</p>
               <p>M. Cherry. They went out on the Thursday in the forenoon, they went out of the shop as if they had been frightened; Mrs. Robinson hold down her head as she went out, and seemed confused; she had stepped back, and told my servant she should be back on the Monday following; after that my niece went up for money to buy her a gown, and came down and said she missed all her money; then we went to Justice Fielding, and put them in an advertisement; on the Tuesday about ten o'clock they came home, they were going up into their room; I asked them where the money was that they had robbed my niece of; Revell the maid was very impudent, they both denied it at first; they said they had been in the country to see the maid's father, and they imagined we had been robbed while they were gone, and then we wanted to lay it upon them; we asked them where they had the money from, which they bought the watch and things with, and to fetch their things from Mr. Flude's, a pawnbroker; Revell said it was nothing to me where she had the money; we sent for a constable; the maid was very saucy, and said she would not go to the Compter without a coach; she bid the constable shew his authority; he shewed it, and took her to the Compter; after she was gone, I talked very closely to the mistress; then she told me she believed the maid had the money out of my niece's box; I asked her, if she had not gone halves in it; she said she had had some of the money, but did not say how much; after that my husband came home, and took her to the other Compter; the next day they were both taken before my Lord Mayor, but before they went there, I went to the mistress, and told her, I hoped she would say the truth; she said she would; she believed her maid had the money out of the box, and that she should say before my Lord Mayor; then I went to the servant, and said, your mistress says you had the money out of the box; she said, how can my mistress be so base to confess that I took the money, when at the same time she got some keys for me to fit the lock, and that my mistress contrived another way to get the money; that we contrived that mistress was to want to see Dolly's hat, that we might make one like it; I was to ask Dolly for it; that I should go up stairs with her to talk to her, that she should forget to lock her box; that I came down with Dolly to my mistress, and my mistress kept her in discourse, while I went up and took the money; and then as soon as I came down, mistress and I went out, and parted the money; I asked her if she counted it; she said no; then they were called in<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176802240044"></xptr> before my Lord Mayor; there I heard her repeat the same, and the mistress acknowledge the gown she had on was bought with some of the money, and also a gown and petticoat the maid had on was bought with part of the money, and that she herself had part of the money: I understood the maid had been up stairs with my niece several times, and had looked in her box, when my niece took things out.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this conversation?</p>
               <p>M. Cherry. This was in the Mansion-house.</p>
               <p>Q. Who besides you heard it?</p>
               <p>M. Cher ry. The constable and another witness, and my niece were present.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not she deny knowing any thing of the robbery?</p>
               <p>M. Cherry. No, she did not; but said she never saw the box, and never was near it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not advise the mistress to make her escape?</p>
               <p>M. Cherry. No, I never did; she offered several times to give ten guineas to make it up, but I would not agree to it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not go after her friends about it?</p>
               <p>M. Cherry. No, I did not, but they came to me several times.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not your debt of 3 l. paid?</p>
               <p>M. Cherry. No, it never was.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-65-person698">
                  Samuel 
                  Cherry 
               <interp inst="t17680224-65-person698" type="surname" value="Cherry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-person698" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-person698" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am husband to the last witness; my niece going to fetch some money down on the Thursday, in a trifle of time after the prisoners were gone, the maid left word with my servant they were gone into the country till the Monday following; upon the money being missing we suspected them; by enquiring, found they had changed gold in several places; when they came in on the Tuesday evening about ten o'clock, we took them up and sent for a constable, and gave him charge of them, they having robbed their ready furnished lodgings of a table-spoon, a sheet, and other things, and upon suspicion of having robbed my niece of her money; the constable and I went with the servant to Wood-street Compter; there the servant told me if I would forgive her, she would tell me the whole truth, and went on her knees, but I would not admit of it.</p>
               <p>Q. What answer did you make her?</p>
               <p>Cherry. My answer was, it was not in my power, if the law will forgive you I am content, I shall go no farther than that; when we came back, the mistress would fain have staid in the house all night; we being told that she said she believed the maid had the money out of my niece's box, and that she had share of it; we took her to the Compter; when we came to the Mansion-house the next day, I heard the conversation between the maid and my wife; my wife has told it as it really was.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the maid and mistress together at that time?</p>
               <p>Cherry. They were in the same room, but I believe they could not hear one another; the maid said the mistress had furnished her with keys, and teazed her, and would not let her rest till she had done it; they had change of raiment which I never saw before.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Cherry. I am a ticket-porter, I live at No 7 in Philip-lane, near London-wall.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any promises made to either of them?</p>
               <p>Cherry. No, there were none at all as I know of.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs. Cherry. What say you to that question?</p>
               <p>M. Cherry. I told them both if they would let us know the truth, I would forgive them as far as in my power.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-65-person699">
                  Dorothy 
                  Rainsford 
               <interp inst="t17680224-65-person699" type="surname" value="Rainsford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-person699" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-person699" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodge in the next room to that which the young woman lodged that lost her money; I was in my room, and heard the maid ask for the hat, and saw the young woman give it her out of her box, and saw them both go down with it, and while the young woman was trying the hat upon the mistress's head, I heard somebody come up stairs and go into the room where the young woman's box was, but I did not go to see who it was; I have several times before thought I heard the young woman, I mean the prisoner in her room; I have opened my door, and seen Revell there looking over things upon the table by her box. One night the maid was in my room and pulled out a great bunch of keys (as my key was missing) and unlocked my box with one; she said there were keys there that would unlock any lock in England; she came up to me, I think it was the day before they went into the country, and asked me to lend her a groat; after that she came up and paid me the groat, I saw more money in her hand; she then said she was going into the country; she said her mistress had 50 l. a year salary, and was going to receive it; they were very deplorable before that, she had hardly any thing to cover her; and so was the mistress in as bad a condition, she had hardly a hat or shoes to her<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176802240045"></xptr> feet, a day or two before they went into the country, and when they came again they flashed away with all new things; the maid had a ring on her finger, new silver buckles, and I saw a ribbon fixed to the bed's-head to hang the watch to; I opened the door for them when they came, and I received the bundle of clothes from them, and I went and got change for a 5 s. 3 d. piece for them to pay the coachman; Mrs. Cherry came down stairs and said they must not go up, for they had robbed her; the maid was very saucy; the mistress said Sophia had received 30 l. of her father to go down into the country, as she said the maid had told her; I heard them both confess they had the money; the maid and the young woman that has been robbed lay together, and she said she pulled the bed from the wall that the maid's pocket might fall down, that they might get the key; she said her mistress would never let her be at peace till she got the money; that she said, you know I want money, and money I will have, you must get the money, I want things; the maid said, she did not care to do it, and the mistress answered, there is no more sin in it than to eat her own breakfast.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this in the hearing of the mistress?</p>
               <p>D. Ransford. It was.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>D. Ransford. My husband is a butcher.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-65-person700">
                  Samuel 
                  Sherwin 
               <interp inst="t17680224-65-person700" type="surname" value="Sherwin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-person700" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-person700" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the constable, I was ordered to search the prisoners; they had a woman's hat box, muslin caps, ruffles, a fan, necklace, things very good; the mistress pulled out about half a guinea, and the maid about two or 3 s. then I ordered the women to take them to some part of the house and search them; they did so, and said they could find nothing; I heard the maid confess before my Lord Mayor, that the mistress put her upon taking the money out of the box, and she did take it; and I heard the mistress say she believed the maid had the money out of the box, and owned she had part of it.</p>
               <p>Robinson's defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing at all of it; what they say of me is all very false; I went out of town to see a friend to Cogshall in Essex; they have every one taken a false oath.</p>
               <p>To her character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-65-person701">
                  Robert 
                  Lackland 
               <interp inst="t17680224-65-person701" type="surname" value="Lackland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-person701" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-person701" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a baker, and live in Rosemary-lane; I have known Robinson almost ten years, I believe she is not much above 20 years of age; she has a very good character; I never heard a word in the world against her, and I never conceived any ill of her.</p>
               <p>Q. What way of life has she been in?</p>
               <p>Lackland. She used to live with her father and mother till within about two years, then she went to service as far as I know.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she ever married?</p>
               <p>Lackland. I have heard she was married, she went for a married woman.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her father?</p>
               <p>Lackland. He is a shoemaker in Peter's-court in Rosemary-lane.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen her often within these two years?</p>
               <p>Lackland. I have, about eight or ten times.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen her within the last three months?</p>
               <p>Lackland. I can't recollect I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know where she lodged?</p>
               <p>Lackland. No, I never knew that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-65-person702">
                  George 
                  Cooper 
               <interp inst="t17680224-65-person702" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-person702" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-person702" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her ten years; she is a very good honest sort of a person.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen her lately?</p>
               <p>Cooper. I have not seen her, I believe, for six months.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she married or single?</p>
               <p>Cooper. I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Can't you tell what she passed for?</p>
               <p>Cooper. She passed for a single woman I believe.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Cooper. I live in Peter's-court.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-65-person703">
                  John 
                  Coats 
               <interp inst="t17680224-65-person703" type="surname" value="Coats"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-person703" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-person703" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Blackmoor's-head in Cartwright-street, Rosemary-lane; I have known her about two years and a half, she bears a very good character; her parents live in pretty good credit.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see her last?</p>
               <p>Coats. I have not seen her these nine months; she passed for a sober young woman when she lived with her father and mother; to the best of my knowledge she went to service once.</p>
               <p>Revell's defence.</p>
               <p>I am innocent, I know nothing of the affair; I never spoke twenty words to the person in my life; they are a vile set of people.</p>
               <p>To her character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-65-person704">
                  Henry 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17680224-65-person704" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-person704" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-person704" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a weaver, and live in Hand-alley, Bishopsgate-street; I have known Revell upwards of seven years, she has been at my house an hundred times; she always bore a very good character; I never heard any harm of her before this.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176802240046"></xptr>Q. How long has she lived with the other woman at the bar?</p>
               <p>Clark. I know nothing of her living with her.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see her last?</p>
               <p>Clark. I saw her at her mother's house within this month last, but did not understand then where she lived; I thought she lived with her mother.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-65-person705">
                  Aaron 
                  Mumford 
               <interp inst="t17680224-65-person705" type="surname" value="Mumford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-person705" type="given" value="Aaron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-person705" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Spring-garden; I have known her some time, she has been a servant in my house about 12 or 14 months ago; I never missed any thing by her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-65-person706">
                  Arthur 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17680224-65-person706" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-person706" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-person706" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Coverley's-fields; I have known her two years, I never heard but that she was an honest girl.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-65-person707">
                  Jane 
                  Hamilton 
               <interp inst="t17680224-65-person707" type="surname" value="Hamilton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-person707" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-person707" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her about five years, I never knew but that she was an honest person; I saw her in the last Christmas holidays, I asked her where she lived, I think she said in Philip-lane, with a gentlewoman.</p>
               <p>Both Guilty. <rs id="t17680224-65-punish420" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-punish420" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-65-defend688 t17680224-65-punish420"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-65-defend691 t17680224-65-punish420"></join>
               Death
            </rs>. <rs id="t17680224-65-verdict421" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-verdict421" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-65-verdict421" type="verdictSubcategory" value="withRecommendation"></interp>
               Recommended to mercy on account of their being young
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>There was another indictment against them for robbing their ready-furnished lodging.</p>
            </div1>
