<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610506-14">
               <interp inst="t17610506-14" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610506-14" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610506-14" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610506"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610506-14" type="date" value="17610506"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610506-14-off74-c134" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-14-defend158 t17610506-14-off74 t17610506-14-verdict77"></join>
         
               <p>170. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610506-14-defend158" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Brett 
                  <interp inst="t17610506-14-defend158" type="surname" value="Brett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-defend158" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-defend158" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17610506-14-deflabel73" type="occupation">gentleman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-14-defend158 t17610506-14-deflabel73"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17610506-14-off74" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-off74" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-off74" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               feloniously forging a bill of exchange, with the name Richard Horton thereunto subscribed, purporting to bare date the <rs id="t17610506-14-cd75" type="crimeDate">13th of March, 1761</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-14-off74 t17610506-14-cd75"></join>. Drawn upon 
                     <persName id="t17610506-14-victim159" type="victimName">
                        Mess.
                         Frazier, Wharton and Mullison<interp inst="t17610506-14-victim159" type="surname" value="Frazier"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610506-14-victim159" type="given" value="Mess."></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610506-14-victim159" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , <rs id="t17610506-14-viclabel76" type="occupation">merchants</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-14-victim159 t17610506-14-viclabel76"></join>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-14-victim161 t17610506-14-viclabel76"></join>, for the payment of 50 l. payable to 
                     <persName id="t17610506-14-person160">
                        William 
                        Huggins 
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person160" type="surname" value="Huggins"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610506-14-person160" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610506-14-person160" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , and for publishing it, with intent to defraud the said Frazier, Wharton, and Mullison.
            </rs> It was laid also for publishing the same, with intent to defraud 
               <persName id="t17610506-14-victim161" type="victimName">
                  Walter 
                  Pringle 
               <interp inst="t17610506-14-victim161" type="surname" value="Pringle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-victim161" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-victim161" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             .*</p> 
               <p>Mr. Mullison. I am partner with Frazier and Wharton. On the 16th of March, at noon, this letter was brought from the post-office, with others (producing a letter) it is purporting to be a letter of credit in favour of 
               <persName id="t17610506-14-person162">
                  Richard 
                  Horton 
               <interp inst="t17610506-14-person162" type="surname" value="Horton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person162" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person162" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , from 
               <persName id="t17610506-14-person163">
                  Walter 
                  Pringle 
               <interp inst="t17610506-14-person163" type="surname" value="Pringle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person163" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person163" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of St. Christopher's, for a thousand guineas. Mr. Pringle is a correspondent of ours, and draws bills upon us, and frequently sends letters of credit for others. We perused the letter, and at first I thought it a real one, only we were surprized Mr. Pringle did not write the letter with his own hand, as he always was wont to do. We were likewise surprized that the person in whose favour this was, should not have delivered it himself, to let us know he was the real person; besides, there was no pocket then arrived from the West-indies, nor no ship, by which this letter might come, that we had heard of; and, upon finding it was delivered in on the Saturday before, we suspected it to be a forgery, and determined not to answer any bills in consequence of it. On Saturday, the 21st of March, while we<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176105060018"></xptr> were at 'Change, a bill was left for 50 l. drawn in the name of 
               <persName id="t17610506-14-person164">
                  Richard 
                  Horton 
               <interp inst="t17610506-14-person164" type="surname" value="Horton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person164" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person164" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , payable to 
               <persName id="t17610506-14-person165">
                  William 
                  Huggins 
               <interp inst="t17610506-14-person165" type="surname" value="Huggins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person165" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person165" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in 20 days sight. This is the bill. (Producing one.) I did not know then who left it. We desired the clerk when the person came for the bill again to stop him. On Monday the 23d of March, Mr. Huggins called for it. I saw him. I asked him how he came by the bill; he said, a gentleman had come to his shop the preceding week, and had looked out 12 pair of silk stockings, and told him he had no money; and produced this bill as payment, and desired to have the rest in cash. He told me, he observed to him the bill was not accepted. I asked Mr. Huggins who he was; he told me, and where he lived. I told him the bill would not be accepted till we saw Mr. Horton. He left the bill with me. About an hour or two after I went and found him in his shop, and found him to be the man he told me he was. There were a number of people in his shop with him He desired I would step into the parlour. I did. When I came out again, I asked him if he had seen the gentleman that brought the bill; he said the gentleman had been in the shop since I came in, and was just gone out. I said I wished he had told me of it. I staid half an hour or more, and told Mr. Huggins my suspicions of a forgery, and desired if that gentleman came again, he might be stopped on that account. Then I went away. The next day at noon we received a note from Mr. Huggins, to inform us a messenger had been there to inquire for the bill; in consequence of that note, we went up to Mr. Huggins's house about half an hour after five o'clock. This was on Tuesday. We applied for an officer to apprehend the person that brought the bill, in case he should come. We waited there till near 12 at night, no one appeared. Mr. Huggins told us perhaps the gentleman would come the next day at noon, being his usual time. We had an officer there the next day; then the prisoner at the bar came, and we apprehended him. I attended his examination before justice Fielding. He there acknowledged that both the letter of credit and the bill were forged.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say who forged them?</p>
               <p>Mullison. He said, 
               <persName id="t17610506-14-person166">
                  Richard 
                  Horton 
               <interp inst="t17610506-14-person166" type="surname" value="Horton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person166" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person166" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , purser of the Arundel, had forged the letter of credit from an original letter of 
               <persName id="t17610506-14-person167">
                  Walter 
                  Pringle 
               <interp inst="t17610506-14-person167" type="surname" value="Pringle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person167" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person167" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, and forged the name 
               <persName id="t17610506-14-person168">
                  Walter 
                  Pringle 
               <interp inst="t17610506-14-person168" type="surname" value="Pringle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person168" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person168" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to it. He said, the bill of exchange was wrote by his own servant, named 
               <persName id="t17610506-14-person169">
                  James 
                  Sunmore 
               <interp inst="t17610506-14-person169" type="surname" value="Sunmore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person169" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person169" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , from a copy laid before him of his that is, the prisoner's, hand-writing, and that the servant had done this, knowing it was intended to defraud. Accordingly warrants were issued out against Horton, and the servant; Sunmore surrendered himself that night, I saw him. Horton was apprehended the next day, and we were sent for to be present at his examination before justice Fielding. They were committed in custody that evening, and both examined the next morning. I was present, the prisoner was there, Horton produced several gentlemen to his character, and denied the fact; and said, he had never seen Mr. Brett since he had been in England. The servant said, he had wrote the bill of exchange, name and all; and that his master, the prisoner, had frequently laid bills and writings before him, in order to copy, and he copied them according to his order. Afterwards the prisoner acknowledged they were both innocent; but he did say, that his servant Sunmore was not intirely so. That Sunmore knew it to be done with intention to defraud</p>
               <p>Q. In whose favour?</p>
               <p>Mullison. In favour of the prisoner; at first he said, Sunmore was to have some of the money; but at last, he did not insist upon it. Mr. Fielding asked him, whether they were guilty or innocent, he said, they were both innocent. He said one Bowman, a clerk, had wrote the body of the letter (whom he had hired) from a copy given him for that purpose; but said nothing as to the name signed in the letter.</p>
               <p>The Letter read to this purport.</p>
               <p>Directed to Mess. Frazier, Wharton and Mullison, merchants in London.</p>
               <p>St. Christopher's, Jan, 7, 1761.</p>
               <p>"Gentlemen,</p>
               <p>"This goes by a St. Eustatia, by one Mr.</p>
               <p>"
               <persName id="t17610506-14-person170">
                  Richard 
                  Horton 
               <interp inst="t17610506-14-person170" type="surname" value="Horton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person170" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person170" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a purser of a man of war,</p>
               <p>"whose bills upon you, to the amount of one</p>
               <p>"thousand guineas sterling, I must request the</p>
               <p>"favour of you to honour, and you may depend</p>
               <p>"that I shall soon send you proper remittances</p>
               <p>"on that account. I have no more</p>
               <p>"to add at present, but to desire you will be</p>
               <p>"kind enough to comply with this, as it will</p>
               <p>"not only be of service to him, but to myself</p>
               <p>"likewise; and in so doing, you will very much</p>
               <p>"oblige your humble servant,"</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-14-person171">
                  WALTER 
                  PRINGLE 
               <interp inst="t17610506-14-person171" type="surname" value="PRINGLE"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person171" type="given" value="WALTER"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person171" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176105060019"></xptr>The bill read to this purport.</p>
               <p>March 18, 1761.</p>
               <p>'Gentlemen,</p>
               <p>'Twenty days after fight, please to pay to</p>
               <p>'Mr. 
               <persName id="t17610506-14-person172">
                  William 
                  Huggins 
               <interp inst="t17610506-14-person172" type="surname" value="Huggins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person172" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person172" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             or order, 50 l. and</p>
               <p>'charge the same to account of 
               <persName id="t17610506-14-person173">
                  Walter 
                  Pringle 
               <interp inst="t17610506-14-person173" type="surname" value="Pringle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person173" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person173" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ,</p>
               <p>'Esq; of St. Christopher's; merchant, as per</p>
               <p>'advise you will find by letter of credit in my</p>
               <p>'favour, by 
               <persName id="t17610506-14-person174">
                  Walter 
                  Pringle 
               <interp inst="t17610506-14-person174" type="surname" value="Pringle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person174" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person174" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-14-person175">
                  RICHARD 
                  HORTON 
               <interp inst="t17610506-14-person175" type="surname" value="HORTON"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person175" type="given" value="RICHARD"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person175" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Directed to Mess. Frazier, Wharton and Mullison, merchants in London.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I beg to alter my plea, and plead guilty. I had not brought it to trial, but should have pleaded guilty to the indictment when arraigned, if I had not been ill advised by my attorney; and as I now plead guilty. I hope the honourable court will give me leave to withdraw my plead. I will not give the court any trouble to prove the name 
               <persName id="t17610506-14-person176">
                  Richard 
                  Horton 
               <interp inst="t17610506-14-person176" type="surname" value="Horton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person176" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-person176" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             not to be his hand-writing. I have nothing to say, but to plead guilty.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610506-14-verdict77" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-verdict77" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17610506-14-punish78" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610506-14-punish78" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-14-defend158 t17610506-14-punish78"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
