<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670218-32">
               <interp inst="t17670218-32" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670218-32" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670218-32" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670218"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670218-32" type="date" value="17670218"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670218-32-off187-c252" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670218-32-defend313 t17670218-32-off187 t17670218-32-verdict191"></join>
         
               <p>166. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17670218-32-defend313" type="defendantName">
                  Henry 
                  Grimsdale 
               <interp inst="t17670218-32-defend313" type="surname" value="Grimsdale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-32-defend313" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-32-defend313" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted, <rs id="t17670218-32-off187" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670218-32-off187" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-32-off187" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               together with 
                     <persName id="t17670218-32-person314">
                        John 
                        Hall 
                     <interp inst="t17670218-32-person314" type="surname" value="Hall"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670218-32-person314" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670218-32-person314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   not taken, for stealing ten yards of linen cloth, value 15 s. two pair of worsted stockings, value 4 s. one linen handkerchief, value 6 d.
            </rs> the property of 
               <persName id="t17670218-32-victim315" type="victimName">
                  John 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17670218-32-victim315" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-32-victim315" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-32-victim315" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670218-32-off187 t17670218-32-victim315"></join>
                  </persName>
             , <rs id="t17670218-32-cd188" type="crimeDate">Feb. 14</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670218-32-off187 t17670218-32-cd188"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>John Brown. I am <rs id="t17670218-32-viclabel189" type="occupation">porter to the House of Lords</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670218-32-victim315 t17670218-32-viclabel189"></join>; I happened to be a little in liquor last Thursday was a week; coming home, about half an hour after eight o'clock in the evening, two men passed by me; one of them called me by my name, and asked me how I did; they desired to drink with me; I gave them a pot of beer at <placeName id="t17670218-32-crimeloc190">the Thistle and Crown in Charles-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17670218-32-crimeloc190" type="placeName" value="the Thistle and Crown in Charles-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17670218-32-crimeloc190" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670218-32-off187 t17670218-32-crimeloc190"></join>; then they said they would see me home; I happened to fall asleep in the house, and when I awaked, I missed ten yards and a half of linen, which I had bought to make me three shirts, and two pair of stockings, that cost me 4 s. 6 d. they were tied up in a handkerchief.</p>
               <p>Q. When you first went into that house, what did you do with them things?</p>
               <p>Brown. I had them in my custody.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner in your company when you went to sleep?</p>
               <p>Brown. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner one of the two persons that drank with you?</p>
               <p>Brown. I do not know that; I know there was a soldier in the house that drawed the beer, and the other two were soldiers; (the prisoner is a soldier.)</p>
               <p>Q. Did you miss your things as soon as you awaked?</p>
               <p>Brown. No, I did not remember about the things, but went home.</p>
               <p>Q. You say you was in liquor, are you sure you carried these things into that house?</p>
               <p>Brown. I am well assured of that; the next day I went to that house again, and asked whether I had left any thing there; they said, no.</p>
               <p>Isabella Gilley. I keep the Dr. Ward's Head, a public-house; last Thursday se'nnight, in the evening, the prisoner and two other soldiers came in, and called for three pennyworth of rum and water; my niece served them, and they paid for it; after that they were quarrelling; I desired them to go out; one of their heads appeared bloody; they said he had fell down and cut his head; they called for a bason of water to clean him; I saw a piece of linen cloth on the floor; I heard one say to the other, why did you take the stockings; the other swore he had got them in his pocket; then they said one to another, let us get away as quick as we can; we suspected all was not right; my-husband went for a constable, but could not get one; they left my house, and went in at the Mitre and Dove; I went there it about half an hour after; there they offered the stockings to sale; they were taken up upon that, and sent to the watch-house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670218-32-person316">
                  William 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17670218-32-person316" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-32-person316" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-32-person316" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was sent for, being a constable, to the Mitre and Dove; when I went in, the three soldiers were offering there a pair of stockings to sale; the prisoner was one of the men; the prisoner pretended to buy the stockings, and to take them into a private room; I pulled out my staff to shew them I was an officer, and shut the door; I insisted upon searching them; I found a pair of stockings and a piece of cloth under the lining of his coat; he told me they belonged to him; then I searched another of them, named White, and found a piece of cloth in his pocket; he said it was his own; they said, serjeant Armstrong had given them the cloth to make each of them a shirt against the next day, being a field-day, I asked how they came by the stockings; they d - 'd me very much; the prisoner threatened me several times, and said he would have his things again; then I called for the watch, and sent them to the watch-house; (the things produced in court) it appeared the cloth had been divided in three parts.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176702180023"></xptr>Prosecutor. The linen and stockings are my property.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I actually took notice of the linen when I bought it; it is three quarters of a yard wide, the piece was ten yards and three quarters.</p>
               <p>Q. Do these agree to that length?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. The other man is gone off with the other piece.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is the Dr. Ward's Head from the house where the cloth was found?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. It is about 200 yards distance.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was drinking in the house when the gentleman came in, he laid his bundle down on the table; John Hall took it up, and desired I would pawn it; the gentleman fell asleep; Hall went out at the door with it, and knocked at the window for us to come out; I went to him; he said, come along; I went with him to Dr. Ward's Head; there we cut the cloth into three parts.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670218-32-person317">
                  Joseph 
                  Hunt 
               <interp inst="t17670218-32-person317" type="surname" value="Hunt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-32-person317" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-32-person317" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a serjeant in the first regiment, under Colonel 
               <persName id="t17670218-32-person318">
                  Ligonier
               <interp inst="t17670218-32-person318" type="given" value="Ligonier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-32-person318" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I have known the prisoner above ten years, seven years I have had him under my care; I was abroad with him in the service in the year 1758; he was at St. Cas; he sometimes will get a little elevated in liquor, but never neglected his duty, and behaved well and honest.</p>
               <p>Q. Will your colonel take him again if the court should be inclinable to shew him favour?</p>
               <p>Hunt. I know he will.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17670218-32-verdict191" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670218-32-verdict191" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-32-verdict191" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder1s"></interp>
               Guilty 10 d.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17670218-32-punish192" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670218-32-punish192" type="punishmentCategory" value="corporal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-32-punish192" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="whipping"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670218-32-defend313 t17670218-32-punish192"></join>
               W
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
