<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660514-8">
               <interp inst="t17660514-8" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660514-8" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660514-8" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660514"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660514-8" type="date" value="17660514"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660514-8-off44-c77" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-8-defend94 t17660514-8-off44 t17660514-8-verdict47"></join>
         
               <p>292. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660514-8-defend94" type="defendantName">
                     Anne 
                     Benton 
                  <interp inst="t17660514-8-defend94" type="surname" value="Benton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-8-defend94" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-8-defend94" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17660514-8-deflabel43" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-8-defend94 t17660514-8-deflabel43"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17660514-8-off44" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660514-8-off44" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-8-off44" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing 45 guineas, the property of 
                     <persName id="t17660514-8-person95">
                        Samuel 
                        Lucar 
                     <interp inst="t17660514-8-person95" type="surname" value="Lucar"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660514-8-person95" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660514-8-person95" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , privately from the person of the said Samuel
            </rs>, <rs id="t17660514-8-cd45" type="crimeDate">March 26</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-8-off44 t17660514-8-cd45"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
               
                  <persName id="t17660514-8-victim97" type="victimName">
                     Samuel 
                     Lucar 
                  <interp inst="t17660514-8-victim97" type="surname" value="Lucar"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-8-victim97" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-8-victim97" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-8-off44 t17660514-8-victim97"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            . I served his Majesty as a soldier 24 years, and am now an <rs id="t17660514-8-viclabel46" type="occupation">out-pensioner at Chelsea</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-8-victim97 t17660514-8-viclabel46"></join>, and live near Chelsea, the prisoner has a lodging-room of her own in Westminster. On the 26th of March I met her in John's-street about 7 or 8 at night at a public-house, the sign of the Bell.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know her before?</p>
               <p>Lucar. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever been in her company before?</p>
               <p>Lucar. I will tell the truth, I had, and laid with her before. From thence we went to her lodgings between 10 and 11.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in liquor?</p>
               <p>Lucar. No, I was not fuddled, I had been drinking; I had 45 guineas in gold and some silver, but how much I cannot swear. When I came from my own lodging I had 58 l. but I had spent the rest.</p>
               <p>Q. Where had you been?</p>
               <p>Lucar. I lay in a very civil house in John's-street on the Monday night, and on the Tuesday I was drinking about, but was very sober all the day, and lay in John's-street that night also. I lay with a woman, not in the same house, but was not wronged of a farthing.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you a bed-fellow on the Monday night?</p>
               <p>Lucar. I had. On the Wednesday morning I had my money in my pocket, I counted it over. I was at the Bell part of the day, and in the afternoon I light of the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you by all this money?</p>
               <p>Lucar. It was left me by an aunt, she left me an hundred pounds.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you receive it?</p>
               <p>Lucar. I received it since Christmas. I had the money mentioned in the indictment. When I went to bed with the prisoner, I counted it in her lodging.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she see you?</p>
               <p>Lucar. I do not know whether she was gone out for liquor; I put it loose in my right-hand breeches pocket; I laid my breeches under my head, and we went to bed together before 11. When I awaked I heard the watchman crying 3<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176605140007"></xptr> o'clock; I found the prisoner was gone; I felt for my breeches, and found them not under my head, but on the bolster where she had laid, the whole tote was gone; she had locked me in, so I lay there till the morning; then the woman of the house came up, and I told her how I had been served; she said the prisoner came down and called to some woman that lay below, and said, come, get up, the coach is waiting. I did not know what to do, so I went home; after that I and 
               <persName id="t17660514-8-person98">
                  Richard 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17660514-8-person98" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-8-person98" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-8-person98" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             went to look for her, and we found her in the Strand, and took her before Sir 
               <persName id="t17660514-8-person99">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17660514-8-person99" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-8-person99" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-8-person99" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; she was searched, and 8 guineas, a quarter guinea, and some silver was found in her pocket; at first she said it came from Cambridgeshire from her friends, but afterwards she confessed it was part of my money; the Justice asked her where the remainder was; she said it was in her lodgings, but would not say where, for that she said should keep her while in goal.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-8-person100">
                  Richard 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17660514-8-person100" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-8-person100" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-8-person100" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed to that of the prisoner's confession.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>The prosecutor gave me 35 guineas to support me and my children; he bid me furnish a room with it; he has been with me night and day; I never wronged him of a farthing in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Did you give the prisoner any money?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I gave her 2 s. for lying with her, and I gave her no more.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660514-8-verdict47" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660514-8-verdict47" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-8-verdict47" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               Guilty of stealing, but not privately from his person
            </rs>. <rs id="t17660514-8-punish48" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660514-8-punish48" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-8-defend94 t17660514-8-punish48"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
