<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610225-14">
               <interp inst="t17610225-14" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610225-14" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610225-14" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610225"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610225-14" type="date" value="17610225"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610225-14-off68-c114" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-14-defend138 t17610225-14-off68 t17610225-14-verdict70"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610225-14-off68-c115" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-14-defend140 t17610225-14-off68 t17610225-14-verdict70"></join>
         
               <p>91. (M) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610225-14-defend138" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Long 
                  <interp inst="t17610225-14-defend138" type="surname" value="Long"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-14-defend138" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-14-defend138" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17610225-14-defend140" type="defendantName">
                     Anne 
                     Kelly 
                  <interp inst="t17610225-14-defend140" type="surname" value="Kelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-14-defend140" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-14-defend140" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17610225-14-deflabel67" type="occupation">spinsters</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-14-defend138 t17610225-14-deflabel67"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-14-defend140 t17610225-14-deflabel67"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17610225-14-off68" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610225-14-off68" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-14-off68" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing one leather purse, value one penny; one mourning-ring, value 7 s. and seven guineas, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17610225-14-victim142" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Crookshanks 
                        <interp inst="t17610225-14-victim142" type="surname" value="Crookshanks"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610225-14-victim142" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610225-14-victim142" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-14-off68 t17610225-14-victim142"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17610225-14-cd69" type="crimeDate">Jan. 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-14-off68 t17610225-14-cd69"></join>. *</p>
               <p>James Crookshanks. On the 21st of January, I met with these two women in Rosemary-lane; I knew 
               <persName id="t17610225-14-person143">
                  Mary 
                  Long 
               <interp inst="t17610225-14-person143" type="surname" value="Long"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-14-person143" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-14-person143" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , she had come up with me from Portsmouth in the machine. She asked me how I did; I told her I was very well. She said, Will you give us any thing to drink? I said I would give them a shilling's-worth of rum and water at any place where she chose it. She brought me to her own room first. I had no less money than a guinea to change, and 
               <persName id="t17610225-14-person144">
                  Nan 
                  Kelly 
               <interp inst="t17610225-14-person144" type="surname" value="Kelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-14-person144" type="given" value="Nan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-14-person144" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said, she would go and change it. I told 
               <persName id="t17610225-14-person145">
                  Nan
               <interp inst="t17610225-14-person145" type="given" value="Nan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-14-person145" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I would not trust her with a guinea; but if she would go and tell the landlord to bring a shilling in rum and water, and change for a guinea, I would treat them with the liquor. The landlord came with the liquor, and the change. Upon my taking a guinea out of my purse, these two girls saw that I had more in it. Then Nan Kelly grew very fond of me, and fell a hugging and kissing of me, and the other seemed to be very busy on the other side of me. I sat in the middle, and from my left-hand pocket of my breeches I soon lost my purse and seven guineas, and a mourning-ring in it.</p>
               <p>Q. Which sat on the left hand of you?</p>
               <p>Crookshanks. 
               <persName id="t17610225-14-person146">
                  Mary 
                  Long 
               <interp inst="t17610225-14-person146" type="surname" value="Long"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-14-person146" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-14-person146" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             did; and while the other was hugging and squeezing me, Long must take my money out. We all three went out of the room. I was not gone above three times the length of the court, before I missed my purse and money. I thought to myself, if I went back I should catch those girls with my money and ring. They, at coming out of the room, turned one way, and I the other. I went in search after them, and soon found they were both got into the room again. I went up stairs into the room, and catched 
               <persName id="t17610225-14-person147">
                  Nan 
                  Kelly 
               <interp inst="t17610225-14-person147" type="surname" value="Kelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-14-person147" type="given" value="Nan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-14-person147" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , she was busy in removing the things out of the room. I asked her where her neighbour Long was. She said she did not know. I said I had lost so much money, and till I can find her I will take care of you. At last, by looking about I found 
               <persName id="t17610225-14-person148">
                  Mary 
                  Long 
               <interp inst="t17610225-14-person148" type="surname" value="Long"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-14-person148" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-14-person148" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in a back closet, covered over with a cloth. Then I took her out into the room, and told her what she had done, and asked her to confess. She would not, but said she had taken nothing from me. I carried her to Mr. Chapman's, a public-house house, and got a watchman to take charge of them. The watch kept them all night, and the next morning carried them before the justice, there they said they found the money upon the bed. The constable found the money upon them in the watch house.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you been in bed?</p>
               <p>Crookshanks. We were all three sitting on the bed</p>
               <p>Q. Had you been tumbling on the bed?</p>
               <p>Crookshanks. No, we were all three sitting flock still.</p>
               <p>Q. Might they not find the money on the bed?</p>
               <p>Crookshanks. No, I am very certain they did not, but 
               <persName id="t17610225-14-person149">
                  Mary 
                  Long 
               <interp inst="t17610225-14-person149" type="surname" value="Long"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-14-person149" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-14-person149" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             took it out of my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. What quantity of liquor had you drank?</p>
               <p>Crookshanks. Only a shilling in rum and water.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you fuddled?</p>
               <p>Crookshanks. No, I was not concerned in liquor at all?</p>
               <p>Q. Had you been drinking before in the day?</p>
               <p>Crookshanks. I had been drinking beer with my victuals, but not all intoxicated.</p>
               <p>Q. How can you swear they did not find your purse on the bed?</p>
               <p>Crookshanks. I am very clear they did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain you put your purse in your pocket after you took it out?</p>
               <p>Crookshanks. I am certain of that; I put my purse with my gold in it in my left hand pocket, and my change in my right-side pocket, and I had not tumbled about. I had my silver in my pocket when I came out of the house, and I know Long took the purse; the other could not, for I had fight of her hands all the time, but I did not see 
               <persName id="t17610225-14-person150">
                  Mary 
                  Long 
               <interp inst="t17610225-14-person150" type="surname" value="Long"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-14-person150" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-14-person150" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's hands.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you pick them up, or they you?</p>
               <p>Crookshanks. They picked me up.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-14-person151">
                  Stephen 
                  Pett 
               <interp inst="t17610225-14-person151" type="surname" value="Pett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-14-person151" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-14-person151" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am beadle of the parish. On the 21st of January, about ten at night, I was told a person had been robbed by two women.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250016"></xptr> I asked him where he had been robbed, he told me in East-Smithfield; and gave the same account there as he has now, to the best of my memory. I asked if they had been searched. I was told they had by my partner, the other beadle, but no money found. Then I told them I would make Adams and Eves of them, if they would not give an account of the money.</p>
               <p>Q. Which of them did you intend to make Adam of?</p>
               <p>Pett. My meaning was, I would strip them naked, but that I would find the money if they had it about them. As Long was going to untie her petticoat, I asked her for her pocket, in which I found a guinea, a half-guinea, some silver and halfpence. Then I clapped my hand under her right arm. She said, I'll be d - ed if you search there; but I forced open her arm, and there I found this purse, with six guineas and a mourning-ring in it. [Produced in court.]</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. This is my purse, I made it myself; and this mourning-ring is my property, which I lost that night.</p>
               <p>Pett. He told me before he saw the ring the date in it was 1743, and so it was. We took the prisoners to the justice, and the money found over and above the quantity which the prosecutor swore he had lost, I, by the justice's direction, returned to Long again.</p>
               <p>Long's Defence.</p>
               <p>My brother belongs to the Magnanime. I had been down to him, and I came up from Ports-mouth with that gentleman. My brother had given me eight guineas to put myself in a way of living. The gentleman and I parted at the corner of Thames-street, Tower-hill. Afterwards, as I was going along Rosemary- lane to buy a few things, as I get my living by buying and selling old cloaths, I met him again; he asked me how I did. I said I did not know him. He said I came up with you from Ports-mouth. He asked me to drink. I said I was going about other business. He said, Do drink. Then I said go in here. Then he said, Have you no place of your own? Then I took him home, and happened to meet this other young woman. I did not know what he wanted with me; and then he sent for some rum and water.</p>
               <p>Kelly's Defence.</p>
               <p>This man and 
               <persName id="t17610225-14-person152">
                  Mary 
                  Long 
               <interp inst="t17610225-14-person152" type="surname" value="Long"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-14-person152" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-14-person152" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             were coming along; she owed me 5 d. for some oysters; she asked me to go along with her, and she would pay me. We went together, he was very sweet upon me, and said he would have to do with me. There was nobody in the room but Mr. Chapman that brought up the liquor and change, so I have no witnesses. <rs id="t17610225-14-verdict70" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610225-14-verdict70" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-14-verdict70" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               Both guilty of stealing, but not privately from his person
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610225-14-punish71" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610225-14-punish71" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-14-defend138 t17610225-14-punish71"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-14-defend140 t17610225-14-punish71"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
