<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660903-47">
               <interp inst="t17660903-47" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-47" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-47" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660903"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-47" type="date" value="17660903"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660903-47-off252-c334" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-47-defend428 t17660903-47-off252 t17660903-47-verdict256"></join>
         
               <p>445. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660903-47-defend428" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Murrey 
                  <interp inst="t17660903-47-defend428" type="surname" value="Murrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-47-defend428" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-47-defend428" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for <rs id="t17660903-47-off252" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660903-47-off252" type="offenceCategory" value="breakingPeace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-47-off252" type="offenceSubcategory" value="wounding"></interp>
               that he, with a certain pistol, loaded with gun-powder and leaden shot, which he had, and held in his right hand, did shoot off and discharge at and against Dorothy, <rs id="t17660903-47-viclabel253" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-47-victim431 t17660903-47-viclabel253"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17660903-47-person429">
                        John 
                        Bourne 
                     <interp inst="t17660903-47-person429" type="surname" value="Bourne"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660903-47-person429" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660903-47-person429" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , with intent the said Dorothy to kill and murder
            </rs>, <rs id="t17660903-47-cd254" type="crimeDate">July 4</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-47-off252 t17660903-47-cd254"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>(At the desire of the prisoner the witnesses were examined apart.)</p>
               <p>
            
               
                  <persName id="t17660903-47-victim431" type="victimName">
                     Dorothy 
                     Bourne 
                  <interp inst="t17660903-47-victim431" type="surname" value="Bourne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-47-victim431" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-47-victim431" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-47-off252 t17660903-47-victim431"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            . My husband 
               <persName id="t17660903-47-person432">
                  John 
                  Bourne 
               <interp inst="t17660903-47-person432" type="surname" value="Bourne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-47-person432" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-47-person432" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             keeps <placeName id="t17660903-47-crimeloc255">the Fourteen Stars in Rosemary-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17660903-47-crimeloc255" type="placeName" value="the Fourteen Stars in Rosemary-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660903-47-crimeloc255" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-47-off252 t17660903-47-crimeloc255"></join>, a public-house; I had forbid the prisoner my house, in May last was twelve months, on account of his using a gentleman; he swore he would be revenged of me</p>
               <p>Q. What were the words he make use of?</p>
               <p>D. Bourne. The ex were at he would come all the jury next door to us. On the 4th of July I was siting in my back kitchen; his back place comes up to mine; 
               <persName id="t17660903-47-person433">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17660903-47-person433" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-47-person433" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-47-person433" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was by the face of the window, which was open; this was between three and four in the afternoon; I heard a great discharge of a pistol at my back; we were both terribly frighted; I looked out and saw the prisoner creeping, pait bent, in at his own back door.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see a pistol?</p>
               <p>D. Bourne. I did not, it sounded like a fowling-piece or a pistol; I ordered the maid to get me some tea, I was afraid I should have had a fit; my husband observing me to shake terribly, said he was afraid I was very bad; immediately I saw a fire flounce by me; I was greatly affrighted; it was eight weeks before I was capable of doing any thing after this; there were marks on the wall within-side; the very house-shook on this second firing; I was carried out of the room very bad.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any reason to believe any of these discharges were intended to hurt you?</p>
               <p>D. Bourne. Yes, I have, from his always saying he would be revenged of me, and he would be the ruin of me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he use to fire his pistol before that time?</p>
               <p>D. Bourne. I never heard the report of a pistol there before that; he only came out of his door, and put out his pistol; it is right to my window.</p>
               <p>Q. Could he reach your window with his hand?</p>
               <p>D. Bourne. He could not, was he to stand upon a stool.</p>
               <p>Q. Could he see you in the room from his yard?</p>
               <p>D. Bourne. He could, from one part of it; my husband said to him, on his first firing, Mr. Murrey, you have murdered my wife, and upon your peril fire another if you dare; he let off several after that, but I cannot say how many.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-47-person434">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17660903-47-person434" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-47-person434" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-47-person434" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner five years, he lives next door to Mr. Bourne; I was<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176609030038"></xptr> with Mrs. Bourne that afternoon; about three o'clock I heard a pistol go off; it gave us very great shocks; Mrs. Bourne was ready to saint away. Soon after that, another went off very loud; she got up; I did not know whether she was shot or not; she fell against the dresser, and shrieked out: I ran to the window and said, you good for nothing thief taking rogue, Mr. Lee is not here; (that is the gentleman he used ill before;) you need not want to kill us; he was then standing by his own door.</p>
               <p>Q. How long might it be betwixt the first and second firing?</p>
               <p>E. Carter. It might be about half an hour; there were five firings; at the third I saw the flash; Mrs. Bourne was then just coming out of a sit; after the fifth firing, there came a great many people in, and a constable was sent for.</p>
               <p>Q. How much time might these five firings take up?</p>
               <p>E. Carter. It might take up three quarters of an hour.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-47-person435">
                  Mary 
                  Waley 
               <interp inst="t17660903-47-person435" type="surname" value="Waley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-47-person435" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-47-person435" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was cleaning the club-room on the 4th of July; there was a pistol went off at me; I was sadly affrighted; I went into the other room to recover myself; he came out and said, I'll kill the whores, or blow their brains out.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>M. Waley. This might be about four in the afternoon; I found my mistress was sadly affrighted; she ordered me to put the tea-kettle on; I was on the stairs, when another firing went off; she took a cup, and then in came another firing like that; she flew from her chair, and fell down, and screamed out, and went into a fit; I held her, and she bit at me like a mad dog; I was not myself for several days after this; this was on the Friday, and on the Saturday I saw little marks like shot-holes in the room over-right the window; I saw a pistol in the prisoner's hand after the second firing; as soon as my mistress was coming to her senses, my master went out, and said, pray, Mr. Murrey, do not fire, for my wife is sadly affrighted.</p>
               <p>Q. How many firings did you hear?</p>
               <p>M. Waley. I heard five in all; I was sent into the club-room to see where the firing came from; I saw him point in at the window; I spoke to him; he said he would blow my brains out; he fired all but one into the kitchen, the other he fired at me; and when he saw my mistress in fits, he stood and made game at her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-47-person436">
                  Mary 
                  Wells 
               <interp inst="t17660903-47-person436" type="surname" value="Wells"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-47-person436" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-47-person436" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 4th of June I came into the lane to buy goods to carry into the country; Mr. Murrey came up to me with a small pistol in his hand, this was betwixt one and two o'clock; he pronounced many bad words; he went away, and came again in about a quarter of an hour, and said, he had been and bought a pound of powder and half a pound of shot, and I will go now and execute the b - h. In less than a minute I heard the report of a pistol go off; presently after that another; then I heard the most dismal shrieks I ever heard in my life; to the best of my knowledge I heard three of four firings.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you think he meant by executing the b - h?</p>
               <p>M. Wells. I understood it to be Mrs. Bourne.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell Mrs. Bourne of it?</p>
               <p>M. Wells. No, I did not; I was advised not to go out, because the prisoner has threatened my life many a time; I was much affrighted, and was forced to go home in a coa.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-47-person437">
                  John 
                  Bourne 
               <interp inst="t17660903-47-person437" type="surname" value="Bourne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-47-person437" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-47-person437" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am husband to 
               <persName id="t17660903-47-person438">
                  Dorothy 
                  Bourne 
               <interp inst="t17660903-47-person438" type="surname" value="Bourne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-47-person438" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-47-person438" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; after the prisoner had fired two or three times, I said he had taken my wife's life away, he had no occasion to fire any more; I was drinking tea with her up one pair of stairs; he fired at the window; I said, forbear, pray; I cannot say where I was when I heard the first firing; my window was open; I saw him one of the times pull out the pistol, and point it towards my window, and my wife was about a yard from it.</p>
               <p>Q. Could he see who was in the room?</p>
               <p>J. Bourne. No, I believe he could not; when he fired it that time, my wife fell back; after I had desired him not to fire no more, and told him what he had done in affrighting my wife, he fired again, as my wife was screaming and crying; the smoak and fire, and whatever there was, came into the room.</p>
               <p>Q. How many times did he fire?</p>
               <p>J. Bourne. In all I believe he fired five or six times; there are dents in the wainscot to be seen.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was firing at a mark</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660903-47-verdict256" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660903-47-verdict256" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
