<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670429-51">
               <interp inst="t17670429-51" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670429-51" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670429-51" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670429"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670429-51" type="date" value="17670429"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670429-51-off278-c347" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-51-defend457 t17670429-51-off278 t17670429-51-verdict280"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670429-51-off278-c349" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-51-defend461 t17670429-51-off278 t17670429-51-verdict280"></join>
         
               <p>248, 249. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17670429-51-defend457" type="defendantName">
                     Francis 
                     Gorman 
                  <interp inst="t17670429-51-defend457" type="surname" value="Gorman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-defend457" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-defend457" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             was indicted, for that <rs id="t17670429-51-off278" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-off278" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-off278" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               he, with a certain loaded pistol, did shoot at 
                     
                        <persName id="t17670429-51-victim459" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Griffiths 
                        <interp inst="t17670429-51-victim459" type="surname" value="Griffiths"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670429-51-victim459" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670429-51-victim459" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-51-off278 t17670429-51-victim459"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , giving him a wound on the left side the head, depth four inches and breadth half an inch, of which wound he instantly died; and 
                     
                        <persName id="t17670429-51-defend461" type="defendantName">
                           Henry 
                           Johnson 
                        <interp inst="t17670429-51-defend461" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670429-51-defend461" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670429-51-defend461" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , together with 
                     <persName id="t17670429-51-person462">
                        Thomas 
                        Brown 
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-person462" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670429-51-person462" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670429-51-person462" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   (not taken) were present, aiding, assisting, comforting and abetting the said Francis to commit the same
            </rs>, <rs id="t17670429-51-cd279" type="crimeDate">March 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-51-off278 t17670429-51-cd279"></join>. They stood charged likewise on the Coroner's inquest for the said murder. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-51-person463">
                  Thomas 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17670429-51-person463" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-person463" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-person463" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Would, 
               <persName id="t17670429-51-person464">
                  John 
                  Griffiths 
               <interp inst="t17670429-51-person464" type="surname" value="Griffiths"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-person464" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-person464" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and I, went to Holloway to see a race; coming back we met with Mr. Underwood; when at the Red Lion, there came a coach; it being wet weather, I proposed to ride home in it; we all four of us got in; we had not been in but about five minutes, but up came 
               <persName id="t17670429-51-person465">
                  Ryan
               <interp inst="t17670429-51-person465" type="given" value="Ryan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-person465" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the evidence, and put a pistol into the coach, and said stop; he put it to my breast (I think it was a pistol, he says it was not;) he then went and stopped the horses, and then came to the coach again. I said, we are all poor people, we have nothing for you; the deceased said to the coachman, go along, we will not be robbed by them. Immediately one of them put a pistol to his head, and blowed his head to pieces; it was so dark I could not tell which it was. I turned about and saw two men at the other side the coach; I jumped out, and Ryan knocked me down directly; I went to get up upon my knees, and he knocked me down again; I went to get up a third time, he knocked me down again; after I got up there came a couple of gentleman, I said, don't go any farther, there are highway men robbing the coach now; they took me to the White Horse. After that, when the coach came up, I was told Griffiths was shot dead; he sat upright in the coach; when we came to move him I saw he was dead. I went to see Johnson when he was in prison; he said he was the man that saved my life, for Ryan after he had killed the other, wanted to come back and kill me; and that Johnson said to him, no, you have killed enough; then Ryan said, I'll kill you directly.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-51-person466">
                  Robert 
                  Would 
               <interp inst="t17670429-51-person466" type="surname" value="Would"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-person466" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-person466" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was very much frighted; I was robbed to be sure of four guineas and four shillings; they swore and d - d so, I was forced to beg for my life. I know nothing farther than what Mr. Smith has said; the account he has given is true; I know none of the men.</p>
               <p>Mr. Underwood. We had been to see a man run in stiles; we were at the Red Lion at Holloway; it grew very dark and rained; we all four agreed to go home in a coach; we had not been set out above six or seven minutes but we were stopt; after that it drove a little way and then stopt again. The words were hardly out of the deceased's mouth, he saying he would not be robbed, before the pistol went off; we never opened the coach door; they went to open it, and down fell the deceased; then they came to the other side and robbed me. Gorman was the man that came<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176704290029"></xptr> into the coach, I know again him by his voice. They took my hat; I said, I hope you will be so kind as to give me my hat; Gorman said, who has the gentleman's hat, they gave it me. As soon as they had done, which was in about ten minutes, they said, here take your messmate into your coach, he is fast asleep. I took and hauled him into the coach, they assisting; and when we came to the White Horse we saw he was dead: his head was shot to pieces. I think I saw about four of the highwaymen. I think it was Gorman's voice that said, it does not signify to make any resistance, for there are twelve of us in the gang, and money we want. Then I said, if it is money you want take it, and do not use us ill. I cannot say I know any of them by their faces.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-51-person467">
                  Jeremiah 
                  Ryan 
               <interp inst="t17670429-51-person467" type="surname" value="Ryan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-person467" type="given" value="Jeremiah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-person467" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . It was proposed to go a robbing by Gorman; we were not acquainted with the road; we trusted to Brown, for that he knew the road. We went to one Fitzpatrick, an Irishman, at the Angel and Crown; we had three or four pots of beer there. Brown had a falling out with a man, and he pulled out a pistol and swore he would blow his brains out. Then we went on to another house and drank there; we talked about the man's running; I said if I had but 5 l. in the world I would lay it against him. After that we went out, Brown went up and stopped a post-chaise boy; but finding nobody in the chaise we let it go by, after Brown had taken 2 s. and a shirt from the boy; immediately came a coach, Brown went and stopped it; I went to the coach door and said, deliver your money; the coach did not stop, I went and laid hold of the horses reins, then I heard a pistol go off. I asked who fired the pistol, I thought the people in the coach had fired against me; then I saw Brown, Gorman, and another man helping the man into the coach; then they shut the door; then I asked again who fired the pistol; Gorman turned about and said he fired it; I upbraided him for firing it, fearing he should take the man's life; he swore by all that was good and great he would take my life if I spoke a word. We left them, and went into a house and shared the money which we took from them.</p>
               <p>Gorman. That evidence will fix upon any body to save his own life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-51-person468">
                  Hugh 
                  Fitzpatrick 
               <interp inst="t17670429-51-person468" type="surname" value="Fitzpatrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-person468" type="given" value="Hugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-person468" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Angel and Crown in Hornsey. On a Monday night, the same day the murder was, about six in the afternoon, there came some men into my house, Brown was one of them; he called me on one side and asked for 
               <persName id="t17670429-51-person469">
                  John 
                  Boucher 
               <interp inst="t17670429-51-person469" type="surname" value="Boucher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-person469" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-person469" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He swore a great oath he would take his life the first time he met him. I said, are you drunk; he said, to shew you I am in my senses, he opened his coat and shewed me a pistol; the two prisoners and Ryan are like the men that were with him, but I will not be positive.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-51-person470">
                  Thomas 
                  Fitzpatrick 
               <interp inst="t17670429-51-person470" type="surname" value="Fitzpatrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-person470" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-person470" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             The prisoners were shipmates of mine some time; Ryan, Johnson, and Gorman were at our house the night the murder was committed, about six o'clock. I live with the last witness.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-51-person471">
                  John 
                  Simpson 
               <interp inst="t17670429-51-person471" type="surname" value="Simpson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-person471" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-person471" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had been at Highgate, and was in at the sign of the Cock at the bottom of Wells's-row at Holloway; there came in the two prisoners, Ryan, and another, which I believe to be Brown; I never knew them before. They all came in a little before eight in the evening, and staid till after eight; they drank and shook hands with us; they had two or three pots of beer. The murder was done soon after they went out.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-51-person472">
                  John 
                  Noaks 
               <interp inst="t17670429-51-person472" type="surname" value="Noaks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-person472" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-person472" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable; upon an information given to Sir 
               <persName id="t17670429-51-person473">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17670429-51-person473" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-person473" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-person473" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I was ordered by him to go and apprehend these people; Fitzpatrick was with us. When we were in Whitechapel, Fitzpatrick said, there is one of them; we all ran, I was behind; just by the corner I heard Brown, who is not taken, say to the evidence, run; he ran cross Whitechapel, he was too quick for me; I called, stop for murder; he was soon taken; Mr. Marsden was with us. He sent me with another man to take Ryan to Sir 
               <persName id="t17670429-51-person474">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17670429-51-person474" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-person474" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-person474" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Sir John told him if he was not the man that actually did the murder, with permission from the Judge, he might be admitted evidence. After he was examined I was dispatched back again, and upon searching Gorman's room I found three cutlasses between the bed and the ticking, and this pocket-pistol in his chest, loaded, (all produced in court.) We went to see for the rest; we found Gorman, Johnson, Sweetman, and Collins, at the White Lion near Ratcliff-highway.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-51-person475">
                  Mary 
                  Barrat 
               <interp inst="t17670429-51-person475" type="surname" value="Barrat"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-person475" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-person475" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I found this pistol under the bench where the prisoners sat when they were taken; they were taken on the Wednesday, and I found it on the Saturday following. (Produced in court)</p>
               <p>Mrs. Leach. Gorman hired a room of me; he, Johnson and Ryan were all shipmates; they used to come in and out; they came into my house a little after nine that Monday night, and lay all there that night.</p>
               <p>Gorman's defence.</p>
               <p>I don't know what to say, my word will stand for nothing.</p>
               <p>Johnson's defence.</p>
               <p>I did not know where I was when Ryan carried me with them. I and Collins were together; we met Ryan; we were very much in liquor, I don't<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176704290030"></xptr> know what house we were in; all I know is, when we were in the house there were some wagers laying about the running; when this thing happened, Ryan, Gorman and Brown were a good way before me. I heard a pistol go off and saw the flash. I went up to the coach and saw the man lie dead; Ryan was beating a man at the time on the ground with a stick; I said to him, do you know what you are doing, you are going to kill the man. He said I deserved to be kill'd, and let's all go to hell together, for it was no matter; I am sure he must have killed him very soon had he went on. I went on the other side and called him, and said, may be the man is dead; he said, let him go to hell and you all together, and swore very much, do you come away; I said I would not go away till I had put the man in the coach. They told me going over the field I deserved to be killed, and go to hell among the rest, and used me very grossly. I saw nobody touch the coachman but Brown. Brown had the man's hat; I asked him about it; he said he would shoot me if I said a word about it. I do not know which way they went, they enquired for Red-cap's; I would not stay with them. Ryan said he would go on the same road and stop a coach. When they found I would go to London they all consented to it. My character was never spotted before; here is my captain and other officers that I belonged to.</p>
               <p>Capt. 
               <persName id="t17670429-51-person476">
                  Thomas 
                  Haywood 
               <interp inst="t17670429-51-person476" type="surname" value="Haywood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-person476" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-person476" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The two prisoners and Ryan did belong to my ship, they were paid off last February; Johnson was a very good seaman, he never was charged with any ill thing on board the ship; he was like others, he would drink when he could get it; they were all three capable men and good seamen.</p>
               <p>Mr. Little and Mr. Hall, two other officers on board the same ship, said they were all three good seamen; they all said Johnson's moral character excelled the others.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17670429-51-verdict280" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-verdict280" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17670429-51-punish281" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-punish281" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-punish281" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="deathAndDissection"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-51-defend457 t17670429-51-punish281"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>This being Friday they received sentence immediately to be executed on the Monday following, and their bodies to be dissected and anatomized.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17670429-51-punish282" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-punish282" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-punish282" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="executed"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-51-defend457 t17670429-51-punish282"></join>
               Gorman was executed
            </rs> accordingly. <rs id="t17670429-51-punish283" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-punish283" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-51-punish283" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="respited"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-51-defend461 t17670429-51-punish283"></join>
               His Lordship respited Johnson during his Majesty's pleasure
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
