<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17630518-45">
               <interp inst="t17630518-45" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630518-45" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630518-45" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17630518"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630518-45" type="date" value="17630518"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17630518-45-off266-c329" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-45-defend424 t17630518-45-off266 t17630518-45-verdict271"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17630518-45-off266-c330" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-45-defend425 t17630518-45-off266 t17630518-45-verdict271"></join>
         
               <p>255, 256. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17630518-45-defend424" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Geaty 
                  <interp inst="t17630518-45-defend424" type="surname" value="Geaty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-defend424" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-defend424" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               <persName id="t17630518-45-defend425" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Charles 
                     Wilkinson 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17630518-45-alias-4" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-45-defend425 t17630518-45-alias-4"></join>Dogood</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-defend425" type="surname" value="Wilkinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-defend425" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-defend425" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , were indicted for that they, <rs id="t17630518-45-off266" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-off266" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-off266" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               on the King's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17630518-45-victim428" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Foster 
                        <interp inst="t17630518-45-victim428" type="surname" value="Foster"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630518-45-victim428" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630518-45-victim428" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-45-off266 t17630518-45-victim428"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17630518-45-viclabel267" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-45-victim428 t17630518-45-viclabel267"></join>, did make an assault, putting her in fear and danger of her life, and stealing from her person one linnen towel, value 3 d. one linnen laced cap, value 6 d. and one linnen handkerchief, value 1 d. her property, and against her will
            </rs>, <rs id="t17630518-45-cd268" type="crimeDate">April 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-45-off266 t17630518-45-cd268"></join>. ++.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630518-45-person429">
                  Mary 
                  Foster 
               <interp inst="t17630518-45-person429" type="surname" value="Foster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-person429" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-person429" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 13th of April, between 8 and 9 at night, I had been at London, and was going home to Islington, where I live <rs id="t17630518-45-deflabel269" type="occupation">in service</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-45-defend424 t17630518-45-deflabel269"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-45-defend425 t17630518-45-deflabel269"></join> to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17630518-45-person430">
                  John 
                  Booth 
               <interp inst="t17630518-45-person430" type="surname" value="Booth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-person430" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-person430" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a salesman, I met three men <placeName id="t17630518-45-crimeloc270">near the Crown and Woolpack brewhouse</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17630518-45-crimeloc270" type="placeName" value="near the Crown and Woolpack brewhouse"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17630518-45-crimeloc270" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-45-off266 t17630518-45-crimeloc270"></join>, I thought they were fuddled, I went to get out of their way; they all three surrounded me, and pushed me down, and took my bundle from me when I was upon the ground, and ran away. I saw a man coming from Islington, I hallow'd out, stop thief!</p>
               <p>Q. What did they say to you?</p>
               <p>Foster. I don't know that they said any thing, I was much afrighted; if they said any thing, it was very low. That man ran after them towards London, about a quarter of an hour or less; after that Mr. Townsend said, where is the woman that hallowed out? I told him, I was the person; he said, they had taken the man with the bundle. I saw the bundle in his hand; the man that was taken was Wilkinson.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you recollect whether he was one of the men who pushed you down?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176305180027"></xptr>Foster. No, I do not know never a one of them; it was dark, and I was so frightened.</p>
               <p>Q. How were they dressed?</p>
               <p>Foster. To the best of my knowledge they were all clothed in black; they had hats on, but what faces, or whether they had their hair, or wigs, I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630518-45-person431">
                  Henry 
                  Townsend 
               <interp inst="t17630518-45-person431" type="surname" value="Townsend"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-person431" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-person431" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming from Islington to London on Wednesday the 13th of April, my wife was with me, I stopt at the Crown and Woolpack to speak to a young man that lived there, I had not been there above five or six minutes before I heard a woman cry, stop thief, I don't think it was a minute after before Wilkinson came by with this bundle under his arm, I immediately fo llowed and came up with him, just by the Woolpack brewhouse.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is that from the Woolpack?</p>
               <p>Townsend. That is about thirty or forty yards from it. I said, you are the man that has got the bundle; I was on the outside of the rails, and he in the path-way; he immediately put his right hand into his pocket, and made an offer at me over the rails, I dropt down by the side of the rails to save myself, thinking he had a knife or pistol in his hand; he made use of some expression, but I do not remember the words; I immediately followed him about a dozen or fourteen yards farther; he took the bundle from under his arm and threw it at my head quite cross the road, I took up the bundle, and was going after him again, I heard somebody say he was taken upon the causeway, I got up to the King of Prussia's head, and had not stood there above a minute before he was brought up by 
               <persName id="t17630518-45-person432">
                  John 
                  Roffe 
               <interp inst="t17630518-45-person432" type="surname" value="Roffe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-person432" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-person432" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; he had a black coat on, I knew him to be the same, as I had been close to him by the rails, and could see the bundle under his arm very plain; his hat was stop'd before over his face, I saw he had his own hair on, but could not take particular notice of his face; I could tell him by his speech, having a gruff voice when he spoke to me. (Such was the prisoner's voice.) I am sure he is the very same man that had the bundle, that is Wilkinson now at the bar. (The bundle produced in the court, with the things in it mentioned in the indictment; deposed to by the prosecutrix as the bundle she was then robbed of, her property.)</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutrix. How near the Woolpack was it you was robbed?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. It was on that side towards Islington.</p>
               <p>Townsend. She shewed me the place afterwards, it was about twenty yards from the Woolpack nearer Islington. When Wilkinson was brought up I immediately said, this is the man that had the bundle, and I will swear to him; I took him by the collar and had him to the Woolpack alehouse, I heard Esquire Cross was at the Angel, I took him there, he advised me to take him to Bridewell.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know Wilkinson before?</p>

               <p>Townsend. I never saw him in my life before to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. When he pursued me, I saw two men running by me, and I cried, stop thief.</p>
               <p>Townsend. That is all false.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630518-45-person433">
                  John 
                  Roffe 
               <interp inst="t17630518-45-person433" type="surname" value="Roffe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-person433" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-person433" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the Woolpack, Mr. Townsend and I were there talking together, I heard the cry, stop thief! three men came by walking as fast as they could towards London, I went up to one of the men and said, a woman cried out, stop thief; Geary being one of them cried out, yonder he goes, cross the fields; I said, you can't for them I am sure.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he dressed?</p>
               <p>Roffe. He had a blue great-coat on, a hat and perriwig.</p>
               <p>Geary. You'll swear your soul to hell.</p>
               <p>Roffe. I touch'd him, and looked him in the face, and kept walking on by his side, he began to move his hands about, then I got a little farther off; the other two were a little before; when they got upon the causeway, Wilkinson made a push, I called out, this man is guilty by his running away; I followed him as far as the King of Prussia's head, till they began to make a run.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it light or dark?</p>
               <p>Roffe. It was not very dark. Wilkinson ran directly down the causeway from the King of Prussia, I ran about half way down the road, (he was foremost, the two went on one side, not down the causeway, but over the fields by the New River side) I was getting up the cause, way to Wilkinson, I said, do not go to strike me, for here is somebody coming, he was come close to the rails to strike me; I got up, and took him by the collar, and kept him four or five minutes till somebody came, then we brought him to the King of Prussia, they seeing a mob about the door would not let us in; we took him to the house where I live, the Crown and Wool-pack. there the woman was, and said that is the man that took my bundle, he had a black coat on, we set him down in the fore room in about a quarter of an hour two men came in and called for six pennyworth of brandy and water, Geary was one of them, I could have sworn to him then as one in company with Wilkinson; he asked what they had done with the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176305180028"></xptr> man? he was told they had taken him to Bridewell, then they went about their business.</p>

               <p>Q. to the Prosecutrix. Did you say, upon seeing Wilkinson, that was the man that took your bundle?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. If I did say so I was so frightened I did not know what I said.</p>
               <p>Roffe. I asked Geary to go into the fore room, as I had told my mistress he was one of them, but he would not.</p>
               <p>Geary. You'll swear a man's life away for a bunch of matches. I did call for brandy and water, but I was fuddled.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630518-45-person434">
                  Richard 
                  Pearce 
               <interp inst="t17630518-45-person434" type="surname" value="Pearce"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-person434" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-person434" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Wilkinson was brought into Clerkenwell Bridewell, and the next morning about 8 o'clock Geary came to drink with him; by the description I had, I suspected he was one of them, I was told one belonging to him was justly and had one black eye, I asked him how he came by that black eye? he said he was fuddled, and fell down on Tower-hill, and hurt it. I turned the key upon him, and carried him before Sir 
               <persName id="t17630518-45-person435">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17630518-45-person435" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-person435" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-person435" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who committed him to New Prison. The last time Wilkinson was examined by Sir John, he wanted to be evidence against Geary, and declared there that Geary was the man that knocked the woman down, and gave the bundle to him, and he put it under his coat, and when Townsend went to lay hold of him he threw it at him, but the Justice would not admit him.</p>
               <p>Geary. Justice Fielding would have admitted me an evidence, but I could not, except I would d - n my poor soul.</p>
               <p>Q. to Roffe. Did you observe Geary had a black eye when you talked to him?</p>
               <p>Roffe. No, I did not, that was observed when he came in for the brandy and water.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630518-45-person436">
                  Thomas 
                  Barrow 
               <interp inst="t17630518-45-person436" type="surname" value="Barrow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-person436" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-person436" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was before Sir 
               <persName id="t17630518-45-person437">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17630518-45-person437" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-person437" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-person437" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             with Wilkinson and Geary, they denied knowing one another.</p>
               <p>Wilkinson's Defence. I know nothing about it, what they have swore to is false.</p>
               <p>Wilkinson called Mr. Mullings and Mr. Anderson, who had known him about three months, the time which he had been from sea, they spoke well of him.</p>
               <p>Geary's Defence. As I was coming from Islington I got a little fuddled, I went into the Woolpack, and called for six pennyworth of brandy and water; I heard a man was taken, I paid for my liquor, and went away, and got up to go to Wapping; I met two girls in Clerkenwell, one of them told me there was an acquaintance of her's in Bridewell or New Prison, I went at their request with them, and there they detained me.</p>
               <p>Geary called to his character 
               <persName id="t17630518-45-person438">
                  John 
                  Dosset 
               <interp inst="t17630518-45-person438" type="surname" value="Dosset"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-person438" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-person438" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17630518-45-person439">
                  Thomas 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17630518-45-person439" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-person439" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-person439" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who gave him the character of a hard-working industrious man.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17630518-45-verdict271" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630518-45-verdict271" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
