<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17651211-33">
               <interp inst="t17651211-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651211-33" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651211-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17651211"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651211-33" type="date" value="17651211"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17651211-33-off192-c244" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-33-defend320 t17651211-33-off192 t17651211-33-verdict196"></join>
         
               <p>37. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17651211-33-defend320" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Reynolds 
                  <interp inst="t17651211-33-defend320" type="surname" value="Reynolds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-33-defend320" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-33-defend320" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted, for that <rs id="t17651211-33-off192" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651211-33-off192" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-33-off192" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he, together with 
                     <persName id="t17651211-33-person321">
                        Richard 
                        Smith 
                     <interp inst="t17651211-33-person321" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651211-33-person321" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651211-33-person321" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , not yet taken, did make an assault on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17651211-33-victim323" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Eaton 
                        <interp inst="t17651211-33-victim323" type="surname" value="Eaton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651211-33-victim323" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651211-33-victim323" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-33-off192 t17651211-33-victim323"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17651211-33-viclabel193" type="occupation">Gent.</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-33-victim323 t17651211-33-viclabel193"></join> on the King's highway, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and violently taking from his person one watch, with inside case metal, and outside shagreen, value 40 s. one steel watch chain, and stone seal set in gold, value 20 s. one pair of silver shoe buckles, one pair of silver knee buckles, one silk handkerchief, one inkhorn, one penknife, and one knife to pare nails with, his property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17651211-33-cd194" type="crimeDate">November 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-33-off192 t17651211-33-cd194"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-33-person324">
                  John 
                  Eaton 
               <interp inst="t17651211-33-person324" type="surname" value="Eaton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-33-person324" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-33-person324" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 2d of last month I was going from Brentford to my own house at <placeName id="t17651211-33-crimeloc195">Ealing</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17651211-33-crimeloc195" type="placeName" value="Ealing"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17651211-33-crimeloc195" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-33-off192 t17651211-33-crimeloc195"></join>. Near my house I was met with by three footpads, about 6 in the evening: they all attacked me; I was on foot. Armstrong, that is evidence, held a pistol to my breast, and struck me with it, and threatened to shoot me; I can't say I was the least affrighted; I would give them nothing. They seized and took my watch, and things mentioned, with about 25 shillings in money (mentioning the things by name). They took papers which they sent me again. There were two ladies with me; one of the men left me, and went and robbed them.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you recollect any of the men?</p>
               <p>Eaton. I cannot recollect the prisoner. It was dark; but by the star light I could see the evidence's face very well. The others took care not to shew their faces. Sir 
               <persName id="t17651211-33-person325">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17651211-33-person325" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-33-person325" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-33-person325" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sent me word to attend at his office last Monday night: there I heard the accomplice Armstrong gave an account of the robbery, and who was with him in it. I there saw my silk handkerchief, the knife to pare nails with, and watch. I could be certain to the watch and knife, but the mark was taken out of the handkerchief. The prisoner was there; he acknowledged the cutting out my breeches pocket, and that he was one in the robbery.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-33-person326">
                  John 
                  Armstrong 
               <interp inst="t17651211-33-person326" type="surname" value="Armstrong"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-33-person326" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-33-person326" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner made earth for the brickmakers, I worked in the brick fields with him. I became acquainted with him the latter end of August; we went out all three together, from Reynolds's house in Labour-in-vain alley.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you set out?</p>
               <p>Armstrong. I think we set out in the afternoon. Smith and I went together to Reynolds's house; from thence we proceeded to Brentford. We generally appointed what place to go to.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober?</p>
               <p>Armstrong. We always kept ourselves sober. I had a pistol, Smith bought it; I believe I carried it all the way. Reynolds and Smith had each a stick. The pistol was loaded. We turned up a lane, and crossed two fields and over some stiles. We overtook the gentleman and two ladies; and after we passed them we turned down a lane; we saw a house, we were at a stand whether we should attack the gentleman or not. We all turned back; and I believe I was the first person that laid hold of the gentleman, and Smith I believe was the next. The ladies flew back, and Smith left me and Reynolds, and went to them. The gentleman asked me if I was in a joke: I said I was in earnest, and took his watch from out of his right hand; then I searched his right hand pocket and took his money; Reynolds was taking money out of his other pocket, and he took and cut the pocket out. To the best of my knowledge Reynolds, took the buckles out of his shoes and knees. Smith took the ladies money, in two purses, and both their buckles. I took one sleeve button out of one of the ladies sleeves. I took this handkerchief from Mr. Eaton; and Reynolds took some papers from him, and the knives. After this we ran away. There are some posts. Reynolds staid behind some time; he said Mr. Eaton shook hands with him: he in coming after us did not observe the post; he ran against one and knocked himself down. We crossed the water by Kewgreen, and so came home, to the best of my remembrance.</p>
               <p>Q. This is so lately you must remember these circumstances?</p>
               <p>Armstrong. We have had so many of these things, that I cannot remember them to distinguish one from the other. I gave my two associates a shilling for this handkerchief; the watch was sold to a gentleman at Charing-cross; I saw Smith sell it: I was about near the door. This knife here produced was found in Reynolds's pocket when<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176512110020"></xptr> taken; the other knife Smith has. The shoe buckles were sold, but I do not know by whom, nor where. The papers were returned by a letter which Smith wrote. I went and surrendered myself last Monday to Sir 
               <persName id="t17651211-33-person327">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17651211-33-person327" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-33-person327" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-33-person327" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             voluntarily; after which I went with three men, and we took Reynolds. I was afraid he would shoot me, by what I could understand by his wife, or go and inform himself; so I thought my life was as dear to me as his was to him. I do not know where to find Smith.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-33-person328">
                  William 
                  Halliburton 
               <interp inst="t17651211-33-person328" type="surname" value="Halliburton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-33-person328" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-33-person328" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Monday morning Armstrong came to Sir 
               <persName id="t17651211-33-person329">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17651211-33-person329" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-33-person329" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-33-person329" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and resigned himself up. Mr. Marsden, I, and another, went with him to Great George-street; the accomplice told us he was to meet Reynolds there, and that the best way would be to send for him to a public house, and not to go to his house, as he had fire arms loaded; so he sent the waiter at the King's-Head for Reynolds; he came, and we seized him, and took this knife out of his pocket, (producing one.)</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. That knife I am sure I was robbed of; I went to his lodgings, and found this pistol and a hanger, and another pair of pistols.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>What Armstrong swears is very true: two of those pistols were Armstrong's, and the hanger was Armstrong's: I intended on Sunday night to leave off the business, and to sell the things on Monday afternoon. Smith brought us both into it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17651211-33-verdict196" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651211-33-verdict196" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17651211-33-punish197" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651211-33-punish197" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-33-defend320 t17651211-33-punish197"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
