<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17600910-34">
               <interp inst="t17600910-34" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600910-34" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600910-34" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600910"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600910-34" type="date" value="17600910"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600910-34-off176-c256" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-34-defend329 t17600910-34-off176 t17600910-34-verdict178"></join>
         
               <p>277. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17600910-34-defend329" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Pennythorne 
                  <interp inst="t17600910-34-defend329" type="surname" value="Pennythorne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-34-defend329" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-34-defend329" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17600910-34-off176" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600910-34-off176" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-34-off176" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one looking-glass, value 7 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17600910-34-victim331" type="victimName">
                     Oliver 
                     Moit 
                  <interp inst="t17600910-34-victim331" type="surname" value="Moit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-34-victim331" type="given" value="Oliver"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-34-victim331" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-34-off176 t17600910-34-victim331"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17600910-34-cd177" type="crimeDate">Aug. 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-34-off176 t17600910-34-cd177"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600910-34-person332">
                  John 
                  Scott 
               <interp inst="t17600910-34-person332" type="surname" value="Scott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-34-person332" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-34-person332" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the prisoner at the bar throw this looking glass into a ditch (producing one)</p>
               <p>Q. Whose property is it?</p>
               <p>Scott. It is the property of 
               <persName id="t17600910-34-person333">
                  Oliver 
                  Moit 
               <interp inst="t17600910-34-person333" type="surname" value="Moit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-34-person333" type="given" value="Oliver"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-34-person333" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; the man has been at sea some time, but I know it is the property of the woman.</p>
               <p>Q. Who are you?</p>
               <p>Scott. I am a waiter, and serv'd my time to a vintner and cooper; I went into the woman's house with a pint of beer; she was gone out, and I was talking to the maid; I heard something give a crack in the room; I said there is somebody gone out of the house; the maid got up; and went into the room, and came and said, she did not see any body, but said the glass was gone.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the prisoner in the house?</p>
               <p>Scott. No, I did not, I ran out, and there I saw the prisoner with the glass in his hand: I ran after him; and he throw'd it into a dry ditch, there I found it,</p>
               <p>Q. Where does the prosecutor live?</p>
               <p>Scott. Betwixt St. James's Park and Chelsea, in the way to Ranelangh.</p>
               <p>Q. How far from the house did you find it?</p>
               <p>Scott. I found it about 50 yards from the house.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Scott. I live at Avery farm, about two doors from the woman's house, at the sign of the Royal Oak.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a house does the woman keep?</p>
               <p>Scott. There is no name only a board wrote up, a coffee-house.</p>
               <p>Q. Do not you know the prisoner to be a man of credit and reputation?</p>
               <p>Scott. I do, I have heard he is so.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think he took it with an intent to steal it.</p>
               <p>Scott. I can't say he did.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is Mrs. Moit?</p>
               <p>Scott. She is at home very ill.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not she angry with you for stopping the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Scott. No, she was only angry, fearing trouble, she wanted no trouble at all, she is a very honest woman, I'll assure you.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not the woman desirous of having the prisoner discharg'd?</p>
               <p>Scott. She was very agreeable to it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600910-34-person334">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Rowson 
               <interp inst="t17600910-34-person334" type="surname" value="Rowson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-34-person334" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-34-person334" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mrs. Moit; I was in the kitchen when Mr. Scott came in; he said he heard something snap in the parlour; he look'd out, and said there is a man gone out of your parlour; I was not so nimble as he, I went and miss'd a looking glass; Mr. Scott ran out, he pursued the prisoner; I went out, and saw the glass under the prisoner's coat, and I saw him put it into the ditch; he was in a different habit then than what he is now, so I will not be positive; his nose and mouth were all bloody.</p>
               <p>Q. to Scott. Was this evidence with you when you was in pursuit of him?</p>

               <p>Scott. She was.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain the prisoner is the person that flung the glass in the ditch?</p>
               <p>Scott. I am very clear in that.</p>
               <p>Q. to Rowson. What house does your mistress keep?</p>
               <p>E. Rowson. She keeps a little coffee-house.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is her husband?</p>
               <p>E. Rowson. He is on board his Majesty's ship the Guernsey.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see her husband?</p>
               <p>E. Rowson. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. How long ago?</p>
               <p>E. Rowson. About six years ago.</p>
               <p>Q. After the prisoner was taken, what was your mistress's behaviour on that occasion?</p>
               <p>E. Rowson. She wanted him to be released.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600910-34-person335">
                  Mary 
                  Bradley 
               <interp inst="t17600910-34-person335" type="surname" value="Bradley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-34-person335" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-34-person335" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am not servant to Mrs. Moit, but she knew me from a child; I call'd to see her that day, Mr. Scott and the maid were in the kitchen; Mr. Scott said, Betty something cracks in the parlour; he look'd to the street door and said, he saw a man go out; I went into the parlour; and said, Betty, your mistress's glass is gone; Mr. Scott and she went out after the prisoner; I saw them pursue him, and he throw'd the glass into the ditch, a little beyond the watchhouse.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure the prisoner is the man?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176009100040"></xptr>M. Bradley. I am sure he is.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was it?</p>
               <p>M. Bradley. I think it might be between four and five o'clock in the afternoon, I can't justly say what day: I really think he was much in liquor when it was done.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>M. Bradley. I know nothing of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he acquainted with Mrs. Moit?</p>
               <p>M. Bradley. Not as I know of.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think he did it with an intent to steal it?</p>
               <p>M. Bradley. Upon my word I do not think he did.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was not at the house, nor know nothing at all of it.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600910-34-person336">
                  Thomas 
                  Huson 
               <interp inst="t17600910-34-person336" type="surname" value="Huson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-34-person336" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-34-person336" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner 16 years, I bound him apprentice to an apothecary in Red Lion street.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he follow'd his business since?</p>
               <p>Huson. He has been a journeyman ever since, but whether he is now I don't know.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Huson. He had a good character the time I knew him.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you known him lately?</p>
               <p>Huson. I have known him to this time.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your opinion of him?</p>
               <p>Huson. I have a very good opinion of him.</p>
               <p>Fra. Bretton. I have known him some years.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Bretton. I am an apothecary, he liv'd with me between 4 and 5 years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character?</p>
               <p>Bretton. His character was extremely good, I never knew any reason to impeach it in the least.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you known him down to this time?</p>
               <p>Bretton. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he go when he left you?</p>
               <p>Bretton. He left me to set up for himself; I was very much surpriz'd to hear of this thing.</p>
               <p>- Bretton. I have known him 15 or 16 years.</p>
               <p>Q. What has been his character?</p>
               <p>Bretton. I never heard any thing bad of him in my life, I always heard a good character of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you known him lately?</p>
               <p>Bretton. I have known him within this two months, I don't think he would steal such a thing as this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600910-34-person337">
                  Mark 
                  Barber 
               <interp inst="t17600910-34-person337" type="surname" value="Barber"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-34-person337" type="given" value="Mark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-34-person337" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him nine years; what I have known of him, when sober he is the civilest man in the world, but when drunk, he is guilty of flighty tricks.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600910-34-person338">
                  Walter 
                  Hatton 
               <interp inst="t17600910-34-person338" type="surname" value="Hatton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-34-person338" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-34-person338" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him twelve years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Hatton. I never knew any harm of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600910-34-person339">
                  Wm 
                  Dawson 
               <interp inst="t17600910-34-person339" type="surname" value="Dawson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-34-person339" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-34-person339" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the family upwards of 30 years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner's character?</p>
               <p>Dawson. His character is extremely good.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600910-34-verdict178" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600910-34-verdict178" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
