<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17631019-28">
               <interp inst="t17631019-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631019-28" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631019-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17631019"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631019-28" type="date" value="17631019"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17631019-28-off142-c203" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631019-28-defend265 t17631019-28-off142 t17631019-28-verdict145"></join>
         
               <p>490. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17631019-28-defend265" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Broughton 
                  <interp inst="t17631019-28-defend265" type="surname" value="Broughton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-28-defend265" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-28-defend265" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for that <rs id="t17631019-28-off142" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631019-28-off142" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-28-off142" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               he having in his custody a certain bill of exchange, with the name 
                     <persName id="t17631019-28-person266">
                        John 
                        Parnell 
                     <interp inst="t17631019-28-person266" type="surname" value="Parnell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17631019-28-person266" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17631019-28-person266" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   thereunto subscribed, bearing date the 6th of Sept. 1763, directed to 
                     <persName id="t17631019-28-person267">
                        John 
                        Puget 
                     <interp inst="t17631019-28-person267" type="surname" value="Puget"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17631019-28-person267" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17631019-28-person267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , merchant, to which he forged an acceptance in the words following: " Pay at the Bank, in six days. J. Puget," and for publishing the same with intention to defraud 
                     
                        <persName id="t17631019-28-victim269" type="victimName">
                           Lawrence 
                           Quin 
                        <interp inst="t17631019-28-victim269" type="surname" value="Quin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17631019-28-victim269" type="given" value="Lawrence"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17631019-28-victim269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  ; it was likewise laid to be done,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176310190014"></xptr> with intention to defraud the 
                     <persName id="t17631019-28-victim270" type="victimName">
                        <rs id="t17631019-28-viclabel143" type="occupation">governors and company</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631019-28-victim269 t17631019-28-viclabel143"></join>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631019-28-victim270 t17631019-28-viclabel143"></join> of the Bank of England<interp inst="t17631019-28-victim270" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17631019-28-cd144" type="crimeDate">September 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631019-28-off142 t17631019-28-cd144"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631019-28-person271">
                  Charles 
                  Jewson 
               <interp inst="t17631019-28-person271" type="surname" value="Jewson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-28-person271" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-28-person271" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the principal in the drawing office at the Bank, on the 30th of Sept. last this bill (producing a bill of exchange) was brought to me by Mr. Stevens, on my seeing the bill I immediately perceived it to be a counterfeit, I pretended to look on the file for an order, knowing at the same time there could be none; I told him there was no order, and that I thought Mr. Puget had made a mistake, and had forgot to give an order, and I would go with him. I went to Mr. Puget, and found him in his compting-house, and told him I had got a bill which I believed to be a forgery, it not being his hand writing. Stevens was called in, he gave an account who he lived with, and how he came by it; it was thought proper to detain Mr. Stevens till we could be better informed, and in the afternoon Mr. Puget, Mr. Brown, his clerk, myself, and Mr. Stevens went to Sir 
               <persName id="t17631019-28-person272">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17631019-28-person272" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-28-person272" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-28-person272" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and acquainted him with the affair, he immediately issued a warrant to bring the body of Mr. Quin, and also of Broughton if we could, but to be sure to bring one of them. Broughton was not at home, Quin was brought, and gave an account that he had the bill of Broughton, who owed him some money, and had lived with him six or seven years off and on.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you acquainted with Mr. Puget's hand-writing?</p>
               <p>Jewson. I am very well acquainted with it; this is not his hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Q. Does he keep cash at the Bank?</p>
               <p>Jewson. He does. I saw Broughton before the Magistrate, he said he had the bill of Parnell, the drawer of the bill, and he acknowledged his indorsement upon it, and that he paid it to Mr. Quin in part of what he owed him.</p>
               <p>The bill read to this purport.</p>
               <p>London, Sept. 6, 1763. Sir, ten days after</p>
               <p>"fight please to pay to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17631019-28-person273">
                  John 
                  Broughton 
               <interp inst="t17631019-28-person273" type="surname" value="Broughton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-28-person273" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-28-person273" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ,</p>
               <p>"or his order, the sum of 49 l. sterling, as by</p>
               <p>"advice from your humble servant,</p>
               <p>"
               <persName id="t17631019-28-person274">
                  John 
                  Parnell 
               <interp inst="t17631019-28-person274" type="surname" value="Parnell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-28-person274" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-28-person274" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>"To be paid at the Bank in six days.</p>
               <p>"J. Puget."</p>
               <p>Q. What is your course at the Bank where gentlemen keep cash with you?</p>
               <p>Jewson. We must have an order specified, besides the acceptance.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether at a banker's they would have paid upon such acceptance?</p>
               <p>Jewson. This is irregular; here is no date to the bill.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631019-28-person275">
                  Thomas 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17631019-28-person275" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-28-person275" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-28-person275" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Mr. Puget's clerk. (He takes the bill in his hand.) This name, I Puget, is not Mr. Puget's Hand-writing; I have often seen him write.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631019-28-person276">
                  John 
                  Stevens 
               <interp inst="t17631019-28-person276" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-28-person276" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-28-person276" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had this bill of Mr. Quin the 28th of September, he paid it me in part of payment; he said he had it endorsed from Mr. Broughton, and I might go and receive the money at the Bank when I would. Mr. Broughton after that came along with Mr Quin to our house, and said, Mr. Stevens, I'll go along with you on Thursday; he acknowledged the endorsement on it; I said let us go on the Friday. On the Friday I said to him, Mr. Broughton, are you ready to go into the city? He said, he should be ready in about an hour and an half; when I went to him, he said he was not very well, and a gentleman was to call upon him; so I went by myself; I thought the bill was not good, seeing the date was not set properly for the payment. He told me the drawer lived at the Grecian Coffee-house, Temple-Bar. I went to the Bank to Mr. Jewson, he said he had no order to pay it, and desired I would go along with him to Mr. Puget; I went with him; Mr. Puget asked me, how I came by it? I told him; then he went to the Grecian Coffee-house to enquire after Mr. Parnell; the person told us there had been such a person there, but he was gone to Ireland. They took me back into the city to the Bank, and from thence to Justice Fielding, who examined how I came by the bill; I gave him the same account as before; then we went and brought Mr. Quin before him.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you part with Broughton that morning?</p>
               <p>Stevens. I parted with him between 10 and 11 o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know Broughton before?</p>
               <p>Stevens. I had seen him at Mr. Quin's house several times, as I have gone there about business. Broughton said, Parnell was a relation of his.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say where Parnell liv'd?</p>
               <p>Stevens. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Lawrance Quin. I received this bill of the prisoner at the bar, (holding it in his hand) the minute I got it, I past it to Mr. Stevens as cash; Broughton owed me a great deal more than that.</p>
               <p>When was this?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176310190015"></xptr>Quin. This was the 28th of last month. The prisoner lodged with me, off and on, 6 or 7 years. When this came to be enquired into I did not see him till I met with him in Thames-street, he never came home that night, nor the next night; he was advertised several times; I found him concealed between the bed and the tick.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631019-28-person277">
                  Samuel 
                  Copack 
               <interp inst="t17631019-28-person277" type="surname" value="Copack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-28-person277" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-28-person277" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Grecian Coffee-house. I know Mr. Parnell, an Irish gentleman, he frequented my house; he has been gone to Ireland two years, I believe he has not been in England since.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know his hand-writing?</p>
               <p>Copack. I have several letters of his.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this bill. (He takes it in his hand.)</p>
               <p>Copack. I think this is not like his hand-writing at all.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I have no person to appear for my character.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17631019-28-verdict145" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631019-28-verdict145" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17631019-28-punish146" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631019-28-punish146" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631019-28-defend265 t17631019-28-punish146"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
