<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17620224-16">
               <interp inst="t17620224-16" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620224-16" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620224-16" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17620224"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620224-16" type="date" value="17620224"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620224-16-off84-c182" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-16-defend208 t17620224-16-off84 t17620224-16-verdict88"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620224-16-off89-c182" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-16-defend208 t17620224-16-off89 t17620224-16-verdict88"></join>
         
               <p>103. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17620224-16-defend208" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Butson 
                  <interp inst="t17620224-16-defend208" type="surname" value="Butson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-16-defend208" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-16-defend208" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17620224-16-deflabel83" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-16-defend208 t17620224-16-deflabel83"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17620224-16-off84" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620224-16-off84" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-16-off84" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one gold ring, val 13 s.
            </rs> the <rs id="t17620224-16-cd85" type="crimeDate">24th of September</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-16-off84 t17620224-16-cd85"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-16-off89 t17620224-16-cd85"></join> last, the property of 
               <persName id="t17620224-16-victim209" type="victimName">
                  Magdalen 
                  Masquerier 
               <interp inst="t17620224-16-victim209" type="surname" value="Masquerier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-16-victim209" type="given" value="Magdalen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-16-victim209" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . ++</p>
               <p>Magdalen Masquerier. <rs id="t17620224-16-viclabel86" type="occupation">I keep a silversmith's shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-16-victim209 t17620224-16-viclabel86"></join> in <placeName id="t17620224-16-crimeloc87">Coventry-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17620224-16-crimeloc87" type="placeName" value="Coventry-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17620224-16-crimeloc87" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-16-off84 t17620224-16-crimeloc87"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-16-off89 t17620224-16-crimeloc87"></join>, and a day or two after the coronation the prisoner at the bar came to my shop, to buy a gold ring, and I shewed her several; she looked them over and over, and there was none of them strong enough, she said; but there was one in particular stronger than the rest, which I missed, and never have seen it since.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you miss it?</p>
               <p>M. Masquerier. Before she was gone; and she bespoke two very strong ones, one of which she was to call for the next day, but I never saw her any more till I saw her before Sir 
               <persName id="t17620224-16-person210">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620224-16-person210" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-16-person210" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-16-person210" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you charge her with having taken it at your shop?</p>
               <p>M. Masquerier. No, I was in such surprize I had not presence of mind to speak to her. Afterwards, upon hearing that some such lost goods were advertised, I thought proper to go to Sir John Fielding's.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know she had it?</p>
               <p>M. Masquerier. I had but one such strong ring; I laid it before her among several others, and never saw it afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the exact number of rings in your shop?</p>
               <p>M. Masquerier. No, but that particular strong one I knew from the rest; I shewed her that ring with several others?</p>
               <p>Q. Did you let her go out of the shop without saying any thing to her?</p>
               <p>M. Masquerier. I cannot say but I did.</p>
               <p>Q. When you were before Sir 
               <persName id="t17620224-16-person211">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620224-16-person211" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-16-person211" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-16-person211" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , did you charge her with stealing the ring?</p>
               <p>M. Masquerier. Yes, and she said she knew nothing of me, nor was ever in my shop.</p>
               <p>Q. You never heard of your ring, you say?</p>
               <p>M. Masquerier. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Might not the ring have fallen down in your shop?</p>

               <p>M. Masquerier. There was nobody in the shop but she and I.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you search for it narrowly after she was gone?</p>
               <p>M. Masquerier. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any-body for you look round the counter and floor, to try if they could find it?</p>
               <p>M. Masquerier. No, Sir, I was satisfied she had it.</p>
               <p>Court. So then, Madam, you form your opinion, and swear to her having taken the ring (which you did not see) merely from your having lost it, and never finding it since.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I never saw the woman till I saw her at Squire Fielding's; which she repeated.</p>

               <p>
                  <rs id="t17620224-16-verdict88" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620224-16-verdict88" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>104. (M.) She was detained on an indictment for <rs id="t17620224-16-off89" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620224-16-off89" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-16-off89" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one silver buckle, val. 7 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17620224-16-victim213" type="victimName">
                     Jacob 
                     Bourset 
                  <interp inst="t17620224-16-victim213" type="surname" value="Bourset"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-16-victim213" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-16-victim213" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17620224-16-cd90" type="crimeDate">Feb. 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-16-off84 t17620224-16-cd90"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-16-off89 t17620224-16-cd90"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620224-16-person214">
                  Jacob 
                  Bourset 
               <interp inst="t17620224-16-person214" type="surname" value="Bourset"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-16-person214" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-16-person214" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . <rs id="t17620224-16-viclabel91" type="occupation">I keep a silversmith's shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-16-victim213 t17620224-16-viclabel91"></join>, and on the 17th instant, about dusk, the prisoner came into my shop to cheapen a pair of buckles. When I came to serve her, a young man in the neighbourhood came into inform me I had a suspicious person to take care of. I took him to the lower end of the shop, to hear what he had to say, and returned again to the drawers, not supposing she had had time to take any thing: She objected to the price of the buckles, and I drew out another drawer to suit her better, and she pitched upon a pair of buckles, and asked for half a dozen of tea spoons, and I produced two sets; upon which I weighed them, and she wanted a larger abatement than is common in our trade; but the intimation I had, made me resolve to see whether she came to buy, or not, and agreed to her price. Then she desired them to be marked, while she went to Covent Garden, and she would call again. I said, If you leave earnest, I will. She said. No, if I did not chuse to mark them, I may let it alone. My neighbour informing me she was a suspicious person, I asked if she had any money to buy spoons; and said; If you have no money, you must be looked upon as having a bad design, and should be dealt with accordingly (In the time of her being in the shop she took this buckle). I then took her before justice Fielding, and we searched her, but found nothing upon her; however, upon my complaint, and an<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176202240017"></xptr> advertisement of a ring lost, she was committed on suspicion. Upon my return I found this buckle lying on the floor, and I inquired if any-body had been there to cheapen any buckles, or any-body had been at the drawers, and nobody had been in the shop; and I can take upon me to say no one but she could take it, for this buckle was in the drawer.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of the fellow of it?</p>
               <p>Bourset. The fellow of it was left in the drawer.</p>
               <p>Court desired the prosecutor to be more cautious in forming his conclusions.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>She declared her innocence as to the charge.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17620224-16-verdict92" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620224-16-verdict92" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
