<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17600416-24">
               <interp inst="t17600416-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600416-24" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600416-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600416"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600416-24" type="date" value="17600416"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600416-24-off150-c211" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600416-24-defend254 t17600416-24-off150 t17600416-24-verdict155"></join>
         
               <p>157. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17600416-24-defend254" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Jaques 
                  <interp inst="t17600416-24-defend254" type="surname" value="Jaques"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-defend254" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-defend254" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17600416-24-off150" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-off150" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-off150" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one quart silver mug, value 39 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17600416-24-victim256" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Haywood 
                  <interp inst="t17600416-24-victim256" type="surname" value="Haywood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-victim256" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-victim256" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600416-24-off150 t17600416-24-victim256"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17600416-24-cd151" type="crimeDate">March 6</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600416-24-off150 t17600416-24-cd151"></join>.</p>
               <p>Thomas Haywood. I <rs id="t17600416-24-viclabel152" type="occupation">keep the <placeName id="t17600416-24-crimeloc153">stone-kitchen alehouse in the Tower</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-crimeloc153" type="placeName" value="stone-kitchen alehouse in the Tower"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-crimeloc153" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600416-24-off150 t17600416-24-crimeloc153"></join>
                  </rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600416-24-victim256 t17600416-24-viclabel152"></join>. The prisoner is a <rs id="t17600416-24-deflabel154" type="occupation">soldier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600416-24-defend254 t17600416-24-deflabel154"></join>, and belongs to the battalion that lies in the Tower, the second regiment, belonging to colonel Blaney. I lost a silver mug th at held a quart on the 6th of March, and the prisoner was in my house at the time, but I did not see him take it. On the 7th at night, 
               <persName id="t17600416-24-person257">
                  Richard 
                  Barnfield 
               <interp inst="t17600416-24-person257" type="surname" value="Barnfield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-person257" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-person257" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , having heard I had lost a tankard, came and told me he saw a young fellow carry it out at my door. I was present when the prisoner was taken, and I charged him upon the information I had heard. He said he did not steal or touch it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you with the prisoner before the justice?</p>
               <p>Haywood. I was with him before justice Manwaring, where he denied knowing any thing of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he ever own the taking of it?</p>
               <p>Haywood. I never heard him own that. The night it was lost he was turned down by the serjeant of the guard, but came up again, and staid a good while. There was a woman that he keeps company with in the house at the same time, who went out of the Tower after that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600416-24-person258">
                  Richard 
                  Barnfield 
               <interp inst="t17600416-24-person258" type="surname" value="Barnfield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-person258" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-person258" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the prisoner at the bar take either a silver tankard or a pewter pot, and go down stairs out of the prosecutor's house with it that night, with beer in it.</p>
               <p>Q. What part of the house did he take it from?</p>
               <p>Barnfield. He took it from the upper end of the kitchen, near the fire place, and I did not see him return with it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he take it publickly or privately?</p>
               <p>Barnfield. I cannot be accountable which.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he seem to hide it?</p>
               <p>Barnfield. He put it in the hollow of his arm.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was you in the house after this?</p>
               <p>Barnfield. Not many minutes after.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you inform the prosecutor of this?</p>
               <p>Barnfield. I did. At that time I did not think any thing about it, not thinking but that he had brought it up again.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you mention this first?</p>
               <p>Barnfield. I mentioned this to some of the servants the night after it was lost.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was in Wellclose Square prison 14 days before he informed Mr. Haywood of it.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176004160029"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17600416-24-person259">
                  Thomas 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17600416-24-person259" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-person259" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-person259" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was standing just on the outside of Mr. Haywood's door, when I saw the prisoner at the bar bring something out, and at the first glimpse I thought it to be a silver tankard, but I will not swear it was, for it might be a bright pewter tankard. He turn'd out on the left from the door, and I stood to the right of the door; he went some little distance from the door.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he bring it out?</p>
               <p>Walker. He brought it out as if it had beer in it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it open in his hand?</p>
               <p>Walker. It was, and he went some little distance by Mr. Haywood's window. I saw no more of him, nor knew no more till the next night, when I heard Mr. Haywood had lost one. Then I was advised to come and give him an account of what I had seen.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoners. Did you see 
               <persName id="t17600416-24-person260">
                  Thomas 
                  Parslow 
               <interp inst="t17600416-24-person260" type="surname" value="Parslow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-person260" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-person260" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a soldier, at the door at that time?</p>
               <p>Walker. I saw nobody come out, neither did I see the prisoner speak to any body.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600416-24-person261">
                  Thomas 
                  Parslow 
               <interp inst="t17600416-24-person261" type="surname" value="Parslow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-person261" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-person261" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is the man that spoke to me when I came out. I did not see 
               <persName id="t17600416-24-person262">
                  Thomas 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17600416-24-person262" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-person262" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-person262" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have two witnesses to the fact.</p>
               <p>Court. Then it is necessary that they be separately examined. (One was put out.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600416-24-person263">
                  Thomas 
                  Parslow 
               <interp inst="t17600416-24-person263" type="surname" value="Parslow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-person263" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-person263" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went along with the serjeant upon his rounds, in the evening of the sixth of March. I saw the prisoner come out of the house called the Stone Kitchen, about a quarter before ten o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. to Walker. What time was it you saw the prisoner come out of the alehouse called the Stone Kitchen?</p>
               <p>Walker. It was much about the same time the last witness mentioned.</p>
               <p>Parslow. There are four men go their rounds; three private men and a serjeant. I stood on the step of the door, and he came down stairs and open'd the door; I asked him if the serjeant was coming down, or if there were a great deal of company up stairs.</p>

               <p>Q. Why did you ask that?</p>
               <p>Parslow. Because the serjeant had staid longer than ordinary. The prisoner had neither quart nor pint pot in his hand, no more than I have this moment.</p>
               <p>Q. to Walker. Was you there at that time?</p>
               <p>Walker. I was there at the time that they went their rounds. The serjeant at that time was above-stairs, seeing the house clear'd of the soldiers.</p>
               <p>Q. to Parslow. Did you see Walker?</p>
               <p>Parslow. I did; he was about a yard or a yard and a half from the door: At that very time the prisoner came out at the door, and went about three or four yards from the door, and stood stock still. I saw both his arms before him when he came out of the door.</p>
               <p>Q. to Walker. Did you see Parslow at that time?</p>
               <p>Walker. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Might he not be there and you not see him?</p>
               <p>Walker. If he was behind me, it is more than I know of.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600416-24-person264">
                  George 
                  Rook 
               <interp inst="t17600416-24-person264" type="surname" value="Rook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-person264" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-person264" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             called in.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600416-24-person265">
                  George 
                  Rook 
               <interp inst="t17600416-24-person265" type="surname" value="Rook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-person265" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-person265" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went into the prisoner's company about a quarter before ten that night; there was nobody but his wife with him in the stone kitchen alehouse. They were drinking out of a silver-tankard.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. It was not that which they were drinking out of that was lost; that which the prisoner had, had a lid to it, and it was a belly tankard, the other was a streight one without a lid.</p>
               <p>Q. to Walker. Had the tankard you saw a lid to it?</p>
               <p>Walker. The tankard I saw had no lid.</p>
               <p>Q. to Rook. How long was you in that house?</p>
               <p>Rook. He and I were both in that house till about eleven o'clock, till after the tankard was missed.</p>
               <p>- Nowel. I was in the house at that time, but not drinking with the prisoner, though in the same room. I saw the prisoner go down stairs, and I followed him immediately after as quick as possible.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>Nowel. I believe about half an hour after nine o'clock or thereabouts.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. He went down again after that.</p>
               <p>Q. to Nowel. Had you ever a silver tankard there without a lid?</p>
               <p>Nowel. There was a tankard with a lid. I was drinking out of a pewter pint by myself.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600416-24-person266">
                  Robert 
                  Hopkins 
               <interp inst="t17600416-24-person266" type="surname" value="Hopkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-person266" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-person266" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the prisoner at the bar; I was a serjeant in the same regiment that he belonged to, but I left the regiment about a year ago last Christmas. It is the second regiment of guards.</p>
               <p>Q. What has been the prisoner's behaviour?</p>
               <p>Hopkins. His behaviour, ever since I knew him, which is from a child, has been very good; I never heard any ill behaviour of him in my life; I was born in the same place with him; I inlisted him at<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176004160030"></xptr> St. Edmundsbury; he was near sixteen years of age when I inlisted him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600416-24-person267">
                  Samuel 
                  Wheeler 
               <interp inst="t17600416-24-person267" type="surname" value="Wheeler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-person267" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-person267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a serjeant. I was corporal of a recruiting party when the prisoner was inlisted. I am still in the regiment.</p>
               <p>Q. How has he behaved in general?</p>
               <p>Wheeler. He has behaved as a good soldier; I never knew him punished at all; he behaved allways very well.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600416-24-person268">
                  William 
                  Spurr 
               <interp inst="t17600416-24-person268" type="surname" value="Spurr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-person268" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-person268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him five years, the 20th of this month. I pay the company which he belongs to. I never heard any misbehaviour of him in my life. He never missed guard, and behaved in his station as well as any gentleman in England, and is as honest I believe as any man this day in England.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600416-24-person269">
                  Peter 
                  Stocken 
               <interp inst="t17600416-24-person269" type="surname" value="Stocken"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-person269" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am his first cousin; I never heard but that he was a very sober lad.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600416-24-verdict155" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600416-24-verdict155" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
