<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17671021-23">
               <interp inst="t17671021-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17671021-23" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17671021-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17671021"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17671021-23" type="date" value="17671021"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17671021-23-off119-c181" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-23-defend233 t17671021-23-off119 t17671021-23-verdict123"></join>
         
               <p>544. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17671021-23-defend233" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     James 
                  <interp inst="t17671021-23-defend233" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-23-defend233" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-23-defend233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, <rs id="t17671021-23-off119" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17671021-23-off119" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-23-off119" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               for that he, on the <rs id="t17671021-23-cd120" type="crimeDate">2d of August</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-23-off119 t17671021-23-cd120"></join>, about the hour of two in the night, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17671021-23-victim235" type="victimName">
                           Charles 
                           Eyloe 
                        <interp inst="t17671021-23-victim235" type="surname" value="Eyloe"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671021-23-victim235" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671021-23-victim235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-23-off119 t17671021-23-victim235"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did break and enter, and steal fifty shillings in money numbered; and on the 6th for breaking the said house, and stealing a shoulder of veal, weight twelve pounds, value 4 s. and a bushel of flour; and on the 14th of September for breaking the said house, and stealing four pieces of beef, weight twenty pounds, value 5 s. the property of the said Charles, in his dwelling-house
            </rs>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-23-person236">
                  Charles 
                  Eyloe 
               <interp inst="t17671021-23-person236" type="surname" value="Eyloe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-23-person236" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-23-person236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the <placeName id="t17671021-23-crimeloc121">Orchard-house, Blackwall</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17671021-23-crimeloc121" type="placeName" value="Orchard-house, Blackwall"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17671021-23-crimeloc121" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-23-off119 t17671021-23-crimeloc121"></join>, where the East-India company send their people to board; the prisoner is a <rs id="t17671021-23-deflabel122" type="occupation">Lascar</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-23-defend233 t17671021-23-deflabel122"></join>; he broke into my house on the 2d of August at night, and broke into my bar, and took three, four, or five pounds in silver, and some halfpence; this he confessed to me after he was taken; two nights following I found my cellar-window broke open again, and some veal was taken away; I had had a new cellar door made; he ripped the hinges from the posts, and got in again; he tried to get into the wine cellar, but could not get the iron bar off: on the 11th he broke into my hen-roost, and stole eight hens and a cock; all this he confessed to me; and on the 14th of September he broke into the cellar again, and stole four pieces of beef, and I do not suppose he went away adry, there was beer, wine, and brandy; I had no suspicion of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your house and cellar made fast over night?</p>
               <p>Eyloe. They were, it was found out by a man who the prisoner had promised to give ten bottles of brandy to; that man sent word he wanted to see me; I sent the prisoner to know what he wanted with me, and the prisoner never came back again to tell me: I hearing about the brandy; ordered, if he came near, to take him; he was taken in a summer-house about an hundred yards from my dwelling-house, by some countrymen of his, and my servant man; he was cut in the wrist, and my man was cut: the countrymen of his would have killed him, if I had not prevented it; he confessed the whole as soon as taken; I asked him how he got in; he said at my kitchen window, by the assistance of a hatchet and a knife; he is a Lascar from Bengal, he belongs to the East-India company; they send them to me to board.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>There were two white men along with me that did it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17671021-23-verdict123" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17671021-23-verdict123" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17671021-23-punish124" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17671021-23-punish124" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-23-defend233 t17671021-23-punish124"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
