<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670218-24">
               <interp inst="t17670218-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670218-24" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670218-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670218"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670218-24" type="date" value="17670218"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670218-24-off135-c163" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670218-24-defend206 t17670218-24-off135 t17670218-24-verdict139"></join>
         
               <p>155. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17670218-24-defend206" type="defendantName">
                     Henry 
                     Rowls 
                  <interp inst="t17670218-24-defend206" type="surname" value="Rowls"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-24-defend206" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-24-defend206" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17670218-24-off135" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670218-24-off135" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-24-off135" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing six brass cranks for hanging of bells, value 14 d.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17670218-24-victim208" type="victimName">
                     Edward 
                     Berry 
                  <interp inst="t17670218-24-victim208" type="surname" value="Berry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-24-victim208" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-24-victim208" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670218-24-off135 t17670218-24-victim208"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17670218-24-cd136" type="crimeDate">Feb. 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670218-24-off135 t17670218-24-cd136"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670218-24-person209">
                  Edward 
                  Berry 
               <interp inst="t17670218-24-person209" type="surname" value="Berry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-24-person209" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-24-person209" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an <rs id="t17670218-24-viclabel137" type="occupation">ironmonger, brazier, and smith</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670218-24-victim208 t17670218-24-viclabel137"></join>, in the working way; I keep a shop in St. Paul's Church-yard; last Monday night about a quarter after seven, one of my men brought the prisoner to me, and said the prisoner had taken a parcel of things out of a drawer, (being work finished, in order to go away when wanted) cranks for hanging of bells, which work the prisoner did for me. I asked the prisoner how he could be guilty of such a thing; he said, Sir, I acknowledge the fact; I cut them in pieces with intent to take them away to sell for old brass; he said, I might hang him if I chose it, and behaved in a very impertinent manner; he did not mind being transported, saying, he had been cross the water before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670218-24-person210">
                  Archibald 
                  Paterson 
               <interp inst="t17670218-24-person210" type="surname" value="Paterson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-24-person210" type="given" value="Archibald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-24-person210" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the foreman of Mr. Berry's shop; on Monday night last I missed a great many things out of the shop; the prisoner was doing something to a lock.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Paterson. He is a <rs id="t17670218-24-deflabel138" type="occupation">bell-hanger, lock-smith, and jobbing-smith</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670218-24-defend206 t17670218-24-deflabel138"></join>; seeing him drop something, I said, you are drunk, go home to bed; at that time he pulled out a piece of paper from his pocket, and seemed, as I thought, he was going to ease himself; I took a candle, and looking down, found there were two new brass cranks cut in pieces, which had fell from his pocket; I found five or six more cut on the board; I challenged him with it; he said, they were old work, and were his property. I took him and them to my master; my master said they were new work, and asked him if it was the first time he had done so; he said no, nor the second, nor the third; my master said, you will come to the gallows; he answered, he did not mind that, if he was not choaked; my master then said, you will surely go over the water, Harry; he said, I have been over the water before, I do not mind that.</p>
               <p>James Grove. I am a constable: I was sent for; there were several pieces of brass lay on the counter; I said to the prisoner, are you guilty of cutting these to pieces, in order to defraud your master; he said, yes; I asked him, how he could do such a frivolous affair as this; he said it was necessity that drove him to it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say it was his perquisite?</p>
               <p>Grove. I heard no such word.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was very much in liquor and troubled in mind, but I did not do it with intent to sell them.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17670218-24-verdict139" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670218-24-verdict139" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
