<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640502-69">
               <interp inst="t17640502-69" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640502-69" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640502-69" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640502"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640502-69" type="date" value="17640502"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640502-69-off395-c508" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-69-defend651 t17640502-69-off395 t17640502-69-verdict398"></join>
         
               <p>303. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17640502-69-defend651" type="defendantName">
                     George 
                     Knight 
                  <interp inst="t17640502-69-defend651" type="surname" value="Knight"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-69-defend651" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-69-defend651" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for that <rs id="t17640502-69-off395" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640502-69-off395" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-69-off395" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640502-69-victim653" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Lawson 
                        <interp inst="t17640502-69-victim653" type="surname" value="Lawson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640502-69-victim653" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640502-69-victim653" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-69-off395 t17640502-69-victim653"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , on the king's highway, did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and taking from his person one silver stock-buckle, value 18 d. one linen stock, value 3 d. and a pair of metal shoe-buckles, value one penny, the property of the said Thomas, and against his will
            </rs>, <rs id="t17640502-69-cd396" type="crimeDate">March 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-69-off395 t17640502-69-cd396"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640502-69-person654">
                  Thomas 
                  Lawson 
               <interp inst="t17640502-69-person654" type="surname" value="Lawson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-69-person654" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-69-person654" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in <placeName id="t17640502-69-crimeloc397">Holborn</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640502-69-crimeloc397" type="placeName" value="Holborn"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640502-69-crimeloc397" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-69-off395 t17640502-69-crimeloc397"></join> very late. Going towards Drury-lane, I asked a young woman the way: she brought me to a gateway: it was dark. I said, you are going out of the way: the prisoner came over the way, and demanded my money: he took my silver stock-buckle and stock; then he put his hand in my pocket, and took out a watch key, which I had found: he then demanded my watch? I said I had never a one: then he swore he would knock me down: he knocked me down, and swore and d - d his eyes, he would cut my throat, if I made any noise: he took from me a halfpenny, of the coin of the Isle of man: he ran away, and I got up and pursued him, and got hold of him: he got my hat, which he would then have delivered to me again, but I would not take it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. We were both in liquor, and we happened to quarrel: we were drinking together: I lost my hat and wig, and he lost his hat.</p>
               <p>Lawson. I never saw him in my life, before he came and demanded my money.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Before Justice Welch, he said he knocked me down a dozen times.</p>
               <p>Lawson. It was about twelve when this first began and it lasted till one, till the watchman came.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he take your hat?</p>
               <p>Lawson. He took that after he knocked me down: I really thought he would have murdered me: the things mentioned in the indictment were found upon him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640502-69-person655">
                  William 
                  Poney 
               <interp inst="t17640502-69-person655" type="surname" value="Poney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-69-person655" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-69-person655" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was constable of the night: my watchman said there was fighting; he went to assist, and brought the prisoner to me to the watch-house. I asked the young man what the prisoner had done? he said the prisoner had robbed him of a stock buckle, a pocket-piece, a stock, and a watch-key: I ordered him to be searched, and they were found in his pockets: he begged for pardon and mercy.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640502-69-person656">
                  Matthias 
                  Chambers 
               <interp inst="t17640502-69-person656" type="surname" value="Chambers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-69-person656" type="given" value="Matthias"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-69-person656" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going to Billinsgate, to buy fish: the quarrel was right under my window: this hat I found in the street (producing one). A little lower down, a man picked up a knife: I came home about 8 o'clock, and my landlady informed me a man had been robbed there, I carried the hat to the round-house, and the prosecutor said it was his hat.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I have no defence to make at all, than that we we were both in liquor, and a quarrel ensued: he knocked me down six times.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640502-69-verdict398" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640502-69-verdict398" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17640502-69-punish399" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640502-69-punish399" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-69-defend651 t17640502-69-punish399"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
