<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17671209-21">
               <interp inst="t17671209-21" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17671209-21" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17671209-21" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17671209"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17671209-21" type="date" value="17671209"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17671209-21-off108-c131" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671209-21-defend167 t17671209-21-off108 t17671209-21-verdict111"></join>
         
               <p>26. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17671209-21-defend167" type="defendantName">
                     Samuel 
                     Ringstead 
                  <interp inst="t17671209-21-defend167" type="surname" value="Ringstead"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-21-defend167" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-21-defend167" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17671209-21-off108" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17671209-21-off108" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-21-off108" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a plain gold ring, value 9 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17671209-21-victim169" type="victimName">
                     Walter 
                     Field 
                  <interp inst="t17671209-21-victim169" type="surname" value="Field"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-21-victim169" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-21-victim169" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671209-21-off108 t17671209-21-victim169"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17671209-21-cd109" type="crimeDate">Nov. 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671209-21-off108 t17671209-21-cd109"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671209-21-person170">
                  Walter 
                  Field 
               <interp inst="t17671209-21-person170" type="surname" value="Field"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-21-person170" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-21-person170" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner came to my house the 5th of November, a public-house, <placeName id="t17671209-21-crimeloc110">the George<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176712090011"></xptr> in Hoxton Market-place</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17671209-21-crimeloc110" type="placeName" value="the George176712090011 in Hoxton Market-place"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17671209-21-crimeloc110" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671209-21-off108 t17671209-21-crimeloc110"></join>; he called for a pint of beer; he drank that, and called for another, and a halfpenny-worth of tobacco; he asked me to drink a draught with him; he had some bags with blue in them, which he put under the bench; he sells blue and indico about the country; he went out, and staid about twenty minutes, or half an hour; then when he came in, he seemed very drunk, and staggered about, and made a great deal of disturbance, and called for more liquor; my wife told him he had had enough, and should have no more; this was about eight at night: he said to me, landlord, your wife seems to be very cross, why will you not let me have a pint of beer; I said, sit down and be quiet, and you shall; I drawed a pint; then he began to be noisy again; I drank rather more than ordinary to get him out of the house; when that was out he asked for more beer; I said, you shall have no more beer here; then he said, d - n it, you seem to be a hearty fellow, the next time I come I will call and see you, but your wife seems to be very cross: then he said, will you shake hands with me; I had a plain gold ring on my finger; he laid hold of my hand, and gave a slap with his other hand; then he said, that is not hearty, let's shake hands again; then he took hold of my hand again, and gave a smart slap on it, and said, that is hearty; I looked, and missed my ring immediately; I said, this fellow has got my ring from my finger; he stooped to lay hold of his bags to go out; I laid hold of his collar directly, and said, you have got my ring, and I insist upon having it; I sent for an officer, he was searched; I never found my ring again; I am sure I had it on when he shook hands with me, and I felt him take it from my finger.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you immediately charge the prisoner upon his shaking hands with you?</p>
               <p>Field. Yes, I held up my hand, and said, he has got my ring.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you drunk or sober?</p>
               <p>Field. I was quite sober as I am now.</p>
               <p>A Witness. I went to the prosecutor's house for a pint of beer; before I went to bed the prisoner came in, and called for a pint of beer; Mrs. Field said, when he wanted more, you have had enough already; at last Mr. Field agreed to let him have another pint; he had it; I saw Field and him clap hands together two or three times; the last blow that he hit Mr. Field, I saw a ring on Mr. Field's little finger; they shook hands, and as soon as ever they parted hands, Mr. Field said he had lost his ring; then there was no ring on his finger.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. How many people were there in the room at the time?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. There might be about half a dozen people.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671209-21-person171">
                  William 
                  Bradley 
               <interp inst="t17671209-21-person171" type="surname" value="Bradley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-21-person171" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-21-person171" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I being an officer, they called upon me; I was not willing to search the prisoner myself; we waited a little time, and the officer of the night came; then we searched him, but found nothing upon him; he stripped himself to his shirt, he denied knowing any thing of the ring.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he drunk or sober?</p>
               <p>Bradley. He was very fuddled.</p>
               <p>Q. How was the prosecutor?</p>
               <p>Bradley. He was pretty drunk.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you call pretty drunk?</p>
               <p>Bradley. I think he was as drunk as the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I never saw a ring he had.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671209-21-person172">
                  Samuel 
                  Fisher 
               <interp inst="t17671209-21-person172" type="surname" value="Fisher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-21-person172" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-21-person172" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at Mr. Field's on the 5th of November last, about half an hour after eight at night; Mr. Field said, young man, come drink.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Mr. Field drunk or sober?</p>
               <p>Fisher. He was very drunk, he could hardly speak; the prisoner was drunk also, he went towards the fire; Mrs. Field said, stand away fellow, I do not want any of Justice Fielding's gang here, she said, here is a quart pot, I will take care of it, may be you will put it in your bags; he said, I shall not hurt you: then the landlord and he went to clapping of hands together; they did not shake hands; Mr. Field stood with his back against the bar, he could hardly stand without holding, and could not speak plain: after that Mrs. Field came to me, and said, have you got my husband's ring; then Mr. Field said to the prisoner, you have got my ring, and I will stick close by you.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was it after the clapping of hands, that he charged the prisoner with taking the ring?</p>
               <p>Fisher. That might be half a quarter of an hour after the clapping of hands; the prisoner submitted freely to be searched; they took a candle, and looked all round the room; Mrs. Field said, do not let the man go; no, said the prisoner, I shall not go; he was taken into another room, and searched, but no ring found; I saw the whole transaction: Mr. Field went out of the room after the clapping of hands, before he made any complaint of losing his ring.</p>
               <p>There were other witnesses, but the jury declared they were satisfied, so they were not called.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17671209-21-verdict111" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17671209-21-verdict111" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
