<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680224-66">
               <interp inst="t17680224-66" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680224-66" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680224-66" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680224"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680224-66" type="date" value="17680224"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680224-66-off422-c560" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-66-defend709 t17680224-66-off422 t17680224-66-verdict424"></join>
         
               <p>238. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17680224-66-defend709" type="defendantName">
                     John Andrew 
                     Martin 
                  <interp inst="t17680224-66-defend709" type="surname" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-66-defend709" type="given" value="John Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-66-defend709" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17680224-66-off422" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680224-66-off422" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-66-off422" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing fifteen ounces of silver, value 3 l.
            </rs> the property of a person or persons unknown, <rs id="t17680224-66-cd423" type="crimeDate">January 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-66-off422 t17680224-66-cd423"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>Mr. Sierra. I live in Staining-lane; on the 8th of January I had been out, when I came home my servant delivered this wedge of silver to me, about fifteen ounces of it; he told me a person had left it and would call again for it; I thought the person had made a mistake in bringing it to me, instead of a working silversmith; he came accordingly between six and seven, it was the prisoner at the bar; the maid said he was at the door, and desired to be introduced in the office; I examined him, having a suspicion he did not come honestly by it; I asked him many questions, among the rest I asked it was a compound of bits was melted; he said it was a compound of bits and pistereens; I told him I was not satisfied with the account he gave, because they are both standard, and bear their own value; I found he was not in any branch of the silver business, but that of a seaman; then I asked him how long it was since he had been at sea; he said he lived in Drury-lane, I thought that an odd place for a seaman to live in; upon enquiring about these bits and pistereens, he told me he brought them from Jamaica; I told him I must be better acquainted as to the manner of his getting them, before I parted with the silver; he then agreed to leave it in my hands till he brought somebody to satisfy me; he brought 
               <persName id="t17680224-66-person710">
                  John 
                  Watts 
               <interp inst="t17680224-66-person710" type="surname" value="Watts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-66-person710" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-66-person710" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who said he knew the prisoner very well, but could not inform me where he lived; I sent for Mr. Phipps, who was acquainted with Mr. Watts, he was a person that carried out notices from Goldsmiths-hall; I took a bit of paper, and took down where the prisoner said he lived, it was 
               <persName id="t17680224-66-person711">
                  John 
                  Martin 
               <interp inst="t17680224-66-person711" type="surname" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-66-person711" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-66-person711" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at Mr. Ford's, a joiner, in the middle of Drury-lane; I enquired, but could find no such person; upon this I asked Mr. Phipps if he would go to Sir 
               <persName id="t17680224-66-person712">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17680224-66-person712" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-66-person712" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-66-person712" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he said he would go; I asked the prisoner the same question, he said he would go; going along he turned short into Maiden-lane, he had walked some time; he was called to, why do you walk so fast; he did not slack his pace, but turned down Maiden-lane, there we lost fight of him; I called after him, Martin, but he was gone: upon the 2d of February he surrendered before my Lord Mayor at the Mansion-house; he was asked there, upon his examination, what that silver was, where he had it; he said it was silver he brought from Holland, and that the Jew he bought it of said it was bits and pistereens; he said he bought them in August last, but could give no account of the weight; he said he gave three guilders, and five or six stivers an ounce; he said he had no receipt for the money, neither did he know the Jew's name, of whom he bought it in Holland; my Lord Mayor thought fit to commit him to goal, and he was afterwards bailed; he had been in search for an assay-master, and he mistook it for Mr. Sierra.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-66-person713">
                  Abraham 
                  Greenwood 
               <interp inst="t17680224-66-person713" type="surname" value="Greenwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-66-person713" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-66-person713" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am clerk to Mr. Sierra; when the prisoner came for the silver, he was shewed into the office; he said then that he melted it in his room; he was asked how he melted it down, he said from experience; then he said he had never melted one down before; he was asked what was his business; he said a seafaring man; I understood he was a common sailor, I understood he was not a dealer in silver.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>Not being a native of this country, I am afraid I shall not express myself as I should do, in order to lay the case before you; I was in Holland, there I bought this piece of silver; I brought over a parcel of ducats, to the number of 130, besides these, and a parcel of double and single reeders, which are likewise a gold coin; I brought them to the office, where I sold the ducats and reeders; Watts was by when I sold them; when I came to enquire after an assayer, I was directed by mistake to Mr. Sierra; I left it there; when I came for it in the evening the gentleman questioned me<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176802240047"></xptr> very much about it; I told him it was sent me from Holland, and that I had followed the sea, but I would bring a man that knew me very well; I brought Mr. Watts, who knew me and my wife, but at that time was not very sober; he did not know where I lived, because I had changed my residence to Drury-lane; the gentleman was going to carry me before Sir 
               <persName id="t17680224-66-person714">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17680224-66-person714" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-66-person714" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-66-person714" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and as I could not prove where I bought the silver, I could show a person that came over with me, but that gentleman was quite a stranger to me, therefore I got out of the way till I could find the gentleman, and at last I did find him, then I went and surrendered myself to my Lord Mayor; the gentleman is here.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hiss. I am a merchant; the beginning of last August I had been at Amsterdam, the prisoner there desired he might come over with me to England; we came together to Helvoetsluys, and from thence to London, but do not know the port we landed at, but we came in a post-chaise to London.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17680224-66-verdict424" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680224-66-verdict424" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>See him tried for stealing a pair of silk stockings, for which be was convicted, and afterwards received his Majesty's pardon, No 127, in Sir 
               <persName id="t17680224-66-person715">
                  Robert 
                  Kite 
               <interp inst="t17680224-66-person715" type="surname" value="Kite"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-66-person715" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-66-person715" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Mayoralty.</p>
            </div1>
