<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650918-57">
               <interp inst="t17650918-57" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650918-57" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650918-57" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650918"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650918-57" type="date" value="17650918"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650918-57-off312-c519" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-57-defend638 t17650918-57-off312 t17650918-57-verdict316"></join>
         
               <p>437. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17650918-57-defend638" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Slack 
                  <interp inst="t17650918-57-defend638" type="surname" value="Slack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-57-defend638" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-57-defend638" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for the <rs id="t17650918-57-off312" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650918-57-off312" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-57-off312" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               wilful murder of 
                     <persName id="t17650918-57-victim639" type="victimName">
                        Millecent 
                        Lacey 
                     <interp inst="t17650918-57-victim639" type="surname" value="Lacey"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650918-57-victim639" type="given" value="Millecent"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650918-57-victim639" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-57-off312 t17650918-57-victim639"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , <rs id="t17650918-57-viclabel313" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-57-victim639 t17650918-57-viclabel313"></join>, by riding a gray gelding over her, and giving her a mortal wound, of which she died
            </rs>: he stood charged on the coroner's inquest for killing and slaying the said Millecent, <rs id="t17650918-57-cd314" type="crimeDate">July 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-57-off312 t17650918-57-cd314"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650918-57-person640">
                  Martha 
                  Cousins 
               <interp inst="t17650918-57-person640" type="surname" value="Cousins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-57-person640" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-57-person640" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I carry milk about; I was coming with my pails about two months ago, on a Friday, in <placeName id="t17650918-57-crimeloc315">Whitechapel</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17650918-57-crimeloc315" type="placeName" value="Whitechapel"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17650918-57-crimeloc315" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-57-off312 t17650918-57-crimeloc315"></join>, just by a last-maker's shop, I saw the prisoner at the bar riding a gray horse full gallop; there was an old woman walking cross the road, she had a stick in her hand, and a bundle under her arm; I heard the prisoner call three times to her, to get out of the way: he said, God bless you old woman, pray get out of the way; and instead of getting out of the way, she got more in his way; he pull'd his horse in at the time; I reckon the horse had been frightened;<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176509180046"></xptr> there was a bonfire in the road, with a parcel of shavings; this was about six or seven o'clock in the afternoon: the horse's feet some how or other knocked the poor woman down; the man stopp'd his horse as soon as he could, and turned, and came back partly up to the woman; but as there was many people said, knock him off his horse, so he turned and gallopped away: this was on Friday night; the woman died in the infirmary on the Saturday morning.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650918-57-person641">
                  Francis 
                  York 
               <interp inst="t17650918-57-person641" type="surname" value="York"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-57-person641" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-57-person641" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 19th of July I saw a man (I don't know that the prisoner is the person) riding a white gelding or mare full speed in Whitechapel road: when he was near the David and Harp, below the church, he rode over an old woman; the feet of the horse struck the left side of her head: I took her up; she died the next day.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see a fire in the road.</p>
               <p>York. No, I did not; there were many voices, so that I could not distinguish whether the man call'd to the old woman or not: I assisted in carrying her to the infirmary.</p>
               <p>Walter Herbert. I was crossing the road at the same time as the old woman was crossing the road: the prisoner and another young man were riding down the road as fast as they possibly could: I imagined they were trying which could go fastest, one on one side of the road, the other on the other. After he had rode over the old woman, he pulled his horse round, to see what was the matter; the people cried, Stop the horse, beat him of his horse; then he rode away.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear him call to the woman?</p>
               <p>Herbert. No, I did not; I was 20 or 30 yards from him: he might call and I not hear him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe the man pulling his horse before he came to the woman?</p>
               <p>Herbert. I did not mind that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650918-57-person642">
                  Thomas 
                  Baker 
               <interp inst="t17650918-57-person642" type="surname" value="Baker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-57-person642" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-57-person642" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the prisoner and another man riding as fast as they could; people called out, Take care of the woman; the prisoner made some answer, but what I do not know; they were riding towards. Mile-end; the prisoner rode over an old woman: I did not observe he made any attempt to stop the horse.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650918-57-person643">
                  Stephen 
                  Flower 
               <interp inst="t17650918-57-person643" type="surname" value="Flower"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-57-person643" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-57-person643" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a surgeon. I received 
               <persName id="t17650918-57-person644">
                  Millicent 
                  Lacey 
               <interp inst="t17650918-57-person644" type="surname" value="Lacey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-57-person644" type="given" value="Millicent"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-57-person644" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             into the London Hospital; her wound was on the back part of her head, rather to the left side, a very small wound; I could just put the end of my little finger into it: it seemed to be done by falling on a pebble-stone; there was no damage done to the skull.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you believe that was the occasion of her death?</p>
               <p>Flower. By the appearance of it, I should not think it was; there was no bruise near it: I take it the woman must be 70 years of age. She was brought in insensible, on the Friday, about seven at night, and I think she died on the Sunday. After she was dead, I observed her back was very much bruised by the extravasated blood: if her death was occasioned by that bruise, there must be something internal that must be the cause of it: there was no mortification, there had not been time for that.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I went to Smithfield with an intent to sell that grey horse: coming home, a young fellow was coming my way, and asked me whether I was willing to sell the horse? I said yes: he said, let me see him go, and if I like him, I'll buy him: he was on a bay mare; I put mine into a soft gallop, and he coming with his bay mare behind mine, mine pushed clear off, I could not stop him; I pulled as hard as I could. This woman was coming cross the road, I halloo'd to her, to get out of the way; she ran in the way, and I rode against her, and shov'd her down: people called out, Knock him down, knock him on the head, and then I rode away.</p>
               <p>He called 
               <persName id="t17650918-57-person645">
                  George 
                  Hope 
               <interp inst="t17650918-57-person645" type="surname" value="Hope"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-57-person645" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-57-person645" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17650918-57-person646">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Burgess 
               <interp inst="t17650918-57-person646" type="surname" value="Burgess"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-57-person646" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-57-person646" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who deposed, they heard the prisoner call out to the woman to get out of the way.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17650918-57-verdict316" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650918-57-verdict316" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
