<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680224-39">
               <interp inst="t17680224-39" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680224-39" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680224-39" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680224"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680224-39" type="date" value="17680224"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680224-39-off253-c330" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-39-defend421 t17680224-39-off253 t17680224-39-verdict257"></join>
         
               <p>203. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17680224-39-defend421" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Alders 
                  <interp inst="t17680224-39-defend421" type="surname" value="Alders"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-defend421" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-defend421" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for that <rs id="t17680224-39-off253" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-off253" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-off253" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he in a certain open place called <placeName id="t17680224-39-crimeloc254">St. James's Park</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-crimeloc254" type="placeName" value="St. James's Park"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-crimeloc254" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-39-off253 t17680224-39-crimeloc254"></join>, near the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17680224-39-victim423" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Baker 
                        <interp inst="t17680224-39-victim423" type="surname" value="Baker"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680224-39-victim423" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680224-39-victim423" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-39-off253 t17680224-39-victim423"></join>
                     </persName>
                     
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and taking from his person one linen handkerchief, value 1 s. one iron key, value 1 d. one pair of leather gloves, value 2 d. one clasp knife, value 1 d. and one tooth-pick case, value 1 d. the property of the said James
            </rs>, <rs id="t17680224-39-cd255" type="crimeDate">Jan. 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-39-off253 t17680224-39-cd255"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-39-person424">
                  James 
                  Baker 
               <interp inst="t17680224-39-person424" type="surname" value="Baker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-person424" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-person424" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am <rs id="t17680224-39-viclabel256" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-39-victim423 t17680224-39-viclabel256"></join> to Lady 
               <persName id="t17680224-39-person425">
                  Diana 
                  Duncomb 
               <interp inst="t17680224-39-person425" type="surname" value="Duncomb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-person425" type="given" value="Diana"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-person425" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 12th of January I went with her Ladyship to my master's mother's house in South Audley-street; she told me she would give me leave to go out in the evening for an hour; I took the opportunity to go and see an acquaintance named 
               <persName id="t17680224-39-person426">
                  Margaret 
                  Lettice 
               <interp inst="t17680224-39-person426" type="surname" value="Lettice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-person426" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-person426" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at Mrs. Martin's, she is house-keeper there, opposite the door to the House of Lords in New Palace-yard. Going along the Green Park, I saw a person about twenty yards from the Mall within the gate; he crossed over to me; he collared me, and said, d - n you for a rogue, give me your watch and money, or I'll knock you down if you stir another step; he took me back to the gate, and took the key out of my pocket, and let me into the Green Park; I went about an hundred yards farther; there he stopped me and rifled my pockets of all I had; he took 7 s. in silver, my pocket handkerchief, the key of the Green Park, my gloves, and my tooth-pick case, and four tickets with my Lady's name on them.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he any thing in his hand?</p>
               <p>Baker. No, he had not, only my stick which he took from me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see nobody at this time?</p>
               <p>Baker. I saw two people at a distance, which frightened me very much.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you not call out?</p>
               <p>Baker. I had not presence of mind, my fright was so great; he said, if you don't bring me two guineas to this place in the Green Park to-morrow morning, I'll knock you down from behind the carriage the next time I see you; I told him I would; then he let me out at the gate, and I went into Piccadilly.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the evening was this?</p>
               <p>Baker. This was about seven o'clock; I left my Lady at half an hour after six; we were not above 20 minutes in the Park together.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go willingly back to the Green Park?</p>
               <p>Baker. No, I did not; after he had robbed me he took me towards the pond, and after that he went and let me out towards Piccadilly; the next day he came to my master's door about three o'clock, and knocked, the porter opened it; he asked for his fellow servant; the porter said which servant; the porter shut the door upon him and came for me; when the porter opened the door I saw him and said, d - n you for a rogue, you are<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176802240025"></xptr> the rogue that robbed me last night; he ran up the square as hard as he could run; I did not pursue him, I don't know how he was taken; there were several of my fellow servants after him before me; we could not all leave the house; he was taken in about half an hour, and they sent to me, I went, it was at a house in Oxford Road; the constable asked me if there was ever a person there that robbed me; the prisoner was put into a corner of the room, I found him; I believe there were an hundred people in the room; the prisoner I am sure is the man that robbed me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you mention your being robbed when you got home?</p>
               <p>Baker. I told all my fellow servants of it, and two chairmen, when I came home, I was very much surprized; I told the porter of it at my first going into the house; I went with the prisoner before a Justice of the peace, he would not confess any thing.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Did you not say I robbed you near Spring-garden gate?</p>
               <p>Baker. I never did; he robbed me in the Queen's Park.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Whether you ever said I robbed you in St. James's Park opposite the Mall?</p>
               <p>Baker. I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. What discourse had we when walking up the Mall?</p>
               <p>Baker. That discourse was what I have told your Lordship.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Whether you let me through into the Green Park or not?</p>
               <p>Baker. The prisoner took the key out of my pocket and let himself through.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. As it was at such a seasonable hour, why did you not make an outcry, as there was a centinel so near to have me taken?</p>
               <p>Baker. As for that I had not the presence of mind; he had hold of my collar all the way.</p>
               <p>Q. Whereabouts in the Mall was you when the prisoner first came to you?</p>
               <p>Baker. I was almost opposite St. James's.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you not call to the centinel?</p>
               <p>Baker. I had not the centinel in my head at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. In going back to the Green Park, did you not go by a centinel-box?</p>
               <p>Baker. Yes, I did, but he had hold of me, and had my stick in his hand.</p>
               <p>Q. How near did you go to a centinel-box?</p>
               <p>Baker. Within seven or eight yards.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Did not you see people passing and repassing at eight or ten yards distance?</p>
               <p>Baker. I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you describe whereabouts in the Mall he first attacked you?</p>
               <p>Baker. It was about the middle of the Mall.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Did you not say you should like such an agreeable man as me for your fellow-servant?</p>
               <p>Baker. I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Whether you did not ask me to go and spend the evening with you, and drink two or three pots of beer, as you had little business to do?</p>
               <p>Baker. I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Whether you did not let me through into Piccadilly?</p>
               <p>Baker. I never did; he let me through, but which way he went I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. The reason why you did not call out to people when in Piccadilly?</p>
               <p>Baker. I did not see any body there, I had not presence of mind.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner come out into Piccadilly?</p>
               <p>Baker. He did; I ran away as fast as ever I could when I saw he was gone, I was very much frightened.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Whether you did not shake hands with me in Piccadilly and part?</p>
               <p>Baker. I believe I did.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Whether he did not give me the key of the Green Park to let myself out, and to let myself into the Green Park to meet him.</p>
               <p>Baker. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you agree to meet the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Baker. I told him I would bring him the two guineas into the Green Park.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was you to have brought it?</p>
               <p>Baker. I was to bring it in the morning, the hour he did not mention.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. What is the reason you did not come the next morning according to your promise?</p>
               <p>Baker. I did not think it worth my while to meet such a rogue, I hoped never to see him again.</p>
               <p>Court. Then you did not wish to see him tried for it?</p>
               <p>Baker. No, my Lord, I never wished to be frightened so again.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The next day morning he was not there; I looked at one of the tickets and took it from the ground; I waited impatient till twelve<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176802240026"></xptr> o'clock; he not coming, I went to the house; I saw him putting his buckles in his shoe; he saw me, and pointed with his-hand, implying he would follow me.</p>
               <p>Baker. I was not buckling my shoe, I never saw him till the porter opened the door.</p>
               <p>Q. from pris. When I was before Major 
               <persName id="t17680224-39-person427">
                  Spinnage
               <interp inst="t17680224-39-person427" type="given" value="Spinnage"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-person427" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , whether you did not say you did not desire to prosecute me, only your mistress spirited you on?</p>
               <p>Baker. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Mr. Odell. I am chairman to Lady Duncomb; I was with her on the 12th of January; she went to South Audley-street near May fair, to Mr. Duncomb's mother; the prosecutor was with me that night; he left us at near half an hour after six; he said, gentlemen, I wish you good bye, her Ladyship has been so good to let me have an hour this evening to myself, and went away; I saw him again about twenty minutes before eight; he was in a great terror, I never saw a man so frightened in my life, he was so confused he could hardly speak; I asked him what was the matter, he with an oath said, I have been robbed to night; he said he was going down the Green Park, after he let himself in, and when in St. James's Park, he was accosted by this man; that he dropped a great oath and said, if he did not deliver his money and watch he would knock him down; he said the man collared him in the Green Park, and rifled his pockets three different times; I asked him how much he had lost; he said he believed eight or nine, or seven or eight shillings, his pocket handkerchief, a pair of gloves, a tooth pick case, a key, and 2 or 3 of my Lady's tickets; he said the man took the key of Lord Bath's gate out of his pocket, and let himself out. The prisoner came the next day about 3 o'clock, I was then in the servants hall; the porter was in the porter's hall, he let the prisoner in; I was not near enough to hear what passed; the porter called, come up, come up, here is the man that robbed James last night; I ran up the area steps, and pursued immediately down Audley-street, till he got into a house, a chandler's shop, in Oxford Road, he got the heels of me; we went into the house, and up and down two or three times: they would not admit my fellow servant; I said I was very certain the man we were after was in that house; they told me I should not without a proper officer or a warrant; I went for a warrant, and at my return they had got the prisoner; we took him up into a room and searched him; there were a watch, three handkerchiefs, three or four shillings, a pair of gloves, and the key of Lord Bath's gate; we took him before Major 
               <persName id="t17680224-39-person428">
                  Spinnage
               <interp inst="t17680224-39-person428" type="given" value="Spinnage"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-person428" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he did not confess any thing; the prosecutor charged him with taking him out of St. James's Park into the Green Park, and there robbing him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-39-person429">
                  Richard 
                  Urland 
               <interp inst="t17680224-39-person429" type="surname" value="Urland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-person429" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-person429" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the other chairman; I was present when the prisoner was taken and search'd; there were three handkerchiefs, a pair of gloves, a tooth-pick-case, 4 s. and a key of the Green Park, and a walking-stick, which he had in his hand; I was with him before Major 
               <persName id="t17680224-39-person430">
                  Spinnage
               <interp inst="t17680224-39-person430" type="given" value="Spinnage"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-person430" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and when he was going to prison, he confessed he committed the robbery, and no body else; and he confessed two other robberies besides.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you what induced him to come to your master's house, after he had committed the robbery?</p>
               <p>Urland. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-39-person431">
                  William 
                  Aslry 
               <interp inst="t17680224-39-person431" type="surname" value="Aslry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-person431" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-person431" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a perriwig maker, and live in Brook-street, Grosvenor-square; I was going along the road, and saw a number of people round a chandler's shop in Oxford Road; I enquired what was the matter; I was told there was a thief in the house that had robbed a footman; I said, are you sure he is there; I was answered, yes; I said, there was one of St. George's constables over the way; I went to him, he and I went in; I went up about four or five steps of the second story, and met the prisoner coming down; I laid hold of him, and said, Sir, you shall go no farther; he said, indeed, Sir, you are mistaken in the person; I said, I shall be farther informed before I let you go; I held him about a minute; by that time the chairman came, and said, that is the man I am in pursuit of; (the things found upon the prisoner produced.)</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I swear to one handkerchief only.</p>
               <p>Aslry. When the prosecutor came, they put the prisoner into a corner of the room, and desired him to look for the man that had robbed him; he looked round, and pointed to the prisoner, and said, that is the man; then we took him to Major 
               <persName id="t17680224-39-person432">
                  Spinnage
               <interp inst="t17680224-39-person432" type="given" value="Spinnage"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-person432" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; when in the coach, going to Bridewell, he was asked whether he had any accomplice; he said, no; I asked him how he came to go and ask for the two guineas; he said, he did not know how he came to go; I said, I am afraid you have been ruined by keeping bad company; he said he had, and did not care what became of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-39-person433">
                  Thomas 
                  Dodsworth 
               <interp inst="t17680224-39-person433" type="surname" value="Dodsworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-person433" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-person433" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am porter to Lady Duncomb; the prisoner came to our house about three o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Baker buckling his shoes then?</p>
               <p>Dodsworth. I did not see him, as I remember; sometimes he does buckle his shoes in the hall.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176802240027"></xptr>Q. When did Baker tell you of his being robbed?</p>
               <p>Dodsworth. He told me of it that night as soon as he came in; he seemed very much frightened; my fellow-servants heard him tell it; he said it was in the Park.</p>
               <p>Q. Which Park?</p>
               <p>Dodsworth. I cannot tell which Park; the next day the prisoner came to our house, and produced this ticket, ( producing one.)</p>
               <p>Baker. This is one of the tickets I had in the Park that night, which the prisoner took from me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was going to the Queen's guard (I am a soldier) to see another soldier; walking through the Park, the footman overtook me; he asked me what o'clock it was; I said, I thought about seven; he still kept walking with me, and asked me which way I was going; I said, to the Queen's guard, to see a friend; just as we came to Lord Harrington's, he said to me, Sir, I should be glad of your company, as you seem so agreeable, and I have but little to do; I said, Sir, I hope you will excuse me till another opportunity, as I am not acquainted with you; if you will wait till I come back, I will oblige you with my company; he still was very desirous for me to go with him; I went with him through the Green Park; just as we came to the top of it, I stopped to make water; he came up to me, and took hold of my private parts; I said, you scoundrel, what do you mean, are there not women enough, what do you mean by it, I do not understand your meaning; he begged I would not hurt him; I said, you scoundrel, let me through the gate; I told him, I had a good mind to lick him; well, he went on his knees, and begged that I would not expose him, it would be his ruin, and he should lose his place; he said he had no money about him, but call to-morrow at such a place, saying he lived in Half-moon-street, Piccadilly, that his name was 
               <persName id="t17680224-39-person434">
                  John 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17680224-39-person434" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-person434" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-person434" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . As we were going to shake hands, he gave me this pocket-handkerchief, and the key to let myself through the Park-gate again. The next morning I went, according to his proposal, he was not there; I waited very impatiently, he did not come; (when he gave me the handkerchief, there dropped two or three tickets on the ground; he was very desirous to have them; I said, when you meet me tomorrow you shall have them; we shook hands and parted;) I put my hand in my pocket, there I saw Lady Duncomb, Grosvenor-square. I went there, when I found where he lived, and saw him at the window; before I knocked, he put his hand out, as if I was to go that way, and he would follow me: after he did not come out, I knocked at the door; the porter came, I asked for his fellow-servant; he said, what is your business; I said, I should be very glad to speak to such a person; he shut the door and called him; I said, I hope you are very well; he said, you are the fellow that robbed me in the Park; in my fright I went away; just as I was turning the corner of the square, I heard the cry, stop thief; I wondered what was the matter, and ran away; I went into that house, and was taken and carried before Major 
               <persName id="t17680224-39-person435">
                  Spinnage
               <interp inst="t17680224-39-person435" type="given" value="Spinnage"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-person435" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I had no talk with any body about a robbery; he is a bad man, and wants to swear my life away.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-39-person436">
                  David 
                  Jourdan 
               <interp inst="t17680224-39-person436" type="surname" value="Jourdan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-person436" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-person436" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17680224-39-person437">
                  Walter 
                  Davidson 
               <interp inst="t17680224-39-person437" type="surname" value="Davidson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-person437" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-person437" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , two serjeants in the third regiment. to which regiment the prisoner belonged, from the 8th of June, 1764; and 
               <persName id="t17680224-39-person438">
                  Andrew 
                  Fowls 
               <interp inst="t17680224-39-person438" type="surname" value="Fowls"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-person438" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-person438" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17680224-39-person439">
                  Anne 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17680224-39-person439" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-person439" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-person439" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             appeared for him, and said, they never heard any thing bad laid to his charge.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17680224-39-verdict257" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-verdict257" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17680224-39-punish258" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680224-39-punish258" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-39-defend421 t17680224-39-punish258"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
