<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17611209-40">
               <interp inst="t17611209-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611209-40" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611209-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17611209"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611209-40" type="date" value="17611209"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17611209-40-off231-c359" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-40-defend438 t17611209-40-off231 t17611209-40-verdict235"></join>
         
               <p>44. (M) 
               <persName id="t17611209-40-defend438" type="defendantName">
                  A.
                   R.
               <interp inst="t17611209-40-defend438" type="surname" value="R."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-40-defend438" type="given" value="A."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-40-defend438" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17611209-40-off231" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611209-40-off231" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-40-off231" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               forging and publishing a counterfeit bill of exchange, with intent to defraud
            </rs> 
            
               
                  <persName id="t17611209-40-victim440" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Ridgeway 
                  <interp inst="t17611209-40-victim440" type="surname" value="Ridgeway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-40-victim440" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-40-victim440" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-40-off231 t17611209-40-victim440"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17611209-40-cd232" type="crimeDate">Nov. 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-40-off231 t17611209-40-cd232"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-40-person441">
                  Wil 
                  Ridgeway 
               <interp inst="t17611209-40-person441" type="surname" value="Ridgeway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-40-person441" type="given" value="Wil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-40-person441" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17611209-40-viclabel233" type="occupation">stationer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-40-victim440 t17611209-40-viclabel233"></join>, and live at the corner of <placeName id="t17611209-40-crimeloc234">Warwick-court, Holborn</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17611209-40-crimeloc234" type="placeName" value="Warwick-court, Holborn"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17611209-40-crimeloc234" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-40-off231 t17611209-40-crimeloc234"></join>. On Monday the 23d of November, the prisoner and Brewer Smith came into my shop. The prisoner asked me, If I could give him money for a bill of exchange for 10 l. or 10 guineas. I had not had the bill a minute before two constables rushed in and took the prisoner away; and immediately Smith snatched the bill out of my hand. Justice Welch sent for me soon after; but I was so affrighted at their suddenly taking him away, that I could give very little account of the matter, not having sight of the bill enough to know it again.</p>
               <p>Brewer Smith. On the 22d of November the prisoner came to me at the Castle in Castle-street, Bloomsbury. He desired, I would call upon him at his lodgings, the duke of Bedford's head. I went in about an hour. We went to Brooks-market, and from thence to the King's-head in Leather-lane: There he shewed me a note or draft; he desired me to go and get the cash for it; he sealed it in a letter, and put it in his pocket. Then he went out; I asked him, Where he was going? he said, A little way farther. And just as we came by Bow Church he said, I must say I come from Mr. Cooper at the White-horse inn, Fetter-lane, and I was to personate the steward of Mr. Mason; I have forgot the name which he told me. We came into Canon-street. He shewed me the house of Mr. Wetherby, a wine-merchant there. Then we went to the cock and bottle, and had a pint of purl there. He said, This should be endorsed, but I do not ask you or any body else to endorse it. Then I went to the necessary-house to consider what to do, as he wanted me to personate another person, and was determined to have nothing to say to it; but I told him that I believed Mr. Ridgeway would pay the money, and accept the note. Then I went to the White-horse in Fetter-lane, and found, upon enquiry, that Mr. Cooper had not been in town since the coronation. I told Mr. Ridgway the transactions we had had that afternoon. Then I went to Justice Welch, and told him the affair. He advised me to take him up. I had appointed the prisoner to meet me at 10 the next day. I met him, and two constables were ready to follow us at a little distance. We went to Mr. Ridgeway's shop; he went in, and delivered this bill to Mr Ridgeway. I gave the signal, and the two constables came in and took him away, and I took the bill out of Mr. Ridgeway's hand. He was taken before the justice. There he acknowleged he himself wrote the bill, and that necessity had drawn him to it, and he did not know but if the bill had been sent to Mr. Mason, he would have paid it.</p>
               <p>The bill read to this purport:</p>
               <p>London, Nov. 21, 1761.</p>
               <p>10 l. 10 s. Ten days after date pay to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17611209-40-person442">
                  William 
                  Cooper 
               <interp inst="t17611209-40-person442" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-40-person442" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-40-person442" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             or order ten pounds ten shillings, for value received, as by advice,</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-40-person443">
                  Richard 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17611209-40-person443" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-40-person443" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-40-person443" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Directed to Will. Mason, Esq; at Neaton, near Swassham. Indorsed, 
               <persName id="t17611209-40-person444">
                  William 
                  Cooper 
               <interp inst="t17611209-40-person444" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-40-person444" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-40-person444" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>On his cross-examination he said, He did not know 
               <persName id="t17611209-40-person445">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17611209-40-person445" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-40-person445" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-40-person445" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; it might be his writing for aught he knew; and that half an hour after he had some doubts of its being a real bill, he advised the prisoner to go to Mr. Ridgeway with it, but that was with an intent to have him taken.</p>
               <p>Pinder and Hartley, two constables, confirmed that of securing the prisoner in the shop of Mr. Ridgeway.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17611209-40-verdict235" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611209-40-verdict235" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
