<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670909-41">
               <interp inst="t17670909-41" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670909-41" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670909-41" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670909"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670909-41" type="date" value="17670909"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670909-41-off247-c378" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-41-defend462 t17670909-41-off247 t17670909-41-verdict249"></join>
         
               <p>453. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17670909-41-defend462" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Guest 
                  <interp inst="t17670909-41-defend462" type="surname" value="Guest"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-defend462" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-defend462" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17670909-41-off247" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-off247" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-off247" type="offenceSubcategory" value="coiningOffences"></interp>
               high treason, in filing, impairing, lightening, and diminishing a guinea and a half guinea, the current coin of this kingdom, against the form of the statute
            </rs>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-41-person463">
                  John 
                  Leach 
               <interp inst="t17670909-41-person463" type="surname" value="Leach"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person463" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person463" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a teller at the Bank, I believe Mr. Guest has been a <rs id="t17670909-41-deflabel248" type="occupation">teller</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-41-defend462 t17670909-41-deflabel248"></join> there between two and three years.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever observe any conduct in him different from the rest?</p>
               <p>Leach. I have seen him pick new guineas from the old ones.</p>
               <p>Q. How long ago is that?</p>
               <p>Leach. Six months ago at least.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you attend to this after to see whether this was a frequent practice?</p>
               <p>Leach. I did, it was his frequent practice; it created a suspicion in my mind, and I communicated my suspicions to some others. On the 4th of July he paid some money to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17670909-41-person464">
                  Richard 
                  Still 
               <interp inst="t17670909-41-person464" type="surname" value="Still"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person464" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person464" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a servant to Mr. Corner, a dyer on the Bank-side, Southwark: at the time I saw Mr. Guest take some money out of a bag in the drawer, and put it among the rest on the table, and when he had paid the man, I went out after him, and asked him if his money was right, and begged the favour of him to walk into the pay-office, and let me tell the money over, which he did, and out of the thirty guineas there were three of them seemed to me to be newly filed; he said that was all the gold he had about him; I carried them three guineas into the hall, and showed them to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17670909-41-person465">
                  Robert 
                  Bell 
               <interp inst="t17670909-41-person465" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person465" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person465" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he looked at them; then I desired he would carry them up to Mr. Race the cashier.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go up with him?</p>
               <p>Leach. No, I did not then.</p>
               <p>Q. How did they appear to you to have been filed?</p>
               <p>Leach. They appeared to me as if the right milling had been taken off, and then filed.</p>
               <p>Q. You say, when he paid some money, you observed he took some out of a bag in the drawer, is not that what is commonly done?</p>
               <p>Leach. That is very seldom done in the Bank, it is sometimes done; this was not the whole of the money, but part; it was mixed with the money upon the table; we put our guineas in one drawer, silver in another, moidores in another, ports in another.</p>
               <p>Q. What was done with the three guineas?</p>
               <p>Leach. Mr. Race weighed them in my presence, they all three weighed fifteen pennyweights, nine grains; the weight should be sixteen pennyweights, four grains and a quarter.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the difference?</p>
               <p>Leach. Nineteen grains and a quarter, that is three shillings and a penny, according to the standard.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you weigh them separately?</p>
               <p>Leach. Yes, one of the guineas weighed five pennyweights, three grains, and nine-sixteenth, that was a guinea of the late King's; there were two of his present Majesty, one wants about ten-pence, the other about thirteen or fourteen-pence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-41-person466">
                  Richard 
                  Still 
               <interp inst="t17670909-41-person466" type="surname" value="Still"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person466" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person466" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I received thirty guineas at the Bank, on Saturday the 4th of July, of Mr. Guest.</p>
               <p>Leach. This is the person that I received the three guineas of.</p>
               <p>Still. As I was coming out of the Bank the gentleman met me, and desired I would step into the office, that they might look at the money that I received; I had no gold about me at that time, but the thirty guineas I received; I had only some half-pence, and eighteen-pence in silver: I told the gentleman he should look at them with all my<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176709090037"></xptr> heart; I turned them all out upon the table, he examined them, and looked at the edges of them, and selected three or four of them, and asked the gentleman on the other side the counter to lay down as many guineas as he had taken out, which he did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-41-person467">
                  Robert 
                  Bell 
               <interp inst="t17670909-41-person467" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person467" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person467" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a teller at the Bank; I remember, on Saturday the 4th of July, Mr. Leach brought me three guineas, which appeared to me to be recently field, two of his present Majesty's, and one of 
               <persName id="t17670909-41-person468">
                  George
               <interp inst="t17670909-41-person468" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person468" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the IId. I said, where did you get these; said he, I have just taken them of a gentleman in the office (that office is fifty yards from me;) I did not see him take them; he said, he had received them of the last witness (Mr. Still) who received them of Mr. Guest; I carried them to Mr. Race by Mr. Leach's desire, and Mr. Race, with great deliberation, looked at the edges of them in his custody; he closed them in a paper, and wrote 4th of July upon them; and said to me, you will carry these to Mr. Leach, and desire him to keep them in his custody; I delivered them back to Mr. Leach.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-41-person469">
                  Daniel 
                  Race 
               <interp inst="t17670909-41-person469" type="surname" value="Race"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person469" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person469" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About the 4th of July Mr. Bell brought three guineas to me; I looked at them very carefully, they appeared to me to be newly filed; I delivered them to Mr. Bell again.</p>
               <p>Q. to Leach. Produce the three guineas you mentioned.</p>
               <p>Leach. These are them, they are in the same state and condition as when I received them, only I have covered the paper with fresh paper (producing three guineas;) I delivered them to Mr. Bell, and received them back from him the same day.</p>
               <p>Race. I did receive them there or thereabouts, and returned them back to him the same day.</p>
               <p>Q. to Leach. Have you had them in your custody ever since?</p>
               <p>Leach. I have, they have not been out of my custody since; they have been locked up in my bag; I delivered them to Mr. Bell on the Saturday, to show them to Mr. Race.</p>
               <p>Bell. The three guineas that I received from Mr. Leach I showed to Mr. Race, and I received them back again, and delivered them to Mr. Leach again.</p>
               <p>Leach. They have never been lout of my custody, excepting these two instances.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-41-person470">
                  Jeremiah 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17670909-41-person470" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person470" type="given" value="Jeremiah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person470" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am one of the cashiers at the Bank.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you inform the court of the method of collecting the tellers bags?</p>
               <p>Thompson. The method is, every cashier, in his turn in waiting, takes the tellers bags, and locks them up in a particular place every night; every telle, has his name put to his bag, as they are all set down in a book.</p>
               <p>Q. Are the bags sealed?</p>
               <p>Thompson. No, they are not, the cashier in waiting that takes the bags, he finds so much money upon every bag, and we examine the book to see that they agree, that they make a balance, and then we lock them up, and they are delivered out the next morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Are there any body besides yourselves as a check?</p>
               <p>Thompson. There are two locks upon the door of the cupboard where they are locked in; the cashier in waiting has one, and some one of the indoor tellers have the other key; the cashier cannot come at these bags without the teller; that indoor teller is one that is in waiting for the night, and we keep a check for them all.</p>
               <p>Q. Who are the waiting in-door tellers?</p>
               <p>Thompson. They take it by turns.</p>
               <p>Q. Who were in waiting that night, the 4th of July?</p>
               <p>Thompson. Kemp and Lucas were; the key is kept by one of them, I do not know which of them; I received orders from Mr. Race, the chief cashier, to inspect into Mr. Guest's bag of the 4th of July, and one or two of the tellers to be with me; Mr. Lucas and Mr. Kemp were present; the whole sum was 1800 l. 16 s. 6 d. in several bags; there were five hundred pound bags tied together, thirteen bags in all; I was ordered to see if there were any new guineas fresh filed; Mr. Kemp and Mr. Lucas told the money over; there was one bag in which was forty guineas, which seemed fresher than the others did, upon the outside.</p>
               <p>Q. When you speak of fresher, what part do you mean?</p>
               <p>Thompson. I mean the edges.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you compared these to any of the other guineas in the other bags?</p>
               <p>Thompson. Yes, they were compared, and they all appeared fresher than the rest.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you closely inspect them?</p>
               <p>Thompson. We examined them with caution and deliberation.</p>
               <p>Q. Where have they been since?</p>
               <p>Thompson. They were sealed up by Mr. Kemp and myself, and have not been opened till this morning; they were kept locked up by the two<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176709090038"></xptr> keys I have mentioned, by the cashier and the teller.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-41-person471">
                  Thomas 
                  Luc 
               <interp inst="t17670909-41-person471" type="surname" value="Luc"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person471" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person471" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             as. I am a teller in the Bank, we take it by turns to be waiting tellers; I was in waiting on the 4th of July, and 
               <persName id="t17670909-41-person472">
                  Thomas 
                  Kemp 
               <interp inst="t17670909-41-person472" type="surname" value="Kemp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person472" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person472" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was the other,</p>
               <p>Q. In what manner do you take care of the money?</p>
               <p>Lucas. We receive it from their own hands; it is in my custody from that time till I deliver it to a porter, who puts it in a box, and from thence it is wheeled into the treasury; we found in a bag of Mr. Guest's forty guineas.</p>
               <p>C. for prisoner. I admit that with all my heart, that these forty guineas were found in Mr. Guest's bag.</p>
               <p>Q. to Lucas. How did they appear?</p>
               <p>Lucas. They appeared much fresher on the edges than other guineas.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-41-person473">
                  Thomas 
                  Kemp 
               <interp inst="t17670909-41-person473" type="surname" value="Kemp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person473" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person473" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a teller at the Bank; I was there that evening, I examined these forty guineas.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you made any particular observation on them?</p>
               <p>Kemp. They appeared to me to be all fresh filed on the edges?</p>
               <p>Q. Did you weigh them.</p>
               <p>Kemp. I did; there was a deficiency from about 8 d. to 14 d. one with the other, I cannot be certain to a penny; there was a deficiency in every one of them.</p>
               <p>Mr. Sewallis. I belong to the Bank; I made a search in the house of Mr. Guest in Broad-street-buildings, in the month of July last; in a two pair of stairs room was a mahogany nest of drawers, the top of which was forced open in the presence of Mr. Hall, Mr. Humberton, and my Lord-Mayor's officer; there we found a vice, files, and other things.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-41-person474">
                  Thomas 
                  Humberton 
               <interp inst="t17670909-41-person474" type="surname" value="Humberton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person474" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person474" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a servant in the Bank; I was present at a search made at Mr. Guest's house; I asked him, while he was at the Bank, for his keys of his book case and a cupboard; I told him I was going to search his house; this was on Monday the 6th of July; there were warrants out against him; he said he did not know what authority any body had to search his house, and refused to deliver his keys; I found all the things there; they were under seal till before the Grand Jury yesterday, and they are now under the seals of the Grand Jury; they were opened, and produced in court. (Note, They were such as were at and proper to effect or contribute to the commission of the particular offence with which he was charged in the indictment on which he was tried; and a bag with 100 guineas, and two bags of gold filings.)</p>
               <p>Humberton. We found these things under the flap of a small chest of drawers; there were three drawers on each side, and a drawer went quite cross at the bottom, about four inches deep; as it opened at the top, a flap before fell down, and there was a skin lay at the bottom, fastened to the back part, and a hole in the front part of it, to fasten to a button on his waistcoat, in the manner the jewellers use them; in that leather lay all the utensils, and the smallest parcel of gold dust loose, and another parcel in a paper by it; and another (the largest parcel) in a secret place under the leather, in a place about six or eight inches square, under the middle of the leather; we observed there was some yellow stuff on the teeth of the file.</p>
               <p>C. for prisoner. We do not controvert the finding these things.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the weight of the gold filings?</p>
               <p>Humberton. The weight is four pounds, eleven ounces, and nineteen pennyweights; that is the weight of all the filings together.</p>
               <p>Q. How much was in that that was concealed under the leather?</p>
               <p>Humberton. That was the greatest quantity; that was three pounds, seven ounces, and twelve pennyweights; that seemed to be very clean, cleanes than the other two parcels; the other parcel next to that weighed one pound, three ounces, and two pennyweights; the inferior parcel is one ounce, five pennyweights; that was loose upon the leather, with a good deal of dirt in it; I have delivered some of each parcel to Mr. Chamberlaine.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-41-person475">
                  Joseph 
                  Nichols 
               <interp inst="t17670909-41-person475" type="surname" value="Nichols"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person475" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person475" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am one of the moniers in the Mint, that is, one of the coiners.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you been in it?</p>
               <p>Nichols. I have been employed twenty years in it, apprenticeship and all.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the use of these tools here produced?</p>
               <p>Nichols. I do; here is one very capable of milling money round the edges.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at these three guineas. (The three guineas were part of the thirty the prisoner paid to 
               <persName id="t17670909-41-person476">
                  Richard 
                  Still 
               <interp inst="t17670909-41-person476" type="surname" value="Still"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person476" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person476" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .)</p>
               <p>Nichols. These are filed guineas, they have had a fresh edging put upon them.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at these guineas; (the hundred guineas found in the prisoner's drawer, put into a bat.)</p>
               <p>Nichols. (He looks at several of them.) These are all artificial edges; I do not see one but what is; they all appear to have fresh edges on them.</p>
               <p>Q. Now look at the forty guineas found in his bag.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176709090039"></xptr>Nichols. (He looks at them.) There is not one of these, as I can perceive, but what is fresh filed; all I have seen might be edged with such an instrument as this produced; they were not done in the Mint at the Tower.</p>
               <p>Mr. Chamberlaine. These three guineas (producing them) are three guineas which Mr. Nichols put edges on in my presence, with this instrument found in the prisoner's room; they were quite plain before.</p>
               <p>Q. to Nichols. Compare these with the others found in the prisoner's drawer.</p>
               <p>Nichols. (He looks at divers of then, and compares them together.) They are so near alike, that I believe they were all done with the same tool.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you in the branch of milling?</p>
               <p>Nichols. I am not, that is a particular office.</p>
               <p>C. for Crown. They in that office cannot be called upon to give evidence how money is milled; they are strictly forbid it.</p>
               <p>Humberton. I took out three small parcels of filings out of the three parcels, and delivered them to Mr. Chamberlaine.</p>
               <p>Chamberlaine. I delivered the same quantity of filings which I received of Mr. Humberton to Mr. Lucas.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-41-person477">
                  Joseph 
                  Lucas 
               <interp inst="t17670909-41-person477" type="surname" value="Lucas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person477" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person477" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I received three parcels of gold filings of Mr. Chamberlaine to assay; I assayed them separately, and found them agreeable to the standard of our money; that parcel that was said to be found upon the leather was mixed with a great deal of dirt, I was obliged to wash and dry it; when I had done that, upon the assay, I found it deviated a little from the true standard, but within the limits of our money; I think it might come from the filings of our guineas; the others were very exact to the standard.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-41-person478">
                  Samuel 
                  Lee 
               <interp inst="t17670909-41-person478" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person478" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person478" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a teller at the Bank; I think it was the latter end of March the prisoner had a bar of gold; it was, I believe, between five and six inches long, under two inches wide, and better than half an inch deep; I asked him how he came by it; he said he had it from Holland; I had it in my hand; I said I thought it was not like a regular bar of gold, it had a deal of copper on the back of it; he said it must be filed off, and that all bars of gold were so.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see bars of gold at the Bank before?</p>
               <p>Lee. I have, but never saw any with such scum on them as that had.</p>
               <p>Q. How often have you seen bars of gold?</p>
               <p>Lee. I have seen bars of gold scores of times before I went into the Bank.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-41-person479">
                  Thomas 
                  Troughton 
               <interp inst="t17670909-41-person479" type="surname" value="Troughton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person479" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person479" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a jeweller; I have known the prisoner four years; I sold an ingot of gold for him the 12th of June last, there was about forty-eight ounces of it. I sold another ingot of gold for him about six months ago, that weighed forty-six ounces, or thereabouts.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you get the price of standard gold for these ingots? </p>
               <p>Troughton. I got thereabouts.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination. </p>
               <p>Q. Have not you a great many ingots come from abroad?</p>
               <p>Troughton. We have, from different places.</p>
               <p>Q. Did this raise any suspicion in your mind at that? </p>
               <p>Troughton No, it did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it standard? </p>
               <p>Troughton. All gold ought to be standard, there is bad and good gold. </p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any appearance of copper or filing?</p>
               <p>Troughton No, none at all; this appeared like other bars of gold that came from abroad; I understood it as such.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did they appear to be?</p>
               <p>Troughton. I took them to be about a foot long; there are various lengths of them; they come from abroad.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-41-person480">
                  Esther 
                  Collins 
               <interp inst="t17670909-41-person480" type="surname" value="Collins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person480" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person480" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I did live servant with Mr. Guest between four and five months; I left his service about the latter end of August, or beginning of September, about a year ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any thing in your master's behaviour?</p>
               <p>E. Collins. Some little time before I came away, he used to be in the back parlour.</p>
               <p>Q. How long before you came away?</p>
               <p>E. Collins. About a month before.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the furniture of that back parlour.</p>
               <p>E. Collins. A desk and half a dozen chairs?</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a desk?</p>
               <p>E. Collins. The same sort as other people's, a writing-desk; I saw it open one Sunday, when Mr. and Mrs. Guest went out a walking; he left his book-case open, I never saw the inside of it before; I went into the room to take his clothes away; the top being open, I looked into it: there I saw a glass cup with some yellow dust in it, and by the cup was a file, much like this that lies here.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I am innocent of the thing laid to my charge.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-41-person481">
                  Robert 
                  Featley 
               <interp inst="t17670909-41-person481" type="surname" value="Featley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person481" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person481" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an optical instrument maker</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this tool; (he takes it in his hand.)</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176709090040"></xptr>Featley. This is fit for various other uses where the edges require milling.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you milled edges to things in your way?</p>
               <p>Featley. We have, to scores of optical instruments; this is proper for several particulars, microscopes, and things in our way.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see any of these kind of instruments before in your trade?</p>
               <p>Featley. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-41-person482">
                  John 
                  Hunter 
               <interp inst="t17670909-41-person482" type="surname" value="Hunter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person482" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person482" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am conversant in mathematical instruments and clock-work both.</p>
               <p>Q. To what purpose is such an instrument as this applicable?</p>
               <p>Hunter. We have several milled nuts, both in the mathematical and clock way; this is more useful than any thing we use, for any thing that will go into it; it is as great an improvement as ever I saw; the edges or jestering nuts for regulating clocks might be done with this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-41-person483">
                  George 
                  Hodgson 
               <interp inst="t17670909-41-person483" type="surname" value="Hodgson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person483" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person483" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a cock-maker; I can make this instrument useful in several things that I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Mention some of them.</p>
               <p>Hodgson. For milling the screws, for regulating pendulums, that is the screw at the bottom to raise the ball, to make it go faster and slower.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-41-person484">
                  Alexander 
                  Sharp 
               <interp inst="t17670909-41-person484" type="surname" value="Sharp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person484" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person484" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; I took lodgings at Mr. Guest's, in December, 1764, and lodged in his house six months; I had very little opportunity of knowing him much; I know none of his connections so as to know his character; I very seldom was with him.</p>
               <p>Mr. Greathead. I have known him since November last; before I went to lodge with him, I had a very good character of him; he bore a very good character as far as I could find.</p>
               <p>Mr. Mowbray. I have known him from his infancy; he bears the character of a very honest man; his family is in the greatest repute in the town he was born; I never heard any accusation against him till this charge.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-41-person485">
                  William 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17670909-41-person485" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person485" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person485" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My knowing and having acquaintance with him commenced when he was an apprentice at Worcester; the universal character that he has bore has been that of a diligent, honest, sober man; I knew his father and grandfather; I have had connections with them all my life-time; I am one of his securities since he came to be in the Bank; every body that had any connections with him have the same opinion with me; this thing was of the utmost astonishment to me when I heard of it; his father was a minister.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-41-person486">
                  John 
                  Eldridge 
               <interp inst="t17670909-41-person486" type="surname" value="Eldridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person486" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person486" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about five years; he is a very sober, diligent, honest man; a man that I understood bore as fair a character as any man in the kingdom; I would as soon have trusted him as any man in the kingdom, from the goodness of his character.</p>
               <p>Sir 
               <persName id="t17670909-41-person487">
                  Thomas 
                  Antwistle 
               <interp inst="t17670909-41-person487" type="surname" value="Antwistle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person487" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person487" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him three years; he was always a very honest man as far as I knew; he has been so reputed by every body in the neighbourhood.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-41-person488">
                  John 
                  Topham 
               <interp inst="t17670909-41-person488" type="surname" value="Topham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person488" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person488" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him twenty years; he had a very good character; I never heard to the contrary till this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-41-person489">
                  William 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17670909-41-person489" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person489" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-person489" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him between four and five years; I always looked upon him as a very worthy honest man; I never heard to the contrary till this affair.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17670909-41-verdict249" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-verdict249" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17670909-41-punish250" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670909-41-punish250" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-41-defend462 t17670909-41-punish250"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He moved an arrest of judgment, but it was overruled by the court.</p>
            </div1>
