<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17661217-34">
               <interp inst="t17661217-34" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-34" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-34" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17661217"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-34" type="date" value="17661217"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17661217-34-off179-c271" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-34-defend348 t17661217-34-off179 t17661217-34-verdict184"></join>
         
               <p>43. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17661217-34-defend348" type="defendantName">
                     Mary
                      M'Cormack
                  <interp inst="t17661217-34-defend348" type="surname" value="M'Cormack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-34-defend348" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-34-defend348" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17661217-34-deflabel178" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-34-defend348 t17661217-34-deflabel178"></join>, was indicted (together with 
               <persName id="t17661217-34-person349">
                  Anne 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17661217-34-person349" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-34-person349" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-34-person349" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             not taken) for <rs id="t17661217-34-off179" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-34-off179" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-34-off179" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing a silk purse, value 2 d. two gold rings for mourning, value 20 s. one 13 s. and 6 d. piece, twenty-six guineas, and four quarter guineas, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17661217-34-victim351" type="victimName">
                           Eleanor 
                           Bird 
                        <interp inst="t17661217-34-victim351" type="surname" value="Bird"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17661217-34-victim351" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17661217-34-victim351" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-34-off179 t17661217-34-victim351"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   
                     <rs id="t17661217-34-viclabel180" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-34-victim351 t17661217-34-viclabel180"></join>, privately from her person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17661217-34-cd181" type="crimeDate">Nov. 9</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-34-off179 t17661217-34-cd181"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-34-person352">
                  Eleanor 
                  Bird 
               <interp inst="t17661217-34-person352" type="surname" value="Bird"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-34-person352" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-34-person352" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I <rs id="t17661217-34-viclabel182" type="occupation">keep a public-house</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-34-victim351 t17661217-34-viclabel182"></join> in <placeName id="t17661217-34-crimeloc183">Well-street, near Well-close-square</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17661217-34-crimeloc183" type="placeName" value="Well-street, near Well-close-square"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17661217-34-crimeloc183" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-34-off179 t17661217-34-crimeloc183"></join>; the prisoner used to come sometimes for a dram. On Sunday morning, Nov. 9, she and 
               <persName id="t17661217-34-person353">
                  Anne 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17661217-34-person353" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-34-person353" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-34-person353" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came in for a dram at the bar, betwixt eight and nine o'clock; I went to serve them; a woman came and asked for change for a 5 s. and 3 d. piece; as soon as she had her change she went out, after that I went to serve the prisoner and White, I put the 5 s. and 3 d. in my purse; there were twentysix guineas in it, a 13 s. and 6 d. and four quarter guineas, besides that which I put in; it was a green silk knit purse, they might see the money through it; they were standing close by me while I gave the change; I wound my purse over my fingers while I was serving them; White said she was in a hurry to be gone; then I went out of the bar, and put my purse in my left side pocket; as I was going to the fire side they both followed me to the fire side, they came on my left side; while I was putting out a pennyworth of purl for a man that stood by, I was pushed down against the man; I asked the women what was the meaning of that, and said if they could not stand quiet to go out of the house; it was done by the prisoner pushing White against me; the prisoner said, I ask your pardon, I hit my toe against the stove, and had like to have fallen myself; the man prevented my falling by putting his arm out; I went into the kitchen, and never went into the drinking room all that day after; I never missed my purse till about three in the afternoon;<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176612170027"></xptr> I am sure I put my purse in my pocket, for I felt my snuff-box in my pocket at the same time; I never saw my purse, money, or rings since; the prisoner was taken up on the 10th of November, and charged with aiding and assisting in robbing me; before the Justice she said she did not take it, but knew who did, and she would tell the next day; she was committed that night, and when she was brought back to be examined again, she denied knowing any thing of the affair; I heard her own in New Prison, she knew who robbed me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your pocket on the outside your cloaths?</p>
               <p>E. Bird. I had only my gown over it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-34-person354">
                  Sarah 
                  Dobbs 
               <interp inst="t17661217-34-person354" type="surname" value="Dobbs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-34-person354" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-34-person354" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mrs. Bird, I saw the prisoner and two other women come in; they asked for a pint of purl, I went and draw'd it; the prisoner looked in my face, and said there is no uproar yet, there is nothing missed; I said, what should be missed; she said there are many things lost that are not missed; this was about a quarter of an hour after they had been in for the drams; I saw them come in for the drams, and saw my mistress tie up her purse, and put it into her pocket as she went along; I saw the prisoner push White against her, and push her against a man (a stranger;) as my mistress was falling, the prisoner stepped towards her, and the man catched my mistress in his arms.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-34-person355">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Wallis 
               <interp inst="t17661217-34-person355" type="surname" value="Wallis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-34-person355" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-34-person355" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When the prisoner was brought to be examined, and was in at the City of Carolina, a public-house in Rosemary-lane, on the day after the robbery, she said she wanted to speak with me, and took me out into the yard; she delivered to me two 5 s. and 3 d. pieces and a golden guinea, and desired me to buy her an under petticoat and a cap, and bring them to her in New Prison; I said I never was there in my life, and I delivered them into her hand again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-34-person356">
                  Robert 
                  Clavering 
               <interp inst="t17661217-34-person356" type="surname" value="Clavering"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-34-person356" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-34-person356" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I asked the prisoner several questions after she was committed concerning the robbery; she said she did not rob her herself, but she knew who did; I then asked her if she had any of the money; she said that was best known to herself; I asked her if she saw the rings; she asked me who I was, I did not resolve her; she said I'll tell you nothing more, but if you'll come to-morrow, I'll tell you every thing of it, but I'll tell no more to day.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-34-person357">
                  John 
                  Delaney 
               <interp inst="t17661217-34-person357" type="surname" value="Delaney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-34-person357" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-34-person357" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was with the prisoner when going from the Justices, she seemed to be very much in liquor; she took me by the arm, and asked me what I would have her do in this affair; I said what affair; she said I was standing by the same time Mrs. Bird was robbed, and I saw her robbed of about 19 or 20 l. and some gold rings; would you have me confess; I said, I tell you what I'd have you do; if you have any of the money that is left, call Mrs. Bird on one side and give it her, and ask her pardon, and I dare say she will not hurt you; she then answered she would say nothing at all, and said she believed that was the best way; I believe she would have said more, but the officer said, it is now too late to say any thing; she said she had none of the money left.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner to prosecutrix. How many people were in your house at the time you served us?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. There were (only the man a stranger,) the prisoner White, and myself.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I went into this house with 
               <persName id="t17661217-34-person358">
                  Nan 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17661217-34-person358" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-34-person358" type="given" value="Nan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-34-person358" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , we had a dram at the bar, after that a pint of purl, we stood by the sire; I went out and fetched some bread and cheese, and if this thing was done, it was done when I was out, for I know nothing of it; I am caught at a nonplus, I have no body here to my character.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17661217-34-verdict184" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-34-verdict184" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
