<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640912-40">
               <interp inst="t17640912-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-40" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640912"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-40" type="date" value="17640912"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640912-40-off229-c292" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-40-defend367 t17640912-40-off229 t17640912-40-verdict233"></join>
         
               <p>521. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17640912-40-defend367" type="defendantName">
                     George 
                     Williams 
                  <interp inst="t17640912-40-defend367" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-defend367" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-defend367" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17640912-40-off229" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-off229" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-off229" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one cloth coat, value 20 s. one sattin waistcoat, value 5 s. one pair of leather breeches, value 20 s. two pair of worsted stockings, value 2 s. one hat, value 7 s. one cardinal, value 5 s. and one crape tail of a gown, value 1 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640912-40-victim369" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Yeoman 
                        <interp inst="t17640912-40-victim369" type="surname" value="Yeoman"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640912-40-victim369" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640912-40-victim369" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-40-off229 t17640912-40-victim369"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling house of 
                     <persName id="t17640912-40-person370">
                        Ann 
                        Baker 
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-person370" type="surname" value="Baker"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640912-40-person370" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640912-40-person370" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , widow
            </rs>, <rs id="t17640912-40-cd230" type="crimeDate">July 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-40-off229 t17640912-40-cd230"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-40-person371">
                  James 
                  Yeoman 
               <interp inst="t17640912-40-person371" type="surname" value="Yeoman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-person371" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-person371" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I <rs id="t17640912-40-viclabel231" type="occupation">work for a refiner in Foster-lane</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-40-victim369 t17640912-40-viclabel231"></join>, and lodge in the house of the widow Baker, in <placeName id="t17640912-40-crimeloc232">Crown-court, St. Martin's-le-Grand</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640912-40-crimeloc232" type="placeName" value="Crown-court, St. Martin's-le-Grand"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640912-40-crimeloc232" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-40-off229 t17640912-40-crimeloc232"></join>. On the 30th of July I left my wife in my room, after breakfast at nine o'clock, and was fetched home from my work; my wife was lying for dead; I took her up and laid her on the bed; then I went to see the prisoner, whom I was told had robbed me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-40-person372">
                  Hannah 
                  Yeoman 
               <interp inst="t17640912-40-person372" type="surname" value="Yeoman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-person372" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-person372" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the prosecutor. My husband went to work at nine o'clock, and left me at home: I went out about one, and locked the door, and returned, I believe, about a quarter before two. Running up stairs, out came a man from my room; he shut to my door: I catch'd hold of him, and screamed out; I believe he drove me down stairs: I remember no more. This was on the Monday, and I received such injury, I remember nothing till the Saturday: it deprived me of my understanding. When I was sensible, I found all the things separated from where I left them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-40-person373">
                  Ann 
                  Baker 
               <interp inst="t17640912-40-person373" type="surname" value="Baker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-person373" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-person373" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in St. Martin's-le-Grand: the prosecutor and his wife lodge at my house. On the 30th of July he was gone to work; and she went out about one o'clock, and came back in about half an hour; I went up stairs, and found the things mentioned in the indictment scattered about, some on the stairs, and some in the passage. I did not see the man; he was got off. The woman was hurt, and did not come to herself for three or four days: she was thrown down into the passage, into a great thoroughfare. I found their room door open. (The goods produced, and deposed to by the prosecutor and his wife.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-40-person374">
                  William 
                  Hatchet 
               <interp inst="t17640912-40-person374" type="surname" value="Hatchet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-person374" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-person374" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a barber, and live in Crown-court, facing Mrs. Baker's house. On the 30th of July, I was going to the Horse-shoe alehouse, to get my master a pint of beer, about a quarter before two o'clock: I heard Mrs. Yeoman cry out for help, on the stairs, in Mrs. Baker's house: I stopped to see what was the matter. I saw the prisoner at the bar push her down stairs; she lay as if she was dead, with no manner of life to be perceived in her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him push her down?</p>
               <p>Hatchet. I could see his hands somewhere about her breast and neck: he jumped over the bannisters of the stairs, and ran: I cried, Stop thief: he ran directly close to me. I took up the woman.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the man so as to know him?</p>
               <p>Hatchet. I did: I took notice of his face and clothes very plain; he had on the very same clothes as now; only he had no neckcloth on his neck: I think his hat was cocked up all round: the prisoner was pursued; I did not run after him;<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176409120029"></xptr> he was taken in about four or five minutes in Angel-street: they came presently to me, to let me know that he was taken: I met them bringing him up St. Martin's-le-Grand; there were many people about him; I knew him directly from all the rest, by his face and clothes: I am certain the prisoner is the man; I saw the constable search him: there were twelve keys found in his waistcoat pockets: (Twelve chamber-door keys produced in court.) these are them. We took him before Sir 
               <persName id="t17640912-40-person375">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17640912-40-person375" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-person375" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-person375" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            : Sir John asked him what trade he was? he said he was a thief. Sir John asked him how long he had been one? he said, not above seven years. Sir John asked him where he was born? he said he did not know. Sir John asked him what countryman he was? he said he did not know.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-40-person376">
                  Francis 
                  Flury 
               <interp inst="t17640912-40-person376" type="surname" value="Flury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-person376" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-person376" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a fan-stick maker. I live in Newgate-street, and went into Maiden-lane to buy some files at the ironmongers, on the 30th of July last; returning home, going up Angel-street, somebody in St. Martin's-le-Grand called Stop him, stop him; I turned about and saw the prisoner come running; he cry'd, Stop him, stop him: seeing there was nobody but he and I, I thought it must be either myself or the prisoner that must be stopped; seeing the people in a body turning up out of St. Martin's-le-Grand, I turned short, and laid fast hold on the prisoner: he went to strike at me with his right hand, but he was so out of breath that he could not. Then I let him go, and ran after him, and got hold of him again, and held him till the people came to my assistance. Hatchet came up among the rest; he said, this is the man. I saw the prisoner searched afterwards, and twelve keys taken out of his pockets. I was before Sir 
               <persName id="t17640912-40-person377">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17640912-40-person377" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-person377" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-person377" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; he asked him what countryman he was? he said he did not know. He asked him where he was born? he said he did not know. He asked him what trade he was? he said he was a thief. He asked him how long he had been one? he said about seven years, or seven years, I don't know which.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-40-person378">
                  Andrew 
                  Weggoe 
               <interp inst="t17640912-40-person378" type="surname" value="Weggoe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-person378" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-person378" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming up the passage, and the prisoner jumped over the bannisters and ran against me: I was behind the first evidence when he called stop thief: I saw him after he was taken, and twelve keys taken out of his pockets: this was in about four or five minutes after he ran against me. I was before Sir 
               <persName id="t17640912-40-person379">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17640912-40-person379" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-person379" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-person379" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; Sir John asked him what trade he was? if he had any friends? where he served his time? he said he did not know. He asked him how long he had been in this thieving way? he said about seven years.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear him say he was a thief?</p>
               <p>Weggoe. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-40-person380">
                  James 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17640912-40-person380" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-person380" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-person380" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable; I was at the Black Lion; I heard the words Stop thief; I came to the door and saw Williams run by me as fast as ever he could: I went after him, but could not run so fast as he: when I came to the corner of Angel-street, the mob were bringing him back: I took him in charge, and carried him to the round-house; I searched his pockets; there I found twelve keys loose: I heard the Justice ask him what business he was of? he said, no trade. The Justice asked him how long he had gone on in that way of life? he said, not above seven years. He asked him if he had any accomplices? he said, he knew some, but he would discover none of them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-40-person381">
                  Mary 
                  Riley 
               <interp inst="t17640912-40-person381" type="surname" value="Riley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-person381" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-person381" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodge at 
               <persName id="t17640912-40-person382">
                  Ann 
                  Baker 
               <interp inst="t17640912-40-person382" type="surname" value="Baker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-person382" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-person382" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's. I was out of the house about an hour, at a neighbour's: I came to see what was the matter, hearing a great out-cry. I saw Mrs. Yeoman lying on the floor; I asked what was the matter? they told me there had been a thief in her room that had knocked her down, and he was run down St. Martin's-le-Grand: I saw the prisoner's back, but soon lost fight of him; he might be upwards of an hundred yards from me, running as hard as he could. I went and turned up Angel-street; there I saw the people had hold of him: he dropt a bunch of keys; I saw them in the corner of his frock, and saw him drop them; I took them up; ( Fourteen keys produced in court.) those are like them, I delivered them out of my hand.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. What are your goods worth?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I have wore the cloth coat but very little; it cost me above 3 l.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it now worth half the money?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. It is; the sattin waistcoat is worth a crown; the leather breeches cost me 25 s. and they are not a shilling the worse for wearing. I have no doubt but they are now worth 20 s. the stocking are worth above a shilling; the hat is worth 7 s.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Yeoman. The cloth cardinal is worth a crown.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing of the things.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640912-40-verdict233" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-verdict233" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17640912-40-punish234" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-40-punish234" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-40-defend367 t17640912-40-punish234"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
