<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17601204-25">
               <interp inst="t17601204-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17601204-25" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17601204-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17601204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17601204-25" type="date" value="17601204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17601204-25-off152-c222" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601204-25-defend278 t17601204-25-off152 t17601204-25-verdict157"></join>
         
               <p>28. (M) 
               
                  <persName id="t17601204-25-defend278" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Burch 
                  <interp inst="t17601204-25-defend278" type="surname" value="Burch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-25-defend278" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-25-defend278" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for <rs id="t17601204-25-off152" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17601204-25-off152" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-25-off152" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he, on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17601204-25-victim280" type="victimName">
                           Giles 
                           Bentley 
                        <interp inst="t17601204-25-victim280" type="surname" value="Bentley"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17601204-25-victim280" type="given" value="Giles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17601204-25-victim280" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601204-25-off152 t17601204-25-victim280"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear, and danger of his life, and taking from his person one silver watch, val. 40 s. three linnen shirts, value 10 s. one pair of garters, one linnen handkerchief, one pair of leather shoes, three pair of worsted stockings, and eight shillings, in money numbered, the property of the said Giles, and against his will
            </rs>, <rs id="t17601204-25-cd153" type="crimeDate">Dec. 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601204-25-off152 t17601204-25-cd153"></join> ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601204-25-person281">
                  Giles 
                  Bentley 
               <interp inst="t17601204-25-person281" type="surname" value="Bentley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-25-person281" type="given" value="Giles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-25-person281" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17601204-25-viclabel154" type="occupation">soldier in the guards</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601204-25-victim280 t17601204-25-viclabel154"></join>; 
               <persName id="t17601204-25-person282">
                  William 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17601204-25-person282" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-25-person282" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-25-person282" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and the prisoner at the bar, and two other <rs id="t17601204-25-deflabel155" type="occupation">soldier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601204-25-defend278 t17601204-25-deflabel155"></join>s, had been tempting me to desert: last Tuesday night Webb and I set out together: going along the road it was very dark; I perceiv'd somebody behind me; I said, Here is somebody behind: we went but a very little way, before a man came up, and knock'd me down with a stick. Webb went from me. I had the watch, money, and things, in my pocket, that are mentioned in the indictment, and four guineas more; I put them in my breeches, and in the struggle they slipp'd down, so that the man could not find them: he took my watch, two half-crowns, and six shillings, and my cloaths: he said, I know you have more money about you. I struggled with him, but found I could not manage him: he beat me so that I lost the fight of one eye above a day, it is very bad now; then he left me.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>Bentley. This was <placeName id="t17601204-25-crimeloc156">near Shepherd's bush</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17601204-25-crimeloc156" type="placeName" value="near Shepherd's bush"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17601204-25-crimeloc156" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601204-25-off152 t17601204-25-crimeloc156"></join>; it might be somewhat after seven o'clock: he told me he knew I had more money about me: I knew him by his tongue to be the prisoner at the bar. I had bought this watch of him but about three weeks before, and he saw my money then, when I paid him for it. Webb had some of my things in his pocket. Then I was forced to get a lodging<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176012040037"></xptr> as I could; and being hurt and bruised, my head was giddy, I hardly knew where I was. I came to London the next morning, and went to my quarters at Westminster, where I found the prisoner and Webb, and told them how it was, and that I had a great suspicion of both of them. They seemed to be greatly surprized, and were for going to the place where I was robb'd: then I went to the place where I had taken lodgings, and told the man of the house (whose name is Murray) what had happened. He went up stairs, and found my shirts, garters, handkerchief, shoes and stockings, that I had been robb'd of, in Burch's brother's room.</p>
               <p>Q. Was his brother a soldier?</p>
               <p>Bentley. No, he was not.</p>

               <p>Q. How long have you been acquainted with the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Bentley. Ever since Michaelmas; we had been together ever since we inlisted: then Mr. Murray went, and told my serjeant of it: we took the prisoner up last Wednesday morning; he was search'd, but nothing found upon him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the watch found upon him?</p>
               <p>Bentley. No, it was not: the prisoner had not his regimentals on when I was robb'd, it was a light coloured coat. Before the justice he said he changed his coat that day with another soldier, that was going to inlist a recruit.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you see his face?</p>
               <p>Bentley. No, I could not, then I thought there was a plot betwixt Webb and him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner lodge in the same house as his brother did?</p>
               <p>Bentley. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Were his quarters searched?</p>
               <p>Bentley. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober?</p>
               <p>Bentley. I was, and I know that the prisoner has the very same voice as the man that knock'd me down and robb'd me.</p>
               <p>Serjeant Trigg. On Wednesday, about 11 o'clock, Mr. Murray (at whose house the prisoner was found, and where his brother lodges) came to me, and acquainted me that a recruit belonging to me had been very much beat, and robb'd.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has the prosecutor been amongst you?</p>
               <p>Trigg. About five weeks: he came out of Gloucestershire.</p>
               <p>Q. What regiment of guards do you belong to?</p>
               <p>Trigg. To the third regiment. I went with Mr. Murray, and there found Bentley, the prisoner, and Webb. I asked Bentley how he came beat in such a manner; he took me on one side, and told me that Webb had advised him to desert eight or nine days before, and that Webb and he went on the road betwixt Tyburn and Acton, and there he was knock'd down and robb'd by a person, which he believed to be the prisoner at the bar: those were three recruits, that came up to town together.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he was positive to the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Trigg. No, he did not. The landlord of the house told me there were things found in the prisoner's room which Bentley had said he had been robb'd of, before the landlord found them; then I went, and charged the prisoner as my prisoner: a constable came, and we took him to a justice of the peace in the Strand, with the goods that were found. There Bentley swore to them. The defence the prisoner made was, that he had changed his coat with a man who was going to inlist a recruit in Hedge-lane: that was a coat found in his brother's room, bloody, a white coat, of the prisoner's.</p>
               <p>Q. to Bentley. Was you bloody after this treatment?</p>
               <p>Bentley. I was very bloody.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I lent my coat, which was a white one, to a soldier, to go and inlist a recruit, and I walk'd a little way with him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601204-25-person283">
                  David 
                  Murray 
               <interp inst="t17601204-25-person283" type="surname" value="Murray"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-25-person283" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-25-person283" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner's brother lodged with me: the prosecutor came to my house last Wednesday morning, very much bruised and bloody; one of his eyes was quite shut up, so that he could not see out of it: he enquired after Webb, and told how he had been robbed, and in what manner: after he had told me I recollected that on the Tuesday in the afternoon, about four o'clock, I saw Webb and the prisoner go out together; the prisoner had a white coat on, with metal buttons, and a large stick in his hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Murray. I live in Westminster. I found that Webb had had a young man sent for him from an alehouse hard by, that Wednesday morning, about a quarter after ten. I let the person in to call him.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was Webb then?</p>
               <p>Murray. He was then at his lodgings in my house; I can't positively tell when he came in: he went over to the alehouse when the young woman came. I heard there were some stains of blood on the person that sent for him. When the prisoner went out on the Tuesday afternoon there were no stains of blood, but there were the next morning, and they were done over with chalk; that made me me go up to the room where his brother lodg'd: the brother told me the prisoner lodged with him that night. I had left the door for Webb to come in, so I know not what time either came in. I went up into the brother's room, the key<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176012040038"></xptr> was in the door, there was a coat lying in a careless manner on the bed; I turned it over, and saw spots of blood all chalked over: I saw a pair of shoes and stockings all dirty; then I went to a pair of drawers, in one drawer I found a shirt, bloody about the wrists, the blood seemed fresh upon it; I found the linnen and things that Bentley had said he had been robbed of; then I put a padlock upon the door, and went for a constable; he not being at home, I went to the justice, and told him the affair: he bid me take care of the man: then I came home, and carried up Bentley to see the things; he said they were his, and what he had been robbed of over-night. [The bloody coat and shirt produced, also the things found in the prisoner's brother's room deposed to by the prosecutor, as part of the things he was robbed of that night.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601204-25-person284">
                  Sarah 
                  Jenkins 
               <interp inst="t17601204-25-person284" type="surname" value="Jenkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-25-person284" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-25-person284" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . A young man came to the alehouse where I live, opposite to Mr. Murray's; he sent me for Webb: he came to the young man, I believe it was the prisoner at the bar, it was like him. This was about ten o'clock on the Tuesday night. Mr. Murray told me he thought Webb was gone to bed, but Webb soon came down stairs. They went out directly, I do not know where they went, and we immediately made our door fast.</p>
               <p>Q. to Murray. How far is Shepherd's Bush from Westminster?</p>
               <p>Murray. It is about five miles from my house.</p>

               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I lent my coat to a soldier with a great deal of swearing. I would not at first, till he followed me down to the Horse-guards. He said the fellow looked a little shy. There came another man up, and said, We are going to enlist a recruit, and we have a suspicion he is a deserter, and if he is, you shall have share of the money. I lent him my white coat, and he let me put his red coat on, and I did not see him for three hours after: when he came back again I gave him his coat, and he gave me mine, and he gave me those things, and said, if I would take care of them, he would come in the morning, and pay me for my trouble: here is 
               <persName id="t17601204-25-person285">
                  Sarah 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17601204-25-person285" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-25-person285" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-25-person285" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             saw me with a soldier's coat on, between six and seven that night.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. What time did you and Webb set out that night from Westminster?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. We set out between 5 and 6 o'clock.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601204-25-person286">
                  Sarah 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17601204-25-person286" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-25-person286" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-25-person286" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the prisoner in a street in Westminster, as I was going of an errand, between six and seven o'clock that night: he asked me if my husband was at home: I said no, and he went directly back again; I cannot tell where he went.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is your husband?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601204-25-person287">
                  Sarah 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17601204-25-person287" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-25-person287" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-25-person287" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . That Webb that has been mentioned in this trial.</p>
               <p>Q. to Murray. Does this woman live with her husband in your house?</p>
               <p>Murray. She does.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she at home or abroad that evening?</p>
               <p>Murray. To the best of my knowledge she was at home.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601204-25-person288">
                  Thomas 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17601204-25-person288" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-25-person288" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-25-person288" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the prisoner betwixt six and seven that night, to the best of my knowledge he had a red coat on: he said he had lent his own to a man that was going after a deserter.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>Harris. This was by Charing-cross.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17601204-25-verdict157" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17601204-25-verdict157" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
