<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17671021-41">
               <interp inst="t17671021-41" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17671021-41" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17671021-41" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17671021"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17671021-41" type="date" value="17671021"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17671021-41-off208-c297" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-41-defend386 t17671021-41-off208 t17671021-41-verdict212"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17671021-41-off210-c299" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-41-defend389 t17671021-41-off210 t17671021-41-verdict214"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17671021-41-off210-c298" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-41-defend387 t17671021-41-off210 t17671021-41-verdict214"></join>
         
               <p>568, 569, 570. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17671021-41-defend386" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Lloyd 
                  <interp inst="t17671021-41-defend386" type="surname" value="Lloyd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-defend386" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-defend386" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             was indicted for <rs id="t17671021-41-off208" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-off208" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-off208" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing sixteen linen handkerchiefs, value 8 s. and two silk handkerchiefs, value 2 s.
            </rs> the property of persons unknown; and 
               <persName id="t17671021-41-defend387" type="defendantName">
                  
                        
                           <persName id="t17671021-41-defend389" type="defendantName">
                              James 
                              Murphy 
                           <interp inst="t17671021-41-defend389" type="surname" value="Murphy"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671021-41-defend389" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671021-41-defend389" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                         
                      and Sarah
                   his 
                  <rs id="t17671021-41-deflabel209" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-41-defend387 t17671021-41-deflabel209"></join>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-defend387" type="surname" value="Murphy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-defend387" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-defend387" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             
                  <rs id="t17671021-41-off210" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-off210" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-off210" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               (together with 
                     <persName id="t17671021-41-person390">
                        Sarah 
                        Murphy 
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person390" type="surname" value="Murphy"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671021-41-person390" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671021-41-person390" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , their daughter, not taken) for receiving the same, well knowing them to have been stolen
            </rs>, <rs id="t17671021-41-cd211" type="crimeDate">Sept. 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-41-off208 t17671021-41-cd211"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-41-off210 t17671021-41-cd211"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-41-person391">
                  John 
                  Noaks 
               <interp inst="t17671021-41-person391" type="surname" value="Noaks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person391" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person391" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had information that the prisoner, 
               <persName id="t17671021-41-person392">
                  James 
                  Murphy 
               <interp inst="t17671021-41-person392" type="surname" value="Murphy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person392" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person392" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , bought stolen goods; Sir 
               <persName id="t17671021-41-person393">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17671021-41-person393" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person393" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person393" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             granted a warrant to search his house; we were told if we came and watched his house, we should see pickpockets go in with things; I, Heley, and Hartley, went and watched at seven in the morning, and waited; after some time Heley said, there is one gone in then Hartley ran across, and took Lloyd before I got in; we had observed Murphy, who is a taylor, at work upon a coat two hours, we could see him through the window; when I came in, Hartley asked Lloyd for the bundle he brought in; Lloyd said, he knew nothing of a bundle, he denied seeing any; I said, we must search the house for it; in searching about there was a bundle of eighteen handkerchiefs, sixteen cotton ones, and two silk, found between the grate and a board that stood before it in the fore-room (produced in court;) Sir 
               <persName id="t17671021-41-person394">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17671021-41-person394" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person394" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person394" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             has advertised them, but no owners came; in the search Mrs. Murphy offered me her pocket to search; I said the bundle could not be put in that.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of handkerchiefs are they?</p>
               <p>Noaks. They are all of different sorts, not two alike; Lloyd said he came with a coat to be mended; I said, I had seen Murphy working two hours upon that coat, as we had been watching the house; we took up Lloyd and Murphy.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-41-person395">
                  John 
                  Heley 
               <interp inst="t17671021-41-person395" type="surname" value="Heley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person395" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person395" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the house of Mrs. Clark opposite Murphy's house, in Playhouse yard, Whitecross-street; I saw Lloyd come down the street, with a bundle in a handkerchief under his arm; I had seen him before, and knew him; we had been told there was a back way to the house, we went out, Hartley went to the back door, and I to the front in the street; I heard Hartley cry, halloo; I went; he said I have one in custody, which was Lloyd. Lloyd had then no bundle. he denied having any; we searched very particularly under the shop-board where Murphy was at work, and could not find the bundle; we were going away; Noaks said, I shall have another look; in going to the fire-place, here it is said he, and took it up; I said, I knew it to be the same bundle that he brought in; Murphy said he brought in no bundle, he brought in this coat, (meaning a coat he was at work upon.)</p>
               <p>Q. Might not Lloyd bring in that coat for what you know?</p>
               <p>Heley. I know Lloyd brought in a bundle, and I saw Murphy working upon that coat, I dare say two hours that morning.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-41-person396">
                  David 
                  Hartley 
               <interp inst="t17671021-41-person396" type="surname" value="Hartley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person396" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person396" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went with Noaks and Heley: I saw a lad coming down the street with a bundle tied in a handkerchief, I saw him go into Murphy's house; I was in a hurry to get to the back-door, I went in and took him; I asked him where the bundle was that he brought in; he said he brought none in; Murphy said, he brought in that coat he was at work upon; I had seen him at work on that coat two hours, or thereabouts; we searched the whole house, and I do not remember seeing any other coat in the house; I saw the bundle found near the fire-place concealed.</p>
               <p>Q. to Noaks. Did you see any other coat in the house but what Murphy was at work upon?</p>
               <p>Noaks. I saw one in a drawer, which Murphy said was his own coat.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-41-person397">
                  Susanna 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17671021-41-person397" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person397" type="given" value="Susanna"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person397" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live facing Mr. Murphy.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. I do business for a cabinet-maker; I have seen many boys go into Murphy's house at different times, and have seen them carry handkerchiefs in, and have seen Mrs. Murphy pay them money upon the counter, I could see it cross the way; when they thought I watched them, they used to go in at the back-door; but when they got into the house, I could see them open the handkerchiefs.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-41-person398">
                  Bartholomew 
                  Fenton 
               <interp inst="t17671021-41-person398" type="surname" value="Fenton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person398" type="given" value="Bartholomew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person398" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About three quarters of 2 year ago, I was drawn into bad company, and did many robberies; Murphy and his wife used<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176710210024"></xptr> to buy things of us; Mrs. Murphy generally paid the money, for what I and other boys carried; they gave us hardly any thing for what we brought.</p>
               <p>Lloyd's defence.</p>
               <p>I was going down to Limehouse to see after some work on the Tuesday night, before the Wednesday that I was taken; coming home between eight and nine in the evening, I had occasion to ease myself; going down a gateway I found that bundle, I took and brought it home; and in the morning I saw what it was; and as Mr. Murphy had made me a coat and several things, and was making a coat at the time, I had seen two or three handkerchiefs hang at his door; I went to see whether he would buy them; I was afraid of getting into trouble, made me not own it at first.</p>
               <p>He called seven people to his character, but none could give any account of him, or his behaviour for three or four years last past.</p>
               <p>Murphy's defence.</p>
               <p>I had a green coat to turn for this young man, he brought it in a bundle; I did not know where he lived; he desired me to get it turned and pressed; I had had it about nine days; then he agreed to let it alone a little while, I being busy; the week following he came for it; I promised he should have it by 12 o'clock the next day; about a quarter past eleven he came in, I was tying my garters, or buckling my shoes, I do not know which, I discerned something under his arm, but what it was I could not tell.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-41-person399">
                  Sarah 
                  Murphy 
               <interp inst="t17671021-41-person399" type="surname" value="Murphy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person399" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person399" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing of the young man; I never denied his bringing in any bundle, I saw no bundle that he brought.</p>
               <p>To their character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-41-person400">
                  Thomas 
                  How 
               <interp inst="t17671021-41-person400" type="surname" value="How"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person400" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person400" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a scowerer, and live in Whitecross-street; I have known Mr. Murphy eight or ten years; he is a very honest industrious man, and she a woman.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear of their dealing in handkerchiefs?</p>
               <p>How. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-41-person401">
                  John 
                  Griffin 
               <interp inst="t17671021-41-person401" type="surname" value="Griffin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person401" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person401" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Playhouse-yard, Whitecross-street, I am a lath-maker; I have known Mr. Murphy and his wife above six years; he is an honest man, one that works hard for his family; this is all through a spiteful neighbour.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-41-person402">
                  John 
                  Brogden 
               <interp inst="t17671021-41-person402" type="surname" value="Brogden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person402" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person402" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a periwig-maker, and live in Whitecross-street; I have known him almost seven years; I look upon him to be a sober honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-41-person403">
                  Edward 
                  Overion 
               <interp inst="t17671021-41-person403" type="surname" value="Overion"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person403" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person403" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a file-cutter; I have known him about four years; he is an honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-41-person404">
                  John 
                  Underwood 
               <interp inst="t17671021-41-person404" type="surname" value="Underwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person404" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person404" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a haberdasher's shop in Whitecross street, I have known him four or five years, he is a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-41-person405">
                  Daniel 
                  Yape 
               <interp inst="t17671021-41-person405" type="surname" value="Yape"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person405" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person405" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never heard the man did any thing amiss in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-41-person406">
                  James 
                  Hollingsworth 
               <interp inst="t17671021-41-person406" type="surname" value="Hollingsworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person406" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person406" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a tallow chandler, and live in Playhouse-yard; I have known him about six or seven years, I look upon him to be a very honest, sober, industrious man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-41-person407">
                  John 
                  Ratford 
               <interp inst="t17671021-41-person407" type="surname" value="Ratford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person407" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person407" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Murphy is a tenant of mine; I am a bricklayer, I have known him about six years; he bears the character of a very honest worthy man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-41-person408">
                  Thomas 
                  Hattersley 
               <interp inst="t17671021-41-person408" type="surname" value="Hattersley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person408" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person408" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a smith, and live in Playhouse-yard; I have known him about four years; I never knew nothing of him, but that of an honest industrious man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-41-person409">
                  Thomas 
                  Sutton 
               <interp inst="t17671021-41-person409" type="surname" value="Sutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person409" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-person409" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a carpenter, and live in Playhouse-yard; I have known him about a year and a half; he bears the character of an honest worthy man.</p>
               <p>Lloyd <rs id="t17671021-41-verdict212" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-verdict212" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17671021-41-punish213" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-punish213" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-41-defend386 t17671021-41-punish213"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Murphy and his wife <rs id="t17671021-41-verdict214" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17671021-41-verdict214" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
