<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17671021-4">
               <interp inst="t17671021-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17671021-4" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17671021-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17671021"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17671021-4" type="date" value="17671021"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17671021-4-off18-c49" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-4-defend59 t17671021-4-off18 t17671021-4-verdict22"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17671021-4-off18-c50" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-4-defend61 t17671021-4-off18 t17671021-4-verdict22"></join>
         
               <p>523, 524. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17671021-4-defend59" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Harvey 
                  <interp inst="t17671021-4-defend59" type="surname" value="Harvey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-defend59" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-defend59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17671021-4-defend61" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Bitters 
                  <interp inst="t17671021-4-defend61" type="surname" value="Bitters"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-defend61" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-defend61" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted, for <rs id="t17671021-4-off18" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-off18" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-off18" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               that they, on the <rs id="t17671021-4-cd19" type="crimeDate">28th of August</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-4-off18 t17671021-4-cd19"></join>, about two in the night, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17671021-4-victim63" type="victimName">
                           Jane 
                           Fisher 
                        <interp inst="t17671021-4-victim63" type="surname" value="Fisher"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671021-4-victim63" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671021-4-victim63" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-4-off18 t17671021-4-victim63"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17671021-4-viclabel20" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-4-victim63 t17671021-4-viclabel20"></join>, did break and enter, and stealing a linen apron, two handkerchiefs, a looking-glass, two pieces of gauze, five silk hats, a sattin hat, a chip hat, two sattin bonnets, a sattin cardinal, twenty-three pieces of blond-lace, two pieces of sattin, six yards of ribband, two yards and a half of muslin, three ruffles, four blond-lace caps, a laced handkerchief, a pair of laced ruffles, twenty-six china cups and saucers, two china basons, two china plates, a china punch bowl, three pair of cotton stockings, a linen shirt, a silk cloak, two other pieces of blond-lace, a linen napkin, and four yards of sarcenet, in the whole to the amount of 36 l. the property of the said Jane, in her dwelling-house
            </rs>. +</p>
               <p>At the desire of the prisoners the witnesses were examined apart.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-4-person64">
                  Jane 
                  Fisher 
               <interp inst="t17671021-4-person64" type="surname" value="Fisher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-person64" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-person64" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17671021-4-viclabel21" type="occupation">millener</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-4-victim63 t17671021-4-viclabel21"></join>, and keep a house at Mile end; on Friday the 28th of August, when<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176710210004"></xptr> I went to bed at twelve, I saw all the house fast; my servant got up, and returned to me immediately, which was about five, and told me the house was broke open; I got up, and found the kitchen window had a pane taken out, and the casement open; the back-door was open; I lost the things mentioned in the indictment (mentioning most of them;) I saw many of them again at the house of Mr. Brebrook in Whitechapel; about three weeks after a person came to my house, and desired I would attend at Sir 
               <persName id="t17671021-4-person65">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17671021-4-person65" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-person65" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-person65" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's; I went; there was Mr. Brebrook with some of them; there I heard Harvey say he was in my house, and I remember his mentioning stealing a looking-glass in particular.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say what time of the night it was?</p>
               <p>J. Fisher. He said he could not rightly tell whether it was four o'clock, or after four; I heard Bitters say, that he was in my house; they both said they were in company there, and 
               <persName id="t17671021-4-person66">
                  Sarah 
                  Carr 
               <interp inst="t17671021-4-person66" type="surname" value="Carr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-person66" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-person66" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was with them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they say who broke the house?</p>
               <p>J. Fisher. No, they did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-4-person67">
                  Sarah 
                  Carr 
               <interp inst="t17671021-4-person67" type="surname" value="Carr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-person67" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-person67" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I met the two prisoners one Friday night in Bishopsgate-street, about eleven o'clock; they asked me to go with them to Mile-end; we went in at the Three Pigeons in Houndsditch, and staid there till about twelve; when we got to Mrs. Fisher's house, Bitters got over a wall, and Harvey after him; they opened a door, and asked me to come in; I went in, this was into the yard; Bitters went and opened the wash-house door, and found nothing there; then they went and got into the kitchen window; how they opened it I do not know; they were in the house a considerable time before they brought any thing out; the first thing they brought out was a great looking-glass, the next was a box of hats, the next a box of laces, caps, and aprons, and a black cloak; the next a large bundle and a child's coat, the next china cups and saucers and a punch bowl; then the clock struck four; they told me I was to carry the things to 
               <persName id="t17671021-4-person68">
                  Abraham 
                  Teracona 
               <interp inst="t17671021-4-person68" type="surname" value="Teracona"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-person68" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-person68" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I carried all the china in a basket; they got there before me; Teracona took the china of me.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was it you left Mrs. Fisher's house?</p>
               <p>S. Carr. Then it was light; Bitters asked three guineas for the whole of the things; at last Harvey said take them at two; then his wife went out with a man, and brought in the money; she took some things out of pawn for Harvey, and gave Bitters a guinea, and me a nine shilling piece.</p>
               <p>Q. What are the prisoners?</p>
               <p>S. Carr. Harvey is a painter, and Bitters is a glazier and painter.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known them?</p>
               <p>S. Carr. I have known them about three months.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>S. Carr. I wind silk; my mother lives in Red-lion-street, Spitalfields.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-4-person69">
                  Martha 
                  Teracona 
               <interp inst="t17671021-4-person69" type="surname" value="Teracona"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-person69" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-person69" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My husband's name is Abraham *; I live in Northumberland-alley, Crutched-friars; a little after four in the morning, the 28th of August, the two prisoners came to our house; they had a hat-box, containing six hats, several pieces of sattin, two bonnets, a sattin cardinal, several white aprons, four gauze handkerchiefs, a looking-glass, a laced handkerchief and ruffles of the same, and three other ruffles; about half an hour after them came 
               <persName id="t17671021-4-person70">
                  Sarah 
                  Carr 
               <interp inst="t17671021-4-person70" type="surname" value="Carr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-person70" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-person70" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             with a basket of china cups and saucers, and a china bowl; they asked me whether I would buy them; I having bought things of them several times before, I thought, as I had had my hand in the lion's mouth, I should come to no more harm if I bought them; Bitters asked two guineas for them; I left them at breakfast, and went out, and brought in the money; I paid Harvey half a guinea, and 
               <persName id="t17671021-4-person71">
                  Richard 
                  Bitters 
               <interp inst="t17671021-4-person71" type="surname" value="Bitters"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-person71" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-person71" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a guinea, and Carr a nine shilling piece; they came and brought more things last Saturday five weeks, which they took in a house they broke near me; I bought them of them; then there was a great stir and disturbance, and my conscience began to prick me; so I went, and had Bitters secured in Wapping, and delivered up as many goods as were taken in eleven robberies; then I went to all the prosecutors, and told them I had such and such things; the prisoners had told me where they took them; the people came and owned them.</p>
               <p>* See him an evidence in the trial of Tinsey, Gibson, and Mackaway, No 407, in last Sessions Paper.</p>
               <p>Q. How did they tell you they got these things?</p>
               <p>M. Teracona. They said they got over backwards, and took out a pane of glass, and so entered the house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-4-person72">
                  James 
                  Brebrook 
               <interp inst="t17671021-4-person72" type="surname" value="Brebrook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-person72" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-person72" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last sessions I was at Hickes's-hall, I was standing by the Swan and Two Necks; there this last evidence came and told me that one 
               <persName id="t17671021-4-person73">
                  Sarah 
                  Carr 
               <interp inst="t17671021-4-person73" type="surname" value="Carr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-person73" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-person73" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was taken, and she knew where a man was locked in a room in St. Catharine's, and there was another man concerned with him, and one of<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176710210005"></xptr> them was concerned in seven robberies, and she had the best part of the goods in her house; I took two men with me and went there, and broke the door, and took Bitters and a young woman, and carried them to Whitechapel; then I went with the woman to her house in Northumberland alley; there she produced divers goods, (producing a box of caps, ruffles, blond-lace, &amp;c. &amp;c. and a large parcel of millenery goods.) The china I have in my house, I have an account of it here in writing; (he produced a hammer, a chissel, a saw, and a knife;) these 
               <persName id="t17671021-4-person74">
                  Sarah 
                  Teracona 
               <interp inst="t17671021-4-person74" type="surname" value="Teracona"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-person74" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-person74" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             told me were the prisoners tools, which she had left at her house, which they worked with.</p>
               <p>Q. to S. Teracona. What do you know of these tools?</p>
               <p>S. Teracona. I have heard Bitters say he used these to get into houses; they were once going out, and Harvey said, d - n it, we will not take them now, we will leave them here, so they left them; this was after the robbery they committed, after that of Mrs. Fisher's.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutrix. Look at these things produced here.</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. These were all taken from out of my house that night, they are my property.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-4-person75">
                  Dominick 
                  Rewer 
               <interp inst="t17671021-4-person75" type="surname" value="Rewer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-person75" type="given" value="Dominick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-person75" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable in Shoreditch parish. On my watch night, the 11th of September, in the morning, information was brought me, th at there was a reward of two guineas for taking Harvey and Bitters; I took some watchmen and searched many bad houses; at last the watchmen brought Harvey; I put him in the cage; then I went to 
               <persName id="t17671021-4-person76">
                  Sarah 
                  Carr 
               <interp inst="t17671021-4-person76" type="surname" value="Carr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-person76" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-person76" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the person he lived with, there we found several things; I ordered her to be secured; I took them before Sir 
               <persName id="t17671021-4-person77">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17671021-4-person77" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-person77" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-person77" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who committed Harvey to Clerkenwell Bridewell. I desired Sir John to let me have the key of Carr's door, saying, I thought I could make a farther discovery; he ordered it me. I went and opened her door; there people came and owned a tub, a pail, a pan; in one of the tubs were seventeen clouts; there was one asked for her carpet; Carr said it was under her bed; there we found it; I told her I would do all I could to get her admitted an evidence; she gave an account of many robberies; the things that I found, and were owned, I delivered back to their owners, as they were not bound over to prosecute.</p>
               <p>The prisoners in their defence, said they knew nothing of the matter.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17671021-4-verdict22" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-verdict22" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17671021-4-punish23" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17671021-4-punish23" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-4-defend59 t17671021-4-punish23"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-4-defend61 t17671021-4-punish23"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>There were two other indictments for burglaries against them.</p>
            </div1>
