<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17620714-22">
               <interp inst="t17620714-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620714-22" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620714-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17620714"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620714-22" type="date" value="17620714"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620714-22-off94-c150" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620714-22-defend191 t17620714-22-off94 t17620714-22-verdict96"></join>
         
               <p>197. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17620714-22-defend191" type="defendantName">
                     Jane 
                     Rogers 
                  <interp inst="t17620714-22-defend191" type="surname" value="Rogers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-22-defend191" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-22-defend191" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17620714-22-deflabel93" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620714-22-defend191 t17620714-22-deflabel93"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17620714-22-off94" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620714-22-off94" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-22-off94" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one silver shoe buckle, value eight shillings, one metal watch with two cases, value thirty shillings
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17620714-22-victim193" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Roe 
                  <interp inst="t17620714-22-victim193" type="surname" value="Roe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-22-victim193" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-22-victim193" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620714-22-off94 t17620714-22-victim193"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17620714-22-cd95" type="crimeDate">July 6</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620714-22-off94 t17620714-22-cd95"></join> ++ .</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the prisoner at the bar?</p>
               <p>Roe. I am not certain whether the prisoner is the person that robbed me or not. I happened to take up a woman of the town: I carried her to my chambers in Staple's Inn. I was very much in liquor. I lost my watch and a pair of buckles. I cannot pretend to swear to the prisoner; but as far as I am able to judge of it, I believe she is the woman. I have two witnesses here to prove my finding the watch again on the prisoner at the bar.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620714-22-person194">
                  Samuel 
                  Slater 
               <interp inst="t17620714-22-person194" type="surname" value="Slater"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-22-person194" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-22-person194" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Tuesday the sixth of this instant the prisoner brought this watch to pledge with me about eleven o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. to the prosecutor. When did you lose your watch?</p>
               <p>Roe. I lost my watch on the same day about eight o'clock. I took her to my chambers the night before. This was the morning of the sixth.</p>
               <p>Slater. I charged a constable with the prisoner, who desired her to be searched. She offered it to pledge. She seemed willing to be searched, and pulled her handkerchief out, and pulled out one of the prosecutor's buckles. Then she was sent to the compter [The watch and buckles produced in court, and deposed to by prosecutor]. I stopt the watch, and charged a constable with her, suspecting it to be stolen.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620714-22-person195">
                  William 
                  Dodington 
               <interp inst="t17620714-22-person195" type="surname" value="Dodington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-22-person195" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-22-person195" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was sent for by the last evidence. The prisoner said, you may search me; and she put her hand in her pocket, and took out her handkerchief; we saw the buckle. I asked her if it was her own, and where the fellow of it was. She said in her shoe. It was not there. Then she said, she did not steal the watch, but knew it to be stolen. The next morning I saw the watch and buckles advertised. I went as directed, and the gentleman swore to them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>A woman gave me the watch to pawn, and said it was her husband's. I was to bring the money to her in Middle Row: I went, and the watch was stopped. I drank a dram and was foolish, and did not know what I said. As to the buckle, the woman said, she had sold the fellow of it for three shillings and sixpence; and she is now gone into the country. Her name is Carrotty Bess.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17620714-22-verdict96" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620714-22-verdict96" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
