<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17651211-56">
               <interp inst="t17651211-56" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651211-56" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651211-56" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17651211"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651211-56" type="date" value="17651211"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17651211-56-off336-c434" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-56-defend561 t17651211-56-off336 t17651211-56-verdict338"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17651211-56-off336-c435" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-56-defend563 t17651211-56-off336 t17651211-56-verdict338"></join>
         
               <p>65, 66. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17651211-56-defend561" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Adams 
                  <interp inst="t17651211-56-defend561" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-defend561" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-defend561" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17651211-56-defend563" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Beckett 
                  <interp inst="t17651211-56-defend563" type="surname" value="Beckett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-defend563" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-defend563" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17651211-56-deflabel335" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-56-defend561 t17651211-56-deflabel335"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-56-defend563 t17651211-56-deflabel335"></join>s, were indicted for <rs id="t17651211-56-off336" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-off336" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-off336" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing two 36 shilling pieces, three guineas, and half a crown
            </rs>, the money of 
               <persName id="t17651211-56-victim564" type="victimName">
                  Hardington 
                  Holdsworth 
               <interp inst="t17651211-56-victim564" type="surname" value="Holdsworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-victim564" type="given" value="Hardington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-victim564" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-56-off336 t17651211-56-victim564"></join>
                  </persName>
             , <rs id="t17651211-56-cd337" type="crimeDate">November 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-56-off336 t17651211-56-cd337"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-56-person565">
                  Hardington 
                  Holdsworth 
               <interp inst="t17651211-56-person565" type="surname" value="Holdsworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person565" type="given" value="Hardington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person565" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 29th of November I was walking homewards towards Rosemary-lane, very much in liquor, I was stopped by several women: where they carried me to I do not know, nor how they used me; I was not sensible. I had 300 l. in Bank notes in my pocket book, and my watch besides. I went into a house; the people tell me since, it was the same place where Mr. Smith, clerk at the Bank, was robbed and murdered *. It was up a court near Church-lane. When I came out of the house, I found I had no money in my pocket; so I lost there two 36 shilling pieces, three guineas, a half crown, and some halfpence. I had my pocket book, with my papers in it, in my side-pocket. When I got out, I laid hold of a woman that had hold of the latch of the door: I told her she was the person, or one of the persons, that had robbed me. She said, no, she was not. I said she should go to the watch-house; I dragged her all along to the watch-house. While I was dragging her, she cried out Cobey, I believe fifty times: that was the person that was to attack me in case any thing should happen. I told her if I was to die I would not leave her. When I came to the watch-house, I believe it was between 7 and 8 o'clock; there was neither watch nor constable. I had a friend went up to the beadle of the parish and got assistance. I offered two guineas to have the people apprehended, so that I might but have my money and the people brought to justice. I went to a dozen public houses, and could find none that I could swear to. I can swear both the women at the bar were in company in the house, but can't swear they are the people that robbed me.</p>
               <p>* See the trial of Grief, Delaney, 
               <persName id="t17651211-56-person566">
                  Catherine 
                  Adams 
               <interp inst="t17651211-56-person566" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person566" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person566" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and Elizabeth Wall, the last an evidence on this trial, No 481, 482, 483, 484. in Septemb. Sessions.</p>
               <p>Q. How many women were in your company?</p>
               <p>Holdsworth. There were four. I was making water at the corner of the alley, and was hauled along by them.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you recollect who robbed you, or how you was robbed?</p>
               <p>Holdsworth. When I came into the house, they asked me to send for something to drink. I had three guineas, and half a guinea, and half a crown; the last was marked with my own name. I told them I would not part with that, I would change the half guinea: I said, when they brought in the change, I would give it them.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain you lost your money there?</p>
               <p>Holdsworth. I was fuddled, but I could walk<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176512110042"></xptr> very well. I know I had my money in my hand, being a fool in my liquor, and pulled it out of my pocket.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-56-person567">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Wall 
               <interp inst="t17651211-56-person567" type="surname" value="Wall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person567" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person567" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in at the Three Tuns, a public house, having some beer, and 
               <persName id="t17651211-56-person568">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Adams 
               <interp inst="t17651211-56-person568" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person568" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person568" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came in, and called for 2 quarters of brandy, and change for half a guinea: she desired the brandy might be brought over, and the silver; for she said the company would not trust her with the half guinea. She called me out, and asked me to go over the way and drink a glass of brandy with her and her acquaintance. I went over; the gentleman was sitting by the fire, and 
               <persName id="t17651211-56-person569">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Beckett 
               <interp inst="t17651211-56-person569" type="surname" value="Beckett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person569" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person569" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in another chair. 
               <persName id="t17651211-56-person570">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Adams 
               <interp inst="t17651211-56-person570" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person570" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person570" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             bid me sit down by the gentleman, which I did: she asked him to send for another dram, which he did, and we drank it: she asked him to make me a present; he put his hand in his pocket and gave me a shilling. After that the company asked me to sit down, and I did. After that the gentleman sent out for another dram; that made the third dram. Then she asked me to pull off my cloaths and go to bed. He said he could not stay all night, if they would give him ever so much. She bid me go to bed. He pulled off his cloaths and put them on the bed, and his breeches under his head. 
               <persName id="t17651211-56-person571">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Adams 
               <interp inst="t17651211-56-person571" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person571" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person571" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             insisted on coming and lying across the bolster of the bed: she went to kiss him, and put her hand over his face and took his breeches away, and carried them out to 
               <persName id="t17651211-56-person572">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Beckett 
               <interp inst="t17651211-56-person572" type="surname" value="Beckett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person572" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person572" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I was sitting on the bed's side with the gentleman. They were about 5 minutes in the entry; then Beckett brought in his breeches, and put them under his head, where he had put them before. Beckett called me out, and 
               <persName id="t17651211-56-person573">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Adams 
               <interp inst="t17651211-56-person573" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person573" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person573" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             opened her hands and said, here is the money, I took it out of the gentleman's pocket; I sent Beckett in with the breeches, for fear he should lay hold of my hand with the money in it. She said, will you go along with me, we will have a pot of hot. I went with them both; they called for a pot of brandy hot. Adams asked the landlord to give her change for a 36 shilling piece; he did: after the pot was out she called for another, and changed another 36 shilling piece at the bar: then she took me into a back parlour, and made me a present of half a guinea. I went away and left them both, and never saw any more of them till I was sent for by the constable, who said he wanted me, to know if I knew any thing about it; and I told him the whole truth.</p>
               <p>Q. Who came for you?</p>
               <p>E. Wall. 
               <persName id="t17651211-56-person574">
                  James 
                  Sullivan 
               <interp inst="t17651211-56-person574" type="surname" value="Sullivan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person574" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person574" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            * met me, and told me they wanted me; so I went with him to the constable's in Goodman's-fields.</p>
               <p>* See Sullivan an evidence for 
               <persName id="t17651211-56-person575">
                  Esther 
                  Coleman 
               <interp inst="t17651211-56-person575" type="surname" value="Coleman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person575" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person575" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , No 36, first part.</p>
               <p>Q. Whose house did you see the prosecutor and these women in?</p>
               <p>E. Wall. It is the last house in the lower apartment, belonging to 
               <persName id="t17651211-56-person576">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Adams 
               <interp inst="t17651211-56-person576" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person576" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person576" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Court. I wonder how you can attempt to go into that court again.</p>
               <p>E. Wall. I have not lived in that court a good while.</p>
               <p>Court. Advice will be but thrown away upon you, so I don't say any thing to you; I have no hopes that you will live above a sessions or two; you have had warning sufficient.</p>
               <p>Adams to prosecutor. Whether your cloaths were ever off while you was in the room?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. They were not off to my knowledge; they were no more off than they are now. I was very careful of my cloaths, because I had 300 l. value in my pocket at that time. At the Rotation Office, Elizabeth Wall swore, that another woman, a lusty woman, took my breeches off the bed. I had my watch safe in my breeches pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was the woman you first took up?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Her name was 
               <persName id="t17651211-56-person577">
                  Catherine 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17651211-56-person577" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person577" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person577" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; she said she was left to take care of the door, by the woman of the house, that is, 
               <persName id="t17651211-56-person578">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Adams 
               <interp inst="t17651211-56-person578" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person578" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person578" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you offer two guineas to, to take up the people that robbed you?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I spoke to 
               <persName id="t17651211-56-person579">
                  James 
                  Sullivan 
               <interp inst="t17651211-56-person579" type="surname" value="Sullivan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person579" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person579" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; he said it was not worth his while to look after them: then I offered him two guineas, and he very soon after brought 
               <persName id="t17651211-56-person580">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Adams 
               <interp inst="t17651211-56-person580" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person580" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person580" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He took from her three 5 s. and 3 d. pieces, and 23 shillings in silver. I was by at the time. I know nothing against Beckett, any farther than she was at the door.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember seeing Wall in the room?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I do.</p>
               <p>Adams's defence.</p>
               <p>This 
               <persName id="t17651211-56-person581">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Wall 
               <interp inst="t17651211-56-person581" type="surname" value="Wall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person581" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-person581" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             would come into my room with this gentleman, and were sitting on the side of the bed when I went for some beer, and when I came back they were gone. After that I met with Sullivan, he said he heard Elizabeth Wall had robbed a man; I told him I knew nothing of it: he said, I must go to the watch-house, but if I would give him part of what I had got he would let me go free. I told him I had no more money than what belonged to me. He took my money,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176512110043"></xptr> and gave me only 10 s. of it. He got Wall sworn to be an evidence, to swear our lives away, to get the money the gentleman proffered him. I hope the court will take it into consideration. I am as ignorant of the money as the child unborn. If the gentleman was robbed, she robbed him.</p>
               <p>Beckett's defence.</p>
               <p>I was in the house when Wall came in, but never afterwards.</p>


               <p>Mr. Noy, a juryman. About a fortnight ago I happened to be at the Rotation Office, I there heard Wall say, that a lusty woman that was there was the woman that took the breeches out and brought them in again; she swore that before Justice Scott.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17651211-56-verdict338" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651211-56-verdict338" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
