<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610401-14">
               <interp inst="t17610401-14" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610401-14" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610401-14" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610401"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610401-14" type="date" value="17610401"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610401-14-off78-c92" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610401-14-defend117 t17610401-14-off78 t17610401-14-verdict81"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610401-14-off82-c92" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610401-14-defend117 t17610401-14-off82 t17610401-14-verdict81"></join>
         
               <p>134. (L) 
               <persName id="t17610401-14-defend117" type="defendantName">
                  Ann, <rs id="t17610401-14-deflabel77" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610401-14-defend117 t17610401-14-deflabel77"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17610401-14-person118">
                        George 
                        Slade 
                     <interp inst="t17610401-14-person118" type="surname" value="Slade"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610401-14-person118" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610401-14-person118" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
                     <interp inst="t17610401-14-defend117" type="surname" value="Slade"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-14-defend117" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-14-defend117" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17610401-14-off78" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610401-14-off78" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-14-off78" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 4 harrateen curtains, value 40 s. one feather-bolster, two feather-pillows, one quilt, two sconses, one copper tea-kettle, and one brass saucepan, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17610401-14-victim120" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Hurst 
                        <interp inst="t17610401-14-victim120" type="surname" value="Hurst"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610401-14-victim120" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610401-14-victim120" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in a certain lodging room let by contract
            </rs>, &amp;c. <rs id="t17610401-14-cd79" type="crimeDate">March 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610401-14-off78 t17610401-14-cd79"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610401-14-off82 t17610401-14-cd79"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610401-14-person121">
                  John 
                  Hurst 
               <interp inst="t17610401-14-person121" type="surname" value="Hurst"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-14-person121" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-14-person121" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner lodged at my house three quarters of a year, or more.</p>
               <p>Q. What was her business?</p>
               <p>Hurst. She was of no business at all; she came to me as a widow; I heard she had an annuity 30 l. per year.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Hurst. I live in <placeName id="t17610401-14-crimeloc80">Salisbury-court, Fleet-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17610401-14-crimeloc80" type="placeName" value="Salisbury-court, Fleet-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610401-14-crimeloc80" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610401-14-off78 t17610401-14-crimeloc80"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610401-14-off82 t17610401-14-crimeloc80"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Who let her the room?</p>
               <p>Hurst. I did, and the goods mentioned in the indictment, with others, to be used with the lodging.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she pay per week?</p>
               <p>Hurst. She paid me two guineas and a half a quarter. After she had been at my house some time, I found she was a wife, separated from her husband. She kept very bad hours, and very indifferent company. About three months ago I had looked through the window, and saw, by the candle-light, that the curtains were gone: I went up to her, and asked her for my rent the day before it was due, to have an opportunity to see what were missing. She seemed to be in a great consternation, and said, Dear Sir, I am so tired I don't know what to do; I have been cleaning my room. I said, What is become of your window-curtains? Said she, I always take them down when I clean my room, to keep them from being dusty. The next night I looked up, and found the curtains were put in their place. After this she made a deal of disturbance in my house, because I would not let my door be unlocked late for her. On the 28th of February she paid my wife a quarter's rent, but she left one week unpaid. I went up to ask her for that: she paid me. Then I said, I expect you will quit these lodgings the next Friday. She said, she could not till the Monday following. I never saw her for eight days after this. Then I went to her husband: he said there should be no process against me, if I broke open the door. Then I went and broke it open, and missed the goods mentioned in the indictment.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you found your goods since?</p>
               <p>Hurst. I found the tea-kettle and brass saucepan as Mr. Wilmot's, a pawnbroker in Bride's-alley. The prisoner was taken up, and she said, She went out into the country, and left Mrs. Pidgeon (a woman that used sometimes to be with her) in the room, and she made away with them; but I am confident she never went out in the country, and left Mrs. Pidgeon there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610401-14-person122">
                  John 
                  Pearsey 
               <interp inst="t17610401-14-person122" type="surname" value="Pearsey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-14-person122" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-14-person122" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Hurst came to me, and told me he had lost the things mentioned in the indictment, and gave me the names of several people that he suspected might bring them. I looked over the book, and could not find any such names. Then I said, perhaps, you may know your own goods. We found this tea-kettle and saucepan, which he says, are his. [Produced and deposed to by the prosecutor.]</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know who brought them to you?</p>
               <p>Pearsey. It was a person very genteely dressed.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at the prisoner, do you know her?</p>
               <p>Pearsey. I cannot say whether it was the prisoner or not, I asked her if she lived-in ready-furnished lodgings, and said if she did she would bring herself and me too into trouble; she said she did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What name were they pawned in?</p>
               <p>Pearsey. They were both pawned in the name of 
               <persName id="t17610401-14-person123">
                  Ann 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17610401-14-person123" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-14-person123" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-14-person123" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Who do you live with?</p>
               <p>Pearsey. I live with Mr. Wilmot in Bride-lane.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176104010012"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17610401-14-person124">
                  Thomas 
                  Pearsall 
               <interp inst="t17610401-14-person124" type="surname" value="Pearsall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-14-person124" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-14-person124" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable. I was by when the prisoner's lodging-room was broke open. The room was left in a dirty condition, and the prosecutor said, there were such things, as mentioned in the indictment, missing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the prisoner acknowledge they had been there?</p>
               <p>Pearsall. I did; she said she let Mrs. Pidgeon lodge there, while she went into the country; and said, she had foul'd the things, and taken them out to wash them, and had never brought them back again.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Did Pidgeon ever lodge in the prisoner's room?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I never knew that she did.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Pidgeon was there a week by herself, and I had been in search of her, but could not find her.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610401-14-verdict81" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610401-14-verdict81" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>(M) She was a second time indicted by the same name, for <rs id="t17610401-14-off82" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610401-14-off82" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-14-off82" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing two silver tea-spoons, value 2 s. 6 d. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17610401-14-victim126" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Huggins 
                        <interp inst="t17610401-14-victim126" type="surname" value="Huggins"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610401-14-victim126" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610401-14-victim126" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  ; the same being in a certain lodging-room, let by contract
            </rs>, &amp;c. <rs id="t17610401-14-cd83" type="crimeDate">May 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610401-14-off78 t17610401-14-cd83"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610401-14-off82 t17610401-14-cd83"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610401-14-person127">
                  William 
                  Huggins 
               <interp inst="t17610401-14-person127" type="surname" value="Huggins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-14-person127" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-14-person127" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17610401-14-crimeloc84">Russel-court</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17610401-14-crimeloc84" type="placeName" value="Russel-court"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610401-14-crimeloc84" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610401-14-off78 t17610401-14-crimeloc84"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610401-14-off82 t17610401-14-crimeloc84"></join>: the prisoner took a lodging of me in August 1759, and continued a lodger with me about a year, till the May following; then she left her lodging, and I could never find her till she was in custody for the other offence. When she was gone I missed two silver tea-spoons.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you let her them with the lodging?</p>
               <p>Huggins. I did, as part of the furniture, and she accepted them as such; I delivered them to her with my own hand. She took away with her the keys of the drawers, which were found afterwards in her lodging in Salisbury-court. She carried away also the key of the room door.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you value the spoons at?</p>
               <p>Huggins. I value them at half a crown.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610401-14-person128">
                  John 
                  Seager 
               <interp inst="t17610401-14-person128" type="surname" value="Seager"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-14-person128" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-14-person128" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When the prosecutor broke the door open I was there: Mr. Huggins desired I would go and see what things were in the room. When we came in, he missed the two silver spoons.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I never touched any thing in the room.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610401-14-verdict85" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610401-14-verdict85" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acq.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>The first prosecutor, desirous to see the event of the second trial, put down his tea-kettle and saucepan by his foot in the court; but before the second trial was finished, his kettle and saucepan were carried off.</p>
               <p>This we think proper to insert, that prosecutors may always remember, it is very common for thieves to attend to hear their fellow-thieves tried.</p>
            </div1>
