<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680224-68">
               <interp inst="t17680224-68" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680224-68" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680224-68" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680224"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680224-68" type="date" value="17680224"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680224-68-off433-c577" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-68-defend729 t17680224-68-off433 t17680224-68-verdict437"></join>
         
               <p>240. (M). 
               
                  <persName id="t17680224-68-defend729" type="defendantName">
                     Rebecca 
                     Pearce 
                  <interp inst="t17680224-68-defend729" type="surname" value="Pearce"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-68-defend729" type="given" value="Rebecca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-68-defend729" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17680224-68-deflabel432" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-68-defend729 t17680224-68-deflabel432"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17680224-68-off433" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680224-68-off433" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-68-off433" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 3 moidores and 13 guineas
            </rs>, the money of 
               
                  <persName id="t17680224-68-victim731" type="victimName">
                     James 
                     Collins 
                  <interp inst="t17680224-68-victim731" type="surname" value="Collins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-68-victim731" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-68-victim731" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-68-off433 t17680224-68-victim731"></join>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17680224-68-cd434" type="crimeDate">Jan. 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-68-off433 t17680224-68-cd434"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-68-person732">
                  James 
                  Collins 
               <interp inst="t17680224-68-person732" type="surname" value="Collins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-68-person732" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-68-person732" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17680224-68-viclabel435" type="occupation">journeyman taylor</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-68-victim731 t17680224-68-viclabel435"></join>, I live in St. James's. On the 18th of January I was passing along in <placeName id="t17680224-68-crimeloc436">Parker's-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17680224-68-crimeloc436" type="placeName" value="Parker's-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17680224-68-crimeloc436" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-68-off433 t17680224-68-crimeloc436"></join>, I met the prisoner, this was about half an hour after ten at night; I went into her room, and lay with her; I put my breeches under my head, I fell to sleep; when I awaked she was gone, and my money too; but after some search, I found my breeches under the bed; all my money was gone, 13 guineas and 3 moidores, that I had put in my fob, and sewed it in with a bit of silk.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you awake?</p>
               <p>Collins. I awaked about half an hour after one; I staid there till morning, then I went to my friend, and we found the prisoner in the Strand, dressed from head to foot, and part of the money in her custody.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you been drinking?</p>
               <p>Collins. I had been that day at the One Tun in the Strand, with some of my shop-mates drinking from about two in the afternoon; I was not very drunk, neither was I sober.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you generally carry so much money about you?</p>
               <p>Collins. No, I do not, I had put the money there about two days before; I received ten guineas of 
               <persName id="t17680224-68-person733">
                  Thomas 
                  Tuley 
               <interp inst="t17680224-68-person733" type="surname" value="Tuley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-68-person733" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-68-person733" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , foreman to Mr. Mitchel, a taylor that I had worked with pretty near four years in Bucklersbury.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you had that money when you was with the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Collins. I am very sure of that.</p>
               <p>Q. What particular reason have you to know you had it at that time?</p>
               <p>Collins. I had a 5 s. 3 d. besides some silver and halfpence in my right-hand pocket, and I know I had this money.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Collins. I never saw her before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-68-person734">
                  John 
                  Hendrey 
               <interp inst="t17680224-68-person734" type="surname" value="Hendrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-68-person734" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-68-person734" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable; the prosecutor applied to me on the 19th of February, about eight in the morning; he said he had been in a room a little below me, he had been and got the prisoner's name; he said she was called Black Bird, or something like it, and said she had robbed him of about 20 l. I went with him where I thought she used, but we did not find her that day; on the Tuesday evening I went to the White Hart in the Strand, she was there, she had other cloathing on; I searched her, and found a guinea and a half, and a moidore; I took her to the Round-house, and from thence to Justice Welch; there she said a taylor had given her the money, and that she was to be married to him the next Monday.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. At the time you lay down was there any body else in the room?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No, there was one woman in the room before I lay down.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any liquor there?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Yes, the prisoner and I drank together, but I did not drink with the other woman.</p>
               <p>Q. What liquor did you drink there?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. We had two quarterns of aniseed, two pots of twopenny, and six pennyworth of ham and beef.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was at the end of Parker's-lane, waiting for a young woman that was gone for sugar; this man stopped me, and said, have you ever a husband; I said no, I do not want you; said he, I will make<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176802240049"></xptr> you a good one; I said, I should like a good one; said he, where do you live; I said, a little way down this lane; what is the name of it; I said, it is Parker's-lane, and said, I live up one pair of stairs backwards, and pay 2 s. a week for my room; said he, I'll go and lie with you; I said, you make very free the first time; said he, what will you drink; I said, a glass of gin; said he, then you must - for it; said I, if you do not like to give me more, there is the door the carpenter made; I was not for his staying, as he would give me nothing; I said, what is the meaning of this, you said you would make me a good husband; said he, if you will behave with honour, I'll give you a shilling in the morning, when I go away; said I, I am afraid to stay all night in the room, I will not trust myself to stay all night, here is such a banditti, I cannot trust a bad halfpenny in the room; if you have a mind to have a bit and away, you may; he swore by Jesus, but he would stay all night, or I'll split your scull; there came up a woman that wanted to broil a couple of sprats, I said you are welcome; said he, I wish I had some; I said I wished I had something; he said he would have some beef and ham; we had some; then he said he liked that woman better than me; he turned me out and kept her there; it is a common lodging-house, where none but thieves come; after I was out I met with a sailor, who gave me both clothes and money; if any body robbed him after I was gone, I cannot help that, I knew in my own conscience I had done no harm, I wondered what I was taken up for; there came in a constable who called me Black Bird, he took a pair of ear-rings from me, and my money, and some other things; I have been at his house in the time of his wife's illness, please to ask him my character.</p>
               <p>Hendrey to the question. When my wife has been ill, the prisoner has come and washed the pots, and done business in the parlour; I never missed any thing by her.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17680224-68-verdict437" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680224-68-verdict437" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
