<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17651211-48">
               <interp inst="t17651211-48" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651211-48" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651211-48" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17651211"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651211-48" type="date" value="17651211"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17651211-48-off287-c341" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-48-defend453 t17651211-48-off287 t17651211-48-verdict290"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17651211-48-off287-c342" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-48-defend455 t17651211-48-off287 t17651211-48-verdict290"></join>
         
               <p>55, 56. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17651211-48-defend453" type="defendantName">
                     Stephen 
                     Wheat 
                  <interp inst="t17651211-48-defend453" type="surname" value="Wheat"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-defend453" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-defend453" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17651211-48-defend455" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Tull 
                  <interp inst="t17651211-48-defend455" type="surname" value="Tull"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-defend455" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-defend455" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17651211-48-off287" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-off287" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-off287" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 20 yards of linen cloth, value 20 s. 21 yards and three quarters of velvet, value 5 l. 15 s. 26 yards of fustian, value 2 l. 7 s. 25 yards and 3/4 of thickset, value 1 l. 5 s. 24 yards of other fustian, value 35 s. 14 yards and 3/4 of other fustian for pockets, value 8 s. 21 yards of corded dimity, value 30 s. 21 yards of pillow fustian, 19 yards and a half of cloth, 2 woollen cloth coats, a cloth waistcoat, 144 mettle buttons, a cotton wrapper, 7 yards of camblet, and a trunk, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17651211-48-victim457" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Freydenberg 
                        <interp inst="t17651211-48-victim457" type="surname" value="Freydenberg"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651211-48-victim457" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651211-48-victim457" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-48-off287 t17651211-48-victim457"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in a certain boat lying on a navigable river
            </rs>; to wit, the river <placeName id="t17651211-48-crimeloc288">Thames</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17651211-48-crimeloc288" type="placeName" value="Thames"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17651211-48-crimeloc288" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-48-off287 t17651211-48-crimeloc288"></join>, <rs id="t17651211-48-cd289" type="crimeDate">November 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-48-off287 t17651211-48-cd289"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-48-person458">
                  Thomas 
                  Hollings 
               <interp inst="t17651211-48-person458" type="surname" value="Hollings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person458" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person458" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . There was a trunk stole out of my boat, that night the fire was in Cornhill, which was I believe the 7th of November: we took it in about 10 o'clock over night, from out of the warehouse, at the Rose and Crown at Queenhithe. My boat lay there when the trunk was stolen; the boy and I were both fast asleep in the boat at the time we missed it, about 3 o'clock the next morning; then I came and told Mr. Freydenberg of it: we were to have delivered it at Teddington, at his house up the river.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-48-person459">
                  William 
                  Pratt 
               <interp inst="t17651211-48-person459" type="surname" value="Pratt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person459" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person459" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am clerk to Mr. Freydenberg, I packed the goods in the trunk, the night before it was sent down to the water-side, being the 6th of November; they were the goods mentioned in the indictment, (mentioning them by name.) I sent it by our porter, 
               <persName id="t17651211-48-person460">
                  George 
                  Houghton 
               <interp inst="t17651211-48-person460" type="surname" value="Houghton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person460" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person460" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , to the Rose and Crown, Queenhithe.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-48-person461">
                  George 
                  Houghton 
               <interp inst="t17651211-48-person461" type="surname" value="Houghton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person461" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person461" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a porter, I carried the trunk that was delivered to me by Mr. Pratt, to the Rose and Crown warehouse at Queenhithe, and delivered it to Hollings the waterman at the door.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a trunk was it?</p>
               <p>Houghton. It was a black leather trunk; I carried it from Mr. Freydenberg's warehouse in Ironmonger-lane.</p>
               <p>Q. to Pratt. Whose property were the things you packed up?</p>
               <p>Pratt. They were the property of Mr. Freydenberg.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-48-person462">
                  Thomas 
                  Mills 
               <interp inst="t17651211-48-person462" type="surname" value="Mills"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person462" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person462" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 7th of last month, 
               <persName id="t17651211-48-person463">
                  Robert 
                  Tull 
               <interp inst="t17651211-48-person463" type="surname" value="Tull"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person463" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person463" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17651211-48-person464">
                  Stephen 
                  Wheat 
               <interp inst="t17651211-48-person464" type="surname" value="Wheat"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person464" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person464" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and I, went out, down Bank side, where we got a boat; whose property I know not. 
               <persName id="t17651211-48-person465">
                  Robert 
                  Tull 
               <interp inst="t17651211-48-person465" type="surname" value="Tull"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person465" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person465" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             rowed us over the water, where we saw a country boat lying; we went along-side the boat, and took out a corded black leather trunk; this was near Queenhithe. I held the boat while the trunk was taken out; I think there were two people asleep in the boat: then Tull rowed us over to Pepper-alley stairs, where we broke the trunk open, and found it contained divers goods, such as velvet and fustian; then we took the trunk down to the house of 
               <persName id="t17651211-48-person466">
                  Mary 
                  Clegg 
               <interp inst="t17651211-48-person466" type="surname" value="Clegg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person466" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person466" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , where I lodge, in Tooley-street. The next day Tull and Wheat came and took out some of the pieces of cloth in a green bag, and another coloured bag.</p>
               <p>Q. How many pieces did they take away?</p>
               <p>Mills. I cannot tell how many, whether 3, 4, or 5, or what: the trunk remained there till the Sunday following, when Tull and Wheat came and took it away, and carried it into Lock-fields, as they told me; I left them in White-street: they came to me again at the Blue Bell. They said they had taken the things out, and hove the trunk into a ditch.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is Lock-fields from the Borough?</p>
               <p>Mills. It is about half a mile distant. What they did with the goods they took out, I do not know; they gave me no account, and they gave me no more than 15 s. and that they gave me that night. I had only one black coat, which I pawned at the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176512110032"></xptr> next door but one to the Black Raven in Tooley-street, for 5 s. and 3 d. and a piece of velvet of 5 yards, which I pawned for 8 s.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you ever concerned with the prisoners before?</p>
               <p>Mills. I was once concerned with Tull before. (See No. 540, i n Mr. Alderman Bridgen's Mayoralty.) I never was concerned with Wheat before.</p>
               <p>Q. Where had you been in the afternoon, on the 6th of November?</p>
               <p>Mills. I was with Tull in the day-time, and appointed to meet at the Blue Bell in the evening, which we did all three.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they tell you before you set out, what they were going upon?</p>
               <p>Mills. No, they did not. I knew we were going upon the water.</p>
               <p>Q. from Wheat. Was I there, at the Blue Bell with you?</p>
               <p>Mills. Yes, you was.</p>
               <p>Q. from Tull. Whether you did not meet me on London-bridge that morning, about 3 o'clock?</p>
               <p>Mills. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-48-person467">
                  Catherine 
                  Clegg 
               <interp inst="t17651211-48-person467" type="surname" value="Clegg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person467" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person467" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Unicorn-yard, Tooley-street, Mills lodged along with me; he and Wheat brought a trunk into my house, about 4 o'clock, the morning that the fire was in Cornhill, and it rested there till the Sunday afternoon following; when Tull came and fetched it away: I insisted on their taking it away. Mills lodged in a two pair of stairs room.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a trunk was it?</p>
               <p>C. Clegg. It was a black leather one, bound up, and carried into Mill's lodging room; it was bound up with a cord all the time it was there.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be up so early that morning?</p>
               <p>C. Clegg. My brother was sick, and I was up with him. I never saw no more of them after they brought it in, till the Saturday morning; Mills and another man came, and went away again; they came again at night to lodge: they were in liquor. I do not know what that other man was; they were very noisy: the next morning I discharged them from the lodging, not to come any more to lodge there. They took the trunk away on the Sunday.</p>
               <p>Q. Who took it away?</p>
               <p>C. Clegg. Mills and Tull brought it down stairs; Wheat was with them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did either of the prisoners lie in the house with Mills?</p>
               <p>C. Clegg. No.</p>
               <p>Q. What time on the Sunday did they fetch it away?</p>
               <p>C. Clegg. They went away on the Sunday morning, and came again in the afternoon and fetched it away; they all three went away with it: I know nothing where they carried it; neither do I know what was in it.</p>
               <p>Q. from Tull. Whether there was not a gentleman came the next day, with his face bound up, and said they were his property?</p>
               <p>C. Clegg. Yes, there was a gentleman came, he went up stairs with me; but whether they opened it or not, I cannot say: he did not say the trunk was his; but said I must not let any body have the trunk. When Mills came to lodge with me, he told me there was a young fellow come to lodge with him, if I approved of it; so I suppose this man came with a view to lodge, for he wanted to pay a shilling a week for his lodging as well as he.</p>
               <p>Q. from Wheat. Was not that man's head bound up with a handkerchief?</p>
               <p>C. Clegg. Yes, it was.</p>
               <p>Q. from Wheat. Did not I ask you whether the lock was broke open?</p>
               <p>C. Clegg. No, I asked that question, Whether the lock came in whole? and he said he could not tell, whether it came tied or corded; I told Wheat a man came and claimed it, and I told him another man had said it must not be taken away, but by his order, and I would not let it go till Mills came.</p>
               <p>Tull. This man that had his face bound up, was named 
               <persName id="t17651211-48-person468">
                  James 
                  Saunders 
               <interp inst="t17651211-48-person468" type="surname" value="Saunders"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person468" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person468" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Whether he did not lie that night with Mills?</p>
               <p>C. Clegg. Yes, he did lie that night with Mills.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-48-person469">
                  Nicholas 
                  Maniarty 
               <interp inst="t17651211-48-person469" type="surname" value="Maniarty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person469" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person469" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable, I keep a public house opposite Mrs. Macuse. This 
               <persName id="t17651211-48-person470">
                  Thomas 
                  Mills 
               <interp inst="t17651211-48-person470" type="surname" value="Mills"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person470" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person470" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             brought a bag of linen to her house, on the 12th of November, for her to sell for him; she came over to me, and desired me to come over and see it, thinking it had been stolen from the fire. I went over, Mills was sitting by the fire in her house; I said where is this linen you have to sell? Young man, he said, here it is; I said how came you by it; he said he bought it in Holland: I said I do not believe any such goods ever came from Holland, I believe they were stolen from the fire; no, said he, they are not: the man was all on a tremble; I said I insist upon your going before a justice, to know whether you came honestly by them or not. I carried him before a justice in Shadwell, there he denied it; the justice desired me to take him before Sir 
               <persName id="t17651211-48-person471">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17651211-48-person471" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person471" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person471" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; saying, Sir John knew better what to do in it than he did. I put him in a coach, to carry him<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176512110033"></xptr> before Sir John; I said going along, you had better confess and clear yourself: then he said they were stolen, but not from the fire. Said I, where were they stolen from; he said from out of a luggage-boat above-bridge. It is table-linen, I stopped it, and have had it in my possession over since. We went before Sir John, there he impeached the two prisoners; and that he was one of the men that stole the trunk out of the luggage-boat, and if any body would go to the Blue Bell, in White-street, over the water, they might find the two prisoners; so Sir John granted a warrant to go and look for them; there were 
               <persName id="t17651211-48-person472">
                  Matthew 
                  Bathwate 
               <interp inst="t17651211-48-person472" type="surname" value="Bathwate"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person472" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person472" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and Mr. Macuse with me: I said go you in first, and call for a pint of beer. I staid behind 3 or 4 minutes after; the two prisoners were coming out, I said to Wheat, (having had them both described) is not your name Stephen; he said no, my name is Jemmy Royal. I took him in charge, there was a candle brought out, I saw his dress answered the description that Mills had given; I took him into the house and gave him in charge of two or three men. I went all over the Borough, and could get no constable; then I took him in a coach, and carried him into my own parish, that is St. George Middlesex, and the next morning before Sir John Fielding: there he confessed he was the person that carried the trunk up to the house, and was concerned in taking it out of the luggage-boat; and that if he had not been drunk he should not have gone. They were all taken the same day, but I know nothing of Tull; I did not hear him examined.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-48-person473">
                  Hannah 
                  Macuse 
               <interp inst="t17651211-48-person473" type="surname" value="Macuse"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person473" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person473" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Ratcliff-highway, in Denmark-street; Mr. Maniarty lives facing my door; Mills and Tull came to my house, I believe it was on the 11th of November.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>H. Macuse. I deal in old cloaths, they brought a green bag, and asked me whether I did not deal in old cloaths. I said yes; they said they came from on board a Holland trader, they had been to Holland, and had got some things, and they were afraid of the Custom-house officers, and if I would sell a piece of Holland for them, they would give me a piece for a table-cloth; they cut me off a piece for a table-cloth from a larger piece; they had other things in the bag, it appeared like fustian, I had just a sight of it: they delivered this piece of cloth to me to sell, (produced in court;) there is 15 yards of it. I took a piece and offered it to sell at a shop in Cable-street. I told the woman I had it from a person that came from Holland, and he was afraid of the Custom-house officers; the woman said I had better take it home and cut it for table linen; Tull and Mills were at my house at the time. A cabinet maker came in and seeing them cut the cloth, he had a suspicion of it being stolen; he called my husband out, and when they were whispering gave them a suspicion, and they went away, and said they would leave the linen till they came back at 4 o'clock in the afternoon: then I went over to Mr. Maniarty the constable, and told him of it; they never came that night. The next day I went to enquire about them, and met Tull on London-bridge. I stopt and collarded him; he got from me. I called stop came, and some were for stopping him, and some not; but I got assistance, and took him before my Lord-Mayor. I left word if Mills should come, to send for the constable: he came, and was taken, so all three were taken that day.</p>
               <p>Q. from Tull Whether I brought any of it into your house?</p>
               <p>H. Macuse. No, you did not, Mills brought it under his great coat.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-48-person474">
                  Thomas 
                  Macuse 
               <interp inst="t17651211-48-person474" type="surname" value="Macuse"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person474" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person474" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Tull and Mills brought these things to my house, when we suspected them, they went out, and said they would come again at 4 o'clock, but they did not; then we put the things in the officer's hands. Mills came the next day, about 12 o'clock: we got assistance, and charged him, and took him before Justice Fielding; he was sent to New-prison: then we had a warrant from Sir John to take up Wheat; we took him at the Blue Bell, on the other side the water. I went on board the ship which they said they came from Holland in, and the people told us, they had no men of their names on board.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-48-person475">
                  Mathew 
                  Bathwate 
               <interp inst="t17651211-48-person475" type="surname" value="Bathwate"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person475" type="given" value="Mathew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person475" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going by Mr. Macuse's house, and saw Tull and Mills measuring about 20 yards of fustian; they cut it in two, and parted it betwixt them: then they pulled out of a green bag, about 14 yards of huckaback; there were more things in the bag. When they cut the fustian, one of them said, the other man concerned would be mad if he had not his share; they asked the woman to go out and sell some huckaback. Said one, cut it in two: no, said the other, let it go whole: first they cut a table-cloth off, and then they sent the remainder out to sell. She came back with it, and said the people said she had better take it back, or she would be stopped with it: then said Mills, cut it up into table-cloths. I whispered her, and said, this stuff is certainly stolen. I would have you not to be concerned with it. We told them the table-cloths should be made, if they came in the evening; they went away, and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176512110034"></xptr> we went and told the officer of it, and intended if they had come, to stop them; we waited their coming, but they did not come that night. The next day while we were waiting at the alehouse, and had left word with the girl, that the mistress had sold the cloth, and would give them the money as soon as she came home. Mills came, and we went and took him, and carried him before the justice: he denied the stealing it, and said he brought it from Holland; the justice ordered us to take him before Sir 
               <persName id="t17651211-48-person476">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17651211-48-person476" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person476" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person476" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When we came into the back lane; I said to him, you had better own it, for the other is taken, (we had heard Tull was taken on London-bridge;) and very likely he will get admitted evidence. Then he said he did steal it, betwixt Black-friars-bridge, and the Old Swan, out of a boat: we asked him where the other man was to be found; he said the other was a lusty man, (describing his clothes,) and that he was to be found at the Blue Bell, in White-street. We told Sir John, and he granted us a warrant, and we went and found Wheat there.</p>
               <p>Q. from Tull. By whose authority was the stuff cut?</p>
               <p>Bathwate. It was by Mills's order.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-48-person477">
                  John 
                  Bartram 
               <interp inst="t17651211-48-person477" type="surname" value="Bartram"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person477" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person477" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with 
               <persName id="t17651211-48-person478">
                  George 
                  Grigg 
               <interp inst="t17651211-48-person478" type="surname" value="Grigg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person478" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person478" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in Barnaby-street, a pawn-broker: this piece of fustian Tull brought to me, on the 11th of November; I lent him half a guinea upon it: he said he lived in Fishmonger's-alley, and that it was his own. (Produced in court.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-48-person479">
                  James 
                  Gathey 
               <interp inst="t17651211-48-person479" type="surname" value="Gathey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person479" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person479" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mr. Spence, facing Barnaby-street: (he produced 10 yards of fustian.) This Tull brought to me on the 11th of November, I never saw him before; he said it was his own.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-48-person480">
                  David 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17651211-48-person480" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person480" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person480" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Kent-street, I am a pawn-broker: on the 9th of November, about 5 in the evening, Mills came. I never saw him before but once. 
               <persName id="t17651211-48-person481">
                  Richard 
                  Saunders 
               <interp inst="t17651211-48-person481" type="surname" value="Saunders"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person481" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person481" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came with him, to satisfy me what he bought was his own; he brought this, (producing five yards of velvet.) I have known Saunders 2 years. Mills told me he bought it at Deptford, for 6 s. a yard, to make him a frock: it is Manchester velvet.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-48-person482">
                  Sarah 
                  Shearer 
               <interp inst="t17651211-48-person482" type="surname" value="Shearer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person482" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person482" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a pawn-broker, and live in Tooley-street: Mills brought this black coat to me, the 7th of November. (Produced in court.)</p>
               <p>Q. to Pratt. Look at these several things, here produced by the pawn-brokers; can you swear to any of them?</p>
               <p>Pratt. I can swear to the velvet, and I think the coat is Mr. Freydenberg's; they were in the trunk.</p>
               <p>Mr. Freydenberg. I can swear the coat is my property, they have artfully divided the piece, and cut my mark off, and pawned it to two pawnbrokers.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mills. Was you along with Tull, at Mr. Macuse's?</p>
               <p>Mills. I was.</p>
               <p>Wheat's defence.</p>
               <p>Mills met me on the bridge, about 3 o'clock in the morning; I was going to Billingsgate-market: he asked me where I was going, I said to the Gate, I never saw him before. Said he, if you will go along with me, I can help you to a shilling or two. I said with all my heart, your money is as good as another man's. I asked what it was to do: he said it was to take a chest, and carry to his lodgings. I did, he said come to-morrow, and I will pay you: I took it up at the foot of the Bridge. I went in the morning, and his landlady said he was not at home; but he and the man that was the owner of the chest had been there, and broke the lock, and took several of the things out, and said they were going to have clothes made of it: she said if I wanted the chest, I might take it with me. I said I had no business with it, she took me up two pair of stairs, to shew me how the lock was broke: I never knew what was in the chest. I lay in Kent-street, and got up about half an hour after two that morning; but I do not know the name of the people where I lay.</p>
               <p>Tull's defence.</p>
               <p>I met 
               <persName id="t17651211-48-person483">
                  Tom 
                  Mills 
               <interp inst="t17651211-48-person483" type="surname" value="Mills"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person483" type="given" value="Tom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person483" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             at the foot of London-bridge; he asked me to give him a lift up with the chest: I knew him, being shipmates together. He asked me where I was going, I said to Gravesend: he said will you stay with me, I can put 2 or 3 shillings in your pocket: he said he was going to be sworn into the militia the next day: he said he had got half a dozen handkerchiefs, some nankeen, and some tea, that came out of an Indiaman; and desired me to walk with him to Mrs. Macuse's; he had some cloth in a green bag.</p>
               <p>Mr. Freydenberg. I was before Sir 
               <persName id="t17651211-48-person484">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17651211-48-person484" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person484" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-person484" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             when Tull was there: he said he would discover every thing, if they would admit him an evidence; he owned he was concerned in taking the things out of the boat.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17651211-48-verdict290" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-verdict290" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17651211-48-punish291" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651211-48-punish291" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-48-defend453 t17651211-48-punish291"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-48-defend455 t17651211-48-punish291"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
