<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17620224-17">
               <interp inst="t17620224-17" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620224-17" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620224-17" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17620224"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620224-17" type="date" value="17620224"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620224-17-off93-c188" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-17-defend216 t17620224-17-off93 t17620224-17-verdict96"></join>
         
               <p>105. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17620224-17-defend216" type="defendantName">
                     Margaret 
                     Lovelock 
                  <interp inst="t17620224-17-defend216" type="surname" value="Lovelock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-17-defend216" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-17-defend216" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17620224-17-off93" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620224-17-off93" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-17-off93" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing out of her ready-furnished lodgings a pair of sheets, two pair of curtains
            </rs>, &amp;c. the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17620224-17-victim218" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Copley 
                  <interp inst="t17620224-17-victim218" type="surname" value="Copley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-17-victim218" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-17-victim218" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-17-off93 t17620224-17-victim218"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17620224-17-cd94" type="crimeDate">Feb. 4</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-17-off93 t17620224-17-cd94"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620224-17-person219">
                  Hannah 
                  Copley 
               <interp inst="t17620224-17-person219" type="surname" value="Copley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-17-person219" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-17-person219" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the wife of 
               <persName id="t17620224-17-person220">
                  John 
                  Copley 
               <interp inst="t17620224-17-person220" type="surname" value="Copley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-17-person220" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-17-person220" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I live in <placeName id="t17620224-17-crimeloc95">Hatfield-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17620224-17-crimeloc95" type="placeName" value="Hatfield-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17620224-17-crimeloc95" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-17-off93 t17620224-17-crimeloc95"></join>, and about five months ago I let the prisoner at the bar an apartment ready furnished by the week; and on or before the 4th of February she stole one pair of sheets, a pair of pillow cases, two pair of linen window curtains. In the morning of the 6th of February I had some mistrust of her, and I asked her leave to go into her apartment. She said, I might go when I pleased. When I came into her room, I missed the things specified in the indictment; and I asked her about the window-curtains, why she took them down; and she said they came down. I asked her where they were. She desired me not to be angry; she had pawned them, but she would take them out of pawn, and put them up again. I asked her how I could rely upon that, when she had so deceived me. I asked her where she had pawned them, that I might get them again. She said, she did not chuse to tell me, but promised to get them again. I told her she must tell me where my things were, otherwise farther trouble would ensue both to her and me. I asked her if she knew the consequence attending these things? She said, No. I then told her, my Lord, the consequence, as I had been informed, would be transportation. At length she told me where she had pledged them.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was it?</p>
               <p>H. Copley. At Mr. Payn's in Golden-lane; and then I sent for a person to go with me; but, being told I must get an officer, I sent for Mr. Cambrook.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go in company with him to Mr. Payn's?</p>
               <p>H. Copley. Mr. Cambrook and the prisoner went to Mr. Payn's; and Payn acknowleged that such things were there, and said she must go before a magistrate. Then, my Lord, I went to Justice Welch, and he ordered me and Payn the broker to come to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Payn produce the things before you went to Justice Welch?</p>
               <p>H. Copley. No, my Lord, not till the Wednesday following.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you there the Wednesday following, when the goods were produced?</p>
               <p>H. Copley. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they the same things mentioned in the indictment?</p>
               <p>H. Copley. Yes; one sheet and the other things were produced before Justice Welch, the other sheet was pawned elsewhere.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say before the justice?</p>
               <p>H. Copley. She acknowleged the fact; said necessity obliged her to do it; that she designed to get them again, and put them in their places.</p>
               <p>Q. You say one of the sheets was pawned elsewhere; where was that?</p>
               <p>H. Copley. At Mr. Batcock's in Golden Lane.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you discover that?</p>
               <p>H. Copley. By her own confession; and Mr. Smith, Mr. Payn's man, went with me, and Mr. Batcock delivered the sheet to me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620224-17-person221">
                  Francis 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17620224-17-person221" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-17-person221" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-17-person221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Payn, pawnbroker, and the prisoner at the bar brought those things [producing them] except one sheet, and pledg'd them at my master's; one sheet the 20th of October, two curtains the 3 d of February, and two more the 6th of February in the morning, as her property.</p>
               <p>Q. Were these produced to Mrs. Copley?</p>
               <p>Smith. Yes.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>My husband was out of business, and he required me to carry those things to pawn; and he went with me to the door; soon after he went for a soldier, and left me in all this trouble?</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any witnesses to prove this?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. No.</p>
               <p>Court asked 
               <persName id="t17620224-17-person222">
                  Francis 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17620224-17-person222" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-17-person222" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-17-person222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , if, when he received those goods, he saw any-body with her at the shop or door?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620224-17-person223">
                  Francis 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17620224-17-person223" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-17-person223" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-17-person223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . No, my Lord, two of the things were pledged the morning she was taken up.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs. Copley. Was it you or your husband let these lodgings?</p>
               <p>H. Copley. I let them, my Lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you let them to, her husband and her together, or to her alone?</p>
               <p>H. Copley. To him and her both together.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176202240018"></xptr>The court were of opinion that the taking the lodgings was the act of the husband, and mentioned to the jury some circumstances in favour of the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17620224-17-verdict96" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620224-17-verdict96" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
