<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17641017-8">
               <interp inst="t17641017-8" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641017-8" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641017-8" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17641017"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641017-8" type="date" value="17641017"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17641017-8-off43-c70" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641017-8-defend90 t17641017-8-off43 t17641017-8-verdict47"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17641017-8-off43-c71" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641017-8-defend92 t17641017-8-off43 t17641017-8-verdict47"></join>
         
               <p>552, 553. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17641017-8-defend90" type="defendantName">
                     David 
                     Spence 
                  <interp inst="t17641017-8-defend90" type="surname" value="Spence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-defend90" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-defend90" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17641017-8-defend92" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Carlow 
                  <interp inst="t17641017-8-defend92" type="surname" value="Carlow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-defend92" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-defend92" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17641017-8-off43" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-off43" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-off43" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 50 yards of woollen cloth, value 10 l. and 40 yards of stuff, called long-ell, value 3 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17641017-8-victim94" type="victimName">
                           Joseph 
                           Crane 
                        <interp inst="t17641017-8-victim94" type="surname" value="Crane"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17641017-8-victim94" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17641017-8-victim94" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   the elder, and 
                     
                        <persName id="t17641017-8-victim96" type="victimName">
                           Joseph 
                           Crane 
                        <interp inst="t17641017-8-victim96" type="surname" value="Crane"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17641017-8-victim96" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17641017-8-victim96" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   the younger, in the warehouse of the said prosecutors
            </rs>, <rs id="t17641017-8-cd44" type="crimeDate">September 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641017-8-off43 t17641017-8-cd44"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641017-8-person97">
                  Joseph 
                  Crane 
               <interp inst="t17641017-8-person97" type="surname" value="Crane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person97" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person97" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , jun. I am in partnership with my father, at <placeName id="t17641017-8-crimeloc45">Old Ford</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17641017-8-crimeloc45" type="placeName" value="Old Ford"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17641017-8-crimeloc45" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641017-8-off43 t17641017-8-crimeloc45"></join>: we are <rs id="t17641017-8-viclabel46" type="occupation">scarlet dyers</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641017-8-victim94 t17641017-8-viclabel46"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641017-8-victim96 t17641017-8-viclabel46"></join>. On Sunday, the 23d of September, at night, our warehouse was broke open, and we missed the pieces of cloth mentioned in the Indictment. I came to Justice Fielding's, and had hand-bills printed, upon which the prisoners were taken; and at Justice Fielding's I heard Spence say, there was a pane of glass broke, and that Goad the Evidence got hold of the handle of the casement, and opened it, and lifted up the bar of the shutter, and went in, and that he and Carlow staid on the out-side, and that Goad handed out the cloth. Carlow was not then taken.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641017-8-person98">
                  William 
                  Goad 
               <interp inst="t17641017-8-person98" type="surname" value="Goad"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person98" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person98" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 23d of September, the two prisoners and I met at the Castle on Saffron-Hill; we proceeded from thence to Mile-End, then to Bow, to the prosecutor's warehouse: we went first into the stable, to see for a sack, but could find none; then I got in at the warehouse window, and gave them out a piece of cloth; after that, two long-ells: then I came out and said, shut the window; they said, no, let the window be d - d: then we came to Bethnal Green; thinking it not proper to come into town, we went then to the 
               <persName id="t17641017-8-person99">
                  Rosemary 
                  Branch 
               <interp inst="t17641017-8-person99" type="surname" value="Branch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person99" type="given" value="Rosemary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person99" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and from thence to Islington: I staid by the cloth while they went to a house and got some purl; then I got some; then we went near White-conduit House; and we afterwards went to the Roe-buck on Saffron-Hill; I staid till they went with part of it to Carlow's mother; they there took the cloth in their own custody. Two days after I went to 
               <persName id="t17641017-8-person100">
                  Thomas 
                  Harriat 
               <interp inst="t17641017-8-person100" type="surname" value="Harriat"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person100" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person100" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; he said he was going to receive the money for the cloth; he took me to the King's Arms, the back of St. Clement's; there was Mr. Wright, he took me in custody, and I was taken to Sir 
               <persName id="t17641017-8-person101">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17641017-8-person101" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person101" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person101" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's: Spence was taken the next morning; then we both were taken to Sir John: Spence was committed to the Gatehouse, and I to New Prison.</p>

               <p>Q. Were there any more goods in the warehouse, besides what you took?</p>
               <p>Goad. Yes, a great many; but we took as much as we could carry away.</p>
               <p>Spence. He wanted to give us more, and we would not take it; he said it was his own property, and that he had been a little extravagant, and wanted to make money of that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641017-8-person102">
                  George 
                  Butler 
               <interp inst="t17641017-8-person102" type="surname" value="Butler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person102" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person102" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to the prosecutors. On the Monday morning I went to open the warehouse door, and found the window open. I went in, and told my master; and we looked about and missed a piece of cloth and two pieces of long-ell.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641017-8-person103">
                  John 
                  Sweet 
               <interp inst="t17641017-8-person103" type="surname" value="Sweet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person103" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Servant to the prosecutors. I fastened up the window on the Saturday night before, and it was open on the Monday morning.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641017-8-person104">
                  Thomas 
                  Harriat 
               <interp inst="t17641017-8-person104" type="surname" value="Harriat"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person104" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person104" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 26th of September, Spence and Carlow came to me, and one Mallot, my brother-in-law; (he is not here). Mallot asked me if I would have a pint of beer? we went in at the Green Dragon in Fleet-street; Mallot asked me if I would have a piece of cloth to make a waistcoat? I asked if I or he must find the lining? as we were sitting drinking, Spence produced a bundle of cloth, which he had under his arm; I took him to be a taylor going to carry some work home in a wrapper; we went out, and Spence gave me the cloth under my arm. I asked what I must do with it? said he, sell it; get what you can for it; he said there were twelve yards of it; I might get six shillings a yard for it: I never measured it; there is thereabouts. I took it home, and locked it up in a drawer; the next morning I went to Sir 
               <persName id="t17641017-8-person105">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17641017-8-person105" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person105" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person105" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and informed him of it; in the Evening I gave the cloth into the possession of 
               <persName id="t17641017-8-person106">
                  Ned 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17641017-8-person106" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person106" type="given" value="Ned"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person106" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; he went to the King's Arms, the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176410170007"></xptr> back of St. Clements; after that, Spence came to receive the money, and I had him taken up.</p>
               <p>Q. What did Carlow say, that night Spence delivered the cloth to you?</p>
               <p>Harriat. He was there; but he said nothing about the cloth, as I know of; he seemed to answer, when Spence desired me to get six shillings a yard for it; but I don't remember what he said.</p>
               <p>Q. from Spence. Did I not ask you if you knew how to dispense with the cloth, and you said yes?</p>
               <p>Harriat. That is true.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641017-8-person107">
                  Edward 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17641017-8-person107" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person107" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person107" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The cloth was left at the last witnesses house; he came to Sir John Fielding's, and applied to Mr. Marsden, and said, some people had left some cloth at his house, that he thought was stole: Mr. Marsden desired me to go with him; I did, and took the cloth to a public house, and when they came for it or the money, he was to bring them to me: so Spence came; I took his own handkerchief from his neck, and tied his hands, and brought him to Sir 
               <persName id="t17641017-8-person108">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17641017-8-person108" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person108" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person108" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641017-8-person109">
                  Henry 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17641017-8-person109" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person109" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person109" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went along with my brother, in order to search for the other prisoner, on the Friday: there was a girl stopped, but afterwards got from the constable: I met with her afterwards; she is now in Newgate; she had this piece of cloth (producing a piece): this appears to be cut from one of the pieces.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641017-8-person110">
                  John 
                  Huston 
               <interp inst="t17641017-8-person110" type="surname" value="Huston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person110" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person110" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in St. Martin's in the Fields: I keep a shop, and sell small pieces of cloth. On the Monday in the Forenoon, one of Mr. Crane's men came to me, and said their warehouse had been broken, and described what sort of cloth was stole, and desired, if any such was brought to my shop, to stop it. About eight at night on the Tuesday, Spence came and asked me if I would buy this piece of cloth, (producing a yard and three quarters of cloth): as soon as I saw it on the compter, I asked him which way he came by it? he said he had bought it promiscuously. I told him there was an information brought me of this cloth.</p>
               <p>Crane, jun. This is our property: it is orange colour; it is a particular thing, to go to the East-Indies.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641017-8-person111">
                  Thomas 
                  Burch 
               <interp inst="t17641017-8-person111" type="surname" value="Burch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person111" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person111" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a pawnbroker. (He produced a yard of the same colour) This was brought me by one 
               <persName id="t17641017-8-person112">
                  Anne 
                  Ludlow 
               <interp inst="t17641017-8-person112" type="surname" value="Ludlow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person112" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person112" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knowing such was advertised, I stopt it.</p>
               <p>Crane, jun. This is part of the same with the other piece produced.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641017-8-person113">
                  Henry 
                  Burton 
               <interp inst="t17641017-8-person113" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person113" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person113" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was employed by Sir 
               <persName id="t17641017-8-person114">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17641017-8-person114" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person114" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to take these men; Carlow was taken last Friday; I was sent with him to Newgate; going in the coach, he told me he and Spence were together; that Spence gave the cloth to Harriat, and he gave it to Wright; that Harriat said, there is the broker, will you go and take the money? no, said Carlow; I will have none of that money, for Sir 
               <persName id="t17641017-8-person115">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17641017-8-person115" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person115" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person115" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is turned broker, for that is one of Sir John's people.</p>
               <p>Alexander Hill. I was with Crane before the Justice: Spence was for being admitted evidence; he said, if he was not, it would touch his life, for he was concerned in the robbery. I did not see Carlow before now.</p>
               <p>Spence's Defence.</p>
               <p>The young fellow that is evidence against me, told me he was foreman at Mr. Crane's, and that this cloth was his property; and if I would go along with him, he would give me half a guinea for my trouble: I went along with him, not thinking any harm, and came back with him into town; I never was in that place in my life before, and can safely swear I cannot find my way to the place again.</p>
               <p>Carlow's Defence.</p>
               <p>We were both together, when he repeated them words as 
               <persName id="t17641017-8-person116">
                  David 
                  Spence 
               <interp inst="t17641017-8-person116" type="surname" value="Spence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person116" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-person116" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             has said. I never saw the evidence before that night; he asked me to go along with him, to help to bring the cloth.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17641017-8-verdict47" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-verdict47" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17641017-8-punish48" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17641017-8-punish48" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641017-8-defend90 t17641017-8-punish48"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641017-8-defend92 t17641017-8-punish48"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
