<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610225-8">
               <interp inst="t17610225-8" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610225-8" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610225-8" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610225"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610225-8" type="date" value="17610225"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610225-8-off36-c67" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-8-defend80 t17610225-8-off36 t17610225-8-verdict39"></join>
         
               <p>85. (M) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610225-8-defend80" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Garnegey 
                  <interp inst="t17610225-8-defend80" type="surname" value="Garnegey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-8-defend80" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-8-defend80" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17610225-8-off36" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610225-8-off36" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-8-off36" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one metal watch, value 7 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17610225-8-victim82" type="victimName">
                     George 
                     Mackenzie 
                  <interp inst="t17610225-8-victim82" type="surname" value="Mackenzie"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-8-victim82" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-8-victim82" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-8-off36 t17610225-8-victim82"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17610225-8-cd37" type="crimeDate">February 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-8-off36 t17610225-8-cd37"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-8-person83">
                  George 
                  Mackenzie 
               <interp inst="t17610225-8-person83" type="surname" value="Mackenzie"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-8-person83" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-8-person83" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the thirteenth of this instant February, the prisoner asked me to be so kind to him, as to give him a piece of a bed, he being short of money.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you know him before?</p>
               <p>Mackenzie. He was a stranger to me.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had he been with you?</p>
               <p>Mackenzie. He was with me about three hours, and he told me his name was Mackenzie.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250006"></xptr>Q. Where did you meet with him?</p>
               <p>Mackenzie. I met with him at a tavern in Covent-garden, about two or three in the morning. He was in company with one or two that I knew.</p>
               <p>Q. At what tavern?</p>
               <p>Mackenzie. The tavern goes by the name of 
               <persName id="t17610225-8-person84">
                  Bob 
                  Derry 
               <interp inst="t17610225-8-person84" type="surname" value="Derry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-8-person84" type="given" value="Bob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-8-person84" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, it is a night-house. He told me he was <rs id="t17610225-8-deflabel38" type="occupation">a midship-man on board a man of war</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-8-defend80 t17610225-8-deflabel38"></join>, he asked me to lend him a guinea, I told him I had not one about me. I said, I did not chuse to lie with a man, and carried him to another night-house in Bow-street, and asked the woman of the house, if she would give him a bed, and I would pay for it. Then he said, he was surprized I should bring him into a house where so many Irish chair-men were. I told him, the best way was to go to bed, but he would not lie there. We staid there till betwixt fix and seven, and drank some hot slip.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in liquor?</p>
               <p>Mackenzie. I might be the worse for liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your memory good at that time?</p>
               <p>Mackenzie. My memory was in as good a condition as a person's could be, that sits up all night.</p>
               <p>Q. Say, was you drunk or sober?</p>
               <p>Mackenzie. I was more drunk than sober; we went to bed between six and seven in the morning. in my lodgings.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was your watch?</p>
               <p>Mackenzie. My watch was hanging on a hook in the room, where I commonly hang it when I go to bed; it had hung there the day before. I had another watch in my pocket, which I left with the woman that keeps the night house.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you leave it with her?</p>
               <p>Mackenzie. Because I did not know what company I might get into.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you by so many watches; one watch will serve one man.</p>
               <p>Mackenzie. I bought them; I bought that he took, about five months ago, of one Bruce,</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you rise that morning?</p>
               <p>Mackenzie. I think I got up about twelve o'clock in the day.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your door locked when you went to bed?</p>
               <p>Mackenzie. I do not recollect whether it was or not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you wind up that watch when you went to bed?</p>
               <p>Mackenzie. I did not; I did not handle it as I remember.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see it?</p>
               <p>Mackenzie. I did; it was hanging before me.</p>
               <p>Q. Does any body lodge in that house besides you?</p>
               <p>Mackenzie. Yes; any body may; there were one or two more.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner get up when you did?</p>
               <p>Mackenzie. No; he got up and left me asleep, and took the watch away.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find it again, and where?</p>
               <p>Mackenzie. The prisoner, before justice Fielding, confessed who he had disposed of it to.</p>
               <p>Q. In what manner did he say he had disposed of it?</p>
               <p>Mackenzie. I think he said he let Mr. Hill have it for three guineas and a half.</p>
               <p>Q. From prisoner. Was not you excessive drunk when you went to bed?</p>
               <p>Mackenzie. I do not know what you mean by excessive drunk; not quite so drunk, but that I knew what I did; and I know I was very foolish in being so good natured to give you part of a bed.</p>
               <p>Q. From prisoner. Did you not fail against a door, and burst it open; and you could not stand?</p>
               <p>Mackenzie. I do not remember that.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you swear you did not?</p>
               <p>Mackenzie. No; I cannot.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>Mackenzie. I am a lieutenant in the service, on half-pay.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner say how he came by the watch?</p>
               <p>Mackenzie. He said he took it out of my lodgings.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-8-person85">
                  Hannibal 
                  Hill 
               <interp inst="t17610225-8-person85" type="surname" value="Hill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-8-person85" type="given" value="Hannibal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-8-person85" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a jeweller's shop in Covent garden, the prisoner has been several times to my shop to buy things; he came to me on Friday morning the thirteenth of February, about ten or eleven o'clock, and told me, he had been in a frolick with some friends, and they were in trouble; and desired I would lend him two guineas and a half on this watch. [Producing a metal watch.]</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. This is my watch, and what I lost that morning; here is my name on the dial-plate, and the Number is 156. Name Bruce.</p>
               <p>Hill. I lent him the money upon it.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray what is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Hill I look upon him to be a young gentleman, I have no reason to think otherwise; but I know nothing of him. After that, I bought the watch right out of him for a guinea more.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250007"></xptr>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>It was my misfortune to happen in company with some young fellows, that Thursday-night, the twelfth of February, We rather exceeded too much in staying out late from our lodgings. We went from where we had been drinking, to a house in Russel-street, where was an acquaintance of mine with Capt. Mackenzie; the Captain asked me to drink with them, I did; after that the company dispersed. He insisted on my staying with him. After that I was locked out of my lodging; he said, if I would go home with him, I should have part of his bed; I went with him; instead of carrying me to his lodgings, he brought me to the Brown-bear in Bow-street, amongst a parcel of Irish chairmen. I did not chuse to stay there; so he said, I should go home with him to his lodgings; I paid all the money in my pocket at Mr. Derry's. When he came to his lodgings, the chairman wanted to be paid for lighting him home. He bid me pay him; I said I had spent all my money. I told him when I was in his lodgings, I was necessitous, and desired he would lend me a little money. He said, I cannot lend you any, but you may take my watch, and put it in pledge, and when you can redeem it you may; and shewed me where it hung, and bid me take it; he was flushed with liquor; and going to shew me where it hung, he fell down against the door of the next room. There were a man and his wife in bed, the door burst open; the man said, [Cannot you keep yourself sober one night in the week.] We went to bed, I took the watch before I went to bed; and this Mr. Hill being an acquaintance, I pawned it to him for three guineas and a half; I expected money soon, and then I intended to fetch it again. After that, he met me in Lincoln's-inn fields, and charged me with it. I told him I knew the circumstances of it, and would go with him to Justice Fielding. There I told him I had the watch of him, by his consent. He committed me to New-prison, and from thence I came to Newgate. We drank together at the Half-moon in Holbourn, there I told him what I had borrowed on it; and he said, if I would get it again, he would never hurt me.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Did you drink with him at the Half moon in Holbourn?</p>
               <p>Mackenzie. Yes, I did, but did not promise him any such thing. As soon as he discovered me he walked faster, and was going into Queen-street; I walked on, then he walked towards Holbourn: as soon as he got into the passage I ran and came up to him, and said, What ship brother? and catched him by the collar; he said, No ship; then I said, How do you do Mr. Mackenzie? Said he, My name is not Mackenzie. I said, You remember you said that was your name, when you robbed me. He cry'd and said, I am guilty of all the charge, but do not expose me in the street; so I clapt my arm under his arm, and we walked away together he desired me to go in at the Half-moon tavern; I did, and called for a pint of wine, and a pipe of tobacco: he wrote a letter to his friend, and sent it by a porter. No-body coming, I said I could not stay any longer. He desired I would indulge him with a coach; then I drove away to the Carlisle-arms, after having left word, if the porter returned, to send him to that house: the porter came, and said he could find no such person as the prisoner talked of: then I sent him to the Round-house, and afterwards had him before justice Fielding.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He began reaping up the circumstances of this watch; I said, let's go to a tavern, and I will satisfy you for it: we went to the Half-moon tavern, there he protected he would not hurt a hair of my head; I said I did not think that was in his power: I sent for a friend, in order to get the watch out, and pay the money; he was not at home; he would not stay till the porter came back, but hurried me away to a house in Queen-street, there I could not send for my friend. I was going abroad as a clerk with capt Scott, to the East-Indies, had not this happened.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-8-person86">
                  James 
                  Lard 
               <interp inst="t17610225-8-person86" type="surname" value="Lard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-8-person86" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-8-person86" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was educated at Westminster-school, and I know he was strongly recommended by admiral Pocock to the governor of Bengal: the admiral wrote a letter with his own hand, and he was to go with capt. Scott as a clerk.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Lard. I know he has not behaved so well of late as he should do, but has got into some disorderly houses, as he was when this unlucky affair happened. His father lives at Newcastle; he had his education from a gentleman with whom there has been some difference, and he went home to his father.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I served my time to one Mr. Burduss, an attorney at Newcastle.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610225-8-verdict39" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610225-8-verdict39" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
