<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670603-32">
               <interp inst="t17670603-32" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670603-32" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670603-32" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670603"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670603-32" type="date" value="17670603"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670603-32-off196-c312" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670603-32-defend379 t17670603-32-off196 t17670603-32-verdict201"></join>
         
               <p>310. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17670603-32-defend379" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Cunningham 
                  <interp inst="t17670603-32-defend379" type="surname" value="Cunningham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670603-32-defend379" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670603-32-defend379" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for that <rs id="t17670603-32-off196" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670603-32-off196" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670603-32-off196" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he on the King's highway, on Mary, the <rs id="t17670603-32-viclabel197" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670603-32-victim383 t17670603-32-viclabel197"></join> of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17670603-32-victim381" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Booking 
                        <interp inst="t17670603-32-victim381" type="surname" value="Booking"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670603-32-victim381" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670603-32-victim381" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , did make an assault, putting her in corporal fear and danger of her life, and taking from her person 3 s. 6 d. in money numbered, the property of the said Robert
            </rs>, <rs id="t17670603-32-cd198" type="crimeDate">May 9</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670603-32-off196 t17670603-32-cd198"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
               
                  <persName id="t17670603-32-victim383" type="victimName">
                     Mary 
                     Booking 
                  <interp inst="t17670603-32-victim383" type="surname" value="Booking"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670603-32-victim383" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670603-32-victim383" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            . I live at the bottom of Well-street, my husband is a <rs id="t17670603-32-viclabel199" type="occupation">smith</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670603-32-victim381 t17670603-32-viclabel199"></join>; I carry out work which he makes, to sell among the brokers. I was coming along betwixt ten and eleven at night, on Saturday the 9th of May, on the <placeName id="t17670603-32-crimeloc200">top of Mill-yard</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17670603-32-crimeloc200" type="placeName" value="top of Mill-yard"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17670603-32-crimeloc200" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670603-32-off196 t17670603-32-crimeloc200"></join>, that is, I had got down Red Lion-street by Rosemary-lane, having been out with my husband's work; I had sold some small pokers for 3 s. 6 d. there was the prisoner and four other men; he came up first, and said, you b - h, lie down, and let me do so and so.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know him before?</p>
               <p>M. Booking. I did, having seen him gambling on Tower-hill; he gave me a blow on my left breast and knocked me down; he stopped my mouth, and took my money out of my pocket as he lay upon me.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he stop your mouth with?</p>
               <p>M. Booking. With his right-hand, and took my money with his left, 3 s. 6 d. he said to the other, d - n her a b - h, we will carry her to such a place; one took me by my head, and others my heels and body, and carried me; and the prisoner who is called Jolly, stopped my mouth with horse-dung, that was while they were concerned with me; they all lay with me in the place where they carried me, the prisoner was the first; they carried me near a brewhouse; after they had all done, Jolly took a knife out and cut my gown in this form, (producing an old gown cut off about the knees;) I called out, murder; he knocked me down three times; they went' one way and I the other.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you miss your money?</p>
               <p>M. Booking. I missed that when he fell upon me; I am sure I felt his left-hand in my right-hand pocket, and none put their hand there but he.</p>
               <p>Q. How far did they carry you?</p>
               <p>M. Booking. They carried me as far as this table here in the court is long.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure your money did not drop out of your pocket as they carried you?</p>
               <p>M. Booking. I am sure it did not; he said, if I cried murder, he would come back and kill me. I felt in my pocket as soon as they were gone; then I went and got a warrant.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after this did you get a warrant?</p>
               <p>M. Booking. This was on a Saturday, and I got the warrant on the Wednesday.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you not to get a warrant on the Monday?</p>
               <p>M. Booking. I had not money to spare; he was taken up on the Monday following.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was along with four lads; this woman came down dead drunk; she called 
               <persName id="t17670603-32-person384">
                  James 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17670603-32-person384" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670603-32-person384" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670603-32-person384" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , one of them by name, he had been concerned with her before; she has been a common prostitute; she said, h ow goes it, Jim; he took her down to the bottom of the bank, and asked me to go along with him; he said, have you any money; she said she had but one penny, and that she would give towards a pot of beer; he took her round Well-close-square; they met the watch; she said, Jim, here is a watchman, let us turn back; he took her up Mill-yard to a stable; he and one Patten, and another lad were together there. As to her money I know nothing of it; she wants to swear my life away.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutrix. Do you know 
               <persName id="t17670603-32-person385">
                  James 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17670603-32-person385" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670603-32-person385" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670603-32-person385" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. I know no more of him than I do of my dying day.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go round Wellclose-square with any body that night?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. No, I did not, with none of them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670603-32-person386">
                  James 
                  Brebrook 
               <interp inst="t17670603-32-person386" type="surname" value="Brebrook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670603-32-person386" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670603-32-person386" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I should be very glad to be sworn, I know a good deal of it; I believe this poor fellow is ill used.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Let him be sworn.</p>
               <p>He is sworn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670603-32-person387">
                  James 
                  Brebrook 
               <interp inst="t17670603-32-person387" type="surname" value="Brebrook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670603-32-person387" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670603-32-person387" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was before the bench of Justices in Whitechapel, when this woman came there for a warrant; Mr. Pell granted a warrant, and gave it to me to take him; there was nothing<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176706030026"></xptr> said about the robbery at that time, I was by all the time; she charged him at last with stealing 3 s. 6 d. from her, and said there were three lay with her; the Justice would give no attention to that, but granted the warrant for an assault; I took him, and was at his examination, he was committed for an assault only.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17670603-32-verdict201" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670603-32-verdict201" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
