<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17600910-10">
               <interp inst="t17600910-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600910-10" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600910-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600910"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600910-10" type="date" value="17600910"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600910-10-off51-c90" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-10-defend121 t17600910-10-off51 t17600910-10-verdict53"></join>
         
               <p>252. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17600910-10-defend121" type="defendantName">
                     Susanna 
                     Addis 
                  <interp inst="t17600910-10-defend121" type="surname" value="Addis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-10-defend121" type="given" value="Susanna"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-10-defend121" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17600910-10-deflabel50" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-10-defend121 t17600910-10-deflabel50"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17600910-10-off51" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600910-10-off51" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-10-off51" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one linnen sheet, value 5 s. one copper tea-kettle, value 4 s. one pewter pot, value 6 d. the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17600910-10-victim123" type="victimName">
                           Michael 
                           Hawkins 
                        <interp inst="t17600910-10-victim123" type="surname" value="Hawkins"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600910-10-victim123" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600910-10-victim123" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-10-off51 t17600910-10-victim123"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , the same being in a certain lodging room let by contract
            </rs>, &amp;c. <rs id="t17600910-10-cd52" type="crimeDate">February 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-10-off51 t17600910-10-cd52"></join>.*</p>
               <p>Michael Addis. The prisoner at the bar lodged at my house, she went away about the 10th of February.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had she lodged with you?</p>
               <p>Addis. She had lodged with me about three or four months.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the lodgings ready furnished?</p>
               <p>Addis. They were.</p>
               <p>Q. At what per week?</p>
               <p>Addis. At 2 s. and 3 d. per week.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you miss the things?</p>
               <p>Addis. We missed the tea-kettle about 3 weeks before she left her lodgings, but we were not willing to mention it, thinking she would bring it back again; when we were informed she was about to leave her lodgings; she came home about eleven o'clock, she would not let my wife go into the room, and begged and cried we would not charge the watch with her; and said, if we would let her go to bed, she would make us satisfaction for what things were missing the next morning; but the next morning she went away, and took the key of the room with her, and we did not see her for four months after, then we found her in another lodging.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she propose to make satisfaction for the things mentioned in the indictment?</p>
               <p>Addis. She did.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to let her go away?</p>
               <p>Addis. We live in another house, and we expected she would call upon us, but she did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did she go away?</p>
               <p>Addis. About eight in the morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you meet with her again?</p>
               <p>Addis. We found her in Leather-lane, at the Queen's Head.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever get the things again?</p>
               <p>Addis. No, Mr. Fielding was pleased to be so good as to indulge her for two or three days, but she never restored them.</p>
               <p>Q. If she had restored them should you have prosecuted her?</p>
               <p>M. Hawkins. No, we should not.</p>
               <p>Q. Then if she had let you have your things again should you have been satisfied?</p>
               <p>M. Hawkins. Yes.</p>
               <p>Eliz. Hawkins. I am wife to the prosecutor, the prisoner at the bar lodged at our house.</p>
               <p>Q. Who let her the lodgings?</p>
               <p>Eliz Hawkins. I did, at 2 s. and 3 d. per week, ready furnished.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did she come in?</p>
               <p>Eliz. Hawkins. She came in about August last.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did she live in that lodging?</p>
               <p>E. Hawkins. About 3 or 4 months; she went away about the 10th of February; I went up to ask her for rent about three weeks before she went away, and then I miss'd my tea-kettle; when I could not find it I ask'd her after it; she said she had taken it to a neighbour's house for some water; I desired her to bring it back again; she told me she would; but I never saw her after that for three weeks; I went to the person where she said it was, and she said there was no tea-kettle there; I had insisted upon going into the room to see my goods; she said they were very safe in the room, and that I had no right to go into the room; I said I had a right, as she did not pay me her rent. After some time she would admit me to go into the room, provided I would let her lie there that night, and not turn her out; then I miss'd the things mentioned; she bid me not to make myself uneasy, for she had a sister that would see them all put into their places before she went out of the room, and she would take me to her; she said where she liv'd; but when I went I could find no such person; she got up the next morning and went away, and I never saw her till three weeks after, till she was taken up on the 22d of July; then she said she intended<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176009100009"></xptr> to get the things again, for she could get 20 or 40 shillings per week, but she never brought them again.</p>
               <p>Q. Is she a single or a married woman?</p>
               <p>E. Hawkins. She came to me as a single woman; she said she could better pay me than if she had a husband; but before the justice she said her husband came to see her, and he was going abroad, and he bundled them up together and gave them to a person.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see her husband?</p>
               <p>E. Hawkins. No; I never saw any husband she had.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I liv'd opposite them with my husband; he went away with another woman.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutrix. Do you know of her living opposite you?</p>
               <p>E. Hawkins. She told me she had lived there, I never knew her till she came to live with me; I have heard since that she did live there; when we took her, we took her from out of a bed with a man, but she did not pretend to say that was her husband; she told the justice her husband was dead.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My husband was living then, he was a soldier, he took the things, and put them into another woman's lap, and he and she went away together.</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. I never saw no man come after her, except a person that said he had had her under cure for a bad distemper; he said she ow'd him some money.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600910-10-verdict53" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600910-10-verdict53" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
