<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17600709-20">
               <interp inst="t17600709-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600709-20" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600709-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600709"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600709-20" type="date" value="17600709"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600709-20-off108-c167" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600709-20-defend202 t17600709-20-off108 t17600709-20-verdict111"></join>
         
               <p>229. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17600709-20-defend202" type="defendantName">
                     Margaret 
                     Edwards 
                  <interp inst="t17600709-20-defend202" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-20-defend202" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-20-defend202" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17600709-20-deflabel107" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600709-20-defend202 t17600709-20-deflabel107"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17600709-20-off108" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600709-20-off108" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-20-off108" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               making an assault upon 
                     
                        <persName id="t17600709-20-victim204" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Linton 
                        <interp inst="t17600709-20-victim204" type="surname" value="Linton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600709-20-victim204" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600709-20-victim204" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600709-20-off108 t17600709-20-victim204"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in her dwelling house, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and taking from his person 3 guineas, his property, and against his will
            </rs>, <rs id="t17600709-20-cd109" type="crimeDate">June 9</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600709-20-off108 t17600709-20-cd109"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600709-20-person205">
                  William 
                  Linton 
               <interp inst="t17600709-20-person205" type="surname" value="Linton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-20-person205" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-20-person205" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a little house in <placeName id="t17600709-20-crimeloc110">Long lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17600709-20-crimeloc110" type="placeName" value="Long lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17600709-20-crimeloc110" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600709-20-off108 t17600709-20-crimeloc110"></join>; I had been at Knights bridge on the 9th of June, and staid there part of the evening; coming home, just as I came out of Broad St. Giles's, into Holborn, the prisoner at the bar was walking along as I was. Said I, I believe this is my way to Smithfield; said she, I am going that way. Soon after she said, as we walk together let's drink together; said I, that is no way unserviceable; this was near Middle Row; she went to a house, and push'd the door open, and went in; said I this is not a public house, we cannot have a pint of beer here; there was a bed, she took and pushed me cross it, and flung her petticoats over my head, and feel upon me; she put her hand in my pocket, in which were 5 guineas. Said I, this is not having a pint of beer, to rob me of my money; then she got up, and went up one pair of stairs, and came down again; said I, you have robb'd me of 3 guineas (I had felt in my pocket and miss'd them) I got hold of her arm; she kept pulling till she got into the street; I call'd the watchman, he came and took her to the watchhouse.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>Linton. I believe it was about 12 o'clock; I had been to pay my rent, and my landlord was not at home; since she has been in custody, several people have come in her name, and offer'd me my money if I would be favourable to her.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What day of the week was this?</p>
               <p>Linton. It was on Monday the 9th of June.</p>
               <p>Q. Had she spoke to you before you did to her?</p>
               <p>Linton. I believe I spoke first, but I will not be positive.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176007090016"></xptr>Q. Did you ask her to go with you?</p>
               <p>Linton. No, I did not; she ask'd me to go and drink a pint of beer together.</p>
               <p>Q. Whereabouts in Holborn was this?</p>
               <p>Linton. It was just before we came to Middle Row, she turn'd down on the right hand.</p>
               <p>Q. When you was before my Lord Mayor, where did you say you had been robb'd?</p>
               <p>Linton. I said it was in Magpye alley, I never was there before, nor since.</p>
               <p>Q. What money had you in your pocket?</p>
               <p>Linton. I had 5 guineas, and 5 shillings in silver; the silver was in the bottom of my pocket, and the gold wrapp'd in a piece of paper.</p>
               <p>Q. What room was this bed in?</p>
               <p>Linton. As soon as we entered the house, there was a bed on the first floor, on the left hand as I went in.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any conversation with the prisoner in that room?</p>
               <p>Linton. I said this is not a public house, you cannot have a pint of beer here; no sooner was the word out of my mouth, but she struck me with a push, and I fell down, and she over me.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Whether you did not ask me to lie down upon the bed?</p>
               <p>Linton. Upon my oath I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you push her down?</p>
               <p>Linton. I never touched her, till I catch'd her hand in my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you made any overtures to her to give her any money.</p>
               <p>Linton. No, I had not; she had a very good cardinal on, and I thought her more like a motherly woman than one of that kind.</p>
               <p>Q. Were all the 5 guineas wrapp'd up together?</p>
               <p>Linton. They were.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it possible, she could out of 5 guineas, wrapt in a bit of paper, take 3?</p>
               <p>Linton. She broke the paper. At the watchhouse I produced the 2 guineas, and the piece of paper which she had broke through.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you set out from Knights bridge?</p>
               <p>Linton. I set out from thence at about 11 o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you put that money in the paper?</p>
               <p>Linton. When I was in Grigg street, I call'd on a friend.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this woman all you met with in your way?</p>
               <p>Linton. I met with several people before I met with her, but I had no conversation with any of them.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was you before you charg'd the prisoner, after you came out of that house in Magpye alley?</p>
               <p>Linton. As soon as possible, she came into the street, I call'd and the watchman came to my assistance.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say, when she took your money?</p>
               <p>Linton. Not a word, good not bad, but pushed me down, and put her hand in my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober?</p>
               <p>Linton. I had been drinking some rum and water, but I was no way at all disguised; this is the paper the money was in (producing a piece of paper that was torne)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600709-20-person206">
                  Edward 
                  Belamy 
               <interp inst="t17600709-20-person206" type="surname" value="Belamy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-20-person206" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-20-person206" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watchman; the clock was ready to strike one when I heard the prosecutor call watch; I was in Castle yard; Magpye alley is infested with such people as this is. I have seen her frequently about on nights; I saw the man and woman standing at the Castle door together, I went and took her to the constable of the night; the prosecutor charg'd her with picking his pocket of 3 guineas; he show'd us the torne paper and the 2 guineas at the watchhouse.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the woman say?</p>
               <p>Belamy. She said nothing to me, nor I to her.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I had been in Long acre, and I met this man; he pushed against me 2 or 3 times, and said Betty, if you'll come and lie down I'll give you a shilling: I said go along, or I'll call the watchman; I call'd the watch, he never did; when the watchman came, he said this woman has pick'd my pocket of 3 guineas. I desired to be searched.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Was the prisoner searched?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No, she was not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I gave the watchman charge of the man; I saw a man and woman run down Magpye alley, he was in another woman's house, it was not in mine; I was in no house upon my word and honour; he desired to make it up with me on the last day of June.</p>
               <p>Q. to watchman. Did the prisoner give you charge of the prosecutor?</p>
               <p>Watchman. No, she did not.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Are you certain this is the woman?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176007090017"></xptr>Prosecutor. I am sure of that.</p>
               <p>Q. to watchman. How far from her own house did you take her into custody?</p>
               <p>Watchman. The very next door to her own.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600709-20-person207">
                  Esther 
                  Connely 
               <interp inst="t17600709-20-person207" type="surname" value="Connely"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-20-person207" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-20-person207" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about 7 or 8 years; she went to market along with me, and we shared fish together.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her character?</p>
               <p>E. Connely. I never knew nothing of her but that of a sober honest woman.</p>
               <p>Q. Does she get her living by that now?</p>
               <p>E. Connel. She does, and works very hard for her living.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600709-20-person208">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Salmon 
               <interp inst="t17600709-20-person208" type="surname" value="Salmon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-20-person208" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-20-person208" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her about 7 years, she lived by selling fish, and sometimes by selling of fruit, according as fruit was; she was always a very hard working woman for her family, always just and honest.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600709-20-person209">
                  Ann 
                  Stunt 
               <interp inst="t17600709-20-person209" type="surname" value="Stunt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-20-person209" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-20-person209" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her about 4 or 5 years; she sold fish, and sometimes went to Leadenhall market; she was very industrious, and has the character of a honest woman, and always paid her way.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600709-20-person210">
                  Samuel 
                  Stuberfield 
               <interp inst="t17600709-20-person210" type="surname" value="Stuberfield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-20-person210" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-20-person210" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her betwixt 6 and 7 years; she gets her living by selling of fish, and so do I; she is very honest as far as ever I knew.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600709-20-person211">
                  Jane 
                  Shoen 
               <interp inst="t17600709-20-person211" type="surname" value="Shoen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-20-person211" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-20-person211" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her 2 years; I lived servant with her a year, she gave me 52 shillings a year; I have been come away from her 2 months; I went out for her with fish in the winter time, and fruit in the summer; she bera s the character of an honest woman, as far as ever I heard or saw; she always bid me go to bed in good hours when I came home, that I might get up in the morning.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600709-20-person212">
                  Mary
                   M. Coone
               <interp inst="t17600709-20-person212" type="surname" value="M. Coone"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-20-person212" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-20-person212" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her going on 7 years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her character?</p>
               <p>M. M. Coone. Her character is selling fruit, and to go to market.</p>
               <p>Q. Is she look'd upon to be honest or dishonest?</p>
               <p>M. M. Coone. She was always an honest woman, as far as ever I heard; I liv'd with her the same time as this happened.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600709-20-verdict111" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600709-20-verdict111" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
