<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680518-20">
               <interp inst="t17680518-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680518-20" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680518-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680518"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680518-20" type="date" value="17680518"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680518-20-off102-c187" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680518-20-defend234 t17680518-20-off102 t17680518-20-verdict104"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680518-20-off102-c188" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680518-20-defend236 t17680518-20-off102 t17680518-20-verdict104"></join>
         
               <p>362, 363. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17680518-20-defend234" type="defendantName">
                     Frances 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17680518-20-defend234" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-20-defend234" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-20-defend234" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17680518-20-defend236" type="defendantName">
                     Anne 
                     Davis 
                  <interp inst="t17680518-20-defend236" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-20-defend236" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-20-defend236" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17680518-20-deflabel101" type="occupation">spinsters</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680518-20-defend234 t17680518-20-deflabel101"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680518-20-defend236 t17680518-20-deflabel101"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17680518-20-off102" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680518-20-off102" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-20-off102" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one moidore, twenty-six guineas, four half guineas, a 5 s. 3 d. piece, and half a crown
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17680518-20-victim238" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Ringrose 
                  <interp inst="t17680518-20-victim238" type="surname" value="Ringrose"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-20-victim238" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-20-victim238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680518-20-off102 t17680518-20-victim238"></join>
                  </persName>
               
            , <placeName id="t17680518-20-crimeloc103">April 20</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17680518-20-crimeloc103" type="placeName" value="April 20"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17680518-20-crimeloc103" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680518-20-off102 t17680518-20-crimeloc103"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680518-20-person239">
                  John 
                  Ringrose 
               <interp inst="t17680518-20-person239" type="surname" value="Ringrose"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-20-person239" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-20-person239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in White's-ground near Barnaby-street, Surry. On the 20th of April the prisoner picked me up upon Tower-hill, and asked me to give her a pint of beer, as I was going to Whitechapel to see an acquaintance; I took her to the Ship and Horseshoe in Nightingale-lane, and gave her a pint of beer; then she desired me to go with her to her lodging; I went with her, there she asked me to lie with her; she said I should not, except I give her three shillings; I said I should not; at last I gave her half a crown, out of that she fetched a quartern of gin; she gave the watchman some, we drank it, I had seen no body else; I undressed myself, and we went to bed; I put my breeches under my pillow, and laid my clothes upon the bed; the other prisoner came in, and put her hand over my head, and took my breeches, and put the candle out, and took out my watch and money; I saw her take them; I went to follow her, and Smith held me; after that I went down stairs, and found my breeches and watch upon the stairs; I came up stairs again, and put my clothes on; after that 
               <persName id="t17680518-20-person240">
                  Anne 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17680518-20-person240" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-20-person240" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-20-person240" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             brought a candle up; I went out, and called the watch; he called the constable, and we took them both; they were searched, but I did not find my money.</p>
               <p>Q. What money did you lose?</p>
               <p>Ringrose. I lost twenty-six guineas, four half guineas, a twenty-seven shilling piece, a 5 s. 3 d. piece, and half a crown in silver; my money was in a brown paper; I was intending to put it out to use with my master, we had been talking about it two or three days before; I know I had my money in my pocket when I pulled my breeches off, the gold in one pocket, and silver in the other.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know either of the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Ringrose. No, I never saw either of them before.</p>
               <p>Q. Where had you been that day?</p>
               <p>Ringrose. I had been at work in the brew house all the day from five in the morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober?</p>
               <p>Ringrose. I was, I had drank but two pints of beer and a quartern of gin the whole day.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to let her take your breeches, you say you saw her take them?</p>
               <p>Ringrose. I was startled, and the other held me; I followed her as fast as I could.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is this lodging?</p>
               <p>Ringrose. It is in Redcross-street, No 19, near East Smithfield, a private house, up two pair of stairs, a fore room.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to go into a place you knew nothing of, with a woman you knew nothing of, with so much money in your pocket?</p>
               <p>Ringrose. She enticed me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680518-20-person241">
                  Archibald 
                  Moslin 
               <interp inst="t17680518-20-person241" type="surname" value="Moslin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-20-person241" type="given" value="Archibald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-20-person241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable, the prosecutor came to me to the watch-house for assistance; I went with him, we took the two prisoners, and searched them, but found nothing upon them; they said they knew nothing about what he charged them with, and they said the same before the Justice.</p>
               <p>Smith's defence.</p>
               <p>I went over Tower-hill with this young woman (meaning Davis) and another young woman, and three men; we went in at the Nag's Head on Tower-hill, and had some beer; it wanted about five minutes of ten o'clock; when we came out two of the young men, and this young woman, and another, turned to go upon the hill; I went to go towards East Smithfield; the prosecutor came up to me, and asked me where I was going; I said home; said he, will you let me go with you; I said, if your way is my way you may; he said he was going towards East Smithfield; they were putting lights up; he said, what do they do that for; I said, I believe they did it for<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176805180013"></xptr> Mr. Wilkes; he said, will you have any thing to drink; I said, what you please; we went in at the Ship and Horseshoe, and had a pint of beer, we drank it; then he got up, and went to the gentlewoman at the bar, and changed some money; he said at the bench of Justices it was a 5 s. 3 d. piece; then he asked me to go home, we went to my lodging together up into a two pair of stairs room; we made a bargain; he gave me half a crown; I asked him for something to drink; he said he could afford no more, but if I behaved well he would make me amends another time; I went down, and fetched a pint of beer; then we both went to bed directly; this young woman Davis, lodges in a one pair of stairs room in the same house; she came and asked me to lend her a bit of a candle, she drank part of the beer, and bid us a good night, and we both lay down; I went to sleep, I believe it might then be about eleven o'clock; when I awaked about twelve he was crying in the middle of the room; I asked him what was the matter, he was several minutes before he would give me an answer; he at last said he was robbed; I said, of what; he said, of 30 l. I said, what was it in; he said, a piece of paper; he called for a light, and Davis brought him in one; he catched hold of her hand, and said, you are the woman, where is my money; I never was out of his presence from the time I came from Tower-hill with him till he charged the constable with me; he cried and said it was his master's money; there was only 2 s. 2 d. halfpenny found upon me, that he said he gave me.</p>
               <p>To Smith's character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680518-20-person242">
                  Anne 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17680518-20-person242" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-20-person242" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-20-person242" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am no relation to her, she was brought up in a very sober manner, and was reckoned a good servant; she has been drawed away I believe by very bad company.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680518-20-person243">
                  Grace 
                  Bentley 
               <interp inst="t17680518-20-person243" type="surname" value="Bentley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-20-person243" type="given" value="Grace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-20-person243" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Smith from a child, she bore a very good character when a servant; I can say nothing to her character now.</p>
               <p>Davis's defence.</p>
               <p>I went up stairs with a candle, he was lying by the side of the young woman in bed; I know nothing what he had about him, I never saw none of his money.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17680518-20-verdict104" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680518-20-verdict104" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
