<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670909-19">
               <interp inst="t17670909-19" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670909-19" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670909-19" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670909"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670909-19" type="date" value="17670909"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670909-19-off116-c255" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-19-defend294 t17670909-19-off116 t17670909-19-verdict120"></join>
         
               <p>430. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17670909-19-defend294" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Cooper 
                  <interp inst="t17670909-19-defend294" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-19-defend294" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-19-defend294" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for that <rs id="t17670909-19-off116" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670909-19-off116" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-19-off116" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he, on the king's highway, on Sarah, <rs id="t17670909-19-viclabel117" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-19-victim298 t17670909-19-viclabel117"></join> of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17670909-19-victim296" type="victimName">
                           George 
                           Holland 
                        <interp inst="t17670909-19-victim296" type="surname" value="Holland"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670909-19-victim296" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670909-19-victim296" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , did make an assault, putting her in corporal fear and danger of her life, and taking from her person six silver medals, value 6 s. two guineas, two half guineas, a crown piece, and a shilling, the property of the said George
            </rs>, <rs id="t17670909-19-cd118" type="crimeDate">August 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-19-off116 t17670909-19-cd118"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
               
                  <persName id="t17670909-19-victim298" type="victimName">
                     Sarah 
                     Holland 
                  <interp inst="t17670909-19-victim298" type="surname" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-19-victim298" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-19-victim298" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             I am wife to 
               <persName id="t17670909-19-person299">
                  George 
                  Holland 
               <interp inst="t17670909-19-person299" type="surname" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-19-person299" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-19-person299" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; on the 12th of August we had been out an airing, going back to Twickenham we were stopt about thirty yards on this side Mr. Whitefield's chapel, near <placeName id="t17670909-19-crimeloc119">Strawberry hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17670909-19-crimeloc119" type="placeName" value="Strawberry hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17670909-19-crimeloc119" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-19-off116 t17670909-19-crimeloc119"></join>; there were two ladies in the coach with me, I sat backwards, I heard somebody call, Stop, stop; the coachman did not stop; then a man rode up to him, and bid him stop, or he would blow his brains out; he did; then the man rode up to us, and desired us to deliver our purses, which we did; he had a pistol in his hand; I desired him not to put it to the coach; he said he would not hurt a hair of our heads, and behaved very civil to us; there was in my purse two guineas, two half guineas, three pocket-pieces, a crown piece, and I believe there might be a shilling or two; he went off in a very little time; I think he rode a bay horse, it was so dark I could not discern the man's face; I saw there was another man on horseback.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-19-person300">
                  Robert 
                  Spooner 
               <interp inst="t17670909-19-person300" type="surname" value="Spooner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-19-person300" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-19-person300" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a cabin maker; I was with the prisoner in this robbery; he is a perriwig-maker, and lived in Mount-Street; he and I are both journeymen; he and I stopped a coach near Twickenham, between nine and ten in the evening; we took about three guineas from them; we had three purses; it was I that called to the coachman to stop, and I took the money; I had a pistol, but did not present it; the prisoner was behind the coach with the footman; there were some dollars and pocket-pieces; we threw them and the purses away, and spent the money; my horse was of a chestnut colour.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-19-person301">
                  John 
                  Gilbert 
               <interp inst="t17670909-19-person301" type="surname" value="Gilbert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-19-person301" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-19-person301" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am coachman to Mr. Nobbs of Twickenham; I was out with the coach; coming home by Strawberry hill, two men came behind us; they bid me stop several times before I did; one of them pulled out a pistol; then I stopped; he went to the coach, and robbed the ladies; the other man was behind with my fellow servant; I cannot swear to either of them; he that robbed the ladies rode a horse that seemed to be a bay horse, with a switch tail, and he seemed to have a surtout coat on.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-19-person302">
                  Samuel 
                  Prosser 
               <interp inst="t17670909-19-person302" type="surname" value="Prosser"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-19-person302" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-19-person302" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am footman to Mr. Nobbs; I was on horseback; just as we came into the common field near Strawberry hill, a man on a bay horse came riding up; then he turned back, and met a man on a gray horse; they came up almost a broad side me, and followed us about 200 yards; then the man on the bay horse rode up to the coachman, and ordered him to stop; and the man on the gray horse came up to me, and demanded me to stop; then the first man turned his horse round to the ladies, and demanded their money; the moon was just getting up, it was dark; I cannot say any thing to either of the men; the man by me appeared to have his own hair, and I believe a surtout coat. (The prisoner had his own hair.)</p>
               <p>Mr. Higgins. I belong to General Elliot. On the 17th of August, I saw the prisoner and evidence, with two of our serjeants, at Kensington barracks, at the suttling house; Spooner pulled out half a Spanish dollar, and offered to sell it; (produced in court,) and he proposed to bring a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176709090030"></xptr> French crown in the morning, or forfeit a shilling.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs. Holland. Was your's a French crown?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Holland. No, mine was an English one.</p>
               <p>Higgins. I think Cooper paid the reckoning, and they went away. The man that offered 2 s. for the half dollar and I went to town together. I saw in the news paper two men described, answering the description of the prisoner and evidence, that had robbed a coach; they had told their names over night; we went and took them; I found this piece here produced upon Spooner. Cooper had 3 s. in money in his pocket; I asked which of them rode the gray horse; one of them replied I, but I cannot say which; they were taken before Sir 
               <persName id="t17670909-19-person303">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17670909-19-person303" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-19-person303" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-19-person303" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and commit ted.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-19-person304">
                  Adam 
                  Scowers 
               <interp inst="t17670909-19-person304" type="surname" value="Scowers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-19-person304" type="given" value="Adam"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-19-person304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I keep a broker's shop in Holbourn; the evidence said at Sir 
               <persName id="t17670909-19-person305">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17670909-19-person305" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-19-person305" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-19-person305" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, they bought the pistols at my shop, and described them to me; it is so long ago, I cannot recollect the men; I remember I told an old pair to two young men about that time</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-19-person306">
                  James 
                  Draper 
               <interp inst="t17670909-19-person306" type="surname" value="Draper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-19-person306" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-19-person306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a stable-keeper in Swallow-street; a man that I knew thirty years asked me if I could let a friend of his a horse; he fetched his friend; then his friend said they should want another; I let them have two, one a chestnut, the other a gray one; two young men went out on them; they were to return that night, but they did not; they went out on the 8th of August; they did not come home till the Thursday night after, betwixt eleven and twelve o'clock; I enquired after them, as they kept them so long, and found out their names, and who they were apprentices to, and where they lived. About ten or eleven, on the Friday morning, a woman came, and let me know there was such a man came to her house in King-street, Golden-square; I went to him, and asked him if he had not been out with two of my horses, and what was his name; he said his name was Spooner, (the evidence) and that he had had my horses; he asked what the hire came to; I said three guineas; he had but two; he gave me them, and was to bring the other; I never saw the prisoner till I saw him at Sir 
               <persName id="t17670909-19-person307">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17670909-19-person307" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-19-person307" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-19-person307" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's; I was in the yard when they mounted, but did not observe them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing of the robbery.</p>
               <p>He called 
               <persName id="t17670909-19-person308">
                  Bernard 
                  Gregory 
               <interp inst="t17670909-19-person308" type="surname" value="Gregory"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-19-person308" type="given" value="Bernard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-19-person308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , with whom he served his time, and five other persons, who gave him a good character.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17670909-19-verdict120" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670909-19-verdict120" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
