<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670429-49">
               <interp inst="t17670429-49" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670429-49" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670429-49" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670429"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670429-49" type="date" value="17670429"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670429-49-off267-c334" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-49-defend439 t17670429-49-off267 t17670429-49-verdict271"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670429-49-off267-c335" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-49-defend441 t17670429-49-off267 t17670429-49-verdict273"></join>
         
               <p>245, 246. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17670429-49-defend439" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17670429-49-defend439" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-49-defend439" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-49-defend439" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17670429-49-defend441" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Hale 
                  <interp inst="t17670429-49-defend441" type="surname" value="Hale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-49-defend441" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-49-defend441" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17670429-49-off267" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670429-49-off267" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-49-off267" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing a gelding of a chesnut colour, value 61.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17670429-49-victim443" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Lacy 
                  <interp inst="t17670429-49-victim443" type="surname" value="Lacy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-49-victim443" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-49-victim443" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-49-off267 t17670429-49-victim443"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17670429-49-cd268" type="crimeDate">October 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-49-off267 t17670429-49-cd268"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-49-person444">
                  John 
                  Lacy 
               <interp inst="t17670429-49-person444" type="surname" value="Lacy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-49-person444" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-49-person444" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the White Lion, Kitts End, about a mile beyond Barnet. I came to <placeName id="t17670429-49-crimeloc269">Smithfield</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17670429-49-crimeloc269" type="placeName" value="Smithfield"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17670429-49-crimeloc269" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-49-off267 t17670429-49-crimeloc269"></join> on the 24th of October, and put my horse up at Mr. Leader's, at <placeName id="t17670429-49-crimeloc270">the King's Head</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17670429-49-crimeloc270" type="placeName" value="the King's Head"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17670429-49-crimeloc270" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-49-off267 t17670429-49-crimeloc270"></join>; a horse of a bright chesnut colour, bald face, flaxen mane and tail, about fifteen hands high; he was lost out of the stable, and about three weeks after he was advertised, and the man that had him was in Ipswich goal. I went there and found Smith in person; I said, you dog, is it you; you lived with 
               <persName id="t17670429-49-person445">
                  Thomas 
                  Warren 
               <interp inst="t17670429-49-person445" type="surname" value="Warren"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-49-person445" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-49-person445" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in Pierpool-lane about two years ago. Ay master, he said, it is me. I found my horse at a place called Stourton near Diss, about twenty two miles on the side hand. I said to Smith, how came you to take my horse away; he said it was through necessity that he did it; I asked him where the saddle was, he would not tell me; I said, I'll call again in about two hours, may be you will consider of it. I went again, then he told me it was at the sign of the Cock, at a place called Clare; there I found it, after I had been for my horse. I know nothing of the other prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-49-person446">
                  John 
                  Field 
               <interp inst="t17670429-49-person446" type="surname" value="Field"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-49-person446" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-49-person446" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am sixteen years old. Mr. Lacy came one market-day, and put his horse up at the King's Head in Smithfield, where I live; he saw me tie him up in the stable; I did not take his bridle and saddle off. Then Mr. Lacy went into the market; my master sent me of an errand; when I came back, Mr. Lacy came and called for his horse and he was gone; it was a chesnut coloured horse.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-49-person447">
                  James 
                  Hewit 
               <interp inst="t17670429-49-person447" type="surname" value="Hewit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-49-person447" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-49-person447" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a public-house at Stourton in Norfolk. I was in my yard; I heard a horse rush out at my gate; I stood a little while to hear what could be the meaning of it; this was between seven and eight at night, on the 27th of October: presently I heard a footman and a horseman come out at the same gate; they made towards Bury. They made a full stop, and came both right back again up into the field. I thought they were after no good; I went and told a neighbour there were some men after the horse; he, his father, and brother, and I, pursued them into the field; there we took the two prisoners at the bar; Hale had a bridle in his hand, Smith had a halter which he dropped down by the side of the horse he was upon, which the prosecutor owns. I asked him to dismount, he said he would not: I said to the boy that was on the other side, have a care; for what, said Smith, I have no fire-arms. We took them before the Justice the next day, and they were committed to Ipswich goal, the horse was delivered into the constable's hands, who took care of him till Mr. Lacy came. The horse was brought to my house, there he saw and swore to him.</p>
               <p>Lacy. The horse I saw there was my horse.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-49-person448">
                  Samuel 
                  Weaver 
               <interp inst="t17670429-49-person448" type="surname" value="Weaver"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-49-person448" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-49-person448" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             Being told there were some people in the field after my horses, I made after them. Hale came running down in a great hurry. I said, halloo; he made no answer; I gave him a little nap on his crown and knocked him down; he got up and came at me; I got the fall of him, and when he was down I catch'd hold of a bridle he had in his hand, but I found he was too strong for me; then I called out for help, we secured him, and took him to the public-house; (the bridle produced) Smith was on horseback; he came up out of the turnips the moment I had caught Hale; we took him, and the next day we took them to the Justice, and they were both committed to Ipswich goal.</p>
               <p>Smith's defence.</p>
               <p>I went to Smithfield, I there asked the prosecutor for a job: he desired the boy to deliver the horse to me, for me to ride him about the market. I rode him about; there came a one-eyed man, and told me where my mare was that I had lost; he said she was down in Norfolk; I rode away directly on Mr. Lacy's horse to see after her; there was no mare. Coming back I met Hale; I thought I saw my mare in a field, I sent him down; he came to me and said there is never a one. I said I saw one over the hedge; he said do you go. I went down to see, and they came and took us.</p>
               <p>Hale's defence.</p>
               <p>Smith came to a place where I was. He said he had lost a mare. I asked him who he had her of; he said of one 
               <persName id="t17670429-49-person449">
                  Isaac 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17670429-49-person449" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-49-person449" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-49-person449" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; he told me her marks. I went with him; coming back he thought he saw her; he said to me, Tom, will you go and see whether it is my mare; I went and came back again, and told him she was not there; he would not believe me; then we both went down, and they came and took us.</p>
               <p>Smith <rs id="t17670429-49-verdict271" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670429-49-verdict271" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17670429-49-punish272" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670429-49-punish272" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-49-defend439 t17670429-49-punish272"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Hale <rs id="t17670429-49-verdict273" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670429-49-verdict273" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
