<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17620526-18">
               <interp inst="t17620526-18" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620526-18" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620526-18" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17620526"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620526-18" type="date" value="17620526"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620526-18-off93-c150" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620526-18-defend179 t17620526-18-off93 t17620526-18-verdict95"></join>
         
               <p>171. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17620526-18-defend179" type="defendantName">
                     Jane 
                     Sibson 
                  <interp inst="t17620526-18-defend179" type="surname" value="Sibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-defend179" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-defend179" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17620526-18-deflabel92" type="occupation">Widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620526-18-defend179 t17620526-18-deflabel92"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17620526-18-off93" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-off93" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-off93" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pettyTreason"></interp>
               that she, not having God before her eyes, but being moved by the instigation of the devil, of malice aforethought, contriving and intending to deprive George her husband of life, feloniously and traiterously to kill and murder, did mix a great quantity of mortal poison called corrosive sublimate, or white mercury, on bread with butter, which by her persuasion he did eat and swallow down, of which he languished from the <rs id="t17620526-18-cd94" type="crimeDate">23d of April</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620526-18-off93 t17620526-18-cd94"></join> till the 26th of the same month, and then died; by which means she the said Jane him the said George did kill and murder.
            </rs>*</p> 
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620526-18-person180">
                  Ann 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17620526-18-person180" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person180" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person180" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live servant with Mrs. Martin at Longford; she is the prisoner's mother; the prisoner lived with her. Mr. Sibson, the deceased, came down to her house on Shrove Tuesday the 23d of February; he had been lately come to England; that was the first day that ever I saw him.</p>
               <p>Q. What state of health did he appear in?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. He did not complain that day. The next day he went to London, and staid all night; the day after he came down to Longford, and then complained of his bowels. He staid at Longford<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176205260014"></xptr> till the Monday, and then went to London again. When he came from London on the Thursday after, he appeared very indifferent, and complained of a cold and cough.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he on the Friday?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. I can't say he complained that day, but he never seemed well.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he on the Saturday?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. I really can't recollect how he was that day. He went to London on the Monday, and Mrs. Sibson went up to him on the Tuesday, and they came back together on the Saturday following, and Mr. M'Coon came down with them. Then Mr. Sibson had a very bad cold, and looked very ill. He staid till the Monday, and then went to London again, and did not come down to Longford till the Tuesday se'nnight after. He had lodgings in Maiden-alley; when he came back, he was very bad with a cold, and coughed very much; he always said London did not agree with him. He staid then at Longford from the Tuesday till the Friday, then he returned to town again. He staid in London till the last time of his going down, which was on the 6th of April; he was then very ill.</p>
               <p>Q. What day was the 6th of April of?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. It was on a Tuesday; he came in between 12 and one at noon; he went and laid down on the bed before he had been in the house many minutes; then he staid there till he died.</p>
               <p>Q. How often did Mrs. Sibson go to London with him?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. She went twice to town, the second time of his going, and the last; but she went the day after him both times; he went on the Monday, and she the Tuesday; the last time he went on the Friday, and she on the Monday; the last time they returned they came in the stage-coach together.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he die?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. He died on the 26th of April.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you attend him all the time till he died?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. I did not attend him so much at first as towards the latter part of the time.</p>
               <p>Q. During the time he was there, till the 26th, describe his disorder?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. The first week he was there he complained very much of his head, sides, and stomach, and had a violent cough; he said the cough gave him pain in his sides; he coughed very much.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he troubled with reachings?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. I never saw him reach but once; that was about a week before he died, upon taking a medicine; I was not long together with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever sit up with him?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. I did one night, the last night but three before he died.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he any bloody stools?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. He had some, and a great purging upon him very often.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear him complain of gripings in his bowels?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. I can't say I ever did.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he complain of that night you sat up with him?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. I can't say he complained of any thing in particular that night, he was very thirsty.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never hear him make any complaint with respect to his mouth?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember any thing of a chamber-pot that had something in it?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. That was about 10 days after he came to Longford, the first night that I sat up with him, a Thursday night, and the Friday morning I saw the chamber-pot; I sat up with him till one o'clock on Friday morning, and Mrs. Sibson sat up with him after I went to-bed. I took away the chamber-pot on the Friday morning about 7 o'clock; it was standing upon the hearth in the room. When I went to empty it, it would not come clear with cold water, and I washed it with warm water. I did not take particular notice of it, it looked to be white and greasy.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a greasiness swimming on the water, or sticking to the sides of the pot?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. It stuck to the sides of the pot, and would not come off.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any conversation with Mrs. Sibson concerning any poison?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. No, only on the Friday night or Saturday morning; we were all up in Mr. Sibson's room, she, Mr. Bearblock, Mrs. Martin, the brother to the deceased, and Mrs. Tooth, five of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell what time it was?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. About two o'clock on the Saturday morning; she was in a sit. When I thought she was going into sits, I went down stairs, and called Mr. Bearblock and his brother; she threw herself upon the bed; we got her off the bed from him, and put her on the other side to lie down. Then she said she brought some opium from London with her, and was determined to die when her husband died. After that I went to bed; she said to me after I was in bed, she went down, and cut some bread and butter, and spread opium upon it, and eat some of it, and it made her sick, and she reached in the pot, and she could not eat it all, and she put it into a bit of paper, and left it in a band-box in the window. I got from behind the bed, and went to the bandbox, because I recollected I h ad emptied the pot in the morning. I took it to the table with the candle. When I opened it, I found a bit of news-paper, in which was a bit of bread and butter. The deceased's<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176205260015"></xptr> brother stood next to me; he heard her speak this, I believe. As I was opening one end of the paper to look at it; he took it out of my hand before I could well look at it.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say to you?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. He did not say a word to me, nor I to him; he put it into his pocket. Mr. Bearblock and Mrs. Martin desired to know what was the matter. I took them into another room, and related to them what Mrs. Sibson had told me. Then we went into the room, and desired Mrs. Sibson to get off the bed; we got her into another room.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear Mrs. Sibson give any account of having opium from any other place than London?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. Mrs. Martin asked her where she had it: She said she brought it from America with her, and that she had been used to take opium in America.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. This was a day or two after.</p>
               <p>Q. In what condition was the prisoner as to health and senses then?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. She was in her senses. She said she used to dissolve it in broth, before she spread it on bread and butter.</p>
               <p>Q. In what condition was the deceased before he died?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. He died on the Monday about a quarter after two in the afternoon. On the Saturday night and Sunday morning he was taken much with bloody stools; they continued on the Sunday; and on the Sunday night he was very much convulsed, and sometimes very restless.</p>
               <p>Q. On the Thursday night before he died, did you leave him and her together?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. He had been very ill, and was very ill when I left him at night, and on Friday he was very ill.</p>
               <p>Q. How did she behave to him?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. She behaved with a great deal of love and affection towards him; I know nobody fonder of one another.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go to London with the prisoner, and at what time?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. I did, about six in the evening; we went to Bearbinders Lane, and that night we went to the Commons.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of her writing a letter to the undertaker?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. She wrote a letter to the undertaker before she went to London; she wrote that about a quarter of an hour after he died.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of any application made for the body to be opened?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. Mr. Sibson, the brother, came about half an hour after two on the Monday, about a quarter of an hour after his death; he asked how his brother did. They told him he was departed. He said, Mrs. Sibson, have you a mind to have him opened?</p>
               <p>Q. Recollect the words as near as you can?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. She made him but very little answer. Before that, I had heard a conversation between Mrs. Martin, Mrs. Bearblock, and the prisoner. The prisoner told me she had mentioned it to Mr. Bearblock, and he had dissuaded her from it.</p>
               <p>Q. What was that?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. She said, that if he died, she would have him opened, and have his heart to keep.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never hear Mrs. Sibson, before he was so ill, talk of an intention, that whoever died first, the survivor was to have the other's heart, to be put into a silver cup, and kept in the room where they lay?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. I have heard her speak of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you now in mourning for him?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. I am.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not Mr. Sibson go to Windsor to be let blood?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. He did; that was on the Wednesday or Thursday, I think the first or second day after he came the last time to Longford.</p>

               <p>Q. Did Mr. Tyrrell come to Longford?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. He did; he came with him the day after he went to be blooded, and Mr. Sibson's brother came also in the chaise with him.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is Windsor from Longford?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. It is about six miles.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Tyrrell treat him as a person consumptive?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. He blooded and blistered him, and gave him stuff for his cough. I heard Mrs. Sibson ask Mr. Tyrrell, if he thought his case dangerous? He said, No.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was this before he died?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. This was a week before. She said, Sir, I beg you will not flatter me, that I may have farther advice. He said, he was not in danger, there was no occasion for it, and he would have him come to Windsor in a day or two, and that it was want of better spirits that kept him so low. He said, if he had better spirits, he would eat and drink heartily, and would soon be well.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he capable of eating?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. He eat but very little, and that was spoon meat; he once eat a pigeon, that was about a fortnight before he died?</p>
               <p>Q. How long before he died did he eat any bread and butter?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. I don't know; when he drank a dish of tea, he did not eat any thing. I never saw him eat any thing but spoon meat (except the pigeon), and when he has had bread in it, he has left that.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176205260016"></xptr>Q. When was a doctor called in?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. Dr. Lucas was sent for on the Thursday night, he lives at Windsor. Mr. Tyrrell advised him to go out every day. On that day he and Mrs. Sibson went out in a chaise, and in the evening he was very deaf, and we were forced to speak very loud to him. Mrs. Sibson left word with Mrs. Martin, that if the brother came before they returned, for him to go back to Windsor to call Dr. Lucas; and if Mr. Tyrrell came, to stay till Dr. Lucas came. Mr. Tyrrell came, and he wrote a note to Dr. Lucas, and he came. Dr. Lucas came on Friday morning, and Dr. Hays on the Saturday; after that Mrs. Sibson was desirous of having Dr. Porthergill: he could not come.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner in her senses, do you think, when she talked of the bread and butter?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. I think she was out of her senses by reason of grief and affliction.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you see how that bread and butter looked?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. It did not look thin to me; it was a very little bit, about three fingers breadth. There was another piece of bread and butter produced at the same time before the coroner.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you say it was not the same?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. Really that bread and butter that I saw before the coroner was something thinner than what I saw in the bandbox, and seemed to be broader; I do think in myself that it could not be the bread and butter that I had seen before.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any talk with Mr. Sibson in the garden, of what he had done with that piece of bread and butter?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. On the Saturday, when he was gone out at the door, I said to him, Mr. Sibson. what have you done with the bread and butter that I took out of the bandbox last night? Said he, I threw it over the wall into the water.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you present when Mr. Sibson said he had thrown some of it into the fire, and it burnt like gunpowder?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. On the Monday after my master died, when he came from Windsor, he inquired for me very much; he came into my room, and asked me what I wanted the bread and butter for? I said, Not for any thing, but to see what was upon it. O, said he, I kept it, it was not opium, it was white arsenic, and Mr. Tyrrell told him so. He said, when he came home, he had two little girls; he asked them, which of them will have a bit of bread and butter: that he broke a little bit of it off, and threw it into the fire, and it burnt like gunpowder: that he went to a shop, and bought some white arsenic, and threw some of that into the fire, and that burnt the same. Mr. Johnson was by; he asked him where he bought it, he refused to tell him.</p>
               <p>Q. When did your master make his will?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. He made his will on that same day that Mrs. Sibson mentioned the bread and butter. Mr. Bearblock and Mr. Sibson were in the room at the time; this was on the Saturday, and he died on the Monday following.</p>
               <p>Q. Did his brother till that time say he had a suspicion that the deceased had not fair play?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. No, not at all, but always said his brother was used very well all the time.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Though you are the prosecutor's witness, I will ask you, had you yourself ever the least suspicion of your mistress having poisoned your master, or having used him ill in any respect?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. No, I never had.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you think your master died of?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. I think he was in a very deep consumption.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you in your conscience believe your mistress was not an affectionate good wife?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. As affectionate and good a wife as any I ever saw in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Tyrrell ever in your hearing express any suspicion of foul play?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620526-18-person181">
                  A.
                   Wright No
               <interp inst="t17620526-18-person181" type="surname" value="Wright No"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person181" type="given" value="A."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person181" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , never in his life. I heard Mr. Tyrrell say before Mr. Fielding he did not see the bread and butter till the Monday morning; and he said, For God's sake, flee away to Longford, and perhaps, if alive. we may save his life. This he said was to Mr. Sibson; and when Mr. Sibson came, he came on foot.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear Mr. Tyrrell, before justice Fielding, say, that Dr. Lucas had told him your master did not die a natural death?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620526-18-person182">
                  A.
                   Wright I
               <interp inst="t17620526-18-person182" type="surname" value="Wright I"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person182" type="given" value="A."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person182" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             can't say I heard that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620526-18-person183">
                  James 
                  Bearblock 
               <interp inst="t17620526-18-person183" type="surname" value="Bearblock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person183" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person183" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I saw the deceased I believe the day after he arrived at Longford, that day he came to my house; I was very glad to see him, and told him I never saw him look so well in my life, and it was taken notice of by all the neighbours in general. I saw him again that evening at the horse-shoe in Newgate-street; it was a general remark among all his acquaintance, how well he looked. I saw him several times afterwards; he dined at our house, it may be ten days after, and he was extremely well then I saw him two or three times a week after this, till the time he was laid up at Longford.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did he begin to complain?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. He began to complain about three weeks after he came here. I called at Mrs. Sibson's lodgings. She told me he was not well. I told him to go into the country for a little air, that might being him about.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he complain of?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. He complained that he was not well.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he complain of any thing in particular?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176205260017"></xptr>Bearblock. I heard nothing in particular.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe him to cough?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. I had not heard him cough since he has been over here, more than at other times.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him at Longford?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. His brother came on Friday the 23d of April, and told me he then lay a dying. I went down that afternoon. He said, They desired I would bring down Dr. Fothergill. We went there; the doctor could not go down. Then we went to the Black Bear in Piccadilly, and got to Longford about half an hour after nine o'clock; I found him very bad indeed. About one or two in the morning, as Mrs. Sibson was lying on the bed, by the side of her husband, she said, Mr. Bearblock, I'll be buried with him. I asked her the reason. She told me she had taken some poison, opium spread on bread and butter, and, if that would not do, she had more in the room, and she would take that. The maid immediately ran to a bandbox in the room, and opened it, and put her hand under some things ( caps, I believe), I did not see any thing in her hand; the brother immediately ran after her, and took it out of her hand, I believe. He came immediately after to me, and said he had got it, and jogged me by the elbow. After that, Mrs. Sibson told me, if he died, she would have him opened, and have his heart taken out to keep by her. I told her it was very idle talking, and endeavoured to persuade her to do no such thing, but she insisted upon it. She said to me, Poor Tom abroad will never forgive me for what I have done, as long as he lives (meaning the brother abroad). I said, For God's sake, Mrs. Sibson, what have you done, that Tom abroad will not forgive you? She made answer, she was sure he would never forgive her. Some time before breakfast Mrs. Sibson's mother and she both said Dr. Tyrell was a booby, for he did not understand Mr. Sibson's case, for that he never would believe he was in a consumption. On the Saturday, as we were at dinner, Mrs. Martin said, I told my daughter, the very day that I saw him at Longford, he was a dead man, for he was in a galloping consumption.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Mrs. Sibson by at that time?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. She was at the table. I told her I had seen him the day after she saw him, and was surprised she should think so, for he looked better than ever I saw him in my life. I went away about 6 o'clock that evening, and lay at a friend's house at Arlington, about three miles off. I said I would call again in the morning, but I was afraid I should not see him alive.</p>
               <p>Q. You say you was informed by Mr. Sibson he had got the bread and butter, did you look at it?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you look upon opium as poison?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you desire him to shew it you?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Nor did he not offer to shew it you?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see it?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. I never saw it till before justice Fielding.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the maid take it out of the bandbox?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. I saw her put her hand in, and take it out again; I cannot say I saw the bread and butter in her hand. She ran away, and the brother ran after her and stopt her, and came and jogged me by the elbow, and said he had got it</p>
               <p>Q. Did you look upon Mrs. Sibson to be in or out of her senses?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. I thought she was in her senses. she appeared to me in a great deal of grief, yet sensible; she appeared as most women do when their husbands are ill.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you a married man?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. No, I am a bachelor. I went there again; she told me he was alive, but very ill, and she thought I could not bear the steach of the room. I went and asked him how he did. He looked at me, but made no answer. I could not bear the room, I went into the next room, and there I could not stay till I got fresh air from the window. Mrs. Martin came in, and said, he had voided six quarts of blood that morning. She desired I would give her daughter a little advice, for she intends to lay out a great deal of money to bury him in a pompous manner ( they talked of burying him in town, at Bow church). I told them I would have them bury him at Aimsworth the parish they lived in. Mrs. Sibson said she would have him opened, and the heart embalmed, and put in a case of silver or pewter, to open and shut, so as to look at it as she had a mind. I told her this was talking in a very idle manner, and bid her have no such thought: I told her, Your mother tells me you are going to do a very foolish thing, to bury him in a very pompous manner. Said she, Mr. Bearblock, I'll lay out a hundred pounds. I said, that will be quite out of character, pray bury him in a decent manner at Aimsworth. I did not know that my reasonings had taken effect. After that, the brother told her he was dead, and they thought he was poisoned; that is all I know of it.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How often had you seen him and his wife since their return from America?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. I believe I saw them three or four times; I dined with him and her together.</p>
               <p>Q. How did they seem to behave towards each other?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176205260018"></xptr>Bearblock. They appeared pretty fond of one another.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she appear to be fond of him?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. She appeared like other people, as married people do.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they appeared to live well together?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. They did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear any disputes with him?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. No; they appeared to live well; I can't say to the contrary.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know which was the person that had the fortune, whether he or she had the better fortune?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. I believe she had the better fortune.</p>
               <p>Q. At the time you heard her talk of this opium, and the maid went to the bandbox, had you any suspicion that she had opium or poison for her husband?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. I had no suspicion, before the husband's death, that the man had been poisoned, or that she had given her husband any thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the brother given you any idea that he had an apprehension that the deceased had the poison given him?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Don't you imagine he would have taken some opportunity of speaking to you, if he thought his brother was poisoned?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. I do not imagine he thought so then; if he had, he would have told me, I make no doubt.</p>
               <p>Q. If she had given her husband poison, can you conceive she would be talking of opium, or bring up the subject of poison?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. They might pretend to have such a regard for their husbands, as to be buried with them.</p>
               <p>Counsel. You say you are not a married man?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. I don't think I should have such a regard for my wife (had I one) as to be buried with her.</p>
               <p>Q. When she told you her brother Tom would never forgive her, what had she done? was that ever explained?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. I asked her the reason; she said he never would forgive her.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you understand by that?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. I could not tell what to think of it then, and know no more of it now.</p>
               <p>Q. You say the brother said, They desired Dr. Fothergill to come down; who did you understand by They?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. I understood Mrs. Martin and Mrs. Sibson.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620526-18-person184">
                  John 
                  Tyrrell 
               <interp inst="t17620526-18-person184" type="surname" value="Tyrrell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person184" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person184" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have made a narrative of Mr. Sibson's case from time to time, and I desire I may have leave to refex to it in the course of my evidence; I made remarks every day, and what I have here, I digested from my remarks.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you your original remarks here?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. No, I have not.</p>
               <p>Court. Then you cannot read what you have.</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. I was desired to see Mr. Sibson on the 8th of April, his brother Robert came to my house for me. I went to his brother's house to him; he was there then; this was at Windsor. He appeared to me then to have fresh complaints upon him; he had a very quick pulse, and complained of his mouth being sore, and he had a very great thirst, and a total loss of appetite. I don't remember he made any other complaints to me at that time; I advised him to lose some blood.</p>

               <p>Q. What did you take his disorder to be at that time?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. I could not tell. When I was inquiring into his complaints, he told me he had rode on horseback from Longford; I did not know but the fresh complaints might proceed from riding on horseback. I thought him so ill, I wondered he should come on horseback from Longford.</p>
               <p>Court. You formed some judgment, or you would not have prescribed?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. I thought he had a fever, and bled him there, and gave him some medicines proper for a fever; at the same time I inquired into the nature of his case, that is, how long he had been ill. He said, Some few days. I asked him about his general state of health. He said, for near three years he had been at Halifax in 
               <persName id="t17620526-18-person185">
                  Nova 
                  Scotia 
               <interp inst="t17620526-18-person185" type="surname" value="Scotia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person185" type="given" value="Nova"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person185" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and had returned to England a few weeks before; and soon after he returned he was taken with griping pains in his stomach and bowels (a flux he called it). I asked him whether it was a bloody flux, and whether it was attended with pains. He told me, Yes, very griping pains. He said the stools were sometimes bloody, not always. I told him he must not ride on horseback by any means, and begged of his brother to hire a post-chaise, and go home with him; he returned home in a post-chaise. I told him I would see him the next day, and advised him to lie in bed in the morning, and I should be a better judge of his feverish complaints when he had lain in bed. I found him much the same; his pulse was not so quick; then he made a very great complaint of his throat and his mouth. I asked him to let me took into his mouth; he did; his mouth was sore, his tongue was full of heats (little blisters); in short, I looked upon it a complaint arising from heat. Mrs. Sibson told me he had a cough; I asked him about the nature of his cough, whether he coughed or no. He said, No, Sir, I have not much of a cough, but there is such a continual dryness in my mouth, that I am always wetting my teeth with my tongue. Mrs. Sibson said,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176205260019"></xptr> He cannot give you so good an account as I can; I will assure you he has a cough. I said, we must order him things for a cough, sperma-ceti, and the like. When I was coming down stairs, she told me her Mamma was very ill, and she desires to speak with you. I went into her room, and after talking with her of her complaint, she asked me how Mr. Sibson her son-in-law did; she said, Well, how do you find Mr. Sibson? I said, I don't know what to say to you about him; this is the second time of seeing him. I hope he is not worse by any means. Sir, said she, whether it is better or worse, he will most assuredly die. Mr. Sibson made answer, and said, Mamma, you are an excellent comforter; whatever your own opinion might be, you might have kept it to yourself, and not frighten me so; you frighten me to tell me this. Said she, Would you not have me tell you this; he is in a galloping consumption, you know your own father died in one 16 years ago; he is in a galloping consumption. I remonstrated with Mrs. Martin, and said, For God's sake, what can be your reason for thinking so, for by his own account, and your account, his illness does not appear to be more than three weeks. He says he was extremely well when he came to England.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any thing material in that conversation?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. No, only Mrs. Martin thought him in a galloping consumption; I was of opinion clearly he was not.</p>
               <p>Q. What was your opinion his illness was?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. His griping stools never left him a whole day, and this I could not account for, it was a singular case; he was continually talking about his drought.</p>
               <p>Q. Would not the sever account for his drought?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. That in a great measure went off after my attendance; in four days his sever left him, upon my second bleeding him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he well after the fever left him?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. He was not; he complained of thirst and a sore mouth, and griping pains in stools; he always called it by the name of flux.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he much of a fever?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. He had no remarkable fever.</p>
               <p>Q. Did that loss of appetite return?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. Yes, so as to eat lamb steaks, by Mrs. Martin's account; she told me he had eat lamb steaks some few days before his death; I think he died on the Monday.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you think of his distemper now?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. It was a singular case.</p>
               <p>Q. I ask you as an apothecary, according to your judgment, tell us your judgment?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. I verily believe he died of poison; I opened him four days after his death, the first part that appeared in view was the stomach, it appeared to be very much inflamed, and towards the upper part of it, it looked darker and darker, of a putrefied colour.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it putrefied?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. Certainly it was; we tied both the orifices of the stomach, in order to see if there was any thing in the stomach, or not; then I opened it with a pair of scissars, and let it in a bason.</p>
               <p>Q. How did the outside appear?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. That appeared to be red, inflamed, and putrefied; the inside appeared the same, and more so.</p>
               <p>Q. What were the contents of the stomach?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. They consisted only of about two or three spoonfuls of very black liquor, which was put into a vial, the internal part of the stomach, the blood-vessel, seemed to be inlarged and thick; there was a mortified stuff in one part of the stomach; it had destroyed the coats of the stomach both internally and externally; the natural solds of the stomach were totally obliterated; it was as smooth as a bit of glass, excepting one part, it was that part towards the upper end of the stomach; after we had made this experiment of the stomach, Mr. Howard took the stomach home.</p>
               <p>Q. Who were with you?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. Mr. Howard and Mr. Johnson, surgeons. I said, Leave the stomach, we will examine it again. He returned the stomach to me in spirits; then I more particularly examined it; it appeared then, if the man had lived a little longer, the stuff would have come out; it appeared more plainly to be mortified.</p>
               <p>Q. How many days after was it that the stomach was returned you?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. That I can't say.</p>
               <p>Q. From the observations you made upon him when alive, and upon opening the body, joining both together, what is your opinion was the cause of his death?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. I apprehend it to be occasioned by poison; the whole bowels were inflamed, more or less, as the stomach; the stench was almost insupportable, so that there was no examining them; as far as they could be inspected, they appeared inflamed in the same manner; I don't know of any disease that could produce the same appearances in the stomach, but some poisonous body.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you go so far as to say what particular kind of poison those appearances indicated?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. It appeared to be corrosive sublimate; many kinds of poison will produce the same effect.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of the bread and butter that was in the possession of the brother?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. Mr. Sibson came to me on Monday. the day he died, at 8 in the morning, and said, What do you think of my brother's illness? I said, Really I do not know what to think, it appears to be a very singular case. He produced some bread and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176205260020"></xptr> butter, and asked me what I thought of that. Upon the first view of it, it appeared like corrosive sublimate. It was two pieces of bread and butter, laid in a triangular form, one upon another.</p>
               <p>Q. How big might they be?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. They might be as broad as my four fingers, like common bread and butter. There was something seemed to me to be strewed on in powder, and the two butter'd parts were together.</p>
               <p>Q. What was it that was strewed on it?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. Corrosive sublimate.</p>
               <p>Q. On what part was it spread?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. It was on the buttered part of the bread and butter: he gave it me wrapt up in a piece of old news-paper: he told me it was in that situation when he took it from Mrs. Martin's maid. I heard the maid say her mistress had brought poison enough from London to poison forty people. She did not mention opium. This was when we came to open the body.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she call Mrs. Sibson her mistress?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. She did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she mention her name?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. She said Mrs. Sibson my mistress: she ever call'd her so, my young mistress and my old mistress.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever apply to Mrs. Sibson to open the body?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. No; Mrs. 
               <persName id="t17620526-18-person186">
                  Robert 
                  Sibson 
               <interp inst="t17620526-18-person186" type="surname" value="Sibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person186" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person186" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             applied to me: he said he was determined to have him opened let it cost him what it will, if he begg'd his bread. This was at my house on the Monday in the evening of the day he died. I said, how did you find matters? He said his brother had been dead about a quarter of an hour. I said, how came you not to go there sooner? I desired you to make particular haste. He said he had had business.</p>
               <p>Q. How soon after he died was the body opened?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. The body was not opened till Friday, four days after.</p>
               <p>Q. How came it not to be opened sooner?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. Mr. Howard and I waited three or four days; there was a young gentleman there, who said he was an agent from Mr. Johnson of Brentford, and he was come to be an assistant in opening of the body. He said, I desire it may not be opened now (this was on the Wednesday.) Mr. Sibson went with me on the Tuesday: Mrs. Martin said her daughter was not at home; but if she was at home it should not be opened for ten thousand pounds: however, when I put her in mind the body was not her property but her daughter's, she gave it up, and said my daughter is not at home, you must stay till she comes home.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you stay till her daughter came home?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. I did: her daughter came in the evening. I asked her. She said, no. It shall not be opened by any means in the world. Then I said, there is a reason for our requesting it so strong, we suspect the body is poisoned. Oh! Sir, said she, if that be the case, by all means the body shall be opened. Then Mr. Howard and I went on the Wednesday, by Mrs. Martin's appointment, to open the body, by the general consent of parties. This young gentleman said he was assistant to Mr. Johnson of Brentford: he said as there are but four of us, that was he, Mr. Howard, myself, and Mr. Sibson, if poison should be found in the stomach we shall never be able to satisfy the ladies but that we had brought it in our pockets. Upon which I said, I shall certainly have nothing more to say to you, and called him dirty fellow. We waited till dark, and I said the weather is very hot, we shall meet with difficulty if it remains in this state.</p>
               <p>Q. What did prevent its being opened?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. Mrs. Martin said the body was in her house, and would not permit us to go up stairs. She said, if I have not a right to resuse the opening the body, this is my right, it shall not be done here. Then, said I, we must have the body out of the house. On the Thursday we went again: then Mr. Sibson, the prosecutor, determined to apply to the Middlesex coroner. He was applied to; but he could not attend. Mr. Howard, Mr. Johnson, of Brentford, and myself opened the body, and it appeared as I have mentioned.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you communicate your opinion to one another?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. There was a great deal of talk. When we had examined the other internal parts, the lungs appeared to be extremely healthy, and so did every other internal part, except the stomach.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you all sign a certificate?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. We all four did; it was drawn up by the coroner.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this after you had inspected the body?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. It was.</p>
               <p>It is read to this purpose:</p>
               <p>From the present appearance of the parts there is no reason to think his death proceeded from any cause occasioned by poison; but do agree at the same time the parts appeared in a putrid state, and a judgment cannot be formed, as if the inspection had been made sooner before the body was infected.</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. The smell was extremely offensive. We examined it in a cursory way: every body was liable to catch a putrid fever.</p>
               <p>Q. At the time you signed this, did you think his death appeared from any cause occasioned by poison? The certificate says, there is no reason to think<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176205260021"></xptr> his death proceeded from any cause occasioned by poison: did you think so when you signed it?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. Upon my oath there was no certain judgment to be formed because of the stench. I objected to the signing any thing for three hours.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they never convince you of it?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. No, they did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Then do you say you signed this certificate unadvisedly? - It does not contain your opinion.</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. I signed, that the stench of the stomach was insupportable.</p>
               <p>Q. What was your opinion when you signed it?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. I was in that opinion in general at the time I signed it.</p>
               <p>Q. Then you had seen the corrosive sublimate on the bread and butter?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. from coroner. Who dictated the certificate?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. Mr. Pitt, I believe. After the stomach was clean'd from filth then these evident marks of poison appeared very plain.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the marks appear in a greater degree after put in spirits than before?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. They did, and made me alter my opinion.</p>
               <p>Q. What was your opinion of this gentleman's disorder, when you considered it as a feverish complaint, and had been told by Mrs. Martin he was in a galloping consumption, upon which you gave him some medicines proper for a cough, and had blistered him?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. I did not consider him consumptive.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you then think his case to be?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. I acknowledge my ignorance; I did not know.</p>
               <p>Q. Point out the singularity of it?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. The insatiable thirst that he complained of, and no other feverish complaints, and no feverish pulse to support an opinion that the thirst was occasioned by a fever.</p>
               <p>Q. Then you think when a man with a flux upon him, a strong purging, and no feverish complaint, it is singular a man should be very thirsty?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. I think it is singular that a man who has a diarrhoea should be thirsty; but here is another case, he had a sore mouth. I ordered things to be applied to his mouth to relieve that soreness.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the case that you speak of ever leave him?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. No.</p>
               <p>Q. In such a very singular case, did you advise a physician?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. I did, and they refused it.</p>

               <p>Q. Did they never desire it, and you refuse it?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. No never, that I recollect.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you recommend it?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. The third day of his illness I very strongly recommended it.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you was not desired by the wife and mother to call in a physician the Monday before he died, and you said there was no occasion, or at any other time, perhaps you may not remember to a day? and did not Mrs. Sibson say to you, if you apprehend my husband to be in a very dangerous condition, for God's sake do not deceive me, let me have the assistance of a physician?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. I do not remember that; there did not appear to me to be any danger.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you, upon your oath, endeavour to perswade them from having a physician?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. I remember I said his illness was a lowness of spirits, and if he would eat and drink heartily he would do well.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether it was your indispensible duty, if you can have a physician, for your own character, as the case was unaccountable, to have recommended one?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. I did insist upon a physician the Thursday before he died: then I first apprehended danger.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you 17 days before he died to say the case was very singular, and you did not know what his disorder was?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. That was through weakness.</p>
               <p>Q. What alteration was there on the Thursday?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. A very great alteration; he was in a very stupid state. I was a good while making him understand that I had sent for a physician.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he free from pain?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. He was very far from being free from pain: he held his hand upon his stomach, and groan'd grievously.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he stupid and sensible of pain?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. He was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you advise this gentleman to go abroad in the chaise?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the last time?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. It was the Monday before his death.</p>
               <p>Q. When did Dr. Lucas see him?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. He saw him on the Friday before his death. I saw him in the garden walking by himself, and congratulated him upon the prospect of his being better.</p>
               <p>Counsel. You signed this certificate, and gave it upon oath to the coroner upon his inquest, according to your judgement, and you are still of that opinion, so far as the then inspection of the body could lead you; what did you think of the corrosive sublimate that you saw upon the bread and butter?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. I know it was poison. I disputed it with the surgeons, and shewed it them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you dispute it with the surgeons, in order to bring them over to any opinion that you had formed?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. I argued it with them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you argue with them, that you imagined the man died of poison?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176205260022"></xptr>No answer.</p>
               <p>Q. At the time you signed the certificate you said you was of opinion the man did not die of poison; had you any reason to think he had taken any of the corrosive sublimate?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. I did not know what to think then.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see an animal that had been poisoned by corrosive sublimate?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Do not you know the animal that has taken corrosive sublimate is in strong convulsive pains within an hour or two after, and continues so till it dies?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. I have no doubt of that at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the deceased these symptoms?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. No, he had not.</p>
               <p>Q. Is there a quantity that will let a man live four days after taken, and then kill him?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. Yes, I believe, four months.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you read in Dr. Mead, that an animal can linger under it four weeks?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. Four months; I give my opinion.</p>
               <p>Q. Do not you know, that if a quantity of poisonous matter is given, so small as not to give a high inflammation to cause immediate death, will not nature discharge itself?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. That is all matter of uncertainty.</p>
               <p>Counsel. After the man was dead, and all this over, you appeared before Sir 
               <persName id="t17620526-18-person187">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620526-18-person187" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person187" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person187" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Mr. Pitt, the surgeon, there at that time?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. He was.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember Dr. Lucas's name being mentioned, and Sir John's wishing the physicians had been there to put it beyond all doubt?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. I do not remember that.</p>
               <p>Q. Do not you remember your telling him, that if Dr. Lucas was there he would put it beyond all doubt; for he was of opinion the man died of poison?</p>
               <p>No answer.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Dr. Lucas tell you so?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. No, he never did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you swear, that Dr. Lucas did say so? Do not you remember you said Dr. Lucas had never seen Mr. Johnson, and there was a long conversation about it?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. Upon my oath, I do not remember it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Dr. Lucas before he saw the patient?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. No; Mr. Sibson went for him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you there when the doctor visited him?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. What was his opinion of him?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. He looked upon him as a dying man.</p>
               <p>Q. At the time of your opening the body, do you remember taking out the lungs, and saying, Brave lungs, gentlemen, here is no consumption; this is not the illness the man died of?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. I did; I remember that.</p>
               <p>Counsel. You had seen the bread and butter, knowing the corrosive sublimate to be poison: you was alarmed with suspicious, yet when you saw the stomach you did not believe he died of poison. The certificate that you signed says,</p>
               <p>"We have carefully</p>
               <p>"examined the body of 
               
                  <persName id="t17620526-18-victim189" type="victimName">
                     George 
                     Sibson 
                  <interp inst="t17620526-18-victim189" type="surname" value="Sibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-victim189" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-victim189" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620526-18-off93 t17620526-18-victim189"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , and are</p>
               <p>"unanimous of opinion that his death could not be</p>
               <p>"occasioned by poison."</p>
               <p>Q. Who was it that you told you would bring to the Old Bailey?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. I don't remember that I mentioned such a word.</p>
               <p>Counsel. I'll put you in mind of it - Here is a brave inflammation, Mr. Howard, we are in the right now; come and look at this inflammation, you young rogue, you shall go with us to the Old Bailey. Did not you say this?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. I swear I did not say so.</p>
               <p>Q. Will you swear you did not say before Justice Fielding, that Dr. Lucas had informed you, it was his judgement that Mr. Sibson died of poison?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. I never said so.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath did you not?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. Upon my oath, I do not remember it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620526-18-person190">
                  Robert 
                  Sibson 
               <interp inst="t17620526-18-person190" type="surname" value="Sibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person190" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person190" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 23d of February last, my brother (the deceased) called upon me; he was just arrived from North America: he appeared to be in as good health as ever I saw him in my life. About three weeks after he came to Windsor, and dined with me; he appeared to be then very well. I saw him on the Friday following. I came to London, and called upon him at his lodgings in Maiden-lane. He complained of some little gripings, and the bloody-flux. I think, on the Thursday following, he came to Windsor, and was ill. I fetched Mr. Tyrrell to him: he complained of a bloody-flux or purging, a pain in his neck, and a reaching. He complained all along of a violent pain in his head. Mr. Tyrrell let him blood. About the 23d of April I came to town at the desire of Mrs. Sibson to fetch Dr. Fothergill; but he could not attend. I went to Windsor for Dr. Hays and Dr. Lucas to attend: at night Mrs. Sibson seemed to be in a great deal of grief, and said, if he died she would be buried with him; she had taken opium or some other poison, and if that would not do she would take more, she would be buried with him; but before that she said she would have him opened, and have his heart to keep. She said also, poor Tom (meaning my brother) would never forgive her. Mr. Bearblock said, why will he never forgive you? She made answer, I am sure he never will for what I have done.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you understand that?</p>
               <p>Sibson. Upon my word I can't tell whether they had any quarrel or what. The maid went from her<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176205260023"></xptr> to a band-box in the window, and took out some bread and butter wrapt in a piece of news-paper. It was under some ribons and caps in the box. By the turning up of the things it appeared to be at the bottom. The maid was then going out of the room; I took it from her, and put it in my pocket, in the presence of all that were there, and did not look at it till I went to Windsor.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you stay at Longford after?</p>
               <p>Sibson. I believe the best part of the day.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day did you take the bread and butter from the maid?</p>
               <p>Sibson. In the morning, and I believe I left Longford about six in the evening.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell any body of it till you came to Windsor?</p>
               <p>Sibson. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Nor shew it to any body?</p>
               <p>Sibson. No; the maid asked me what I had done with it, and I said I threw it over the garden-wall.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to tell her so?</p>
               <p>Sibson. I was willing to examine it to see what it was, and not to let her have it again. I had no thought of any thing at that time. I was resolved Mrs. Sibson should never have it again; for I really thought she intended to destroy herself.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you throw it over the garden wall?</p>
               <p>Sibson. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Mr. Bearblock there all that day?</p>
               <p>Sibson. He was.</p>
               <p>Q. What day was this?</p>
               <p>Sibson. This was on Saturday.</p>
               <p>Q. to Tyrrell. Was you there on that Saturday?</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. I was not.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the reason you never look'd at it yourself, nor produced it the whole day?</p>
               <p>Sibson. Upon my word I had no suspicion.</p>
               <p>Q. Then why did you not throw it away?</p>
               <p>Sibson. I was willing to look at it; but being so much fatigued in fetching the gentlemen, first I went for Dr. Fothergill, then to Windsor, sitting up all night, and having a dying brother before my eyes, I had no thought of looking at it. I wish I had looked at it then, as Dr. Lucas and Dr. Hays were both there. On the Saturday I waited on my brother again, and on my return to Windsor I waited on Dr. Lucas, and told him of it; He said it was impossible to spread opium on bread and butter. This was the day before my brother died: then hearing the maid say her, mistress had brought as much poison as would poison 40 people, and Mrs. Sibson say she would have my brother's heart, the thing struck me about poison, and never before.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you look at the bread and butter?</p>
               <p>Sibson. I looked at it as soon as I came home to Windsor on the Saturday night.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell Dr. Lucas how it appear'd?</p>
               <p>Sibson. To the best of my knowledge I told him it appeared white. I went to Longford on the Monday; then my brother had been dead about a quarter of an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. What was Mrs. Sibson doing?</p>
               <p>Sibson. She was then writing a letter to an undertaker. She desired me to read it; but I can't give the particulars of it. I staid till she sent the boy with it. I desired of her that my brother might be opened. She waved it off by talking about his funeral. I told her I would wait upon her the next day with Mr. Tyrrell; which I did. After that Mrs. Martin said no such thing should be done in her house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mrs. Sibson consent to have him opened when she heard it was poison?</p>
               <p>Sibson. To the best of my knowledge she did. I know they refused his being opened, till I came to town to fetch the coroner. It was on the Thursday that the coroner had notice of it.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had your brother been had before the bread and butter was found?</p>
               <p>Sibson. Very near a fortnight.</p>
               <p>Q. What was Mr. Tyrrell's opinion of his disorder?</p>
               <p>Sibson. Mr. Tyrrell never look'd upon it as a consumption. I heard him say he never thought it a consumption in his life-time.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he recommend to your brother?</p>
               <p>Sibson. He recommended exercise to him. In short, my brother seemed rather hypocondriac or low-spirited.</p>
               <p>Q. How did your brother and his wife agree together?</p>
               <p>Sibson. In short, I never saw any two more affectionate to each other.</p>
               <p>Q. Which had the fortune, she or your brother?</p>
               <p>Sibson. I don't know that my brother had five shillings or five pounds. They were married abroad; I believe at Halifax.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he ever inform you of his reason for coming to England?</p>
               <p>Sibson. No, he never did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did your brother make a will?</p>
               <p>Sibson. I believe my brother's will was made on the Saturday: I was in the room.</p>
               <p>Q. By that will, who did he give his effects to?</p>
               <p>Sibson. He gave all to his wife.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he sensible?</p>
               <p>Sibson. I cant say he was totally sensible: he was not so at all times; but he was better then than he had been all the day.</p>
               <p>Q. At the time he made his will, did you look upon him as a man capable of knowing what he did?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176205260024"></xptr>Sibson. He was more so then than he was all the day. He appeared quite sensible at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. What were the contents of it?</p>
               <p>Sibson. I really cannot say. I remember he directed the gentleman to make over every thing to his wife.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you shew the bread and butter to Dr. Lucas when you returned to Windsor?</p>
               <p>Sibson. I did. he said it was no more capable of being spread than a board. It was these things that struck me with suspicion that my brother was not fairly dealt by.</p>
               <p>Q. What powder did you yourself conceive it to be?</p>
               <p>Sibson. That I cannot say.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you buy any powder?</p>
               <p>Sibson. I bought no powder any way in the world.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever ask your children to eat a bit?</p>
               <p>Sibson. When I got home on the Saturday night, it appeared then as white as white sugar. I broke a bit and threw it into the fire. It appeared to burn blue like saltpetre, or whether the paper might make that I don't know.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you buy any in order to try?</p>
               <p>Sibson. I did not: I had a little from Mr. Tyrrell to try the experiment two or three days after. I shewed it to Mr. Tyrrell the next morning after. I brought it home.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he call it?</p>
               <p>Sibson. He called it corrosive sublimate. He gave me some white powder.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell him it burnt blue?</p>
               <p>Sibson. I might tell him so.</p>
               <p>Q. Did that stuff burn blue that he gave you for corrosive sublimate.</p>
               <p>Sibson. I can't tell that.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never say, when you went home on the Saturday, to your little girls, do you love bread and butter, and a little bit fell off, and you threw it in the fire, and it burnt like gunpowder?</p>
               <p>Sibson. I never said it burnt like gunpowder.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never say you went and bought some white arsnick?</p>
               <p>Sibson. No.</p>
               <p>Q. What experiment did Mr. Tyrrell order you to make with that stuff he gave you?</p>
               <p>Sibson. Nothing at all. I did nothing but of my own imagination; he gave me no directions about it. Then I had suspicions my brother was poisoned, and never before. This was on Monday morning about 8 o'clock. I then communicated my suspicions to Mr. Tyrrell.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Tyrrell tell you it was poison?</p>
               <p>Sibson. He did.</p>
               <p>Q. How came Mr. Tyrrell to send you to Longford to see a poisoned man, instead of going himself?</p>
               <p>Sibson. I can't tell that: according to his desire I went. He desired me to make all the speed possible.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Then it did not occur to you to think it would be more proper to take this piece of bread and butter to those men who are skilled in it; for no time is to be lost in cases of poison?</p>

               <p>Sibson. I can't tell why Mr. Tyrrell did not do it?</p>
               <p>Q. Was you before Sir 
               <persName id="t17620526-18-person191">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620526-18-person191" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person191" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person191" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             at the time Mr. Tyrrell was examined there about that affair?</p>
               <p>Sibson. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember the doctors of physick being mentioned by Mr. Fielding; that it would have been more proper for the physicians to have been there?</p>
               <p>Sibson. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember what Mr. Tyrrell said was the opinion of Dr. Lucas as to the occasion of your brother's death? don't you remember Mr. Tyrrell told the justice Dr. Lucas told him over and over what had been the occasion of his death?</p>
               <p>Sibson. I can't tell that: I can't recollect it: I was in too much confusion a great deal.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you recollect that Mr. Tyrrell told Sir John that Dr. Lucas told him he had never seen Mr. Johnson?</p>
               <p>Sibson. I do not recollect any such conversation as that.</p>
               <p>Q. As soon as there was a declaration from you to have your brother opened, was not Mrs. Sibson consenting to it?</p>
               <p>Sibson. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember Mr. Martin's proposing to send for Dr. Hays?</p>
               <p>Sibson. No, I do not. I sent for both the physicians myself by the desire of the family.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>Of what I am accused I am quite innocent; as to bread and butter I took some opium upon it. I put it into water, and it would not melt; then I put it into broth, and it did, and I put it on bread and butter. The first time I ever saw my brother Sibson, he carried my husband to his house, and gave him some warm alder wine, and that brought the flux upon him.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mr. Howard. I went with Mr. Tyrrell to the opening of Mr. Sibson's body: he opened the body. It was all in a putrid state. After that I said, there is a notion this gentleman has been poisoned, I desired to see the stomach, the lower parts of which were all mortified. We closed the mouth of the orifice. I said, cut the stomach out, and bring it to me in a bason. We laid it open and took the contents<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176205260025"></xptr> out, and examined them, and said, Here is no poison at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the stomach afterwards?</p>
               <p>Howard. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. What observations did you make on it?</p>
               <p>Howard. It looked of a dingy livid colour; the man had been dead five days, and the body stunk in such a manner that we could not bear the room.</p>
               <p>Q. From any appearance you saw, do you judge he came by his death by poison?</p>
               <p>Howard. No, I can't say he did, I could see no poison; I don't believe he died of poison: I poured water in the stomach, and saw no poison in the contents of the stomach.</p>
               <p>Q. What would have been the effect, if it had been sublimate?</p>
               <p>Howard. I did that to clear it, that I might see the mercury?</p>
               <p>Q. If he had been poisoned four days before he died, by corrosive sublimate, would you have found it in the body?</p>
               <p>Howard. There would have been some of it left, to be sure.</p>
               <p>Dr. Lucas. On Friday morning, the 25th of April, I first attended the deceased; I was called in by Mr. Sibson the brother; he came to me on Thursday evening; he brought this note to me from Mr. Tyrrell [producing a paper.]</p>
               <p>Q. Does that mention any thing of the disorder?</p>
               <p>Howard. It does: Mr. Sibson told me his brother was at Longford, and was very ill, and he apprehended he was very near dying. I asked him what he apprehended to be the case? He told me he apprehended it was a consumption, as all the family were consumptive. He pressed me very much to go; he said his brother and sister were then gone out in the chaise, he thought as far as Hounslow. Then I said, If he is able to go out, there can't be any necessity for my going now. I had rather come to morrow morning, then I can stay two or three hours, and hear the whole of his complaints. He said he would go back again, and let him know. Then I said, if they are not satisfied, if you call on me, I will go along with you. He returned and said, they had put him to bed, and they were very well satisfied with my coming in the morning. I went in the morning: I had a messenger from Mr. Tyrrell to hasten, he being very ill. I expected to meet Mr. Tyrrell there. I went, and Mr. Tyrrell came after me; we got off our horses, and walked through the yard together. I said it is very unserviceable to be sent for to close people's eyes; I wish you had sent for me sooner, or not at all. He said he had pressed a physician very much, but they never would be prevailed upon to have one. I went up stairs, and found the man in bed, in all appearance dying, in the last stage of a consumption, his cheek bones rose up, and he had every appearance of a man in the last stage of a consumption, totally emaciated as a man could be to be alive. There was a very hard and quick pulse, such as always attends a hectic fever, it appeared to me to be a true hectic; the man seemed very deaf, and did not appear to me sensible of his own condition. I thought it unreasonable to ask him any thing; I sat down, and asked the women how long he had been ill. They said to weeks: that he had gone over from England three years ago, to America, in a consumption, and the air agreed with him there, and he grew better. I asked if he was very well the three years he was there. They said, he had something of a barking cough that he never got clear of: that he was very well, as in general he was, on going on board; but from that instant of going on board, till he arrived in England, during the time of extreme cold weather, and catching cold upon cold he became in that manner that I saw him. The next morning we went again with Mr. Hayes; we found him much in the same state, only more like a dying man. Mr. Tyrrell and the brother were both in the room at the time. They never contradicted the women in one single article; I had no reason to suspect they said one single word that was not true.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you think this man died of?</p>
               <p>Dr. Lucas. There was no symptom that I could impute to poison in the least.</p>
               <p>Q. Are these symptoms of poison?</p>
               <p>Dr. Lucas. No, none at all. There were symptoms of a dying man, there must have been other symptoms to give a suspicion of poison; if that had been the case, I should have expected very great pain, tormenting pain in the stomach and bowels, a complaint of burning pains in the bowels, and pain in the jaws; but there was not a single symptom of it.</p>
               <p>Q. What was your opinion that he died of?</p>
               <p>Dr. Lucas. That he died of a consumption.</p>
               <p>Q. If he had eaten a piece of bread and butter strewed over with corrosive sublimate, how soon would it begin to operate?</p>
               <p>Dr. Lucas. I dare say he would have been in extreme pain in less than an hour, were there but six or eight grains of it.</p>
               <p>Dr. Hayes. I went with Dr. Lucas on the Saturday; the deceased looked then in the very condition he has now described, only nearer his end, so far, that I did not think he would have held till we got out of the house.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your opinion was the cause of his death?</p>
               <p>Dr. Hayes. it is my opinion he died of a consumption: I have no doubt of it.</p>
               <p>Q. to Dr. Lucas. Did you ever tell Mr. Tyrrell the deceased died of poison?</p>
               <p>Dr. Lucas. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176205260026"></xptr>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17620526-18-person192">
                  Edmund 
                  Pitt 
               <interp inst="t17620526-18-person192" type="surname" value="Pitt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person192" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person192" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a surgeon in Bartholomew hospital; I saw the stomach two or three hours after the body was opened, I narrowly inspected it; I was called upon to see whether there were any marks of poison; I have no reason to believe the person died of poison.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you before Mr. Fielding when Mr. Tyrrell was there?</p>
               <p>Pitt. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether Mr. Tyrrell did not tell Mr. Fielding that Dr. Lucas had informed him he was of opinion the man died of poison?</p>
               <p>Pitt. I am certain he did. Sir 
               <persName id="t17620526-18-person193">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620526-18-person193" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person193" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person193" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             expressed great difficulty there. I said, I believe you would have no difficulty, if the physicians had attended here. No, said Mr. Tyrrell, you would have had no difficulty, for Dr. Lucas told me he believed the man died of poison. The next day I again attended Sir 
               <persName id="t17620526-18-person194">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620526-18-person194" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person194" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person194" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Tyrrell there said, he believed Dr. Lucas had never seen Mr. Johnson.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Tyrrell tell you at Longford something about making a pamphlet?</p>
               <p>Pitt. Mr. Tyrrell told me at Longford he could make an excellent twelvepenny pamphlet of it.</p>
               <p>Tyrrell. So I shall.</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17620526-18-person195">
                  Robert Wallis 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17620526-18-person195" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person195" type="given" value="Robert Wallis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person195" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was present at the time the deceased was opened. Upon seeing the lungs, Mr. Tyrrell pronounced with a loud voice, Brave lungs, gentlemen! here is no consumption. As the intestines appeared, I desired they would observe well the intestines. The stomach appeared of a pale red, which gradually becomes darker and darker; upon that side that lies next to the spleen, it appeared of a very dark colour, rather darker than red; that part of the stomach that lay next to the liver, and the forepart of the stomach, I did not observe to be inflamed at all. Mr. Tyrrell pronounced with a joyful countenance, A brave inflammation, gentlemen! A brave inflammation, Mr. Howard! Soon after he said, We are right now. Presently he said, Come, you rogue, look at this inflammation; you shall go along with us to the Old Bailey. He said, I have in my pocket sublimate on white arsenic, part of which I believe to be in this stomach. He pronounced with a loud voice, Here is not only inflammation, but mortification. I begged of him to lay the stomach down, and behave with decency, and desired him to examine the lungs. Said he, I'll oblige you, and examine them. There appeared a little place of redness; whether Mr. Tyrrell saw it, or not, I can't say, but he immediately laid it down, and said, I will not inspect the body any longer, and went to the other side of the room, and began to undress. I spoke to the undertaker, and desired him to see that no gentleman went out till I had intirely inspected the body myself. I desired Mr. Tyrrell to come round to see whether this was an inflammation upon the lungs, and be sure what it was, and I desired Mr. Howard and his son to do the same. We examined the liver and the spleen; it was proposed to take the stomach out, to have an experiment tried upon a dog. We agreed to open it, and did examine it. I saw no excoriation nor laceration, nor any symptoms of poison in the contents of it.</p>
               <p>Dr. Grosvenor. I was before Sir 
               <persName id="t17620526-18-person196">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620526-18-person196" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person196" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-person196" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             when Mr. Tyrrell was there. I heard part of his evidence; he was examining upon oath when I went in; I heard him declare there, that Dr. Lucas told him he was of opinion that poison was the occasion of the death of Mr. Sibson, and I heard Mr. Sibson, that was here examined, declare the same.</p>
               <p>Q. to Sibson. Did you fetch Dr. Lucas?</p>
               <p>Sibson I did.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you tell him was your brother's illness?</p>
               <p>Sibson. I told him I really believed he was in a decline.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you mention any thing of a consumption?</p>
               <p>Sibson. I told him something of it; I myself have been as bad as bad could be of a consumption.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17620526-18-verdict95" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620526-18-verdict95" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Mr. Tyrrell was told by the court he must either get bail or be committed, to take his trial for perjury, &amp;c. His reply to the court was, he was glad of it. He was bailed, and parties bound over to prosecute him.</p>
            </div1>
