<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650918-56">
               <interp inst="t17650918-56" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650918-56" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650918-56" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650918"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650918-56" type="date" value="17650918"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650918-56-off307-c506" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-56-defend622 t17650918-56-off307 t17650918-56-verdict311"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650918-56-off307-c508" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-56-defend626 t17650918-56-off307 t17650918-56-verdict311"></join>
         
               <p>485, 486. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17650918-56-defend622" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Gould 
                  <interp inst="t17650918-56-defend622" type="surname" value="Gould"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-56-defend622" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-56-defend622" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             was indicted for the <rs id="t17650918-56-off307" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650918-56-off307" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-56-off307" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               wilful murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17650918-56-victim624" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Knight 
                        <interp inst="t17650918-56-victim624" type="surname" value="Knight"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650918-56-victim624" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650918-56-victim624" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-56-off307 t17650918-56-victim624"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , by shooting him with a pistol ball, and 
                     
                        <persName id="t17650918-56-defend626" type="defendantName">
                           Jonathan 
                           Stevens 
                        <interp inst="t17650918-56-defend626" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650918-56-defend626" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650918-56-defend626" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , for being present, aiding, helping, abetting, comforting, and maintaining the said Gould the murder to commit
            </rs>, <rs id="t17650918-56-cd308" type="crimeDate">April 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-56-off307 t17650918-56-cd308"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650918-56-person627">
                  John 
                  Assiter 
               <interp inst="t17650918-56-person627" type="surname" value="Assiter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-56-person627" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-56-person627" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a gardner, and live at <placeName id="t17650918-56-crimeloc309">Whallam-green</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17650918-56-crimeloc309" type="placeName" value="Whallam-green"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17650918-56-crimeloc309" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-56-off307 t17650918-56-crimeloc309"></join>: the deceased 
               <persName id="t17650918-56-person628">
                  James 
                  Knight 
               <interp inst="t17650918-56-person628" type="surname" value="Knight"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-56-person628" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-56-person628" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             
                  <rs id="t17650918-56-viclabel310" type="occupation">kept a public house there</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-56-victim624 t17650918-56-viclabel310"></join>: I was going to market with goods on Tuesday the 16th of April: about half an hour after four in the morning I saw 
               <persName id="t17650918-56-person629">
                  James 
                  Knight 
               <interp inst="t17650918-56-person629" type="surname" value="Knight"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-56-person629" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-56-person629" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             lying dead upon the steps at Mr. Shelmerdine's door, the Cow and Calf, at Chelsea; I call'd, and the servant came down, and after that the master: I saw a hole in the coat, where I imagined a ball went in.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650918-56-person630">
                  Richard 
                  Shelmerdine 
               <interp inst="t17650918-56-person630" type="surname" value="Shelmerdine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-56-person630" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-56-person630" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep that public house at Chelsea: on the 16th of April I was called up in the morning by 
               <persName id="t17650918-56-person631">
                  John 
                  Assiter 
               <interp inst="t17650918-56-person631" type="surname" value="Assiter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-56-person631" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-56-person631" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I came down in about four or five minutes; there I found 
               <persName id="t17650918-56-person632">
                  James 
                  Knight 
               <interp inst="t17650918-56-person632" type="surname" value="Knight"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-56-person632" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-56-person632" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             lay dead: he had been drinking at my house the day before, from about eleven till one o'clock: I saw a wound on his right breast made with a ball: I can't say I ever saw either of the prisoners in my house in my life.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176509180045"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17650918-56-person633">
                  Robert 
                  Chambers 
               <interp inst="t17650918-56-person633" type="surname" value="Chambers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-56-person633" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-56-person633" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Chelsea pensioner, so are the two prisoners: the night before this thing happen'd. Gould and I were on the patrole between Buckingham-gate and Ranelagh; we pass'd a gentleman from the Engine to Buckingham-gate; he gave us half a guinea instead of a six-pence: Gould kept it till the next day, then he discovered it to me; he changed it, and gave me half; then we had a pot of beer; after that we had another pot at the George: we came from thence to Mr. Shelmerdine's, and there we had two pints of twopenny; then I believe it was four o'clock, or after; then we went in at the Thistle and Crown, there was Stevens; when we came out there, I was for going home; the two prisoners said, if I would go with them. I should see something: I was not for going; this was about a quarter before ten: I had a stick, they took my stick, I followed them, and as I was easing myself about twenty or thirty yards from them, I heard a pistol go off; I put up my breeches as fast as I could: when I came up to them, there was the deceased gasping for life, crying, Ha, Ha, Ha! he was close by them; he ran about fifteen yards towards Shelmerdine's, and dropt down; Stevens ran away: Gould pull'd me me along, I said, somebody is kill'd or robb'd; they said, what was that to me; this was just before the man dropt: the prisoners were taken up five weeks ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Had either of them a pistol?</p>
               <p>Chambers. I never saw either of them have a pistol.</p>
               <p>Q. Why were they not apprehended sooner?</p>
               <p>Chambers. I was afraid of my life, fearing they would kill me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in sight when the pistol went off?</p>
               <p>Chambers. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did Gould and you go after this?</p>
               <p>Chambers. We went down by the church, and had a quart or three pints of beer at the Black Lion.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not there a reward of five pounds publish'd for any body that would discover this affair?</p>
               <p>Chambers. Yes, there was: I made this discovery a great while after the reward was publish'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650918-56-person634">
                  John 
                  Peaver 
               <interp inst="t17650918-56-person634" type="surname" value="Peaver"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-56-person634" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-56-person634" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Chambers said, he and Gould were drinking at Mr. Shelmerdine's the day before this thing happen'd, and Gould denied his being there: Chambers, to confirm what he had said, gave an account there was a bricklayer at work there: all I have to say, I am a bricklayer, and was paving the hearth that day.</p>
               <p>Q. to Shelmerdine. Did you perceive the deceased had been robb'd?</p>
               <p>Shelmerdine. There was his watch, and sixpence, and a piece of chalk in his pocket.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650918-56-person635">
                  Alexander 
                  Reed 
               <interp inst="t17650918-56-person635" type="surname" value="Reed"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-56-person635" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-56-person635" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a surgeon; I open'd the deceased body; I found the ball had penetrated his breast, and into his lungs; I took it out, it was a pistol ball; that undoubtedly was the occasion of his death: there is no place in the world better situated for robberies, or easier to get off, than the place where the deceased was found; there frequently are a great number of prostitutes and bad people about there on nights: there are roads go several different ways: Stevens was at that time in the Infirmary with a broken arm (I am assistant surgeon to Chelsea hospital): he was well enough to go out, but not to use his arm; he always behaved very decent and sober; he never was out but one night late in the time, and then he came in about ten o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Do the patroles carry pistols.</p>
               <p>Reed. No, they carry muskets with bayonets fix'd.</p>
               <p>The prisoners in their defence denied the charge, and said, Chambers had told nothing but a parcel of lies.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650918-56-person636">
                  Alexander 
                  Macdonel 
               <interp inst="t17650918-56-person636" type="surname" value="Macdonel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-56-person636" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-56-person636" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Gould about seven years; he has an extraordinary good character; I never knew a man have a better: I have known Stevens forty years; I never knew any thing of him but that of an honest soldier; I never heard any ill of him.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17650918-56-verdict311" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650918-56-verdict311" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
