<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610916-15">
               <interp inst="t17610916-15" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-15" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-15" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610916"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-15" type="date" value="17610916"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610916-15-off78-c101" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-15-defend123 t17610916-15-off78 t17610916-15-verdict81"></join>
         
               <p>234. (M) 
               <persName id="t17610916-15-defend123" type="defendantName">
                  John 
                  Spragg 
               <interp inst="t17610916-15-defend123" type="surname" value="Spragg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-15-defend123" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-15-defend123" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17610916-15-off78" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-15-off78" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-15-off78" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing one guinea, the property of 
                     <persName id="t17610916-15-victim124" type="victimName">
                        Samuel 
                        Isaac 
                     <interp inst="t17610916-15-victim124" type="surname" value="Isaac"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610916-15-victim124" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610916-15-victim124" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-15-off78 t17610916-15-victim124"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , privately from his person
            </rs>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-15-person125">
                  Samuel 
                  Isaac 
               <interp inst="t17610916-15-person125" type="surname" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-15-person125" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-15-person125" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17610916-15-viclabel79" type="occupation">shoe-maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-15-victim124 t17610916-15-viclabel79"></join>, and live at <placeName id="t17610916-15-crimeloc80">Isleworth</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-15-crimeloc80" type="placeName" value="Isleworth"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-15-crimeloc80" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-15-off78 t17610916-15-crimeloc80"></join>; I went in at the sign of the Feathers, an ale-house there; I found the prisoner, and my man there; I told my man it was time to go home to his quarters; he said, he had called for a pint of beer, and when it was out, he would go home with me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he lodge with you?</p>
               <p>Isaac. No; before ever my man had drank it, the prisoner and his comrade came to my man; the comrade said, he would fight my man, and the prisoner he would fight his second; I suppose he meant me; I said, I should not concern myself in it; my man was down twice, and they both beat him after he was down; I said, that was not using him well; upon which, the prisoner knocked me down, and struck me over my temple, and I felt his hand in my left side pocket, where was a guinea; I called out murder; he let me get up, as soon as I was up, I missed the guinea; I went for the beadle; it was then almost ten at night; he was gone to bed, having taken a sweat, I could not have him; the next day I made my complaint to the justice, and got a warrant for him, and the prisoner was brought before him; I charged him with taking the guinea; he acknowledged he knocked me down, but denied taking the guinea.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you felt his hand in your pocket?</p>
               <p>Isaac. I am positive of that; when his hand was in my pocket, he struck me several blows with the other hand.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. When you felt my hand in your pocket, why did you not call out to prevent me?</p>
               <p>Isaac. I did call out murder, and he was beating me violently; I would have been glad to have been out of the house, if it had been five guineas.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I belong to my lord 
               <persName id="t17610916-15-person126">
                  Robert 
                  Rich 
               <interp inst="t17610916-15-person126" type="surname" value="Rich"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-15-person126" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-15-person126" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's regiment; he ran out of the door when I struck him, like a hen in the rain; there was his man and my comrade fighting on the floor; I went and parted them, and after that a second time; then the prosecutor came up, and said, you rascal, if you don't let them alone I'll knock you down; said I, I question whether you can or not; he laid hold on my coat, then I knocked him down; he went out at the door, and never said a word; then he came in again, and said, he had lost a guinea; one said, who has it? And another said, who has it? Then he said to me, you<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160011"></xptr> are the man that has it; I said, then why do you not come and search me. He stood in the passage, and would not come in: his wife was at the door at the same time, and said, swear a robbery against the rascal; and he held up his fist, and said, I will do for you directly.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. What answer can you give to this?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. This is as false as God is true; he, and his comrade too, were both in buff before my man was struck: my wife was then at home, and not there at the time.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610916-15-verdict81" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-15-verdict81" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
