<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17631207-9">
               <interp inst="t17631207-9" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-9" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-9" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17631207"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-9" type="date" value="17631207"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17631207-9-off45-c84" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-9-defend103 t17631207-9-off45 t17631207-9-verdict50"></join>
         
               <p>11. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17631207-9-defend103" type="defendantName">
                     Daniel 
                     Doland 
                  <interp inst="t17631207-9-defend103" type="surname" value="Doland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-9-defend103" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-9-defend103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17631207-9-off45" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631207-9-off45" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-9-off45" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he, on the King's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17631207-9-victim105" type="victimName">
                           Sarah 
                           Rice 
                        <interp inst="t17631207-9-victim105" type="surname" value="Rice"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17631207-9-victim105" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17631207-9-victim105" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-9-off45 t17631207-9-victim105"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17631207-9-viclabel46" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-9-victim105 t17631207-9-viclabel46"></join>, did make an assault, putting her in corporal fear and danger of her life, and stealing from her person one sattin cloak, called a cardinal, value 21 s. the property of her the said Sarah
            </rs>, <rs id="t17631207-9-cd47" type="crimeDate">Nov. 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-9-off45 t17631207-9-cd47"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-9-person106">
                  Sarah 
                  Rice 
               <interp inst="t17631207-9-person106" type="surname" value="Rice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-9-person106" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-9-person106" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going home to Coleman-street on Sunday the 13th of November , about half an hour after 8 in the evening. A man followed me; and between <placeName id="t17631207-9-crimeloc48">King-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17631207-9-crimeloc48" type="placeName" value="King-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17631207-9-crimeloc48" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-9-off45 t17631207-9-crimeloc48"></join> and the <placeName id="t17631207-9-crimeloc49">Old Jury, in Cheapside</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17631207-9-crimeloc49" type="placeName" value="Old Jury, in Cheapside"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17631207-9-crimeloc49" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-9-off45 t17631207-9-crimeloc49"></join>, he seemed to pass by me; he appeared to be very much in liquor. I turned down the Old Jury; he turned back, and ran to me, and catched hold of me, and held me a few minutes, and kept me so as to prevent my crying out. I endeavoured to get from him, but could not disengage myself from him till he let me go.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he offer any violence to you?</p>
               <p>S. Rice. He did not; he kiss'd me when he laid hold of me. I am sure I had my cloak on when he laid hold on me; it was united; and his behaviour frighted me a good deal, so that I am not capable of knowing whether the prisoner is the man or not; neither am I certain that he took it. He ran cross Cheapside, and I after him, crying, Stop thief. I did not stand to see whether it had fell where he stopt me. The prisoner was taken at the top of Bucklersbury, just at the corner of the Poultry.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you the man in your view till taken?</p>
               <p>S. Rice. No, I lost sight of him as he cross'd the way.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go back to look at the place where you miss'd your cloak?</p>
               <p>S. Rice. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say when he was taken?</p>
               <p>S. Rice. He said he knew nothing of it, he was running after the company. All I can say is, it was a man about his size, and he had a light-colour'd coat on.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-9-person107">
                  John 
                  Rayer 
               <interp inst="t17631207-9-person107" type="surname" value="Rayer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-9-person107" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-9-person107" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming home that Sunday night in company with my wife; it wanted something of 9 o'clock; as we pass'd the end of King-street, we were remarking how thin the street was of people. When we got past Mercer's chapel, we heard the cry, Stop theif. I stood to listen which way the voice came, and saw the prisoner cross the way from the end of the Old Jury: he salter'd, and was almost down when he got cross (I believe his foot might take a stone): he felt down, and there I laid hold of him. He asked me what I stopt him for? Said I. you are in the hand of a constable, and I'll see what you are charged with. The prosecutrix came up, and charged him with taking her cloak from her. I said, go the way he came, and see for it. I believe six or seven people went down the Old Jury to look for it: nothing was found: he was searched, and nothing found upon him. I asked him why he ran; he said he was running after a friend; but there was no other person running in the street at that time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-9-person108">
                  Q. 
               <interp inst="t17631207-9-person108" type="given" value="Q."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-9-person108" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (to Prosecutrix). Was any body near you, when you was stopt, besides the man that stopt you?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. There was but one, as I saw, and he was I believe about 20 yards from me in Cheapside: this was when I first saw him: when he stopt and kiss'd me I saw nobody near me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever get your cloak again?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17631207-9-verdict50" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631207-9-verdict50" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
