<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680224-14">
               <interp inst="t17680224-14" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680224-14" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680224-14" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680224"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680224-14" type="date" value="17680224"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680224-14-off84-c117" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-14-defend144 t17680224-14-off84 t17680224-14-verdict88"></join>
         
               <p>168. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17680224-14-defend144" type="defendantName">
                     Henry 
                     White 
                  <interp inst="t17680224-14-defend144" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-14-defend144" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-14-defend144" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17680224-14-off84" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680224-14-off84" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-14-off84" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing six ox hides, value 6 l. and four cow hides, value 3 l. 10 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17680224-14-victim146" type="victimName">
                           Martin
                            Kyke Van Mieup
                        <interp inst="t17680224-14-victim146" type="surname" value="Kyke Van Mieup"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680224-14-victim146" type="given" value="Martin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680224-14-victim146" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                     
                  , and 
                     
                        <persName id="t17680224-14-victim148" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Willet 
                        <interp inst="t17680224-14-victim148" type="surname" value="Willet"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680224-14-victim148" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680224-14-victim148" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                     
                  , in a certain lighter on the river <placeName id="t17680224-14-crimeloc85">Thames</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-14-crimeloc85" type="placeName" value="Thames"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-14-crimeloc85" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-14-off84 t17680224-14-crimeloc85"></join>
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17680224-14-cd86" type="crimeDate">Jan. 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-14-off84 t17680224-14-cd86"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-14-person149">
                  Robert 
                  Hunt 
               <interp inst="t17680224-14-person149" type="surname" value="Hunt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-14-person149" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-14-person149" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a public-house in Goat-yard, Horsleydown; about three weeks ago, when I got up, there was the prisoner and ten hides in my skittle-ground; he said they were his hides, that they were Irish hides.</p>
               <p>Q. What is he?</p>
               <p>Hunt. He is a <rs id="t17680224-14-deflabel87" type="occupation">journeyman lighterman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-14-defend144 t17680224-14-deflabel87"></join>; he went away, and after that there came a wharfinger, and asked me if I had any hides in my house, saying, he had lost three; I said there are ten here; he went and looked at them, and owned them all; they were all marked with the letters B, C, and D, some one letter some the other.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-14-person150">
                  Ralph 
                  Dean 
               <interp inst="t17680224-14-person150" type="surname" value="Dean"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-14-person150" type="given" value="Ralph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-14-person150" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I happened to be at Mr. Hunt's that morning, I saw two porters bring those hides through the house into the skittle-ground; when Mr. Hunt got up there came the prisoner, who said the hides were his property.</p>
               <p>Mr. Liscoe. I am a wharfinger at Hays's wharf, in Shad Thames; we had delivered a lighter, and missed ten hides, I do not particularly remember the day, it was about a fortnight or three weeks ago; they were marked A, B, and C on the left horn, that is according to the quality of the hides.</p>
               <p>Q. On which side the water is Hays's wharf?</p>
               <p>Liscoe. That and Horsleydown are both in Southwark; I do not know where the vessel lay when the hides were taken.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had the hides been in the lighter?</p>
               <p>Liscoe. I think they had been in her a day and a night.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did they come from?</p>
               <p>Liscoe. They came from Cork in Ireland; the vessel that brought them lay in the stream in the middle of the river.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the hides ever on the Middlesex side the water?</p>
               <p>Liscoe. When the hides were put into the lighter, the lighter was carried over to this side the water, being Sunday; I can swear to the hides by the marks, all by the same branding-irons; they were all raw hides, salted and tied up.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-14-person151">
                  Edward 
                  Thorn 
               <interp inst="t17680224-14-person151" type="surname" value="Thorn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-14-person151" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-14-person151" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a lighterman, it was my lighter that they were in; they were delivered the last day of the last month, the ship lay in Hanover-hole; the lighter was brought to Porter's key near the Custom-house that night, and she lay there all the Sunday, and brought to Hays's wharf<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176802240009"></xptr> on Monday the 1st of February, and she was delivered the day following; and about twelve, or a little after, the wharfinger came to me to know if I knew of any lighter being robbed, saying, there were some hides at the Goat in Goat-yard.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know when the lighter was robbed?</p>
               <p>Thorn. I imagine it might be between four and five in the morning before she was brought from Porter's key, but we have no proof of that.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any body here to prove the hides were delivered from the ship to the lighter?</p>
               <p>Thorn. No, we have not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-14-person152">
                  Martin 
                  Kyke 
               <interp inst="t17680224-14-person152" type="surname" value="Kyke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-14-person152" type="given" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-14-person152" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-14-person153">
                  Van 
                  Mieup 
               <interp inst="t17680224-14-person153" type="surname" value="Mieup"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-14-person153" type="given" value="Van"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-14-person153" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw one of these hides when before my Lord-Mayor; they were the joint property of Mr. 
               <persName id="t17680224-14-person154">
                  Thomas 
                  Willet 
               <interp inst="t17680224-14-person154" type="surname" value="Willet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-14-person154" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-14-person154" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I had lost my skift that Sunday morning; I was on the keys about half an hour after one, I saw two men row by in one, I imagined it to be mine; I asked where they were going with her; they said, what was that to me; they crossed over to the other side the water, I took a boat and pursued after them; I kept in sight of them, but there being two of them, I was afraid to board her; I waited some time; after that I heard a lumbering, and I saw but one man in her; I called watch, then the other man ran out of her; by and by there came two men by, I asked them if they would have a job; they said, to do what; I said, to carry a parcel of hides up to a friend's house; there were six of them lay in an alley, and four in the skift; I agreed to give the porters six-pence each to carry them; they said it was a hard job, and hoped I would give them something to drink; they took and carried them to the Goat, I knocked at the door; they were carried into the skittle-ground; my master is here to prove I was out the same night on his duty.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-14-person155">
                  John 
                  Shaw 
               <interp inst="t17680224-14-person155" type="surname" value="Shaw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-14-person155" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-14-person155" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a lighterman, the prisoner was my servant; the prisoner was taken into custody on the 1st of February, and I lost my skift on the Friday following.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Shaw. I can say nothing against him, nor for him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-14-person156">
                  George 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17680224-14-person156" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-14-person156" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-14-person156" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was by the water-side between five and six on that morning, it was about break of day; the prisoner asked me to carry some hides for him; there was another man employed besides me, but I do not know nothing of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say how he came by them?</p>
               <p>Jones. No; to the best of my knowledge he did not want to do any thing clandestinely.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Jones. I did, I never heard any body speak in any disrespect of him; he is a hard working man; I took some of them, and carried and flung them down facing a public-house in the street.</p>
               <p>Q. How happened you to be on the spot that morning?</p>
               <p>Jones. I was going to look after my daily labour.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Jones. I live in Seething-lane, by Tower-hill.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you going to work?</p>
               <p>Jones. Any where where I could.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you first see the skins?</p>
               <p>Jones. In an alley.</p>
               <p>Q. Very likely you can tell how they came into that alley?</p>
               <p>Jones. I know nothing how they came there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not ask him how they came there?</p>
               <p>Jones. I asked him no questions at all.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-14-person157">
                  John 
                  Ellis 
               <interp inst="t17680224-14-person157" type="surname" value="Ellis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-14-person157" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-14-person157" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a waterman, I have known the prisoner twelve years and upwards; he is an industrious hard working man, and has always behaved with honesty in all his employments.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-14-person158">
                  James 
                  Bowden 
               <interp inst="t17680224-14-person158" type="surname" value="Bowden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-14-person158" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-14-person158" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a victualler, I have known him six years, I never heard any thing amiss of him.</p>
               <p>There not being any evidence of their being in the possession of the prisoner in the county of Middlesex, he was <rs id="t17680224-14-verdict88" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680224-14-verdict88" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
