<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17661217-54">
               <interp inst="t17661217-54" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-54" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-54" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17661217"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-54" type="date" value="17661217"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17661217-54-off275-c465" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-54-defend586 t17661217-54-off275 t17661217-54-verdict279"></join>
         
               <p>67. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17661217-54-defend586" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Field 
                  <interp inst="t17661217-54-defend586" type="surname" value="Field"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-54-defend586" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-54-defend586" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for the <rs id="t17661217-54-off275" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-54-off275" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-54-off275" type="offenceSubcategory" value="infanticide"></interp>
               wilful murder of a new born child, by casting it into a tub of water
            </rs>, <rs id="t17661217-54-cd276" type="crimeDate">Nov. 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-54-off275 t17661217-54-cd276"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-54-person587">
                  Mary 
                  Duck 
               <interp inst="t17661217-54-person587" type="surname" value="Duck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-54-person587" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-54-person587" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Potter's Bar , in the parish of South Mims. The prisoner is a <rs id="t17661217-54-deflabel277" type="occupation">day labouring man</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-54-defend586 t17661217-54-deflabel277"></join>, he lives just by me; I have known him from a child; he had been in that house but about five weeks: he lived with a woman, but I look upon it they were never married. He came to me in the dusk of the evening, on the 13th of November, and said, dame Duck, come and go to my wife, for I think she is fetching her last breath; I went with him; I asked him what she ailed; he said she had an ague and fever; after that I asked him again, and he said, indeed it is a miscarriage; I said, where have you been all day; he said, at home; I said, why did you not come to me sooner, and I would have fetched three or four, or half a dozen women; he said, she would not let him come for any body; this was as we went along; he went in, and up stairs, and I followed him; he held his face cross his wife's face, and said, Lord have mercy on me, my wife is dead!</p>
               <p>Q. Was any body in the house beside you and he?</p>
               <p>M. Duck. There were only he and I, and his five children. I took hold of her hand, it was very cold.</p>
               <p>Q. How far distance between his house and your's?</p>
               <p>M. Duck. Not a quarter of a mile; his house is in <placeName id="t17661217-54-crimeloc278">Enfield parish</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17661217-54-crimeloc278" type="placeName" value="Enfield parish"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17661217-54-crimeloc278" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-54-off275 t17661217-54-crimeloc278"></join>. I said, give me a handkerchief and I'll tie up her jaw; I did: I turned myself round, and saw a half butter firkin set under the bed; I pulled it out; there I saw a child, which frighted me very much; I then went and fetched some other women, and four of us laid her out; after that I took the child out of the tub, and laid it on a blanket and cleaned it.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the prisoner at that time?</p>
               <p>M. Duck. He was below stairs; I took a chamber-pot full of water out of the tub, and I believe there was about half another in it.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was he when you first took notice of the child?</p>
               <p>M. Duck. He was gone down stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you say any thing to him when you went to fetch the other women?</p>
               <p>M. Duck. No, I did not say a word to him; we neither of us asked him any questions about it; we examined the child, it was a girl.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it full grown?</p>
               <p>M. Duck. I think it was, it had nails and hair; there were no marks of violence upon it; the child was parted the same as if a midwife had parted it, and all were in the tub together; then we went down stairs and left the man below, and said nothing to him; after we were out at the door he desired me to go and send one George, a cobler; I went, he not being at home, I went and got a woman to be with him; I went with the woman; he said, that will be of no service at all to be here to night; then we went away, and left him and the five children in the house; he came and fetched the woman in the morning: I went there about ten or eleven in the morning, to help the woman to wash the linen; I had laid the child by the woman, and there I found it; he was then gone to church to get leave of the parish to bury them. On the Saturday or Sunday, as he sat in my house, I asked him if the child was born alive; he said he did not know.</p>
               <p>Q. When were they buried?</p>
               <p>M. Duck. The child and woman were both buried on the Sunday; the woman was a stranger; I never saw her but once before, and never spoke to her in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-54-person588">
                  Dorothy 
                  Ripard 
               <interp inst="t17661217-54-person588" type="surname" value="Ripard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-54-person588" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-54-person588" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went at Mrs. Duck's desire to the prisoner's house; I took Mrs. Roberts and Mrs. Sams with me; Mrs. Duck met us there; the man met us at the gate; we said we were surprized he did not call some women to his wife's assistance; he said she would not let him; we went up stairs, and found the woman dead on the bed; Mrs. Duck, I, and Mrs. Sams, laid the woman out; then we took the child out of the water, and took a chamber-pot full of water out of the tub, and I believe there remained half a chamber-pot full more in the tub; Mrs. Duck laid the child on a blanket, and laid it by the side of the mother. There were no marks of violence about it; it was a female child; we called to the prisoner to know if he had ever a sheet to lay over his wife; he said he had never a one; I said, then lend us a table-cloth for decency; he said he had none; then we came down stairs, and I was the last woman<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176612170046"></xptr> that went out of the house; he said he had some gin in the house and asked if I chose to drink a glass of gin; I did not chuse it; then he desired I would tell Mrs. Duck to send 
               <persName id="t17661217-54-person589">
                  George 
                  Howard 
               <interp inst="t17661217-54-person589" type="surname" value="Howard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-54-person589" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-54-person589" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to him at night; I went and sent Mrs. Duck back to take her message herself; I was over frighted, and did not go near him after that</p>
               <p>Q. Had Mrs. Duck told you before you went she had seen the child?</p>
               <p>D. Ripard. She told me she had found a child in a tub under the bed.</p>
               <p>Q. How near do you live to the prisoner?</p>
               <p>D. Ripard. I live about 20 poles from him; he came to our house on the Friday morning, to get a horse to go to church; then I asked him how the child came in the tub of water; whether he heard me I cannot say, he turned himself and gave me no answer; he came to our house also on the Sunday (we keep a public-house) for four gallons of beer; I knew nothing of him before he came to live there; he had been there about 5 or 6 weeks; he had five children in the house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-54-person590">
                  Mary 
                  Sams 
               <interp inst="t17661217-54-person590" type="surname" value="Sams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-54-person590" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-54-person590" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was one of the women that helped to lay the woman out; I asked the prisoner at first going in, why he did not fetch some women to his wife; he said she would not let him: we laid the woman out, then took the child out of the tub and cleaned it, and laid it by her, and then came away and said nothing to him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-54-person591">
                  Catharine 
                  Roberts 
               <interp inst="t17661217-54-person591" type="surname" value="Roberts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-54-person591" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-54-person591" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have no more to say than what has been said; I never spoke to the prisoner, or was in the house afterwards.</p>
               <p>Mr. Roberts. I am a surgeon. On the 25th of November I was sent for by the officers of the parish, and the coroner, to meet him at Mims; there were various reports that the woman and child were murdered; I believe this was seven or eight days after the woman and child had been buried; they had taken the woman and child up; the child was laid under the bellfry, I believe the name of the place they call the bone-house: I examined it; all the jury were with me; I opened the chest, and separated the lungs from the other part, and suspended them in water; it is generally imagined, that in case they sink, they have been no ways inflated, or received the air; they swam upon the surface of the water, but I believe they barely had received air they were so triflingly inflated; I blowed into them afterwards, to convince the jury of what a deal of difference there was, when they had received a due portion, and when they had received little or none.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your opinion about this experiment?</p>
               <p>Roberts. I am not always quite satisfied as to that; from my own knowledge and experience I cannot positively declare, that the child was born alive; as Mrs. Duck mentioned at that time, that every thing was done as if by a midwife, I expected to see every thing was so done; but when I came to inspect that, there were four or five hand breadths of the navel-string left; an effusion of blood might happen from that, which might destroy the child; the end of it seemed to me to be rather torn than cut: that is a circumstance that should be paid due regard to, in every child that is born.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any marks of violence upon it?</p>
               <p>Roberts. No, there were not. I was desired likewise to inspect the body of the woman; there were no marks of violence on the body, nor no bad appearance.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that a sufficient quantity of water as has been mentioned here to drown a child?</p>
               <p>Roberts. To be sure it was; there was a trifle of water in the child, but the coffin was full of water when they were taken up.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was bad 3 weeks, and my wife was bad a fortnight, with the fever and ague; we nursed one another as well as we could; she was worse that day, being the Thursday, than any day; I had had a pair of shoes of a shoemaker, and a bottle of stuff, which he sells for a pain in the side; I took 30, 40, 45 drops at a time; he said it would do my wife good; it had done me good; I gave her a few drops of it in a little tea; she thought herself better, after that she thought herself worse; then she desired me to make her a little gin hot; I got some, and gave her a dram of cold gin; she was very bad; I said, shall I fetch any body; no, she said, she was a stranger in the place: I asked her again; she would not have any body sent for; she grew worse and worse. In about an hour after she drank the gin she miscarried; I said, dear heart, what is the reason you did not tell me of all this; why did you not tell me you was in labour; said she, I shall be very well, hold your tongue, I am as well as if I had 20 women here, I have done all the work myself; the chamber-pot was full by the bed-side; I was not in the room at the time of her labour; I was with the children below; she desired me to bring up something to empty the pot in, and I carried up a half butter firkin which she used to wash in; if there was any water in it, it was but a trifle: she grew so ill that I could not understand what she said; then I went for Mrs. Duck; I came from the same parish to that house, but I am quite a stranger there; that<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176612170047"></xptr> place is five miles distance from where I came from.</p>

               <p>Q. to Duck. How did the prisoner's children appear?</p>
               <p>Duck. They were very well, hearty and clean, for a poor man's children; they looked as if they had been taken care of; the prisoner behaved well when he was a boy; I knew him a child, but I had not seen him for 26 years, till he came to that place.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17661217-54-verdict279" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-54-verdict279" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
