<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17600910-13">
               <interp inst="t17600910-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600910-13" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600910-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600910"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600910-13" type="date" value="17600910"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600910-13-off67-c107" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-13-defend142 t17600910-13-off67 t17600910-13-verdict70"></join>
         
               <p>255. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17600910-13-defend142" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Curtis 
                  <interp inst="t17600910-13-defend142" type="surname" value="Curtis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-defend142" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-defend142" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17600910-13-deflabel66" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-13-defend142 t17600910-13-deflabel66"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17600910-13-off67" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-off67" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-off67" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch, value 50 s. and one pair of silver buckles, value 15 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17600910-13-victim144" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Underwood 
                        <interp inst="t17600910-13-victim144" type="surname" value="Underwood"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600910-13-victim144" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600910-13-victim144" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-13-off67 t17600910-13-victim144"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17600910-13-cd68" type="crimeDate">July 25</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-13-off67 t17600910-13-cd68"></join>.*</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600910-13-person145">
                  James 
                  Underwood 
               <interp inst="t17600910-13-person145" type="surname" value="Underwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person145" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person145" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 25th of July I was very much in liquor, in Hounsditch, or in Whitechapel, and I met with this 
               <persName id="t17600910-13-person146">
                  Sarah 
                  Curtis 
               <interp inst="t17600910-13-person146" type="surname" value="Curtis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person146" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person146" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day did you meet with her.</p>
               <p>Underwood. I believe betwixt 10 and 11 in the forenoon; she asked me where I was going, I said I did not know rightly, for I wanted to go to sleep; she said come and go along with me, and lie down on my bed, I have a very good bed; she took me to <placeName id="t17600910-13-crimeloc69">Church-lane, in Whitechapel parish</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17600910-13-crimeloc69" type="placeName" value="Church-lane, in Whitechapel parish"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17600910-13-crimeloc69" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-13-off67 t17600910-13-crimeloc69"></join>, and up stairs, and brought up 3 more women, the evidence, and 2 others that are in, Clarkenwell bridewell.</p>
               <p>Q. What are their names?</p>
               <p>Underwood. 
               <persName id="t17600910-13-person147">
                  Catherine 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17600910-13-person147" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person147" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person147" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17600910-13-person148">
                  Susanna 
                  Haywood 
               <interp inst="t17600910-13-person148" type="surname" value="Haywood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person148" type="given" value="Susanna"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person148" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17600910-13-person149">
                  Jane 
                  Trueman 
               <interp inst="t17600910-13-person149" type="surname" value="Trueman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person149" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person149" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , they asked me to give them something to drink; I said I have not much money, I will send for a pot of beer; I gave them six-pence: then said the prisoner at the bar, send your watch; said I, that is the last thing I do, then she said come let us have some beer; after that I gave her the buttons out of my sleeves, she went and pawned them for 18 d. then I said I want nothing but to go to sleep; I lay down upon the bed, and slept I believe 6 hours, from 12 to between 5 and 6; when I awaked my watch and buckles were gone, they were silver.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were they before you went to sleep?</p>
               <p>Underwood. My watch was in my pocket, and buckles in my shoes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go to sleep with all them women in the room?</p>
               <p>Underwood. I cannot say that, I know there was the evidence 
               <persName id="t17600910-13-person150">
                  Catherine 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17600910-13-person150" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person150" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person150" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and the prisoner at the bar; but when I awaked there was no one but myself in the room, and the door was open.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176009100012"></xptr>Q. When did you see the prisoner afterwards?</p>
               <p>Underwood. I saw her in half an hour afterwards in another house; when I came down stairs 
               <persName id="t17600910-13-person151">
                  Catherine 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17600910-13-person151" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person151" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person151" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was below stairs. I told her what I had lost; they said they knew nothing at all of it; then I sent for an officer and charg'd them all four upon suspicion, I took them before justice Berry, and 
               <persName id="t17600910-13-person152">
                  Catherine 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17600910-13-person152" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person152" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person152" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             turn'd evidence against the prisoner at the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you got your watch again?</p>
               <p>Underwood. No, nor have not seen it since.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say before the justice?</p>
               <p>Underwood. She pleaded innocent; she said she knew nothing at all of it; the evidence swore there, that she saw her with a watch in her hand.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Did not you offer your watch, before you did your buttons, and I would not let you.</p>
               <p>Underwood. No; she ask'd me to pawn it, but I said that was the last thing I would part with.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600910-13-person153">
                  Catherine 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17600910-13-person153" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person153" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person153" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodg'd below stairs in the same court opposite the prisoner, under the room where the prisoner brought him in, which was a little before eleven o'clock. She called to me to fetch a pot of beer; Mr. Underwood gave me 6 d. he took the pot and drank, and pull'd out his watch to see what o'clock it was; he ask'd her whether it was her own house; she said it was; then he said, I thought we were to go to bed; she ask'd him for some money; he said he had none; she said pawn your watch; he would not, but gave her his studs.</p>
               <p>Q. For what purpose?</p>
               <p>C. Smith. For some beer; she went for the beer; after that she call'd the other two up to drink; one is 
               <persName id="t17600910-13-person154">
                  Susannah 
                  Haywood 
               <interp inst="t17600910-13-person154" type="surname" value="Haywood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person154" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person154" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the other 
               <persName id="t17600910-13-person155">
                  Jane 
                  Trueman 
               <interp inst="t17600910-13-person155" type="surname" value="Trueman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person155" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person155" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I had a bit of bread and butter in my hand, and I did not drink any; after that the other two women came down stairs and left the prisoner and prosecutor together a considerable time; after that she knock'd with the heel of her shoe; I went up to ask what she wanted.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>Smith. This was a little after 12 o'clock; she said she had got his watch, and wanted me to go with her to pawn it. I said I would not; he lay on the bed, whether he was asleep I know not, his lips did not move, he seem'd as if asleep.</p>
               <p>Q. What part of the room was she in?</p>
               <p>C. Smith. She was on the bed at the time; I did not see any buckles she had, she had the watch in her hand; she staid up stairs some time, and then she came down, and was backwards and forwards in the lane after that, and was sadly in liquor about five in the morning, and went into her own apartment.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the watch afterwards?</p>
               <p>C. Smith. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you swear the same as now before the justice?</p>
               <p>C Smith. I did.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>He offered me the watch, and I told him I did not carry such things for any man; then he gave me the buttons, I pawned them for 18 d. and carried him the 3 d. and a full pot of beer and a shilling.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600910-13-person156">
                  Jonathan 
                  Strong 
               <interp inst="t17600910-13-person156" type="surname" value="Strong"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person156" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person156" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a weaver by trade; I have known the prisoner about 7 or 8 months, she is an engine windster, that is, she winds silk for weavers; she did live in my house, I know nothing amiss of her; when they were gone for an officer she said, I will not fly, for I have done no harm, in my hearing.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know 
               <persName id="t17600910-13-person157">
                  Catherine 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17600910-13-person157" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person157" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person157" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Strong. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. How does she get her livelihood?</p>
               <p>Strong. She can tell best, I can say nothing of her goodness, I believe she does not like to work too hard.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business at present?</p>
               <p>Strong. I kept a public house since Christmas, not before.</p>
               <p>Q. Does 
               <persName id="t17600910-13-person158">
                  Catherine 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17600910-13-person158" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person158" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person158" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             come to your house?</p>
               <p>Strong. No, I will not suffer her to come into it, I bring her out head foremost, she can't deny it, I have slung her out head foremost; she never wrong'd me of any thing, but I don't like she should come there. Underwood bears an undeniable character, he is a very hard working man, that can't be denied.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600910-13-person159">
                  Mary 
                  Langley 
               <interp inst="t17600910-13-person159" type="surname" value="Langley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person159" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person159" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I wind silk; I have known the prisoner above 30 years, she liv'd with me a great many years, about 10 successively, she was always very honest.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Harris. I have known her about twenty years, I never heard any dishonesty by her, she always had a general good character; she has nurs'd my children, and my kinsman's children, and always behav'd very honest.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176009100013"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17600910-13-person160">
                  Sarah 
                  Galaway 
               <interp inst="t17600910-13-person160" type="surname" value="Galaway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person160" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-person160" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her a great many years; she work'd along with me about a year and a half ago, she never wrong'd me, I never heard she wrong'd man, woman, or child.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600910-13-verdict70" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600910-13-verdict70" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
