<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670909-71">
               <interp inst="t17670909-71" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670909-71" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670909-71" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670909"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670909-71" type="date" value="17670909"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670909-71-off421-c619" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-71-defend770 t17670909-71-off421 t17670909-71-verdict426"></join>
         
               <p>496. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17670909-71-defend770" type="defendantName">
                  Jonathan 
                  Park 
               <interp inst="t17670909-71-defend770" type="surname" value="Park"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-71-defend770" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-71-defend770" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17670909-71-off421" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670909-71-off421" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-71-off421" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing two guineas
            </rs>, the money of 
               
                  <persName id="t17670909-71-victim772" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Graham 
                  <interp inst="t17670909-71-victim772" type="surname" value="Graham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-71-victim772" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-71-victim772" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-71-off421 t17670909-71-victim772"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17670909-71-cd422" type="crimeDate">June 26</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-71-off421 t17670909-71-cd422"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-71-person773">
                  John 
                  Graham 
               <interp inst="t17670909-71-person773" type="surname" value="Graham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-71-person773" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-71-person773" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I <rs id="t17670909-71-viclabel423" type="occupation">drive the Halifax waggon</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-71-victim772 t17670909-71-viclabel423"></join>, belonging to 
               <persName id="t17670909-71-person774">
                  William 
                  Beal 
               <interp inst="t17670909-71-person774" type="surname" value="Beal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-71-person774" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-71-person774" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I went to bed at the inn, the <placeName id="t17670909-71-crimeloc424">White Bear, Basinghall-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17670909-71-crimeloc424" type="placeName" value="White Bear, Basinghall-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17670909-71-crimeloc424" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-71-off421 t17670909-71-crimeloc424"></join>, on the 25th of June, about eleven at night; the prisoner went to bed at the time, he is the <rs id="t17670909-71-deflabel425" type="occupation">boot-catcher</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-71-defend770 t17670909-71-deflabel425"></join> there; there are two beds in the room; he lay in the other bed, I believe he was in bed ten minutes before me; he saw me undress myself; when I had my breeches in my hand, I pulled out my purse; I had nothing but three guineas in gold, and 7 s. in silver in it; I put it in my breeches again, and buttoned it, and put it under my pillow, and went to bed; I believe I was asleep in two minutes; I left the candle blazing by his bed side; I awaked about four, and saw he was out of bed; my breeches were removed from under my bolster and pillow, and I found my purse not in the situation I had put it; I had tied it in a knot, and doubled it up, but I found it not so; I jumped out of bed directly, and found there was nothing in the purse; I ran down stairs after I had got my clothes on, there was the prisoner standing by the gate; I said, d - n thee, what hast thon been doing; he said, what is the matter; I said, thou knowest what the matter is; I told him what I missed, and said he must have taken it; he said he had a person bound in a bond of 200 l. for his honesty; I told the master of the inn that I went to bed with that man, and all my silver and gold was gone out of my pocket, and I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176709090064"></xptr> have a great suspicion of him; he asked how much I had lost; I said between 3 and 4 l. he said, hold your tongue, and I'll come down; he came down, and said to the prisoner, what business had you in that room, have I not discharged him from lying in that room; said the prisoner, I wish I had laid on the dunghill, or any where; then he said to me, I have two guineas, if they are thine, thou shat have them; he opened his box; the landlord said, thou fool, if thou hast the two guineas, thou woust not lay them there; then he said, waggoner, be not afraid, here is a man bound in a bond for 200 l. for his honesty; then he went out into the city, and came back again; and said nothing to me, nor I to him; then I went to him, and said, Mr. Collier, is there nothing to be done; he said, h old your tongue, they will be here presently; still nothing was done; then I began to be angry; I said it is very hard money should be gone out of my pocket, and no account of it; then he said, waggoner, come here; he took me into a room among some gentlemen, and examined me; I told him what I had spent upon the road; then he attempted to cast up my account; they sent me out of the room, and called in the prisoner, and examined him; in about an hour they called me in again, they were drinking punch; they said, come, waggoner, drink; they asked me again, what I had taken and spent; I told them over again; then the landlord said, gentlemen, I will make it appear this man has lost nothing at all, he is a d - d scoundrel and a villain; he said to me, I will send Justice Fielding's servants for you before you go out of my yard; he put the prisoner to hold the door; there they kept me two hours, till my horses came into the waggon; then he swore to me, I'll knock your head off, thou art a villain; a gentleman said, hold your tongue, Collier; then he said again, gentlemen, I will make it apparently appear this man has lost not a farthing.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I never saw no money that he had.</p>
               <p>He called 
               <persName id="t17670909-71-person775">
                  Henry 
                  Collier 
               <interp inst="t17670909-71-person775" type="surname" value="Collier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-71-person775" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-71-person775" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who said, according to the account the prosecutor had first given of his expences, and what money he received, he could not have lost any thing; be, Mr. Colfield, Mr. Wade, Mr. Fielding, Mrs. Ezard, and Mr. Meeking, all gave the prisoner the character of an honest man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17670909-71-verdict426" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670909-71-verdict426" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
