<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660702-40">
               <interp inst="t17660702-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660702-40" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660702-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660702"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660702-40" type="date" value="17660702"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660702-40-off218-c287" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-40-defend365 t17660702-40-off218 t17660702-40-verdict221"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660702-40-off218-c288" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-40-defend367 t17660702-40-off218 t17660702-40-verdict221"></join>
         
               <p>376, 377. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660702-40-defend365" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Cowen 
                  <interp inst="t17660702-40-defend365" type="surname" value="Cowen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-40-defend365" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-40-defend365" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17660702-40-defend367" type="defendantName">
                     Peter 
                     Bonks 
                  <interp inst="t17660702-40-defend367" type="surname" value="Bonks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-40-defend367" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-40-defend367" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted, for that <rs id="t17660702-40-off218" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660702-40-off218" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-40-off218" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               they, in a certain alley near the King's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17660702-40-victim369" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Norwell 
                        <interp inst="t17660702-40-victim369" type="surname" value="Norwell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660702-40-victim369" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660702-40-victim369" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-40-off218 t17660702-40-victim369"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and taking from his person a silk handkerchief, value 6 d. his property, and against his will
            </rs>, <rs id="t17660702-40-cd219" type="crimeDate">June 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-40-off218 t17660702-40-cd219"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-40-person370">
                  William 
                  Norwell 
               <interp inst="t17660702-40-person370" type="surname" value="Norwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-40-person370" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-40-person370" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Monday night I was going home to my habitation in White-cross-street, out of <placeName id="t17660702-40-crimeloc220">Golden-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17660702-40-crimeloc220" type="placeName" value="Golden-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660702-40-crimeloc220" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-40-off218 t17660702-40-crimeloc220"></join>, into some alley, about half an hour after ten o'clock all alone; four or five men met me in the alley; they first got to the side of me, and knocked me down without speaking, which almost took away my senses; I made as much resistance as I could. They catched hold of me by the collar, and by my handkerchief about my neck, and dragged me five or six yards back; then they knocked me down again. Some of the company asked me, if I was an Irishman; I could make no answer, being obliged to call out for help; then they kicked me; I called murder I about half a dozen times; I called to Mr. Boldridge, who lives near, I serve him with bread; his wife came to the window and called out, let the man alone; you are murdering fellows: they knocked me down again; somebody said, let him alone, he is no Irishman; some of the witnesses that are here, fetched some watchmen; by that time I was almost strangled with blood coming out at my mouth and nose; if it had not been for the neighbours and the by-watch, I should certainly have lost my life; I desired them to take all I had got, so that they spared my life; they d - d me, and said, I was no Irishman; I believe they are Irish.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they demand any thing of you?</p>
               <p>Norwell. I cannot say whether they did or not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they put their hands in your pocket?</p>
               <p>Norwell. No, not to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any money or watch about you?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176607020030"></xptr>Norwell I had both, but lost nothing but my handkerchief; the two prisoners were there among them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know them before?</p>
               <p>Norwell. I never saw them before to my knowledge: they both violently laid their hands upon me; Cowen knocked me down; he had my handkerchief. The prisoners were apprehended in about two or three hours after in the same court, by the constable and assistance: I was there, and pointed them out.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-40-person371">
                  Henry 
                  Hodskin 
               <interp inst="t17660702-40-person371" type="surname" value="Hodskin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-40-person371" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-40-person371" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming down Golden-lane; this passage comes down between two streets, it is called Sun-alley; these people had been in a quarrel before; I stood by and saw it: there were the two prisoners, and two or three more, quarrelling with a man that they met accidentally, this was better than half an hour after ten o'clock; they parted with him, and came cross Red-lion-market, and down into this alley. There was another man, who said, these people are very quarrelsome: he would not go on, but turned another way; it was my way to go through; I staid at the top of the alley, thinking they might be got to the bottom, but instead of that, they turned into this court; when I came within 15 or 20 yards of the court, they turned back into a narrow passage; Cowen set his back against the wall of Mr. Dickenson's brewhouse, the others set their backs against the wall on the other side; I came boldly down, and cried, halloo, my boys! I was just got past the last of them; the prosecutor came; I had not gone past five or six steps before he was knocked down, they catched hold of him, and dragged him into the narrow court out of the open passage; at the corner of the court they knocked him down again; one of them d - d his eyes, and said, he is an Irishman; another d - d his eyes, and said, he is no Irishman, and down with him again; he cried, murder! another gentleman was coming; I ran to call the watchman, and just as we came up, Cowen catched the prosecutor by the breast, and threw him down again; they had been kicking of him before; I had seen that, but dar'd not go to his assistance; I went to call the constable; he was rather dilatory in coming, and I went back again; then the neighbours got out of their beds, and went to fetch the constable; he then came, and two or three watchmen; in the mean time these men were gone into a house; then we went all back to the watch-house. The prosecutor insisted on the constable setting somebody at the door where they went in; they set three men. I went home to bed, but was called up afterwards, and went to the watch-house, and was sure the two prisoners were two of them; that is a very dangerous place in a night.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think people that had just committed a robbery would go into a house directly?</p>
               <p>Hodskin. People were got about, so that they could not get either way to get off.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-40-person372">
                  William 
                  Boldridge 
               <interp inst="t17660702-40-person372" type="surname" value="Boldridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-40-person372" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-40-person372" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an inhabitant in this neighbourhood; we went to bed about ten o'clock; hearing a noise, I got up and went to the door in my shirt; my wife went to the window; I saw the prosecutor on the ground; he is a baker, and serves me with bread; he called to me, but his mouth was full of blood, I could hardly understand him; I saw the fellow run into a house; the man of the house says they lodge there; the prosecutor had lost his handkerchief; we took him into our house; he was there some time before the prisoners were taken; I went to the watch-house with him; he said he was positive the two prisoners were two of the men that abused him; they are a very bad set of people; I have seen them abuse others so, and run into that house; they threaten ruin now to me, and others that have concerned ourselves about them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-40-person373">
                  Tobias 
                  Vickers 
               <interp inst="t17660702-40-person373" type="surname" value="Vickers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-40-person373" type="given" value="Tobias"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-40-person373" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a lodger in Mr. Boldridge's house; about a quarter before eleven, I heard the cry of murder several times; I got out of bed, and saw the baker lying on the ground, and four or five men about him; he got up; I saw them knock him down again; he arose upon his knees, they knocked him down again; he cried murder! in a very alarming manner. The woman where I live got to the window and cried, you murdering thieves! have you a mind to murder another man: then I saw them run into the house where they were taken. When I came down to the baker, his mouth was full of blood; when I asked him what was the matter, he was not able to answer. I was at the taking the prisoners in their lodgings.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-40-person374">
                  Charles 
                  Marnet 
               <interp inst="t17660702-40-person374" type="surname" value="Marnet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-40-person374" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-40-person374" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming home that night about half an hour after ten o'clock; I heard a noise of a parcel of people, and murder was cried; I pushed forward towards the broad place; I had not been there a minute before the prisoner Cowen knocked the baker down, and the other prisoner stamped upon him with his knee; they cried out, d - n him, he is no Irishman. I was obliged to make my escape as fast as I could. I ran to the watch-house in Red-cross-street: by that time people got to the watch-house; then we came up to the place where they abused him, and the men were got into their place of abode. We set three or four watchmen at the door; the constable knocked and asked for admittance; it was some time before they would open the door; the mob<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176607020031"></xptr> insisted upon going up, and seeing what people there were in the garret: I went up with them; the constable would not break the door open; we came down again; the constable went to the watch-house, and three watchmen more came to watch; there came three or four people quite enraged, and insisted the door should be broke open: the constable came and went up with us, and a man took a watchman's staff and broke the door open; there we found four men in bed, the two prisoners were two of them; we guarded them one by one to the watch-house; the baker gave charge of the two prisoners, which I can swear to, that one knocked him down, and the other kneeled upon him. The landlord of the house where they lodged came to the watch-house, and said he could swear the other two were in bed by nine o'clock, upon which the constable allowed them bail; I could have swore to one of them that is let go.</p>
               <p>Cowen's defence.</p>
               <p>I was coming home; I accidentally met this man about six doors from my lodging; I happened to shove against him; but as to striking him, I never did.</p>
               <p>Monks's defence.</p>
               <p>One of them tumbled over the other, and the man cried out, murder! and watch! I got up and said, Gentlemen, I beg you will be easy; we went home to bed, and lay there; if the gentleman has lost his handkerchief, it may be so, but I know nothing of it; they got sufficient help to take us out of our beds: our landlord was not by, he was in bed; he had no right to come as a witness.</p>
               <p>For the prisoners.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-40-person375">
                  Thomas 
                  Lyon 
               <interp inst="t17660702-40-person375" type="surname" value="Lyon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-40-person375" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-40-person375" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Newtoner's-lane, and am a bricklayer; Cowen lodged with me about eight months; I know him to be an honest sober lad.</p>
               <p>Catherine his wife, gave the same evidence</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-40-person376">
                  Anne
                   O'Brian
               <interp inst="t17660702-40-person376" type="surname" value="O'Brian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-40-person376" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-40-person376" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Tottenham-court-road; 
               <persName id="t17660702-40-person377">
                  Peter 
                  Monks 
               <interp inst="t17660702-40-person377" type="surname" value="Monks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-40-person377" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-40-person377" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was my lodger going on two years; he was honest and just, and never kept bad hours with me; he had used to take my advice as a mother; nobody can say black to him, God bless your Lordship.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17660702-40-verdict221" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660702-40-verdict221" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>They were detained, to be tried for violently assaulting the prosecutor, &amp;c.</p>
            </div1>
