<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17651211-41">
               <interp inst="t17651211-41" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651211-41" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651211-41" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17651211"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651211-41" type="date" value="17651211"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17651211-41-off240-c283" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-41-defend375 t17651211-41-off240 t17651211-41-verdict245"></join>
         
               <p>46. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17651211-41-defend375" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Pyner 
                  <interp inst="t17651211-41-defend375" type="surname" value="Pyner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-defend375" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-defend375" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17651211-41-deflabel239" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-41-defend375 t17651211-41-deflabel239"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17651211-41-off240" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-off240" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-off240" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a moidore, a 6 s. and 9 penny piece, 14 guineas, 1 half guinea, 3 quarter guineas, 5 s. in money, numbered; and 2 stone ear-rings, set in gold, value 5 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17651211-41-victim377" type="victimName">
                           Edward 
                           Gibbons 
                        <interp inst="t17651211-41-victim377" type="surname" value="Gibbons"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651211-41-victim377" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651211-41-victim377" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-41-off240 t17651211-41-victim377"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling-house of the said Edward
            </rs>, <rs id="t17651211-41-cd241" type="crimeDate">November 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-41-off240 t17651211-41-cd241"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-41-person378">
                  Edward 
                  Gibbons 
               <interp inst="t17651211-41-person378" type="surname" value="Gibbons"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-person378" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-person378" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I <rs id="t17651211-41-viclabel242" type="occupation">keep the <placeName id="t17651211-41-crimeloc243">Bell at Paddington</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-crimeloc243" type="placeName" value="Bell at Paddington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-crimeloc243" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-41-off240 t17651211-41-crimeloc243"></join>, a public house</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-41-victim377 t17651211-41-viclabel242"></join>; the prisoner lived <rs id="t17651211-41-deflabel244" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-41-defend375 t17651211-41-deflabel244"></join> with me: I think she came on the 7th of October. In the room where I lie, I had a little box covered with leather, which I used to put my money in; I had 17 guineas and some silver, and 2 gold ear-rings with stones in them in it.</p>
               <p>Q. Describe what pieces of money as near as you can?</p>
               <p>Gibbons. There was a moidore, a 6 s. and 9 d. 3 quarter guineas, and some silver, a few shillings, I cannot tell how much, and 14 guineas and a half.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you seen the money last?</p>
               <p>Gibbons. I had seen it, I believe, about an hour before I lost it, which was on the 29th of November: I missed it between 4 and 5 in the afternoon. I had put in two guineas about an hour before. I had a little cow-house in my yard, with a truss of hay in it; it was set on fire; we all in the house went out to it to put it out; my wife bolted the fore-door, she sent the prisoner in at the back door, and when we all went into the house we found the fore-door unbolted, and open; then we went all up stairs, and the box was gone.</p>
               <p>Q. What distance of time between your going out to put out the fire, and your coming in again?</p>
               <p>Gibbons. I believe it might be 6 or 8 minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the girl when you returned?</p>
               <p>Gibbons. She was in the house when the box was missing; we asked her if she saw any body; she said she was knocked down by a soldier and another man, who both stepped over her in the house; then we went all out to see who we could see, some one way, and some another.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell whether the girl at the bar ever saw you open the box?</p>
               <p>Gibbons. I cannot say she ever did, I believe she knew we had money in it. It was kept on a little mahogany table, I never saw the box since.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner in the house all that evening?</p>
               <p>Gibbons. She was out some time, but not after she told us a soldier knocked her down.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you suspect her?</p>
               <p>Gibbons. No, I had no suspicion of her taking it.</p>
               <p>Q. How came she to be taken up?</p>
               <p>Gibbons. Because she owned it herself.</p>
               <p>Q. When did she own it?</p>
               <p>Gibbons. On Tuesday I believe in last week; she was in my service then, but I did not hear her. I was gone to London. But here is a witness here<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176512110024"></xptr> that did, and after that I heard her own it before Justice Welch.</p>
               <p>Q. When was she taken up?</p>
               <p>Gibbons. She was taken up this day week. At first she said her mother was guilty of it, and we had the mother in St. Giles's Round-house. She said her mother came to her and asked her, If she knew where her master kept his money; she having no money, and she must help her to some: that the girl answered, How can I do it? And the mother said, You must set some part of your master's house on fire; and if you will not do it I will kill you, or set somebody else to do it; and upon that the stable was set on fire the first time; (my place was three times set on fire, on the 22d, the 27th, and 29th of November) the hay was set on fire in the rick the two first times; the last was a truss of hay on the ground. After this she said it was her sister; and all the reason she gave was, that her sister and mother were so much alike, she could not tell which it was: then after that she owned she had taken the box away and hid it, and broke it to pieces, and lighted the fire with it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she own to the taking the money?</p>
               <p>Gibbons. I do not remember she owned any thing of that; the money was found upon her last Friday, and then she was taken before Justice Welch. I did not see it found, but I saw it counted before Mr. Welch.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-41-person379">
                  Edward 
                  Holdway 
               <interp inst="t17651211-41-person379" type="surname" value="Holdway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-person379" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-person379" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable of Paddington. On the 29th of November the prosecutor came to my house, and said he had been robbed, and his stables had been set on fire; that he had lost a box with 16 or 17 pounds, or guineas, and desired I would assist him. I went with him; he desired me to go up stairs: the beds I found strangely tumbled about. He said the box was taken from off the table. The prisoner said, People came down stairs, and a man in soldiers cloaths had knocked her down with a candle and lanthorn in his hand, and a box under the other. I looked her in the face, and said, Are you hurt? She said, No. Mr. Gibbons said, he had some suspicion of a soldier that was quartered in his house about nine months. I said I knew the man very well, and know where he keeps company not far off, and perhaps we shall find him. I went and found the girl he keeps company with, and the people could prove the girl was never out of the way of the door; the people gave leave to search the house. I went home, not having found out any thing; the next morning the prosecutor desired I would come to his house: I went, and found he, and his wife, and the girl at breakfast. I observed the girl did not care to look me in my face. We went and got a warrant, in order to take the soldier up. When we came to the barracks, we enquired for the captain, named Smith. We were told we could not see him till 4 in the afternoon; we waited. When he came, we told him the affair. It being St. Andrew's day, and the soldier being a Scotchman, we thought he might be a merry-making. The captain said we might have him the next morning. We went the next morning and took the soldier, and put him in the watch-house; after that there were people that proved the fellow never was out of their company, so he was acquitted. Then I desired Mr. Gibbons to go home and try his maid: he said he had no suspicion of her. On the Wednesday the prosecutor's wife sent for me; I went. She said she had heard of the money. I found the girl crying in the room. I put the people out of the room, and asked the girl what was become of the money. Said she, I'll tell you the truth. A day or two before the first time the fire was (which was on the 22d of November), my mother came to me, and asked me where my master puts his money. I asked for what reason. She said, money she wanted, and money she would have; that her sister lay-in in St. Andrew's work-house. She said she could not help her to any; that the old woman said, you must set fire to something, and I'll go up stairs and fetch the money down. Then she said her mother came, and asked her who set fire to the stables on the 27th; she said she could not tell, she saw nobody. She said her mother came to the house with a candle and lanthorn, and set fire to it on the 22d. I asked who set fire to it on the 29th. She said her mother: that she saw her go through the passage and take the box away. I asked how she knew; her mother took the box away. She said she went up stairs, and shewed her mother the room where the box was, and after that she stood in the passage and saw her bring the box down stairs, and carry it into the stable and hide it, and set fire to the place, and then went away. I asked her what became of the box; she said her mother came the next morning, between 11 and 12 o'clock, and fetched it away; and she went down into the stable along with her, and saw her take it under her cloak: then I took her to Mr. Welch's, the clerk examined her, she seemed to say all this, and signed her examination there.</p>
         
               <p>*** The Last Part of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17651211-41">
                  <interp inst="t17651211-41" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17651211-41" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17651211-41" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17651211"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17651211-41" type="date" value="17651211"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176512110025"></xptr>THE WHOLE PROCEEDINGS ON THE KING's COMMISSIONS of the PEACE, OYER and TERMINER, and GOAL DELIVERY FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the GOAL DELIVERY FOR THE COUNTY of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 11th, Thursday the 12th, Friday the 13th, Saturday the 14th, and Monday the 16th of DECEMBER, 1765.</p>
                  <p>In the Sixth Year of His MAJESTY's Reign. Being the First SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of THE RIGHT HONOURABLE 
                  <persName id="t17651211-41-person380">
                     GEORGE 
                     NELSON 
                  <interp inst="t17651211-41-person380" type="surname" value="NELSON"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651211-41-person380" type="given" value="GEORGE"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651211-41-person380" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Esq; LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>NUMBER I. PART II.</p>
                  <p>LONDON,</p>
                  <p>Printed for J. WILKIE, at the Bible, in St. Paul's Church-Yard.</p>
                  <p>[Price Six-Pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176512110026"></xptr>THE WHOLE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Goal Delivery held for the City of LONDON, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Continuation of the Trial of 
               <persName id="t17651211-41-person381">
                  Mary 
                  Pyner 
               <interp inst="t17651211-41-person381" type="surname" value="Pyner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-person381" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-person381" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>


               <p>Prosecutor. I SAW her sign it before Justice Welch.</p>
               <p>Holdway. This was not an examination taken before the Justice; it was only before the clerk. Then we got a warrant, and went to the workhouse where the sister lay-in: we found she had been gone out three weeks. Then we heard where the mother lodged in Gray's inn-lane: we went there, and found she had been gone from thence two months. Then we went to the Black Horse in Gray's-inn-lane; there they recommended us to another place: then we heard the mother lodged at the Cock and Crown in Little Britain. While we were asking about this in Gray's-inn-lane, in came the mother: the people said that was she; we took her into custody. We had left the prosecutor and girl together hard by: when we brought them together, the girl upbraided the mother with all I have said: we searched the mother, but could find nothing upon her. I took them both to the round-house, and ordered them to be kept asunder, and nobody to come near them. The next morning I went again to enquire the mother's character about Little Britain; but before I set out, I ordered a woman to search the girl: she was searched, and nothing was found upon her. I searched the bed and under the bed: then I went to the Cock and Crown to ask about the mother: the woman of the house could recollect the mother was out about the 22d, but was sure she was not out on the 27th. I asked if she could recollect she was out on the 29th. The man of the house, and one 
               <persName id="t17651211-41-person382">
                  John 
                  Lemon 
               <interp inst="t17651211-41-person382" type="surname" value="Lemon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-person382" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-person382" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , both said they were sure the mother was there, and not out that day. I asked if she was out on the Saturday in the afternoon: they said no. Then I desired them to come up and be examined, that the old woman might be cleared: they did. Then I went to the girl, and said you are a sad girl; I am afraid you are going to hurt your mother: here are her master and mistress coming, and they will prove you a story teller. Then I took her by herself; she began to cry, and said she would tell the truth. Then she said, indeed it was my sister that came in the room of my mother: she said my mother could not come, and I lighted my sister up stairs, and she took the box and carried it into the stable, and put it into a grain-hole, and covered it over with old rags. I asked her who came for the box: she said my sister. I said, are you sure of it: she said, I am. Now, said I, you'll send me on such another errand: then I went and got another warrant, and went after the sister to one Jenkins's in Gray's-inn-lane. I went there, and was informed that the girl had an aunt in Monmouth-street: I went for the aunt, and said you must go and assist me in this matter: if she will tell where the money and things are, perhaps the man will be favourable. We went to the girl: I told her she would have no favour, if she went before the Justice. She seemed to cry and held down her head: said I, I'll go and get me some victuals; I went, and about one o'clock the aunt sent for me. When I came, the aunt said the girl took her down stairs.</p>
               <p>Court. The aunt must give an account of that.</p>
               <p>Holdway. Then the girl told me she did it herself; her mother and sister were not present. I took the money from the man of the round-house, and told it 17 l. 19 s. two ear-rings, and some silver. The girl said she had hid the box in the coal-hole under a sack, and had after that broke it to pieces and burnt it. The Justice then discharged the mother and sister.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-41-person383">
                  Frances 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17651211-41-person383" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-person383" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-person383" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the round-house, the prisoner was confined there: she came on the Wednesday; I had her three days. On the Friday there were her mother and sister; but they never were together, nor never spoke to each other. We prayed the girl to tell the truth; and told her<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176512110027"></xptr> what a sad thing it would be, at the great day, if she should wrong her mother and sister: she said they were guilty: at last she clapped her hand upon her aunt, and said, aunt save me. Then she said she had something to say to her aunt: they went by themselves; I followed and watched them, and saw her deliver a purse out of her bosom to her aunt: her aunt delivered it to me, and I never opened it till I delivered it to the constable.</p>
               <p>Q to Holdway. Produce it.</p>
               <p>Holdway. This is the purse which the last witness delivered to me, with the money in it.</p>
               <p>Q. to Clark. Did you hear the prisoner say any thing when she delivered the money.</p>
               <p>Clark. I heard her say, after she went below; aunt I'll give it you, if you can save me. Then I sent for the constable from the public house, and delivered it to him. ( The money produced)</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Can you swear to any of these pieces?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I described the pieces to Justice Welch before I saw the money: the moidore and six and nine-pence I can swear to be my property, which were among the other money.</p>
               <p>To her character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-41-person384">
                  Kenelm 
                  Dawson 
               <interp inst="t17651211-41-person384" type="surname" value="Dawson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-person384" type="given" value="Kenelm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-person384" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about three years; I live in Monmouth-street; the prisoner's aunt lives next door to me; she lived with her aunt. I don't know any girl had a better character than she had, when she lived there: a well behaved girl I looked upon her to be; she had the esteem of the whole neighbourhood.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has she left her aunt?</p>
               <p>Dawson. I believe she has left her aunt six months.</p>
               <p>Q. How old do you take her to be?</p>
               <p>Dawson. I look upon her to be 15 or 16 years of age.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-41-person385">
                  John 
                  Ledward 
               <interp inst="t17651211-41-person385" type="surname" value="Ledward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-person385" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-person385" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her about 10 years; I lodged in her aunt's house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-41-person386">
                  Eliz 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17651211-41-person386" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-person386" type="given" value="Eliz"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-person386" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her two years; she always bore an honest good character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-41-person387">
                  Ebenezer 
                  Averingham 
               <interp inst="t17651211-41-person387" type="surname" value="Averingham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-person387" type="given" value="Ebenezer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-person387" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her eight or nine years; I never heard any ill of her in my life before this; I could have trusted her with untold gold.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-41-person388">
                  Barnard 
                  Bailey 
               <interp inst="t17651211-41-person388" type="surname" value="Bailey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-person388" type="given" value="Barnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-person388" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her almost 10 years; I lodged in her aunt's house; I am in the watch way; I never missed any thing; she always behaved with an extreme good character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-41-person389">
                  James 
                  Coleman 
               <interp inst="t17651211-41-person389" type="surname" value="Coleman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-person389" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-person389" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her two years last Michaelmas; I was a lodger in the house; during which time she behaved herself as honest as any person in the world. She had recourse to my room; I have had above 50 guineas at a time, and rings and things; she had a key that unlocked the door next to mine, which would unlock the door that went into mine, and she knew it; I never missed any thing.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17651211-41-verdict245" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-verdict245" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17651211-41-punish246" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651211-41-punish246" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-41-defend375 t17651211-41-punish246"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
