<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17661217-62">
               <interp inst="t17661217-62" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-62" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-62" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17661217"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-62" type="date" value="17661217"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17661217-62-off320-c527" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-62-defend665 t17661217-62-off320 t17661217-62-verdict325"></join>
         
               <p>76. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17661217-62-defend665" type="defendantName">
                     Anne 
                     Willis 
                  <interp inst="t17661217-62-defend665" type="surname" value="Willis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-defend665" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-defend665" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             
                  <rs id="t17661217-62-deflabel319" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-62-defend665 t17661217-62-deflabel319"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17661217-62-off320" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-off320" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-off320" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 10 s. in money numbered
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17661217-62-victim667" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Fox 
                  <interp inst="t17661217-62-victim667" type="surname" value="Fox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-victim667" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-victim667" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-62-off320 t17661217-62-victim667"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17661217-62-cd321" type="crimeDate">October 4</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-62-off320 t17661217-62-cd321"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>At the desire of the prisoner the witnesses were examined apart.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-62-person668">
                  Alice 
                  Fox 
               <interp inst="t17661217-62-person668" type="surname" value="Fox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person668" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person668" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My husband's name is 
               <persName id="t17661217-62-person669">
                  Thomas 
                  Fox 
               <interp inst="t17661217-62-person669" type="surname" value="Fox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person669" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person669" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , we <rs id="t17661217-62-viclabel322" type="occupation">keep <placeName id="t17661217-62-crimeloc323">the Hercules Pillars in Great Queen-street</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-crimeloc323" type="placeName" value="the Hercules Pillars in Great Queen-street"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-crimeloc323" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-62-off320 t17661217-62-crimeloc323"></join>
                  </rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-62-victim667 t17661217-62-viclabel322"></join>; on the 3d of October between eleven and twelve at night, I took the silver and gold out of the till, and afterwards locked the till, with very near 20 s. in halfpence in it; then I went to bed, and took the keys with me; the prisoner was our <rs id="t17661217-62-deflabel324" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-62-defend665 t17661217-62-deflabel324"></join>; the next morning there was 10 s. at least missing; I searched the prisoner's boxes, but found nothing; she was charged with this in the morning; she went away that day.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she paid her wages?</p>
               <p>A. Fox. No, she never was paid; she has had her cloaths away.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-62-person670">
                  John 
                  Fox 
               <interp inst="t17661217-62-person670" type="surname" value="Fox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person670" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person670" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am going into fourteen years of age, I am Mr. Fox's nephew, I live with him; the only servants in the house, were 
               <persName id="t17661217-62-person671">
                  William 
                  Salmon 
               <interp inst="t17661217-62-person671" type="surname" value="Salmon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person671" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person671" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and the prisoner; she followed me up and down the house that night to get me to bed; between twelve and one I went up stairs, she was in the bar; I could not think what business she had there, Salmon was asleep in the kitchen; the bell rang, there was company above; I called Salmon to answer the bell; the prisoner had this thing in her hand; (producing an instrument to mark vessels with) I went softly down stairs, she did not hear me till I got down; she was trying to break the till open with it; the company paid their reckoning, then Salmon went into the kitchen; after that Salmon and I went up stairs; he looked through the ballusters, and I looked out of the window to the street; we heard her go to the till, and rattle down some halfpence; I heard the till fall to the ground; she staid till morning almost; we wondered she did not come to bed; we told master of it next day, and he turned her away directly.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-62-person672">
                  William 
                  Salmon 
               <interp inst="t17661217-62-person672" type="surname" value="Salmon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person672" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person672" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was a servant to Mr. Fox on the 3d of October; after master and mistress were gone to bed, at about eleven, the maid and the boy and I were up; there was company up stairs; after they had paid their recconing and were gone, I went to go to bed, and left the prisoner below stairs, that was about one o'clock; the boy told me, he saw the prisoner trying to open the till; I not hearing her come up, I leaned over the ballusters; I saw her go into the bar, and presently heard the till creak, and in about a minuet the till fell down; it made a great noise of halfpence falling about.</p>
               <p>Q. How high is the till from the ground?</p>
               <p>Salmon. It was about breast high.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you see her when she was in the bar?</p>
               <p>Salmon. No, I could not; there was then no foul below stairs but herself; presently we saw her come out of the bar, she went down into the cellar, and brought some beer up in a mug; then she opened the door, and after that came to the door again; then she went into the kitchen, and took some bread and butter, and went to the door.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>Salmon. This was about half an hour after one;</p>
               <p>Q. Is that the usual time of the maid's being up?</p>
               <p>Salmon. No, it is not; I never knew her to be up after twelve; after she came from the door, she went to the bar again; this was her third time of going to the bar; we listened a little, and heard no more, and then we went to bed; then the watchman was going two; the boy and I came down first in the morning.</p>
               <p>Q. When the till fell, why did you not go down stairs?</p>
               <p>Salmon. I said to the boy I'll go down; the boy said no, do not, she will say it is you; in the morning we found the till about half way open; my master came down in about ten minutes after us, the lock was almost wrenched off; I told my master of what had passed; he taxed her as soon as she came down; she said she did not know what he meant; I found some halfpence in a drain in<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176612170054"></xptr> the back room in the yard, and some on the ledge among some feathers, about a fortnight after this.</p>
               <p>Q. How much money did you find?</p>
               <p>Salmon. There was about two or three and twenty-pence of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did your master get a warrant for her?</p>
               <p>Salmon. He did, I went with him to get it; I think it was on the 13th of October; ( produced, dated the 12th of October) this is it; it was delivered to the constable; the constable came to our house several times after; I heard my master desire him to seek for her; he said he could not find her.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Had not the prisoner and you often quarrelled?</p>
               <p>Salmon. No, not often.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you not a quarrel with her that night?</p>
               <p>Salmon. I did not pass two words with her that night; she wanted to know what was her share; I said I should not give it her then, having no change; this was in the kitchen; I saw she wanted to quarrel, and I made no words with her, so I and the boy went up to bed together.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you not know whether Mrs. Fox has had any suspicion of this boy?</p>
               <p>Salmon. She has missed halfpence sometimes I believe, but I was but new come then.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of any silver being missing?</p>
               <p>Salmon. There was a six-pence lost I believe, from off the shelf.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know who took it?</p>
               <p>Salmon. I cannot tell who did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not upon some occasion search the boy's pockets for a six-pence that he had taken?</p>
               <p>Salmon. Yes, I did.</p>
               <p>Q. What time does your water come in?</p>
               <p>Salmon. That comes in on Mondays, Wednesdays, and Fridays.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not this on a Friday night that you talk of, that your water should have come in?</p>
               <p>Salmon. It was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she not save some water that night?</p>
               <p>Salmon. I don't know that she did; there was not always water saved on Fridays.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the prisoner discharged?</p>
               <p>Salmon. On the Saturday morning.</p>
               <p>Q. When did she come to your house again?</p>
               <p>Salmon. She came again that morning, for some cloaths to put on.</p>
               <p>Q. When did she come the next time?</p>
               <p>Salmon. That was the week following, then she took one box away; I believe that was on the Monday or Tuesday.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she come after that?</p>
               <p>Salmon. She did one night, about nine or ten o'clock, I believe that was the same week; she wanted her other box; master said she might come again in the morning.</p>
               <p>Q Did she come again after that?</p>
               <p>Salmon. No, she never came again at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the warrant taken out when she was at your house?</p>
               <p>Salmon. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any talk when she came, of charging a constable with her?</p>
               <p>Salmon. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was she taken?</p>
               <p>Salmon. She was taken in our tap-room on a Saturday night; she came in with another woman; the other woman called for a pint of beer.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear her say she came to surrender?</p>
               <p>Salmon. No, I heard it said she was come to surrender to the warrant.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-62-person673">
                  William 
                  Goodall 
               <interp inst="t17661217-62-person673" type="surname" value="Goodall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person673" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person673" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watchman, I stand at Mr. Fox's door; that night the maid came to the door about one o'clock the first time; she came a second time a little before two; she asked my wife for some snuff.</p>
               <p>Q. Has she ever come to you when you have been upon your watch before?</p>
               <p>Goodall. She has; she complained of her fellow-servant, that he would not let her have what money was her due, and said, she would tell her master the next day; I believe she went away the next morning.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you known her sit up to save water?</p>
               <p>Goodall. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. How late have you known company stay at that house?</p>
               <p>Goodall. I have known company to stay till two in the morning, or after, sometimes.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-62-person674">
                  Thomas 
                  Fox 
               <interp inst="t17661217-62-person674" type="surname" value="Fox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person674" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person674" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Hercules Pillars: on the 3d of October I went to bed about half an hour after eleven; I always order that the maid should go to bed at eleven, sometimes to stay a little longer up on a Saturday night; but there was nothing to cause her to stay up longer than usual on the 3d of October; after I was gone to bed, I heard some company go down; after that I went to sleep, and afterwards I heard a noise; in the morning, when I came down, my man came to me, and said, Sir, we have had thieves in the house, Nanny has broke the till in the bar; he said the boy and he watched her; I said, why did you not come and call me, I don't recollect his answer; he said, when they got into the room,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176612170055"></xptr> the boy said, he went down stairs, and saw Nanny trying to open the till with the instrument we mark casks with; then he went, and from the ballusters of the two pair of stairs he sooped down, and saw her come out of the bar; there was a few halfpence and farthings in the till, which was open; part of the wood was wrenched.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it in that condition when you had seen it before?</p>
               <p>Fox. No, it was not; the maid came down a little before eight; I followed her into the kitchen, and desired her to give me the money she had taken; she said she did not know what meant; then I desired her to go about her business; she went away; she came again the same day for some of her things; and the after, on either Monday or Tuesday she came again; after that some of the neighbours talked to me a good deal for turning her away, and not prosecuting her, saying, it might bring me into a good deal of trouble; I took out a warrant on the 12th of October; this is it here produced; I sent it up to Mr. M'Ginnis, a constable; he not being at home, came to me; then I desired him to make it his business to and the prisoner; I heard she lodged at a hatter's, in Leather-lane; about three weeks after this, I was served with a copy of a writ, the copy dated the third of November (produced in court) I was served with it the same day. On the Monday or Tues day, when she came for her things, she went backwards in which room there is a drain which she used to clean: she staid there some time, and that day fortnight as she went away, I sent a man to clean that drain; I went with a candle, there I saw some halfpence; I took them up; there were 19 l d. among the dirt, and 61/2 d. lay by the side of the drain.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How often might she have been at your house after you turned her away?</p>
               <p>Fox. I believe three or four times.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever any talk with her at any of these times about charging the constable with her?</p>
               <p>Fox. No, I had not.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was she taken up?</p>
               <p>Fox. She was taken up in my house.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you heard of her coming before she did come?</p>
               <p>Fox. I heard she was to come on the Thursday; I was told that was to indict me, if I did not take hold of her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she not tell you she was come to surrender to the warrant?</p>
               <p>Fox. No, she did not; I gave the constable charge of her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-62-person675">
                  Terence
               <interp inst="t17661217-62-person675" type="given" value="Terence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person675" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             M'Ginnis. I am a constable; this warrant here produced. Mr. Fox gave to me on the 13th of October; he told me it was to take up his servant maid, 
               <persName id="t17661217-62-person676">
                  Anne 
                  Willis 
               <interp inst="t17661217-62-person676" type="surname" value="Willis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person676" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person676" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , for breaking his till, and taking some money: he told me to enquire at a hatter's in Leather-lane, there he said I should find her. On a Saturday night she came to Mr. Fox's; he sent for me, and I went and took her; Mr. Fox has called upon me, and begged I would look out for her, and take her.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q Did she make any attempt to escape?</p>
               <p>M'Ginnis. No, she did not; she behaved modest and agreeable.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I never wronged my masters of a farthing in no place wherever I lived. This Friday night I sat up while two o'clock almost to save water, which we usually do; as to the ti: I never touched it, or was near it; as to the halfpence, I know no more of them than the child unborn; when I came down stairs, my master was there and the boy; I came into the kitchen, in order to go about my work; there was a woman came to scour the pots in the morning; I said to her, have you had your dram; I went to the bar for the bottle of gin; master came and said, Nanny, What do you want there; I said, I am going to give the woman a dram; master said, serve her Jack (meaning the boy) I set the bottle down on the floor, and came into the kitchen; I thought that was very odd; in about a quarter of an hour after, master came into the kitchen, then the woman went out; master said, Nanny, if you please, give me the halfpence you took out of the bar last night; I said I never touched any; he said, the till then; there are two people saw you; I said, Sir, you are joking; I thought this boy who had pilfered and robbed him several times, I thought he spoke of him; he stood peeping in the kitchen. When mistress came down, she began upon me much the same, and bid me go and fetch the halfpence, and said, there were people that could swear it; she desired me to go up and fetch them; I said I would not go up without she would go up with me; master and she went up with me; I pulled my drawers out, and opened my boxes; I opened my least box, but could not find the key of my large one; I desired them to break it open; he desired I would go and get a key, in order to open it; I went to Mr. Pitt's, but could get none; I came back again; master and mistress were still in the room, and in taking some caps out of a small drawer, I found my key underneath them; then I opened the large box, and there was only<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176612170056"></xptr> a black petticoat in it; mistress said, Hussey, you have stole these halfpence, and have conveyed them away, you are a thief. I said, Madam, I shall make you prove your words, if you say any such thing; she said she could do it; master said, let her go about her business; I said, what, without my cloaths and wages; I went away, and came back in about an hour, having only my old cloaths on; when I went in, mistress came to me, and called me names, and said I had better own it, I was heard to do it; Mr. Fox said, with an oath, do not say heard, she was seen to do it; I desired she would not call me thief; she said, if you speak so, I'll send for a constable; after some time, she bid me go about my business; I went away, and on the Saturday night I went again, and demanded my little box, and on the Monday I was hired to a place; the gentleman went for my character, and they gave me the character, that I was a great thief and a drunkard, as ever came into a house; the same day, in the evening, I went to the house again, and Mr. Candy along with me; he went into the tap-room, and called for something to drink; I went to the bar, in order to ask for my cloaths and wages. Master told me, I should have nothing there that night, and bid me get out of the house, or he would kick me out, or to that purpose; I went to Mr. Candy in the tap-room, and sat about half an hour, then we went away; I went again, October the 8th, and asked after my large box, which was up three pair of stairs when I left it; that I desired Mr. Salmon to fetch down into the dining-room, and said, I would send for it in about an hour; he did; I went up into the room to him: Mrs. Fox came up to me, and asked me how I came to send for my character; I told her, I had a just right to send for it, and a character I would insist upon from her; she said, you are a thief; I said, do not call me thief; you have thieves among yourselves, and want to lay it to me; she said she would send for a constable; I said, I wish you would, rather than let me lie under this scandal; she bid me go about my business; I said, I would not go without my wages; she said, you have paid yourself, I think. Master said, let her come down to me, and I'll talk to her about wages; I went down stairs to him; he said, what wages is due to you, Madam; I said, you know; he said, get about your business, for you shall not have cloaths or wages here; then I said I must get it by force; I did not know where to go. I went to Sir 
               <persName id="t17661217-62-person677">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17661217-62-person677" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person677" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person677" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , to ask his advice; I told the story to his clerk; the clerk said, if I was accused falsely, I must take an action out; I asked him where I must get the action; he told me I must go to some attorney; I went to an attorney, and had an action out against him; but before I took this action, I hired myself to another place. Mr. Fox gave this answer to the person that went for my character, that he had no character with me, nor none he would give me. I found I was entirely destitute of getting my bread, then I took the clerk's advice, and took out the action against Mr. Fox; some time after this, I heard he had a warrant against me; and I went on the Saturday night, in order to be taken up, if he had a warrant against me.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-62-person678">
                  Mary 
                  Helibourn 
               <interp inst="t17661217-62-person678" type="surname" value="Helibourn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person678" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person678" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went with the prisoner to Mr. Fox's; she was informed there was a warrant against her, and she went to see if it was so: we had a pint of beer; Mr. Fox came in about ten minutes; he said to a person there, take care of 
               <persName id="t17661217-62-person679">
                  Anne 
                  Willis 
               <interp inst="t17661217-62-person679" type="surname" value="Willis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person679" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person679" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , she is a thief, fetch a constable; somebody went, and a constable came; the constable said he thought it was better to make it up; 
               <persName id="t17661217-62-person680">
                  Anne 
                  Willis 
               <interp inst="t17661217-62-person680" type="surname" value="Willis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person680" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person680" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said, I have nothing to make up; if Mr. Fox wanted me here I am.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-62-person681">
                  Thomas 
                  Mason 
               <interp inst="t17661217-62-person681" type="surname" value="Mason"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person681" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person681" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When I lay with the boy 
               <persName id="t17661217-62-person682">
                  John 
                  Fox 
               <interp inst="t17661217-62-person682" type="surname" value="Fox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person682" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person682" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he picked my pocket of half a crown.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you live then?</p>
               <p>Mason. I lived then with Mr. Fox the prosecutor.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you live with Mr. Fox?</p>
               <p>Mason. I lived with him two years and three quarters.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell any body about this half crown?</p>
               <p>Mason. Yes, I told Mr. and Mrs. Fox of it; Mrs. Fox said she would chastize him, but his uncle should not know of it.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Mason. I live at a public-house in Shire-lane.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is it ago since you lived at Mr. Fox's?</p>
               <p>Mason. It is about a year and a half ago.</p>
               <p>Q. How long before you left Mr. Fox that he took this half crown?</p>
               <p>Mason. It was about a year and a half before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-62-person683">
                  William 
                  Swain 
               <interp inst="t17661217-62-person683" type="surname" value="Swain"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person683" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person683" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lived at Mr. Fox's; I have known the boy 
               <persName id="t17661217-62-person684">
                  John 
                  Fox 
               <interp inst="t17661217-62-person684" type="surname" value="Fox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person684" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person684" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             about half a year.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Swain. He was accounted a very pilfering lad.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you left Mr. Fox's service?</p>
               <p>Swain. I left it about four months ago.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176612170057"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-62-person685">
                  Joseph 
                  Eakin 
               <interp inst="t17661217-62-person685" type="surname" value="Eakin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person685" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person685" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a hat-maker, and live in Leather-lane; I have known 
               <persName id="t17661217-62-person686">
                  Anne 
                  Willis 
               <interp inst="t17661217-62-person686" type="surname" value="Willis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person686" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person686" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             eight or nine years; she was servant to me almost two years, six years ago, and better; she is as honest and good a servant as ever came into a house; I have trusted her with untold gold; she would neither wrong me, nor see me wronged; I would sooner take take her for a servant than any body I know.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not go to Mr. Fox's to enquire her character?</p>
               <p>Eakin. I did; my partner had hired her as a servant, so I had a just right to go and enquire her character.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not she at your house after she left Mr. Fox's?</p>
               <p>Eakin. She was sometimes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she not lie in your house?</p>
               <p>Eakin. She has laid at my house.</p>
               <p>Q. For how long together?</p>
               <p>Eakin. A week or a fortnight at a time.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Helibourn. She has laid at my house some nights since she came from Mr. Fox's: I live in Fox-court.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-62-person687">
                  Walter 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17661217-62-person687" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person687" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person687" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Queen's-head tavern in Great Queen-street; the prisoner lived with me three different times; it is about fourteen months since she left me the last time; she had the care of my house for five years together, and behaved very justly; I would take her directly if she was at liberty.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-62-person688">
                  Sarah 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17661217-62-person688" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person688" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person688" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am second wife to the last witness; I have known the prisoner four years and a half; she lived with me two years and a half; she was trusted with every thing in the hous e, and I would trust her again; she behaved very just and honest.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-62-person689">
                  Margaret 
                  Tod 
               <interp inst="t17661217-62-person689" type="surname" value="Tod"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person689" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person689" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Griffin in Holbourn; the prisoner lived with me six months after she went from Mr. Williams's; I never had the least reason to suspect her honesty; I would trust her again with all my heart, as soon as any body I ever had.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-62-person690">
                  Mary 
                  Dickerson 
               <interp inst="t17661217-62-person690" type="surname" value="Dickerson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person690" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person690" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her six years; she lived with me six months, six years ago; she was a good servant, and bears an honest character.</p>
               <p>To 
               <persName id="t17661217-62-person691">
                  John 
                  Fox 
               <interp inst="t17661217-62-person691" type="surname" value="Fox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person691" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person691" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-62-person692">
                  Godard 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17661217-62-person692" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person692" type="given" value="Godard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person692" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a housekeeper, and live in Queen-street; I frequent Mr. Fox's house; I never heard any thing of the boy 
               <persName id="t17661217-62-person693">
                  John 
                  Fox 
               <interp inst="t17661217-62-person693" type="surname" value="Fox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person693" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person693" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's dishonesty in my life.</p>
               <p>Mr. Sturney. I live in Great Queen-street; I have known 
               <persName id="t17661217-62-person694">
                  John 
                  Fox 
               <interp inst="t17661217-62-person694" type="surname" value="Fox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person694" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-person694" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ever since he lived at his uncle's; he has a very good character; I heard of the half crown talked of by two boys; I thought it was only a thing between boy and boy; I never heard he was a pilfering boy, only of that half crown.</p>
               <p>Q Did you hear the evidence given here about it?</p>
               <p>Sturney. I did.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17661217-62-verdict325" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-62-verdict325" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
