<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670715-24">
               <interp inst="t17670715-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670715-24" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670715-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670715"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670715-24" type="date" value="17670715"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670715-24-off142-c194" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-24-defend244 t17670715-24-off142 t17670715-24-verdict147"></join>
         
               <p>363. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17670715-24-defend244" type="defendantName">
                     Andrew 
                     Hallgeel 
                  <interp inst="t17670715-24-defend244" type="surname" value="Hallgeel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-24-defend244" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-24-defend244" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for the <rs id="t17670715-24-off142" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670715-24-off142" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-24-off142" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               wilful murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17670715-24-victim246" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Cartwright 
                        <interp inst="t17670715-24-victim246" type="surname" value="Cartwright"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670715-24-victim246" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670715-24-victim246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-24-off142 t17670715-24-victim246"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  ; he stood charged on the coroner's inquest for the said murder
            </rs>, <rs id="t17670715-24-cd143" type="crimeDate">June 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-24-off142 t17670715-24-cd143"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670715-24-person247">
                  Patrick 
                  Dermot 
               <interp inst="t17670715-24-person247" type="surname" value="Dermot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-24-person247" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-24-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about seven or eight weeks before this affair happened, he is a <rs id="t17670715-24-deflabel144" type="occupation">seafaring man</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-24-defend244 t17670715-24-deflabel144"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the deceased Mr. Cartwright?</p>
               <p>Dermot. I did, he lived at <placeName id="t17670715-24-crimeloc145">Bromley</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17670715-24-crimeloc145" type="placeName" value="Bromley"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17670715-24-crimeloc145" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-24-off142 t17670715-24-crimeloc145"></join>, he was a <rs id="t17670715-24-viclabel146" type="occupation">school-master</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-24-victim246 t17670715-24-viclabel146"></join>; the prisoner's wife lived with Mr. Cartwright as a housekeeper, for about twelve months.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had the prisoner been absent?</p>
               <p>Dermot. I understood he had been absent above a year; I was often in company with the prisoner. On Sunday the 7th of June, in the afternoon, about three or four o'clock, I am not certain to the hour, Mr. Cartwright sent for me; I went to his house.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176707150018"></xptr>Dermot. I live in Bow; the prisoner went into his house along with me; (I believe he was most commonly at Mr. Cartwright's house since he came home from sea, his wife being there) there was another person went in with us; Mr. Cartwright being in the parlour, he whispered me, that the prisoner's wife might escape; he said, there was some terrible affair at stake, and he was afraid he would commit murder, and begged of me to take him away with me, while she made her escape out of the house; I did so, I took him out to the White Horse; he staid there with me about six or seven minutes, and went out from me with a walking-stick in his hand; after he had been absent about twelve or fifteen minutes, he came back without the stick, and had a naked hanger in his left bosom, I saw the handle of it; this hanger I had seen hanging naked in Mr. Cartwright's parlour; when I took the prisoner out with me, the prisoner told me he had done for them both; as soon as he came to the door, he said they both lay dead on the floor, and desired me to go and see; I went immediately to Mr. Cartwright's house, which was about 2 or 300 yards distant.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner go with you?</p>
               <p>Dermot. No, he did not; I saw the prisoner's wife in the kitchen, she appeared very low; there was a very great effusion of blood that lay by her; the back of her gown was cut in several places, where I believe he had struck her; her wound was upon her thigh, I did not see that; I could see no wound about her face; I enquired where Mr. Cartwright was; I went up stairs, and found him in a chair at his study-door, leaning on his left side.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he for health before?</p>
               <p>Dermot. He was as hearty and well as ever I saw him, when I took the prisoner away to the White Horse; I found he was wounded very deep on his right elbow, there was a large effusion of blood by him; I asked him how he came by that wound; he told me Mr. Hallgeel had murdered him; this was the 7th, and he died on the 21st; I sent for a coach, and sent him to the hospital; he seemed very faint.</p>
               <p>Q. What was his age?</p>
               <p>Dermot. I believe he might be about sixty years of age; he was a very hale stout man of his age.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the age of the prisoner's wife?</p>
               <p>Dermot. I do not know, she may be about forty, or seven and eight-and-thirty.</p>
               <p>Q. Is she a comely woman?</p>
               <p>Dermot. She is a good motherly-looking woman, she is fat.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see his wound?</p>
               <p>Dermot. I did, we pulled his morning-gown off and saw it; his shirt was cut through; the wound was just in the joint of the right arm, and his left shoulder was dislocated; I saw him two days after in the hospital; I saw him frequently till he died; I saw Surgeon 
               <persName id="t17670715-24-person248">
                  Grindal
               <interp inst="t17670715-24-person248" type="given" value="Grindal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-24-person248" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he told me the wound was mortal, and would be the death of him; the deceased considered himself as a dying man, and told me his time was but short, and declared upon the word of a dying man, that what he was accused of concerning the woman was false. The prisoner was taken the next Sunday morning; I saw him in custody in the watch-house at Bromley, nothing material passed.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any thing of jealousy in the way?</p>
               <p>Dermot. There were hints thrown out to that purport; about six days before, the prisoner and I were going from London to Bow; he fell down on the road, and hurt his face and his knuckles on his right hand; I took him in at the Black Swan alehouse at Bow to wash him; words passed between the landlady and him; he called her b - h; what she said I did not rightly hear, but she told me afterwards, that she bid him go home to the b - h his wife that cuckolded him; the prisoner told me the same thing when we were got out of the house; the landlady said to me, why do you bring such a person here; the prisoner told me, she bid him go home to Cartwright's whore, you cuckold; when he got home to Cartwright's house, he began with his wife the same evening, and Mr. Cartwright was afraid he would kill his wife.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Cartwright a married or a single man?</p>
               <p>Dermot. He was a single man.</p>
               <p>Q. In what capacity did the prisoner's wife live with the deceased?</p>
               <p>Dermot. In the capacity of a housekeeper.</p>
               <p>Q. How many servants did he keep?</p>
               <p>Dermot. He kept a servant girl and a boy; she had the command of the other servants.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of any intimacy between the deceased and the prisoner's wife?</p>
               <p>Dermot. Upon my word I know of none, nor never suspected none.</p>
               <p>Q. Has it not made much noise in the neighbourhood?</p>
               <p>Dermot. I do not know that it has.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176707150019"></xptr>Q. How far does that woman live from Mr. Cartwright's, with whom the prisoner had these words?</p>
               <p>Dermot. About 3 or 400 yards.</p>
               <p>Q. Whereabouts was the prisoner's wife's gown cut?</p>
               <p>Dermot. It was about the back and hip above the stays; I saw no cut below, except the hole in her petticoat, where some sharp instrument had penetrated, that was in the hind part; I saw none in the fore part of her petticoat. I understood by the surgeon that dressed her, the wound was in her groin, rather behind.</p>
               <p>Q. Had Mr. Cartwright any instrument in his hand when you saw him?</p>
               <p>Dermot. He had a sword in his wounded hand, with the scabbard on it; I found the stick which the prisoner had in his hand when he went from me in the dining-room, splintered and broke; when I went up stairs, Mr. Cartwright held out the sword, and said, I'll kill you before I die, you have murdered me, thinking I had been the prisoner coming again; that sword he had in his hand I have frequently seen hanging in his study.</p>
               <p>Q. Is there not a bed-room by the dining-room?</p>
               <p>Dermot. There is a little bed-chamber at one end of it; I believe the woman locked herself in it, because there were three or four places where he had attempted to run the sword through; it opens into the dining-room.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know whether Mr. Cartwright and she were both locked in that room together?</p>
               <p>Dermot. I do not know that they were; the bed was turned up then.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the deceased ever tell you how the fray began?</p>
               <p>Dermot. He told me he was going up stairs, to hurry the woman out of the house, and taking advantage of the prisoner's absence, they were talking together about a little family account, and he had hold of the knob of the lock, the door was not quite shut, when the prisoner came and beat him with the stick, and broke it about him, and then he ran down for the hanger; he told me this several times without variation; (the hanger, broken stick, and long sword produced in court.)</p>
               <p>Q. Have you often seen the prisoner at Mr. Cartwright's house?</p>
               <p>Dermot. I have seen him eat and drink there several times.</p>
               <p>Q. How did they seem to behave together?</p>
               <p>Dermot. They seemed to behave and agree very friendly; I believe the prisoner was very unhappy in his temper to his wife after that affair at the Black Swan; before, the prisoner and deceased were as friendly as any two brothers could be.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670715-24-person249">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Golding 
               <interp inst="t17670715-24-person249" type="surname" value="Golding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-24-person249" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-24-person249" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was servant to Mr. Cartwright, I lived there eight months before his death; the prisoner's wife was housekeeper there when I came; the prisoner frequently dined and breakfasted there, and lay with his wife every night for six weeks before my master's death; he and my master behaved and agreed very well together.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the first time you discovered the prisoner showing any ill-will?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. That was on Whitsunday morning; he had used to quarrel with his wife before, but I did not know what it was about; the first time that I had observed it, was about a week before that; he was one of the best tempered men in the world.</p>
               <p>Q. What happened on Whitsunday?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. Then he got up about seven in the morning, and packed up his clothes, and our boy helped to carry them to London; he was then going to his own apartment in London; he returned again about one or two o'clock in the afternoon, I had just sent up dinner as he knocked at the door; I said you are just come in time; he walked up stairs to the fore parlour, the dining-room is up another pair of stairs; there was my master and the prisoner's wife; I went to the parlour to take the things away.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner dine there?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. I believe he did; the plates were foul when I fetched them away; he was a little in liquor, he was quarrelling with his wife; all I heard him say, she had pawned his clothes, and pawned his plate since he was gone; my master made answer and said, Poh, poh, poh, what have I to do between a man and his wife quarreling, what signifies making a noise; then the prisoner went with a design to take a walk out; our boy, to the best of my knowledge, was sent to Mr. Dermot; he came; this was about an hour after dinner; when he came, I was not up in the parlour at all; very soon after he came, he and the prisoner went out together; I saw them go out at the fore door as I stood in the kitchen.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after this was it that you saw the prisoner again?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. It might be about a quarter of an hour; when he came back again, I was standing leaning against the back door; the prisoner came in at that door, he had only a stick in his hand; he said to me, where is the whore my wife; I said, she is gone to London.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176707150020"></xptr>Q. Was she gone to London?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. No, she was not.</p>
               <p>Q Why then did you say so?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. I said so by her order; she had ordered me, in case he came back, to give that answer, when she was in the back kitchen.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was your master at that time?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. He was up stairs. Then he asked where my my master was; I said I would go and call him; I went up the kitchen stairs, and called Sir, several times, there was no answer; the kitchen is under ground, the kitchen stairs come into the hall and the parlour.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you think your master was?</p>
               <p>E Golding. I thought to have found him in the fore parlour.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did the prisoner stay when you went up the kitchen stairs?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. He stood in the back kitchen till I came down again</p>
               <p>Q. Did you open the parlour door?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. No, the door was open, there was no body there; I came down and told him, I could not make my master answer; the prisoner made no answer; I immediately went out at the back gate, to see if the boy was coming with the beer; I staid not above five or six minutes at the gate; when I came back again, the prisoner was beating my mistress down the kitchen stairs; he had a hanger, I saw no stick; she was all cut across her stays and gown.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any blood?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. No, I did not then; then he beat her in the kitchen with the hanger; I saw him give her a prick behind; he did it with a push with his hand, right forward; presently I saw blood; as soon as I saw him beating her down stairs, I sent for Mr. Dermot; I staid in the kitchen, and gave her a little water to drink; the prisoner went out at the back door; soon after that, I heard my master stamping about, up one pair of stairs, that is above the kitchen where the study is; I did not go up till Mr. Dermot came.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was your mistress after dinner?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. She was in the dining-room; she said, in case her husband came, she desired to be denied, for he was in a very bad temper, and she told me she should go up-in the dining-room.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your master up into the dining-room with the prisoner's wife?</p>
               <p>E. Golding I cannot say he was; I know she was there, for she had called to me to bring her the chamber-pot, that was before the prisoner came back again; I carried one up to the dining-room, the door was locked when I went up; she opened the door, and took the chamber-pot of me; we have a little room in the dining-room, and there is a bed in it, it opens to the right-hand of the door; when she opened the door for me to deliver the chamber-pot, that little room door was shut; I carried it up from the back kitchen, and I believe the parlour-door was shut at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see your master at that time?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. That hanger which the prisoner had, where does that hang?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. That always hangs naked in the fore parlour, I saw it there that morning; after Mr. Dermot came, I saw the wound on my master's arm.</p>
         
               <p>*** The last Part of these Proceedings will be Published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17670715-24">
                  <interp inst="t17670715-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17670715-24" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17670715-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670715"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17670715-24" type="date" value="17670715"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176707150021"></xptr>THE WHOLE PROCEEDINGS ON THE KING's COMMISSIONS of the PEACE, OYER and TERMINER, and GOAL DELIVERY FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the GOAL DELIVERY FOR THE COUNTY of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 15th, Thursday the 16th, and Friday the 17th, of JULY.</p>
                  <p>In the Seventh Year of His MAJESTY's Reign. Being the Sixth SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of THE RIGHT HONOURABLE SIR 
                  <persName id="t17670715-24-person250">
                     ROBERT 
                     KITE 
                  <interp inst="t17670715-24-person250" type="surname" value="KITE"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670715-24-person250" type="given" value="ROBERT"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670715-24-person250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , KNT LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>NUMBER VI. PART II</p>
                  <p>LONDON,</p>
                  <p>Printed for J. WILKIE, at the Bible, in St. Paul's Church-Yard,</p>
                  <p>[Price Six-Pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176707150022"></xptr>THE WHOLE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Goal Delivery held for the City of LONDON, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Continuation of the Trial of 
               <persName id="t17670715-24-person251">
                  Andrew 
                  Hallgeel 
               <interp inst="t17670715-24-person251" type="surname" value="Hallgeel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-24-person251" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-24-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. HOW was the prisoner in general for temper?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. He was always a very good-tempered man before he went to the Black Swan.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you never told any body that your master and mistress were in a bed-chamber at that time?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. No, I never saw them in any bed-chamber together in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you never said they were both in that little room?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did she lie?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. She lay in the back-parlour.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did your master lie?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. He lay in a room even with the dining-room.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you lie?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. I lay under the stair-case.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never hear your master come down in a morning when you have been in bed?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. I have heard him come down at four or five in the morning, when she has been in bed, several times.</p>
               <p>Q. How often have you heard that?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. I have heard it three or four times; I used to think it was a thief, he used to come so softly; I used to think he had no shoes on; he came as if he intended to have nobody hear him; they could not move but I could hear them.</p>
               <p>Q. How long might he stay below?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. I believe he might stay an hour in my mistress's room; I have heard him go up again.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear any thing pass between them?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. They could not move nor stir in bed but I heard them.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever heard them in bed?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. I have heard them move in the bed together.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this before the prisoner came home, or when?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. It was before he came home from sea.</p>
               <p>Q. How often have you heard them move in the bed together?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. I am positive I have heard them three times, much in the same way; and I have heard him, after an hour or two, go up stairs again; and about seven o'clock she used to carry him up a bason of broth, and he used to come down about nine.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you call her when you spoke to her?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. I always called her madam, as my mistress.</p>
               <p>Q. When you called, Sir, Sir, was it loud enough for him to have heard you?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. It was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he in the parlour then?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. No, he was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he in the kitchen?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he in the yard?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. No, I heard the prisoner say he found them both in the dining-room together when he went up.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you see your master last, before the prisoner came in?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. That was in the fore-parlour, and she was up in the dining-room.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know when he went out of the parlour?</p>
               <p>E. Golding. No, I do not know, for I was washing up my things below.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any quarrel or dispute between your master and the prisoner?</p>

               <p>E. Golding. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670715-24-person252">
                  Thomas 
                  Saunders 
               <interp inst="t17670715-24-person252" type="surname" value="Saunders"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-24-person252" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-24-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a pupil under Mr. Grindal; I saw the deceased about seven in the evening, on Whitsunday, in the London-hospital; I found him with a wound in the joint on the right<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176707150023"></xptr> elbow, and his left shoulder was dislocated; the wound was cut across the elbow in the joint quite to the bone; a small blood-vessel or artery was cut; the wound seemed to be given by some edged weapon; there appeared to have been a good deal of blood lost; the man was very faint when he came in, the blood was not then stopt; I applied some lint to it, and that stopt it; there was a contusion about his shoulder by the blows, they appeared very black; I could not tell what they proceeded from; I attended him daily.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he die?</p>
               <p>Saunders. He died that day fortnight.</p>
               <p>Q. What in your opinion was the cause of his death?</p>
               <p>Saunders. A fever was the cause of his death, I believe.</p>
               <p>Q. What occasioned that fever?</p>
               <p>Saunders. Whether it was occasioned by the fever or otherwise, I cannot determine.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the wound and the injury you saw he had received the cause of his death?</p>
               <p>Saunders. Very possible they might occasion his death; I rather think they were the occasion of his death.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he say his shoulder became dislocated?</p>
               <p>Saunders. He told me it was by putting up his arm to defend himself, and he ran against the ballusters of the stairs with his left shoulder.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think the dislocation was the cause of his death?</p>
               <p>Saunders. I do not think that alone was; I do not think that alone brought on the fever.</p>
               <p>Q. When you was first called in, would you have thought that kind of wound a mortal wound,</p>
               <p>Saunders. No, I did not think it a mortal wound; that was my opinion then; Mr. Grindal saw him the day after he came in.</p>
               <p>Mr. Grindal. I saw the deceased the day after the accident happened, about twelve o'clock; the young gentleman has given you my opinion; I found the deceased in a high fever; I believe, if they had thought of the consequence that has attended it, they would have sent for me over night, (if they find any thing of great consequence they send for us immediately) I have seen many worse wounds than that that have done well; the young gentleman had put his arm in before I came. The second or third day after the fever increased very much, I called a friend of his on one side, to desire him if the deceased had any affairs to settle to get him so to do, thinking him in a dangerous condition.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon the whole of this wound and these bruises, were they the occasion of his death?</p>
               <p>Mr. Grindal. I cannot help thinking, but upon the whole his death was the consequence of the wound; his fever might proceed from his being so long neglected.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. When a fever proceeds from a wound, do you not call it a sympathetic fever?</p>
               <p>Mr. Grindal. We do; at first it was a sympathetic fever, no doubt, we could never by bleeding get it over. For the first two or three days, I thought he stood a chance to do well; but a fever much stronger and higher than that took him, and from that I told his friend I saw no hopes of his recovery.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>When I came to Mr. Dermot, before he and I went out, Mr. Cartwright called him in out of the fore-parlour into the back-parlour; then he came to me again, and told me he was going to take a walk to Ham and Plaistow; he said to me, I had better take a walk along with him, it will pass away time; accordingly I said with all my heart; we went out to take a walk; Mr. Dermot's maid was at the door, and said a gentleman wanted to speak with him; accordingly we went to Mr. Dermot's house, and then was told the gentleman was gone to the White-horse at Bow; we went to the White-horse, he asked who wanted him; they told him the person was in the parlour, we went in. Mr. Dermot asked him what he had to say; we sat down, he drank to Mr. Dermot, and Mr. Dermot drank to me, and I to the other gentleman; they fell into some discourse together; I said to Mr. Dermot, I find you are so deep in discourse you will hardly go to Plaistow to night, I want to go home; said he, I would not have you hinder yourself as you are in a hurry; I said, gentleman, your servant, and went out; and as a boy told me before, that he catched my wife and Mr. Cartwright together, if I had gone out to go to Ham, I should have turned back, though I had not mentioned it to any body. I came back again, the maid was looking out at the garden-gate; I said, Betty, where is my wife; she said she is gone to London; I walked in by her; she ran past me, and ran up stairs, and called Sir, Sir, five or six times, as loud as she could; I went into the back-kitchen and took the hanger, and carried it in one hand, and the stick in the other: as the maid was coming down stairs I went up; I first went into the fore-parlour, and then into the back-parlour; I opened his bed-chamber, and saw nobody<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176707150024"></xptr> there; then I opened the dining-room door very softly; then I came to the little room door, I found it fast, I got my shoulder against it with the hanger and stick in my hands; I burst it open, there Mr. Cartwright was in the action with my wife; he arose up, she could not cover her nakedness; he was going to get his breeches up, I fetched him a blow with the stick, he got his breeches buttoned, and went to take hold of his sword that lay upon a chair; I took the hanger and cut him in the arm, he ran out of the dining-room and I after him; my wife locked the door against me: I said, you whore, if you do not open the door I'll break it open; I fetched her a blow, and as I was going to give her another, she ran out at the door; there are two stair-cases, she ran down the other stairs, and I after her, and into the kitchen, I gave her half a dozen strokes across the stays; she came to clasp her arms round me; I said, you whore, do not go to take hold of me, and with the hanger as I held it, by her turning, pierced her thigh: then I went and told Mr. Dermot that I catched them both in the action, and paid them pretty well for it; I did not think to do any murder, as I went out with Mr. Dermot; she said to the maid get me some water, I am going up-stairs to shift myself, I am going to London; she heard Betty come up; she knocked at the wainscot, and said, madam, I want to speak with you; said my wife, Betty, can't I trust you with a secret, if my husband should come tell him I am gone to London, and do you bring up the chamber-pot.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670715-24-person253">
                  Thomas 
                  Hallgeel 
               <interp inst="t17670715-24-person253" type="surname" value="Hallgeel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-24-person253" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-24-person253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the prisoner's nephew, I have known him twenty-seven years; he was always, whenever I saw him, of a very peaceable temper, respected in all stations by every one that knew him; he was a boatswain of a man of war.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670715-24-person254">
                  Sarah 
                  Hallgeel 
               <interp inst="t17670715-24-person254" type="surname" value="Hallgeel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-24-person254" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-24-person254" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the other evidence, the prisoner always behaved very well, and was always very fond of his wife; they lived in great harmony together, he was very fond of her, never desired her to wash her own clothes, I never knew him to lift his hand against her in my life; I have known him 14 years.</p>
               <p>Eadey Launder. I have known him 26 years, he was always kind and tender to his wife, I never heard to the contrary; he is a very honest hard working man, quite a civil man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17670715-24-verdict147" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670715-24-verdict147" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-24-verdict147" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of Manslaughter
            </rs>. <rs id="t17670715-24-punish148" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670715-24-punish148" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-24-punish148" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-24-defend244 t17670715-24-punish148"></join>
               B
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>There was a detainer against him for assaulting his wife.</p>
            </div1>
