<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610916-56">
               <interp inst="t17610916-56" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-56" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-56" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610916"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-56" type="date" value="17610916"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610916-56-off294-c419" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-56-defend516 t17610916-56-off294 t17610916-56-verdict296"></join>
         
               <p>276. (M) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610916-56-defend516" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Wood 
                  <interp inst="t17610916-56-defend516" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-56-defend516" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-56-defend516" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17610916-56-deflabel293" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-56-defend516 t17610916-56-deflabel293"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17610916-56-off294" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-56-off294" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-56-off294" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch, value 40 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17610916-56-victim518" type="victimName">
                     Patrick 
                     Caffry 
                  <interp inst="t17610916-56-victim518" type="surname" value="Caffry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-56-victim518" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-56-victim518" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-56-off294 t17610916-56-victim518"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17610916-56-cd295" type="crimeDate">July 28</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-56-off294 t17610916-56-cd295"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-56-person519">
                  Patrick 
                  Caffry 
               <interp inst="t17610916-56-person519" type="surname" value="Caffry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-56-person519" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-56-person519" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 28th of July last, I met the prisoner at the bar in Covent-garden; I asked her where she was going, and told her I was going to the upper-end of Compton-Street, and if she would go along with me, she should drink with me. I did not apprehend she had any place of lodging material. She came with me, and we agreed to go together to a lodging, and went to bed together. I locked the door, and took the key out, and hid it towards the upper-end of the bed. I soon fell asleep, and awaked between two and three in the morning. Upon missing the prisoner, I called for a candle, looked for my breeches under my head (having put them there) but found them on the floor, at the feet of the bed. I asked in what manner the prisoner got out. The door was open, but the key was not in it. This was on Tuesday night, and on Wednesday I carried an advertisement; and on Friday the 31st, it was in the paper. I heard nothing of my watch till the 8th of August, when serjeant Hyde came to me, and told me he had it: and desired me to come to justice Welch's, and he would give me an account of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you look at your watch at going to bed?</p>
               <p>Caffry. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure it was in your pocket when you went to bed?</p>
               <p>Caffry. I am not sure.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-56-person520">
                  William 
                  Hyde 
               <interp inst="t17610916-56-person520" type="surname" value="Hyde"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-56-person520" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-56-person520" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was ordered by the commandant at the Tower to take one 
               <persName id="t17610916-56-person521">
                  William 
                  Pope 
               <interp inst="t17610916-56-person521" type="surname" value="Pope"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-56-person521" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-56-person521" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             before justice Welch, which I did. and the prisoner at the bar was there; and she swore Pope, a soldier, had robbed her of a watch, upon which he was committed. This was on a Thursday; and on the Friday one 
               <persName id="t17610916-56-person522">
                  William 
                  Heritage 
               <interp inst="t17610916-56-person522" type="surname" value="Heritage"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-56-person522" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-56-person522" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a soldier, belonging to the same company, brought me the key of Pope's cupboard, for me to send him a hat and a pair of shoes; and he would send his regimentals, because he would not appear in his regimentals there; and he told me the watch was in the upper part of Pope's cupboard. Then I asked the serjeant-major how I should proceed in it. He advised me to go to the commandant, and tell him I had got the key, and he would give me an order which way to proceed. I carried the key to the commandant, and told him the watch was in Pope's cupboard. Then I went and took it out of the cupboard. [Produced in court, and deposed to by the prosecutor.] Then I went and told the commandant I had found it. He ordered me to carry it to justice Welch's. The justice said, Such a watch as this has been lately advertised as lost, and sent me to Pell, a pawnbroker, who informed me where the maker lived, by which means I came to find out the owner.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>This gentleman came to me, I was just come out of the country, and asked me to go and drink with him. I told him I did not chuse to go. He got hold of me, and insisted upon my going to drink with him. I went to a tavern with him; he asked me a favour, which I did not chuse to grant. He told me he had no money, but he would leave his watch, pulled it out of his pocket, laid it down on the table, and desired me to take it up. I said I would not. He took it up, and put it in my hand, and desired me to keep it 'till he came to me, and brought me the money.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160064"></xptr>Q. to Prosecutor. Did you give her the watch?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No, I never did upon any account whatsoever.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610916-56-verdict296" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-56-verdict296" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
