<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17620917-31">
               <interp inst="t17620917-31" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620917-31" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620917-31" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17620917"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620917-31" type="date" value="17620917"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620917-31-off153-c141" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620917-31-defend197 t17620917-31-off153 t17620917-31-verdict155"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176209170011"></xptr>268. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17620917-31-defend197" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Tyrrell 
                  <interp inst="t17620917-31-defend197" type="surname" value="Tyrrell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-defend197" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-defend197" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17620917-31-off153" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-off153" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-off153" type="offenceSubcategory" value="perjury"></interp>
               wilful and corrupt perjury, on the trial of 
                     <persName id="t17620917-31-person198">
                        Jane 
                        Sibson 
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person198" type="surname" value="Sibson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620917-31-person198" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620917-31-person198" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , in May sessions, for the wilful murder of George her husband, at Longford in the county of Middlesex
            </rs>, <rs id="t17620917-31-cd154" type="crimeDate">May the 29th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620917-31-off153 t17620917-31-cd154"></join> ++ .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620917-31-person199">
                  Robert 
                  Want 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person199" type="surname" value="Want"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person199" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person199" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was present at the time Mrs. Sibson was tried, and concerned for her as solicitor. I remember 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person200">
                  John 
                  Tyrrell 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person200" type="surname" value="Tyrrell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person200" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person200" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             appearing as a witness in that prosecution.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember his being sworn?</p>
               <p>Want. I do; the words were in general the kind of evidence he should give to the court and the jury sworn, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Q. Give an account what was the evidence Mr. Tyrrell gave on that trial, as to the matter of this indictment.</p>
               <p>Want. Mr. Tyrrell, when he was called upon to give evidence, introduced it by giving an account that he attended the deceased Mr. 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person201">
                  George 
                  Sibson 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person201" type="surname" value="Sibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person201" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person201" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             as an apothecary; and he went on describing the case; and in the course of his examination, it was asked him, whether Mrs. Martin and Mrs. Sibson had never desired a physician; he said, no, they never did desire a physician; but he himself pressed it.</p>
               <p>Q. What were his words, as near as you can recollect?</p>
               <p>Want. He said, I myself pressed it often, and they were always averse to it; I think he added, he pressed it more than he had ever done in any case before, and they were always averse to it; I am confident this passed at the trial; he said, he even said more than as an apothecary he thought he ought to have done; but when he found them so averse to it, he desisted. He was asked, if they desired it, and he dissuaded them from it? He said, no; he never dissuaded them from it. In the course of the evidence, when they came to that part of it, which was on the Thursday before he died, when Dr. Lucas was sent for, he then said, when he saw him, he was so much altered, he then insisted upon a physician, and Dr. Lucas was sent for. Dr. Lucas was sent for that day, and his evidence struck me, so I well remember it. He was asked, whether upon opening the body at Long-ford, he did not say to young Mr. Howard, son to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person202">
                  Howard
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person202" type="given" value="Howard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person202" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the surgeon, Come and look at this inflammation, you young rogue. Nay, you shall go with us to the Old Bailey. He said, he never did say so; the examination then led to what passed before Sir John. Fielding; he was then asked touching a conversation before Sir 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person203">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person203" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person203" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person203" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . There was a good deal of matter intervening.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you before Sir 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person204">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person204" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person204" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person204" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Want. I was not; I only speak of what was said as to the question put to him what passed before Sir 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person205">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person205" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person205" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person205" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he was asked, whether he did not say there, that Dr. Lucas had told him he had not the least doubt, but that the deceased was poisoned; he was a long time before he gave any answer to that; variety of questions were put, and a long time it was before he gave a direct answer. He was asked by Serjeant Davy, whether Dr. Lucas did tell him so? He answered, - He did not recollect - He could not say - He did not believe - At last the serjeant asked him, Did Dr. Lucas tell you so? He said, No. Then the serjeant said, If he never did, you can certainly say so. Then he said, he was sure he never did.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you been acquainted with the prosecutrix?</p>
               <p>Want. I knew nothing of any of them, before I became employed for her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take any of this evidence in writing?</p>
               <p>Want. I took only two questions in writing; I did not know that I had took any, but upon looking over an old brief, I found I had taken one question; it was asked Mr. Tyrrell, whether it had not been requested to send for a physician; his answer was, never. And I took the question about calling to young Howard to come and look at the inflammation; I found I had taken those two on the back of the brief.</p>
               <p>Q. Then I may freely say, you had forgot you had taken it?</p>
               <p>Want. You may say so.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you be positive to every word that you have sworn now?</p>
               <p>Want. I'll tell you why I can: I examined all the witnesses myself, separately and apart, in order to prepare for that trial; one part of the defence which we strongly insisted upon was, the frequent and repeated application of Mrs. Sibson to have a physican, and his constant refusal. The other two questions about the inflammation were stated particularl y in the brief, and asked from the brief. And as the last question about Mr. Fielding, he was committed upon that.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the first question concerning having a physician?</p>
               <p>Want. It was, whether they did not desire a physician. He said, No, never.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there no question, nor no answer, passed between that question and answer?</p>
               <p>Want. No; his answer would have been inconsistent, had that been the case; he repeated it in the course of his evidence numbers of times, that he had frequently pressed it, and he always found them remarkably averse.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he at first admit he had said, You young rogue, &amp;c.?</p>
               <p>Want. He answered that immediately, and denied it.</p>
               <p>Q. With regard to Dr. Lucas, you say he was asked that question many times?</p>
               <p>Want. He was.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176209170012"></xptr>Q. In any answer, did he say he could not recollect?</p>
               <p>Want. He never gave a direct answer for a considerable time, even to that Mr. 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person206">
                  Baron 
                  Adams 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person206" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person206" type="given" value="Baron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person206" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said to Serjeant Davy, Brother, why do you press him? you see he will not give you an answer. Then the Serjeant shifted the question, and asked him if he never did tell you so? He then said, No. Then Serjeant Davy said, If he never did, then can you doubt it? Then he gave it the denial, and said, he was sure he did not say so; and, upon that answer, Mr. Groot and Mr. Pott were examined, and proved he did say so.</p>
               <p>Q. I do desire to know, whether at any time he did not say he could not recollect that at Justice Fielding's?</p>
               <p>Want. He never hesitated about that; I remember particularly he said, No, Dr. Lucas never did tell him so. Then Serjeant Davy said, Can you have a doubt whether you said so, or no? There were two witnesses appeared, that said, he did say so at Justice Fielding's.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620917-31-person207">
                  Jane 
                  Sibson 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person207" type="surname" value="Sibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person207" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person207" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the unhappy woman that was at that bar last May, tried for the murder of my husband.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember Mr. Tyrrell being a witness against you?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. When did your husband die?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. My husband had been in a long state of lingering illness before he died; he died on the 26th of April, on a Monday.</p>
               <p>Q. When was Mr. Tyrrell called in as an apothecary?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. I cannot recollect the day: My husband went to Windsor to him on horseback; and when he came back, he came in a chaise. He had been blooded, and came home with some medicines with him; the next day he visited my husband.</p>
               <p>Q. How long before your husband died?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. It was three weeks, or upwards, before he died.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say was the matter with your husband?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. I had not much talk with Mr. Tyrrell about his illness the first day; Mr. Tyrrell told me he had a violent fever; and my husband told me he had told Mr. Tyrrell he had a fever 14 or 15 days before. After he came from visiting my husband, I took him into the parlour, and asked him, whether there was any danger; and I begged, for God's sake, if there was, he would let me know, because I might have assistance in time?</p>
               <p>Q. What was his answer?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. He said at that time, Madam, I have attended him but a very little time; don't you think his fever is greatly abated? I said, Yes. Don't you think his cough is greatly abated? I said, Yes. He said, Madam, can you expect him to mend all at once? I have not attended him but two or three days. I often asked him if there was any danger, that I might send for a physician: He always said, there was no occasion.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you first ask him for a physician?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. I asked him several times: When he came again, I asked him. He said, Why, Madam, he is very low-spirited, and you indulge him too much; if he would but eat and drink, and I would but talk and laugh to him, instead of crying by him, he would be a great deal better.</p>

               <p>Q. When did you first mention to him to have a physician?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. I often begged he would let me know in time: He always told me there was no danger, none in the world.</p>
               <p>Q. What were the words you made use of?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. I begged he would let me know, that I might have assistance; he knew my meaning.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he ever propose it to you?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. No, never to me, nor to any-body in my hearing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you mention the word physician?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. No; but Mr. Tyrrell understood it, or he would not have talked and argued with me in that manner as he did. His answers were, There was no danger; and that if he would but eat and drink, and be merry, he would grow better: And on the Monday before he died, he thought him so much better, that he said he should not come any more, but begged to see him at Windsor before the Thursday following; and if he did not, he should imagine he was worse, and he would come and see him. When I pressed it so much, he said, Madam, if you chuse it, for your own satisfaction, you may have one; but I don't think there is any danger, or necessity for it.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether Mr. Tyrrell, at any time in all your husband's illness before his death, ever advised the calling in of a physician?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. No, never; only he said, if I chose to have one for my own satisfaction, I might.</p>
               <p>Q. Did your husband go to Windsor before that Thursday he mentioned?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. No; he was not able to go. There was a gentleman came from Waltham the 22d of April, the Thursday before he died, to see him at Longford; he was in bed very ill. The gentleman was going to London that night and could not stay; Mr. Tyrrell had always advised him to ride out in the post-chaise. My husband said to the gentleman, As it will be a long walk for you, and I have been advised to take a ride every day in the chaise, I'll<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176209170013"></xptr> take you in the chaise, and carry you to Hounslow. I would have persuaded him not to go, he being very bad in bed; but he was very obstinate, and he was very fond of Mr. Tyrrell's advice, and he would go; and he, I, and the gentleman, went in the chaise together; and, instead of going as far as Hounslow, we went to Smallbury Green. We expected my husband's brother that afternoon from Windfor: I left word, unknown to my husband (for he would never consent to have a physician, being so advised by Mr. Tyrrell) with my mother, as I expected his brother, that, as soon as he came, he would go back to Windfor, and call a physician.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was it when you returned?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. I can't say; to the best of my remembrance it was about the dusk of the evening; when we came home, I found Mr. Tyrrell there.</p>
               <p>Q. Had Mr. Tyrrell ever visited him from the Monday till then?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. No, he had not: I did not know any physician at Windsor; I found my brother, who was there also, had consulted him concerning one.</p>
               <p>Q. When was Dr. Lucas called in?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. My mamma told me she had, according to my direction, desired my brother to go for a physician; and in a little time my brother returned, and said, Dr. Lucas was gone out, and he would be there on the Friday. He afterwards took me aside, and told me Dr. Lucas was not gone out, but was at home: That he had asked him about Mr. Sibson, and he told him he was gone out in a post-chaise: That the doctor said, I do not think there is any necessity for me to come to-night, as he is able to go out in a post-chaise; but I'll go to-morrow, then I can sit a little while with him, and shall be more able to know his case. He came the next morning; my husband then appeared to be excessively bad, as bad as any-body could be. Dr. Lucas did not like to tell me much, but shook his head, and did not give me much hopes; I found he said more to my mamma. I can't say I was satisfied with having one physician: There was a gentleman came over from America in a deep consumption; he had had Dr. Fothergill, and was a great deal better. I often desired my husband to have him; my husband said, What signifies having him, for I will not take any thing?</p>
               <p>Q. Did you send for Dr. Fothergill?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. I did. I sent my husband's brother for him to London: He returned, and told me the doctor could not attend, it was so far, or he was not well, I know not which, but recommended Dr. Hayes of Windsor. Upon that I sent for Dr. Hayes that same night, though it was very late. I begged my brother to go away to Windsor for him, and to bring Dr. Lucas along with him: They both came on the Saturday morning (my husband died the Monday following, about a quarter after two).</p>
               <p>Q. When was it you first heard yourself charged with the murder of your husband?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. As soon as ever I came home from London, on the Tuesday evening, about 6 or 7 o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. On what account did you go to London?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. My husband had made me executrix to his will; and I had a particular occasion to go to London to prove it; I went that very evening; I apprehended some obstruction, that is, a caveat to be thrown in; but I did not prove it till the next morning. I had not been five minutes in the house before they came down, and told me they suspected my husband was poisoned.</p>
               <p>Q. Who told you so?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. I don't know whether it was Mr. Sibson the brother, or Mr. Tyrrell; they said they had a suspicion the body was poisoned, and they would have it opened; they did not tell me of it at first, but only desired me to have the body opened. They asked me whether I would have the body opened? without expressing any suspicion why. The answer I made them was this; Mr. Bareblock and my mother said, they thought it would be cruel for me to have it opened (this was before my husband's death). I refused it.</p>
               <p>Q. On what account did they advise you not to have your husband's body opened?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. In my husband's life-time there was a talk between us, that whoever died first, my husband or I, the body should be opened, and the heart taken out, to be kept. Mr. Bareblock objected to it, and said, it would be cruel. It was upon that I refused it, and said, Mr. Bareblock and my mother had dissuaded me from it. Then the brother said, Here is a suspicion of poison: I am his brother, and you are his wife, and I insist upon having him opened.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Mr. Tyrrell there?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. I do not know whether Mr. Tyrrell was not walked out into the garden; he was backwards and forwards all the time.</p>
               <p>Q. What was done then, when your brother-in-law insisted upon it?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. It really startled me for some minutes; I knew not how to give him an answer; I said, Well, if you suspect any thing of that kind, I as much insist upon his being opened as you.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he opened?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. He was opened on the Friday.</p>
               <p>Q. How came the body not to be opened before the Friday?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. Because we wanted the physicians that attended him, to attend: After the Jury had sat, was cleared; they sat Friday and Saturday.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you been taken up before that?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. No, only the constables put in the house to watch me; then one of the jurymen came and took the constables out of the house. After that, word was sent down, that Sir 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person208">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person208" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person208" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person208" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             wanted to see me; that was on the Tuesday seven-night. I went up in a post-chaise. When I came<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176209170014"></xptr> there, Mr. Tyrrell was there all the time, to the best of my remembrance; I cannot recollect whether he did go out of the room once or twice.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you recollect any conversation there was between Mr. Tyrrell and Mr. Pitt about Dr. Lucas?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. I remember Mr. Pitt said to Sir 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person209">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person209" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person209" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person209" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he wished the physicians were there, they would put it beyond all doubt; Mr. Pitt said something else that I do not recollect. Mr. Tyrrell made answer to Sir 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person210">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person210" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person210" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person210" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Yes, that I believe he would, for Dr. Lucas had told him he had not the least doubt but that the man died of poison.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure he said so?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. I am; that was the only thing that struck me there. Mr. Fielding had some doubt at that time about committing me; and I was sent in and out, and I could not tell what he would do with me. A few minutes after that, he ordered me out, and I was out I believe half an hour; after that I was committed for murder.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you committed upon that?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. I do not know that I was committed upon that; I was sent to New Prison, and then brought to be re-examined on the Thursday.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Tyrrell attend at the re-examination?</p>
               <p>J. Sibson. He did; but whether at the first or second examination, I can't tell.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620917-31-person211">
                  Mary 
                  Martin 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person211" type="surname" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person211" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person211" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am mother to the last witness.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember your son in-law Mr. Sibson and daughter coming over to England?</p>
               <p>M. Martin. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you look upon your son-in-law then for health?</p>
               <p>M. Martin. I thought him but in a very indifferent state of health; he had a cold and a cough, which they told me was occasioned by the sea.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember his coming to live at Longford?</p>
               <p>M. Martin. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember Mr. Tyrrell's coming to him at Longford?</p>
               <p>M. Martin. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was Mr. Tyrrell at Longford before Mr. Sibson died?</p>
               <p>M. Martin. Mr. Sibson came first to my house on the 6th of April, and on the 8th he went to Windsor; and the next day Mr. Tyrrell came to my house; he attended him as an apothecary; that was the first time he attended him at Longford.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Sibson grow better or worse as to health?</p>
               <p>M. Martin. Mr. Tyrrell thought him better after he attended him a little while; but I can't say I thought so: I was very ill at that time myself; I had occasion to have Mr. Tyrrell in my room; I was ill in bed; and, after I had told him my own case, I asked him how Mr. Sibson did? He said, thought he was better.</p>
               <p>Q. What day was this?</p>
               <p>M. Martin. I really can't say. I then thought Mr. Sibson was very ill; I said to him, Mr. Tyrrell, pray what do you think of Mr. Sibson? (this was two or three days after he first came.) I said, I think Mr. Sibson is in a deep consumption; and, for my part, I think it necessary he should have a physician, for I think he will not live; then I gave him my reason. I said my husband was in the same way, and died in about a fortnight. He gave me this answer: The family were consumptive, and that his own brother was consumptive, and was called the walking ghost of Windsor for four years. He then gave me another proof in regard to a man that lived at Chelsea; this was to dissuade me from a physician.</p>
               <p>Q. I will not go through all Mr. Tyrrell's arguments. I ask you whether you and your daughter recommended it to Mr. Tyrrell to send for a physician?</p>
               <p>M. Martin. I recommended it at that time; and never did after, till the Thursday before Mr. Sibson died.</p>
               <p>Q. What were his answers?</p>
               <p>M. Martin. His answers were, We might have one, if we chose it, for our own satisfaction; but there was no occasion for one.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember your daughter leaving word with you, when she and Mr. Sibson went to Hounslow, for you to send for a physician?</p>
               <p>M. Martin. I do: My daughter left word with me on the Thursday to have a physician.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you ever present at any time when your daughter asked Mr. Tyrrell to have assistance?</p>
               <p>M. Martin. No, I was not, for I was very ill all the time.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether Mr. Tyrrell at any time recommended it to your daughter in your presence, or to you, the sending for a physician, or that you or your daughter opposed it?</p>
               <p>M. Martin. No, never.</p>
               <p>Q. First of all, to yourself: Whether he proposed sending for a physician, and you opposed it?</p>
               <p>M. Martin. No, he never proposed it to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Nor to your daughter, and she opposed it?</p>
               <p>M. Martin. No, not to my knowledge. My daughter and I consulted together, before she went out on the Thursday, to send for a physician, and, as soon as the brother came, I was to send him for one; which I did; so that a physician was sent for by my order: But I should tell you, that Mr. Tyrrell came to Longford that day before the brother, and I told Mr. Tyrrell he must stay till Mr. Sibson came home, for he was worse. The brother came presently afterwards; Mr. Tyrrell was in the garden; the brother went to him: I sent the maid out to fetch Mr. Sibson to me; he came into the kitchen to me: I said to him, Mr. Sibson, my daughter has left orders that you should go directly for a physician. He asked me which he should go for, as there were two?<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176209170015"></xptr> I said I did not know either, so he should go for which he thought best. He asked me if he should consult Mr. Tyrrell. I said he might do as he pleased: He went to Mr. Tyrrell, and Tyrrell gave orders for Dr. Lucas; I was present in the parlour, and heard it. I did not go immediately in with the brother; but I was there when that was agreed upon, and reached the pen and ink for Mr. Tyrrell to write the note.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the consultation about?</p>
               <p>M. Martin. It was about which physician to go for: He wrote the note to Dr. Lucas, and Dr. Lucas came on the Friday morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Had Mr. Tyrrell on that Thursday seen Mr. Sibson between that and the Monday?</p>
               <p>M. Martin. No, Dr. Lucas was sent for almost two hours before Mr. Sibson returned from Hounslow.</p>
               <p>Q. What said Dr. Lucas to Mr. Sibson's case, when he did come?</p>
               <p>M. Martin. He pronounced it a very desperate case?</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember any other physician being sent for?</p>
               <p>M. Martin. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you before Sir 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person212">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person212" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person212" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person212" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>M. Martin. I was taken out of bed in a high fever to go.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what passed there?</p>
               <p>M. Martin. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you deliver in an examination at Justice Fielding's?</p>
               <p>M. Martin. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Who wrote it?</p>
               <p>M. Martin. Mr. Richardson wrote it.</p>
               <p>Q. Where?</p>
               <p>M. Martin. At Mr. Bell's in Maiden Lane. I came to town on Tuesday, and was extremely ill then. I thought myself not able to go; and I was advised to lie in my bed, to recollect what I knew; so it was drawn up, and I signed and swore to it.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>M. Martin. I live at Mr. Mackoun's house; they came to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he not some of Mr. Sibson's effects in his hands?</p>
               <p>M. Martin. He has been a manager of my affairs, but not of her affairs.</p>
               <p>Council. You soon pronounced Mr. Sibson would die?</p>
               <p>M. Martin. I thought he would not live.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not say he would certainly die?</p>
               <p>M. Martin. I did think he would.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not your husband die of an apoplexy?</p>
               <p>M. Martin. No, h e did not, he died in a deep consumption; he rode from my house at Walthamstow but about a fortnight before he died; he had been ailing a long time; but he was able to go out three days before he died.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this letter [a letter is delivered into her hand]; is this your hand-writing?</p>
               <p>M. Martin. It is my hand-writing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620917-31-person213">
                  Ann 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person213" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person213" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person213" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant maid to Mrs. Martin, and was so from the time of Mr. Sibson's illness to the time of his death.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear your young mistress desire Mr. Tyrrell to call in a physician?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. I heard Mrs. Sibson, the Monday before he died, which was the 19th of April. She followed Mr. Tyrrell to the door, and asked how Mr. Sibson did: He said, Madam, I have been talking to him; he is very low spirited, and like vapoured; and if he would but have better spirits, and eat and drink, and take exercise, he would be better. He said, he had been advising him to come to Windsor, and hoped he should see him there before Thursday; if not, he would come over again. Mrs. Sibson said, Sir, if my husband is dangerous, I beg you will not flatter me, that I may have a physician, or assistance, I am not certain which word she used.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you understand it to mean?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. I understood it to mean a physician.</p>
               <p>Q. What answer did he give to that?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. He said, if he would eat and drink, and take exercise, he would be better; he did not think there was occasion for any farther advice, or a physician, or assistance, which of these three expressions it was, I cannot say, it was one of them; this was the Monday before he died.</p>
               <p>Q. What particular happened on the Thursday?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. On the Thursday Mr. and Mrs. Sibson went out towards Hounslow with another gentleman. Mr. Sibson was very ill; Mrs. Sibson thought of having a physician; she grew very uneasy, because he was so very ill.</p>
               <p>Q. Had Mr. Tyrrell been there then?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. No, he had not.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember any word left?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. Mrs. Sibson left word, that if the deceased's brother came from Windsor, to return again for a physician.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did she leave that word with?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. She left it with Mrs. Martin, my mistress.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Sibson the brother come?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. He did, but Mr. Tyrrell came first. Mrs. Sibson had left word, if Mr. Tyrrell came in the mean time, he should be detained till the brother returned: Mr. Sibson the brother went for Windsor before Mrs. Sibson and her husband returned.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any conversation with Mr. Tyrrell?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176209170016"></xptr>A. Wright. No, I did not; I heard my mistress deliver the massage to Mr. Sibson the brother, but I was not in the room with them; and I saw Mr. Tyrrell deliver the note in the yard to Mr. Sibson, just before he went out.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of your young mistress sending to another physician?</p>
               <p>A. Wright. I know of her sending for Mr. Fothergill, and he could not come.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620917-31-person214">
                  Thomas 
                  Howard 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person214" type="surname" value="Howard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person214" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person214" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was present at the time Mr. Sibson's body was opened.</p>
               <p>Q. Who were present?</p>
               <p>Howard. There was Mr. Johnson of Brentford, Mr. Tyrrell, my father, and myself.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember, upon the body being opened, any thing being said by Mr. Tyrrell upon the appearance of it.</p>
               <p>Howard. Yes, Sir; I was standing at the window after they had opened the body; he desired me to come to him, to see the inflammation; he said I should go to the Old Bailey.</p>
               <p>Q. Repeat his words.</p>
               <p>Howard. He said, Come, youngster, see this inflammation; you shall go with us to the Old Bailey.</p>
               <p>Mr. Johnson. I was one of the persons present at the time the body of Mr. Sibson was opened.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you remember who were present?</p>
               <p>Johnson. The persons were the same the young gentleman has spoke to; I remember the body being opened: When Mr. Tyrrell was viewing the stomach in its natural situation, he spoke out with a joyful countenance and a loud voice, A brave inflammation! Mr. Howard. Then he addressed himself to Mr. Howard's son, Come, youngster, look at this inflammation; you shall go with us to the Old Bailey. I remember it very well; it affected me very much to see a man expressing himself with so much joy, before we were certain it was so.</p>
               <p>Q. Who were present in the room?</p>
               <p>Johnson. Mr. Howard senior, Mr. Howard jun. Mr. Tyrrell, and myself; I am not certain if there was not a woman or two; there was one woman, I think, in the room, and one upon the staircase.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Howard. Was there any woman in the room?</p>
               <p>Mr. Howard. There was a woman in the room.</p>
               <p>Mr. Want. The question put to Mr. Tyrrell, at the trial here, was not youngster, but young rogue.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620917-31-person215">
                  Mary 
                  Tyrrell 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person215" type="surname" value="Tyrrell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person215" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person215" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Have you heard the evidence given by Mr. Howard and Mr. Johnson?</p>
               <p>M. Tyrrell. I have; I was by when Mr. Tyrrell made use of that expression; I heard the same words, whether it was young rogue, or youngster, I am not sure; I am sure it was one of them: I am sure he said, You shall go with us to the Old Bailey; and, more than that, I remember Mr. Johnson stroked it with his hand, and said it was only a flash with a knife.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620917-31-person216">
                  Robert 
                  Groat 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person216" type="surname" value="Groat"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person216" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person216" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            *. I was present at Sir 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person217">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person217" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person217" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person217" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's on the second examination, the night before Mrs. Sibson was committed. Mr. Johnson sent his papers to me (as he was extremely bad) to have them read; but they were refused to be read, as Mr. Tyrrell seemed to invalidate Mr. Johnson's evidence, saying, he did not believe there was any truth in them. When I came in, Mr. Tyrrell was making a declaration before Sir 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person218">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person218" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person218" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person218" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I presume he had been sworn before, and that he was examining upon oath. What I heard Mr. Tyrrell say, was, That Dr. Lucas told him (Mr. Tyrrell) that it was his (Dr. Lucas's) opinion, that poison was the occasion of the death of Mr. Sibson.</p>
               <p>* By mistake, Mr. Groat is called Grosvenor, in the trial of Mrs. Sibson, in the sessions paper of May last.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you present at the Old Bailey when Mrs. Sibson was tried?</p>
               <p>Groat. I was; and, upon my giving evidence here in this court, that question was asked him. He denied it, and said, he was sure he had never said any such thing.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the evidence you gave here on that trial?</p>
               <p>Groat. The same evidence that I have given now, as near as I can recollect. On the occasion of his having said so, I was examined to contradict him. I was asked whether Mr. Tyrrell had said so at Sir 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person219">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person219" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person219" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person219" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's. I said he had; and Mr. Tyrrell denied it. Mr. Tyrrell had given his evidence first.</p>
               <p>Dr. Lucas.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you ever in your life time told Mr. Tyrrell, that you had no doubt but that the deceased Mr. Sibson died of poison, or that it was your opinion that this man died of poison?</p>
               <p>Dr. Lucas. I never told him so, nor thought nor suspected it.</p>
               <p>Counsel for Prosecution. We rest it here.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Jos. Sibson. On the 10th of April I was at Longford. I went down to visit my brother the deceased. I put up my horse at the Queen's Head: From thence I wrote a letter to my brother, at Mr. Mackoun's, that there was an acquaintance of my brother's wanted to see him. On sending that note, I received an answer to it, wrote by my brother, all but the direction, which was wrote by Mrs. Sibson; the contents were, that he was very bad, and consined to the house for six days, but desired I would immediately come, with the bearer of that note, there.</p>
               <p>Q. Who brought the note?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176209170017"></xptr>Sibson. That was Mr. Mackoun's boy, I believe. I told him I would follow him as soon as I had dined. When I came there, Mrs. Sibson called for a pen and ink to write; she desired I would write for her; she said it was to write to Mr. Tyrrell for some things for my brother. I said, I had not been at Windsor for some years; I desired to go there to fetch them. Mrs. Martin said, As my horse might be tired in coming so far, I should be welcome to her horse. Upon coming to Windsor, I immediately went to my other brother that lives there, and quickly after I went to Mr. Tyrrell's</p>
               <p>Q. How did you find your brother that is deceased?</p>
               <p>Sibson. I was surprised at finding him so very bad. I told Mr. Tyrrell I came from Mrs. Martin's for the medicines. He said they would be ready soon. I asked him what he thought of my brother's illness, and if he thought him dangerous? He said, No, he did not think him dangerous. Said I, he appears very bad, and it greatly affects me. Said he, If you think him very bad, we have two very good physicians in Windsor, I should be glad to have the opinion of either of them; and recommended me to have the opinion of Mrs. Sibson or Mrs. Martin, or both of them. The next morning I took an opportunity to acquaint Mrs. Sibson, that I thought my brother was very bad, in a dangerous way, and I thought it would be expedient to call in a physician. I told her, Mr. Tyrrell had told me there were two very eminent physicians in Windsor, and that he would be very glad to consult either of them. She said, I don't think there is any occasion for it, your brother is much better than he was. Quickly after that, I received this letter from Mrs. Sibson. While I was at Windsor, I desired Mr. Tyrrell would come on the Sunday morning, before I left Longford: He promised me he would come. Some time late in the morning I saw Mr. Tyrrell coming on horseback: I went into the yard to meet him.</p>
               <p>Q. What Sunday was this?</p>
               <p>Sibson. This was Sunday the 11th of April; he immediately said to me, Did you recommend what I said concerning a physician, to Mrs. Martin or Mrs. Sibson? I told him I had mentioned it to Mrs. Sibson; but she neither did consent to it, or say she would not: She said, she saw no occasion for a physician, as my brother was much better than he had been. Mr. Tyrrell quickly went into the chamber where my brother lay; and, upon his asking him how he was, and some other questions, Mr. Tyrrell asked him if he had any objection to losing a little more blood? He said, No, Sir, if you think it expedient. Then, said he, I'll take a little more from you. There was a little bason, which Mr. Tyrrell took, and desired I would hold it which he was opening the orifice. Accordingly I did; after that, he said to me, I cannot think why Mrs. Martin and Mrs. Sibson should be of opinion that he is in a consumption; he said, here are strong museles, as strong as wire, and recommended me to feel his pulse; and said, Here is a strong pulse The letter Mrs. Sibson sent to me just after I got home, was dated Apr. 18, 1702. Longford.</p>
               <p>"Dear Brother,</p>
               <p>"Yours of the 14th of Apr. last Sunday, which</p>
               <p>"brings the unwelcome news of the return of the</p>
               <p>"disorder. [I am much subject to the gout, which I had wrote about in mine. - Her letter says,]</p>
               <p>"As to Mr. Sibson, he is much better as can be expected</p>
               <p>"in the time, and has been out four days in</p>
               <p>"the chaise; and as soon as he gets his stomach, I</p>
               <p>"don't in the least doubt but he will gather strength,</p>
               <p>"which is all he wants."</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Counsel for Prosecution. Look at these two letters [ be takes them into his hand].</p>
               <p>Sibson. These are both my hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Q. Then the 10th of April was the first time you ever saw Mr. Tyrrell, was it not?</p>
               <p>Sibson. It was.</p>
               <p>Q. Then you can't answer to any thing that happened before or after that time, can you?</p>
               <p>Sibson. I cannot.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you present when application was made by Mrs. Sibson to her husband to have a physician?</p>
               <p>Sibson. No, I don't remember that.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you desire Mrs. Sibson to mention it to your brother?</p>
               <p>Sibson. No; I recommended it to her, and likewise recommended these two gentlemen which Mr. Tyrrell recommended to me; they are both strangers to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your saying you thought him very bad, then it was Mr. Tyrrell said, if you thought him very bad, there were two good physicians at Windsor, he would be very glad to consult either of them; is this what you say?</p>
               <p>Sibson. I asked him if it would not be expedient to have a physician? He said there were two very good ones at Windsor, and he should be very glad to consult either of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Which mentioned a physician first, he or you?</p>
               <p>Sibson. I did.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Then Mr. Tyrrell observed to you, there was a very strong pulse, and strong muscles, even as strong as wire?</p>
               <p>Sibson. He did.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Then he did not apprehend any danger at all?</p>
               <p>Sibson. He did not apprehend any danger</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620917-31-person220">
                  Diana 
                  Tyrrell 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person220" type="surname" value="Tyrrell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person220" type="given" value="Diana"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person220" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I remember I was at Mr. Sibson's house on a Thursday, during his illness; I went along with my brother there to Longford.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176209170018"></xptr>Q. What Thursday was this?</p>
               <p>D. Tyrrell. This was the Thursday before the Monday on which he died.</p>
               <p>Q. What Mr. Tyrrell do you mean?</p>
               <p>D. Tyrrell I mean Mr. Tyrrell at the bar; he was going alone in the post-chaise, and I said I would go along with him if he choose it, for an airing: When we went in, Mr. Sibson and his wife were gone out a airing; there was nobody at home but Mrs. Martin: When my brother went in, she said, Doctor, here is a great alteration since you was here last Monday. My brother said, Then madam, we had better call in a physician.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that before any body had mentioned it to him?</p>
               <p>D. Tyrrell. It was. Mr. Sibson the barber, from Windsor, went over with us, but as he walked, he was left behind.</p>
               <p>Q. What did Mrs. Martin say to that?</p>
               <p>D. Tyrrell She said he was very obstinate, and would not have a physician; but she would mention it when he came in: My brother said, it will be late to send, when he came home. 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person221">
                  Robert 
                  Sibson 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person221" type="surname" value="Sibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person221" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             then came into the house; they went into the parlour and consulted; then he came out, and said, they had agreed to send for a physician; He and my brother talked together in the kitchen; Mrs. Martin went out a little while and came in again; my brother and he agreed this in the kitchen; my brother called for pen and ink, and wrote a note to Dr. Lucas, and Mr. 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person222">
                  Robert 
                  Sibson 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person222" type="surname" value="Sibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person222" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             carried it. When Mr. Sibson and his wife came in, and Mrs. Sibson was told of it, and he was gone up stairs, she said, she must mention it tenderly to him. When Mr. Sibson came down, she said to him, Mr. Tyrrell says, you had better have a physician; I was sitting by the fire by them, when she said it.</p>
               <p>Q. Recollect the words she made use of?</p>
               <p>D. Tyrrell. She said. My dear, as you are not better than you was, Mr. Tyrrell would advise you to have a physician. They said he was very obstinate, and would not take any thing; he complained of a violent griping and gnawing in his stomach. They desired me to persuade him to take some chicken broth, and I did persuade him, and he took them.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person223">
                  Robert 
                  Sibson 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person223" type="surname" value="Sibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person223" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Was you the person that carried on the prosecution here against Mrs. Sibson?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you carry it on by yourself?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Had Mr. Tyrrell any hand in the prosecution?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. Mr. Tyrrell had nothing to do with it, as my eldest brother was not in England, I took it upon myself.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you visit your brother often in his illness.</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. I hardly missed a day seeing him; he first came over to me to Windsor, and made great complaint about a fortnight before he died; I cannot be exact to a day.</p>
               <p>Q. When did your brother come to Longford?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. He came on Shrove-Tuesday; he came from North-America. I received a letter he had dated from Bristol, and he came within half an hour after the letter: the stage stopped at the Salt-hill, and he took a horse and came to see me; and I must needs own, I never saw him look better in my life; he expected to meet Mr. Mackouns, Mrs. 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person224">
                  Martin
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person224" type="given" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person224" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the mother, and Mrs. Sibson; about three weeks after he came and dined with me; he was then very well; after that, he came again, and complained of gripings, and desired I would get Mr. Tyrrell for him, because Mr. Tyrrell was an acquaintance of his before he left England; Mr. Tyrrell attended him the next day; Mr. Tyrrell thought him vastly bad, and desired I would take him home in a chaise, which I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you visit him most days?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. I very seldom missed going two days together. Mr. Tyrrell constantly attended him.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he begin to grow bad?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. He grew a great deal better, I have a note here which Mrs. Sibson sent me that he was better.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you there the day he died?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. I was there about a quarter of an hour after he was dead.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Mrs. Sibson then?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. She was then writing a letter to an undertaker. This was about a quarter of an hour after he died.</p>
               <p>Q. How did she seem upon it?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. She did not seem very bad upon it; for I found within two hours after, she came up to Doctor's-commons to prove the will.</p>
               <p>Counsel. You seemed to think he did not die fairly?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. I thought by some expressions which I heard in the family, that he did not die fairly.</p>
               <p>Q. What were they?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. Mrs. Sibson said, if he died she would have him opened, and have his heart taken out, and she would take opium and die, and be buried along with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it opium or poison?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. I believe they both were mentioned; and I heard the maid say, her mistres s had brought down as much poison, as would poison forty people.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her name?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. Her name is 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person225">
                  Ann 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person225" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person225" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person225" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. When did you hear this?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. This was on the Friday before my brother died.</p>
               <p>Q. How came she to mention this?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. It was upon her husband's being so bad, she would take it.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176209170019"></xptr>Q. Who was this mentioned before?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. She mentioned it before Mr. Bearblock and I, and several other people. Mr. Tyrrell has heard her say so, I dare say, once or twice, as well as I.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you present when Mr. Tyrrell has heard her?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. I was; and from this, it struck in my mind that he was poisoned.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you mention your thoughts to Mr. Tyrrell?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. I told Mr. Tyrrell I did think so.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any thing of bread and butter?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. The maid took some bread and butter out of a band-box.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. This was the Friday night before my brother died.</p>
               <p>Q. How came she to do that?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. I don't know.</p>
               <p>Q. Were any body by at the time?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. There were Mr. Bearblock, Mrs. Martin, Mrs. Sibson, and there might be more women.</p>
               <p>Q. What was done with it?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. I took it away with me. I had it in my possession; and when I came home, I repeated this to Dr. Lucas; and he clapped his finger on the table, and said, You may as well spread this table, as to spread laudanum.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you acquaint Dr. Lucas of it?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. It was on the sunday-night before he died. From this I thought it incumbent on me to go on with a prosecution.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you, when you was at your brother's, ever hear Mrs. Sibson or Mrs. Martin propose a physician?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. I don't recollect that I ever did. My brother Joseph came from Baldock, and he was surprized to see him so bad: I went with my brother Joseph to Mr. Tyrrell, and left Mr. Tyrrell and he together upon that subject, that is, concerning a physician being called for.</p>
               <p>Q. When was that?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. This was on the Saturday was se'nnight before he died, I believe it was then, but I will not be positive; I heard at that time Mr. Tyrrell advise a physician.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you be certain how long it was before he died? was it a week before, or longer?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. It was better than a week before. Mr. Tyrrell said, There were two very good physicians at Windsor; and begged of my brother to recommend it when he returned.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at Sir 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person226">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person226" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person226" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's when Mr. Tyrrell was there?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. I was. I remember Sir John wrote a card and gave it to Mr. Tyrrell, and I believe the contents of it were to beg of Dr. Lucas to know his opinion. I asked him what was Dr. Lucas's answer to the card? he said, Dr. Lucas did not chuse to give his opinion to any one, till he came to the Old Bailey, if he was called there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear Mr. Tyrrell say Dr. Lucas was clear of opinion he died of poison?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. No; I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you there at both examinations when the women were there?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. I was.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you hear it from, that it was agreed that the first that died was to take the heart out for the other to keep by them?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. I had it from Mrs. Martin's own mouth.</p>
               <p>Q. When was it agreed upon?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. That was, I believe, before they came to England.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Then the thoughts of that, and hearing of poison in the house, gave you this suspicion?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. Yes; from thence I thought he might be poisoned; the maid said, there was as much brought down as would poison forty people.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of Mr. Tyrrell advising Mrs. Sibson, or Mrs. Martin, to call in the aid of a physician, of your own knowledge?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. No; I really do not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you before Sir 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person227">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person227" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person227" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person227" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             all the time?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. I might be out, but not to stay any time.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember Mr. Pitt being before Sir 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person228">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person228" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person228" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. I do; the more he looked in it, the blacker it appeared to him, he said; and begged of Sir John not to be called again.</p>
               <p>Q. Which was the black affair, the charge against this poor woman for having poisoned her husband, or what?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. The reason was concerning all this money that was missing.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Was not that mentioned on the trial here?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether Sir John did not say, it was a matter so doubtful, as the Coroner's Inquest having found the man died from a natural cause, that he should be very glad to receive some satisfaction from somebody of better knowledge?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. I imagine that was the reason this card was sent to Dr. Lucas.</p>
               <p>Q. Now will you undertake to say, That Mr. Tyrrell did not step forth, and say at once, he could clear up that difficulty, for Dr. Lucas was clear of opinion he died of poison?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176209170020"></xptr>R. Sibson. I did not hear him say so.</p>
               <p>Q. Will you undertake to say he did not say so?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. I don't recollect it.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath, did you not hear it?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. Upon my oath, I never did hear it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Sir John sign the card?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. I did, with his own hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the card sent the last time of examination?</p>
               <p>R. Sibson. I really cannot say whether it was the last time or no.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620917-31-person229">
                  William 
                  Marsden 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person229" type="surname" value="Marsden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person229" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was present at this examination before Sir 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person230">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person230" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person230" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Mr. Mombray. Mr. Mombray has been here a good part of the day, in order to give evidence on this matter, but he is now gone.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you was present at Sir 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person231">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person231" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person231" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person231" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, at the time of the examination of these people?</p>
               <p>Marsden. I was; and I took them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear, either in point of examination, or point of conversation this expression, it is a material one, That Mr. Tyrrell said there to any body, and to whom, That Dr. Lucas's opinion was, that the deceased was poisoned?</p>
               <p>Marsden. No; I never heard any such thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in the room all the time?</p>
               <p>Marsden. I was; it was in Bow-street.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you write all the time?</p>
               <p>Marsden. I wrote some part of the time. I am very sure Mr. Tyrrell never swore any such thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any talk about Dr. Lucas?</p>
               <p>Marsden. I did hear some talk about him; Mr. Fielding desired to know the opinion of Dr. Lucas and Dr. Hays, and ordered me to write to Dr. Lucas.</p>
               <p>Q. At which examination was it?</p>
               <p>Marsden. I believe it was that evening she was committed for further examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember any thing being said about Mr. Johnson?</p>
               <p>Marsden. I do; I remember one thing being said about him; which I think was said to be at the same time this other thing was said. Mr. Tyrrell said, he believed he should be able to prove Mr. Johnson had not seen Dr. Lucas, though in that writing Mr. Johnson had said he had seen Dr. Lucas; that I think upon the trial here, was said to be at the same time of the other expression; and I was surprized to think I did not hear that expression.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether there was any talk of what Dr. Lucas had said?</p>
               <p>Marsden. Yes; Mr. Johnson sent a writing. I read it over to the justice; there was one circumstance mentioned; that was, Whether he knew Dr. Lucas's opinion? Mr. Tyrrell said, he believed he should be able to prove Dr. Lucas had not seen Mr. Johnson.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether that was not in answer to a conversation touching something that Dr. Lucas should have said, and that Dr. Lucas had said something different from Mr. Johnson?</p>
               <p>Marsden. It might.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether Justice Fielding said, I should be very glad if some of the physicians were here: and Mr. Tyrrell should say, If Dr. Lucas was here, he would put it out of doubt; for he had told him, it was his opinion the man died of poison; take it whole together?</p>
               <p>Marsden. The justice expressed he should be glad to have the doctor's opinion on it; and expressed an uneasiness how to act in it. There was no such declaration from Mr. Tyrrell; it was rather connected with that thing of Mr. Johnson; but it was not sworn I am positive.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there no such conversation with Mr. Tyrrell?</p>
               <p>Marsden. No, not in that manner.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not there a letter from Mr. Johnson, with a remarkable postscript in it, directed to Sir 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person232">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person232" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person232" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person232" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , which was read, and an objection taken, that it could not be Mr. Johnson's hand-writing?</p>
               <p>Marsden. I do remember that, I remember it was wrote in two different hand-writings.</p>
               <p>Q. Rub up your memory again, and see if you can go a little farther, whether there was not a dispute about this letter, whether it was from Mr. Johnson?</p>
               <p>Marsden. I cannot charge my memory with the conversation.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you recollect you was at the trial here of Mrs. Sibson?</p>
               <p>Marsden. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you recollect what was given in evidence by Dr. Groat, concerning what passed at Sir 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person233">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person233" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person233" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's.</p>
               <p>Marsden. Yes; and I was a good deal surprized at hearing that, because it was not mentioned at Sir 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person234">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person234" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person234" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person234" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you was here at the time Mr. Pitt gave his evidence, and that he and Mr. Groat both swore, that Tyrrell said at Sir 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person235">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person235" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person235" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, Dr. Lucas told him, he was of opinion the man died of poison?</p>
               <p>Marsden. Yes, I was.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Then why did not you, as an honest man, stand up and say, I was by, and heard no such thing.</p>
               <p>Marsden. I do not thrust myself into things I have no business in; I am subpocna'd here, or I had not been here now.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you not to do it, and not suffer a man to be committed for wilful and corrupt perjury?</p>
               <p>Marsden. I did not understand he was committed<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176209170021"></xptr> for that; as for that I never looked on it as any sort of weight at all.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620917-31-person236">
                  George 
                  Pearson 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person236" type="surname" value="Pearson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person236" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I attended at three of the examinations before Sir 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person237">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person237" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person237" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person237" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; the first was of 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person238">
                  Ann 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person238" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person238" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person238" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the servant girl on the Monday morning; and Mrs. Sibson's on the Tuesday. I came when she was gone out into the yard, on the account of being sick; and I was here on her re-examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear Mr. Tyrrell examined?</p>
               <p>Pearson. He was examined frequently.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you there all the time of examination?</p>
               <p>Pearson. I was out backwards and forwards on the Tuesday evening; that was the second examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you there when Dr. Groat was examined?</p>
               <p>Pearson. I was; that was on the Thursday.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you attentive to what passed?</p>
               <p>Pearson. I was very attentive; and if that expression had been mentioned, I think I must have heard it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the doctor there any other time?</p>
               <p>Pearson. No; never but on the Thursday, as I remember.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you there the whole time Dr. Groat was there?</p>
               <p>Pearson. I was; I was there when he came in.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you hear Tyrrell say, Dr. Lucas had told him (Mr. Tyrrell) that he the said Dr. Lucas had not the least doubt that the man was poisoned?</p>
               <p>Pearson. No, I did not; what I heard was this: He was asked by Sir 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person239">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person239" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person239" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , if he had seen Dr. Lucas? Mr. Tyrrell said, he had: Sir John said, Pray, what does the doctor say? Mr. Tyrrell said, the doctor told me he would not declare his opinion till he came to the Old Bailey, or words to that effect.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that when Dr. Groat was there?</p>
               <p>Pearson. I should imagine it was.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath, whether at the time that you heard this Dr. Groat was there?</p>
               <p>Pearson. I do apprehend it was at the time he was there, but I cannot be positive.</p>
               <p>Q. to Dr. Groat. Did you hear Mr. Tyrrell mention as this evidence has said before Sir 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person240">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person240" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person240" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Dr. Groat. Upon my oath, Mr. Tyrrell said no such words while I was there.</p>
               <p>Q. to Pearson. What are you?</p>
               <p>Pearson. I am a clerk in the law; I am clerk to Mr. White, in Arundel-street in the Strand.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be at the examinations?</p>
               <p>Pearson. Mr. Sibson is a townsman of mine; Mr. Bearblock called upon me, and said, here is a terrible thing happened; and said, we do imagine Mr. Sibson has been poisoned, and if you go you will hear what passes; so I went.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620917-31-person241">
                  Peter 
                  Graham 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person241" type="surname" value="Graham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person241" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was present when Mr. Tyrrell was asked the question concerning Dr. Lucas of Windson: Sir John asked him, If he had seen Dr. Lucas he said opinion? He said, Dr. Lucas says he will not his opinion at present, but if he is called upon at the Old Bailey, he will give it there.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he to give it verbally or in writing?</p>
               <p>Graham. I can't say which.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620917-31-person242">
                  William 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person242" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person242" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was present at all the three examinations.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be there?</p>
               <p>Smith. I have known 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person243">
                  George 
                  Sibson 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person243" type="surname" value="Sibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person243" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person243" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a great man, years; the first day he was in London, he called upon me; he being an intimate acquaintance, carried me there. I heard Sir 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person244">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person244" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person244" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person244" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ask Mr. Tyrrell, if he had called upon Dr. Lucas? He said he had. He asked what was Mr. Lucas's opinion I regard to the deceased? He said, he would not declare his opinion to him, but if he was called upon to come to the Old Bailey, he would declare there.</p>
               <p>Q. If Mr. Tyrrell had said that Dr. Lucas tell him the man died of poison, should you have hear it?</p>
               <p>Smith. I am certain I should.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any thing of it from Mr. Tyrrell?</p>
               <p>Smith. I did not hear a syllable of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you there when Mr. Johnson was there?</p>
               <p>Smith. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you there when Mr. Groat was there?</p>
               <p>Smith. I was; he came in with a parcel of papers. I knew him by sight very well.</p>
               <p>Q. Don't you remember a conversation with these two gentlemen; and that Mr. Pitt told Mr. Fielding, that if Dr. Lucas was there, he would put the matter out of doubt; and Mr. Tyrrell made answer, that he would, for he had told him it was his opinion the man died of poison?</p>
               <p>Smith. I never heard any such thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Might it have been said, and you not have heard it?</p>
               <p>Smith. I don't think it was possible to be said without my hearing it; it was not said in my hearing.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Then you must think Mr. Pitt and Mr. Groat perjured?</p>
               <p>Smith. I don't say that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620917-31-person245">
                  James 
                  Bearblock 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person245" type="surname" value="Bearblock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person245" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at all the examinations before Sir 
               <persName id="t17620917-31-person246">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620917-31-person246" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person246" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-person246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear Mr. Tyrrell say, it was Dr. Lucas's opinion that the deceased died of poison?</p>
               <p>Bearblack. No; I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think if such a thing was said, you must have heard it?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. I think I must.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. I am a woollen-draper, and live in Smithfield.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you there during the whole examinations?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. I was; Monday, Tuesday, and Thursday.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you remain in the room all the time?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176209170022"></xptr>Bearblock. Mrs. Sibson did go out once or twice, but I remained in the room all the whole time</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember a letter being produced that Mr. Johnson sent?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. I do; there were two different handwritings in it, and some dispute about the hand-writings.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any thing at all said about Dr. Lucas's opinion?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. Mr. Tyrrell came in, and Sir John asked him, if he had seen Dr. Lucas? He said, yes: Sir John asked what was his opinion? Mr. Tyrrell said, Dr Lucas would not give his opinion till he was called to the Old Bailey; then he said, he would give his opinion.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear Mr. Tyrrell say, Dr. Lucas told him, it was his opinion the man died of poison?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. No; I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Will you say, he never did say so?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. Sir, you shall not catch me there; I say, I never did hear it.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the contents of a card that Sir John sent to Dr. Lucas?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. I do, I believe; it was Sir John's respectful compliments to Dr. Hayes and Dr. Lucas, and he desired to have their opinions on this thing; I don't know, whether Sir John did not ask Mr. Tyrrell, if he had got a writing.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the dispute about the letter from Mr. Johnson?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. The letter and the direction were not by the same hand; then afterwards, they found the postscript, was not the same hand with the letter, and there was a dispute about it.</p>
               <p>Q. Recollect yourself, whether or no upon that dispute about the letter, containing what was Dr. Lucas's opinion, Mr. Tyrrell did not give the justice an account of what Dr. Lucas had told him?</p>
               <p>Bearblock. I don't recollect that.</p>
               <p>Counsel for the Prisoner. We have done, except to character.</p>
               <p>Counsel for the Prosecution. I dare say he has a very good character; we admit he has a very good character.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17620917-31-verdict155" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-verdict155" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620917-31-verdict155" type="verdictSubcategory" value="withRecommendation"></interp>
               The Jury found him Guilty, but recommended him to all the mercy his case would bear
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
