<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660514-25">
               <interp inst="t17660514-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660514-25" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660514-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660514"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660514-25" type="date" value="17660514"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660514-25-off151-c215" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-25-defend271 t17660514-25-off151 t17660514-25-verdict155"></join>
         
               <p>309. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660514-25-defend271" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Lewis 
                  <interp inst="t17660514-25-defend271" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-defend271" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-defend271" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for the <rs id="t17660514-25-off151" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-off151" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-off151" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               wilful murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17660514-25-victim273" type="victimName">
                           Elizabeth 
                           Thompson 
                        <interp inst="t17660514-25-victim273" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660514-25-victim273" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660514-25-victim273" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-25-off151 t17660514-25-victim273"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17660514-25-viclabel152" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-25-victim273 t17660514-25-viclabel152"></join>. He stood charged on the Coroner's Inquest for manslaughter, <rs id="t17660514-25-cd153" type="crimeDate">April 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-25-off151 t17660514-25-cd153"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-25-person274">
                  Mary 
                  Gibons 
               <interp inst="t17660514-25-person274" type="surname" value="Gibons"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person274" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person274" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The deceased, 
               <persName id="t17660514-25-person275">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17660514-25-person275" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person275" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person275" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was my mother; she lodged at Mr. Scott's at Hampstead, Mr. Lewis <rs id="t17660514-25-deflabel154" type="occupation">keeps coaches</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-25-defend271 t17660514-25-deflabel154"></join> there; my mother and I went in one of his coaches from the Blue Posts in Tottenham-court-road to Hampstead, about three weeks ago; one of his men drove us; I got out at Mr. Scott's door, and went into the yard, and ask'd for a little child I had there; my mother went in the coach to Mr. Lewis's, which is about a stone's throw distant; then I went after my mother; going into Mr. Lewis's kitchen, I was behind her. Mr. Lewis went in before her; he clapped the door in my mother's face; my mother said, You good for nothing fellow, what did you do that for: he said, I did not see any body behind me. There were no more words said about that.</p>
               <p>Q. Did it hurt her?</p>
               <p>M. Gibons. It hit her in the forehead, but did not much hurt her; then we all went into the kitchen; there were Mr. and Mrs. Lewis, the cook, my mother, I, a little girl, and my little girl; mine is about three years old, the other girl is servant to Mr. Lewis, I do not know her age. My little girl had occasion to go into the yard, after we had been there about an hour: I went out with her; Mr. Lewis was standing talking to a man at the fore door when I went out.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>M. Gibons. This was about five in the afternoon; I only staid while the child made water, and went into the kitchen again; then Mrs. Lewis was helping my mother off the ground: I said. What have you done to my mother? She said, Your mother has struck her hand against Mr. Lewis's knife. No, said my mother, don't say so, for Mr. Lewis jobb'd the knife into my hand. They put some stuff to it to stop the blood.</p>
               <p>Q. Whereabouts was the wound?</p>
               <p>M. Gibons. It was on her left hand, on the back part between the fore finger and the next to it; it appeared like the scratch of a pin, about half the length of a middling pin. I went home in about three quarters of an hour, and left my mother there.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was you gone out of the house?</p>
               <p>M. Gibons. I believe I was not out of the house above two minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any thing else said about it after you went into the kitchen?</p>
               <p>M. Gibons. No, there was not for the time I staid, which was about three quarters of an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Did your mother seem to be in pain?</p>
               <p>M. Gibons. No, she did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your mother sober?</p>
               <p>M. Gibons. She had been drinking; she was a little in liquor, but not fuddled, I believe.</p>
               <p>Q. How old was your mother?</p>
               <p>M. Gibons. She was sixty-four years of age; my mother came to me in Berwick-street, Soho, the next day; then she complained a great deal of her hand; I saw it, it was swelled; Mr. Bedford was the surgeon, and Mr. Maschall the apothecary,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176605140024"></xptr> which she employed. She lived better than a fortnight after, and then died</p>
               <p>Q. What was the occasion of her death?</p>
               <p>M. Gibons. Her hand mortified, of which she died; she said she should die of it.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you recollect what day this was done?</p>
               <p>M. Gibons. No, I cannot, nor the day my mother died</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-25-person276">
                  Mary 
                  Walls 
               <interp inst="t17660514-25-person276" type="surname" value="Walls"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person276" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person276" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was servant to Mrs. Thompson's daughter in Berwick-street. Mrs. Thompson came home on the Thursday, the day after she was hurt, and said she had had a hurt on her hand with a knife; I never heard her say how she got it.</p>
               <p>Q. When did she die?</p>
               <p>M. Walls. She died on Monday was a week, of a mortification in her hand. My mistress sent me with a letter to Mr. Lewis; the kinswoman told me he was eating bread and cheese, and she behaved very indecent, and he said if she did so again he would strike her. but he did not; but she up with her hand, and hit the back of her hand against the knife.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Mrs. Thompson the day she went to Hampstead?</p>
               <p>M. Walls. She went from our house about one o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she sober?</p>
               <p>M. Walls. I did not see her go down stairs, I was busy in the kitchen.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-25-person277">
                  Anne 
                  Thorn 
               <interp inst="t17660514-25-person277" type="surname" value="Thorn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person277" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person277" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in a room of my own in King-street.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know how Mrs. Thompson came by her death?</p>
               <p>A. Thorn. No, I did not; only by what Mr. Lewis said about it, the Monday after it was done; I went to him with the last witness, he said Mrs. Thompson behaved indecent; he was eating bread and cheese, and he said if she did so again, he would strike her; she did do so again, he did not strike her, but she held up her hand and struck it against the knife, or pushed her hand against it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-25-person278">
                  Susanna 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17660514-25-person278" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person278" type="given" value="Susanna"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person278" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The day after my mother received the wound, she came to me, and said Mr. Lewis had run a knife into the back of her hand; she said her hand was extremely bad, and it mortified. I lay with her: one morning she awaked me, and said, Do not you do any thing with the man, I shall die of the wound.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she ever say what provocation he might have for doing so.</p>
               <p>S. Thompson. No; she never said any thing of that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-25-person279">
                  Henry 
                  Maschall 
               <interp inst="t17660514-25-person279" type="surname" value="Maschall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person279" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person279" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the apothecary. I saw the deceased on Sunday the 20th of April, she said she had received a wound on her hand on the Wednesday; she complained of great pain in her hand, which was much inflamed and swelled; I examined it, and found a small wound, I thought it to be but a slight wound; there was no mortification began at that time; I attended her again in the afternoon; the next morning the symptoms increased; I advised her to send for a surgeon; she did, and I attended with him till her death. She imagined, when I first came to her, it was done by a poisoned knife.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any reason to think that the case?</p>
               <p>Maschall. No, none at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say who gave her that wound?</p>
               <p>Maschall. I do not recollect she did; at times she would say it would be her death, and sometimes she expressed some marks of resentment against the man that had done it.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How long might the wound be?</p>
               <p>Maschall. It was very short; I never saw a probe introduced into it; it was almost healed up.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-25-person280">
                  David 
                  Bedford 
               <interp inst="t17660514-25-person280" type="surname" value="Bedford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person280" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person280" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a surgeon. I attended the deceased on the 21st of last month; I found the back of her hand very much inflamed, and the arm below the elbow swelled, and a small wound a little oblique on the back of her hand, the length under an inch, seemingly very superficial.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you probe it?</p>
               <p>Bedford. I did not; it was rather too much inflamed.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by superficial?</p>
               <p>Bedford. I mean a wound that extended but very little in depth; it was what might be called an exceeding slight wound; the depth was in a very slight proportion to the length; the length might be from half an inch to three quarters of an inch.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you suppose it could have been done with a stab?</p>
               <p>Bedford. It rather appeared to me to be done with a round edged knife; it appeared as if a drawn cut had been made with a round pointed instrument; from the inflamation there came a mortification, of which mortification she died, which was that day fortnight I was called in.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176605140025"></xptr>Justice Wright. On the 24th of April 
               <persName id="t17660514-25-person281">
                  Mary 
                  Gibons 
               <interp inst="t17660514-25-person281" type="surname" value="Gibons"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person281" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person281" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the daughter, came and told me her mother had been wounded in the hand, by a man at Hampstead, and it was not expected she would live till one o'clock; this was about twelve. I went with her to her lodging; I met a gentleman in the dining-room: I asked him if he was the surgeon; he said he attended the deceased for another gentleman; I asked him whether she was in her senses; he said she was. I went into the room and asked her her story, and to be punctual that she was in her senses, she answered every thing very reasonably; I asked her three or four times before I took it, and she never varied from it; she was sworn to the examination; here it is ( producing it) this is her mark upon it; she set this to it after I had read it over to her two or three times; the surgeon had told her there was no probability of her recovery; upon this a warrant was granted to take up the prisoner for an assault.</p>
               <p>The information read to this purport.</p>
               <p>April 24, 1766.</p>
               <p>"The information of 
               <persName id="t17660514-25-person282">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17660514-25-person282" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person282" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person282" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ,</p>
               <p>"widow, who being upon oath, says, That on</p>
               <p>"Wednesday the 16th of this instant, she went</p>
               <p>"to the George at Hampstead, about four o'clock</p>
               <p>"in the afternoon; says, that upon her first entering</p>
               <p>"the house, Lewis, who keeps the said</p>
               <p>"house, pushed the door in her face; that she</p>
               <p>"asked him why he used her so; he bid her go</p>
               <p>"look, and soon after 
               <persName id="t17660514-25-person283">
                  drew
               <interp inst="t17660514-25-person283" type="given" value="drew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person283" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a knife out of his own</p>
               <p>"pocket, and stabbed her with it on the back of</p>
               <p>"her left hand."</p>
               <p>The mark + of 
               <persName id="t17660514-25-person284">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17660514-25-person284" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person284" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person284" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>The deceased came into our house on the 16th of April, in the afternoon, and her daughter with her; they had some beer. I had been out, and had no dinner; I had got some bread and cheese, and one of the common case knives in my hand, and sat down on a chair by the kitchen fire; but her daughter was not in the house at the time, there was no body in the kitchen but my wife, she, me, and two servants: the deceased began to pull up her coats a good part up her thigh; I said, Mrs. Thompson, I am surprised that a woman of your years should behave in the manner you do. She and her daughter were both drunk; but the daughter was gone out. The deceased d - d me, and said, Don't you like it? and pulled them up again. I said, If you do so again, I'll give you a slap on the back-side; I put the knife out of my right-hand into my left, and held my hand up; I did not strike her; she said, you Welsh son of a b - h, who values you? and was going to strike me in the face, but did not touch me, but hit her hand against the knife which I had in my hand.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-25-person285">
                  Anne 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17660514-25-person285" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person285" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person285" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I go out a washing and scouring. I was at Mr. Lewis's at the time Mrs. Thompson and her daughter came in; they had two pots of beer; this was on a Wednesday between four and five o'clock, three weeks or a month ago; the deceased, and her daughter too were both very much in liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. Who else was in the room?</p>
               <p>A. Wood. There was a little girl, named 
               <persName id="t17660514-25-person286">
                  Esther 
                  Burrows 
               <interp inst="t17660514-25-person286" type="surname" value="Burrows"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person286" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person286" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , my master and mistress. They first at coming in called for a pint of half and half; my master went to shut the door; the deceased said, What was that for? she was then coming in; Mr. Lewis said, Mrs. Thompson, I ask your pardon, I did not know any body was there; the door did not touch her; she had had a blow on her forehead some days before; when she had the half and half, she said to Mr. Lewis, You Welsh son of a b - h, you cannot shew such a handsome leg and thigh as I can; her daughter was then gone out with the child; this was after they had been there half an hour; Mr. Lewis was eating a bit of bread and cheese, she was sitting by the table by the fireside; Mr. Lewis was between the table and the dresser, he had a knife in his hand.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a knife, a case or clasp knife?</p>
               <p>Wood. It was a clasp knife; she pulled up her petticoats several times; at last Mr. Lewis said, If you do pull up your cloaths again, I'll hit you a spank, but he never touched her; she went to get up from the chair to pull up her cloaths again; she stood against the table as well as she could, and she flung her hand against his knife; I saw a little scratch on it.</p>
               <p>Q. Which way did she throw her hand?</p>
               <p>A. Wood. She threw her hand backwards, because she had like to have been down.</p>
               <p>Q. Which hand had Mr. Lewis the knife in?</p>
               <p>A. Wood. I believe he had it in his left hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath tell the Jury, whether he struck her hand on purpose to stick it, or whether she hit her hand against the knife.</p>
               <p>A. Wood. She hit her hand against the knife, and he never struck her indeed; the next morning<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176605140026"></xptr> she came in and asked his pardon for being so rude, and said she was in liquor; and said, if she had cut her hand worse it would have been no matter: I was in the house and heard this, and 
               <persName id="t17660514-25-person287">
                  John 
                  Carr 
               <interp inst="t17660514-25-person287" type="surname" value="Carr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person287" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person287" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             heard it as well as myself.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-25-person288">
                  Esther 
                  Burrows 
               <interp inst="t17660514-25-person288" type="surname" value="Burrows"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person288" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person288" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am 15 years of age; I was in Mr. Lewis's kitchen at the time the accident happened; there was the cook, my master and mistress in the kitchen at the time; Mrs. Thompson was sitting in a chair, and called for a pint of half and half; being much in liquor they would not draw it; she got up and gave me a slap in the face; then she went to the boy, he said he would not draw it without master was willing; my master said, draw it, then she will go out contented; she had it; after that, the daughter went to the child. I saw the deceased pull up her cloaths 3 times; my master said, do it again and I'll give you a good spank; she did, she got up and said, you Welsh son of a b - h, you give me a slap of the face! my master had his bread and cheese in his left hand, and a knife in his right; she struck her hand backwards against the knife, and there were two or three scratches, as if done with a pin.</p>
               <p>Q. Did your master strike her with the knife?</p>
               <p>E. Burrows. No, he did not; she said she would slap his chops. She came the next day, and said to my master, I beg your pardon for what I did yesterday; if I had not been drunk I should not have done so; she said, she did it herself, and she could blame nobody else.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-25-person289">
                  John 
                  Carr 
               <interp inst="t17660514-25-person289" type="surname" value="Carr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person289" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-person289" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at Mr. Lewis's the next day after this accident; when Mrs. Thompson came there in the morning, she begged Mr. Lewis's pardon, and said she was in liquor, and believed she had offended some people; she said it was her own doing, and she must thank herself for it; this she said several times, and was very sorry if she had offended any body.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Carr. I lodge in the house.</p>
               <p>There were several people to the prisoner's character, but the jury said it was needless to call them.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660514-25-verdict155" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660514-25-verdict155" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
