<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17630706-40">
               <interp inst="t17630706-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630706-40" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630706-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17630706"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630706-40" type="date" value="17630706"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17630706-40-off230-c328" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-40-defend414 t17630706-40-off230 t17630706-40-verdict233"></join>
         
               <p>316. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17630706-40-defend414" type="defendantName">
                     Patrick 
                     Cane 
                  <interp inst="t17630706-40-defend414" type="surname" value="Cane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-40-defend414" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-40-defend414" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17630706-40-off230" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630706-40-off230" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-40-off230" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               robbing 
                     
                        <persName id="t17630706-40-victim416" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Harding 
                        <interp inst="t17630706-40-victim416" type="surname" value="Harding"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630706-40-victim416" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630706-40-victim416" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-40-off230 t17630706-40-victim416"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the king's highway of a hat, value 2 s. and a perriwig, value 2 s. his property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17630706-40-cd231" type="crimeDate">June 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-40-off230 t17630706-40-cd231"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630706-40-person417">
                  William 
                  Harding 
               <interp inst="t17630706-40-person417" type="surname" value="Harding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-40-person417" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-40-person417" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 10th of June I was coming from the White Hart in Pennington-street, Ratcliff-highway, alone; coming up Harty-choak-hill, at past 11 at night, (I was turned into <placeName id="t17630706-40-crimeloc232">Ratcliff-highway</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17630706-40-crimeloc232" type="placeName" value="Ratcliff-highway"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17630706-40-crimeloc232" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-40-off230 t17630706-40-crimeloc232"></join> about 3 yards) three men came up and surrounded me, one struck me on the jaw-bone, and they proceeded with blows, till the knocked me down, I was almost senseless when I fell; as I was on the ground, and a little recovered from the blows, I found one of them feeling for my watch, the string of my watch was within-side my breeches, they could not get it, then I cried out murder, then the last man took my wig from my head, (I believe my hat was gone before) and ran away; the gentlemen in the watch-house heard me, that was about 50 or 60 yards distance, they come out, the prisoner ran against a post, and knocked himself down, he got up and ran again, and was soon taken; he was brought to me to see if I knew him, I said I did not, I could not be positive to either of their faces; my hat and wig were found in the road afterwards; the prisoner denied it before the magistrate.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630706-40-person418">
                  John 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17630706-40-person418" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-40-person418" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-40-person418" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Ratcliff-highway, the corner of Princess-square. I was at Mr. Alcote's door, where I live, between eleven and twelve that night; there is a lamp at the corner, right cross the way from our house, about three doors from the place were Mr. Harding was attacked; I saw him coming up the hill, and turn the corner; there were three fellows came and knocked him down, he cried, murder; the prisoner said to the others, D - n your eyes, make off. He crossed the way towards our house, the light from the shop blinded his eyes, he ran against a post, it took him in his breast, and he pitched over it, and fell on his head; I got past him, he seeing what I was upon, put his hand on his bosom and made off; I hollo'd out, there was a public-house just by, six or eight men pushed out, we all ran after the prisoner; the officer of the night was looking over the hatch in the watch-house, catched hold of the prisoner's collar, and stopped him; I had my eye upon him all the way, he ran, and I was within four or five yards of him when he was stopped. The officer took him into the watch-house, and asked him where he lodged? he said on Saltpetre-bank; he denied having any hand in the knocking down and robbing Mr. Harding, but I am sure he is one of the three, and is the very man that said, d - n your eyes, make off; there were lamps in that part of the road where he ran, and I had my eye upon him all the while.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630706-40-person419">
                  Thomas 
                  Golton 
               <interp inst="t17630706-40-person419" type="surname" value="Golton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-40-person419" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-40-person419" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was the officer of the night. I was at the watch-house at the bottom of Wellclose-square; on the 8th of June, at past 11 at night, as the prisoner came running I ran out of the watch-house and stopped him; I enquired for the person robbed, there I found Mr. Harding with his mouth bleeding, without hat or wig; I took the prisoner into the watch-house, he denied the charge. I asked him what company he had been in? first he said he had been to the Navy-office, the next day before the Justice he said he had been at Shadwell, at the Noah's Ark; Mr. Harding and I went there, the people said no such person had been there; after that he said he had been at a house by Stepney. The hat and wig were found in the road after he was taken.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>That night I was coming to one Mr. Brooks, to receive my money; I had been at Stepney about 4 o'clock, and Shadwell-dock was the last place I had been at. Going home I met a gentleman, he asked what noise that was? I said I did not know: he said, come back and see what is the matter. I came back directly, then these men stopped me, and brought me into the watch-house.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17630706-40-verdict233" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630706-40-verdict233" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
