<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650227-23">
               <interp inst="t17650227-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650227-23" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650227-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650227"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650227-23" type="date" value="17650227"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650227-23-off128-c166" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-23-defend219 t17650227-23-off128 t17650227-23-verdict134"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650227-23-off128-c167" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-23-defend221 t17650227-23-off128 t17650227-23-verdict132"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650227-23-off128-c168" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-23-defend223 t17650227-23-off128 t17650227-23-verdict132"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650227-23-off135-c166" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-23-defend219 t17650227-23-off135 t17650227-23-verdict134"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650227-23-off135-c167" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-23-defend221 t17650227-23-off135 t17650227-23-verdict132"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650227-23-off135-c168" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-23-defend223 t17650227-23-off135 t17650227-23-verdict132"></join>
         
               <p>181, 182, 183. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17650227-23-defend219" type="defendantName">
                  
                        
                           <persName id="t17650227-23-defend221" type="defendantName">
                              John 
                              Carroll 
                           <interp inst="t17650227-23-defend221" type="surname" value="Carroll"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650227-23-defend221" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650227-23-defend221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                         
                     , Mary, his <rs id="t17650227-23-deflabel126" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-23-defend219 t17650227-23-deflabel126"></join>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-defend219" type="surname" value="Carroll"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-defend219" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-defend219" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17650227-23-defend223" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Carroll 
                  <interp inst="t17650227-23-defend223" type="surname" value="Carroll"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-defend223" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-defend223" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17650227-23-deflabel127" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-23-defend223 t17650227-23-deflabel127"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17650227-23-off128" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-off128" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-off128" type="offenceSubcategory" value="shoplifting"></interp>
               stealing one hundred yards of linen cloth, value 15 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17650227-23-victim225" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Greenfield 
                        <interp inst="t17650227-23-victim225" type="surname" value="Greenfield"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650227-23-victim225" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650227-23-victim225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately in the shop of the said John
            </rs>, <rs id="t17650227-23-cd129" type="crimeDate">February 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-23-off128 t17650227-23-cd129"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-23-off135 t17650227-23-cd129"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650227-23-person226">
                  John 
                  Greenfield 
               <interp inst="t17650227-23-person226" type="surname" value="Greenfield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person226" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17650227-23-crimeloc130">Fleet-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17650227-23-crimeloc130" type="placeName" value="Fleet-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17650227-23-crimeloc130" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-23-off128 t17650227-23-crimeloc130"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-23-off135 t17650227-23-crimeloc130"></join>, and am a <rs id="t17650227-23-viclabel131" type="occupation">linen draper</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-23-victim225 t17650227-23-viclabel131"></join>; on the 7th of this instant, between four and five in the evening, the two women at the bar came into my shop, for a silk handkerchief: I shew'd them some: I had only one other customer in the shop at that time; that was a lady who was sitting at the farther end of the counting-house, which one of my men was serving; my other man had left the shop a little time before, and was with Mr. Peltroe, of Spitalfields; they were examining my books and silk handkerchiefs: I shew'd the two women some silk handkerchiefs, and asked four shillings and sixpence apiece; they bid me three shillings and sixpence; they stood just at the coming in at the door, where I had a great stock of handkerchiefs, to the value of 4 or 500 l. In the mean time came in the man at the bar, and asked for a handkerchief; I left them, and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176502270015"></xptr> went up farther in the shop. to serve him with a blue one, prize 14 d. he threw me 13 d. and ask'd if that would do: I said no, then he gave me the other penny, and went away: then I went to the women; they would give me no more than 3 s. 6 d. as they were going out of the door, I said they might have them for 4 s. 3 d. they would not give it me, and went away; and in ten minutes time they returned: my handkerchiefs were all there, I can safely swear, before they came in; they said, shall we have this silk handkerchief? I said, if they liked it at the price; the old woman said 4 s. is too much: I said it is 4 s. 3 d. the young woman said, it is so; they stood just by the piles of handkerchiefs, which were in four rows: I stood facing them: the old woman gave me 5 s. I put up the handkerchief, and I returned her 9 d. and away they went. In about ten minutes after they were gone, I took the loose handkerchiefs up, and found the board was cleared of one row, about a yard in length; I could not tell what I had miss'd, till the next morning: the first pattern I miss'd was a piece of fine blue borders, twenty-one handkerchiefs; I miss'd about a dozen or fifteen of red and white, then three parcels of another pattern of red and white, of what we call spoiled work, they were not cleared at the printers. I lost more, that I cannot describe, having such a great quantity. I went to Mr. Fielding, for his advice: he advised me to advertise; I did, and printed some hand-bills, and sent them to the pawnbrokers. One of my men told me, that Field-lane was a great place for handkerchiefs, and such things: I sent both my men there, they saw two parcels at Mrs. Taylor's, and bought each of them a handkerchief. The gentlewoman having seen the advertisement, went to Mr. Fielding with the handkerchiefs: when I came there, to get a search-warrant, she was there, and said she bought them of the three prisoners at the bar; this was on the Saturday morning, (several pieces of handkerchiefs produced in court, some good and some spoiled work. He takes up two parcels) I am sure these two parcels were in my shop, when the prisoners were in my shop; they are my property. Mrs. Taylor told us where the prisoners lodged, by Hicks's-hall. When we came there, they had quitted their lodging about a fortnight before, in the night: Mrs. Taylor told us they had sold some more to a person in Field-lane, and were to come there again in the evening; she got a constable, and took the two women, the man got away; then she sent for me: I went to them; they had them at a public house going down Holbourn-hill; I knew them to be the same people. I charged them with having robbed me; they pretended they knew nothing of me; they were sent to the counter: the man going to the constable's house, to ask what they had done with his mother and wife, the constable secured him, and took him to the counter, and on Monday I had them all three before my Lord Mayor, and swore to my goods. I have not found any more of them. Here are twenty handkerchiefs of what we call spoiled work, and I have the other half-piece at home, belonging to one of these. The man told my Lord Mayor, that he lodged at the house of one Magennis, the George, in Broad St. Giles's; but when he came there, we found he did not, nor ever did.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you say the women stood?</p>
               <p>Greenfield. They stood just by the door, coming in.</p>
               <p>Q. Whereabouts is your house?</p>
               <p>Greenfield. At the corner of Mitre-court, Fleetstreet.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had the women been in, before the man came in?</p>
               <p>Greenfield. He came in about three or four minutes after them.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he at the same counter they were at, or the other?</p>
               <p>Greenfield. He was at the same counter, but farther up.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he abide long in your shop?</p>
               <p>Greenfield. He did not stay long; but it is possible the women might give him some of the handkerchiefs as he came out.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it possible he could conceal them from your seeing them?</p>
               <p>Greenfield. They will lie in a little room; I have pieces of handkerchiefs that cost ten guineas a-piece; you may put two pieces of them in one pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. You say the women went out, and returned again; had you missed any before they came in again?</p>
               <p>Greenfield. No, I had not; they were covered with light goods.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you miss the goods before or after the the gentlewoman who was in your shop went away?</p>
               <p>Greenfield. I missed them after she went away.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you miss your goods before Mr. Pelteroe went away?</p>
               <p>Greenfield. No, I did not, till after he was gone.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176502270016"></xptr>Q. Did you observe the women, when they went away?</p>
               <p>Greenfield. No, I did not; neither did I observe which way they went: I could not see the bottom part of them for the piles of handkerchiefs that were between us.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think they could be taken away in their aprons?</p>
               <p>Greenfield. I think one apron could take away three times as much.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you imagine they could take away such a quantity?</p>
               <p>Greenfield. As they lay piled up, one hand could sweep them all into an apron; I could see their faces, but could not see their hands; the piles of handkerchiefs were breast-high.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650227-23-person227">
                  Catharine 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17650227-23-person227" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person227" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person227" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Field-lane, and sell linen handkerchiefs, cheques, and old cloaths; I deal with hawkers; I have dealt with the prisoners at the bar ever since the 13th or 14th of December last: they came sometimes with wallets, and sometimes bundles under their arms: they brought large quantities of goods; they usually brought silk and cotton: I never saw them have linen, till these two parcels I bought on the 7th of February.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day did they come to your shop?</p>
               <p>Taylor. It might be about five in the afternoon. They were all three in company; they asked me as usual if I wanted any thing; they said they had some very handsome blue-bordered ones; (the prosecutor produced a handkerchief with a blue border) they were like this; but I said they were too fine for me.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Such I missed.</p>
               <p>Taylor. I bought a dozen of handkerchiefs, fancy-grounds, or mosaic; my man came in, and bid them money for some damaged ones; they would not take his money; they went away, and called the next day, and asked if he would advance any thing more; I said I did not care whether I had them or not. Then they took the money he bid, and I paid them: I gave them 18 s. a dozen for the first parcel, and 14 s. a dozen for the damaged ones, and hung some of them out in the street for sale. The prosecutor's two men came and bought each a handkerchief; our people said they behaved very comically: I was then afraid there was something amiss, and my man read of such goods being stolen in the Advertiser. I went to Mr. Fielding's with them; the gentleman came there, and said he believed they were his goods, (these are the same here produced); then I was ordered to take up the people that brought them. I had taken a receipt of them the first time I bought of them, and at that time I asked who they served besides me: the man named four shops; we enquired at the places where they said they lived, and Mr. Fielding's man and my man went to the places where they had lived. I was afterwards going up Holbourn, I met the two women above Turnstile; I made a full stop; I thought they seemed to shun me: I asked them if they had any more handkerchiefs to sell; they said they had none with them: said I, Can you go home and fetch some, and the wife that is big with child may stay at my house the while. Then they went faster, and I could not follow them so fast: I called out for people to stop them; they ran up a place, and were taken, and brought to my house, and charged with a constable. Two or three hours after that the man came to another house in the lane, and said Mrs. Taylor had taken up his wife, and he would ruin her. When he came to my house, and asked where his wife was, I said, she is in one of the counters; my man went with him to the constable, and the constable took him in custody, and carried him to his wife: then we sent to Mr. Greenfield to come; he came, and said they were the same persons.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you take the prisoners to be?</p>
               <p>Taylor. I took them to be hawkers: sometimes the man had a pack over his shoulders, and sometimes under his arm.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they all together when you bought the things?</p>
               <p>Taylor. They were.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any thing particular in these handkerchiefs?</p>
               <p>Taylor. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any licence they had?</p>
               <p>Taylor. No, I never did: they always told me they dealt in Spital-fields.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650227-23-person228">
                  John 
                  Carroll 
               <interp inst="t17650227-23-person228" type="surname" value="Carroll"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person228" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Defence.</p>
               <p>I used to deal in these things; I go down to the water-side, and buy handkerchiefs, sometimes good, sometimes bad; I bought these handkerchiefs, but cannot prove where I bought them: I had them of a Scotch pedlar, who was going to his own country: this woman here by me is my wife.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176502270017"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17650227-23-person229">
                  Mary
               <interp inst="t17650227-23-person229" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person229" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the wife's Defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing at all about them; I never was in the prosecutor's shop in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650227-23-person230">
                  Mary 
                  Carroll 
               <interp inst="t17650227-23-person230" type="surname" value="Carroll"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person230" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person230" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , widow, her Defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing at all about them; I never was in the prosecutor's shop in my life: I am not this man's mother; I am his sister-in-law.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. This woman told my Lord Mayor she was his mother.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoners.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650227-23-person231">
                  Bridget 
                  Delvin 
               <interp inst="t17650227-23-person231" type="surname" value="Delvin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person231" type="given" value="Bridget"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person231" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in White-cross-street; I know the three prisoners.</p>
               <p>Q. What is their general character?</p>
               <p>Delvin. I never heard any bad of them; they get their living by dealing in handkerchiefs and other goods, which they buy by the water-side: the man and his wife lodged with me about two years; the mother lives in the country.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650227-23-person232">
                  Ann 
                  Field 
               <interp inst="t17650227-23-person232" type="surname" value="Field"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person232" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person232" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known all three of them going on four years: they have very good characters; they get their living by dealing by the water-side, in buying damaged goods.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. What sort of a handkerchief did the man buy of you?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. He bought a blue paste-work one, two different patterns.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of one did the woman buy?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. That was a striped silk one.</p>
               <p>Q. Were either of these of a particular sort?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No.</p>
               <p>Q. What are those handkerchiefs worth, for which Mrs. Taylor gave 14 s. a dozen?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Being damaged work, I bought them at 18 s. a dozen.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650227-23-person233">
                  John 
                  Carroll 
               <interp inst="t17650227-23-person233" type="surname" value="Carroll"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person233" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17650227-23-person234">
                  Mary 
                  Carroll 
               <interp inst="t17650227-23-person234" type="surname" value="Carroll"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person234" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person234" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , widow, <rs id="t17650227-23-verdict132" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-verdict132" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-verdict132" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               Guilty of stealing, but not privately in the shop
            </rs>. <rs id="t17650227-23-punish133" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-punish133" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-23-defend221 t17650227-23-punish133"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-23-defend223 t17650227-23-punish133"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Mary Carroll, the wife, <rs id="t17650227-23-verdict134" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-verdict134" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>(M.) They were all three a second time indicted for <rs id="t17650227-23-off135" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-off135" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-off135" type="offenceSubcategory" value="shoplifting"></interp>
               stealing 36 silk handkerchiefs, value 6 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17650227-23-victim236" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Cook 
                        <interp inst="t17650227-23-victim236" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650227-23-victim236" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650227-23-victim236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately in the shop of the said John
            </rs>, <rs id="t17650227-23-cd136" type="crimeDate">Feb. 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-23-off128 t17650227-23-cd136"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-23-off135 t17650227-23-cd136"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650227-23-person237">
                  Francis 
                  Harding 
               <interp inst="t17650227-23-person237" type="surname" value="Harding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person237" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person237" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mr. 
               <persName id="t17650227-23-person238">
                  John 
                  Cook 
               <interp inst="t17650227-23-person238" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person238" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a <rs id="t17650227-23-viclabel137" type="occupation">linen-draper</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-23-victim236 t17650227-23-viclabel137"></join> in <placeName id="t17650227-23-crimeloc138">Holbourn</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17650227-23-crimeloc138" type="placeName" value="Holbourn"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17650227-23-crimeloc138" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-23-off128 t17650227-23-crimeloc138"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-23-off135 t17650227-23-crimeloc138"></join>; the two women at the bar came into our shop, and asked to look at some long lawns, on the 8th of February, I believe, between four and five in the afternoon. I shewed them some; they took it to the door to look at it; as they were looking at it a man came in, but I cannot swear to him. About two hours before, we had six dozen of silk handkerchiefs just came in from the weaver's: I had examined them, and they were lying on the counter, on the right side going in, two or three yards from the door. The man asked to look at a handkerchief, but I did not serve him; the man is here that did; I attended upon the two women.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the man take any notice of the woman?</p>
               <p>Harding. No, he did not. The women took the long-lawn, and threw it over the silk handkerchiefs at the door: I took it from that side to the other counter, and sold them a yard and a half: then they asked to look at some silk handkerchiefs; I shewed them some, a parcel that lay in the window, and sold them one out of that parcel: then the women went away; I missed afterwards two dozen; that parcel was not opened while the man was in the shop; I missed one dozen from the other parcel, the eight dozen, that had been come in but a little before: this was on the Friday, and we did not examine the parcel: I sold none out of it, till the Monday following. We went directly to Sir 
               <persName id="t17650227-23-person239">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17650227-23-person239" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person239" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , upon missing the two dozen, and had them advertised: on the Saturday, we found three handkerchiefs, of the same pattern and sort of the two dozen, at Mrs. Hatton's, in Field-lane; I cannot swear positive to them: the person that made them, says he had not made that pattern above two months: betwixt the time of the prisoner's buying that handkerchief, and the time we missed them, we had not shewed that parcel the dozen were stole out of: they lay tied up.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650227-23-person240">
                  Betty 
                  Hatton 
               <interp inst="t17650227-23-person240" type="surname" value="Hatton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person240" type="given" value="Betty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person240" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a cloaths-shop, in Field-lane. I bought those three handkerchiefs of the prisoner at the bar: there was a piece of it; I have sold all the rest.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you buy the piece?</p>
               <p>Hatton. On Friday the 8th of this instant February, when it was just dusk: the three prisoners were frequently at my house, with goods under their arms, as Hawkers; they had great quantities sometimes, of all manner of sorts.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see any licence they had?</p>
               <p>Hatton. No, I never asked them to see it; the man said he was a Spitalfields-weaver, and lived at the Golden-hall there: these three handkerchiefs, here produced, are part of the piece I bought of them.</p>
               <p>Mr. Boaker. I live with Mr. Cook, in Holbourn. On Friday, the 8th of February, between four and five, the prisoner, 
               <persName id="t17650227-23-person241">
                  John 
                  Carroll 
               <interp inst="t17650227-23-person241" type="surname" value="Carroll"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person241" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , came into our shop, and desired to look at a pocket handkerchief: I shewed him one of those eight dozen of handkerchiefs, which came in that afternoon,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176502270018"></xptr> and lay piled up in two piles. I took down some handkerchiefs from another place to shew him; he took and pulled them towards the window, and covered the silk handkerchiefs with them: upon examining the selvage, my mistress happened to be looking at him: Madam, said he, will they wash well? yes, said she. He asked the price; I said 15 d. he said they were too dear. I said, I had some cheaper; he said he would look at them, he did, and said they would not do at all. At last, he bough t one of the other, at 14 d. when he was gone, I went to put the handkerchiefs up; there was no more than seven dozen; this was not half an hour after I had counted them before: we advertised them, and described the man at the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. to Hatton. What relation did the woman pass for, to the man?</p>
               <p>Hatton. One passed for his wife, and the other for his brother's wife.</p>
               <p>Q. to Boaker. Were there any women in the shop, when the man bought the handkerchiefs?</p>
               <p>Boaker. There were two women in the shop at the time, but I took no notice of them; neither of their coming in, or going out.</p>
               <p>John Carroll's Defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing about the affair; I never was in the prosecutor's shop in my life.</p>
               <p>Mary his wife's Defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing about it; the woman came to me and said, if I was in any danger, she could hide the handkerchiefs: I said, you need not be afraid, I bought them very honestly.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650227-23-person242">
                  Mary 
                  Carroll 
               <interp inst="t17650227-23-person242" type="surname" value="Carroll"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person242" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person242" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , widow, her Defence.</p>
               <p>I never was in the prosecutor's shop in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650227-23-person243">
                  John 
                  Carroll 
               <interp inst="t17650227-23-person243" type="surname" value="Carroll"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person243" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person243" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17650227-23-person244">
                  Mary 
                  Carroll 
               <interp inst="t17650227-23-person244" type="surname" value="Carroll"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person244" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-person244" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , widow, <rs id="t17650227-23-verdict139" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-verdict139" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-verdict139" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               guilty of stealing, but not privately in the shop.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>Mary, the wife, <rs id="t17650227-23-verdict140" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650227-23-verdict140" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
