<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17600910-8">
               <interp inst="t17600910-8" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600910-8" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600910-8" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600910"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600910-8" type="date" value="17600910"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600910-8-off40-c82" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-8-defend109 t17600910-8-off40 t17600910-8-verdict44"></join>
         
               <p>250. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17600910-8-defend109" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Walker 
                  <interp inst="t17600910-8-defend109" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-8-defend109" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-8-defend109" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17600910-8-off40" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600910-8-off40" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-8-off40" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one serge waistcoat, value 4 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17600910-8-victim111" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Flavel 
                  <interp inst="t17600910-8-victim111" type="surname" value="Flavel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-8-victim111" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-8-victim111" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-8-off40 t17600910-8-victim111"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17600910-8-cd41" type="crimeDate">August 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-8-off40 t17600910-8-cd41"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600910-8-person112">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Druit 
               <interp inst="t17600910-8-person112" type="surname" value="Druit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-8-person112" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-8-person112" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Flavel is <rs id="t17600910-8-viclabel42" type="occupation">a master slopper</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-8-victim111 t17600910-8-viclabel42"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. What is that?</p>
               <p>E. Druit. <rs id="t17600910-8-viclabel43" type="occupation">He keeps a slop-shop for seamen</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-8-victim111 t17600910-8-viclabel43"></join>, he gives me out work at the first hand, and I imploy people under me; I imploy'd the prisoner to make serge work, or any thing I had to do (she produc'd the serge waistcoat) this I had of Mr. Flavel, it is his property, I did not know that the prisoner had this waistcoat, or that it was out of my house, till I catched the prisoner a making of it.</p>
               <p>Q Did she work at your house?</p>
               <p>E. Druit. She did with me.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you find it?</p>
               <p>E. Druit. I found it upon her in her own room where she lodg'd, and Mrs. Anderson found the lining to it between the bed and the sacking.</p>
               <p>Q Did you give her authority to carry this out of your house?</p>
               <p>E. Druit. No; she had no authority for that.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to go to her lodgings?</p>
               <p>E. Druit. I had given her a waistcoat to make, and I went after that.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say when you found it upon her?</p>
               <p>E. Druit. She said, she took it to make a present of it to a man that she kept company with. She said she would clear the man, for she took it, and made him a present of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600910-8-person113">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Anderson 
               <interp inst="t17600910-8-person113" type="surname" value="Anderson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-8-person113" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-8-person113" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 17th of the last month Mrs. Druit my Mrs. whom I work'd for eleven years, came and got me to go to see what I could get out of the prisoner, about some work she had lost; I went into the prisoner's room at unaware to her; she was at work upon the sleeves to this waistcoat; I said, that is my Mrs's waistcoat; she got up and lock'd the door, thinking somebody else was coming; I took one of the sleeves, and throw'd it out of the window to my Mrs. then she opened the door, and let my Mrs. in.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear her confess any thing?</p>
               <p>E. Anderson. I heard her own before the justice she took this waistcoat without her mistress's leave; I found the lining to the waistcoat hid under the prisoner's bed.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>Last monday was 5 weeks I went to the prosecutrix's house for work, my child was sick, and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176009100007"></xptr> I us'd to work at her house, but I had then work from her at home, and I staid at home on the monday to wash my cloaths; she had given me a waistcoat to make, she measured 5 yards of binding, I took and wrapp'd that about it; I ask'd her to lend me some money; she said she had no change; I went to the sign of the king of Prussia's head joining to her house, and got 2 sixpences for a shilling; I had laid my parcel on a bench at the door, then I took it and went home; and when I came to open it, instead of one waistcoat there was two; I finished one and carried it home, and she paid me; I kept the other at home to employ me at night, and on saturday mornings I was finishing my work, and when I came home she had a great dispute with her work-women. I said, if you please to give me a waistcoat to do I will be running the lining in; she fetch'd me one; she came about five hours after, and told me I had taken four pieces for the backs of waistcoats; I said I knew nothing of them, and went with her to her house. Then she said, she believed they were left on the back of a chair, and were lost. The sunday after she came again, and the other woman with her, then I was finishing the waistcoat, which came to 13 d. which I made an account to carry home to her; I thought it was a stranger coming up, made me hide the lining under the bed quilt: she said, this is the lining my mistress has lost, and I had robb'd her of it; I said you are an impudent saucy slut, I have not, you shall not risle my room upon a sunday, nor make an uproar. She took the sleeves and threw them out at the window, and said, mistress come up this minute, for here is the waistcoat. I said let your mistress in, I did not know what I said or did; I said, for God's sake Mrs. Druit do not make an uproar; they took the waistcoat, and carried it away by force; and the next morning I went to go to the house, and met a woman that lives in Whitechapel; she said Mrs. Druit has got a warrant against you for stealing a waistcoat, value 8 s. she swore before the justice she never gave me a bit of work home.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutrix. Did you give her any work home?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. Yes; but I did not give her this home.</p>
               <p>A witness. I am the prisoner's sister, Mrs. Druit brought her to my house, and said she had found two waistcoats at her lodgings; she has employ'd her many a sunday, and her child being sick, she gave her work home.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that?</p>
               <p>Witness. Mrs. Druit told me, that she had often given her work home.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say she gave her that waistcoat home?</p>
               <p>Witness No; but she said she had got 2 waistcoats instead of one.</p>
               <p>Q to Mrs. Druit. Do you recollect what the witness has mentioned?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Druit. I told her I was frighted to find a waistcoat upon her sister, that I never knew to be out of my house.</p>
               <p>Q to witness. Upon your oath, did Mrs. Druit say the prisoner had two waistcoats instead of one.</p>
               <p>Witness. Upon my oath she did say so.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Druit. I said I had found a waistcoat upon her, which she was making, and it gives me a great deal of reason to suspect she has got a ready made one that I miss.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600910-8-person114">
                  Mary 
                  Abbot 
               <interp inst="t17600910-8-person114" type="surname" value="Abbot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-8-person114" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-8-person114" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner four years.</p>
               <p>Q What is her general character?</p>
               <p>M. Abbot. I never knew any thing of her but what was very honest, her character was such as far as ever I heard.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600910-8-verdict44" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600910-8-verdict44" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
