<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660219-32">
               <interp inst="t17660219-32" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660219-32" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660219-32" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660219"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660219-32" type="date" value="17660219"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660219-32-off179-c257" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-32-defend334 t17660219-32-off179 t17660219-32-verdict184"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660219-32-off179-c258" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-32-defend336 t17660219-32-off179 t17660219-32-verdict184"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660219-32-off179-c259" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-32-defend338 t17660219-32-off179 t17660219-32-verdict184"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660219-32-off180-c261" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-32-defend342 t17660219-32-off180 t17660219-32-verdict186"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660219-32-off180-c262" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-32-defend344 t17660219-32-off180 t17660219-32-verdict188"></join>
         
               <p>147, 148, 149, 150, 151. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660219-32-defend334" type="defendantName">
                     Matthew 
                     Dun 
                  <interp inst="t17660219-32-defend334" type="surname" value="Dun"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-defend334" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-defend334" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17660219-32-defend336" type="defendantName">
                     Frank 
                     Egar 
                  <interp inst="t17660219-32-defend336" type="surname" value="Egar"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-defend336" type="given" value="Frank"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-defend336" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17660219-32-defend338" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Ash 
                  <interp inst="t17660219-32-defend338" type="surname" value="Ash"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-defend338" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-defend338" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17660219-32-off179" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-off179" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-off179" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 200 weight of cochineal, value 150 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17660219-32-victim340" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Collins 
                  <interp inst="t17660219-32-victim340" type="surname" value="Collins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-victim340" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-victim340" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17660219-32-defend342" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Hodson 
                  <interp inst="t17660219-32-defend342" type="surname" value="Hodson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-defend342" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-defend342" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17660219-32-defend344" type="defendantName">
                     Godfrey William 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17660219-32-defend344" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-defend344" type="given" value="Godfrey William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-defend344" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , for <rs id="t17660219-32-off180" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-off180" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-off180" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving the same, well knowing it to have been stolen
            </rs>, <rs id="t17660219-32-cd181" type="crimeDate">January 11</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-32-off179 t17660219-32-cd181"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-32-off180 t17660219-32-cd181"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660219-32-person345">
                  William 
                  Collins 
               <interp inst="t17660219-32-person345" type="surname" value="Collins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person345" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person345" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I missed a barrel of cochineal on the 11th of last month, in the morning, from out of my ship, called <placeName id="t17660219-32-crimeloc182">the Friendship, lying at West-lane stairs Rotherhithe</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17660219-32-crimeloc182" type="placeName" value="the Friendship, lying at West-lane stairs Rotherhithe"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660219-32-crimeloc182" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-32-off179 t17660219-32-crimeloc182"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-32-off180 t17660219-32-crimeloc182"></join>. I suspected Dun and Ash, they were <rs id="t17660219-32-deflabel183" type="occupation">lumpers</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-32-defend334 t17660219-32-deflabel183"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-32-defend338 t17660219-32-deflabel183"></join> on board; that is to assist in getting goods out: I had them taken<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176602190019"></xptr> up and carried before Sir 
               <persName id="t17660219-32-person346">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17660219-32-person346" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person346" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person346" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , for want of proper proof they were at that time acquitted. After this there was some all-spice carried to Smith's house. I went to Justice Cox's at their examination, expecting something of this might transpire; there a person that draws beer at 
               <persName id="t17660219-32-person347">
                  Godfry 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17660219-32-person347" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person347" type="given" value="Godfry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person347" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, named Dyke, told me the cochineal was brought to his house by Egar and Ash, and told me the waterman was named Beck, that brought it on shore. I went and brought Beck before the Justice, and he declared the same, and swore against all the prisoners at the bar; I got a search-warrant, and searched Smith's house, this was I believe the 12th of January, but I found nothing. I have not seen my cochineal since.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you seen it last?</p>
               <p>Collins. It was seen every day by my mate and my men. It was marked upon the barrel J. R. I must be answerable for it to the owner.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How many gallons, suppose the barrel was liquid measure, would it hold?</p>
               <p>Collins. It held upwards of forty gallons, it was larger than a cask of wine; it was worth about 14 s. and 6 d. a pound.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see it last?</p>
               <p>Collins. I saw it about a week before it was lost.</p>
               <p>Q. The prisoners did not confess any thing, did they?</p>
               <p>Collins. They did, Dun, Egar, and Ash, confest it before the Justice, that they stole it, and that they were set on by bad people.</p>
               <p>Q. What were their words as near as you can recollect?</p>
               <p>Collins. They declared they brought it on shore, and sold it to Hodson, and he paid them 21 l. 5 s. for it. Egar said he carried it, Dun declared at the same time, he had not got all his dividend of Hodson yet.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660219-32-person348">
                  Bartholomew 
                  Mead 
               <interp inst="t17660219-32-person348" type="surname" value="Mead"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person348" type="given" value="Bartholomew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person348" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am mate of the Friendship. I saw the barrel of cochineal that evening, before it was taken away in the night: early the next morning I found the hatches unlaid, and the tackle hanging over the ship side. I immediately went down and missed the cochineal, which lay forward the night before between decks.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660219-32-person349">
                  William 
                  Dyke 
               <interp inst="t17660219-32-person349" type="surname" value="Dyke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person349" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person349" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am turned of 14 years of age. I lived with Mr. Smith, the prisoner; he keeps a public house, I drawed beer: Dun, Ash, and Egar, brought a cask of cochineal to our house.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know it was cochineal?</p>
               <p>Dyke. Because I heard them talk of it, I saw the cask.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see it open?</p>
               <p>Dyke. I did, and it was in a bag.</p>
               <p>Q. to Collins. Was it in a bag in the barrel?</p>
               <p>Collins. It was in one bag.</p>
               <p>Q. to Dyke. What colour was it?</p>
               <p>Dyke. It was like powder almost, it was blackish.</p>
               <p>Collins. It is of a dark brown.</p>
               <p>Dyke. They turned up the cask and shook the bag out, and I never saw it afterwards; I do not know what was done with it.</p>
               <p>Q. What part of the house was this in?</p>
               <p>Dyke. This was in the entry by the parlour.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is it ago?</p>
               <p>Dyke. It is about a couple of months ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it before, or after Christmas?</p>
               <p>Dyke. It was after Christmas?</p>
               <p>Q. What time was it of the day or night?</p>
               <p>Dyke. It was about one or two o'clock in the morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Who were by at the time?</p>
               <p>Dyke. There were Dun, Egar, Ash, my master 
               <persName id="t17660219-32-person350">
                  Godfrey 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17660219-32-person350" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person350" type="given" value="Godfrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person350" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17660219-32-person351">
                  Beck
               <interp inst="t17660219-32-person351" type="given" value="Beck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person351" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a waterman.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the waterman before?</p>
               <p>Dyke. I did, he had used our house in drinking beer.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of the cask after the stuff was taken out?</p>
               <p>Dyke. That was broke up, and burnt in our parlour.</p>
               <p>Q. Who broke it?</p>
               <p>Dyke. My master did.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there fire in your parlour at that time of night?</p>
               <p>Dyke. There was a little one.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Has your master a great many customers at different times come to your house?</p>
               <p>Dyke. He has.</p>
               <p>Q. Are there not stairs to the water?</p>
               <p>Dyke. There are.</p>
               <p>Q. Are not different goods landed there?</p>
               <p>Dyke. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you lived with your master?</p>
               <p>Dyke. I have lived with him 16 months.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you and your master ever quarrelled?</p>
               <p>Dyke. He has sometimes beat me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever threaten to be revenged of him?</p>
               <p>Dyke. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. What was said to you before the Justice?</p>
               <p>Dyke. They said they would hang me if I did not become an evidence against my master; that<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176602190020"></xptr> was if I did not tell what I knew about the cochineal.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660219-32-person352">
                  William 
                  Beck 
               <interp inst="t17660219-32-person352" type="surname" value="Beck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person352" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person352" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a waterman, and ply at Wapping New stairs. About a month and a half ago, I don't know the particular night,) I was employed by Ash, Dun, and Egar, to go on board the ship belonging to Captain Collins, lying at West lane, by Rotherhithe. I have since known her to be the Friendship; I stood in my boat, and they hunted a vessel out of that ship into my boat. I rowed on shore at Mr. Smith's back door, and there landed it, and carried it into his house: then the stuff was taken out of the vessel, and conveyed away.</p>
               <p>Q. Who took it out?</p>
               <p>Beck. We did among us.</p>
               <p>Q. What is Smith?</p>
               <p>Beck. He keeps a public house, his back door comes to the shore.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Smith at the time?</p>
               <p>Beck. I did, he did not meddle with any thing; he was sitting by his fire in the kitchen, the vessel was rolled in just by the kitchen door; the back door was left open.</p>
               <p>Q. What was in the cask?</p>
               <p>Beck. They said it was cochineal.</p>
               <p>Q. Which of them said so?</p>
               <p>Beck. They all said so, one among another.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any money talked of?</p>
               <p>Beck. They were to have 85 l. for it.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that?</p>
               <p>Beck. I was concerned in it, we were to have it among us; Hodson was to pay it, he was there, and it was conveyed out of the house by him: he went out of the house while I was sitting in the kitchen. We had a guinea each of us that night, Hodson paid it us.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the sign Smith keeps?</p>
               <p>Beck. It is the King's Arms. Some time after that, we four, Dun, Egar, Ash, and I, had 10 guineas each paid us by Hodson.</p>
               <p>Q. What business is Hodson?</p>
               <p>Beck. I don't know, he uses that house.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after you conveyed the vessel there was it that you each received the 10 guineas?</p>
               <p>Beck. I believe it was about three weeks after, I received mine in the same house, at the King's Arms; Egar received his 10 guineas at the same time, then he married my sister: the other two were then on board a ship, but I heard them say they received theirs also; and last Saturday night I received 8 guineas more of Hodson, that was the last dividend.</p>
               <p>Q. to Collins. When were the prisoners taken up?</p>
               <p>Collins. They were taken up last Sunday morning. Beck, Dun, and Egar, received their eight guineas each; but Ash has not received his.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Smith act any part in it?</p>
               <p>Beck. He brought us liquor, and was about in the house; I don't know that he had any concern in it.</p>
               <p>Q. to Dyke. Did you see Hodson in the house that night.</p>
               <p>Dyke. Hodson was there; he went home with the bag.</p>
               <p>Q. to Beck. What was done with the vessel?</p>
               <p>Beck. That was burnt in the parlour fire, because it should not be found out.</p>
               <p>Dun's Defence.</p>
               <p>On Sunday morning I went to look for work on board this ship; the mate employ'd Ash and me, and worked sometimes half a day, and we were taken up on the Monday morning following, we were examined and cleared; I know no more of the thing than the child unborn.</p>
               <p>Egar's defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing about it; I should not know the ship was I to see her.</p>
               <p>Ash's defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing of the matter.</p>
               <p>Hodson's defence.</p>
               <p>I can't help it if they have a mind to swear against an innocent man; I know nothing of it: I did keep a coal-shed, and used to deal in stockings.</p>
               <p>Smith's defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing at all of the story that has been told; if such a thing came in, it was without my knowledge; it is a common landing place; there are a great many vessels come broken from on board, and lying about the yard; we sometimes throw them into the fire, many things are brought on shore to my house.</p>
               <p>For Hodson and Smith.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660219-32-person353">
                  David 
                  Roberts 
               <interp inst="t17660219-32-person353" type="surname" value="Roberts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person353" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person353" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a king's officer, I belong to the Excise; I have been acquainted with Smith between four and five years, I survey his house, and am often there; he has a very fair character; I have inspected all parts of his house, I never found any such things; he keeps a reputable house. I know Hodson by his being there, he keeps a sort of a coal-shed, and deals in stockings. I know nothing of his character.</p>
               <p>Jos. Towlson. I know Smith, he has an exceeding good character. I have been acquainted with Hodson two or three years; I never heard<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176602190021"></xptr> any thing bad of him, but that of a good character. I have a particular reason for knowing Smith's character; I was once inclined to take him into partnership, and I inquired his character, and found it an exceeding good one.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660219-32-person354">
                  Diederick 
                  Peckerson 
               <interp inst="t17660219-32-person354" type="surname" value="Peckerson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person354" type="given" value="Diederick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person354" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Smith 17 years: he always bore a very honest character.</p>
               <p>John Hill. I am a cooper in Shadwell; I have known Smith 4 or 5 years: he is a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660219-32-person355">
                  John 
                  Dolby 
               <interp inst="t17660219-32-person355" type="surname" value="Dolby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person355" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person355" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who had known Smith 14 or 15 years, 
               <persName id="t17660219-32-person356">
                  George 
                  Shadow 
               <interp inst="t17660219-32-person356" type="surname" value="Shadow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person356" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person356" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             9, 
               <persName id="t17660219-32-person357">
                  Thomas 
                  Freck 
               <interp inst="t17660219-32-person357" type="surname" value="Freck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person357" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person357" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             10, 
               <persName id="t17660219-32-person358">
                  Nicholas 
                  Adams 
               <interp inst="t17660219-32-person358" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person358" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person358" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             23, 
               <persName id="t17660219-32-person359">
                  William 
                  Lincoln 
               <interp inst="t17660219-32-person359" type="surname" value="Lincoln"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person359" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person359" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             8 or 9, 
               <persName id="t17660219-32-person360">
                  Edward 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17660219-32-person360" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person360" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person360" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             2 or 3, 
               <persName id="t17660219-32-person361">
                  George 
                  Waltishbank 
               <interp inst="t17660219-32-person361" type="surname" value="Waltishbank"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person361" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person361" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             7, and 
               <persName id="t17660219-32-person362">
                  Thomas 
                  Pike 
               <interp inst="t17660219-32-person362" type="surname" value="Pike"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person362" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person362" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             several years, gave him a good character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660219-32-person363">
                  Alexander 
                  Mackintosh 
               <interp inst="t17660219-32-person363" type="surname" value="Mackintosh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person363" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person363" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who had known Hodson 12 months, and 
               <persName id="t17660219-32-person364">
                  Thomas 
                  Cooper 
               <interp inst="t17660219-32-person364" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person364" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-person364" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             7 years, gave him a good character.</p>
               <p>Dunn, Egar, and Ash, <rs id="t17660219-32-verdict184" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-verdict184" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17660219-32-punish185" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-punish185" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-32-defend334 t17660219-32-punish185"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-32-defend336 t17660219-32-punish185"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-32-defend338 t17660219-32-punish185"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Hodson <rs id="t17660219-32-verdict186" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-verdict186" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17660219-32-punish187" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-punish187" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-32-defend342 t17660219-32-punish187"></join>
               T. 14
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Smith <rs id="t17660219-32-verdict188" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660219-32-verdict188" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>. He was detained on another affair.</p>
            </div1>
