<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17661217-55">
               <interp inst="t17661217-55" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-55" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-55" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17661217"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-55" type="date" value="17661217"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17661217-55-off280-c471" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-55-defend593 t17661217-55-off280 t17661217-55-verdict287"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17661217-55-off281-c474" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-55-defend599 t17661217-55-off281 t17661217-55-verdict289"></join>
         
               <p>68, 69 (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17661217-55-defend593" type="defendantName">
                     David 
                     Atchinson 
                  <interp inst="t17661217-55-defend593" type="surname" value="Atchinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-defend593" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-defend593" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             was indicted for <rs id="t17661217-55-off280" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-off280" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-off280" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 33 yards of linen-cloth, value 33 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17661217-55-victim595" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Story 
                  <interp inst="t17661217-55-victim595" type="surname" value="Story"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-victim595" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-victim595" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17661217-55-victim597" type="victimName">
                     Christopher 
                     Alderson 
                  <interp inst="t17661217-55-victim597" type="surname" value="Alderson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-victim597" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-victim597" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            ; and 
               
                  <persName id="t17661217-55-defend599" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Faulkner 
                  <interp inst="t17661217-55-defend599" type="surname" value="Faulkner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-defend599" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-defend599" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             for <rs id="t17661217-55-off281" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-off281" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-off281" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving the same, well knowing it to have been stolen
            </rs>, <rs id="t17661217-55-cd282" type="crimeDate">Oct. 25</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-55-off280 t17661217-55-cd282"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-55-off281 t17661217-55-cd282"></join>. +</p>
               <p>Christ. Alderson. 
               <persName id="t17661217-55-person600">
                  John 
                  Story 
               <interp inst="t17661217-55-person600" type="surname" value="Story"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-person600" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-person600" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and I are partners; we <rs id="t17661217-55-viclabel283" type="occupation">keep a warehouse</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-55-victim595 t17661217-55-viclabel283"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-55-victim597 t17661217-55-viclabel283"></join> in <placeName id="t17661217-55-crimeloc284">Laurence-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17661217-55-crimeloc284" type="placeName" value="Laurence-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17661217-55-crimeloc284" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-55-off280 t17661217-55-crimeloc284"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-55-off281 t17661217-55-crimeloc284"></join>; we <rs id="t17661217-55-viclabel285" type="occupation">sell worsted goods wholesail</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-55-victim595 t17661217-55-viclabel285"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-55-victim597 t17661217-55-viclabel285"></join>; I was informed on Saturday night the 25th of Oct. by 
               <persName id="t17661217-55-person601">
                  George 
                  Cape 
               <interp inst="t17661217-55-person601" type="surname" value="Cape"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-person601" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-person601" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             one of our clerks, that he had that evening discovered a piece of hessian secreted in the house, and that he believed it was taken away by Atchinson; he was <rs id="t17661217-55-deflabel286" type="occupation">a porter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-55-defend593 t17661217-55-deflabel286"></join> of ours: when Atchinson came to work on the Monday, we called him up stairs, and asked him how he came to take away a piece of hessian on the Saturday night; he at first denied he did take any away; but, upon telling him we had proof of it, he confessed the fact, and begged we would forgive him, and said he would get the piece again; he said it was at a neighbour's, near where he lives, near Aldersgate-street; we asked him the person's name where it was, which he seemed very averse to telling us; we insisted upon knowing; he then said he had sold it the same night, to one Mr. Faulkner, who lived near Queenhithe; I asked him what business Mr. Faulkner was; he said he dealt in linen, and old wrappers. I asked him what he sold it for; he said for half a guinea; (it cost us a guinea) we got a search-warrant, and went to Mr. Faulkner's on the Tuesday morning; he keeps a little shop; there appeared to be several bags of cotton or wool, I cannot tell properly what shop to call it; it is in Black-Swan-alley, at the bottom of Garlick-hill; we met with Mr. Faulkner; I told him I was informed, he had bought a piece of hessian, that was stolen from us the Saturday night before; he said there was a piece brought to him on the Saturday night, but he did not buy it; he only advanced 14 s. upon it; I asked him to let me see the piece; he stepped backwards and brought it; I looked at it, and saw it was marked with the same mark, as other hessians are that we had by us, the maker's mark; ( a piece produced in court) I believe this to be ours, but I cannot positively swear to it; then I ordered the constable to serve the warrant upon him, and he was taken before the Alderman at Guildhall; then he said he advanced 14 s. upon it; the other prisoner declared he sold it him for 14 s. before Mr. Faulkner's face; Faulkner said he knew Atchinson was our servant, and that he had sold him ropes for our use; we make use of ropes in putting them round cases and bails.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had Atchinson lived with you?</p>
               <p>Alderson He lived with us four or five years, and I looked upon him as to be as honest a man as any in the house.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not see ropes in Faulkner's shop?</p>
               <p>Alderson. I did not see a rope there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he immediately produce the piece upon your asking him to see it?</p>
               <p>Alderson. He did; but stopped a few paces back, and took it out of a place, which I thought was a place of concealment.</p>
               <p>Mr. Bagley. I served the warrant on the 28th of October. Mr. Alderson and his man went with me; Mr. Alderson asked Mr. Faulkner, if he had not bought a piece of hessian-cloth on the Saturday night; he answered, no, he had not bought it, but your man brought a piece here, and told me he bought it for his own family's use, and desired me to lend him so much money upon it, which he said he did, I think it was 14 s. he said this is the piece, and took it from off a half sack of cotton, and laid it before him, and said, I expected him here before now, to come to fetch it away; Mr. Alderson looked at the piece, and desired I would serve the warrant; I told Mr. Faulkner he was my prisoner; he said he would find bail: Mr. Alderson went away; then we went to Guildhall and had a hearing; but I was on the outside the door, and did not hear what passed.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What does Mr. Faulkner deal in?</p>
               <p>Bagley. He deals in cottons, and has it spun in the country; he serves tallow-chandlers and lamp-lighters with cotton-yarn.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he a man of credit?</p>
               <p>Bagley. I am pretty sure he is trusted with thousands, and tens of thousands of pounds worth of goods.</p>
               <p>Q. What were the words Mr. Alderson made use of?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176612170048"></xptr>Bagley. When I looked into the body of the warrant at the alehouse, I said, God bless me, I have known the man 12 years; well, said he, if he is an honest man, he will give us the piece without making us search for it, and he gave us the piece without any hesitation.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-55-person602">
                  George 
                  Cape 
               <interp inst="t17661217-55-person602" type="surname" value="Cape"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-person602" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-person602" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Alderson; I was going down stairs, and behind a bit of a board I saw a parcel tied up; I took it out, and saw it was a piece of brown hessian; I put it in the same place again; after that I went into the warehouse, and staid there; and after the prisoner and other porter came in, I walked backwards and forwards in the warehouse; then I went up stairs, and left them together; in a little time I thought I would go and see whether the piece lay where it did before, I went and found it was gone.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you been absent?</p>
               <p>Cape. I had been absent about a quarter of an hour; then I went in order to tell Mr. Alderson, but he was not in the way, but I told him afterwards.</p>
               <p>Atchinson said nothing in his defence.</p>
               <p>Faulkner's defence.</p>
               <p>I did not know it to have been stolen; Atchinson brought down the bundle of linen, tied up in a piece of paper, about seven at night; he desired me to walk backwards with him; he said I am very short of money at present, I wish you would lend me 15 s. I said, what security can I have for it; said he, if you are afraid of your money I'll leave this piece; I put my hand in my pocket, and had no more than 14 s. which I very readily gave him.</p>
               <p>To their characters.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-55-person603">
                  William
               <interp inst="t17661217-55-person603" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-person603" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             M'Moran. I have known Atkinson about seven years, he bears the best of characters; he has a large small family, living only upon the donation of the charitable, since he was in confinement.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-55-person604">
                  Richard 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17661217-55-person604" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-person604" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-person604" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I believe I have known him six or seven years; when he first came to London, he worked for me pretty near 12 months; he kept himself sober, and attended his hours at labour; after that he was porter to Sir 
               <persName id="t17661217-55-person605">
                  Richard 
                  Glyn 
               <interp inst="t17661217-55-person605" type="surname" value="Glyn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-person605" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-person605" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and after that he came to the prosecutors; they asked me some questions about his character, I gave him a good one, which he deserved, and no better.</p>
               <p>Q. What character can you give him now?</p>
               <p>Wood. He behaved in general as an honest man; I have so good an opinion of him, was he clear, I would take him into my service; I never heard any ill of him till this affair.</p>
               <p>Mr. Baskerville. The prisoner Atchinson worked for me three years ago; he behaved as an honest man.</p>
               <p>For Faulkner.</p>
               <p>George Street I live at Dowgate-hill, and keep a warehouse; the prisoner Faulkner has been in my service seven years; I have trusted him with perhaps ten, twenty, or thirty thousand pounds worth of goods at a time; I trust him with silks, carpets, mohair, yarn, and all that we have that come from Turkey and Leghorn; I never missed any thing since he has been in business by him; he is as honest a man as any in the world; was he to leave me, I would be bound for him for 500 l. as an honest man; I would be very unwilling to part with him; I would give him 10 l. a year more than I do rather than part from him.</p>
               <p>Mr. Walford. I have known Faulkner between eight and nine years, I live in the same parish that he lives in; he bears a very good character. It never was impeached, and the general opinion of him in the neighbourhood now is, that he is an honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-55-person606">
                  John 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17661217-55-person606" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-person606" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-person606" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Laurence-lane, I have known Faulkner three or four years; I am partner with Mr. Murrel, a large dealer in cotton; we trust him with things of great value; within two or three months, we have trusted him with three or four thousand pounds; we look upon him to be a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-55-person607">
                  William 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17661217-55-person607" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-person607" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-person607" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him six or seven years, he was always a very honest man; he has had great trust put in him to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Mr. Greenwood. I have known him about five years, he has a very good character; I never heard the least imputation on his character, he has goods to the amount of several hundred pounds; I believe two thousand pounds at this time, belonging to me; was it ten I should not be in the least doubt about it; he is a very honest, sober, industrious man, a person one can conside in.</p>
               <p>Mr. Downs. I have known him above seven years, he is a very honest industrious man; I never heard the least impeachment on his character; I should have no doubt of trusting him.</p>
               <p>Mr. Shrub. I have known him about eight or nine years; he has as good a character as any man in England; he has had great trust; I would trust him with any thing.</p>
               <p>Atchinson <rs id="t17661217-55-verdict287" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-verdict287" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-verdict287" type="verdictSubcategory" value="withRecommendation"></interp>
               Guilty, Recommended
            </rs>. <rs id="t17661217-55-punish288" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-punish288" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-punish288" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-55-defend593 t17661217-55-punish288"></join>
               B
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Faulkner <rs id="t17661217-55-verdict289" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-55-verdict289" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
