<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610116-3">
               <interp inst="t17610116-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610116-3" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610116-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610116-3" type="date" value="17610116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610116-3-off20-c56" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610116-3-defend63 t17610116-3-off20 t17610116-3-verdict24"></join>
         
               <p>40. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610116-3-defend63" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Urwin 
                  <interp inst="t17610116-3-defend63" type="surname" value="Urwin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610116-3-defend63" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610116-3-defend63" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17610116-3-off20" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610116-3-off20" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610116-3-off20" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he, on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17610116-3-victim65" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Jay 
                        <interp inst="t17610116-3-victim65" type="surname" value="Jay"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610116-3-victim65" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610116-3-victim65" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610116-3-off20 t17610116-3-victim65"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and taking from his person 18 d. his property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17610116-3-cd21" type="crimeDate">Dec. 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610116-3-off20 t17610116-3-cd21"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610116-3-person66">
                  John 
                  Jay 
               <interp inst="t17610116-3-person66" type="surname" value="Jay"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610116-3-person66" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610116-3-person66" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 22d of December last I was going home to Brentford-end on horseback. The prisoner at the bar met me on foot with a musket in his hand, when I was about twenty yards within <placeName id="t17610116-3-crimeloc22">Hyde-park, near the halfway-house</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17610116-3-crimeloc22" type="placeName" value="Hyde-park, near the halfway-house"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610116-3-crimeloc22" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610116-3-off20 t17610116-3-crimeloc22"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was it when he met you?</p>
               <p>Jay. It was about a quarter after four in the afternoon. It was quite daylight. He asked me for my money, and said, necessity drove him to it, and he must have it. I put my hand in my pocket, and gave him 18 d. He said that would not do, he wanted a guinea more. I told him I had not the value of a guinea in my pocket. Then he put up his piece, and cocked it at me, and said, he had a good mind to blow my brains out. I begged of him not to shoot me, saying, that would be of no service to him. Then he said, D - n you, go along.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>Jay. I am a <rs id="t17610116-3-viclabel23" type="occupation">breeches-maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610116-3-victim65 t17610116-3-viclabel23"></join>. After this I went on. I cannot say whether it was 30 or 40 yards before I turned. Then I saw the prisoner going across the Park, towards the Serpentine-river-head. There was one Mr. Bunny, a butcher in St. James's-market, came by when he put up his piece to me. I turned my horse about, and went to him, and told him that man had robbed me: we made a hue and cry after him. We met with a soldier, almost at the Park-gate, and told him of it, and Shewed him the prisoner, and he struck across the Park, and went and took him. He was never out of my sight, till he was taken. The soldier delivered him to us, and went away, and I have never seen him since. The prisoner begged of me, that I would let him go, and said he would never do the like again; for if he went to gaol, he should die. I took him to justice Wright, who committed him.</p>
               <p>Mr. Bunny. I had been in Hampshire, and coming home that day through the Park, I saw the prisoner on foot, talking to Mr. Jay. I came riding pretty fast. I went to break out of the way, and Mr. Jay stopped me, and said that man had robbed him. I saw him clap the piece up to Mr. Jay's head, and heard him say: I'll be d - n'd if I will not; that is all the words I heard. It surprized me, and I got on as fast as I could.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I had no thoughts of robbing him: I have a same arm, it was shot through abroad: I did ask the gentleman to give me some money, I had lost<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176101160006"></xptr> mine. I have been a soldier 45 years: my arm is so lame, I cannot cock a gun, if you would give me a thousand guineas. He stripped and shewed his right-arm, which had received a wound; and between his elbow and shoulder, it was little more than skin and bone; but he seemed to use it as if he was capable of doing his duty as a soldier.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you belong to any regiment now?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I now belong to the third regiment of guards.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Did the prisoner apply to you as a beggar?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No, he bid me stop, and demanded my money by force.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he put you in fear?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Yes, he did.</p>
               <p>Q. to prisoner. Have you any witnesses, your serjeant or any body?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. No, I have none; I thought my arm would have done</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610116-3-verdict24" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610116-3-verdict24" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17610116-3-punish25" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610116-3-punish25" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610116-3-defend63 t17610116-3-punish25"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
