<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650417-38">
               <interp inst="t17650417-38" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650417-38" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650417-38" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650417"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650417-38" type="date" value="17650417"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650417-38-off218-c274" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-38-defend352 t17650417-38-off218 t17650417-38-verdict221"></join>
         
               <p>258. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17650417-38-defend352" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Bayless 
                  <interp inst="t17650417-38-defend352" type="surname" value="Bayless"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-38-defend352" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-38-defend352" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17650417-38-deflabel217" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-38-defend352 t17650417-38-deflabel217"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17650417-38-off218" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650417-38-off218" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-38-off218" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a looking-glass, value 2 d. a copper pottage-pot, value 4 d. a copper sauce-pan, value 4 d. a copper tea-kettle, value 2 d. and a flat iron
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17650417-38-victim354" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Booth 
                  <interp inst="t17650417-38-victim354" type="surname" value="Booth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-38-victim354" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-38-victim354" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-38-off218 t17650417-38-victim354"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17650417-38-cd219" type="crimeDate">March 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-38-off218 t17650417-38-cd219"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650417-38-person355">
                  John 
                  Booth 
               <interp inst="t17650417-38-person355" type="surname" value="Booth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-38-person355" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-38-person355" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . A gentleman took an apartment of my wife; the prisoner was his <rs id="t17650417-38-deflabel220" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-38-defend352 t17650417-38-deflabel220"></join>; the things mentioned were part of the furniture of the room, and some were to be used by the other lodger. On the 29th of March, she had quarrelled with her master, and, he desired a padlock might be put upon the door: my wife went into the room, and missed the things, and desired the prisoner to bring them again; she was taken up the first of April, and carried to the house of 
               <persName id="t17650417-38-person356">
                  George 
                  Bulmore 
               <interp inst="t17650417-38-person356" type="surname" value="Bulmore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-38-person356" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-38-person356" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , but would not tell where the things were; they were afterwards found at Bulmore's house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650417-38-person357">
                  George 
                  Bulmore 
               <interp inst="t17650417-38-person357" type="surname" value="Bulmore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-38-person357" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-38-person357" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner came and lodged with a woman that lodged in my house; there were some things brought to my house; Mr. Booth came and desired me to stop the woman; I did, and heard her own before Justice Girdler, that she brought these things out, but did not say from where. (The goods mentioned in the indictment produced in court, and deposed to by the prosecutor).</p>
               <p>Bulmore. They were concealed under my roof.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650417-38-person358">
                  James 
                  Whiskey 
               <interp inst="t17650417-38-person358" type="surname" value="Whiskey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-38-person358" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-38-person358" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an officer; I took the woman up with a warrant; these things were produced, and she acknowledged she had them from Mr. Booth's room.</p>

               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>My master thought I had a right to take the things out; I took them out in order to wash my master's linen.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mr. Kinsey. The truth of the case is this She is a woman that has too much spirit; with regard to taking away feloniously, that is entirely<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176504170023"></xptr> out of the question; she took these things and made use of them for my use: I told Mr. and Mrs. Booth their things were ready to be produced, and will be produced; we shall go to the other end of the town, and you shall have them at our return. There is not a woman in the kingdom more honest than the prisoner, (this is the truth); her imprudent behaviour to Mr. Booth has occasioned this: I told him I was ready to make him satisfaction, with respect to the padlock. She was not at home, to have a fire for me, and I told her she should be no longer with me: I came home and got a little tipsey. and said, Mr. Booth, be so good as to put a padlock on the door, she shall come no more here.</p>
               <p>Q. For what purpose were those goods carried out of the lodging-room?</p>
               <p>Kinsey. She washed my linen with the woman where she lodged, and she had these things for that purpose.</p>
               <p>Q. Could the tea-kettle be of use in washing your linen?</p>
               <p>Kinsey. She had the tea-kettle to boil the water, because the woman where she was had none: it was to boil the water to wash the linen in: these are the facts and truth of the case.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you authorise her to take away these things?</p>
               <p>Kinsey. I do not say I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she take them away with your knowledge?</p>
               <p>Kinsey. I don't say that. I desired her, as soon as she had done her business, to carry them home; she had no authority from me to take them away: as to the feloniously taking away, it is entirely out of the question; I don't think she would wrong a worm.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to lock her out?</p>
               <p>Kinsey. As long as I had things convenient for me, I did not care whether she was in or out of the room.</p>
               <p>Q. As the tea-kettle was taken out of your room? how did you manage for your breakfast?</p>
               <p>Kinsey. I breakfasted at the coffee-house; sometimes I am at one place and sometimes at another; sometimes I breakfast at Grosvenor-square: in case there was a bad intention I would not appear here on any consideration.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you recollect Mr. Booth going into your room, and missing the things?</p>
               <p>Kinsey. Mrs. Booth broke open my door and searched the room; I don't remember her missing the things: I don't know any thing about it: I had this room only for sleeping.</p>
               <p>Q. to Bulmore. Whether the things were made use of in your house for washing?</p>
               <p>Bulmore. I know Kinsey was blowing the fire one Sunday morning, to light it, while my wife was ironing of a shirt.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17650417-38-verdict221" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650417-38-verdict221" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
