<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660219-53">
               <interp inst="t17660219-53" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660219-53" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660219-53" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660219"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660219-53" type="date" value="17660219"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660219-53-off302-c456" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-53-defend588 t17660219-53-off302 t17660219-53-verdict305"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660219-53-off302-c457" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-53-defend590 t17660219-53-off302 t17660219-53-verdict305"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660219-53-off306-c456" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-53-defend588 t17660219-53-off306 t17660219-53-verdict305"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660219-53-off306-c457" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-53-defend590 t17660219-53-off306 t17660219-53-verdict305"></join>
         
               <p>180, 181. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660219-53-defend588" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Swift 
                  <interp inst="t17660219-53-defend588" type="surname" value="Swift"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-defend588" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-defend588" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17660219-53-defend590" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Evans 
                  <interp inst="t17660219-53-defend590" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-defend590" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-defend590" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted for <rs id="t17660219-53-off302" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-off302" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-off302" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               robbing 
                     
                        <persName id="t17660219-53-victim592" type="victimName">
                           Edward 
                           Birch 
                        <interp inst="t17660219-53-victim592" type="surname" value="Birch"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660219-53-victim592" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660219-53-victim592" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , on the King's highway, of 20 d. in money numbered
            </rs>, <rs id="t17660219-53-cd303" type="crimeDate">January 31</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-53-off302 t17660219-53-cd303"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-53-off306 t17660219-53-cd303"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660219-53-person593">
                  Edward 
                  Birch 
               <interp inst="t17660219-53-person593" type="surname" value="Birch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-person593" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-person593" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I <rs id="t17660219-53-viclabel304" type="occupation">carry about pies for my living</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-53-victim592 t17660219-53-viclabel304"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-53-victim595 t17660219-53-viclabel304"></join>, and live at Hounslow. I was coming from Brentford on the 31st of January. I got over Smallberry-green turnpike about 11 at night: there came two men to me, and turned me round. I said, gentlemen, I hope you will not molest me on the highway, I hope you'll let me pass: I went on. When I came to the Rose and Crown, I crossed the way, being in fear; one of them crossed over to me, and knocked me down, I cannot tell with what; it was not his fist, because it hit so hard. I got up as quick as I could, they knocked me down again. I got up a second time, then they knocked me down again, and I could not then get up. One of them got his hand in my mouth; I strove to bite his finger to mark him, but I could not; then I cried, murder. I had 5 s. in one pocket, and a few halfpence in another: they took 20 or 22 d. I do not know which.</p>
               <p>Q. What colour were their cloaths?</p>
               <p>Birch. I could not distinguish which; I cannot sware to them, but they knew me: one of them said, I'll be d - d if it is not All Hot (a name given me by crying my pies), they seemed to be sorry, and said, he knows us. I was a long time before I got out of the ditch: there came a lad that had been robbed; he said, halloo; I said, halloo, who are you. I have been robbed said he. I said, so have I: he said, he had been robbed of all he had: I said, then I'll go along with you to Brentford, because I had some left, and give you part of a pot. We went there, but nobody was up. The two prisoners were taken up before I came back, on another affair. I called at the turnpike. Mr. Smith that keeps it, said, All Hot, you may go on very safe, for the men are taken, I saw the corporal, and said, I had been robbed by two of his light-horse-men: he bid me go home to bed, so I did.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17660219-53-verdict305" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-verdict305" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>They were a second time indicted, for that <rs id="t17660219-53-off306" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-off306" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-off306" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               they, with a certain offensive weapon, called a pistol, which Evans had and held in his right hand, did make an assault on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17660219-53-victim595" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Spinnage 
                        <interp inst="t17660219-53-victim595" type="surname" value="Spinnage"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660219-53-victim595" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660219-53-victim595" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17660219-53-viclabel307" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-53-victim595 t17660219-53-viclabel307"></join>; with a felonious intent his money to steal
            </rs>, <rs id="t17660219-53-cd308" type="crimeDate">Jan. 31</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-53-off302 t17660219-53-cd308"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-53-off306 t17660219-53-cd308"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660219-53-person596">
                  John 
                  Spinnage 
               <interp inst="t17660219-53-person596" type="surname" value="Spinnage"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-person596" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-person596" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; I was in a post chaise with four horses. There was Mr. Marsden and Adams with me. On the 31st of January we were stopped about a quarter before 12 at night, <placeName id="t17660219-53-crimeloc309">about 40 yards on this side Lord Northumberland's , beyond Brentford</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17660219-53-crimeloc309" type="placeName" value="about 40 yards on this side Lord Northumberland's , beyond Brentford"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660219-53-crimeloc309" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-53-off302 t17660219-53-crimeloc309"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-53-off306 t17660219-53-crimeloc309"></join>. I called to know what was the matter. The post-boy said, some gentlemen will not let us go on: we let down the fore glass. I heard a voice say, d - n you, go to the door, and demand the money. Upon which I saw Evans come with a pistol in his hand close up to the sash, on the left hand. I was in the center: he talked about money, when close to the window, d - n you, your money, I'll blow your brains out, or something of that kind. I saw by the presenting his pistol, if there had been a ball, it must go through the roof of the chaise, he elevated the point pretty high. I bid Adams let the glass down, the moment that was down, I cried, fire away: upon which Evans fired, I could see his face extremely plain by the slash of the pan. We fired two pistols immediately upon him from the chaise; I thought it would have knocked his head off, as the pistols were not three feet from his head: there was another man: they went away towards London. I bid the boy drive on as fast as possible to the first house. When we<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176602190036"></xptr> came to Smallberry-green, I asked the turnpike man to lend me a lanthorn: he did, with a bit of candle in it. I asked the post-boy if his heart lay right; he answered, it does lay very right. I thought we had killed the person, and I was determined not to let him lay in the road, but to carry him to Brentford. We went to the place, and hunted about with the lanthorn, and could see no man nor blood; I thought then these fellows could not have got far. In a little time up came Evans to me; this was just as you turn down to the Lord of Northumberland's house. I laid hold of him, and Marsden seized Swift: we tied Evans's hands behind him; then I went to assist Marsden, and found Swift had got a pistol in the lining of his regimentals: we took it out; it was a horse pistol. He wanted to get away; they can jump like greyhounds: we tied Swift's hands behind him also, and Marsden and Adams took them to the turnpike. When we got there, I held a candle to the face of Evans, and all about his eye were the appearance of gunpowder, and there was the least touch in the world of the graze of a ball on his nose. Swift desired to have his pistol. I said, you shall never have it no more: his pistol was laid on the table, and by the smell of it, I am sure it had not been fired off 10 minutes. Evans was dressed in his watering jacket and cap, and Swift in his regimentals. I did not see Swift at the time we fired: Mr. Marsden will account for him. When his wife came to him, he said, don't make yourself uneasy, I bless God there was no ball in my barrel.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660219-53-person597">
                  William 
                  Marsden 
               <interp inst="t17660219-53-person597" type="surname" value="Marsden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-person597" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-person597" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Friday the 31st of January, after we had been examining the men on a slight suspicion at the barracks, at Kensington, five were committed to goal. We discovered about fourteen: one was upon centry, he flung down his piece, and ran away: we thought proper to give notice to the different officers where the men were quartered; we ordered a post chaise with four horses. Mr. Spinnage offered to go, and I offered my service to go with him. Adams went with us. We were unprepared for any journey: the major at the barracks offered us pistols: we had two brace given us loaded for our guard: first of all they brought us four pistols, with but one lock to them all. Going along, when we got to this place, about 40 yards on this side the lane that turns down to Isleworth, the first I observed was the chaise stopped. I called out, what is the matter: the boy, I think, said, two gentlemen stopped him; I guessed what it was. Swift, whom I have known for years, stood directly opposite the window. I sat on the farther side, and he on the near side very forward, so that I had a full view of him: he was in his full regimentals, cap, and every thing. I then had no doubt but that we were stopped: I had my pistol ready, intending if he had offered any pistol, to have shot him; it was so ready, I knew I could be before hand with him. In the mean time, I heard him say something to the other man, I observed nothing more than the word chaise. The other came up, and said something of money; he came on the same side, but the instant he spoke, off went the pistol; I fired instantly, we could but just see which pistol went off first: he came in a direction from the horses to the chaise, I saw but little more of him than his head and his hand. Mr. Spinnage fired, and so did Adams, at the other, then they ran away, and we went on; he that fired into the chaise, was in a woollen cap and white jacket. We went on to the turnpike, and got a lanthorn; I took one of the pistols that I found loaded, and went on. I saw Swift, and laid hold of him, and knew him directly; he was servant to a lady that used to visit Sir 
               <persName id="t17660219-53-person598">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17660219-53-person598" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-person598" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-person598" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            : we took them to the turnpike-house, and went to see how many pistols we had; we got him to a house at Hounslow, and got a constable. Evans ran away for that night, and was not taken till the Sunday after. I saw his face when we brought him to the light, all the left part of his cheek and his eyelid was all plain powder to be seen in it. When they were examined last Monday se'nnight, Swift began mentioning the stopping the chaise, and Evans acknowledged the same, but that it was with intention to ride, not to take any thing.</p>
               <p>- Adams. I was likewise in the chaise; we were stopped a little beyond Brentford. I saw a man in regimentals standing in the foot-path a little way from the chaise. I kept my eye upon him. I did not see the other man till he came to the window; there was something said, like d - n you, your money. Major 
               <persName id="t17660219-53-person599">
                  Spinnage
               <interp inst="t17660219-53-person599" type="given" value="Spinnage"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-person599" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said, let down the window; we let down the side glass, and Mr. Marsden said, keep off: the major said, fire, and I directly fired at the man that stood by the chaise; he was dressed in white, with his watering cap on, I did not distinguish his face: then we went on to the turnpike at Smallberry-green; we got out of the chaise, and came down and met with the two prisoners in the road, and secured them. We searched them; there was a pistol found on Swift. When we came to Hounslow, on the left side of Evans's face, the blood<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176602190037"></xptr> had a little started; it looked a little freshish. The pistol that was taken from Swift, had been fired off; the pan was quite wet. Mr. Marsden held it up and said, is this your pistol? Swift said it was: there was only two pistols fired in the chaise, I fired one, and I believe Mr. Marsden the other.</p>
               <p>- Brooks. I was the foremost post-boy: going along, we perceived two men; as we came near them, they parted, one went upon the causeway, and the other in the middle of the road; one in white, with his watering cap on, the other in his red regimentals: he in his watering dress came and held a pistol to me; there were some words passed between them. Then I heard Evans demand the money at the chaise door; the glass was down, and, to the best of my knowledge, there were three pistols fired: after that Evans came towards my horses: they called out of the chaise to go on, and we galloped all the way to Smallberry-green turnpike, after that they went back and brought the two prisoners to the turnpike.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660219-53-person600">
                  Henry 
                  Gascoyne 
               <interp inst="t17660219-53-person600" type="surname" value="Gascoyne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-person600" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-person600" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . We were going along just on. the other side Brentford, by the lane that goes up to Sion-house: all on a sudden we stopped. I asked the boy what was the matter; he said, Harry, here is a man has hold of my horses, and will not let me go. They let down the glass of the chaise, and asked what was the matter. I said, here is a man stops us: the man in regimentals stood on the bank side. He said, You scoundrel, why don't you go and demand their money: he let go the horses heads, and ran by me, and said, your money, gentlemen. Who fired the pistols, I cannot say, but I could hear the report of two; they were so close, I could hardly distinguish them: after that there was another pistol discharged, which was, I believe, to the man on the bank; then they ordered us to go along as hard as we could to the turnpike.</p>
               <p>The prisoners in their defence denied the fact, and said they had been out, and staid till locked out of their quarters: that they imagined the chaise to be a return post chaise, and they went up to it in order to get a ride.</p>
               <p>Evans called 
               <persName id="t17660219-53-person601">
                  Mary 
                  Barber 
               <interp inst="t17660219-53-person601" type="surname" value="Barber"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-person601" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-person601" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17660219-53-person602">
                  Daniel 
                  Jopson 
               <interp inst="t17660219-53-person602" type="surname" value="Jopson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-person602" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-person602" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17660219-53-person603">
                  Richard 
                  Sealtock 
               <interp inst="t17660219-53-person603" type="surname" value="Sealtock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-person603" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-person603" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17660219-53-person604">
                  William 
                  Gough 
               <interp inst="t17660219-53-person604" type="surname" value="Gough"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-person604" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-person604" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17660219-53-person605">
                  John 
                  Purcer 
               <interp inst="t17660219-53-person605" type="surname" value="Purcer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-person605" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-person605" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who gave him a good character.</p>
               <p>Swift called 
               <persName id="t17660219-53-person606">
                  Stephen 
                  Kendrick 
               <interp inst="t17660219-53-person606" type="surname" value="Kendrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-person606" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-person606" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17660219-53-person607">
                  William 
                  Kendrick 
               <interp inst="t17660219-53-person607" type="surname" value="Kendrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-person607" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-person607" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who gave him the same.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17660219-53-verdict310" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-verdict310" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17660219-53-punish311" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660219-53-punish311" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-53-defend588 t17660219-53-punish311"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-53-defend590 t17660219-53-punish311"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
