<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17621208-48">
               <interp inst="t17621208-48" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17621208-48" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17621208-48" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17621208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17621208-48" type="date" value="17621208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17621208-48-off244-c313" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-48-defend392 t17621208-48-off244 t17621208-48-verdict248"></join>
         
               <p>50. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17621208-48-defend392" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Maria 
                     Smith 
                  , <rs id="t17621208-48-deflabel243" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-48-defend392 t17621208-48-deflabel243"></join>, otherwise <rs id="t17621208-48-alias-10" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-48-defend392 t17621208-48-alias-10"></join>Margaret Levet</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-48-defend392" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-48-defend392" type="given" value="Maria"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-48-defend392" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17621208-48-off244" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17621208-48-off244" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-48-off244" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 8 linnen shirts, val. 7 s. ten caps, val 10 s. four linnen forehead-cloths, val. 1 s. 2 linnen waistcoats, and 2 biggins
            </rs>, the property of 
               <persName id="t17621208-48-victim394" type="victimName">
                  Thomas 
                  Hill 
               <interp inst="t17621208-48-victim394" type="surname" value="Hill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-48-victim394" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-48-victim394" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-48-off244 t17621208-48-victim394"></join>
                  </persName>
             , <rs id="t17621208-48-cd245" type="crimeDate">Dec. 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-48-off244 t17621208-48-cd245"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-48-person395">
                  Thomas 
                  Hill 
               <interp inst="t17621208-48-person395" type="surname" value="Hill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-48-person395" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-48-person395" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I<rs id="t17621208-48-viclabel246" type="occupation">keep a public house</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-48-victim394 t17621208-48-viclabel246"></join> in <placeName id="t17621208-48-crimeloc247">Chandois Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17621208-48-crimeloc247" type="placeName" value="Chandois Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17621208-48-crimeloc247" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-48-off244 t17621208-48-crimeloc247"></join>. Yesterday was sen'night, about 6 o'clock in the evening, I lost a parcel of child-bed linnen, tied up in a red handkerchief; I cannot mention the particular things, there were caps, shirts, biggins, forehead-cloaths, and the like.</p>
               <p>Q. Why do you charge the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Hill. I never saw her before she was taken up; she was taken up on Monday evening; it will appear the things were pawned by her, they were found at a pawnbroker's. ( Produced in court and deposed to.) My wife is very ill, or she had been here.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say upon your charging her?</p>
               <p>Hill. She said she did not steal them, but that they were given her by another woman for a debt, which was owing to her 4 years.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176212080031"></xptr>Q. Did she mention that woman's name?</p>
               <p>Hill. Yes, she said her name was Murphy.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see one Murphy in your house the day the things were lost?</p>
               <p>Hill. No. I did not.</p>
               <p>Thomas Hall. The prisoner at the bar pawned these things with me, (here produced,) yesterday se'nnight, in the evening between 9 and 10 o'clock, at the name of 
               <persName id="t17621208-48-person396">
                  Maria 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17621208-48-person396" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-48-person396" type="given" value="Maria"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-48-person396" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. What did you lend her upon them?</p>
               <p>Hall. I lent her half a guinea.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-48-person397">
                  William 
                  Weedler 
               <interp inst="t17621208-48-person397" type="surname" value="Weedler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-48-person397" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-48-person397" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to the prosecutor. The prisoner came to our house yesterday se'night, and called for a halfpenny worth of gin. I served her; she brought this fork and brush with her, (producing an iron beef fork, and cloaths brush) she came in between 5 and 8 o'clock, and staid about 5 minutes; I saw the parcel of child-bed linnen there before she came into the house, they were in the same room where she was; she had not been gone above half an hour before they were missing.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. That waiter swore to another woman, and sent her to Newgate in my place.</p>
               <p>Weedler. There was another woman came into our house that night, but as soon as I saw the prisoner I knew the other was not the woman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-48-person398">
                  Mary 
                  Scott 
               <interp inst="t17621208-48-person398" type="surname" value="Scott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-48-person398" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-48-person398" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was in my shop yesterday was se'nnight in the evening between 9 and 10 o'clock, she said she was going out, and a washerwoman owed her about 15 s. she came home by 11, and said she had given her some things instead of money, she did not know what they were, she had a parcel with her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she mention the washer-woman's name?</p>
               <p>Scott. No, she did not, ( she takes up a handkerchief) this is the handkerchief the things were tied up in.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. This is my property, the same handkerchief my things were in.</p>
               <p>Scott. She went out between 9 and 10, and returned again and said she had pawned them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>The pawnbroker's shop was shut up between 10 and 11 o'clock. I went into the prosecutor's house that night; the waiter was coming out of the parlour and said, my mistress has had her fortune told by a woman that tells the truest fortunes of any. He persuaded me to go in and have mine told. I went into the back parlour, and staid there about 10 or 14 minutes. The woman told me my fortune; it was not that I should come here to the Old-Bailey. I gave her 2 d. and came out at the back door. I had appointed to go to the washer-woman for money she owed me; she told me, she would pay me. I wanted something for supper; she went out and brought some buttock of beef. She lives in Princes's-street. I had lent her some child bed linnen two years ago. The woman told me, she had not received any money for her work, but she returned in about half an hour and said, I can't get any money, but I have got your things and others to them; but I must have them again, for my daughter is big with child. She bade me take care of the handkerchief they were in, and said, it was a gentleman's handkerchief that I wash for, and that he lives in Sheer-lane at a chandler's shop. I came home to this woman's house, she said, she had nothing to eat or drink; so I went out and pawned these things, and got something for supper.</p>
               <p>Q. to Weedler. Do you remember any woman having her fortune told her that night?</p>
               <p>Weedler. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-48-person399">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17621208-48-person399" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-48-person399" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-48-person399" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Clerkenwell; I am a cardinal-maker by trade. I have known her twenty years; she is a milliner by trade, that is, she used to work at milliners. I never was so shocked in my life, as I was when I heard she was here. She is a very honest body.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17621208-48-verdict248" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17621208-48-verdict248" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
