<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660903-40">
               <interp inst="t17660903-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-40" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660903"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-40" type="date" value="17660903"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660903-40-off211-c274" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-40-defend354 t17660903-40-off211 t17660903-40-verdict216"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660903-40-off212-c276" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-40-defend358 t17660903-40-off212 t17660903-40-verdict218"></join>
         
               <p>437, 438. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660903-40-defend354" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Rushton 
                  <interp inst="t17660903-40-defend354" type="surname" value="Rushton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-defend354" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-defend354" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             was indicted for <rs id="t17660903-40-off211" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-off211" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-off211" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               stealing four yards of buckram, four yards of glazed linen, and four yards of linen for pockets
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17660903-40-victim356" type="victimName">
                     Philip 
                     Dobbins 
                  <interp inst="t17660903-40-victim356" type="surname" value="Dobbins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-victim356" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-victim356" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17660903-40-defend358" type="defendantName">
                     William
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176609030030"></xptr> Ashby<interp inst="t17660903-40-defend358" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-defend358" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             for <rs id="t17660903-40-off212" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-off212" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-off212" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving the same, well knowing them to have been stolen
            </rs>, <rs id="t17660903-40-cd213" type="crimeDate">August 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-40-off211 t17660903-40-cd213"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-40-off212 t17660903-40-cd213"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-40-person359">
                  Philip 
                  Dobbins 
               <interp inst="t17660903-40-person359" type="surname" value="Dobbins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-person359" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-person359" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17660903-40-viclabel214" type="occupation">taylor</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-40-victim356 t17660903-40-viclabel214"></join>, and live in <placeName id="t17660903-40-crimeloc215">Rood-lane, Fenchurch-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17660903-40-crimeloc215" type="placeName" value="Rood-lane, Fenchurch-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660903-40-crimeloc215" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-40-off211 t17660903-40-crimeloc215"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-40-off212 t17660903-40-crimeloc215"></join>; the prisoner Rushton was a turn-over to me; he had served five years of his time, and had been with me one month; while he was with me, I missed several things at different times; I was informed by Eliz. Fletcher, that he went out with his pockets stuffed out with things; I charged him upon that with taking out things my property; he owned he had taken some buckram, glazed linen, and pocketting, and afterwards he recollected the sum of money he had sold them for; after a great deal of consideration, he told me there were 11 yards of it all together, but he could not account for them separately.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell him you would be favourable if he would confess?</p>
               <p>Dobbins. No, I did not; I promised him nothing; I said, if he would tell, perhaps I might be favourable.</p>
               <p>Q. What was that favour?</p>
               <p>Dobbins. My favour was to know where the things were.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the lad to understand from you by the word favourable?</p>
               <p>Dobbins. The favour was, I had not given him in charge of the constable; this was to know who had been the buyer of the goods.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your meaning, as soon as he confessed, you would put him into the hands of the constable and prosecute him?</p>
               <p>Dobbins. No.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-40-person360">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Fletcher 
               <interp inst="t17660903-40-person360" type="surname" value="Fletcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-person360" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-person360" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Dobbins. On the 13th of August I watched the prisoner carrying things out, I did not know what they were, but I saw his pockets stand out, they were full of something; he used to go out with no money in his pocket, and come home with a great deal, which gave me a suspicion of him; he was gone out about an hour, and in the mean time the other apprentice came in; this was between 7 and 8 in the evening, when the other men were gone from work; the other apprentice and I, both of us charged him with taking something; he said he went for paper, but could not find a stationer's shop; we said he did not go out for paper, but to sell some of his master's goods; he denied it a good while, and at last he owned he had a quarter of a yard of buckram in each pocket; I said he had more, and at last he owned he had two yards and a half in the whole; we asked him what he did with it; he said he had carried it up into Newgate-street to his father, and that his father gave him 1 s. 9 d. to get some tea, and he had spent the money; I said his father was an unworthy man to take it of him; he said his father did not know that he stole it; then he said he had left it in Newgate-street for his father; the next morning when the constable was charged with him, I heard him confess to the taking it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-40-person361">
                  Theodore 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17660903-40-person361" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-person361" type="given" value="Theodore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-person361" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I shall be 18 years of age the 13th of October next, I am apprentice to Mr. Dobbins; when I came home on the 13th of August, the maid told me she was afraid Tom was gone out with some things of my master's, and we consulted to talk to him; when he came home, she said, Tom, what was that you went out with in your coat lining; he said, nothing at all; said I, she says you went out with your pockets stuffed out; he said he would be d - d if he did; I said, you may as well own it if you did take any thing out; then he owned he had taken out buckram for his father; then I said, well, Tom, what did you do with it; said he, I carried it up to Newgate-street; I said, did your father desire you to rob my master; he said, no. I said, why did you carry it to Newgate-street, to whom did you carry it; he did not say to whom, but said his father had given him 1 s. 9 d. and he had spent it; he desired we would not say any thing to his master of it; I told my master of it the next morning as soon as he got up; when my master charged him, he swore at first he did not take any thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you before the Alderman?</p>
               <p>Johnson. I was; there he said he sold these goods to 
               <persName id="t17660903-40-person362">
                  William 
                  Ashby 
               <interp inst="t17660903-40-person362" type="surname" value="Ashby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-person362" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-person362" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , that is buckram, pocketting, and glazed linen, and that there were 11 yards of it all together, but he could not cleverly tell how much there was of each.</p>
               <p>Q. Was 
               <persName id="t17660903-40-person363">
                  William 
                  Ashby 
               <interp inst="t17660903-40-person363" type="surname" value="Ashby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-person363" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-person363" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             present?</p>
               <p>Johnson. No, he was not; he said he could not tell the name of the man, but it was facing the Leather Breeches; I went there and saw Mr. Ashby, and said, my master desires to speak with you; after we came from the Mansion-house, we got a search warrant and went to Ashby's house, there the buckram, pocketting, and glazed linen were delivered to us, twelve yards of it; there I saw Mr. and Mrs. Ashby.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say?</p>
               <p>Johnson. He said nothing, his wife spoke for him.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say?</p>
               <p>Johnson. She had been at our house while we were gone to the Mansion-house; she said she spoke to her Billy about it, and desired my master to be as favourable as he could about it;<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176609030031"></xptr> she told my master they had it of Rushton, and that Rushton told them he came out of Holbourn; we asked Rushton how often he had been at Ashby's he said he had been there five times; the woman owned she saw him there twice; I was before Sir 
               <persName id="t17660903-40-person364">
                  Thomas 
                  Rawlinson 
               <interp inst="t17660903-40-person364" type="surname" value="Rawlinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-person364" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-person364" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , when Ashby and Rushton were there; Rushton there owned to his being at Ashby's house five times; Ashby said he never saw him but about three times, and that he bought of him the three times for 8 s. and 2 s. and 5 s. 6 d. Rushton offered to take his oath he had been there five times.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What is Ashby?</p>
               <p>Johnson. He is a piece-broker.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you never been sent to buy of piece-brokers for your master?</p>
               <p>Johnson. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. What have you bought of them?</p>
               <p>Johnson. I have bought pieces of cloth for seating of breeches.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did Rushton say he sold these pieces?</p>
               <p>Johnson. He said Mr. Ashby was shutting up shop, and he went in and pulled them out of his pockets, and I think no honest person will buy of such a one that brought them so.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he not tell you Mrs. Ashby bought the things, and that he was busy at the time with his birds?</p>
               <p>Johnson. No, he said Mrs. Ashby measured the pieces, and she came and asked what she must give; and he said, m y dear, you must give 8 d. a yard.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not Mr. Ashby say, he thought Rushton came honestly by them?</p>
               <p>Johnson. He did; he said he thought the lad came honestly by them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not Ashby insist upon it he bought them in his shop.</p>
               <p>Johnson. He did; he said he came one night with some things, and said he was going into the country, and was willing to dispose of them, that was the first time; Ashby said that was the usual price, but he did not give to the rate of that, but I do not think it is usual to sell remnants of buckram to piece-brokers.</p>
               <p>Eldrington Wood. I live in Poor-jury-lane; I was at the examination of the two prisoners; the boy made an open confession before the Alderman of the goods that he had sold to Ashby; he said he had sold 11 yards in the whole, that is, buckram, pocketting, and glazed linen.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear him say where he had them from?</p>
               <p>Wood. He owned he took them from Mr. Dobbins's house, and other quantities at separate times, and had sold them to Mr. Ashby for 22 shillings, and that he had been there in the whole 5 times; and that Mr. Ashby told him the last time, there were 12 yards odd measure, and said if he had any more of these things to come to him.</p>
               <p>Q. What did Ashby say to it?</p>
               <p>Wood. He denied it, and said Rushton had been there but three times; he owned he bought the buckram, pocketting, and glazed linen the night before, which was the 13th of August; I went there with the search warrant; the goods were taken down from a shelf by Mrs. Ashby, and delivered to us; she said, gentlemen, never such a thing happened before, here are the goods that I bought of the young man, and said her husband was shutting up the shutters, and she called to him to know what she must give for them, he said 8 d. a yard.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Wood. I am Mr. Dobbins's foreman.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see buckram disposed of to piece-brokers?</p>
               <p>Wood. No, never in my life, not in remnants; they buy it in the piece, and sell it out as it is wanted; Ashby said he asked Rushton where he came from, and he answered he lived in Holbourn, and had a little trade of his own, and he bought the things for his own use; but being a little distressed for want of money, he having some things to send into the country, was obliged to dispose of these, but he denied his ever desiring him to bring more when he had it.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you never bought of piece-brokers?</p>
               <p>Wood. I have bought remnants of cloth to seat breeches.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say any thing of a suspicion he had that they were not honestly come by?</p>
               <p>Wood. He said, after the prisoner was gone the last time, he had a suspicion they were not honestly come by, after he came to look at them; and that if ever he came there again, he would stop him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-40-person365">
                  John 
                  Hazard 
               <interp inst="t17660903-40-person365" type="surname" value="Hazard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-person365" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-person365" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About three weeks ago I was at the Compter; I was acquainted with Mr. Ashby some time; I asked him concerning the nature of buying these goods; he told me he had seen the boy once before he bought the quantity he was taken up for.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you understand the piece-broking business?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176609030032"></xptr>Hazard. I do very well.</p>
               <p>Q. Tell the court what you think a piece-broker can fairly and honestly afford to give for these goods?</p>
               <p>Hazard. ( He takes the goods in his hand) I believe upon my oath, no man, in justice to the trade, could give more than what he has done, that is, 8 d. a yard.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he always insist upon it, that he bought them not knowing them to have been stolen?</p>
               <p>Hazard. He always did.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it usual for master taylors to buy of piece-brokers?</p>
               <p>Hazard. I believe there is not one master taylor in London but what buy of piece-brokers; they are under a necessity of buying of them.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known Mr. Ashby?</p>
               <p>Hazard. I have known him about 11 years; I have had dealings with him several times, and believe there is not an honester man under the canopy of heaven than he is, I am sure of it.</p>

               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Hazard. I was brought up a woollen-draper and salesman, and was afterwards in the stop business.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you deal in pieces and remnants of buckram?</p>
               <p>Hazard. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it an uncommon thing for master taylors to sell remnants of buckram?</p>
               <p>Hazard. It is not common, except upon necessity.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-40-person366">
                  John 
                  Dove 
               <interp inst="t17660903-40-person366" type="surname" value="Dove"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-person366" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-person366" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a master taylor: I cannot buy such buckram (holding it in his hand) so cheap by 3 d. a yard now, nor no man in the trade; it is not usual for piece-brokers to buy such pieces, except they are stolen, that is fact; neither is it usual for taylors to sell pieces of buckram; the prime cost of this buckram was 10, or 11, or 11 d. halfpenny per yard at the best hand, by the piece; I never bought it so cheap in my life as this, though I have bought 40 pieces at a time, when it was cheaper than it is now: the piece-broker's trade is a very iniquitous trade, we have groaned under it for more than 100 years: some journeymen, whatever they can save, they will run away to the piece-brokers with it, even if it will fetch no more than a halfpenny-worth of snuff; I declare upon oath, I never sold or bought little pieces of buckram in my life.</p>
               <p>Rushton's defence.</p>
               <p>I made myself over to serve Mr. Dobbins for two years; when the agreement was made, my father told him not to let me have any money till my time was expired, and that drove me to this thing.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Branson. I live in Bear lane, Thames-street; I have known the prisoner Rushton ever since he was born; he was apprentice to his uncle, and behaved very honestly; he died, then he was turned over to this master.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Collumbine. I have known him almost ever since he was born; I never knew or heard any harm of him; his father is a taylor, a poor working man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-40-person367">
                  William 
                  Grissel 
               <interp inst="t17660903-40-person367" type="surname" value="Grissel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-person367" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-person367" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about 6 or 7 years; I never heard any thing amiss of him.</p>
               <p>Rushton, <rs id="t17660903-40-verdict216" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-verdict216" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17660903-40-punish217" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-punish217" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-punish217" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-40-defend354 t17660903-40-punish217"></join>
               B
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>Ashby, <rs id="t17660903-40-verdict218" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660903-40-verdict218" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
