<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17630518-14">
               <interp inst="t17630518-14" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630518-14" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630518-14" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17630518"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630518-14" type="date" value="17630518"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17630518-14-off81-c120" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-14-defend148 t17630518-14-off81 t17630518-14-verdict86"></join>
         
               <p>213. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17630518-14-defend148" type="defendantName">
                     Edmund 
                     Collins 
                  <interp inst="t17630518-14-defend148" type="surname" value="Collins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-14-defend148" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-14-defend148" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17630518-14-deflabel80" type="occupation">gent.</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-14-defend148 t17630518-14-deflabel80"></join> was indicted for <rs id="t17630518-14-off81" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630518-14-off81" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-14-off81" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he, on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17630518-14-victim150" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Vigne 
                        <interp inst="t17630518-14-victim150" type="surname" value="Vigne"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630518-14-victim150" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630518-14-victim150" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-14-off81 t17630518-14-victim150"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and taking from his person one metal watch, value 5 l. one gold ring set with diamonds, value 22 l. one other gold ring, value 12 s. and two quarter guineas, his property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17630518-14-cd82" type="crimeDate">March 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-14-off81 t17630518-14-cd82"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630518-14-person151">
                  James 
                  Vigne 
               <interp inst="t17630518-14-person151" type="surname" value="Vigne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-14-person151" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-14-person151" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17630518-14-viclabel83" type="occupation">watch maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-14-victim150 t17630518-14-viclabel83"></join>. On the 28th of March; about one in the morning, I was coming home towards Charing-cross, where I live; I was accosted by three men, two of them dressed in sailors jackets, the other in common cloaths; this was near York-buildings in the Strand, the prisoner was one of them; they surrounded me, and talked to each other, I could not tell what, in a mumbling way. They said, give us something to drink. I said, I could not then, I was going home. They insisted upon it very strongly; I thought it most prudent to comply with three such desperate fellows, (as they kept very close to me) to pass my own door, which is opposite Northumberland-house, fearing if I should knock, and have it opened, they, by seeing valuable things there, might knock me down, and force into the house. I said, I would treat them at the first house I came to; they obliged me to go up the Haymarket I was fearful to run from them, fearing they would follow me, and use me ill. I saw a cellar open in the Haymarket, on the right hand side, which seemed to have a decent appearance; I proposed to treat them there; they said, no, they would have it at a house of there own at the top of Piccadilly, at the Red Lion. We went all there, I ordered some liquor, a half crown bowl of punch, I think they called for slip: they forced me to the upper end of the place; there were a great number of people there, coachmen and chairmen, it is a night house. As I was sitting with my head leaning on my hand, the prisoner took my watch from my fob. I took it out of his hand, and said, what do you mean to rob me? I got out of the house as soon as I could, I believe I had been there about an hour; I made for home as fast as I could, betwixt <placeName id="t17630518-14-crimeloc84">Panton-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17630518-14-crimeloc84" type="placeName" value="Panton-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17630518-14-crimeloc84" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-14-off81 t17630518-14-crimeloc84"></join> and <placeName id="t17630518-14-crimeloc85">James-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17630518-14-crimeloc85" type="placeName" value="James-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17630518-14-crimeloc85" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-14-off81 t17630518-14-crimeloc85"></join>, there is no lamps; they all three came running on the other side of the way, two of them took hold of me on each side, I said, what do you want with me now, have not I given you something to drink? Said they, do not chatter, Sir, come, come, deliver. They took my watch, a quarter guineas, and 2 s. from my pocket, and struck me several blows with a stick, one on my thigh, and others on my hands. One of them said, don't use him ill, you know that he has been a good natured fellow, but he has got a ring, and by G d we will have it. I had at that time my glove on, but they had seen it I believe in the house; they took it, it was a diamond cluster ring, 9 large and 8 small ones; then they left me, and I went home, the ring was worth at least 22 l.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you pass no watchman in the street?</p>
               <p>Vigne. No, I did not, nor nobody else, and they had hold of my shoulder almost all the way, and kept close to me. I got home about half an hour after two.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober?</p>
               <p>Vigne. I was. I advertised my ring the next day; after that I heard there was such a person as the prisoner in the Gatehouse, for an assault, I went to Sir 
               <persName id="t17630518-14-person152">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17630518-14-person152" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-14-person152" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-14-person152" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he was brought up, I knew him directly, it was the prisoner at the bar, he owned he was in that house with me. I have found only the setting of my diamond ring again, that is, the hoop and setting. Mr. Underwood said he had sold the stones, and he sent the hoop to me: here it is, (producing it) I am certain it is the same, having several reasons to know it by, and here is Mr. Le Sage, that made it for me.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176305180010"></xptr>Q. Why did you not take an opportunity to get protection from the Landlord at the Red Lion in Piccadilly?</p>
               <p>Vigne. I did not, I have blamed myself since for not doing it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630518-14-person153">
                  Charles 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17630518-14-person153" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-14-person153" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-14-person153" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am apprentice to the prosecutor, this hoop I had of Mr. Underwood, and I delivered it to my master.</p>
               <p>Mr. Underwood. This ring, with the diamonds in it, was brought to me by 
               <persName id="t17630518-14-person154">
                  James 
                  Thorp 
               <interp inst="t17630518-14-person154" type="surname" value="Thorp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-14-person154" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-14-person154" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , sent by Mr. Warren, in Fleet-lane, to know what I would give for it, it was wrapped up in paper, this was some time between 3 and 5 weeks ago, it was a very remarkable ring, not one in a thousand like it; I gave 9 guineas for it, the boy said his master asked 10 guineas</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630518-14-person155">
                  James 
                  Thorp 
               <interp inst="t17630518-14-person155" type="surname" value="Thorp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-14-person155" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-14-person155" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I carried a ring wrapped up in paper from Mr. Warren, in Fleet-lane, to Mr. Underwood; Mr. Warren is a jeweller: I saw 
               <persName id="t17630518-14-person156">
                  James 
                  Geary 
               <interp inst="t17630518-14-person156" type="surname" value="Geary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-14-person156" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-14-person156" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             give it to Mr. Warren; my master said to Geary, he did not know whether they were diamonds or not.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is your master Warren?</p>
               <p>Thorp. He is now a prisoner in the Fleet.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630518-14-person157">
                  James 
                  Geary 
               <interp inst="t17630518-14-person157" type="surname" value="Geary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-14-person157" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-14-person157" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had a cluster ring set with stones, I asked Mr. Warren what it might be worth? he tried it with a file, and said it might he worth 10 guineas, I was to pawn it for Collins, this was about six weeks ago; he sent the boy, I think, to Gutter-lane first, to a jeweller, to know the value of it; the boy brought word back that it was a diamond ring. After that I sent it by a woman, and pawned it for 4 s. on Ludgate-hill.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you in custody for?</p>
               <p>Geary. I do not know, I am charged with a highway robbery.</p>
               <p>Mr. Le Sage. I set this ring (taking the hoop in his hand) for the prosecutor.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the market price to sell again?</p>
               <p>Le Sage. I would have given 16 l. for it to sell again, but I should not have bought it of a boy. On Friday last the hoop was produced to the prisoner, and I heard him acknowledge he sent it by Geary to pawn, and Geary pawned it for 4 s.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630518-14-person158">
                  John 
                  Tompson 
               <interp inst="t17630518-14-person158" type="surname" value="Tompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-14-person158" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-14-person158" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Red Lion in Piccadilly. I saw the prisoner with the prosecutor at my house, it was, I believe, about 3 in the morning, but I cannot tell the day of the month or week; he was dressed in a sailor's jacket, he goes by the name of the fighting cobler.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I did not see the ring that is alledged against me, I know I gave a common paste ring to Geary, he left it at a pawnbroker's for 4 s. a woman brought it from Plymouth, and gave it me. I have been in the king's service this seven years: I was paid off from the Saltash man of war at Deptford.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17630518-14-verdict86" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630518-14-verdict86" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
