<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17641212-28">
               <interp inst="t17641212-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641212-28" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641212-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17641212"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641212-28" type="date" value="17641212"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17641212-28-off146-c176" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-28-defend233 t17641212-28-off146 t17641212-28-verdict150"></join>
         
               <p>30. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17641212-28-defend233" type="defendantName">
                     Francis 
                     Tophurst 
                  <interp inst="t17641212-28-defend233" type="surname" value="Tophurst"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-28-defend233" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-28-defend233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17641212-28-off146" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17641212-28-off146" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-28-off146" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing a silver watch, value 50 s. a 27 shilling piece, and six shillings in money, numbered, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17641212-28-victim235" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Clark 
                        <interp inst="t17641212-28-victim235" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17641212-28-victim235" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17641212-28-victim235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-28-off146 t17641212-28-victim235"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17641212-28-cd147" type="crimeDate">October 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-28-off146 t17641212-28-cd147"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641212-28-person236">
                  William 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17641212-28-person236" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-28-person236" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-28-person236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was a <rs id="t17641212-28-viclabel148" type="occupation">soldier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-28-victim235 t17641212-28-viclabel148"></join>, but was discharged last week: I was going from the Isle of Jersey, on a furlough, to Newcastle upon Tyne; I was a stranger in London; I lay at a private house in <placeName id="t17641212-28-crimeloc149">Church-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17641212-28-crimeloc149" type="placeName" value="Church-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17641212-28-crimeloc149" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-28-off146 t17641212-28-crimeloc149"></join>; I was in liquor, and my sight being bad, could not find my way to Milbank, where I had lain two nights before.</p>
               <p>Q. Where had you been?</p>
               <p>Clark. I had been at the Turk's Head with an old soldier that I knew.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go into that private house alone?</p>
               <p>Clark. There was an old woman that I pick'd up in the street; she took me to the house; I can't tell the landlord's name; I got there a little after ten o'clock; I had my watch and moidore in one pocket, and six shillings in the other; I pull'd out my watch to see what time it was, when I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176412120016"></xptr> went to bed; and I had a pot of beer after I was in bed: there was a woman that lay in the next room; she came into my room; I gave her six-pence to go for the beer; she drank twice of it, and I gave her two pence for her trouble; she saw me pull my watch out; I put my breeches, with my watch and money under my head; and in the morning, my breeches were lying in the room, and my watch and money gone; I awaked a little before seven; by that time that woman and her companion was gone; the woman with whom I went to bed was still with me; the prisoner was her companion; I never saw him before he was taken up: I went and got a warrant to take that woman up, upon suspicion; she went by the same name; this was on the 10th of October, and the prisoner was committed the 18th: I took her up, and by her information, we found the watch near St. George's church, in the Borough; the pawnbroker is named Davidson. (The watch produced and deposed to). The Justice set 
               <persName id="t17641212-28-person237">
                  Ann 
                  Tophurst 
               <interp inst="t17641212-28-person237" type="surname" value="Tophurst"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-28-person237" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-28-person237" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             at liberty: the pawnbroker took the prisoner up.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641212-28-person238">
                  William 
                  Davidson 
               <interp inst="t17641212-28-person238" type="surname" value="Davidson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-28-person238" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-28-person238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live next door to St. George's Church, in the Borough; this watch produced here the prisoner at the bar brought to me the 11th of October, and said it was his own, and said he lived with Mr. Rogers, a Fishmonger, in Thames-street; he asked a guinea and a half upon it; I lent him 27 s. upon it. On the 15th the prosecutor and another man came to enquire for a watch that was left with me the Thursday before: they described it both by name and number; I went with them to Justice Welch; he desired I would take care of the watch, and if the thief came again, to stop him. On the 17th the prisoner came, with a servant to a man that sells things by Auction; the servant was to advance the money to take it out, and they were to sell it: I charged a constable with the prisoner, and carried him before Justice Welch; he said it was his own watch, and did not care where I carried him: first of all, he said he bought it in Dark-house lane for half a guinea, of a man that he did not know, about a week before: when the woman was brought and examined, they were examined separately; he said the woman had part of the money, and that there was another woman in the room; that they stole it, and he went and pawned it, and they all had a share of the money.</p>
               <p>The prisoner said nothing in his defence.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17641212-28-verdict150" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17641212-28-verdict150" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-28-verdict150" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               Guilty of stealing, but not privately from his person
            </rs>. <rs id="t17641212-28-punish151" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17641212-28-punish151" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-28-defend233 t17641212-28-punish151"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
