<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17641212-34">
               <interp inst="t17641212-34" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641212-34" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641212-34" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17641212"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641212-34" type="date" value="17641212"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17641212-34-off179-c213" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-34-defend284 t17641212-34-off179 t17641212-34-verdict182"></join>
         
               <p>36. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17641212-34-defend284" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Whitton 
                  <interp inst="t17641212-34-defend284" type="surname" value="Whitton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-34-defend284" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-34-defend284" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17641212-34-off179" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17641212-34-off179" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-34-off179" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a cloth coat, value 20 s. a cloth waistcoat, value 10 s. a shag waistcoat, value 10 s. a napkeen waistcoat, value 8 s. a linen shirt, value 3 s. a pair of cotton stockings, value 1 s. and a pair of worsted stockings, value 1 s. 20 iron bits, a Guinea, two quarter guineas, and 23 shillings and six-pence in money numbered, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17641212-34-victim286" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Sims 
                        <interp inst="t17641212-34-victim286" type="surname" value="Sims"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17641212-34-victim286" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17641212-34-victim286" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-34-off179 t17641212-34-victim286"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling house of 
                     <persName id="t17641212-34-person287">
                        Mary 
                        Guest 
                     <interp inst="t17641212-34-person287" type="surname" value="Guest"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17641212-34-person287" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17641212-34-person287" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17641212-34-cd180" type="crimeDate">December 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-34-off179 t17641212-34-cd180"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641212-34-person288">
                  John 
                  Sims 
               <interp inst="t17641212-34-person288" type="surname" value="Sims"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-34-person288" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-34-person288" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17641212-34-viclabel181" type="occupation">Carpenter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-34-victim286 t17641212-34-viclabel181"></join>; I have lodged in the house of 
               <persName id="t17641212-34-person289">
                  Mary 
                  Guest 
               <interp inst="t17641212-34-person289" type="surname" value="Guest"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-34-person289" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-34-person289" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             about twelve months; I left my chest there, with a cloth coat, three waistcoats, a shag, a cloth, and a nankeen; a shirt, a pair of cotton stockings, and a pair of worsted stockings; twenty bits for carpenters use, made of steel; a guinea, two quarter guineas, and the rest in silver, to make up 55 s. all locked in it; I had the key; my landlady asked me if I should come back again? I said I was not certain; so she took in the prisoner: I happened to come home this day week, and found my chest broke open; I looked round the room, and found nothing in it belonging to me, but the bare chest, and a few trifling things: I came down and asked Mrs. Guest whether that man lodged with her? she said, Yes; and that he had been gone out about an hour: I told her he had taken all I had: she went up and found it so: looking round the room, I found a pillow-bier full of tools, and his own clothes upon them; she said he would come back again soon; that he was gone to the jolly sailors; I said, If he is as big as Goliah, I'll take him; we went out and saw him coming; when he came to the door, I said, you are my prisoner, till an officer comes: he said, What's the matter? what's the matter? I sent for an officer; this was in Mrs. Guest's house: I said, are not you a villain, to rob me so? said he, Countryman, don't be hard upon me: the officer came in; we took him to a public house; he had breeches on, that long to a suit of clothes of mine; we found a penny chip box, that my money was in, was thrown into the close-stool, and there lay his breeches over it in the close-stool; he acknowledged taking all the things but the money; he said he had not seen any money: he was asked how he came to put the box into the close-stool? to which he made no answer: he had left my coat and a piece of dowlas at Mrs. Murray's, at the Noah's Ark, where he had had a shilling in eatables.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that?</p>
               <p>Sims. He told us so; we found them there; some of the other things he had sold, and some he had pawned: in shaking the breeches he had on, out fell a piece of copper, that had been among my money, when in the chest: he was put into the watch-house, and the next morning carried before the bench of Justices in Whitechapel, and was committed.</p>
               <p>Q. What were your clothes worth?</p>
               <p>Sims. The suit of clothes cost me five guineas, not three months ago.</p>
               <p>Mr. Danislow. I am an officer; I was sent for to carry the prisoner to the watch-house: I found this coat at Mrs. Murray's (producing it): this pair of breeches the prisoner had on; (producing them and a waistcoat: deposed to by prosecutor.)</p>
               <p>Mrs. Murray. The prisoner brought this coat and left it with me last Thursday, between 11 and 12 o'clock; he desired I would put it by till he called for it; he had had a shilling in meat and drink, and asked me for a lodging.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>As to the money, I know nothing of it; I never saw it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17641212-34-verdict182" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17641212-34-verdict182" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17641212-34-punish183" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17641212-34-punish183" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-34-defend284 t17641212-34-punish183"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
