<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17601022-12">
               <interp inst="t17601022-12" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17601022-12" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17601022-12" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17601022"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17601022-12" type="date" value="17601022"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17601022-12-off72-c116" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-12-defend138 t17601022-12-off72 t17601022-12-verdict76"></join>
         
               <p>302. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17601022-12-defend138" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Anderson 
                  <interp inst="t17601022-12-defend138" type="surname" value="Anderson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-defend138" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-defend138" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17601022-12-off72" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-off72" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-off72" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing five several warrants, one for the payment of 16 l. 9 s. 4 d. to 
                     <persName id="t17601022-12-person139">
                        William 
                        Lawson 
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-person139" type="surname" value="Lawson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17601022-12-person139" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17601022-12-person139" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  . One for the payment of 46 l. 4 s. 11 d. to 
                     <persName id="t17601022-12-person140">
                        John 
                        Nodes 
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-person140" type="surname" value="Nodes"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17601022-12-person140" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17601022-12-person140" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  . One for the payment of 3 l. 11 s 4 d. to 
                     <persName id="t17601022-12-person141">
                        Alexander 
                        Petery 
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-person141" type="surname" value="Petery"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17601022-12-person141" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17601022-12-person141" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  . One for the payment of 3 l. 11 s. 4 d. to 
                     <persName id="t17601022-12-person142">
                        John 
                        Patterson 
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-person142" type="surname" value="Patterson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17601022-12-person142" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17601022-12-person142" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  . One for the payment of 3 l. 11 s. 4 d. to 
                     <persName id="t17601022-12-person143">
                        Samuel 
                        Wilson 
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-person143" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17601022-12-person143" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17601022-12-person143" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  . The said money being then unpaid, and one promisory note, value 4 l. 3 s. 6 d. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17601022-12-victim145" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Morris 
                        <interp inst="t17601022-12-victim145" type="surname" value="Morris"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17601022-12-victim145" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17601022-12-victim145" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , and three other promisory notes
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17601022-12-victim147" type="victimName">
                     Deborah 
                     Morris 
                  <interp inst="t17601022-12-victim147" type="surname" value="Morris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-victim147" type="given" value="Deborah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-victim147" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17601022-12-viclabel73" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-12-victim147 t17601022-12-viclabel73"></join>, <rs id="t17601022-12-cd74" type="crimeDate">December 2. 1760</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-12-off72 t17601022-12-cd74"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601022-12-person148">
                  Thomas 
                  Morris 
               <interp inst="t17601022-12-person148" type="surname" value="Morris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-person148" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-person148" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17601022-12-viclabel75" type="occupation">cabinet-maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-12-victim145 t17601022-12-viclabel75"></join>. I was persuaded by the prisoner at the bar to buy these several seamen's tickets. I lost them all five, and found three of them again.</p>
               <p>Court. Give an account when and how you lost them.</p>
               <p>Morris. I went down to the navy office to have them cast up. I had them, with the notes mention'd, in a canvas-bag. I had lent the prisoner 4 l. to take him out of a spunging-house, and I call'd upon him to see if he could pay me, either the whole or part of it; going cross Tower-hill, we met with 
               <persName id="t17601022-12-person149">
                  Archibald 
                  Glass 
               <interp inst="t17601022-12-person149" type="surname" value="Glass"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-person149" type="given" value="Archibald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-person149" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; we went in at the sign of the 13 Cantoons on Tower hill. I show'd the tickets to Glass, one by one.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to take them out to show to him?</p>
               <p>Morris. I did it at the desire of the prisoner. He said to me, as you are a stranger to this navy-affair, if you will show them to my friend, he'll let you know whether they are good or bad (I had never seen any seamen's tickets before I had these) one of them cost me 46 l. and upwards. The prisoner, instead of paying me my money, he dilly-dally'd me about from place to place.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Morris. This was on the 2d of Decemb. 1756; he desired me to go to John Hambleton's, at the Black-boy at the Hermitage; he said, he would treat me there, so he, I, and Glass went there.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you your bag of papers when you went in there?</p>
               <p>Morris. I had, very safe; I was very suspicious of the prisoner, for he would always be on that side me where I had them, and I thought he had some design of taking them from me; it was about four o'clock when I went there, and I continued there till half an hour after ten. Then I said, Mr. Anderson, can you give me any money? he said, he could not that night; we call'd the reckoning; I had observ'd the prisoner to take Glass out, to talk together several times at the door for four or five minutes; at the time I kept my hand on my bag of papers, the prisoner's wife came and inquired after him; Glass said to me, pray is your name Morris? I said, yes; (I had never seen him before) he said, will you give Mr. 
               <persName id="t17601022-12-person150">
                  Anderson
               <interp inst="t17601022-12-person150" type="given" value="Anderson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-person150" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a receipt for all debts, dues, and demands; I said, who set you on to ask this, why should I do that, when he owes me 4 l. We parted, and I did not miss my bag of papers till next morning, at about seven o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you give an account where you lost them?</p>
               <p>Morris. I am very sure I lost them at going down the steps from the door, or in that house, but I believe in going down the steps; I went to the prisoner's house upon missing them; I ask'd<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176010220015"></xptr> him, if he knew any thing of them; he said, Mr. Morris, you have not lost them; somebody has play'd the rogue with them, you'll have them again; I said, I beg for Christ's sake you would help me to them; then he said, I know nothing of them. On the 11th of February last I heard two of them were paid; one was in the hands of Mr. 
               <persName id="t17601022-12-person151">
                  Joseph 
                  Murrey 
               <interp inst="t17601022-12-person151" type="surname" value="Murrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-person151" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-person151" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , that is, that of 
               <persName id="t17601022-12-person152">
                  John 
                  Nodes 
               <interp inst="t17601022-12-person152" type="surname" value="Nodes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-person152" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-person152" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, pawn'd by the prisoner at the bar for 12 l. 2 s. 6 d. the next day I went to the goal to the prisoner; he told me, another ticket was in pawn to Mr. Miles Row for 6 guineas.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the prisoner then?</p>
               <p>Morris. He was then in Gosport bridewell; the prisoner own'd he pawn'd that to Mr. Murrey, and Mr. Murrey delivered it to Anderson, and Anderson to me.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Morris. This was on the 23d of April last; the third I found with Mr. 
               <persName id="t17601022-12-person153">
                  William 
                  Humbley 
               <interp inst="t17601022-12-person153" type="surname" value="Humbley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-person153" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-person153" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             pawn'd for 48 s. and 10 d. the name of that ticket was 
               <persName id="t17601022-12-person154">
                  Alexander 
                  Ubly 
               <interp inst="t17601022-12-person154" type="surname" value="Ubly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-person154" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-person154" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; the prisoner said, he did not remember he had taken one, but if he had he had lost it, and he would be accountable to me for the money. The others are all paid; Anderson own'd to me, he had receiv'd the money for them. I apprehended the prisoner on the 22d of April, with my lord Mansfield's warrant, at Gosport; the prisoner never own'd to having the notes of hand.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. Whether I did not give you a note for 4 l. for the use of them, and they were put into my hands by your consent?</p>
               <p>Morris. No; he gave me a note of hand for a note that was lost among the papers, but not on any such condition as he would insinuate. I lost more notes than these laid in the indictment; here is a person in court that saw that note wrote.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I acknowledge I came out at the door five or six times to talk to Mr. Glass; I would ask him, why he call'd for two tankards of beer at one time for?</p>
               <p>Morris. I don't know that I did.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. It was on purpose that I should take the silver tankard away, and leave the pewter one in its place; the silver tankard was not mark'd.</p>
               <p>Court. How could you leave one tankard in the room of two?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601022-12-person155">
                  William 
                  Ubly 
               <interp inst="t17601022-12-person155" type="surname" value="Ubly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-person155" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-person155" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . (he takes a seaman's ticket in his hand) This to 
               <persName id="t17601022-12-person156">
                  Alexander 
                  Petery 
               <interp inst="t17601022-12-person156" type="surname" value="Petery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-person156" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-person156" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I receiv'd this ticket of the prisoner at the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. When?</p>
               <p>Ubly. About two years and a half ago, in the payment of a debt he owed me, 2 l. 8 s. 10 d.</p>
               <p>Q. to Morris. Look at this ticket.</p>
               <p>Morris. (he takes it in his hand) This is one of the tickets which I lost; it is for the Royal George. Here are the other two which I have got again. They three are worth about 70 l.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I did leave that note with Mr. Ubly for some security for what I ow'd him; I told him I would take it again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601022-12-person157">
                  Alexander 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17601022-12-person157" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-person157" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-person157" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I receiv'd a ticket of the prisoner at the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the name of that ticket?</p>
               <p>Smith. I can't remember the man's name. I gave him 3 l. 8 s. for it.</p>
               <p>Q. When?</p>
               <p>Smith. On the 14th of April, 1757.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do with that ticket?</p>
               <p>Smith. I gave it to Mr. Mould.</p>
               <p>Mr. Mould. I receiv'd a ticket of Mr. Smith, I can't tell whose it was.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do with it?</p>
               <p>Mould. I gave it to Mr. Charley at the navy-office, and receiv'd the money of him, and gave him a receipt for it.</p>
               <p>Q. Should you know it again?</p>
               <p>Mould. I should.</p>
               <p>Q. What is Mr. Charley?</p>
               <p>Mould. He is a clerk in the navy office.</p>
               <p>Alexander Charley. I remember paying Mr. Mould for a ticket.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the name?</p>
               <p>Charley. It was 
               <persName id="t17601022-12-person158">
                  John 
                  Patterson 
               <interp inst="t17601022-12-person158" type="surname" value="Patterson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-person158" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-person158" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             of the Royal George, for 3 l. 10 s. 6 d.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at these three tickets.</p>
               <p>Charley. (He takes them in his hand.) These are three seamen's tickets.</p>
               <p>Q. Look on any one of them; tell the name and the sum.</p>
               <p>Charley. I suppose these are cast up, but whether by people in the office or not, I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your method of casting them up?</p>
               <p>Charley. They are cast up by three people.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you with any certainty tell how much is due on any one of them?</p>
               <p>Charley. I can in some little time; but there is no ascertaining the exact sum of these tickets; there may be something more upon the books than on these tickets.</p>
               <p>Q. If you buy a seaman's ticket, are you certain of any particular sum?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176010220016"></xptr>Charley. No, I am not, but I take it according to what may appear to me upon the book, when the account is made up, the ticket is not a determin'd account of any certain sum of money.</p>
               <p>Q. Look upon the ticket, 
               <persName id="t17601022-12-person159">
                  William 
                  Lawson 
               <interp inst="t17601022-12-person159" type="surname" value="Lawson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-person159" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-person159" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Charley. (He takes it in his hand.)</p>
               <p>Q. Is that ticket worth any thing upon the face of it?</p>
               <p>Charley. It cannot be said to be worth any thing till it comes to be cast up, and comes for payment; they pay to the chest at Chatham is a month, and to Greenwich hospital 6 d. per month; there are four officers sign the ticket, the captain, the master, the purser, and the boatswain; there should be an account of what he is indebted to the ship's book.</p>
               <p>Q. Can a man go to the navy office, and ask for his wages, without producing a ticket?</p>
               <p>Charley. No, he cannot.</p>
               <p>Q Whether, from the uncertainty of the instrument, it is such a warrant for the payment of money, as the act of parliament mentions, are you prepared to give in evidence how much is exactly due on this ticket?</p>
               <p>Charley. No; there are five books delivered in, before the ticket can be paid; they are all produced at the pay-table together, and all to correspond when the ticket is examined; till the time of payment, it can never be exactly known what is the value to be receiv'd. A ticket may be brought to the office, when the materials are not there to examine it by.</p>
               <p>Q. Then you can't with no certainty tell what is due on any of these three tickets.</p>
               <p>Charley. No, nobody can tell without the ship's pay-books.</p>
               <p>Court. Then those can be no warrants for the payment of any certain sums of money.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17601022-12-verdict76" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17601022-12-verdict76" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>* See No 264. in last paper. </p>
            </div1>
