<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17600521-1">
               <interp inst="t17600521-1" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600521-1" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600521-1" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600521"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600521-1" type="date" value="17600521"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600521-1-off2-c30" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600521-1-defend31 t17600521-1-off2 t17600521-1-verdict5"></join>
         
               <p>173. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17600521-1-defend31" type="defendantName">
                     Esther 
                     Urwin 
                  <interp inst="t17600521-1-defend31" type="surname" value="Urwin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-1-defend31" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-1-defend31" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17600521-1-deflabel1" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600521-1-defend31 t17600521-1-deflabel1"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17600521-1-off2" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600521-1-off2" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-1-off2" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 3 silver tea spoons, value 3 s. one pair of silver tea tongs, value 1 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17600521-1-victim33" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Brown 
                  <interp inst="t17600521-1-victim33" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-1-victim33" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-1-victim33" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600521-1-off2 t17600521-1-victim33"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17600521-1-cd3" type="crimeDate">April 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600521-1-off2 t17600521-1-cd3"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600521-1-person34">
                  William 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17600521-1-person34" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-1-person34" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-1-person34" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Kensington Gore, the prisoner came to live with me, on trial as a <rs id="t17600521-1-deflabel4" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600521-1-defend31 t17600521-1-deflabel4"></join>, some time in March.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your imployment?</p>
               <p>Brown. I keep a public house, I had company, there were 3 Ladies which drank tea; I gave the prisoner 3 tea spoons and tongs for their use, about 6 in the evening.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had she lived with you?</p>
               <p>Brown. About 7 or 8 days; after they had drank tea, I look'd in her face, and thought she look'd a little stupid in liquor, I order'd her to wash the spoons up, and put them into their proper place where they always are; this was near 8 o'clock; in about half an hour she took her bundles, and slipp'd off with the spoons in her pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that?</p>
               <p>Brown. There was a painter there that told me. as soon as we miss'd her, that he saw her put the spoons in her pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he here?</p>
               <p>Brown. No; he was a stranger to me. About 5 weeks afterwards, as I was going through St. Giles's, I saw her come out of a house; she seeing me, ran away, and through a house, and into another; I pursued and took her, and carried her before justice Fielding. She begg'd I would not take her there; and said, she would tell me where my things were: she own'd she had pawn'd them at the corner of Russel court, Drury Lane, at the house of one Rochford. I lost 3 spoons, but she own'd but to 2, and the tongs. Mr. Fielding sent for the pawnbroker, and his servant that took them in came; and she own'd she pawn'd them to him. (produced in court, and deposed too.) They have the same marks which they had when I bought them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600521-1-person35">
                  Peter 
                  Peel 
               <interp inst="t17600521-1-person35" type="surname" value="Peel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-1-person35" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-1-person35" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mr. Rochford, a pawnbroker, I took these spoons and tongs in of a woman; I can't recollect the prisoner, they were brought at 2 separate times. I lent her 4 s. on the whole; I heard the prisoner own before the Justice she pawn'd them with me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I am very sorry for what I have done, but I was not in my senses when I did it, my master has not paid me my wages.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176005210003"></xptr>Q. to prosecutor. Did you take her to be out of her senses?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No, I did not; I thought her to be a little in liquor then, for the time she was there I owe her about 15 d. it cannot be above that, but I will give her half a crown (which he did) telling her he was sorry for her; recommending her to the court for mercy.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600521-1-verdict5" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600521-1-verdict5" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>After she was found guilty, instead of returning her master thanks for his civility, and recommending her, &amp;c. she curs'd him, and wished he might break his neck before he got home.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600521-1-punish6" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600521-1-punish6" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600521-1-defend31 t17600521-1-punish6"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
