<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17631019-13">
               <interp inst="t17631019-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631019-13" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631019-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17631019"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631019-13" type="date" value="17631019"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17631019-13-off68-c99" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631019-13-defend133 t17631019-13-off68 t17631019-13-verdict70"></join>
         
               <p>474. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17631019-13-defend133" type="defendantName">
                     George 
                     Kelly 
                  <interp inst="t17631019-13-defend133" type="surname" value="Kelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-13-defend133" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-13-defend133" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for that <rs id="t17631019-13-off68" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631019-13-off68" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-13-off68" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               he, on the <rs id="t17631019-13-cd69" type="crimeDate">8th of October</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631019-13-off68 t17631019-13-cd69"></join>, about the hour of 10 in the night, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17631019-13-victim135" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Sinclair 
                        <interp inst="t17631019-13-victim135" type="surname" value="Sinclair"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17631019-13-victim135" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17631019-13-victim135" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631019-13-off68 t17631019-13-victim135"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did break and enter, and stealing one silver watch, value 4 l. one silver seal, value 6 d. six linnen shirts, value 36 s. three half guineas, four quarter guineas, and 26 s. in money numbered, the property of the said Robert, in his dwelling-house
            </rs>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631019-13-person136">
                  Robert 
                  Sinclair 
               <interp inst="t17631019-13-person136" type="surname" value="Sinclair"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-13-person136" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-13-person136" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 8th of October I had been out, and going home as the watch was going eleven, having nobody in the house but myself, I went to bed, and the next morning, going to look for a shirt, found the money and things mentioned were gone; I found a pane of glass out and the casement open, I suspected the prisoner and took him before the Justice, he began to beg my pardon; the Justice asked him what he had done with the money; he said he bought a blue surtoute coat that morning with part of it: I found my shirts in his lodgings afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were the things when you went out?</p>
               <p>Sinclair. My money was in a little till in a chest in my bed-chamber, and my watch hanging up by my bed-side, and my shirts were lying dirty in a basket.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631019-13-person137">
                  Richard 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17631019-13-person137" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-13-person137" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-13-person137" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am headborough, I took the watch out of the inside of the prisoner's breeches before the Justice, he delivered up to me two quarter guineas which he had left with his landlady; I examined him in a public-house, he said he would give a bond to make the deficiency of what was lost, and he would work it out; Mr. Sinclair declared he would not be concerned with him upon any score. (He produced the shirts and watch deposed to by the prosecutor.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631019-13-person138">
                  John 
                  George 
               <interp inst="t17631019-13-person138" type="surname" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-13-person138" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-13-person138" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner lodged at my house, on Saturday night he brought half a dozen shirts to wash.</p>
               <p>Q. How near do you live to the prosecutor?</p>
               <p>George. Not above 40 poles; on the Sunday they came with a search-warrant, the shirts appear'd to be Mr. Sinclair's property, with the initial letters of his name upon them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was coming home at half an hour after 8 from Shoreditch turnpike, there was a man<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176310190008"></xptr> standing with a bundle in his hand, I asked him what he was standing looking about for, he said I want to speak with you, I am in distress and have something to sell, and if you'll buy them I'll sell them cheap: I said I wanted no such thing; I said, if I had them I would go to a public-house; he would not, then I said you have not come honestly by them: He asked a guinea and half for the six shirts, I gave him 24 s. that was 4 s. a-piece; after that he asked me if I would buy a watch; I said I never wear any; he said he bought it since he came from sea, and had no money left; he asked me two guineas and a half, I offer'd him two guineas and went away, he follow'd me and gave it me, and I gave him two guineas; I immediately went in at the White-hart, then it was 5 minutes after 10, then I went home to my own lodging, I was so drunk I was hardly capable of walking.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17631019-13-verdict70" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631019-13-verdict70" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17631019-13-punish71" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631019-13-punish71" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631019-13-defend133 t17631019-13-punish71"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
