<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17641017-30">
               <interp inst="t17641017-30" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641017-30" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641017-30" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17641017"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641017-30" type="date" value="17641017"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17641017-30-off162-c282" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641017-30-defend346 t17641017-30-off162 t17641017-30-verdict165"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17641017-30-off162-c283" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641017-30-defend348 t17641017-30-off162 t17641017-30-verdict165"></join>
         
               <p>578, 579. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17641017-30-defend346" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Wright 
                  <interp inst="t17641017-30-defend346" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-defend346" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-defend346" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17641017-30-defend348" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Shittle 
                  <interp inst="t17641017-30-defend348" type="surname" value="Shittle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-defend348" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-defend348" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted, together with 
               <persName id="t17641017-30-person349">
                  John 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17641017-30-person349" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person349" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person349" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , not yet taken, for making an <rs id="t17641017-30-off162" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-off162" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-off162" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               assault on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17641017-30-victim351" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Mell 
                        <interp inst="t17641017-30-victim351" type="surname" value="Mell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17641017-30-victim351" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17641017-30-victim351" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641017-30-off162 t17641017-30-victim351"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , on the King's highway, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and violently taking from his person two clasp knives, value 6 d. one brass inkhorn, value 6 d. one worsted purse, value one penny, one linen purse, value one farthing, and two-pence three farthings, in money, numbered. the property of the said William
            </rs>, <rs id="t17641017-30-cd163" type="crimeDate">October 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641017-30-off162 t17641017-30-cd163"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>At the request of the prisoners, the witnesses were examined separate.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641017-30-person352">
                  William 
                  Mell 
               <interp inst="t17641017-30-person352" type="surname" value="Mell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person352" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person352" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was called, and did not appear. His recognizance was ordered to be estreated.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641017-30-person353">
                  Martha 
                  Wolfe 
               <interp inst="t17641017-30-person353" type="surname" value="Wolfe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person353" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person353" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in company last Friday night with 
               <persName id="t17641017-30-person354">
                  William 
                  Mell 
               <interp inst="t17641017-30-person354" type="surname" value="Mell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person354" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person354" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in a public-house, the Marquis of Granby's Head, in Chick-lane.</p>
               <p>Q. What is he?</p>
               <p>M. Wolfe. He lives <rs id="t17641017-30-viclabel164" type="occupation">servant with a brewer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641017-30-victim351 t17641017-30-viclabel164"></join>; I was with him all the afternoon: the prisoners came to the door to me, and 
               <persName id="t17641017-30-person355">
                  James 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17641017-30-person355" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person355" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person355" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said, Wolfe, give me a dram; I gave them each a glass; we had a quartern between us three: after that, a young girl in company said, the man has money, I'd have you rob him? No, said I, I will not do any such thing. Said she, this young man, in his own hair, that I gave a dram to, will do it, if I would let him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mell hear that?</p>
               <p>Wolfe. No, he did not; it was whispered in my ear. Then Wright said, let's go to another house: we went then to the One Tun, in Chick-lane; Mell went with me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he drunk, or sober?</p>
               <p>Wolfe. He was middling, between half and half; I had hold on one of his arms, and Wright on the other: Shittle went with us. Then John Wright came (he is not in custody); they called him in: 
               <persName id="t17641017-30-person356">
                  John 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17641017-30-person356" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person356" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person356" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said, has he got any money? I said I saw money: then we went on, and down the road together; we went in at a public-house, just by Battle-bridge, and had a pot of beer; then they said, let us take him down the road; when we came down the road, 
               <persName id="t17641017-30-person357">
                  James 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17641017-30-person357" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person357" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person357" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             held Mell by one arm, and I the other: the first thing done, was, I picked his pocket of a purse, and five farthings; that I took out of his right hand pocket: I held his arm with my right hand, and picked his pocket with my left hand: he struggled very hard at the time. When Wright found he struggled, he said, You had better let her take it; for if you do'nt by fair means, you shall by foul: then I felt in his breeches pocket again, and took out another purse (a sort of a net-one) made of pack-thread; there were two pieces of money in it; one seemed to be half a guinea; 
               <persName id="t17641017-30-person358">
                  John 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17641017-30-person358" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person358" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person358" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             snatched it out of my hand, and gave it to Shittle: I took two clasp knives, and a brass ink-horn, out of his waistcoat pocket: after that, 
               <persName id="t17641017-30-person359">
                  John 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17641017-30-person359" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person359" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person359" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sharped a knife upon a stone, and began to be very resolute, and said, if I did not rob him, he would kill the man and me too: the others said, no, don't take his life. Then we left him in the middle of the road, and went to a publick-house and divided the money. I said, you have got half a guinea; Wright said, you b - h, here is no half guinea; we will have you taken and hanged. Shittle took the purse, and threw it in the fire, and 
               <persName id="t17641017-30-person360">
                  John 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17641017-30-person360" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person360" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person360" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             picked it up.</p>
               <p>Q. What public house was this?</p>
               <p>Wolfe. It is an ale-house near where the robbery was done: they would have murdered me, if I had not run away; I don't know the sign: there were six of them came about me: there were the two prisoners, 
               <persName id="t17641017-30-person361">
                  John 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17641017-30-person361" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person361" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person361" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17641017-30-person362">
                  Joe 
                  Makedy 
               <interp inst="t17641017-30-person362" type="surname" value="Makedy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person362" type="given" value="Joe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person362" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and one Sarah, a creature he keeps company with, and a woman that the prisoner Wright keeps company with; they call'd me all the b - s, and swore they would kill me, or have me taken up and hanged. I went home; the prisoners came into Chick-lane, and told people, if ever they met me, what they<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176410170026"></xptr> would do to me, and on the Saturday night I went and resigned myself to Mr. Deleney. The first that I had apprehended, was the woman that 
               <persName id="t17641017-30-person363">
                  James 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17641017-30-person363" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person363" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person363" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             lives with; she sells goods that he steals: we went before Justice Girdler; he admitted me an evidence; then we found the prosecutor, and he swore the same as I do. This was the first time I ever was guilty, and my conscience pricked me; and I do this to serve my King and Country.</p>
               <p>Shittle. This evidence lived with 
               <persName id="t17641017-30-person364">
                  Anthony 
                  Carrol 
               <interp inst="t17641017-30-person364" type="surname" value="Carrol"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person364" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person364" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , that was tried last Sessions.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you in company with Mell?</p>
               <p>Wolfe. He was drinking in company, and I was a disorderly woman; he asked me to drink, and I kept him company all the afternoon. Shittle owned before the Justice, to his being down the road with me.</p>
               <p>Israel Wolfe. I am father to 
               <persName id="t17641017-30-person365">
                  Martha 
                  Wolfe 
               <interp inst="t17641017-30-person365" type="surname" value="Wolfe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person365" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person365" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            : last Friday I was in search of the prosecutor, to find him, in behalf of my daughter; I found him in Chick-lane: I asked him whether he had been robbed by any person? he said, yes: I desired him to go with me to the constable; he would not: I went and told the constable where the prosecutor was; he said he had no right to go there, for that was in the city: he said, if I could get him to come to him in good will, well and good: I and another person went and got him to come; then he opened all the story; then the constable said, he must get him to go along with him, to Justice Girdler: we went first to New-Prison: as soon as he came there, he knew the evidence and 
               <persName id="t17641017-30-person366">
                  James 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17641017-30-person366" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person366" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person366" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; saying, that is the man that had hold of my arm, upon the spot where I was robb'd. Wright said, can you say so? he said, yes; you are the man: and as for Shittle, he said he was with them, and walked up and down round him; but never meddled with him: he said there was another man drawed a knife out, and sharpened it on a stone; and 
               <persName id="t17641017-30-person367">
                  James 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17641017-30-person367" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person367" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person367" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said at the time,</p>
               <p>"you had better be easy, or we'll make you</p>
               <p>"easy:" and after they had got what they could, they let him go; and he went one way, and they another. We went to Justice Girdler; the prosecutor said the same there: the Justice asked him where he lived? and whether he had any body to be bound in recognizance for his appearing to prosecute? he said he had not: then the Justice said he must send him to a place of safety till the trial came on: he agreed to go to Clerkenwell Bridewell: this was on the Friday night: I went to the Justice after that, and the Justice told me he had sent for him, and examined him again; and he had made a greater discovery than before; and he had set him at liberty, and given him a crown to support him, and bound him over in his own recognizance: I have been to search for him, and he is not to be found.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641017-30-person368">
                  John 
                  Deleney 
               <interp inst="t17641017-30-person368" type="surname" value="Deleney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person368" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person368" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am headborough of the parish of St. Sepulchre; I had a prisoner in custody; this girl Wolfe applied to me in Chick-lane: she said she had been an accomplice with three men in a robbery; and if I would take her into custody, she would shew me where they were. She carried me to the Castle, opposite Chick-lane; there she shewed me the two prisoners, and gave me charge of them, for committing a robbery at the upper end of Gray's-Inn-lane; they were examined before the Justice: there she told the particular place; the Justice was not satisfied till she would go with me and show me the place, which she did; she said they robbed the man of two clasp knives, some farthings, and two purses: I think she said she went to the sign of the Yorkshire Grey, and the robbery was done near the Foundling Hospital burying-ground: that 
               <persName id="t17641017-30-person369">
                  John 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17641017-30-person369" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person369" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person369" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             took out a knife and whetted it on a stone, and said, if she did not rob this man, he would kill her; and she accordingly did rob the man: and that those men which were at her elbow conveyed the things away immediately.</p>
               <p>Q. What answer did the prisoners give to this?</p>
               <p>Deleney. They did admit they were at the Yorkshire Grey with her about the hour she mentioned; that they did go up to the upper end of Gray's-Inn-lane, but they denied the fact of the robbery: his worship was satisfied they were accomplices; they were both examined separate; they both owned to the same purport. Mell was found the next day, and he went before Justice Girdler; the Justice would not examine him till such time he sent for the prisoners; they were brought face to face: Mell said he knew Wright very well; but as to the other prisoner, he was in a doubt about him, because it was dark, or something like it; he said there was another person in company; the Justice asked him if he was certain he was robbed? he said he was, of the things mentioned: he was bound over, and sent to Clerkenwell for security, to give evidence here.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641017-30-person370">
                  Thomas 
                  Pentilow 
               <interp inst="t17641017-30-person370" type="surname" value="Pentilow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person370" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person370" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to the keeper of New-Prison: last saturday was se'ennight, I was in company with Mr. Deleney: we had a man committed to New-Prison; he said he could discover a set of very bad people; we went down to Chick-lane, to the Marquis of Granby's Head;<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176410170027"></xptr> this woman, Wolfe, was in the house: going up Black-Boy-Alley, she came running after us, and said, It is a pity the innocent should suffer; I can open such a scene of villainy, that will take me up some time, of a street-robbery. She shewed us the two prisoners; we took them in custody, and carried them to New-Prison; they were taken on the Monday before Justice Girdler; she charged them with a street-robbery in Gray's-Inn-lane; she said she had been along with a man, and the two prisoners and another man were with her, at the Yorkshire Grey, at the corner of the road; that she got hold of him, and led him up to the Blue Lion, and turned round the corner; that one of the men 
               <persName id="t17641017-30-person371">
                  drew
               <interp inst="t17641017-30-person371" type="given" value="drew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person371" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a knife, and sharped it on a stone, and insisted on her robbing the man, and accordingly she did rob him; that there were some farthings, a couple of clasp knives, and a canvas bag, or something of that sort, taken from him; that then they took hold of her, and swore, if she did not give the things to them, they would kill her with the knife. When the prisoners were examined, they did not deny being in company with this woman; but they denied that of the robbery.</p>
               <p>Wright's Defence.</p>
               <p>Last Friday se'ennight, about half an hour after four o'clock, Shittle said he had been at work at New Cross, Deptford; he asked me if I would drink part of a pint of beer with him, we went to the Marquis of Granby's head; the girl Wolfe was sitting in company with a man much in liquor; she said, young man, if you will see this man home, I shall be obliged to you: I took hold of one arm, and she the other; we went down to the One Tun, and had a pot of beer; she paid for it; then we went to the Yorkshire Grey; there we had another; I came away and left the man, she, and 
               <persName id="t17641017-30-person372">
                  John 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17641017-30-person372" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person372" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person372" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             together; I knew nothing at all of this till next night: I believe I got home about ten o'clock.</p>
               <p>Shittle's Defence.</p>
               <p>I had been at work at New-Cross, Deptford; and having not seen this young man for some time before, being taken with an ague and fever, I took the opportunity of going to see him; I went about four in the afternoon to Chick-lane to drink a pot of beer; he said, he would have a dram; we had a halfpenny-worth each; we saw this girl, with a man by her side very much in liquor; she said, he was going somewhere up Holbourn; we went to see him home, at her desire; when we got to the Castle, we had a pot of beer; the man had no money, the girl paid for it; then we went down Saffron hill, and at the Yorkshire Grey we had another pot of beer; we went a little way beyond that, and then left 
               <persName id="t17641017-30-person373">
                  John 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17641017-30-person373" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person373" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person373" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , this woman, and the man together.</p>
               <p>Q. to Wolfe. At what time was the robbery committed?</p>
               <p>Wolfe. That was committed between the hours of 7 and 8 in the evening.</p>
               <p>For Wright.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641017-30-person374">
                  Peter 
                  Wolfe 
               <interp inst="t17641017-30-person374" type="surname" value="Wolfe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person374" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-person374" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Hand-Alley, Bishopsgate-street.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>P. Wolfe. I am a weaver: I have known Wright two or three years.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath, what character does he bear?</p>
               <p>P. Wolfe. I can't say I ever knew him to do any harm.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the general character that he bears?</p>
               <p>P. Wolfe. He is a man that works for his living.</p>
               <p>Q. Answer, is his character a good one, or a bad one?</p>
               <p>P. Wolfe. I had rather be excused than to say any thing.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17641017-30-verdict165" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17641017-30-verdict165" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
