<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17600227-6">
               <interp inst="t17600227-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600227-6" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600227-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600227"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600227-6" type="date" value="17600227"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600227-6-off24-c53" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600227-6-defend64 t17600227-6-off24 t17600227-6-verdict27"></join>
         
               <p>82. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17600227-6-defend64" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Clayton 
                  <interp inst="t17600227-6-defend64" type="surname" value="Clayton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-6-defend64" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-6-defend64" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17600227-6-deflabel23" type="occupation">single woman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600227-6-defend64 t17600227-6-deflabel23"></join>, was indicted for the <rs id="t17600227-6-off24" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600227-6-off24" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-6-off24" type="offenceSubcategory" value="infanticide"></interp>
               murder of her female bastard infant, by casting it into a certain pond of water
            </rs>, in the grounds of 
               <persName id="t17600227-6-person65">
                  Samuel 
                  Page 
               <interp inst="t17600227-6-person65" type="surname" value="Page"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-6-person65" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-6-person65" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17600227-6-cd25" type="crimeDate">Jan. 31</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600227-6-off24 t17600227-6-cd25"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600227-6-person66">
                  Henry 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17600227-6-person66" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-6-person66" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-6-person66" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I first saw an infant child dead in the pond of Mr. 
               <persName id="t17600227-6-person67">
                  Samuel 
                  Page 
               <interp inst="t17600227-6-person67" type="surname" value="Page"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-6-person67" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-6-person67" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at Ruslet, on the 30th of January: I was with a team of horses, and went away about my business. I did not see it taken out; it was frozen in with the ice.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you examined before the coroner?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176002270005"></xptr>Webb. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the prisoner at the bar?</p>
               <p>Webb. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her character?</p>
               <p>Webb. A very good one; she lived with Mr. Page, and went to live with him last Michaelmas.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was this?</p>
               <p>Webb. It is the fore part of the day.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is this pond from Mr. Page's house?</p>
               <p>Webb. It was about a dozen poles off.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600227-6-person68">
                  Mary 
                  Groves 
               <interp inst="t17600227-6-person68" type="surname" value="Groves"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-6-person68" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-6-person68" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I took the child out of the water on the 30th of January.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a male or female child?</p>
               <p>M. Groves. A female</p>
               <p>Q. Do you live in the neighbourhood?</p>
               <p>M. Groves. I do; I never had any suspicion of the prisoner being big before the child was found.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600227-6-person69">
                  Mary 
                  Parrot 
               <interp inst="t17600227-6-person69" type="surname" value="Parrot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-6-person69" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-6-person69" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . As I was going by the road I heard the water in that pond flounce, and saw the prisoner go away from the pond.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>M. Parrot. This was in January, but I cannot say the day of the month.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it the same pond where the child was found?</p>
               <p>M. Parrot. It was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it the beginning, or middle, or latter end of January?</p>
               <p>M. Parrot. That I cannot say.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it dark or light?</p>
               <p>M. Parrot. It was some time of the day; it was light, but I cannot tell what time of the day.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see what made that flounce in the water?</p>
               <p>M. Parrot. No.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600227-6-person70">
                  Samuel 
                  Page 
               <interp inst="t17600227-6-person70" type="surname" value="Page"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-6-person70" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-6-person70" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know there was a child found in my pond near my house; the prisoner was my <rs id="t17600227-6-deflabel26" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600227-6-defend64 t17600227-6-deflabel26"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the child in the pond?</p>
               <p>Page. I did, on the 30th of January; it would have floated, had it not been frozen in with the ice. I had occasion on the 31st of December to go into the garret, and looking through where the prisoner lay, I was surprised at seeing a large quantity of blood on the floor. I went down stairs, and told my mother immediately, and said, I was afraid a murder had been committed in the house. She went up stairs, and came down and told me she was afraid so too. I know nothing more than by hear-say.</p>
               <p>Q. Is she here?</p>
               <p>Page. No; she is a very ancient woman, and it is dangerous to bring her here. After this I perceived the prisoner to grow visibly less.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you a married man?</p>
               <p>Page. I am, but my wife was not then at home.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you suspect the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Page. Yes; she had not been in the house a fortnight before we suspected her, and had been with us from the day after 
               <persName id="t17600227-6-person71">
                  Michaelmas, O. S.<interp inst="t17600227-6-person71" type="given" value="Michaelmas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-6-person71" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            
               </p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What character had you with her?</p>
               <p>Page. An extreme good one, and she behaved like a good servant.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether she did not do her work as usual?</p>
               <p>Page. Yes, she went about her work as usual; but I observed an alteration in her countenance.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the blood appear to be fresh?</p>
               <p>Page. It appeared to be done that night.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs. Groves. Did the child appear to be fresh thrown into the pond, or to have been there a month?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Groves. It bled fresh at the nose.</p>

               <p>Q. to Page. Did any body examine under the bed, or in the bed?</p>


               <p>Page. My wife did, I believe.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600227-6-person72">
                  Sarah 
                  Page 
               <interp inst="t17600227-6-person72" type="surname" value="Page"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-6-person72" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-6-person72" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at London the last day of the old year, and when I came home the house was in great confusion, upon the sight of that blood. I asked my mother what was the matter. She said, the old story; that was from the suspicion we had of the girl's being with child. Then my husband ask'd the prisoner if she had been at supper, if not, he bid her to take it, and go to bed. My husband went to bed, that was because my mother should have an opportunity to tell me all about it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she go about her business as usual?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Page. She did.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any other servant?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Page. No other but a man. Then my mother said she was in hopes it was but a miscarriage; there had been something. The next morning I look'd into the room, and it had been mopped; but I saw streaks of blood down the wall, and on the floor.</p>
               <p>Q. What quantity of blood might there appear to be by the marks?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Page. There might be a hundred large spots of blood. I look'd on the ground under the window; it was scratched about with a broom, but I saw no blood there, so we were in hopes it was but a miscarriage. We did not care to take the girl's<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176002270006"></xptr> character away; something of that nature there had been to be sure.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you the girl examined on that?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Page. No; we were careful of taking her character away.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the girl continue with you?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Page. We kept her till the coroner was there. She was a good servant. She dined at our table, and used to say she was as well as ever she was in her life.</p>

               <p>The prisoner had nothing to say in her defence, but called the following witnesses.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600227-6-person73">
                  Hannah 
                  West 
               <interp inst="t17600227-6-person73" type="surname" value="West"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-6-person73" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-6-person73" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner lived servant with me three years; she was a very sober, civil, modest girl, and went from me to Mr. Page's.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she appear to be with child at the time she went from you?</p>
               <p>H. West. Not as I know of.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Taylor. I am a midwife, and by the justice of the peace's order was obliged to search the prisoner after the child was found, on the 2d of February.</p>
               <p>Q. If she had had a child about the latter end of December, do you think you should have discovered it?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Taylor. I think I should; there were no marks of her ever having a child. I am very sure if she had had a child I should have known it, for I thoroughly searched her.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600227-6-verdict27" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600227-6-verdict27" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
