<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660116-29">
               <interp inst="t17660116-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660116-29" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660116-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660116-29" type="date" value="17660116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660116-29-off182-c299" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-29-defend357 t17660116-29-off182 t17660116-29-verdict187"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176601160027"></xptr>106. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660116-29-defend357" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Willson 
                  <interp inst="t17660116-29-defend357" type="surname" value="Willson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-defend357" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-defend357" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17660116-29-off182" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-off182" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-off182" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               forging a certain bill of exchange, purporting to bear date the 17th of October 1765, drawn by 
                     <persName id="t17660116-29-person358">
                        David 
                        Latouch 
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person358" type="surname" value="Latouch"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660116-29-person358" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660116-29-person358" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   and Sons, merchants in Dublin, for the payment of one thousand pounds, and publishing the same with intent to defraud 
                     
                        <persName id="t17660116-29-victim360" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Puget 
                        <interp inst="t17660116-29-victim360" type="surname" value="Puget"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660116-29-victim360" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660116-29-victim360" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-29-off182 t17660116-29-victim360"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17660116-29-viclabel183" type="occupation">merchant</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-29-victim360 t17660116-29-viclabel183"></join>
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17660116-29-cd184" type="crimeDate">October 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-29-off182 t17660116-29-cd184"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660116-29-person361">
                  Thomas 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17660116-29-person361" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person361" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person361" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am clerk to Mr. Puget, merchant, in London.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his christian name?</p>
               <p>Brown. His name is John. On the 29th of October last, the prisoner came to Mr. Puget's compting-house, and delivered a bill to me of a thousand pounds.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is Mr. Puget's compting-house?</p>
               <p>Brown. That is in Broad-street.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know him before?</p>
               <p>Brown. I never saw him before to my knowledge. This is the bill (delivering it in.)</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say at his first coming?</p>
               <p>Brown. He enquired of me if Mr. Puget was at home. I said he was, and asked what he wanted. He told me he brought two bills for acceptance. I desired to see them. He delivered them both to me. This for a thousand pounds is one of them, and the other was for 900 l.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know 
               <persName id="t17660116-29-person362">
                  David 
                  Latouch 
               <interp inst="t17660116-29-person362" type="surname" value="Latouch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person362" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person362" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Sons hand writing?</p>
               <p>Brown. I do very well.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen them write?</p>
               <p>Brown. I have not seen them all write. I have seen some of them write.</p>
               <p>Q. Which are they?</p>
               <p>Brown. 
               <persName id="t17660116-29-person363">
                  David 
                  Latouch 
               <interp inst="t17660116-29-person363" type="surname" value="Latouch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person363" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person363" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the younger, and 
               <persName id="t17660116-29-person364">
                  Peter 
                  Latouch 
               <interp inst="t17660116-29-person364" type="surname" value="Latouch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person364" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person364" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . We received a letter from Mr. Latouch the same day as this was dated, which gave no account of these bills.</p>
               <p>Q. What partners are there?</p>
               <p>Brown. There are 
               <persName id="t17660116-29-person365">
                  David 
                  Latouch 
               <interp inst="t17660116-29-person365" type="surname" value="Latouch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person365" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person365" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the elder, and David, John, and Peter his sons.</p>
               <p>Q. Is this bill the hand writing of either of these?</p>
               <p>Brown. No, it is not. It is not at all like either of their writing. It has not the similitude of either of their hand writings.</p>
               <p>Q. Is Mr. Puget a correspondent of theirs?</p>
               <p>Brown. He is: he transacts business with them. I asked the prisoner who was the holder of the bills, he said he was. I asked him where he brought them from; he said they were sent from Dublin to get them accepted, that they might be ready for Sir 
               <persName id="t17660116-29-person366">
                  Thomas 
                  Sinclare 
               <interp inst="t17660116-29-person366" type="surname" value="Sinclare"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person366" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person366" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             when he came over to London, who, he said, was expected very soon.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you the letter here that you received from Mr. Latouch?</p>
               <p>Brown. I have, it is dated the 17th of October (delivered in). There came two letters on the same day by the post, as from Mr. Latouch, one a false one, the other a real one.</p>
               <p>Q. What day did you receive them?</p>
               <p>Brown. They came on the 22d of October, each had the Dublin post mark, and the London mark too.</p>
               <p>Q. What answer did you give the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Brown. I desired him to leave the bills with me, and call for them the next morning about eleven o'clock. He came again on the 30th, being the next day, between four and five o'clock in the evening. I asked him what he wanted, he said he called for the two bills he left at Mr. Puget's house, with Mr. Puget's clerk, (he seemed as if he had forgot me) I asked him what the sums were, he said one was a thousand pounds, and the other nine hundred pounds. I asked who they were payable to, he said to Sir 
               <persName id="t17660116-29-person367">
                  Thomas 
                  Sinclare 
               <interp inst="t17660116-29-person367" type="surname" value="Sinclare"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person367" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person367" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I then desired him to sit down: I had got an officer ready from my Lord-Mayor to secure him. I went to Mr. Puget for the bills: I brought them and the forged letter of advice and told him they were all forged, the two bills and the letter, and that he must go before my Lord-Mayor to give an account how he came by them.</p>
               <p>Q. What answer did he make to that?</p>
               <p>Brown. He said he was sorry to hear that, but he would go with me where I pleased: upon that he was carried before Sir 
               <persName id="t17660116-29-person368">
                  William 
                  Stephenson 
               <interp inst="t17660116-29-person368" type="surname" value="Stephenson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person368" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person368" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , late Lord-Mayor I went with him; he was asked his name, he said it was 
               <persName id="t17660116-29-person369">
                  John 
                  Willson 
               <interp inst="t17660116-29-person369" type="surname" value="Willson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person369" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person369" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; he was asked where he lived, he said he was a grocer and lived in Virginia street, that is in Ratcliff-highway: he was asked how he came by those bills; he said he received them in a letter from Dublin from Sir 
               <persName id="t17660116-29-person370">
                  Thomas 
                  Sinclare 
               <interp inst="t17660116-29-person370" type="surname" value="Sinclare"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person370" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person370" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Were the bills produced before him?</p>
               <p>Brown. They were, and he was desired to produce the letter he mentioned, but he said he could not tell what was become of it. He was asked how long he had been in England, he said he had been here about three or four years, and that he corresponded with Sir 
               <persName id="t17660116-29-person371">
                  Thomas 
                  Sinclare 
               <interp inst="t17660116-29-person371" type="surname" value="Sinclare"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person371" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person371" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Upon this my Lord-Mayor was going to send to Virginia-street to see if any body there could give any account of him; but when the prisoner found that, he whispered to a person, and that person told my Lord-Mayor that the prisoner had told him he did not live there.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176601160028"></xptr>Q. Was this in the hearing of the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Brown. It was.</p>
               <p>Q. What man was that?</p>
               <p>Brown. It was a marshal's man, that was the person ordered by my Lord-Mayor to go to Virginia-street, but it was another person that the prisoner whispered to.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner tell where he lived?</p>
               <p>Brown. No, he would not tell. He was asked several times by my Lord-Mayor, but he would make no answer. I think he was then desired by my Lord-Mayor's clerk to write his name, he said he could not write. I then asked him if he could read, he said he could not. He was then asked by my Lord-Mayor how he came to carry on a correspondence with Sir 
               <persName id="t17660116-29-person372">
                  Thomas 
                  Sinclare 
               <interp inst="t17660116-29-person372" type="surname" value="Sinclare"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person372" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person372" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , when he could neither write nor read; to which he answered, many a one did a great deal of business that could neither read nor write. He was re-examined on the 20th of November-last, before the present Lord-Mayor, then he said all that he had said before the late Lord-Mayor was false, not a word of it true. He said then he was born at a place called Lisbourn, in the north of Ireland, and that he and one Osbourn came over to London together on purpose to buy goods, and that they had been in London about one or two days when they found these bills in Whitechapel, wrapped up in a piece of paper, that they intended to sell the goods they bought here in the north of England. He was then asked where he lodged, he said he lodged at Mile-end, but he could not tell the person's name at whose house he lodged, neither could he tell whether he could go to the house was he set at liberty, then he still said he could neither write nor read. Upon that a question was put to him, whether he had not wrote a letter to the turnkey of Newgate, then he acknowledged he had, upon which he was remanded back to Newgate.</p>
               <p>Q. Does the letter you call the forged letter bare any resemblance of either of the partners?</p>
               <p>Brown. It neither bears the form nor stile and manner of writing of any of them. Here is the real letter to compare, (producing it.)</p>
               <p>Q. Did you receive the letters that day?</p>
               <p>Brown. I think Mr. Puget himself did.</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17660116-29-person373">
                  John 
                  Puget 
               <interp inst="t17660116-29-person373" type="surname" value="Puget"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person373" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person373" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am acquainted with 
               <persName id="t17660116-29-person374">
                  David 
                  Latouch 
               <interp inst="t17660116-29-person374" type="surname" value="Latouch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person374" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person374" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and all his sons.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen them all write?</p>
               <p>Puget. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this bill here produced. (He takes it in his hand.)</p>
               <p>Puget. This bill was not wrote by either of their hands.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain of that?</p>
               <p>Puget. There is not the least similitude of either of their hands, neither is it in the form of the house.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you accepted either of these two bills?</p>
               <p>Puget. No, I have not.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at these two letters. (The forged letter and real letter, which came in the post together, put into his hand.)</p>
               <p>Puget. This is a forged letter, the other is a real one; that purports to be signed Latouch and Sons, but it does not at all correspond with the forged one.</p>
               <p>Q. In whose hands has the forged letter been since you received it?</p>
               <p>Puget. It has been in my hands ever since I received it.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you corresponded with Messrs. Latouch?</p>
               <p>Puget. I and my father have corresponded since the year 1716.</p>
               <p>Q. Do they ever sign any bills by their clerks?</p>
               <p>Puget. No never, they are always signed by one or other of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Are they all four partners?</p>
               <p>Puget. They are. They have not missed writing to me or my father for these thirty years every post, and we to them.</p>
               <p>The bill read to this purport:</p>
               <p>Dublin, 17 October, 1765.</p>
               <p>"Twenty one days after sight pay this our</p>
               <p>"first per exchange to the order of Sir Thomas</p>
               <p>"Sinclare one thousand pounds value received,</p>
               <p>"which passes advice by procuration, from</p>
               <p>"Your humble servant,</p>
               <p>"
               <persName id="t17660116-29-person375">
                  David 
                  Latouch 
               <interp inst="t17660116-29-person375" type="surname" value="Latouch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person375" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person375" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Sons."</p>
               <p>1000.</p>
               <p>Puget. The original letter, which bears date to that bill, gives an account of the bills of exchange drawn upon me, is dated Dublin, 17 Oct. 1765, signed Latouch and Sons, directed to me, London.</p>
               <p>(It is read in court, in which is no account of the forged bill.)</p>
               <p>Puget. The genuine letter is signed for his christian name Dd. which is his usual method, but the forged one is wrote David at length.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176601160029"></xptr>Q. Was you present at the prisoner's examination?</p>
               <p>Puget. I was before my Lord-Mayor on his second examination, then he said he found the two bills in Whitechapel, and that one Osbourn was along with him at the time.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear him asked if he could write?</p>
               <p>Puget. He was asked if he could write, he said he could not; then there was a question put to him, whether he had not wrote to one of the turnkeys at Newgate.</p>
               <p>Q. How came that question to be put to him?</p>
               <p>Puget. Mr. Akerman said a note had been received by one of his turnkeys, sent from the prisoner, and that he was ready to produce it. He was asked three times whether or no he could write, he said he could not. He was asked which of the prisoners in Newgate he had got to write the note for him, then he said he wrote it himself.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660116-29-person376">
                  Thomas 
                  Rothway 
               <interp inst="t17660116-29-person376" type="surname" value="Rothway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person376" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person376" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am one of my Lord-Mayor's marshalmen. I was present when the prisoner was under examination before Sir 
               <persName id="t17660116-29-person377">
                  William 
                  Stephenson 
               <interp inst="t17660116-29-person377" type="surname" value="Stephenson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person377" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person377" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was asked who he was, and where he lived; he said he kept a grocer's shop in Virginia-street. I was ordered to go to Virginia-street, to enquire into the truth of what he said, by Sir 
               <persName id="t17660116-29-person378">
                  William 
                  Stephenson 
               <interp inst="t17660116-29-person378" type="surname" value="Stephenson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person378" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person378" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was suspicious of the truth of it, I took the prisoner by himself, and asked him whether he really lived there or not, he said I might go and see. Then one of my Lord-Mayor's clerks took him aside, and examined him, and found he did not live there.</p>
               <p>Q. What is that clerk's name?</p>
               <p>Rothway. His name is Sharp.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the prisoner tell him he did not live there?</p>
               <p>Rothway. No, but Mr. Sharp immediately told me he had saved me a journey, for the prisoner says he does not live there.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner present when Sharp mentioned this?</p>
               <p>Rothway. Yes, he was.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say in answer to that?</p>
               <p>Rothway. He said nothing at all.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660116-29-person379">
                  John 
                  Sharp 
               <interp inst="t17660116-29-person379" type="surname" value="Sharp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person379" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person379" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am clerk to my Lord-Mayor. I remember Mr. Rothway being ordered to go to Virginia-street, to enquire whether a person then under examination did live there, and I asked that person whether he did or not; and said do not go to give the person unnecessary trouble, if you do not live there say so; he answered he did not live there.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember what that person said was his business?</p>
               <p>Sharp. I remember he said he had some sugar-loaves hung out at his door.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you recollect that person?</p>
               <p>Sharp. I do not, so as to be certain to the prisoner; I only remember such conversation passed between a person under examination and I.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell Rothway what that person told you?</p>
               <p>Sharp. I did, and that prevented his going.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Puget. Did you ever hear of that person Sir 
               <persName id="t17660116-29-person380">
                  Thomas 
                  Sinclare 
               <interp inst="t17660116-29-person380" type="surname" value="Sinclare"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person380" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person380" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Puget. I have wrote to Ireland about it, but cannot find out any such person.</p>
               <p>Q. Supposing you had accepted those bills, and the prisoner had got the possession of them, there must first be an indorsement of Sinclare before any money could have been made of them, must there not?</p>
               <p>Puget. Yes, there must; but I suppose the person, that wrote the body of the bill, could easily have wrote such a name upon it.</p>
               <p>Mr. Akerman. I was before Sir 
               <persName id="t17660116-29-person381">
                  William 
                  Stephenson 
               <interp inst="t17660116-29-person381" type="surname" value="Stephenson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person381" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person381" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , late Lord-Mayor, when the prisoner was taken there to be examined. The prisoner being asked if he could write, said in answer, he could not. I recollecting while he was in Newgate, he had wrote a letter or note to one of my turnkeys, I mentioned that. Upon which he being asked whether he wrote it or not, owned he did write it. This is it, (producing a writing.)</p>
               <p>(The forged letter read, giving an account that Sir 
               <persName id="t17660116-29-person382">
                  Thomas 
                  Sinclare 
               <interp inst="t17660116-29-person382" type="surname" value="Sinclare"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person382" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person382" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             called upon him, and had lodged 2033 l. with him, on which account he had sent the two bills to be accepted, &amp;c. signed 
               <persName id="t17660116-29-person383">
                  David 
                  Latouch 
               <interp inst="t17660116-29-person383" type="surname" value="Latouch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person383" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-person383" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Sons.)</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was coming up Whitechapel, I saw a piece of paper lying on the ground; I took it up and went into the Talbot-inn and called for a pint of beer. I took the paper to see if there was any advertisement about it. Seeing there was not, I took the paper and went to Mr. Puget's to get him to accept it; the clerk told me to call the next day at eleven o'clock; that day it was not in my power to call at that time, but about half an hour after four I called, then I was detected; and your Lordship will please to consider, had I known these bills to have been forged, no person<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176601160030"></xptr> in the world in his senses would have called twice upon a man about them. I hope your Lordship and the gentlemen of the jury will consider, that no person has proved that I was the person that Forged these bills, or that I knew that these bills were forged. My trial was put off last sessions upon an affidavit by my application, not having any thing ready for my trial; and about a fortnight ago I wrote to Ireland to have an evidence in time, and I applied to the court on the first day of this sessions to have my trial put off till the next, with intention to get proper witnesses; I have been sick three weeks, or I would not have desired that of the court. There are two men at Lisbourn in the county of Antrim, in Ireland, that could give an account of my finding those hills. I am a <rs id="t17660116-29-deflabel185" type="occupation">soap-boiler</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-29-defend357 t17660116-29-deflabel185"></join> and <rs id="t17660116-29-deflabel186" type="occupation">chandler</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-29-defend357 t17660116-29-deflabel186"></join> in the north of Ireland.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660116-29-verdict187" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-verdict187" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty of publishing it, knowing it to have been forged
            </rs>. <rs id="t17660116-29-punish188" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660116-29-punish188" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-29-defend357 t17660116-29-punish188"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
