<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17630706-55">
               <interp inst="t17630706-55" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630706-55" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630706-55" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17630706"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630706-55" type="date" value="17630706"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17630706-55-off304-c433" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-55-defend552 t17630706-55-off304 t17630706-55-verdict307"></join>
         
               <p>338. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17630706-55-defend552" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Geary 
                  <interp inst="t17630706-55-defend552" type="surname" value="Geary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-55-defend552" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-55-defend552" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17630706-55-off304" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630706-55-off304" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-55-off304" type="offenceSubcategory" value="housebreaking"></interp>
               that he, in company with 
                     <persName id="t17630706-55-person553">
                        Charlotte 
                        Bonney 
                     <interp inst="t17630706-55-person553" type="surname" value="Bonney"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630706-55-person553" type="given" value="Charlotte"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630706-55-person553" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , not taken, on the <rs id="t17630706-55-cd305" type="crimeDate">5th of June</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-55-off304 t17630706-55-cd305"></join>, between the hours of three and five in the afternoon, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17630706-55-victim555" type="victimName">
                           Terrance 
                           Havers 
                        <interp inst="t17630706-55-victim555" type="surname" value="Havers"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630706-55-victim555" type="given" value="Terrance"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630706-55-victim555" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-55-off304 t17630706-55-victim555"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did break and enter, no person being therein, and stealing two silver salt-sellers, six silver table spoons, two silver tumblers, a pair of silver shoe-buckles, twelve silver coat buttons, a pair of silk stockings, a sattin handkerchief, two guineas, one quarter guinea, and 4 l. 19 s. in money numbered, the property of the said Terrance, in the said dwelling-house
            </rs>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630706-55-person556">
                  Terrance 
                  Havers 
               <interp inst="t17630706-55-person556" type="surname" value="Havers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-55-person556" type="given" value="Terrance"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-55-person556" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17630706-55-crimeloc306">Parker's-lane, by Drury-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17630706-55-crimeloc306" type="placeName" value="Parker's-lane, by Drury-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17630706-55-crimeloc306" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-55-off304 t17630706-55-crimeloc306"></join>. On the 5th of June, about a quarter before 3 in the afternoon, I, my wife, and daughter went to church and left 
               <persName id="t17630706-55-person557">
                  Charlot 
                  Bonney 
               <interp inst="t17630706-55-person557" type="surname" value="Bonney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-55-person557" type="given" value="Charlot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-55-person557" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in the house; she had taken a lodging of me, and she came on that Sunday about half an hour after one, and asked to go to her own room to clean herself, and said after that she would walk abroad; my wife desired her if she came out to shut the outward door after her. I returned about 5, and found the street door locked as I left it; my wife went up stairs, and in a surprize called me up; there I saw a poker standing at the outside of our room door, the door cut twelve inches in length where the lock was, and that wrench'd off, and a chest upon chest, and a large box broke open and the things mentioned in the indictment and many more taken away. I heard 
               <persName id="t17630706-55-person558">
                  Michael 
                  Miners 
               <interp inst="t17630706-55-person558" type="surname" value="Miners"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-55-person558" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-55-person558" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had shook hands with the prisoner at my door as he came out of the house, by which means the prisoner was taken up, and searched at Sir 
               <persName id="t17630706-55-person559">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17630706-55-person559" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-55-person559" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-55-person559" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, and a sattin handkerchief, a pair of black silk stockings, and a ribbon were found in his pocket. (Produced in court.) The stockings are my wife's, I carried them to be grafted a little before, and they came home but on the Friday night; the handkerchief is a sattin handkerchief with a red border, my wife never wore it but when she went to be churched, we have had twenty-two children, and she at those times always wore it; I went to him the next day in Newgate, there he said he bought them of the other man for five shillings; what man he meant I know not; he owned he was in my room, and said he wanted to lie down to rest, and he stumbled up stairs, he did not know which way; he said also if I would call for a bottle of wine and a crust of new bread, may be he would inform me more. I never recovered the rest of my things, all I lost were worth above sixty guineas.</p>
               <p>Ann his wife confirmed his evidence as to the house being left safe, finding it broke, and the goods being missing; and deposed to the ribbon, which her husband could not be certain to.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630706-55-person560">
                  Michael 
                  Miners 
               <interp inst="t17630706-55-person560" type="surname" value="Miners"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-55-person560" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-55-person560" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Parker's-lane. On Sunday the 5th of June, about half an hour after one, I spoke to the prisoner as he passed me in the lane, there was a young woman waited at a door with something on her arm; he went in, I was not near enough to see what door that was, but about a quarter after 4 I saw him come out at the street door of the prosecutor's house, and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176307060030"></xptr> the woman leaned over the hatch of the door, and looked after him for about six or seven minutes; he stopped with me about two minutes, and we shook hands, he had a sort of a red handkerchief, with a bundle tied up in it. I had known him five years ago, he is an Irishman, a Farrier by trade.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630706-55-person561">
                  John 
                  Adams 
               <interp inst="t17630706-55-person561" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-55-person561" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-55-person561" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I took these stockings and ribbons out of the prisoner's coat pocket before Sir 
               <persName id="t17630706-55-person562">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17630706-55-person562" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-55-person562" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-55-person562" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and the handkerchief out of his breeches pocket; he said a man gave him a bundle in the street, and these things were among them.</p>
               <p>A. Havers. When he was going in the coach to go to Newgate, he said if he had his hand at liberty and a pistol, he would shoot me dead for sending him where he was going.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>About 10 o'clock that day I was a walking through Drury-lane, I met a young fellow name Moore, he asked me to have some beer; we went to the Sugar-loaf, there came another of his shop-mates, we had five or six pots of porter; I had a shirt and things tied up in a red handkerchief. In came 
               <persName id="t17630706-55-person563">
                  Charlot 
                  Bonney 
               <interp inst="t17630706-55-person563" type="surname" value="Bonney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-55-person563" type="given" value="Charlot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-55-person563" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and a young man name Conner, she had a bundle under her arm; says Moore, what is the reason you have not a clean shirt on? I said, I had it here. Connor said I might go into his room and put it on. Said Bonney, I have taken a room just by, you may put it on there; I went in with her up two pair of stairs, and put my shirt on, and put my foul shirt and stockings in the same handkerchief, and came out again, and met Miners, and we shook hands, and I went about my business. On the Monday following I met Connor and Bonney in St. Gyles's, she had a great bundle under her cloak, we drank a pot of beer; Conner pulled out two handkerchiefs, a pair of stockings, and a good many pieces of ribbon; he said he brought them from the Havanna, that he intended to go to Ireland, and he had those to sell, he asked 7 s. for the handkerchiefs and stockings, I bought this handkerchief, produced here, and the stockings for a crown, and had that ribbon into the bargain.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630706-55-person564">
                  Jonathan 
                  Barber 
               <interp inst="t17630706-55-person564" type="surname" value="Barber"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-55-person564" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-55-person564" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a shoe-maker, I have known the prisoner about a year and a half, I know nothing but that he was a working man, and would spend his money as fast as he gets it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17630706-55-verdict307" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630706-55-verdict307" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17630706-55-punish308" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630706-55-punish308" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-55-defend552 t17630706-55-punish308"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>See him tried last sessions for a highway robbery in Islington, No 255.</p>
            </div1>
