<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610401-8">
               <interp inst="t17610401-8" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610401-8" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610401-8" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610401"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610401-8" type="date" value="17610401"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610401-8-off40-c60" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610401-8-defend75 t17610401-8-off40 t17610401-8-verdict44"></join>
         
               <p>128. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610401-8-defend75" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Simpson 
                  <interp inst="t17610401-8-defend75" type="surname" value="Simpson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-8-defend75" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-8-defend75" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-8-defend75" type="age" value="16"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17610401-8-deflabel39" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610401-8-defend75 t17610401-8-deflabel39"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17610401-8-off40" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610401-8-off40" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-8-off40" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one India silk handkerchief, value 3 s. one yard and three quarters of long<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176104010007"></xptr> lawn, val. 7 s. and 7 s. in money numbered
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17610401-8-victim77" type="victimName">
                     Mary 
                     Adams 
                  <interp inst="t17610401-8-victim77" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-8-victim77" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-8-victim77" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610401-8-off40 t17610401-8-victim77"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17610401-8-viclabel41" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610401-8-victim77 t17610401-8-viclabel41"></join>, <rs id="t17610401-8-cd42" type="crimeDate">Nov. 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610401-8-off40 t17610401-8-cd42"></join>. +.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610401-8-person78">
                  Mary 
                  Adams 
               <interp inst="t17610401-8-person78" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-8-person78" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-8-person78" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was my <rs id="t17610401-8-deflabel43" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610401-8-defend75 t17610401-8-deflabel43"></join> between 4 and 5 months.</p>
               <p>Q. How old is she?</p>
               <p>M. Adams. She is about 16 years of age. I found about 7 s. in her pocket on the 23d of November; I examined her how she came by it, she said she had it of her father.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does her father live?</p>
               <p>M. Adams. He was on board a ship at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Has she any mother?</p>
               <p>M. Adams. Her mother is dead. I missed an India silk handkerchief, I charged her with taking it, she confessed she had taken it, and carried it to her father, and told him she gave me 3 s. for it. Likewise she confessed the same before the justice, and the yard and three quarters of lawn she confessed she bought with my money.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find the handkerchief again?</p>
               <p>M. Adams. That was found on her father's neck in my house.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>M. Adams. I am a pawnbroker.</p>
               <p>Q. from the prisoner. Did not my father ask you if you had any handkerchiefs?</p>
               <p>M. Adams. Yes, he did, and I told him I had some. I did not miss it till the person that owned it came to redeem it; then when the prisoner owned to the taking it, I sent to her father, and he came with it on; he said his daughter told him she gave 3 s. for it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610401-8-person79">
                  James 
                  Dempster 
               <interp inst="t17610401-8-person79" type="surname" value="Dempster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-8-person79" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-8-person79" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodge in Mrs. Adams's house; on the 23d of November in the morning, Mrs. Adams came down stairs, and said, Sall, have you any money, Sall? She said, I have. She asked, how much? She answered 7 s. Said her mistress, last Thursday you had not a farthing. She prevaricated a little, and then said she got it of her father; then she said she had 5 s. of Mrs. Hill, and two of Mrs. Woodrow. Mrs. Adams desired me to go and ask them if that was true; they said they had not seen her for three months, then I talked with the girl, and she said she had taken it in the shop, and kept the money.</p>
               <p>Q. Had she used to be employed in the shop?</p>
               <p>Dempster. Yes; her mistress gave her money to lend upon goods in mornings, if any body came before she was up. Mrs. Adams desired me to go on board to her father, and he owned she brought a handkerchief to him, and said, was that about his neck. I heard her say she gave her father a handkerchief, and he gave her 3 s. for it.</p>
               <p>The prisoner said nothing in her defence.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Collins. The girl is not quite 15 years old; she was with me after the death of her mother. Her father settled her with me till he got a place for her.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Collins. I keep a cook's shop, she behaved very orderly with me; when I heard of this, I said to her, Sally, what is this I hear of you? She said, Thank God it is not true, and said, her mistress said she would transport her for taking her character away, for saying when she awaked Mr. Dempster was in bed with her mistress.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610401-8-person80">
                  Mary 
                  Harrison 
               <interp inst="t17610401-8-person80" type="surname" value="Harrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-8-person80" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-8-person80" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the girl between five and six years, her mother kept a chandler's-shop next door to me; the girl was a very orderly girl, and behav'd well.</p>
               <p>A witness. I have known her five years. I teach children to read, she was a scholar of mine, her friends were very honest people, I never heard any ill of her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610401-8-person81">
                  Ann 
                  Pool 
               <interp inst="t17610401-8-person81" type="surname" value="Pool"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-8-person81" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-8-person81" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner between five and six years, she has been all over my house, I never heard any thing amiss of her, or lost any thing by her.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610401-8-verdict44" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610401-8-verdict44" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
