<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17651211-59">
               <interp inst="t17651211-59" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651211-59" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651211-59" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17651211"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651211-59" type="date" value="17651211"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17651211-59-off350-c479" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-59-defend611 t17651211-59-off350 t17651211-59-verdict354"></join>
         
               <p>69. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17651211-59-defend611" type="defendantName">
                     Adam 
                     Thompson 
                  <interp inst="t17651211-59-defend611" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-59-defend611" type="given" value="Adam"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-59-defend611" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17651211-59-off350" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651211-59-off350" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-59-off350" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a gun, value 18 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17651211-59-victim613" type="victimName">
                           Henry 
                           Pyefinch 
                        <interp inst="t17651211-59-victim613" type="surname" value="Pyefinch"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651211-59-victim613" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651211-59-victim613" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-59-off350 t17651211-59-victim613"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , and two bottles filled with rum, the property of persons unknown
            </rs>, <rs id="t17651211-59-cd351" type="crimeDate">November 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-59-off350 t17651211-59-cd351"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-59-person614">
                  Henry 
                  Pyefinch 
               <interp inst="t17651211-59-person614" type="surname" value="Pyefinch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-59-person614" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-59-person614" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an <rs id="t17651211-59-viclabel352" type="occupation">optician</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-59-victim613 t17651211-59-viclabel352"></join>; I was burnt out when the fire was in Cornhill. On the 7th of November my man told me he heard a man was taken into custody, for stealing a gun, my property. I went to the constable's and saw it there I also saw two bottles of rum: the prisoner was then in the Compter.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you attend his examination?</p>
               <p>Pyefinch. I did not; my affairs were so perplexed at that time (a gun produced in court). I believe this to be my property.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-59-person615">
                  Thomas 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17651211-59-person615" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-59-person615" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-59-person615" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a shoemaker: when the fire was in Cornhill, my landlord and I went to assist Mr. Pyefinch: the prisoner and several other men were in the house at the time. A young man took hold of this gun, and said, I'll carry this over to the church, that was the place where Mr. Pyefinch's goods were deposited: said the prisoner give it to me; no, said the young man, I can carry it myself: but the young man soon delivered it to him. When he had got it of the young man, the prisoner wink'd to me: I thought he had some ill design, so I thought proper to watch him. Presently after he stooped down; I put my hand behind him, and felt something hard on each side, in each coat pocket. After that, I perceived something in his breeches; I felt: he said, hold your tongue, follow me. I was determined to follow him: I followed him down the street, and before I got down he was out of sight. I ran towards the 'Change, and overtook him by St. Michael's church. When I overtook him, he said, now we'll go and have some beer together. As he was going by the sign of the Mansion-house, facing the Mansion-house, I said, here is a public house. Said he, have you any money in your pocket: I said, no. Said he, I'll have some beer some way or other. He said to the woman, take care of my fire-lock (note, the prisoner was a <rs id="t17651211-59-deflabel353" type="occupation">soldier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-59-defend611 t17651211-59-deflabel353"></join> in his regimentals), and gave the gun to her: then he went further into the house, and offered the liquor he had in bottles to sell; the woman would not buy it. We had some tobacco, and he wanted more. I said, I must go home to work: then he said, if you will not stay, we will go to Mr. Pyefinch's house, and take each a bundle, and carry them to the church, and make him pay us. He told me he had made upwards of 50 l. for himself that morning. He left the gun, and two bottles of liquor, in the bar at that house. We went both to Mr. Pyefinch's house, and into that room where he had the gun from. Soon after I perceived he was gone. I told two young men what he had been doing, and what he had told me, and desired their assistance to take him; and desired them both to follow me out of the house. We followed him to the church, and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176512110046"></xptr> told Mr. Holmes the affair, and desired to go to the house where the gun was, and ask for it: he did. Coming up again to see for the prisoner, we met the prisoner going up the entry into the house for the gun and liquor: we secured him there, and took him to the Compter. It quite slipped my memory to have his breeches examined for what I felt hard there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-59-person616">
                  Charles 
                  Holmes 
               <interp inst="t17651211-59-person616" type="surname" value="Holmes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-59-person616" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-59-person616" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This evidence, Robinson, came to me, and said, you are a proper constable, I wish you would go along with me; a soldier has carried a gun and two bottles of liquor to the Mansion-house alehouse, and he believed he was there: we went, but he was not there; but the gun and liquor were. We called for a pint of purl, and when we were coming out of the alehouse door into the passage, there we met the prisoner. Robinson said, that is the man: I said, soldier, you have been robbing at the fire; he said he had not: I said, how came you to carry these things so far? he answered, he carried some to one place, and some to another.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>That morning I was coming from guard; I stopped at the fire. A man came and said, soldier, how can you stand there and not assist? He asked my colonel's name; I said Colonel Hays. He said, I'll take care you shall not be blamed for missing your duty. I assisted, and carried over things to the church. I brought this musket from a two pair of stairs room to the church: there was a constable standing, he said no fire-arms should be carried into the church. I said, where must I carry it? he said, he did not care, it should not come in there. I asked a fire-man to give me a little drop to drink out of a bottle; there were 3 or 4 bottles stood by him. He said, here, do not bother me, none of you; you soldiers have been pressing me for liquor all this morning. He gave me the two bottles, and I put them into my pockets. I knew no other place to carry them to, than to that house where I did carry them. It is a house where I have been before. I gave them to the landlady to take care of. I said to her, if you chuse to take them you may; she took them in charge into the bar. Said I, Somebody will have the musket, but as for the bottles, they were given me. This young man was along with me: if he saw any thing in my breeches, there were company enough in the house to have searched me. I went back to the fire again, and was helping down with things. Coming down the stairs, they were so slippery with the water, that I fell backwards over the bannisters, that I was not able to work any more. I have been so bad since, as not to be able to turn myself in my bed; one of the fire-men picked me up, and sat me down by the side of a house. When I came to myself, I was coming towards home; I met this man and constable; they asked me if I knew any thing of a musket and two bottles of liquor: I said I brought a musket there, because they would not let me carry it into the church. They took me to the Compter, and in a quarter of an hour to the Mansion-house. After that I was carried before the Alderman at Guildhall; that young man, the evidence, said, after I was committed, he should not have given himself so much trouble, but that he wanted to be paid for his labour.</p>


               <p>Q. to Robinson. Why did not you discover this when you got back to Mr. Pyefinch's house?</p>
               <p>Robinson. He was gone in an instant out of sight. I went as fast as possible after him.</p>
               <p>Q. How long might he be out of the house before you?</p>
               <p>Robinson. I think not above a minute or two before me. I first saw him beyond the church, almost by the Royal Exchange, on the other side the way.</p>
               <p>Q. to Holmes. Did the prisoner say any thing to you about being refused carrying the gun into the church?</p>
               <p>Holmes. No, not a word.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you the two bottles of liquor were given him by a fireman.</p>
               <p>Holmes. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they appear to be full?</p>
               <p>Holmes. They did.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner sober?</p>
               <p>Holmes. I believe he was a little in liquor.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-59-person617">
                  Jeremiah 
                  Wilmore 
               <interp inst="t17651211-59-person617" type="surname" value="Wilmore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-59-person617" type="given" value="Jeremiah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-59-person617" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I belong to the same company; I have known him four years all but three months; he always behaved well, with an honest character since I knew him.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17651211-59-verdict354" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651211-59-verdict354" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
