<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17601204-13">
               <interp inst="t17601204-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17601204-13" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17601204-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17601204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17601204-13" type="date" value="17601204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17601204-13-off77-c123" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601204-13-defend150 t17601204-13-off77 t17601204-13-verdict81"></join>
         
               <p>14. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17601204-13-defend150" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Wilson 
                  <interp inst="t17601204-13-defend150" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-defend150" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-defend150" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17601204-13-deflabel76" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601204-13-defend150 t17601204-13-deflabel76"></join>, was indicted for the <rs id="t17601204-13-off77" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-off77" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-off77" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               wilful murder
            </rs> of 
               
                  <persName id="t17601204-13-victim152" type="victimName">
                     Ann 
                     Bourke 
                  <interp inst="t17601204-13-victim152" type="surname" value="Bourke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-victim152" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-victim152" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601204-13-off77 t17601204-13-victim152"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17601204-13-viclabel78" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601204-13-victim152 t17601204-13-viclabel78"></join>, <rs id="t17601204-13-cd79" type="crimeDate">October 20</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601204-13-off77 t17601204-13-cd79"></join>*.</p> 
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601204-13-person153">
                  Michael 
                  Bulger 
               <interp inst="t17601204-13-person153" type="surname" value="Bulger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person153" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person153" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 20th of October, about nine o'clock at night, as I was coming down <placeName id="t17601204-13-crimeloc80">Drury-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17601204-13-crimeloc80" type="placeName" value="Drury-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17601204-13-crimeloc80" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601204-13-off77 t17601204-13-crimeloc80"></join>, I saw the prisoner at the bar and 
               <persName id="t17601204-13-person154">
                  Ann 
                  Bourke 
               <interp inst="t17601204-13-person154" type="surname" value="Bourke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person154" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person154" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the deceased, fighting; they fought about ten minutes while I was by them, and they had been fighting before I came up.</p>
               <p>Q. What did they fight with?</p>
               <p>Bulger. They hit one another with their hands, and knocked one another down several times.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>Bulger. This was in the street between two juttings out like bulks: they were both very bloody. Towards the latter end there came up one Spencer, a Jew, as I am told, a company-keeper of the deceased woman: he cried out to part them. I laid hold of the prisoner at the bar, and he of the deceased, and we separated them; then the deceased was very eager to fight again; I went away in about 10 minutes. After-wards 
               <persName id="t17601204-13-person155">
                  Catharine 
                  French 
               <interp inst="t17601204-13-person155" type="surname" value="French"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person155" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person155" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came to a house where I was drinking, and said the deceased was cur: at that time I looked upon the prisoner to be sadly cut, but she was not I found afterwards. I was told that the woman at the bar was up in a 2 pair of stairs room.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any body with the prisoner in that room?</p>
               <p>Bulger. She was alone, lying on the boards, and bleeding sadly. I first saw the deceased, after the fight, in Orange-court at 
               <persName id="t17601204-13-person156">
                  Catharine 
                  French 
               <interp inst="t17601204-13-person156" type="surname" value="French"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person156" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person156" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's house.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176012040017"></xptr>Q. How far is 
               <persName id="t17601204-13-person157">
                  Catharine 
                  French 
               <interp inst="t17601204-13-person157" type="surname" value="French"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person157" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person157" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's-house from the place where they were fighting?</p>
               <p>Bulger. It is about a hundred or two hundred yards: she was bloody, and stabbed on the left-side her throat , and a cut on each side her face; and several others about her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they fight again after you parted them?</p>
               <p>Bulger. I believe they did not. The deceased was taken away by the Jew, and the prisoner was left by herself in the street.</p>
               <p>Q. How was the deceased as to strength?</p>
               <p>Bulger. She was sitting in a chair: she was brought to justice Fielding's that night.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you stay with her at Mrs. French's?</p>
               <p>Bulger. Not three minutes. Then I went and broke the door open where the prisoner lay bleeding on the floor. I brought her down; she was all over blood: she bled terribly at the nose, We took her to justice Fielding.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any wounds on the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Bulger. I did not examine her for any, neither did I see any. We carried them both (bloody as they were) to justice Fielding's. The prisoner was searched, but no weapons were found upon her; only a pair of scissars tied to her side by a piece of ribbon, about three quarters of a yard long.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the scissars bloody?</p>
               <p>Bulger. They were bloody all over, as her cloaths, to the top of the shanks.</p>
               <p>Q. How were the scissars at the point?</p>
               <p>Bulger. One side was pointed, and the other round. [A pair of scissars produced, about five inches long, with a ribbon.] These are the scissars.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the deceased swear before the justice?</p>
               <p>Bulger. There she said the prisoner gave her the wounds.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say in what manner?</p>
               <p>Bulger. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they fall often in those ten minutes?</p>
               <p>Bulger. They were down very often.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they both fall together at any time?</p>
               <p>Bulger. I never saw them down both together, but both of them had been several times on the ground.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think the prisoner's mouth and nose bled from the blows the other had given her, or was it the other person's blood that was upon her?</p>
               <p>Bulger. I am positive she bled at the mouth and nose, from the blows the deceased had given her: her mouth and nose were very bloody.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did the deceased live after this?</p>
               <p>Bulger. I believe she died ten or eleven days after. The prisoner was committed to the Gatehouse.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe the prisoner at the bar to make use of a pair of scissars?</p>
               <p>Bulger. No, I did not, I did not observe that; she had scissars about her, till we had her before the justice, and searched her.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you find the scissars, on the outside, or under her cloaths?</p>
               <p>Bulger. They were hanging by her side, on the out-side of her cloaths.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601204-13-person158">
                  Aaron 
                  Spencer 
               <interp inst="t17601204-13-person158" type="surname" value="Spencer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person158" type="given" value="Aaron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person158" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 20th of October, I was in Mrs. French's house: about nine o'clock there came a woman by the court, and said, young man, there is an acquaintance of your's a fighting. I ran out, there were the prisoner and the deceased a fighting by Orange-court, near the Plough-alehouse. There was a fellow there that said to me: You dog, if you come nigh them, I'll knock your brains out.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did they fight after you came to them?</p>
               <p>Spencer. When I came to them. 
               <persName id="t17601204-13-person159">
                  Anne 
                  Bourke 
               <interp inst="t17601204-13-person159" type="surname" value="Bourke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person159" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person159" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was on the ground, under the prisoner: I took her away directly.</p>
               <p>Q. How did the prisoner lie upon the deceased?</p>
               <p>Spencer. She lay sprawling upon her, and I took Bourke by force from underneath her.</p>
               <p>Q. In what condition did they appear to be when you came to them?</p>

               <p>Spencer. 
               <persName id="t17601204-13-person160">
                  Anne 
                  Bourke 
               <interp inst="t17601204-13-person160" type="surname" value="Bourke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person160" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person160" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was all over of a gore of blood; her black gown that she had on, and her shift, were both bloody, and cut.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe the blood on Wilson to be her own blood?</p>
               <p>Spencer. The prisoner said, I am bloody as well as she. I think the blood came from Bourke. She had a cut on her right cheek, it was cross her face. I took my neckcloth from my neck, and tied it round it; it was a very broad cut. I gave her to a young man, that was along with me, and he brought her to Mrs. French's. After that I observed a cut on her throat: when Mrs. French washed her, I saw all the wounds.</p>
               <p>Q. How many wounds did you see?</p>
               <p>Spencer. There were three or four by the side of her forehead, and two or three little ones on her face. Then I went out to see for the prisoner. Then she was shoved into the Plough-alehouse. Mr. Bulger opened the sash-window, and got in, and brought her out. Then a coach was sent for, to carry her to the justice. I jumped into the coach to go with her, and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176012040018"></xptr> catched hold of her hands. She wanted to get them from me, for what I do not know. The deceased was in the coach at the same time. Another young fellow that went for a constable that I delivered the deceased to, to carry to Mrs. French's jumped into the coach with me. Mr. Fielding he deceased who stabbed her. She said, the prisoner stabbed her, and gave her them wounds.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say how?</p>
               <p>Spencer. She could not tell how. She was a little in liquor, so could not tell with what the prisoner did it.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say when you parted them?</p>
               <p>Spencer. All she said, when I took her in my arms, was: I shall die, I shall die. The deceased told me how the thing first began.</p>
               <p>Q. When?</p>
               <p>Spencer. The very same night, when she was sent home in a chair, I said how was the first of this quarrel? She said, I was at the corner of the alley with another young woman, 
               <persName id="t17601204-13-person161">
                  Mary 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17601204-13-person161" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person161" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person161" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             being by the corner of the court, there came two young fellows, and one laid hold of 
               <persName id="t17601204-13-person162">
                  Mary 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17601204-13-person162" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person162" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person162" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the other of her. After they went away, 
               <persName id="t17601204-13-person163">
                  Mary 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17601204-13-person163" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person163" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person163" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said to her, You b - ch, what did you set your fellows to begin with me for? She said, she told her, she was but a stranger this way, and hoped she would not use her ill. Said Wilson, I wish I was drunk for your sake. Then the prisoner went in at the Plough-alehouse, and came out again, and gave her a blow on the face: then they fell to fighting.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she tell you any thing about the manner of fighting?</p>
               <p>Spencer. She said the prisoner gave her a blow, and she gave her another; and when she was down on the ground, she received some stabs from her.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. That man was not there: I did not see him that night: he takes a false oath indeed. As for his character, it is very well known to a great many: he gets his bread in a very lewd, idle manner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601204-13-person164">
                  Catharine 
                  French 
               <interp inst="t17601204-13-person164" type="surname" value="French"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person164" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person164" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know nothing about it at all: I could not get within ten yards of them, when they were fighting. The Jew's wife went out of our house for a pot of beer, and she went to fighting with that woman at the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the deceased afterwards?</p>
               <p>C. French. I saw both of them afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Which did you see first?</p>
               <p>C. French. I saw the girl that is dead first, the Jew's wife, she came all bloody to my house.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say?</p>
               <p>C. French. I did not hear her say a word.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any wounds?</p>
               <p>C. French. No, I did not; I know not a word relating to this matter, no more than I have mentioned.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601204-13-person165">
                  John 
                  Adams 
               <interp inst="t17601204-13-person165" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person165" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person165" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When the prisoner was brought to Mr. Fielding's, all over blood. I took these scissars [here produced] from her side.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her before she was brought there?</p>
               <p>Adams. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you find the scissars?</p>
               <p>Adams. They were on the outside of her cloaths, hanging by a string.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the deceased brought in?</p>
               <p>Adams. I did; but did not observe her: the prisoner was committed to the Gate-house: I went with her.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any blood on the scissars?</p>
               <p>Adams. They were all over bloody. Mr. Fielding ordered me to take care of them, and I did. The holes where the fingers are put in, and the lower part of the string, were bloody.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take notice how far the string was bloody?</p>
               <p>Adams. I did not take particular notice of that, it was specked on the string; but the scissars were all over bloody.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601204-13-person166">
                  Jeffry 
                  Saul 
               <interp inst="t17601204-13-person166" type="surname" value="Saul"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person166" type="given" value="Jeffry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person166" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was sent for by Mr. Fielding that night about nine o'clock, to look at the deceased's wounds.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Saul. I am a surgeon.</p>
               <p>Q. What wounds did you observe?</p>
               <p>Saul. There was one very material one on one side the throat, near two inches deep I believe, by the windpipe.</p>
               <p>Q. How wide was it?</p>
               <p>Saul. It only admitted the end of the probe, which is as big as a large corken pin.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you think that might be made with?</p>
               <p>Saul. Some pointed instrument.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at these scissars.</p>
               <p>Saul. Very likely it was done with something like this: perhaps the very same.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a cut or a stab?</p>
               <p>Saul. It was a stab.</p>
               <p>Q. Will not the scissars make a wider wound?</p>
               <p>Saul. Yes: but the skin will contract after the instrument is drawn out. The wound sometimes afterwards will not admit the probe: it was not a double-edged instrument, if it had, it would have made a broad wound. I do not imagine the orifice could have been broader than the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176012040019"></xptr> edge of the point, it is not like a broad-edged tool.</p>
               <p>Q. How was the direction?</p>
               <p>Saul. That was in a streight line.</p>
               <p>Q. What other wound you observe?</p>
               <p>Saul. There was another on the right side of the neck, that was not half the depth of the other which I have mentioned, in the front by the windpipe; this was a wound of the same kind.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the direction of that?</p>
               <p>Saul. Streight. I mean right-forward, not slanting; it pierced inward to the centre of the neck, it wounded no blood-vessel any more than the former.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any other?</p>
               <p>Saul. There was one upon her cheek, and another upon her forehead.</p>
               <p>Q. What kind of a wound was that on her cheek?</p>
               <p>Saul. It was an immaterial one, about the bigness of a sixpence: it was a cut made with some pointed instrument, in an irregular form.</p>
               <p>Q. Did it look like a cut or a stab?</p>
               <p>Saul. It looked like a cut, not deep, very shallow, just penetrated thro' the skin, and that on her forehead was of the same kind.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any other?</p>
               <p>Saul. There was one on the fore part of her arm.</p>
               <p>Q. What kind of a wound was that?</p>
               <p>Saul. It was a punctured wound: a cut, I believe the instrument had gone thro' the skin; consequently there had been both a cut and a stab.</p>
               <p>Q. How wide was it?</p>
               <p>Saul. About the size of one's middle finger, pretty near a square; I believe it was torn in the fray by some fall; it was done very likely by the point of the scissars being drawn thro' it; none hung loose, it was dilated, a torn wound; I believe there were a dozen more stabs in divers parts of the body and arms, all inconsiderable fresh wounds, that would not admit of the probe.</p>
               <p>Q. Mention the parts of the body where the wounds were.</p>
               <p>Saul. Several on the arms, some on the breast, I cannot particularly say where; I attended her to her death.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she die of?</p>
               <p>Saul. She died of a fever.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you think was the occasion of her death?</p>
               <p>Saul. I apprehend the wounds, and her irregular improper diet together, were the of her death.</p>
               <p>Q. Were any of the wounds mortal?</p>
               <p>Saul. No, none of them were in themselves.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you say yes or no, whether any of those wounds were the occasion of her death?</p>
               <p>Saul. In three or four days after she received those wounds she had a fever, which was attended with St. Anthony's fire; which, with improper diet, wanting fire. curtains to her bed, and other proper necessaries [they were poor people where she lodg'd] I believe to be the cause of her death.</p>
               <p>Q. From the best of your judgment, can you say these wounds were the occasion of her death, or not?</p>
               <p>Saul. I cannot say they were; I say they were in part the occasion of her death, together with what I have mentioned.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601204-13-person167">
                  George 
                  Humphreys 
               <interp inst="t17601204-13-person167" type="surname" value="Humphreys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person167" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-person167" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 20th of October, between ten and eleven o'clock, I was sent for by justice Fielding to his house, there I found a woman fitting in a chair, covered with blood, laying with her head back: I saw a wound on her throat, which bled very plenteously. I felt her pulse, and found it low and languid, and she speechless. I introduced my probe into the wound in a direct line, and thought, by the direction of it, it had entered the windpipe. There was another wound in her neck, a flaunt wound: I attempted to introduce my probe there, and it gave her exquisite pain. This brought her to herself: she put up her hands, and desired me to desist: I examined a wound on her forehead, which was a transverse one, and another on the right-side of her neck, that went transverse about an inch; another in the arm, which seemed to be a lacerated wound, partly a stab, and partly a cut. There were several other wounds on the breast and arms, but none of them had penetrated thro' the skin itself.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she bleed?</p>
               <p>Humphreys. They all bled; I mean they did not penetrate all the skin: the most dangerous wounds were those about her head. The next day I attended her at her lodgings with Mr. Saul, and also dressed her wounds the day after that.</p>
               <p>Q. Give an account of the nature of those wounds that you say were the most dangerous.</p>
               <p>Humphreys. That on her neck was a stab, that on her cheek was both a cut and a stab.</p>
               <p>Q. How deep was that in her neck?</p>
               <p>Humphreys. I had got my probe in about half an inch, when she came to herself; it was downwards towards the jaw-bone; that on her forehead was a sort of a transverse one, not above half an inch long, not thro' the skin; the other wounds about her breast and arms appeared to<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176012040020"></xptr> be stabs more than any thing else: very small punctures: there were 16 of them in the whole.</p>
               <p>Q. When did she die?</p>
               <p>Humphreys. She dy'd, I was told, on the first of November; I did not attend her all the time; I was taken ill.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you judge whether those wounds might be the cause of her death?</p>
               <p>Humphreys. My operator opened the body, I came in after the operation was done. I examined all the wounds, particularly that in the throat, which I apprehended had penetrated the windpipe; I had it made clear four inches, and found it had not touched the windpipe. I examined all the others, and found them as I have described them. I cannot say any of the wounds were mortal. I apprehend she died of the sever which arose from those wounds.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I did not do it. The night that it happened I was drinking at the Plough in Drury-Lane; I drank there 'till I was a little in liquor. I came out to the door, where was that woman and another; they had done something at salt-petre-Bank, and they came there to make their escape. This Jew belonged to her that is dead; there were he and another man who belonged to the other woman; those two men came by and I spoke to one of them. The other woman that belonged to her said, if she did not lick me, she would lick her; then she struck me, and I did give her a blow or two, but I did not use any unlawful weapons. As to that Jew, he would take my life away if he possibly could.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17601204-13-verdict81" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-verdict81" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-verdict81" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17601204-13-punish82" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-punish82" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-13-punish82" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601204-13-defend150 t17601204-13-punish82"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
