<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660903-24">
               <interp inst="t17660903-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-24" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660903"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-24" type="date" value="17660903"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660903-24-off125-c156" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-24-defend205 t17660903-24-off125 t17660903-24-verdict130"></join>
         
               <p>420. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17660903-24-defend205" type="defendantName">
                  John 
                  Hill 
               <interp inst="t17660903-24-defend205" type="surname" value="Hill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-24-defend205" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-24-defend205" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17660903-24-off125" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660903-24-off125" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-24-off125" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a silver candlestick, value 3 l. three silver tablespoons, value 20 s. nine silver tea-spoons, a silver cream-pot, seven china cups, eight china saucers, three china bowls, and a china tea-pot, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17660903-24-victim207" type="victimName">
                           George 
                           Cook 
                        <interp inst="t17660903-24-victim207" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660903-24-victim207" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660903-24-victim207" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-24-off125 t17660903-24-victim207"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17660903-24-viclabel126" type="occupation">Gent.</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-24-victim207 t17660903-24-viclabel126"></join> in the dwelling-house of the said George
            </rs>, <rs id="t17660903-24-cd127" type="crimeDate">Aug. 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-24-off125 t17660903-24-cd127"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17660903-24-person208">
                  George 
                  Cook 
               <interp inst="t17660903-24-person208" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-24-person208" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-24-person208" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at <placeName id="t17660903-24-crimeloc128">Hayes</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17660903-24-crimeloc128" type="placeName" value="Hayes"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660903-24-crimeloc128" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-24-off125 t17660903-24-crimeloc128"></join>, in Middlesex. The prisoner was my <rs id="t17660903-24-deflabel129" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-24-defend205 t17660903-24-deflabel129"></join>; I hired him for a month upon trial; he lived with me the four weeks all but two days. The robbery was committed on the Sunday, and he was to have gone away on the Tuesday following. On that Sunday morning the servant maid came to me about seven o'clock, and told me my house had been robbed. The prisoner went through my room to his bed; it appeared he had been up that morning an hour sooner than usual, which gave us a suspicion of him. My wife was called up, and they went and searched about. I can only say the things are my property, and being before Justice Wegg, heard the prisoner confess she taking them.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was he apprehended?</p>
               <p>Mr. Cook. At my house. As soon as my wife had given me an account of what things were stolen, I went to Justice Fielding's, and gave his clerk an account of what was gone, and desired him to advertise the things. When I came back, my wife had taken the prisoner up, from such circumstances that she was clear he was the person. I did not see him till the Monday morning; he was brought by the headborough; they said he wanted to speak to me; he begged mercy; I said but little to him.</p>
               <p>Q. What were his words he made use of?</p>
               <p>Mr. Cook. He said he hoped I would forgive him.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Cook. I am wife to the prosecutor. When the alarm was, I got up and went and examined, and missed the things mentioned in the indictment, (naming them) some were taken out of the pantry, and some out of the scullery.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the pantry door locked over night?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Cook. It was, but the key was in the door.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner then in the house?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Cook. He was, and went about with us in the searching.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you then any suspicion of him?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Cook. I had.</p>
               <p>Q. What gave you a suspicion.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Cook. There was a light of the window taken out; the window was in a passage that led to the pantry. The casement was not opened; the leaden bands that go round the bars were untwisted, and a bar cut in two. I was certain it was not done on the outside; I put the light up again, and twisted the bands to try if I could untwist them on the outside, and found that impossible. There was never a pane of glass cracked.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the bands twisted close before?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Cook. I believe they were; they were found and all whole; this confirmed my supposition; and after Mr. Cook was gone to Sir 
               <persName id="t17660903-24-person209">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17660903-24-person209" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-24-person209" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-24-person209" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I sent the prisoner out for some walnuts, to get him out of the way while we searched for the things lost. The maid and I searched several places, and in going into the stable, we found the silver candlestick and part of the china in the manger, under some hay. Then I went for a constable and other people to assist; and when the prisoner came back, I took him into the room where they were, and delivered him into their custody, and said, I believed it was he that had robbed the house: he denied it at first, but at last when he found I had found part of the things, he cried, and said he would show me where he had concealed the rest. The officer went with us; he took us to a hole in the ceiling in the brewhouse; there we found the nine tea-spoons, three tablespoons, the cream-pot, and the rest of the china; he then offered to pay for the things rather than lose his character, and confessed he did do it in the morning after he got up.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was by when he confessed this?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Cook. Before me and others; two of the witnesses are here; he owned he took the light down, and did the whole fact. There grows some flowers, and is a little edging of box, which were not broke down in the least. We asked him how long he had thought of doing it? He said, he did not think of doing it till he was up in the morning; he was carried to goal on the Monday, after that, he said I was going away, and he did it to serve me; but for that had no foundation. (The goods produced in court, and deposed to.)</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176609030013"></xptr>Q. By what do you know them?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Cook. There are but two of the spoons but what are marked, and there is a small hole through the candlestick, by which we all know it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-24-person210">
                  Jane 
                  Douse 
               <interp inst="t17660903-24-person210" type="surname" value="Douse"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-24-person210" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-24-person210" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Cook; I was with my mistress when the things were found; and after that I heard the prisoner confess he took down the light, and did the whole fact.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he make this confession?</p>
               <p>J. Douse. In the parlour.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-24-person211">
                  Robert 
                  Coombs 
               <interp inst="t17660903-24-person211" type="surname" value="Coombs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-24-person211" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-24-person211" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am headborough; I was sent for to Mr. Cook's. Mrs. Cook delivered the prisoner into my custody; when Mrs. Cook asked him if he did the fact, he said he knew nothing of it; after that he looked down and said nothing. I said he had better confess, it might be the better for him; then he said he did take the things, and he would go and show us where the rest of the things that were missing were; he took us to the brewhouse, and shewed us a hole, where I took the things out.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-24-person212">
                  John 
                  Young 
               <interp inst="t17660903-24-person212" type="surname" value="Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-24-person212" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-24-person212" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was the first man that came into Mr. Cook's house when Mrs. Cook sent for assistance. Mrs. Cook said she had a very great suspicion of the prisoner, having found some of the things; she charged him when he came in with it; he at first denied it; a little while after he began to cry, and said he had rather pay for the things than have any more to do about it, and went and shewed us where the rest of the things were.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>It was by my mistress's order that I took the things away: she came to me one morning, and asked me if I could keep a secret; I said yes, if she desired it. She said my master was very cross to me and her, and she had a design to go away once before but did not, but she would now go away; she bid me take the plate out of the pantry, and break the bureau open, and take what money there was, and we were both to g o away together. The next Sunday morning I got up, and did not think any thing of doing it; she cut the bar herself over night; she asked me about it three times, and I was not willing. On the Sunday morning after it was done, the maid went and told my master; he went out to advertise it; then I began to be frightened, and said, I would bring the plate again at night; she said if I did, she would be revenged on me as sure as I was born; so she sent me out. I had told her where I had laid some part of it; while I was gone she sent for the constable, but I had not told her where I had laid the other parcel; she would have poisoned my master if I would have given consent to it. She gave me some poison, and desired me to beat it; she said it was to poison the rats; I beat it; she had got some boiled milk, and crumbs of bread and sugar; I asked what she did it for; she said it was for the rats, but she thought it was too good for the rats, she could freely give it my master. I said, I will have ho hand in it. I come from Buckingham, and have no body here to give me a character.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any time fixed for the doing this, was it agreed upon over night?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. No, it was not.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs. Cook. You hear what the prisoner has been saying, what do you say to it?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Cook. All he has been saying is false; he was so despiseable a fellow in the house, we could not bear with him; he was to go away on the Tuesday.</p>
               <p>Young. Mrs. Cook said she knew where the things, or part of the things were; we went there, and she said she had told Mr. Cook, that she should find them before he came back; and when we went before Mr. Wegg, Mr. and Mrs. Cook were for laying the indictment only to transport the prisoner: then Mr. Wegg desired us to go to Sir 
               <persName id="t17660903-24-person213">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17660903-24-person213" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-24-person213" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-24-person213" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , as he understood it better than he; we set out, Mr. and Mrs. Cook in their post-chaise, and we and the prisoner in a little cart. When we came to the White-horse at Shepherd's-bush, Mr. and Mrs. Cook got out, and went into a parlour backwards; Mrs. Cook came to the street-door, and desired me to let the prisoner come to her; she said she had a particular question to ask him, that none could resolve but he; she said she would see he should be forth-coming to me again.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he tied?</p>
               <p>Young. No, he was not; I suffered him to go to her; he went into the garden with her; the headborough came to me, and said, he saw the prisoner jump over the hedge into the road; he was gone in two or three minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. How did Mrs. Cook behave upon that?</p>
               <p>Young. I went to her; she said she had let him go, she would not have him hanged upon any account; I said, I thought it was a very bad action; we went into the room to Mr. Cook, and told him, and he was angry that she should do so, and declared to me it was wholly unknown to him. After we had eaten our dinners at the White horse we returned home, and found he had been at home, and taken some money, a shirt, and other things; we heard no more of him till the next day; then Mr. Cook sent for me to take him into custody: he was taken, as we were informed, at Aylesbury, and brought back; then we took him before Mr.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176609030014"></xptr> Wegg, and he committed him to Newgate; this was on the Wednesday; then was the first time that he said it was by his mistress's order that he had done what he had; he had given some slight hints before, but did not tell us this till then.</p>
               <p>Q. to Coombs. Did you hear the prisoner charge this on his mistress?</p>
               <p>Coombs. He told me on the Wednesday that his mistress had ordered him to do the thing, and that they were to go away together; this was before we went to Mr. Wegg, after he was taken the second time; and he said she told him, these were not half the things he should have.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him go over the hedge?</p>
               <p>Coombs. I saw him when he was over, running.</p>
               <p>Q. How was it you did not pursue?</p>
               <p>Coombs. It was a thick hedge, and I went to enquire, and said, I believed Mrs. Cook had let him go. We had no warrant, and he was out of sight in a minute.</p>
               <p>Q. to Douse. Did the prisoner come back to Mr. Cook's house?</p>
               <p>J. Douse He did, and said his mistress gave him an order for me to pay him 8 s. for his wages; and if I had not the money, he said Miss was to go over the way and borrow it; he said his mistress ordered him to ask me for a ruffled shirt of his master's that was slit down the back, which was in a white basket. I let him have the 8 s. that being my own if it was lost; but the other not being my own, I refused to give it him; he went up and took it, and some odd bits of silk of little value.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he describe the shirt rightly?</p>
               <p>J. Douse. He did; he might know of that by rummaging about; it was in a basket in his own room. I asked him how he came to come back? he said his mistress had been so kind to let him go, and he should be bound to pray for her as long as he lived; then he set off directly and went away.</p>
               <p>Court to Mrs. Cook. It is very necessary you should explain what has come out from those witnesses.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Cook. After we went to Mr. Wegg's, he said it would hang the prisoner: it frightened me a good deal; I was very sorry, he being a young fellow, I was sorry for his friends; and I made that excuse in order to let him get away. I did not order him to go and receive the 8 s. nor shirt; when I got him into the garden I said, John, you will surely be hanged; now make your escape, and never be seen in this part of the country: he said, God Almighty bless you, Madam; I shall be bound to pray for you as long as I live; as to the shirt, I did not know that shirt was in the room; it was in the room where he lay; after he was retaken, we examined the bundle which he had; there was a piece of silk and a piece of an old shirt our property.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs. Cook. You see your compassion has thrown a great cloud over this affair: this man's life is at stake; I must ask you a few questions. Did you, directly or indirectly, give him any order or encouragement to take away these things?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Cook. Not the least in the world; I knew no more of it than your Lordship.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you cut the bar?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Cook. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner, before you sent him out for the walnuts, tell you where he had put any of the things?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Cook. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever threaten to be revenged on him?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Cook. No, I never did; he did not suspect that I had found the things; for he said afterwards, if he had thought I suspected him, he would never have come back again, when I sent him for the walnu's.</p>
               <p>Coombs. I said, after he had owned it, it was a wonder you did not make off, and not comeback; his answer was, Who would have thought of any such thing, that Mrs. Cook should have got them there to take him; he had no suspicion of it.</p>
               <p>Mr. Cook. The prisoner used to have the key of the stable, and I telling my wife of that before I went out, made my wife suspect the things might be in the stable.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you say to this? you have heard what has been said.</p>
               <p>Mr. Cook. I am satisfied, thoroughly satisfied, there is not a word of truth in all this; I am certain her design in letting the prisoner get away, was real mercy and compassion in her; I know we had not had any word in quarrelling all the time the prisoner was with me, we lived on good terms. I cannot say but I was angry at her letting the prisoner get away.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Cook. Mr. Cook said, when I came in out of the garden, You have saved a thief from the gallows, and he will cut your throat.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660903-24-verdict130" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660903-24-verdict130" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17660903-24-punish131" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660903-24-punish131" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-24-defend205 t17660903-24-punish131"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
