<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17600116-9">
               <interp inst="t17600116-9" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600116-9" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600116-9" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600116-9" type="date" value="17600116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600116-9-off39-c71" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600116-9-defend86 t17600116-9-off39 t17600116-9-verdict44"></join>
         
               <p>51. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17600116-9-defend86" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Ann 
                     Sparkes 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17600116-9-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600116-9-defend86 t17600116-9-alias-1"></join>Booker</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-9-defend86" type="surname" value="Sparkes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-9-defend86" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-9-defend86" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17600116-9-deflabel38" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600116-9-defend86 t17600116-9-deflabel38"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17600116-9-off39" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600116-9-off39" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-9-off39" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one silver pepper box, value 10 s. one silver milk ewer, value 10 s. one silver salt, value 5 s one pair of silver shoe buckles, value 5 s. two silver table spoons, two silver tea spoons, and one silver watch, the property of the <rs id="t17600116-9-viclabel40" type="occupation">right reverend</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600116-9-victim88 t17600116-9-viclabel40"></join> 
                  
                     <persName id="t17600116-9-victim88" type="victimName">
                        Thomas 
                        <rs id="t17600116-9-viclabel41" type="occupation">lord bishop of London</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600116-9-victim88 t17600116-9-viclabel41"></join>
                        <interp inst="t17600116-9-victim88" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600116-9-victim88" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  . It was laid over again to be the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17600116-9-victim90" type="victimName">
                           Elizabeth 
                           Somner 
                        <interp inst="t17600116-9-victim90" type="surname" value="Somner"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600116-9-victim90" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600116-9-victim90" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17600116-9-viclabel42" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600116-9-victim90 t17600116-9-viclabel42"></join>; and it was laid a third time to be the property of persons unknown
            </rs>, <rs id="t17600116-9-cd43" type="crimeDate">Jan. 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600116-9-off39 t17600116-9-cd43"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600116-9-person91">
                  Charles 
                  Doxey 
               <interp inst="t17600116-9-person91" type="surname" value="Doxey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-9-person91" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-9-person91" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Kentish-town; the prisoner came along with a clean looking man to lodge at my house, I did not know the man's name till after he was dead.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had they lodged at your house?</p>
               <p>Doxey. They were there I believe two months this day. The man came into my house on the last day of the old year, about nine o'clock, well and hearty. I was just about going to bed. The prisoner came in soon after, and I heard no more of them, till about five o'clock in the morning, when the prisoner came to my room door and knock'd, saying my husband is dead. I said what the plague is the matter with the woman, are you mad? she said he was dead indeed. My wife got out of bed and opened the door, when the prisoner came in with a candle in her hand. I said, pray what time did he die? she answered, about two o'clock, and said to my wife, Madam, have you got any thing in the house, I am sick, or tired, I don't know which, and my wife gave her a glass of rum.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she give any reason why she had not acquainted you with it sooner?</p>
               <p>Doxey. No, she did not. I arose and went up stairs to their room, and said you have not acted like a prudent wife. Said she, what have I acted like. I said, like a d - d bitch of a whore, because you did not tell me, or my family, but say he has had a fit, and a fit. [She had told me he had two fits, that she had occasion to go down into the yard, and when she went up again he was dead.] I looked at the man, and saw he was dead. I said, pray where are his friends and acquaintance? He<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176001160007"></xptr> has none, she said. I said, it is very odd that this man has been so long in London, as you say, and has no acquaintance or friends, where are his lodgings in London? She said it was somewhere by Charing Cross. Said I, he once told me he had a child, where is that? She said she did not know, it was somewhere on the other side of the water. I said, it looks dark to me, where are the effects he had about him, for I think you intend to pillage him here, and then go to London and pillage his lodgings there. On this I demanded the things to be left in my hands in order to bury the man, he has a watch and rings, I will give you a bond of 40 l. that every halfpenny shall be accounted for. She told me I had no business to molest her, the man shall be buried. I said, if you want half a guinea or a guinea, I will lend you that till you get your friends, but I could get no satisfactory answer. Then I said I would charge an officer with her, so sent for one and gave him charge of her. As we were going over the fields with her towards London, she said she did not know what business she had to go before a justice, she would deliver the things to me if I would acquit her. We said we would not acquit her if she would give us one hundred guineas. We took her before justice Welch, where she cry'd and said she was not his wife, but that he promised to marry her. She pulled out a little bit of paper and shewed it to us; then she pulled out a silver watch, a table spoon, and a tea spoon, and to the best of my knowledge she told the justice they were all she had. I told the justice she had more things about her, so the justice desired she would produce them, which she refusing to do, he with his own hand took out from her bosom a silver cream pot, or silver pepper box, and then ordered her to be searched. There were then found in her bosom a pair of silver shoe buckles, and either the pepper box or cream pot, a salt, a table spoon, and a tea spoon.</p>
               <p>Q. How did she appear when she came to you at five o'clock, was she dress'd?</p>
               <p>Doxey. She was dress'd, with all her cloaths on. [The goods produced in court, sealed up with the justice's seal.] The prisoner said the cream pot was her own property, and that her name was on the bottom of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Is her name upon the bottom of it?</p>
               <p>Doxey. No, it is not her name.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600116-9-person92">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Somner 
               <interp inst="t17600116-9-person92" type="surname" value="Somner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-9-person92" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-9-person92" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the deceased, my husband bought this cream pot many years ago, it is my property.</p>
               <p>Q. to Doxey. Did the prisoner go by the deceased's name at your house?</p>
               <p>Doxey. I never knew his name; she went for his wife.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever been in the deceased's company?</p>
               <p>Doxey. No farther than that he came down sometimes for an hour or two, to fit by our fire.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he use to call the prisoner his wife?</p>
               <p>Doxey. He used to call her his wife, and she call'd him her husband.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear him mention a will, or of his making one?</p>
               <p>Doxey. No, never; at first I thought she was his wife, but lately I did not think so.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever seen these things here produced about the house?</p>
               <p>Doxey. I have, and in the prisoner's hand; the watch I have seen the deceased pull out of his pocket, and gold rings on his fingers.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she deny having those effects about her?</p>
               <p>Doxey. She said I had no right to ask for them.</p>
               <p>Q. When you charged her, did she offer to run away?</p>
               <p>Doxey. We took care of that, and would not let her; I stood with my back against a little gate, and kept her there till the officer came; I saw plainly that she intended to leave me the deceased to bury, and carry all his effects away.</p>
               <p>Q. Do not you know the name he went by?</p>
               <p>Doxey. Indeed I do not; he was a well dress'd man, and had a creditable look.</p>
               <p>Q. Which of them took the lodgings?</p>
               <p>Doxey. He and she together.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not every thing seem common betwixt them?</p>
               <p>Doxey. Yes.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600116-9-person93">
                  Francis 
                  Gordon 
               <interp inst="t17600116-9-person93" type="surname" value="Gordon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-9-person93" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-9-person93" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a headborough in Kentish town. Mr. Doxey told me when he sent for me that a man was dead in his house, and he did not know but that the prisoner had murdered him, she having kept his death concealed for two or three hours. He desired her to leave the effects there till she went to London, for his security, but she would not. Then I said, I shall take you up on suspicion, for the murder of the man. We had a surgeon to search him, and it was his opinion that the man died a natural death. We took her before justice Welch, who ordered her to deliver up the things, upon finding she was not the deceased's wife, and about two or three hours after she had produced the watch, a table spoon, and a tea spoon, we found the rest of the things upon her, which I have had in my custody ever since.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176001160008"></xptr>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not she say they were her own?</p>
               <p>Gordon. She screamed out, and said, do not shew my nakedness. She owned to me that morning she had two rings, and said she had put them in such a place, but we never could find them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not she go with you willingly?</p>
               <p>Gordon. No, but I obliged her to go.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say she had done with the gold rings?</p>
               <p>Gordon. She said she had left them in a drawer in the room upstairs, and when we went with the surgeon to examine the body, we went to the drawer. where she shewed us a cap, and said they were in that; but they were not there.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say when these things were found upon her?</p>
               <p>Gordon. She said she had no more than what she had produced before. We searched her, and after we had found them, she said nothing.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600116-9-verdict44" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600116-9-verdict44" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>[The goods were delivered to Mrs. Somner, the widow of the deceased.]</p>
            </div1>
