<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650522-26">
               <interp inst="t17650522-26" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-26" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-26" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650522"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-26" type="date" value="17650522"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650522-26-off164-c288" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-26-defend340 t17650522-26-off164 t17650522-26-verdict169"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650522-26-off166-c289" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-26-defend342 t17650522-26-off166 t17650522-26-verdict169"></join>
         
               <p>323, 324. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17650522-26-defend340" type="defendantName">
                     Matthew 
                     Carroll 
                  <interp inst="t17650522-26-defend340" type="surname" value="Carroll"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-26-defend340" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-26-defend340" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17650522-26-defend342" type="defendantName">
                     Margaret 
                     Brooks 
                  <interp inst="t17650522-26-defend342" type="surname" value="Brooks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-26-defend342" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-26-defend342" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted, the first, for that <rs id="t17650522-26-off164" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-26-off164" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-26-off164" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               he on the <rs id="t17650522-26-cd165" type="crimeDate">28th of April</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-26-off164 t17650522-26-cd165"></join>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-26-off166 t17650522-26-cd165"></join>, about the hour of two in the night, the dwelling house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17650522-26-victim344" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Robinson 
                        <interp inst="t17650522-26-victim344" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650522-26-victim344" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650522-26-victim344" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did break and enter, and stealing eight hats, value 40 s. the property of the said Richard, in his dwelling house
            </rs>; and the other for <rs id="t17650522-26-off166" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-26-off166" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-26-off166" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving six of the said hats, well knowing them to have been stolen
            </rs>, +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-26-person345">
                  Richard 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17650522-26-person345" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-26-person345" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-26-person345" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17650522-26-viclabel167" type="occupation">hat maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-26-victim344 t17650522-26-viclabel167"></join>, and live on <placeName id="t17650522-26-crimeloc168">Holbourn-hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17650522-26-crimeloc168" type="placeName" value="Holbourn-hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17650522-26-crimeloc168" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-26-off164 t17650522-26-crimeloc168"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-26-off166 t17650522-26-crimeloc168"></join>: last Monday was three weeks, between two and three in the morning, I was alarmed by the watch that my house was broke open. I hardly ever go to bed without burning a lamp in my chimney corner: I came down stairs, and perceived all my goods moved from the shelves, and one of my window shutters down: I let the watch-man in: I found the bolt of the hatch over the door was broke: my son made all fast over night: the shutter was taken down: the shop was open to the street: there was no glass: I went and put my cloaths on; after that either my son or apprentice called out, here are the hats, under the bulk before the door; they brought them in; I examined them and missed six of them: three of them were not lined; there was my brand-mark in them: the mark is R. R. I thought they would carry them to be lined, by which means I thought I might hear of them; I told it about in the trade, and desired the person to be stopped that brought them: on the Saturday morning I had a person came and desired me to go with him to Mr. Snoak's, in Little Turnstile, Holbourn: I went. Mr. Snoak told me he had finished one, and they had had it away; and would come for the other in the afternoon: he said he would tell them when they came it was mislaid, and we cannot find it; and do you plant yourself in the public house over the way, and I'll let you know: he went and shut his shop up, thinking then they would come; they soon came; then he came over to me, and told me to come: I went over with him, there I found the prisoner Carroll, and Bourn the evidence, and two other persons that were customers; Mr. Snoak said to me, there is one, and there is the other, pointing to them; then I put my hand on the evidences collar, and said, where are my hats; he pleaded heartily that he might not be hanged: then I said to the prisoner, if you do not let me know, I'll hang you too, and laid hold of him: somebody sent for a constable: Bourn said, he bought them of an old cloaths man: I think Carroll said, you lie, it was of a Jew: the constable seemed to know them both; he took them to the Round-house; then they were taken before Sir 
               <persName id="t17650522-26-person346">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17650522-26-person346" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-26-person346" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-26-person346" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; and told Sir 
               <persName id="t17650522-26-person347">
                  John
               <interp inst="t17650522-26-person347" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-26-person347" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the same as here: he sent one to the Gate-house, and the other to New prison: they both insisted upon it there they bought them of an old cloaths man.</p>
               <p>Mr. Snoak. I live in Little Turnstile, Holbourn: on the 30th of April, about seven in the evening, the prisoner and Bourn came to my shop: I had sold Bourn hats before, at a wholesale price; he told me he had them raffled for, and said he was a hat maker: he said, I want you to line two hats and cock them up: I looked at them, and said, where did you get them? he said, he got them of a friend: he ordered a silk lining in one, and a linen lining in the other; to be done by next day at noon: the next day they<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176505220033"></xptr> both came again, and only the linen one was done; Bourn paid me, and took that away: on the other I observed the mark R. R. then I began to think they did not come honestly by them: I ordered my wife to put it out of sight, till I enquired at the dyers: on Saturday I saw a journeyman dyer: upon asking him, he said Mr. Robinson on Snow-hill marked with R. R. and he had lately been robbed: I desired him to go and tell him I had such a hat: Mr. Robinson came to me and said, he would swear this was one that he had lost: I said the men would be here to-night, and desired him to wait at the alehouse opposite me till they came; they came, and we secured them: he took hold of Carroll, and said, you dog, you will be hanged: Bourn began to cry, and said, Lord have mercy on his soul if he is. He asked them how they came by the hats? Bourn said, he bought them of an old cloaths man: Carroll said, no, it was a Jew you told me. He said he knew nothing about it: then Carroll said, Bourn knows nothing about it; pray let him go. On the Monday we took them before Sir 
               <persName id="t17650522-26-person348">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17650522-26-person348" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-26-person348" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-26-person348" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; they both denied the fact: Sir John committed one to the Gate-house, and the other to New-prison, for farther examination. On the Friday following he ordered us to come to another examination: we went; and in an alehouse, while Bourn was in one of the boxes with one of the keepers of New-prison, he said to me, if you will let me go in first and speak to Sir John, I will confess the whole fact: he went in, and Sir John admitted him an evidence; he said the hats were in a street in Shoreditch, opposite the Dun Cow: we got a warrant to apprehend the woman at the bar; and another to search: we went there; the woman was sitting by the fire; we asked her where the six hats were that Bourn had given her; she said, she knew nothing of the matter; I said, if you will not let us know where they are, you must go before Sir 
               <persName id="t17650522-26-person349">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17650522-26-person349" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-26-person349" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-26-person349" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            : Mr. Robinson took her a little way down the street: I said I would not leave the house, for I thought the hats were there, and they would be moved off: Mr. Robinson soon returned, and said, he knew where they were; for she had told him they were in the house: we searched the house over and over, but found none: the woman said they were in the house: then the woman of the house said, if you know where they are, go and take them: we went with her into the cellar, but could not find them: then I said, she must go before Sir John: we took her over the way to an ale-house; then I went over again, and told the people in the house, (there were several women) they would certainly come into trouble if they did not let us have them: one said, do you fetch them; another said, do you: no, said one, he'll transport me: I said, I'll not touch any of you: then they said, if I would go out of the house five minutes, I should see them lying in a chair: I went again to them to the ale-house, and returned in about eight or ten minutes, and saw these six hats lying in the chair; one of the women said, there they are: I took and brought them away: (produced and deposed to by the prosecutor:) we took her before Sir 
               <persName id="t17650522-26-person350">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17650522-26-person350" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-26-person350" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-26-person350" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; there she said Bourn and Carroll brought them to her, where she lived in St. Giles's.</p>

               <p>Robinson. I forgot to give an account of our apprehending the woman; I can only say the same as Mr. Snoak has.</p>
               <p>Blanch Bourn. I am a Carpenter, and live in St. Giles's; I have come from Ireland very near two years: I knew Carroll in Ireland; he plays on the violin for his living: on a Sunday night, about three weeks ago, as he and I came down Holbourn, with intent to rob, we came to Mr. Robinson's shop at about 12 at night; we had been drinking together at the George Inn, in Broad St. Giles's; he fell to working at Mr. Robinson's door; he went to feel whether the pins were in, and fast or not; he bid me to watch; I did; and can't tell how he got the shutters down then he called me to him, and persuaded me to go in; in going in he lifted my foot over an iron that was there; there was a plank on the inside that they used to make hats upon; I handed the bundles of hats over the plank to him; he stood out at the window, and he put them under the bulk at the door; from whence we intended to take them away; but he told me the watch was coming; and I made the best of my way out at the window, and he made off with eight hats: we made towards St. Giles's, to his lodgings, and he gave the hats to the woman at the bar; she was his bed-fellow: she put them into a box: the next day he said, he would buy linings and loops, and do them up himself: I said, I would carry them to an acquaintance of mine, Mr. Snoak; we took them to him on the Tuesday night, by which means we were both taken.</p>
               <p>Carroll's Defence.</p>
               <p>This man has perjured himself: I know no more of the hats being taken than the child unborn: I happened to be at the George Inn, Broad St.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176505220034"></xptr> Giles's; he asked me to be a pint along with him, he sat down, and told me he had about half a dozen new hats, and if I wanted one he would deal reasonably; and that they were at his lodging, and if I would be there at four or five in the afternoon, he would shew me some: I went at that time; he was there, with the two hats in his apron; he took me backwards and showed me them; and said, if I pitched upon one, he would have it finished; and if I would go with him to a hat-maker in Little Turnstile, Holbourn, I might make the agreement; but he would not let me have one under half a guinea: we came to the end of Drury-lane; there was one Deacon, a brewer's servant, he asked him do you want a hat? they agreed for one; and he was to bring it to such an alehouse: he desired me to be there with my fiddle, saying, it might be something in my way: we went; Deacon was there; he took half a guinea for it; and asked Deacon to get him a customer for another: the Saturday following he came to the George Inn, in Broad St. Giles's, and said he was going for my hat; I went with him; he asked if the hat was done; Mr. Snoak said, it would be done in a quarter of an hour: while we were there Mr. Robinson came in, and we were taken into custody.</p>
               <p>Brook's Defence.</p>
               <p>Bourn came up in the morning to Carroll's apartment, and brought the hats, I think on a Monday morning: Carroll was fast asleep; he begged of me to go as far as Shoreditch with them; he said, he was going into the country, and the people would not be against his leaving them there till he returned: I did not know they were stole; I carried them as desired.</p>
               <p>For Carroll.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-26-person351">
                  Barney 
                  Deacon 
               <interp inst="t17650522-26-person351" type="surname" value="Deacon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-26-person351" type="given" value="Barney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-26-person351" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I came acquainted with the prisoner and evidence last harvest, in Essex: on the 1st of May I met them in King's-street, Long-acre; Bourn asked me if I wanted a good hat? he appointed to meet me at the Hammer and Trowel, in Church-street: I was there in the evening; Bourn brought a hat; I bought it of him for half a guinea.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. This witness brought the hat to me of his own free-will.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17650522-26-verdict169" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-26-verdict169" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
