<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17661217-41">
               <interp inst="t17661217-41" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-41" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-41" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17661217"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-41" type="date" value="17661217"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17661217-41-off212-c334" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-41-defend428 t17661217-41-off212 t17661217-41-verdict215"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17661217-41-off212-c335" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-41-defend430 t17661217-41-off212 t17661217-41-verdict215"></join>
         
               <p>53, 54. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17661217-41-defend428" type="defendantName">
                     Charles 
                     Dennet 
                  <interp inst="t17661217-41-defend428" type="surname" value="Dennet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-41-defend428" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-41-defend428" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17661217-41-defend430" type="defendantName">
                     Samuel 
                     Newcomb 
                  <interp inst="t17661217-41-defend430" type="surname" value="Newcomb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-41-defend430" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-41-defend430" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted for <rs id="t17661217-41-off212" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-41-off212" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-41-off212" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing ten pounds weight of brass nails, value 5 s.
            </rs> the property of persons unknown, <rs id="t17661217-41-cd213" type="crimeDate">Dec. 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-41-off212 t17661217-41-cd213"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-41-person431">
                  William 
                  Saunders 
               <interp inst="t17661217-41-person431" type="surname" value="Saunders"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-41-person431" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-41-person431" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the parish of St. Clement Danes, in the Butcher-row. Dennet was <rs id="t17661217-41-deflabel214" type="occupation">grave-digger</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-41-defend428 t17661217-41-deflabel214"></join>, Newcomb was under him: I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176612170034"></xptr> have seen them when I have been going by about my business, when they have been digging graves, they have had pieces of coffins that had nails in them; they have taken them aside; this I have seen them do two or three times.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they appear to be new or decayed old boards?</p>
               <p>Saunders. They appeared to be decayed old boards.</p>
               <p>Mr. Wilmot. Dennet was made grave-digger, and after that steeple-keeper: I believe he had the care of all the keys of the church.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he key of the vault?</p>
               <p>Wilmot. He had. I received a letter on the 1st of this instant, from an unknown hand; I thought it my duty to acquaint the church-wardens with the contents of it, that they might take such measures as they thought proper. One Mr. Tapper, an undertakes and carpenter, and I, went with the two church-wardens; we waited in the church while Mr. Tapper went down in the vault with the prisoner Dennet.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that the vault that was lately on fire?</p>
               <p>Wilmot. It was on fire the Saturday morning following.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Had no other persons the key to that vault but Dennet?</p>
               <p>Wilmot. I do not know that any body had besides him.</p>
               <p>Q. Might not other people go down in it?</p>
               <p>Wilmot. I make no doubt but that other people might; but I cannot charge my memory that that vault was made use of to inter any body in my memory.</p>
               <p>Q. Suppose a poor grave-digger was digging a grave in a church-yard, should you have thought the old nails in old bits of coffin boards were the perquisites of the man, or should you have called him to an account for it?</p>
               <p>Wilmot. I should never have called him to an account for that.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has Dennet lived in the parish?</p>
               <p>Wilmot. I believe he has been the chief part of his life in our parish.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear any charge of this nature of him before?</p>
               <p>Wilmot. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he the key of the church plate?</p>
               <p>Wilmot. I never knew to the contrary but that he had.</p>
               <p>Q. What has his character been since you have known him?</p>
               <p>Wilmot. I never heard any thing against his character, as to his dishonesty; I have heard of his negligence touching his business.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known Newcomb?</p>
               <p>Wilmot. I have known him two years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character?</p>
               <p>Wilmot. I never knew any thing against him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-41-person432">
                  Thomas 
                  Tapper 
               <interp inst="t17661217-41-person432" type="surname" value="Tapper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-41-person432" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-41-person432" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went and searched into this vault, I believe on the 4th of this inst. Dennet and I went into it together; I was ordered by the church-wardens to see if any coffin was deficient; I found one lying at the farther end, appeared very fresh; I looked upon the plate, and found it was buried in August 1766; I said, I never saw a coffin finished so oddly in my life. I looked a little closely on the top of it, and said, surely, Charles, here has been some nails taken out of this coffin; he said, he believed not: I found there were nails gone out of the edge of the lid; I said to him, you see the print of every nail head where they have been taken out, as regular as they were knocked in, and I saw the inside row on the top was taken out; there were three rows in all taken out. Dennet said, I hope, master, you will not take any notice of this, for it will hurt me; coming out of the vault, there were three or four coffins higher up; I shewed him them and said, you see here has been the same work here; that was one that died in the year 1765, there were a great many nails taken out of the edge of that: he desired me to report favourable, that the vault was in tolerable good order. These were brass nails that were missing.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing against Newcomb?</p>
               <p>Tapper. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Were whole rows taken out?</p>
               <p>Tapper. There were.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the nails complete when the coffin was deposited there?</p>
               <p>Tapper. I cannot tell that.</p>
               <p>Q. Tell the Jury all he said when he desired you to report favourable; did he tell you how it would hurt him?</p>
               <p>Tapper. No, he did not tell me how it would.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he had taken them himself?</p>
               <p>Tapper. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say it would hurt his wife and family?</p>
               <p>Tapper. I don't remember he did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he not say there were other vaults to be searched, and desire you to look into them?</p>
               <p>Tapper. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Tapper. I am an undertaker.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176612170035"></xptr>Q. Is it not usual and customary when coffins ore deposited in vaults, for other people to go down into vaults, as well as the man that keeps the key?</p>
               <p>Tapper. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know the nails had been taken out?</p>
               <p>Tapper. I could see the print of the nails as regularly as they were put in.</p>
               <p>Q. Do not people sometimes take out nails before the coffin is put into the vault?</p>
               <p>Tapper. It is not usual.</p>
               <p>Eliz. Shelcroft. I lodge in 
               <persName id="t17661217-41-person433">
                  Samuel 
                  Newcomb 
               <interp inst="t17661217-41-person433" type="surname" value="Newcomb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-41-person433" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-41-person433" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's house. I saw a quantity of brass nails upon a square table in his apartment.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of nails were they?</p>
               <p>E. Shelcroft. They were round-headed nails; they appeared to me as if they came out of coffins.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Newcomb by at the time you saw them?</p>
               <p>E. Shelcroft. No, he was not.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever seen nails in your own trunk?</p>
               <p>E. Shelcroft. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they like them?</p>
               <p>E. Shelcroft. Yes.</p>
               <p>Council for prosecution. Were they like coffin nails?</p>
               <p>E. Shelcroft. They were.</p>
               <p>Council for prisoners. Can you tell the difference between a coffin nail and a trunk nail?</p>
               <p>E. Shelcroft. I cannot.</p>
               <p>Council for prisoners. Did they look very bright?</p>
               <p>E. Shelcroft. They did.</p>
               <p>Council for prosecution. Did you see a trunk they belonged to?</p>
               <p>E. Shelcroft. No.</p>
               <p>Council for prisoners. Nor a coffin?</p>
               <p>E. Shelcroft. No.</p>
               <p>A witness. I have seen Newcomb picking nails out of rotten coffins in his yard.</p>
               <p>Q. What colour were they?</p>
               <p>A witness. I don't know.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-41-person434">
                  Philip 
                  Buckley 
               <interp inst="t17661217-41-person434" type="surname" value="Buckley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-41-person434" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-41-person434" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About three years ago I buried a corpse in the vault at St. Clement Danes: upon going into Dennet's room, I desired him to go and see where I could have a deep grave; I saw a prodigious number of pieces of coffin boards, old decayed boards, and in another part of the room on a table, was a quantity of brass nails, all of them appearing to be old.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17661217-41-verdict215" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-41-verdict215" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
