<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610916-21">
               <interp inst="t17610916-21" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-21" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-21" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610916"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-21" type="date" value="17610916"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610916-21-off108-c152" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-21-defend184 t17610916-21-off108 t17610916-21-verdict111"></join>
         
               <p>240. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610916-21-defend184" type="defendantName">
                     Basil 
                     Francis 
                  <interp inst="t17610916-21-defend184" type="surname" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-21-defend184" type="given" value="Basil"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-21-defend184" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17610916-21-off108" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-21-off108" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-21-off108" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing four silver shirt-buckles, set with a composition of paste, value 2 s. twelve gold rings, value 4 l. two silver girdle-buckles, two silver stock-buckles, seven other gold rings, set with paste, value 2 l. four metal rings, value 12 s. nineteen stay-hooks, value 3 l. six pair of silver shoe-buckles, value 6 l. and twenty-eight guineas, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17610916-21-victim186" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Perrins 
                        <interp inst="t17610916-21-victim186" type="surname" value="Perrins"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610916-21-victim186" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610916-21-victim186" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-21-off108 t17610916-21-victim186"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling-house of the said John
            </rs>, <rs id="t17610916-21-cd109" type="crimeDate">July 26</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-21-off108 t17610916-21-cd109"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-21-person187">
                  John 
                  Perrins 
               <interp inst="t17610916-21-person187" type="surname" value="Perrins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-21-person187" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-21-person187" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watchmaker, on the 26th of July last my maid came to me between four and five in the morning, and told me there was a thief in my house below, and he had packed up all my watches. I got out of bed as soon as possible, and went to go down stairs in my shirt; but I returned, and put my coat, waistcoat, breeches, and shoes on. When I came down into the shop, I found several people there.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Perrins. I live in <placeName id="t17610916-21-crimeloc110">St. Clement's-Danes</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-21-crimeloc110" type="placeName" value="St. Clement's-Danes"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-21-crimeloc110" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-21-off108 t17610916-21-crimeloc110"></join>, near the church; I said, Gentlemen, you are all strangers to me, I desire you will withdraw, and turned them all out but two or three. There is a place petitioned off in the shop where I work; I opened the door, and there found the prisoner within-side. He lay with his head stooping towards the ground, across a stool; so as I could not see him by looking over. When I turned him up I knew him; he hath served part of his time with me, that is, two years and a half. I said to him, You villain, how came you here? He answered, Tom let me in. That was his fellow-apprentice. I found my nest of drawers in that closet were broke open, and a purse of gold was taken out of the drawer where I kept my money.</p>
         
               <p>*** The Second Part of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17610916-21">
                  <interp inst="t17610916-21" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-21" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-21" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610916"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-21" type="date" value="17610916"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commission of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 16th, Thursday the 17th, Friday the 18th, Saturday the 19th, and Monday the 21st of SEPTEMBER.</p>
                  <p>In the first Year of His MAJESTY's Reign. Being the Seventh SESSION in the MAYORALTY of The Right Honble Sir 
                  <persName id="t17610916-21-person188">
                     Matthew 
                     Blakiston 
                  <interp inst="t17610916-21-person188" type="surname" value="Blakiston"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610916-21-person188" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610916-21-person188" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Knt. LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>NUMBER VII. PART II. for the YEAR 1761.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by J. SCOTT, at the Black-Swan, in Pater-noster Row.</p>
                  <p>M. DCC. LXI.</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commission of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery held for the City of London, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Q. HOW were them drawers fastened?</p>
               <p>Perrins. There is a door shuts up, and locks in all the drawers, with-in-side. I said, You villain, what have you done with my money that was there? I had him then by the collar. He said, I have not got it. I led him into the parlour.</p>
               <p>Q. How much money was there?</p>
               <p>Perrins. There were twenty-eight guineas of it. He said, You will find it in one of the drawers. I got a candle, and found it in another drawer, but not in the drawer that I left it. I looked about with the candle, and found the instrument he had brought along with him, with which he had broke the lock. I found the things in my show-glass, shoe-buckles, shirt-buckles, girdle-buckles, gold rings, and the like, tumbled about, and lay higgle de-piggiedy about, some on the shop-board, and some in the show-glass.</p>
               <p>Q. Were any things carried out of the house?</p>
               <p>Perrins. No, the prisoner was bound apprentice to me; and being but an indifferent one. I thought proper to turn him over to another person, about three months ago.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say was his intent in being let in?</p>
               <p>Perrins. He said, Tom and he had agreed to go together to wash themselves in the river Thames: and he said, they both went down into the kitchen together, and he came up again, and said, Tom, I will go on, and wait for you at the end of Arundel-street; so he went up, and concealed himself in the shop, and he accused him with being concerned with him in the robbery. When he was in the parlour, my maid said to him, Where is the handkerchief that you packed up the things in? He said, I have never a handkerchief. She said, You have a handkerchief, it is a white one, for I saw the things in it in your hand, when I came down stairs. She took the candle, and went and looked in the closet, where he was found; and behind a clock-case she took out this night-cap: [Producing a white one] he owned it to be his night-cap; I said to him, You premeditated this robbery before you came here; you was not contented to break my drawers and take my money, but you must bring a night-cap to bag up all you could: he said, Indeed I had no intention of robbing you, but only a favourable opportunity.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What had you with the prisoner when you took him apprentice?</p>
               <p>Perrins. I had 30 l. he has been but a very indifferent boy from first to last.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether there was an intention of his quitting your service?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160023"></xptr>Perrins. I had recommended him to another master before he was with this, and he was five days with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he going to part from you?</p>
               <p>Perrins. He was, he had provided himself another master.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any dispute about returning some money with him?</p>
               <p>Perrins. I did propose giving five guineas with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it light or dark in your closet?</p>
               <p>Perrins. It was dark.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find any thing upon the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Perrins. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the money in?</p>
               <p>Perrins. That was in a purse.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was the drawer (in which you found the money) from the drawer in which you left it?</p>
               <p>Perrins. There are about eight drawers in the nest, it was the second drawer above it.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain with regard to the drawer where you put your money?</p>
               <p>Perrins. I am very certain as to that.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you miss any money?</p>
               <p>Perrins. I cannot say I did; if I was to be upon my oath, I could have sworn I believed there had been more.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know that the prisoner used to have such a night-cap as this?</p>
               <p>Perrins. I believe he might.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it usual to look behind clock-cases often?</p>
               <p>Perrins. No, it is not.</p>
               <p>Q. Then how long do you know it had been there?</p>
               <p>Perrins. The prisoner owned it to be his; there is nobody comes into that place besides myself, without it be to clean my window, or the like.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Mr. Mills?</p>
               <p>Perrins. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember any thing of a Tyburn-ticket being mentioned?</p>
               <p>Perrins. No, never in my days.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-21-person189">
                  Thomas 
                  Knott 
               <interp inst="t17610916-21-person189" type="surname" value="Knott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-21-person189" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-21-person189" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am going into the 17th year of my age. [He gave proper answers as to the nature of an oath, after which he was sworn] The prisoner asked me whether I would go with him on Sunday morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he fix any time?</p>
               <p>Knott. No, he did not; he came between three and four o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. What Sunday was it?</p>
               <p>Knott. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it in June or July, or what month?</p>
               <p>Knott. It was in July, I let him in at the shop-door; we went down stairs directly into the kitchen; then we came up again; I went into the shop to dress myself; then he said he would was at the corner of Arundel-street, 'till I came to him. My shoes and coat were in the kitchen; I desired him to stay till I put them on; then I went down, and left him in the shop.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you stay in the kitchen?</p>
               <p>Knott. About five minutes; I heard him, when I was below, open the door, and shut it again; but I found afterwards, he concealed himself in the shop. I put on my things, and went directly out to see for him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him that morning after this?</p>
               <p>Knott. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. How soon after?</p>
               <p>Knott. I saw him about a quarter after seven.</p>
               <p>Q. Where?</p>
               <p>Knott. In the parlour; he was then in custody; my master and others were with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether any of the things in the shew-glass were missing?</p>
               <p>Knott. I cannot tell, there were several sorts of goods there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see them after you came home?</p>
               <p>Knott. I did; some were in the shew-glass, and some were out; my master shewed me them in that condition; he asked me where I had been; I told him I had been out a walking; he asked me who I had been with; I told him I had appointed to go a walking with the prisoner, and so to go into the Thames to wash.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you spend your time till a quarter after seven?</p>
               <p>Knott. I went about a good while to see if I could find him; and when I could not find him, then I went and took a walk by myself; and when I came home, I found him in the parlour with my master.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you before the justice when prisoner was there?</p>
               <p>Knott. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you hear him say?</p>
               <p>Knott. He said he did not come with an intent to do what he did, but he had an opportunity.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he had taken any thing?</p>
               <p>Knott. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he had an opportunity of going into that room?</p>
               <p>Knott. I did not hear him say so.</p>
               <p>Q. At the time when he and you had agreed to go out, what was it to do.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160024"></xptr>Knott. It was only to walk and wash, that was all.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-21-person190">
                  Ann 
                  Feild 
               <interp inst="t17610916-21-person190" type="surname" value="Feild"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-21-person190" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-21-person190" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live servant with the prosecutor: I was not very well on that Sunday morning, the 26th of July: I came down stairs between four and five o'clock, and heard a noise in the shop. I thought it was the last witness getting up: I came down and heard a rattling; I saw a coloured coat lying on the counter.</p>
               <p>Q. Whose coat was that?</p>
               <p>A. Feild. I was the prisoner's: I looked over the counter, to see if the apprentice was in bed. I called Tom, he was not there. I turned myself round, and found master's little window was open, on the right hand side: that was the room where master works.</p>
               <p>Q. Is that room always shut on nights?</p>
               <p>A. Feild. It is; it opens into the shop: I looked in at the window, and saw a man stand double stooping down. I thought it had been the apprentice: I said, Tom, what business have you there? I spoke to him again, but had no answer: then I said, you know Tom you are a thief, and I will take care of you: then I opened the shop-door, and saw a young man standing in the church-yard; I desired him to come, and said I had got a thief in the shop. When that man came just to the outside the door, I shut it to again: then I went and called my master; master was coming down, but he turned back to put on his cloaths, then he came down and opened the closet-door, and found it was the prisoner at the bar. When I called the young man to come and help me, then the prisoner was standing at the shew-glass with a handkerchief full of things. Master said, you villain, how came you here? he said Tom let me in. Master said, I am afraid Tom and you are both rogues alike; but when he was down in the kitchen, he told my master he told Tom he would go out in the street, and Tom might come after him. I found the prisoner's shoes on the aprentice's bed; this night-cap here produced is the thing that I saw in, his hand full of things: and while I went up stairs to call my master, he turned them all out again, for some were lying on the board, and some in the shew-glass.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Were all the things taken out of the shew-glass?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor No.</p>
               <p>A. Feild. The justice asked the prisoner if he intended to come to rob my master? he said no, he did not intend it; but only he saw a favourable opportunity.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it dark or light?</p>
               <p>A. Feild. It could not be very light.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you distinguish any of the things be had got?</p>
               <p>A. Feild. I could not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it so dark that you can not undertake to say you could distinguish whether it it was a cap or a handkerchief he had in his hand?</p>
               <p>A. Feild. I cannot say which; he owned the cap was his.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see the things at all in that cap.</p>
               <p>A. Feild. Yes; but I cannot tell what things they were.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him put any things into it?</p>
               <p>A. Field. No; he told my master he was going over-night to carry that cap to be washed.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I did appoint to go along with this lad into the water. I was in the house, the boy went down stairs, and I thought somebody was coming from above stairs, and I knowing my master to be a very rigid man, pulled off my shoes, and went in at the window into the closet, to get out of his way, that he should not see me, knowing I had no business there. There had been some painting at my master's door, and I put this screw-driver into my pocket, to fasten a stick to it, that the point should not damage my cloaths, and did not think to take it out again. I had that cap in my pocket, going with it to be washed at my mother's, on the Saturday night; but did not leave it.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Cha. Maxey. I have known the prisoner ever since he was with the prosecutor at first. I was apprentice there at the same time.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is that ago?</p>
               <p>Maxey. It is about three years ago.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he behave then?</p>
               <p>Maxey. He behaved himself very well: I never saw any thing by him but what was honest, and I look upon him as a honest lad.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-21-person191">
                  Geo 
                  Mills 
               <interp inst="t17610916-21-person191" type="surname" value="Mills"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-21-person191" type="given" value="Geo"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-21-person191" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him ever since<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160025"></xptr> he was with his master. On Sunday was three weeks, I was with him, (I mean the prosecutor) I said I would have you be a little favourable to the boy: a good deal of discourse arose, at last he said, If he should be hanged, all I can say is, there will be a Tybourn-ticket. My wife was with me at the time.</p>

               <p>Mr. Gibbs. The prisoner at the bar has been with me about three months: he behaved himself very well, and very honestly.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Gibbs. I am a watch-maker: I have things of value equal with his master. His master was genteel enough to give me the character of an honest lad with him: I in particular asked him, if the lad was honest? as to his other complaints, I did not pay any regard to them. I should have bound the lad the Tuesday after this thing happened, as he served me diligently.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-21-person192">
                  Esther 
                  Slee 
               <interp inst="t17610916-21-person192" type="surname" value="Slee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-21-person192" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-21-person192" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was servant to Mr. Perrins two years. I never heard any complaints of the prisoner as to dishonesty, the time I lived there; he always minded his church twice a day, and he would take a good book and read in the winter evenings. I never saw any thing by him but that of a well disposed lad.</p>
               <p>Mr. Moody. I have known him about a year and half: he always behaved like an honest lad, and bore a good character.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610916-21-verdict111" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-21-verdict111" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-21-verdict111" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder40s"></interp>
               Guilty 39 s.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610916-21-punish112" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-21-punish112" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-21-punish112" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-21-defend184 t17610916-21-punish112"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
