<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17630413-38">
               <interp inst="t17630413-38" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630413-38" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630413-38" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17630413"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630413-38" type="date" value="17630413"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17630413-38-off203-c316" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630413-38-defend408 t17630413-38-off203 t17630413-38-verdict207"></join>
         
               <p>187. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17630413-38-defend408" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Gillet 
                  <interp inst="t17630413-38-defend408" type="surname" value="Gillet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630413-38-defend408" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630413-38-defend408" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17630413-38-deflabel202" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630413-38-defend408 t17630413-38-deflabel202"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17630413-38-off203" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630413-38-off203" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630413-38-off203" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing one 3 l. 12 s. piece of gold, four moidores, one half guinea, and one shilling, the money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17630413-38-victim410" type="victimName">
                           Edward 
                           Claxton 
                        <interp inst="t17630413-38-victim410" type="surname" value="Claxton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630413-38-victim410" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630413-38-victim410" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630413-38-off203 t17630413-38-victim410"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17630413-38-cd204" type="crimeDate">Jan. 25</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630413-38-off203 t17630413-38-cd204"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630413-38-person411">
                  Edward 
                  Claxton 
               <interp inst="t17630413-38-person411" type="surname" value="Claxton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630413-38-person411" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630413-38-person411" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I met the prisoner in the Old Bailey between 10 and 11 at night on the 25th of Jan. one 
               <persName id="t17630413-38-person412">
                  Fanny 
                  Pepper 
               <interp inst="t17630413-38-person412" type="surname" value="Pepper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630413-38-person412" type="given" value="Fanny"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630413-38-person412" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was along with her, they asked me, whether I would give them any thing to<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176304130024"></xptr> drink? I said, I did not care if I did. We went into the Bell at the Old Bailey, I called for a pint of purl. When we came out they asked me, if I would go and see their lodgings? I said, with all my heart. We went there, it was the second house on the right hand in <placeName id="t17630413-38-crimeloc205">Fleet-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17630413-38-crimeloc205" type="placeName" value="Fleet-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17630413-38-crimeloc205" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630413-38-off203 t17630413-38-crimeloc205"></join>; we went up stairs, one before and the other behind me, into a one pair of stairs room; we called for a pint of wine, while we were drinking it, they got to raking and tearing my pockets, which I did not like. I desired Mrs. Pepper to be absent, because one I thought was enough for me. She would not go for a good while, but still kept on the old way of raking and tearing my pocket. I said to Pepper, I insist upon your going out of the room, and took her by the arm and said, I advise you to go out, and at last she did go. I shut the door, and this gentlewoman and I struck up a bargain in a minute. I asked her, what she would have? she said half a crown; I told her I thought it was too much by 18 d. that I never gave above a shilling; I gave her that, my purse was in my pocket then.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you a married man?</p>
               <p>Claxton. I am.</p>
               <p>Court. Are not you ashamed of yourself?</p>
               <p>Claxton. I am.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Claxton. I am <rs id="t17630413-38-viclabel206" type="occupation">ostler</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630413-38-victim410 t17630413-38-viclabel206"></join> at the George in Smithfield. When I came to open the door, there was 
               <persName id="t17630413-38-person413">
                  Fanny 
                  Pepper 
               <interp inst="t17630413-38-person413" type="surname" value="Pepper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630413-38-person413" type="given" value="Fanny"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630413-38-person413" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             there; as soon as I came into the street, I was feeling for a penny to have a pennyworth of purl at the Baptist head, and I had never a halfpenny in the world; thinks I, I'll change 6 d. rather than go home a-dry, then I found my purse was gone. I called the watch, he came; I charged him to stand at the door till I went to the watch-house to fetch assistance. I went and fetched Mr. Draper, with two or three watchmen; with a little persuasion they opened the door, I went up stairs to the very room, I did not know but it might drop upon the bed, but I could not find it.</p>
               <p>Q. What was in the purse?</p>
               <p>Claxton. There was 9 l. 11 s. 6 d. in it, it was all gone. I went every night backwards and forewards for a fortnight to see if I could see this unfortunate woman, but could not see her; at last a man came and told me, she was to be found at the Red Lion in Poppin's-alley; there she was standing at the bar; as soon as she saw me, she quitted the house. There was a gentleman with her, he said, if any body came to molest her, he would knock them down. She was going up Fleet-street, I followed her directly, I went before her and said, do you know me? she fell to blasting my eyes and said, no; said I, I know you, and back again you shall go. I brought her to St. Sepulchre's watch-house, from whence she was sent to the compter. In two or three days after I went to the Red Lion to enquire what sort of money she changed there? he said, he had changed a moidore for her.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630413-38-person414">
                  William 
                  Collins 
               <interp inst="t17630413-38-person414" type="surname" value="Collins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630413-38-person414" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630413-38-person414" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Red-lion in Poppin's-alley, Fleet-street. I was serving the prisoner with a dram when the prosecutor came in; I asked him what he wanted? he could not tell me: the woman went out, and he after her. Two or three days after he came again, to know if I changed any money for her. Her husband is a hatter, and used to change his money at my house.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does he live?</p>
               <p>Collins. He lives in Shoe-lane, I have changed him a great deal of money for these nine months past.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember changing the prisoner any the night the robbery was committed?</p>
               <p>Collins. I cannot say that, for I do not know the day.</p>
               <p>Q. What money have you changed for her?</p>
               <p>Collins. I have changed guineas and half guineas often.</p>
               <p>Q. Is her husband a master hatter?</p>
               <p>Collins. He is.</p>
               <p>Q. How many men does he keep?</p>
               <p>Collins. I have seen three there at work, I used to send them beer there, a gallon at a time.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever change a moidore for her?</p>
               <p>Collins. I have. I am sure the prosecutor did not know her when he came into my house.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that?</p>
               <p>Collins. I said, do you want a woman? he said, yes, a woman that robbed me. I said, there was but one woman here, and she is gone out. Then he went out after her. There was a gentleman name French drinking a three halfpenny glass of brandy with her, he often calls in at my house for a glass of brandy, he lives at the other end of the town. The prosecutor did not know her then.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a character does the prisoner bear?</p>
               <p>Collins. A good character.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath has she the character of a woman of the town?</p>
               <p>Collins. I never saw any thing of that done in my house.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176304130025"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17630413-38-person415">
                  Edward 
                  Draper 
               <interp inst="t17630413-38-person415" type="surname" value="Draper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630413-38-person415" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630413-38-person415" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the constable. The prosecutor came to me on the 25th of Jan. and said he had been robbed of a 3 l. 12 l. four moidores, a half guinea, and a shilling, at the second house in Fleet-lane, one OHarrow keeps it; they frequently have different hands when any mischief is done, then that person is gone and another comes. I went with the prosecutor, and searched the house, there are three very bad houses together, I found nothing belonging to this man there. I went several times along with him to see for 
               <persName id="t17630413-38-person416">
                  Fanny 
                  Pepper 
               <interp inst="t17630413-38-person416" type="surname" value="Pepper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630413-38-person416" type="given" value="Fanny"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630413-38-person416" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and she: in about a month after he heard she was at the Red-Lion in Poppin's-alley; I went with him, and brought her up to the watch-house. OHarrow is now in Newgate.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17630413-38-verdict207" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630413-38-verdict207" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
