<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17641212-24">
               <interp inst="t17641212-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641212-24" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641212-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17641212"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641212-24" type="date" value="17641212"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17641212-24-off122-c153" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-24-defend201 t17641212-24-off122 t17641212-24-verdict125"></join>
         
               <p>25. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17641212-24-defend201" type="defendantName">
                     Anne 
                     Coffey 
                  <interp inst="t17641212-24-defend201" type="surname" value="Coffey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-24-defend201" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-24-defend201" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17641212-24-deflabel121" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-24-defend201 t17641212-24-deflabel121"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17641212-24-off122" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17641212-24-off122" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-24-off122" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing two guineas, half a guinea, and a 36 s. piece
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17641212-24-victim203" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Evans 
                  <interp inst="t17641212-24-victim203" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-24-victim203" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-24-victim203" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-24-off122 t17641212-24-victim203"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17641212-24-cd123" type="crimeDate">November 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-24-off122 t17641212-24-cd123"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641212-24-person204">
                  John 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17641212-24-person204" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-24-person204" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-24-person204" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodge at Rotherhithe. Three weeks ago last Saturday, I happened to be late, and did not go over the water, but went to the prisoner's house, in <placeName id="t17641212-24-crimeloc124">Denmark-street, Ratcliff-highway</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17641212-24-crimeloc124" type="placeName" value="Denmark-street, Ratcliff-highway"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17641212-24-crimeloc124" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-24-off122 t17641212-24-crimeloc124"></join> (a private house) between ten and eleven at night; there was a woman along with me; I do not know her name, I met her in the street.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober?</p>
               <p>Evans. I was sober enough. I asked this woman at the bar for a lodging; she let us in, and told me I must pay a shilling for my bed, for us both: I drank a pot of beer, and had my money as mentioned, in a purse in my pocket, when I went to bed; I had seen it a little before. I awaked about seven the next morning, and found, out of three guineas I had, two were gone, and the half guinea and a 36 s. piece; I had 18 d. in silver: the shilling was taken out of another pocket and put into my purse, with the guinea that was left: I put my breeches under my head.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the other woman lie with you all night?</p>
               <p>Evans. She did. I told her I had been robbed, and searched her cloaths, but found nothing. Then I desired her to get up, but found nothing: I searched her hair, and all over her, but could find nothing; I am sure a 36 s. piece could not be concealed about her, but I must have found it:<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176412120014"></xptr> then I bid her go away, and told the woman of the house (the prisoner) that I had been robbed, and she must know of it; then we searched all the house: I did not search her, for she went out of the house, to lie with a man all night, for us to lie upon her bed on the ground floor.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was in the house when you went to bed?</p>
               <p>Evans. There was the prisoner, and 
               <persName id="t17641212-24-person205">
                  Thomas 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17641212-24-person205" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-24-person205" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-24-person205" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the man that lay with her, 
               <persName id="t17641212-24-person206">
                  Mary 
                  Magnab 
               <interp inst="t17641212-24-person206" type="surname" value="Magnab"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-24-person206" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-24-person206" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the maid-servant, and the woman and I that lay together: Ward and the prisoner went out after we were in bed: Magnab lay all night on the floor, by my bedside. When I got up in the morning, the door was locked, we could not get out: Ward and the prisoner came and opened the door, between seven and eight o'clock. I charged the prisoner with it; she wanted to lay it to the other woman, but they all denied it: this was Sunday morning: I went to Deptford, to my ship, and on Tuesday night I came again, and found the prisoner and Magnab. She would fain have persuaded me that Magnab had my money: I got a warrant, and took them both up, and Justice Berry sent one to New Prison, and the other to Bridewell; after the prisoner was committed, she wanted to give me a note of hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say why, or for what?</p>
               <p>Evans. No, she did not; I would not take it. I never had a halfpenny of it again.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner ever acknowledge she had taken the money?</p>
               <p>Evans. No.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641212-24-person207">
                  Mary 
                  Magnab 
               <interp inst="t17641212-24-person207" type="surname" value="Magnab"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-24-person207" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-24-person207" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prosecutor came and asked if he might have a lodging for his wife and himself? the prisoner said, she must lie out of her bed if he lay there: he asked for something to drink, and sent for a pot of slip, and paid a shilling for his bed: then he asked if he might have some beer? I fetched him a mug of beer, and set it by his bedside: the woman he called his wife and he quarrelled several times, but I cannot say what about. I saw nobody take the money: in the morning, I saw the guinea and 18 d.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>This gentleman came to my house with a woman, and asked for a lodging; he insisted on her staying, and lying with him: I had no other bed but my own: he gave me a shilling, saying, he could not go home at that time of night. He sent for a pot of slip, which was all the money I saw. I lay out of my house that night.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17641212-24-verdict125" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17641212-24-verdict125" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
