<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660702-26">
               <interp inst="t17660702-26" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660702-26" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660702-26" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660702"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660702-26" type="date" value="17660702"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660702-26-off145-c199" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-26-defend248 t17660702-26-off145 t17660702-26-verdict149"></join>
         
               <p>360. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17660702-26-defend248" type="defendantName">
                  Joshua 
                  Muns 
               <interp inst="t17660702-26-defend248" type="surname" value="Muns"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-26-defend248" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-26-defend248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17660702-26-off145" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660702-26-off145" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-26-off145" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a cotton handkerchief, value 18 d.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17660702-26-victim250" type="victimName">
                     Henry 
                     More 
                  <interp inst="t17660702-26-victim250" type="surname" value="More"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-26-victim250" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-26-victim250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-26-off145 t17660702-26-victim250"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17660702-26-cd146" type="crimeDate">June 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-26-off145 t17660702-26-cd146"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-26-person251">
                  Henry 
                  More 
               <interp inst="t17660702-26-person251" type="surname" value="More"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-26-person251" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-26-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Sunday last, about half an hour past eight in the evening, I was coming up <placeName id="t17660702-26-crimeloc147">Snow-hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17660702-26-crimeloc147" type="placeName" value="Snow-hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660702-26-crimeloc147" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-26-off145 t17660702-26-crimeloc147"></join>; as I crossed the way from one side to the other, I felt something brush against me; I felt in each pocket, and found my handkerchief gone; I turned round, and saw it dropping out of the prisoner's hands, and he was offering to stoop to pick it up; he stooped; I stooped and took it up, and seized him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know him before?</p>
               <p>More. No, I did not; he got hold of it at the same time as I did; first of all he begged my pardon; after I came a little way with him, the mob desired me not to forgive him, but take him to prison. A gentleman came all the way with me to the Counter, where I delivered him: (the handkerchief produced and deposed to.) I knew I had it in my pocket just before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-26-person252">
                  Robert 
                  Butler 
               <interp inst="t17660702-26-person252" type="surname" value="Butler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-26-person252" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-26-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was walking with Mr. More up Snow-hill; he called out, I have lost my handkerchief. I saw it hang between the prisoner and his companion; it was neither on the ground nor in their hands; the handkerchief fell on the ground, and the other man made off: the prisoner said, when Mr. More took hold of him, Sir, if I have offended you, I ask pardon.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>On Sunday night last I was coming up Snow-hill; Mr. More dropped his handkerchief; I saw it drop out of a man's hand, and I saw him make away. Mr. More said to me, you have picked my pocket; I said, I am very certain I have not; I gave him the handkerchief, and he collared me. I am a shagreen case-maker by trade.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-26-person253">
                  William 
                  Eagan 
               <interp inst="t17660702-26-person253" type="surname" value="Eagan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-26-person253" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-26-person253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming from Islington down Cow lane, about half an hour after eight o'clock that night: I came cross the way, and saw the lad at the bar stoop to pick a handkerchief up, which lay on the ground: upon that, this negro fellow took hold of him.</p>
               <p>Note, The prosecutor was a black, <rs id="t17660702-26-viclabel148" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-26-victim250 t17660702-26-viclabel148"></join> to a gentleman.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Eagan. I never saw him in my life before.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Eagan. I have not been home from the West-Indies above a month.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Did you see this evidence at the time you lost your handkerchief?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I did not, as I remember.</p>
               <p>Butler. The man that made off was much like this man, much the same size; if not him, he was much like him, only he was in other coloured cloaths.</p>
               <p>Q. to Eagan. What coloured cloaths had you on that evening?</p>
               <p>Eagan. The same I have on now.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be here a witness?</p>
               <p>Eagan. I was at Guildhall, and saw the prisoner there on Monday; then he begged of me to speak for him.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you there?</p>
               <p>Eagan. I went there for a summons, and was saying I saw it.</p>
               <p>Butler. I saw the evidence Eagan on the Monday night; he had on then a brown coat, the same he had on when he made off, if he is the man.</p>
               <p>Q. Describe the man that made off.</p>
               <p>Butler. The man had a brown coat on, and wore his own hair.</p>
               <p>Note, The evidence had his own hair.</p>
               <p>Q. to Eagan. What was you bred to?</p>
               <p>Eagan. I am a shipwright, and served four years in Port-Royal yard.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660702-26-verdict149" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660702-26-verdict149" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17660702-26-punish150" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660702-26-punish150" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-26-defend248 t17660702-26-punish150"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
