<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680706-29">
               <interp inst="t17680706-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680706-29" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680706-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680706"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680706-29" type="date" value="17680706"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680706-29-off149-c189" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-29-defend251 t17680706-29-off149 t17680706-29-verdict153"></join>
         
               <p>439. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17680706-29-defend251" type="defendantName">
                     Philip 
                     Blake 
                  <interp inst="t17680706-29-defend251" type="surname" value="Blake"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-29-defend251" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-29-defend251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17680706-29-off149" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680706-29-off149" type="offenceCategory" value="breakingPeace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-29-off149" type="offenceSubcategory" value="wounding"></interp>
               unlawfully, knowingly, and feloniously shooting off a pistol loaded with gunpowder and a leaden hall at 
                     
                        <persName id="t17680706-29-victim253" type="victimName">
                           Phillis 
                           Ewen 
                        <interp inst="t17680706-29-victim253" type="surname" value="Ewen"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680706-29-victim253" type="given" value="Phillis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680706-29-victim253" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-29-off149 t17680706-29-victim253"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17680706-29-viclabel150" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-29-victim253 t17680706-29-viclabel150"></join>, she being in a certain garden ground of her the said Phillis
            </rs>, <rs id="t17680706-29-cd151" type="crimeDate">May 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-29-off149 t17680706-29-cd151"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680706-29-person254">
                  Phillis 
                  Ewen 
               <interp inst="t17680706-29-person254" type="surname" value="Ewen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-29-person254" type="given" value="Phillis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-29-person254" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17680706-29-crimeloc152">Brumpton-lane, opposite the Bell, in the parish of Kensington</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17680706-29-crimeloc152" type="placeName" value="Brumpton-lane, opposite the Bell, in the parish of Kensington"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17680706-29-crimeloc152" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-29-off149 t17680706-29-crimeloc152"></join>, and keep a garden-ground; I was married to the prisoner six years ago, it will be the 17th of this month; I tried him in this court for bigamy last March sessions, he was found guilty, and branded (see his trial, No 245, in this Mayoralty;) since that he<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176807060014"></xptr> met with a misfortune of falling down and hurting his leg; he sent for me, and begged I would come and speak to him, for he was a dead man; accordingly I went two or three times, his leg was excessive black and bad; all his discourse was, that he repented of his past life, and begged I would let him come and live with me again; I told him I could not answer it before God nor man: the last time of my going he told me, if I would not condescend, it should be the utter ruin of us both; this might be I believe in April, or the beginning of May; he was then in his lodging by Nibes's pound by Oxford-road, that was the last time I saw him till the 2d of May, between nine and ten at night; then a gentlewoman that lodged at my house went up stairs to supper, after which she flung up the sash, and perceived somebody fly from the window; she came down, and told me; the prisoner's own son, that lives with me, flew out of the house to see who it was, and a man with him, who is since gone away; they found a man among the gooseberry-bushes, they asked him what he wanted there; then I heard it was the prisoner's voice, saying, I want to speak with your mistress, and speak with her I will; I went to the door, he came and asked me what was the reason I would not let his son come to him, and said he had sent for his things, and wanted to know the reason why I did not send them; I was then close by him; I told him his son had been to see him three or four times, and could not find him; he said he was come for his clothes (some of his clothes had continued in my house from the time of his conviction) at his own desire, because he was going to move his lodgings, he sent such word by his son; I did intend to send them, had he not sent for them: then he pushed to come in, I made way for him; as I was standing at the front-door he came in and sat down, and began to talk about what would become of him, and what he was to do; I begged he would go home to his lodgings, for I had nothing to do with him, or he with me; he, in an abrupt manner, began to upbraid me in taking his bread from him: I told him he must endeavour for his bread as I do; he said, if I would open the door for him he would go; I got up, and was going to open it; when I got to the door I had no power to open it, I was in a terror, something seized me; I turned round, and looked him in the face; a gentlewoman that lodged with me screamed out, and cried, Mr. Blake, what are you going to do; she said afterwards she saw the head of a pistol as he pulled it out of his pocket, what answer he made I know not, but I immediately seized hold of the pistol, and his son assisted me; we struggled in the passage, the prisoner fell down at the foot of the stairs, this was in the dark; I begged of him he would spare my life, if it was but for the sake of his of his own child, and I would do any thing; he said, if I got the pistol from him he had another in his pocket; then my strength went away; I told him I would do any thing he desired if he would spare my life; he said, will you; I said, yes, that I would; well then, said he, if you will come to the door I will tell you what I will have you do, or what I want (I cannot tell which) I went to the door; when he had got me about three yards from the door he clapped his left arm round my head, and held it to his bosom, and fired a pistol, and shot me in at the left-side of my neck, and the ball came out on my right-side; it went through my neck (she showed the scars, which showed the ball must go through much about the middle of her neck;) he turned about, and went into an arbour; in about ten minutes after I heard another pistol go off, they were going to see for him; I said, do not go after him, for I believe he has shot himself, but he was found the next morning, between four and five. with his throat cut in the stable; I never saw him afterwards till before Sir 
               <persName id="t17680706-29-person255">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17680706-29-person255" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-29-person255" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-29-person255" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             last Friday se'nnight.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you live when you were together?</p>
               <p>P. Ewen. A very unhappy life, he was a very bad husband.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you apprehend him to be in his senses?</p>
               <p>P. Ewen. I did, as much as I am now.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he make proposals that time to you that he might come and live with you?</p>
               <p>P. Ewen. He did, and I told him I would sooner beg my bread.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you imagine he had made away with himself?</p>
               <p>P. Ewen. Because he must imagine justice would overtake him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you fall when he shot you?</p>
               <p>P. Ewen. No, I was supported by two persons.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he never out of his senses while he lived with you?</p>
               <p>P. Ewen. No, only when he was drunk, he was then as other drunken men are.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680706-29-person256">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Freeman 
               <interp inst="t17680706-29-person256" type="surname" value="Freeman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-29-person256" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-29-person256" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodge in the house, I was in my own apartment, I heard a great cry of murder, I thought there were thieves below murdering the people, and if I go down they will murder me; I listened at the window, and heard Mr. Blake's voice, which I knew very well, I was at his wedding at Kensington; I hearing the maid<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176807060015"></xptr> cry murder in the garden, I went to the window; just as I got to the window I heard a pistol go off, I saw Mrs. Ewen's hair and cap all on fire; she cried, hold me, hold me, I am a dead woman, that wretch (or that poor creature) has murdered me.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know who fired the pistol?</p>
               <p>E. Freeman. I am sure it was the prisoner that fired it; I went down into the entry, she met me, and said, O Mrs. Freeman, he has shot me, he has shot me! I said, God forbid; she said, the bullet is in me, send for a doctor; I saw blood running down her neck: after this I heard another pistol go off in the garden.</p>
               <p>P. Ewen. It was not this gentlewoman that saw the prisoner fly from the window, she is gone into Essex, that was she that said she saw the pistol come out of his pocket; as soon as she heard he was coming out of the hospital she was in great terror, and would not stay.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>She came to my lodgings about three or four days before this happened; I asked her for a few things that were planted in the garden; she said I should have none; I desired to have a few of some that were mine when I married her; she would not let me; I made over some houshold goods to her, and have not had them to this moment; I also made over some houses to her, one at Hyde park-corner, and another at Knights-bridge, and the house she lives in; she has a silver punch ladle that was mine.</p>
               <p>P. Ewen. These were my houses before I was married to him, the ladle was bought with my money.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I did not think of any such thing as firing a pistol; I went there and sat down, and asked for a little small beer; she would not give me any; I asked for a little water; she denied it me, and said she would turn me out of the house; I said I would not go out till she turned me out; I said, will you be friends with me; she said she would; I went to buss her, and going to put my mouth to her she snatched her head away, and the pistol went off accidentally; as for another pistol, I had never another about me; when she cried out, she was killed, I was so frightened that I did not know what I did; I intended to make away with myself, if she would not let me be with her, that was the reason I carried a pistol; when I married to her, the other woman was parted from me 26 or 27 years, and had married another man.</p>
               <p>The record of his trial and conviction for bigamy was read in court, and also his receiving his punishment for the same.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17680706-29-verdict153" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680706-29-verdict153" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17680706-29-punish154" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680706-29-punish154" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-29-defend251 t17680706-29-punish154"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
