<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17620526-8">
               <interp inst="t17620526-8" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620526-8" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620526-8" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17620526"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620526-8" type="date" value="17620526"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620526-8-off40-c68" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620526-8-defend77 t17620526-8-off40 t17620526-8-verdict42"></join>
         
               <p>159. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17620526-8-defend77" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Darby 
                  <interp inst="t17620526-8-defend77" type="surname" value="Darby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-8-defend77" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-8-defend77" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17620526-8-off40" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620526-8-off40" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-8-off40" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing two silver salts, value 2 s. and one silver salt-spoon, value 6 d.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17620526-8-victim79" type="victimName">
                     David 
                     Cockburn 
                  <interp inst="t17620526-8-victim79" type="surname" value="Cockburn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-8-victim79" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-8-victim79" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620526-8-off40 t17620526-8-victim79"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17620526-8-cd41" type="crimeDate">May 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620526-8-off40 t17620526-8-cd41"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620526-8-person80">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Cockburn 
               <interp inst="t17620526-8-person80" type="surname" value="Cockburn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-8-person80" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-8-person80" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My husband is named David, he is captain of a ship now abroad. I was in the cellar, drawing a little beer; I heard a noise above; as I was coming up, I met the prisoner at the bar coming out at my parlour door; I catch'd him by the left arm, and asked him what he had got. He said nothing, and went out at the door. I followed him, and called Stop thief. A gentleman stopt him, he was brought back to me: As soon as I got to the parlour door, I missed my salts out of the basket; I charged him with them. He denied it: he made a pretence to sit down in a chair, and one of the salts was found in the chair; and he turned himself round towards the table, then the other salt was found on the table, and the falt spoon was found on the floor.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure your falts and spoon were not in a places you mention before the prisoner was bought back?</p>
               <p>E. Cockburn. I saw none of them lying on the floor or on the table before he was brought in.</p>
               <p>On her cross examination, she said she missed the things as soon as she went to the parlour door, and charged the prisoner with taking them: that the door was open, and she could see the beaufet where the plate used to lie: that the prisoner pretended to faint away when he sat down: that the table was behind him.</p>
               <p>Q from Prisoner. Did not you say before the justice, you could not tell but that your children might put the things there?</p>
               <p>E. Cockburn. I told the justice I had two children, and a third in arms; I was asked whether they in play might have put them there? I said I could not tell, but I was pretty certain they were in the beauset before the prisoner had been in the parlour.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620526-8-person81">
                  Christopher 
                  Manning 
               <interp inst="t17620526-8-person81" type="surname" value="Manning"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-8-person81" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-8-person81" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 3 d of May I was coming home to dinner; Mrs. Cockburn called Stop thief, as I was at my door. Seeing the prisoner running and she after him, I ran and took him and brought him back to her. When he got into the chair, I saw one salt lying in the chair I was told there was the other salt lying on the table; the prosecutrix said they were in the beauset before; the spoon was found just within the parlour door, upon the ground. Before the justice she was asked if her children might not have been playing with the salts; and, to the best of my knowledge, she said she could not tell.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. Had you not hold of both my hands?</p>
               <p>Manning. No; the prisoner had his right hand in his pocket.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I had sold a sea bed to a man, and was directed by an acquaintance to call upon 
               <persName id="t17620526-8-person82">
                  Christian 
                  Slane 
               <interp inst="t17620526-8-person82" type="surname" value="Slane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-8-person82" type="given" value="Christian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-8-person82" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who lodged thereabouts. I inquired at a chandler's shop; I was told, if I went into that street, there were several people took in lodgers. I went into her house; but, seeing nobody there, I inquired of a gentleman I met with. Then she called Stop thief I asked her what she had lost. She said she could not tell. I desired to be searched; the people said, here is one salt on the table, and another in a chair; she said I must have taken them. Justice Berry asked her what she brought this man for? She said, when I was brought back again, she missed her falts. He asked her when she saw them last? She said, On the Saturday night, or Sunday. Then he asked her if she had any children. She said she had three. He said, had they not put them there. She said, she could not tell.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176205260007"></xptr>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620526-8-person83">
                  William 
                  Dolley 
               <interp inst="t17620526-8-person83" type="surname" value="Dolley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-8-person83" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-8-person83" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about two years, he is in the brokering way; I always took him to be a very honest man, I never heard to the contrary; I have lent him money when he has been going to sea; if it had been 20 or 30 l. I would have lent it him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620526-8-person84">
                  Richard 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17620526-8-person84" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-8-person84" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-8-person84" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him 18 years; he has a very good character, as far as ever I knew; he is a broker now, and lives in good repute; he served his time to my father, who is a shoemaker.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620526-8-person85">
                  Sarah 
                  Hodges 
               <interp inst="t17620526-8-person85" type="surname" value="Hodges"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-8-person85" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-8-person85" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about four years; he is a shoemaker by trade, I never heard any harm of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620526-8-person86">
                  William 
                  Welch 
               <interp inst="t17620526-8-person86" type="surname" value="Welch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-8-person86" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-8-person86" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him three years, his general character is extraordinary good, all the neighbours know him. I keep a bed and blanket warehouse pretty near where he lives; I have dealt with him many a time, and always regarded and respected him: As to his honest dealing with me. I believe him to be an honest man, upon my life.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17620526-8-verdict42" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620526-8-verdict42" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.*</p> 
               <p>*See him tried by the name of Jos. Derbin, Number 93. in Sir Matthew Blackiston's mayoralty, for a crime of the same name.</p>
            </div1>
