<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610916-39">
               <interp inst="t17610916-39" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-39" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-39" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610916"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-39" type="date" value="17610916"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610916-39-off204-c308" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-39-defend375 t17610916-39-off204 t17610916-39-verdict207"></join>
         
               <p>259. (L) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610916-39-defend375" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Garnett 
                  <interp inst="t17610916-39-defend375" type="surname" value="Garnett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-39-defend375" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-39-defend375" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for the <rs id="t17610916-39-off204" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-39-off204" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-39-off204" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               wilful murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17610916-39-victim377" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           King 
                        <interp inst="t17610916-39-victim377" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610916-39-victim377" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610916-39-victim377" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-39-off204 t17610916-39-victim377"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17610916-39-cd205" type="crimeDate">September 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-39-off204 t17610916-39-cd205"></join>. He stood charged on the coroner's inquest for manslaughter. *</p> 
               <p>Thomas Bradbourn. 
               <persName id="t17610916-39-person378">
                  William 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17610916-39-person378" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-39-person378" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-39-person378" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the deceased, and I, went into a house that was sitting up on <placeName id="t17610916-39-crimeloc206">Ludgate-hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-39-crimeloc206" type="placeName" value="Ludgate-hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-39-crimeloc206" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-39-off204 t17610916-39-crimeloc206"></join>, on Tuesday the 8th of September, between five and six o'clock; I said to 
               <persName id="t17610916-39-person379">
                  Michael 
                  Newton 
               <interp inst="t17610916-39-person379" type="surname" value="Newton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-39-person379" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-39-person379" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Do you want a job? if you do I can help you to one. Then King said, You have got a boy, help him, for I can help myself. Then Garnett said to King, Do you help yourself? King said, Yes, I do help myself, and always could, better than you: we are all journeymen carpenters. Then more words arose, 'till King went up to the prisoner, and jostled him with his arm, and his fist was doubled. Then Garnett took up a hammer, and threatened to knock him down, if he did not desist; and made motions four times with it towards his head, but did not hit him. Then they had a good many aggravating words one with the other. Garnett went to the beaufet. and fetched two chissels out, which King had broke, and said, See here, you scoundrel how you have broke my chissels. King said, Cannot I make them good to you, you puppy you, cannot I make them good to you? Then after more words King ran up to him, and shoved him about, and made motions to strike him with the chissels; and after that ran up to him, and put his head under Garnett's chin, and made motions as if he was going to hit him in the face with his head, and seemed as if he wanted to fight him, and jostled him him from one end of the bench to the other, and round the bench. After this I ran between them, and said to King, Come, come, let us go home, there will be mischief done. King came away almost as far as the door; Garnett then called him thief. King said, What, thief and all! thief and all! am I to bear all this. Then he ran back in a sort of a trot to Garnett, in a great passion. I said, come, there will be mischief, let us go home. He was coming along; then somehow or other Garnett hit him over the head. This was as I was pushing King by his back to go home. I did not see him hit him the blow, but I heard it; the blow came over my head. The deceased fell down on the stairs, and the blood ran out of his ear. I saw the prisoner lay the plane down afterwards. Said I, you have killed<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160044"></xptr> the man. Garnett then said, I must be hanged for him. He was then asked to assist in helping the deceased up. He said, Let him lay and be d - d. Then he was asked to fetch a coach for him. He answered, Let him fetch a coach and be d - d; if it was to do again I would do the same. When he was called to help him, he d - d his blood, and said, Let him help himself. I went to the deceased's home, and fetched his wife. Then we put him upon a window-shutter, and carried him to the hospital. I never heard him speak but once after the blow, that was when his wife came, he cried out, Where is my wife? This is all I know of it.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was present at this time?</p>
               <p>Bradbourn. There was Metcalfe, Killingworth, Wilson, and 
               <persName id="t17610916-39-person380">
                  Michael 
                  Newton 
               <interp inst="t17610916-39-person380" type="surname" value="Newton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-39-person380" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-39-person380" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; but Newton was gone up-stairs when the blow was given.</p>
               <p>Q. Were one or both of King's fists doubled?</p>
               <p>Bradbourn. Both of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he put his head under the prisoner's chin with intent to fight him?</p>
               <p>Bradbourn. I do not know but he did; it appeared he did all he could to provoke the prisoner to fight.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner strike him?</p>
               <p>Bradbourn. No, only that fatal blow.</p>
               <p>Q. How long might this last from beginning to end?</p>
               <p>Bradbourn. It might be ten minutes; I cannot say how long; seeing the man lay for dead, put me almost out of my senses.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-39-person381">
                  Charles 
                  Metcalfe 
               <interp inst="t17610916-39-person381" type="surname" value="Metcalfe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-39-person381" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-39-person381" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Tuesday the 8th instant I was at work at a house next door to Mr. Dalmahoy's, on Ludgate-hill; the deceased came into the work with Bradbourn; the deceased was in liquor; he forced his discourse to a person, and the prisoner interfered in the discourse, and there were contradictions and words passed about some tools. Garnett bid him mind his business, and said he had no business there, and they came to very high words. The deceased shoved Garnett against some sash-doors at the farther end of the shop, with pretty great force; and Garnett stumbled against them, but he did not fall. After that I saw him endeavour to strike Garnett with his head, and shoved him about with his elbows. I heard the prisoner say, If he served him so any more, he would knock him down with a hammer, which he had in his hand. After that King retired almost as far as the shop-door: then turned round in a passion, and went up to Garnett again. He had his hand up with an intent to strike Garnett I believe, only the evidence that has been examined was between them. The prisoner immediately laid hold of a plane, and struck the deceased on the right-side of the head with it. The deceased fell immediately with his head on the stairs, on his left-side. We were all surprized. He lay as dead for the space of three minutes, without any motion of life. We got him up, and set him upon a work-stool. He was afterwards carried to the hospital, and put to bed. I heard the sister of the ward say, he lived 'till about half an hour after 12, and then died.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. On whose part was the pushing?</p>
               <p>Metcalfe. The pushing was all by the deceased.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Garnett ever offer to strike the deceased?</p>
               <p>Metcalfe. No, only when he took up the hammer, and said he would hit him with it, if he offered to do so again.</p>
               <p>Q. If that motion the deceased made with his head had hit the prisoner, would it have h him?</p>
               <p>Metcalfe. It would greatly; and after the deceased was got almost to the door, he went back in a great passion, and said, I will, I will, I will. I imagine he went back with intent to strike Garnett.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you believe he would have struck Garnett?</p>
               <p>Metcalfe. I really believe he would, but Garnett immediately took up the plane, and struck him.</p>
               <p>Court. The other witness says the deceased was going towards the door when Garnett struck him that blow.</p>
               <p>Metcalfe. That must be entirely false; for if that had been the case, he must have had the blow on his left side; the prisoner and the deceased were face to face, when the blow was given.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-39-person382">
                  James 
                  Killingworth 
               <interp inst="t17610916-39-person382" type="surname" value="Killingworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-39-person382" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-39-person382" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . King and Bradbourn came into the works between five and six o'clock; King was in liquor. There was a stranger talking to Metcalfe, and King had words with the stranger, and Garnett said to King, You have no business here. King went up to the prisoner, and they had words. King shoved him about, and against some sash-doors, and ran his head up to his face.</p>
               <p>Q. Did his head hit his face?</p>
               <p>Killingworth. I cannot say whether it did or not, I believe not. Then the deceased went almost to the front-door, and words continued between them. Then the deceased turned round in a great passion, and held his hand up, and went very fast, saying, I will, I will, I will. I did not turn my head round to see what was done,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160045"></xptr> but I heard a blow given, and heard something fall, I turned and saw the deceased lying down: I asked Metcalfe who knocked him down; he said Garnett. Then I said to Garnett, have you knocked the man down? Why do not you come and lend a hand to get him up. Wilson, Garnett, and another, set him on one of our work-stools; then a surgeon was fetched to bleed him. I said, now you have hurt the man, why do not you get a coach? He answered, I do not know where. He was carried to Bartholomew's hospital, and died between twelve and one, as I was informed.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you believe he went back with intent to strike the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Killingworth. I really believe he would have struck him, if he had not took the plane and struck him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-39-person383">
                  Wm 
                  Willson 
               <interp inst="t17610916-39-person383" type="surname" value="Willson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-39-person383" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-39-person383" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had an order by my master, to tell King, when he came to take his tools from the shop, he was to go to work in another place; he came to the work in the afternoon much in liquor. Words past between the prisoner and he: he shoved Garnett against the sash-doors with a large shove; Garnett recovered himself, and told the deceased, if he did not desist using him so he would knock him down with the hammer. The deceased being a quarelsome man, I said to him, my dear Billy, good buy, go home, and do not let us have quarrelling here. With that he went towards the front-door, and when he returned back, I had my head in the chimney, and I did not see the blow. The last evidence said, you have killed the man; then I lifted up my head, and saw the deceased lying on his back, with his head upon the stairs. I, Killingworth and Garnett, helped him up: Mr. Farmer was sent for to bleed him; he remained speechless I believe about four minutes; then he cryed, stop, stop, stop. The gentleman, not thinking there was blood enough taken from him, was for taking more. He was very rustical, and said, I cannot stay here: then he wanted to lie down; we laid him on some shavings: after that he was carried to the hospital on a shutter, and I was charged by the constable to go down to Bridewell with the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the deceased a quarelsome man?</p>
               <p>Willson. In liquor he was very quarelsome. I have known him some years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is Garnett as to that?</p>
               <p>Willson. I have kept him company a dozen or fourten years; I never found him a quarrelsome man: he received a great deal of provocation and abuse in his tools from King.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-39-person384">
                  James 
                  Farmer 
               <interp inst="t17610916-39-person384" type="surname" value="Farmer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-39-person384" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-39-person384" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am journeyman to Mr. Dalmahoy. I served my time to an apothecary. I was sent for to bleed the deceased, but did not examine the wound; I could do nothing there.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he die?</p>
               <p>Farmer. I saw him dead when the coroner sat on the body, three or four days after.</p>
               <p>Counsel for the prisoner. I have many witnesses here to the prisoner's character, and as I cannot vary the case, it is to be sure manslaughter, so I shall not take up the time of the court to call them.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610916-39-verdict207" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-39-verdict207" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-39-verdict207" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty. Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610916-39-punish208" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-39-punish208" type="punishmentCategory" value="imprison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-39-punish208" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="newgate"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-39-defend375 t17610916-39-punish208"></join>
               
                     <note>[Imprisonment. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610916-39-punish209" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-39-punish209" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-39-punish209" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-39-defend375 t17610916-39-punish209"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
