<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610401-27">
               <interp inst="t17610401-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610401-27" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610401-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610401"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610401-27" type="date" value="17610401"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610401-27-off147-c167" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610401-27-defend222 t17610401-27-off147 t17610401-27-verdict149"></join>
         
               <p>107 (M) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610401-27-defend222" type="defendantName">
                     Theodore 
                     Gardelle 
                  <interp inst="t17610401-27-defend222" type="surname" value="Gardelle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-defend222" type="given" value="Theodore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-defend222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for the <rs id="t17610401-27-off147" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-off147" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-off147" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               wilful murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17610401-27-victim224" type="victimName">
                           Ann 
                           King 
                        <interp inst="t17610401-27-victim224" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610401-27-victim224" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610401-27-victim224" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610401-27-off147 t17610401-27-victim224"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>. He stood likewise charged on the coroner's inquest for the said murder, <rs id="t17610401-27-cd148" type="crimeDate">Feb. 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610401-27-off147 t17610401-27-cd148"></join> +.</p>
               <p>He being a foreigner, desired to be tried by a jury of half foreigners; whose names are as follows.</p>
         
               <p>
               
                  <persName id="t17610401-27-person225" type="jurorName">
                     William 
                     Hawkins 
                  <interp inst="t17610401-27-person225" type="surname" value="Hawkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person225" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               ,</p>
               <p>
               
                  <persName id="t17610401-27-person226" type="jurorName">
                     Porto 
                     Vallot 
                  <interp inst="t17610401-27-person226" type="surname" value="Vallot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person226" type="given" value="Porto"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person226" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
               ,</p>
               <p>
               
                  <persName id="t17610401-27-person227" type="jurorName">
                     John 
                     Haley 
                  <interp inst="t17610401-27-person227" type="surname" value="Haley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person227" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person227" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               ,</p>
               <p>
               
                  <persName id="t17610401-27-person228" type="jurorName">
                     Paul 
                     Julian 
                  <interp inst="t17610401-27-person228" type="surname" value="Julian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person228" type="given" value="Paul"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               ,</p>
               <p>
               
                  <persName id="t17610401-27-person229" type="jurorName">
                     Thomas 
                     Nicoll 
                  <interp inst="t17610401-27-person229" type="surname" value="Nicoll"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person229" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               ,</p>
               <p>
               
                  <persName id="t17610401-27-person230" type="jurorName">
                     Francis 
                     Eggers 
                  <interp inst="t17610401-27-person230" type="surname" value="Eggers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person230" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               ,</p>
               <p>
               
                  <persName id="t17610401-27-person231" type="jurorName">
                     Thomas 
                     Walter 
                  <interp inst="t17610401-27-person231" type="surname" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person231" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person231" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               ,</p>
               <p>
               
                  <persName id="t17610401-27-person232" type="jurorName">
                     Cornelius 
                     Jongsma 
                  <interp inst="t17610401-27-person232" type="surname" value="Jongsma"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person232" type="given" value="Cornelius"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person232" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               ,</p>
               <p>
               
                  <persName id="t17610401-27-person233" type="jurorName">
                     John 
                     Briant 
                  <interp inst="t17610401-27-person233" type="surname" value="Briant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person233" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               ,</p>
               <p>
               
                  <persName id="t17610401-27-person234" type="jurorName">
                     Paul 
                     Triquand 
                  <interp inst="t17610401-27-person234" type="surname" value="Triquand"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person234" type="given" value="Paul"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person234" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               ,</p>
               <p>
               
                  <persName id="t17610401-27-person235" type="jurorName">
                     Edmond 
                     Franklin 
                  <interp inst="t17610401-27-person235" type="surname" value="Franklin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person235" type="given" value="Edmond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               ,</p>
               <p>
               
                  <persName id="t17610401-27-person236" type="jurorName">
                     Joseph 
                     Schomberg 
                  <interp inst="t17610401-27-person236" type="surname" value="Schomberg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person236" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               .</p>
         
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610401-27-person237">
                  Paul 
                  Vaillant 
               <interp inst="t17610401-27-person237" type="surname" value="Vaillant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person237" type="given" value="Paul"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person237" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq, was sworn Interpreter.</p>
               <p>The gentleman who interpreted the evidence in the French language to Gardelle did not do it sentence by sentence, but in parts, as much as his memory with certainly could contain; after which the prisoner, if he had any thing to say, would speak; which answers of his are not to be understood by our readers as having a regard to the last sentence foregoing his answers, but to the whole part last interpreted, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610401-27-person238">
                  John 
                  Muzard 
               <interp inst="t17610401-27-person238" type="surname" value="Muzard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person238" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Muzard. I was acquainted with the deceased Mrs. 
               <persName id="t17610401-27-person239">
                  Ann 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17610401-27-person239" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person239" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person239" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q Do you remember any evening you past with her?</p>
               <p>Muzard. I do, it was Wednesday evening, the 18th of February.</p>
               <p>Q. How was she then as to her health?</p>
               <p>Muzard. She was very well in health.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you spend the evening with her?</p>
               <p>Muzard. It was at her own house in Leicester-fields; I made an appointment then to go to the Opera with her on the Saturday following.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her between that time and the Saturday following?</p>
               <p>Muzard. No, I did not, I have not seen her from that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you come in consequence of that appointment to her house in Leicester-fields?</p>
               <p>Muzard. I did come on that Saturday, between two and three o'clock in the afternoon.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you see?</p>
               <p>Muzard. The prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say to you?</p>
               <p>Muzard. I asked him where Mrs. King was; and he answered she was gone to Bath or Bristol.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610401-27-person240">
                  Ann 
                  Windsor 
               <interp inst="t17610401-27-person240" type="surname" value="Windsor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person240" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person240" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. I lived with Mrs. King as a servant.</p>
               <p>Q. Give an account of that Thursday you<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176104010020"></xptr> have heard much talk of. What was the first thing you did that morning?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. That was Thursday the 19th of February, I opened my mistress's parlour-windows.</p>
               <p>Q At what time?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. About seven o'clock. As soon as I had opened her windows I went to the passage-door, and knock'd at it; there is a drop; the key lay on the dressing-table by a looking-glass; that is, the key of the street-door. I went into the room, and took the key, and she shut the door, and let the drop down directly.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say any thing to you?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. She asked me how I did; I said I was very poorly; she ordered me to open the other door, that is, the door of her bed-chamber, that opens into the parlour.</p>
               <p>Q. How many doors are there to her bed-chamber.</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. There are two. I opened it, then the fore-parlour was upon the latch. I light my mistress's fire, and at eight o'clock I went up into the prisoner's room. He asked me to go to the Haymarket with two letters, a guinea in gold, and a snuff-box, and bring him a pennyworth of snuff.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he dressed then?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. He was dressed then in a gown, a mixture of red and green; I went down, and carried the box, and two letters, and the guinea, and laid them down on my mistress's table, and told my mistress what he desired me to do.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was your mistress then?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. Then she was in bed.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. My mistress said, Nanny, you can't go, for here is no-body to answer at the door. I told her Mr. Gardelle would come down and sit in the parlour till I came back again, and answer at the door for me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Gardelle tell you he would do so?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. No, I told my mistress that of my own accord; then I went to him, and told him of it, and he said he would come down and answer the door till I did go; accordingly he did come down.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. That is all true.</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. I went out, and left him in the parlour, he had two books in his hand; as I went out at one door he came in at the other. I carried the two letters, one to Mr. Mozier in the Haymarket, and the other to the next door.</p>
               <p>Q Who let you in again when you returned?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. I let myself in again, I carried the key with me, I did not stay for an answer; I went to the snuff-shop, and paid three shillings and nine-pence out of the guinea, and came back again, I really believe, in about a quarter of an hour. When I came back I could find no-body. I unlocked the door, and let myself in, and went into the parlour, there were two books laying, I saw no-body. I laid down the snuff on the table, and the change, and went into Mr. Gardelle's room, up two pair of stairs, and I could find no-body.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I had fainted away, and lay on the ground, near the deceased.</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. I went into every room in the house except my mistress's bed-chamber, I never used to go there unless I was rung for, or called for.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see the prisoner?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. After I had been in his apartment I came down again, and I could find no-body; I made my water boil, and made me a bit of toast, and sat down, and soon heard somebody walk over my head.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you suppose this person was walking?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. I sat in the kitchen, and they seemed to be walking in the parlour or passage. I heard them go along the passage, and up stairs, but did not see them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe where the person came from?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. I did not take any notice of that: after I had done I went into my mistress's parlour, and stirr'd the fire against she got up; then I went up stairs into Mr. Gardelle's room.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the snuff and change when you went into the parlour?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. No, they were gone then.</p>
               <p>Q. What was your business in his room?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. I went there on purpose to clean the room out in a proper manner, in the way I used to do it.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day might that be?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. This was between ten and eleven o'clock.</p>
         
               <p>*** The Last Part of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17610401-27">
                  <interp inst="t17610401-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610401-27" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610401-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610401"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610401-27" type="date" value="17610401"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176104010021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commission of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BALIEY, On Wednesday the 1st, Thursday the 2d, Friday the 3d, and Saturday the 4th of APRIL.</p>
                  <p>In the first Year of His MAJESTY's Reign. Being the Fourth SESSION in the MAYORALTY of The Right Honble Sir 
                  <persName id="t17610401-27-person241">
                     Matthew 
                     Blakiston 
                  <interp inst="t17610401-27-person241" type="surname" value="Blakiston"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610401-27-person241" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610401-27-person241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Knt. LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>NUMBER IV. PART II. for the YEAR 1761.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by J. SCOTT, at the Black-Swan, in Pater-noster Row.</p>
                  <p>M. DCC. LXI.</p>
                  <p>[Price FOUR-PENCE.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176104010022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commission of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery held for the City of London, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Q WAS Mr. Gardelle in his room then?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. No, he was not; he came down stairs out of the garret.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know his business there?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. No; I do not know any business he had there. When I saw him first, he blushed vastly, and had a little bump over his eye, and a black patch over it; he came down from the garret, and went down to his bed-chamber.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he stay in his bed-chamber, before you saw him?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. He staid there the space of an hour, before I saw him; he wrote a letter, and sent me with it into great Suffolk-street, afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he that bump over his eye when you went out?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. No; then he had no blemish at all; but when I came home again, he had a great bump over his left eye, and a black patch over it, as big as a shilling; this was at the time of his blushing.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. That is true.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he dressed then?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. He had changed his dress, and put on a scarlet one.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this the first time of your seeing of him after your return?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. It was; when I went out he was in a green and red night-gown.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say to you?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. He sent me to Great Suffolk-street, next door to the Feathers, to a gentleman. I said, Must I stay for an answer? I went directly. The gentleman said he would be there in the evening.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was you out this time?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. This, was as quick as possibly I could go; I could not be a quarter of an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was he when you came back?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. Then he sat in the fore-parlour.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. That is very true.</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. I told him the gentleman would be there in the evening. Then he said to me, One gentleman has been in the room with your mistress, and your mistress is gone out with one gentleman in a coach.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he speak to you in English?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. I did not understand French. He told me as this; one gentleman had been in your room with your mistress, your mistress is gone out in a coach with one gentleman. This was from his own mouth.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I don't know whether I did say so; I may have said it, but with the hurry and confusion I was in, I cannot tell whether I did or not.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you look at your mistress's bed-chamber?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. I did, and saw it was locked.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you look at the door in the passage?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176104010023"></xptr>A. Windsor. I did not so much as look at that, the other I saw the lock was shot.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you carry any other message for him that day?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. About three o'clock, or between two and three, he wrote a letter, and sent me to the Eagle and Pearl in Suffolk-street; he was upstairs and down all the day. I asked Mr. Gardelle, Must I stay for an answer? He said, if I could not see the gentleman, I was to bring it back again. I went; the gentleman was called down to me. He read the letter, and called me to his apartment, and asked me if I knew of Mr. Gardelle's discharging me. I said, no. He said, Mrs. King was gone out, and gave him orders to discharge me, for she was to bring a woman home with her. I was surprized, and smiled; and said, My mistress is not out, I have been at such a place, and when I came home I did not see her; though she has had neither breakfast nor dinner, and I am positive she is not gone out. I said I was but so far as the Hay-market, and when I came home I could see nobody.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you mention this then?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. I told this to Mr. Broshet.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any farther discourse?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. He asked me if I could write: I said, no: he said, If I would sign it, he would write me a receipt, and I was to give it to Mr. Gardelle when I was paid. I signed it, and he gave it me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Things may be so, but I don't know.</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. Mr. Gardelle paid me, and I returned to the place where I came from to Mrs. King's, and told my former mistress of the affair. She was surprized to see me.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was it that Mr. Gardelle paid you?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. I came back to Mrs. King's about three o'clock, and staid there till between six and seven; then Mr. Gardelle discharged me, and I gave him the receipt.</p>
               <p>Q. During that time did you see your mistress?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. What money did he pay you?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. He paid me six shillings.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you been there?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. I had been there only a fortnight and two days.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was Mr. Gardelle when you came in at three o'clock?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. He was sitting in the parlour, and another gentleman with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the person's name that was with him?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any body else?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. No, nobody: Mr. Wright's servant came in directly as I went out.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is Mr. Wright?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. He is a gentleman that lodged in the first floor at Mrs. King's.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you say any thing to Mr. Wright's servant of your going away?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. I said to him, I went as far as the Hay-market, and when I came in I could see nobody. I said Thomas, when you go in, you'll see my mistress come out of her bed-chamber, for she has not eat nor drank to-day.</p>
               <p>Q Where was this?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. This was at the door as I went out.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you, while you was in your mistress's service, at any time, leave any blankets or sheets, or curtains, in a tub of water?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. No, nothing at all of that sort.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you a person that can give an account of the shifts belonging to Mrs. King?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. I am.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Then you will be called to that presently.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you had any quarrel with your mistress?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. No, none at all; I was surprized at my being paid off.</p>
               <p>Q. What was your reason for thinking she would not see you?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. My mistress was a very merry gentlewoman, and I did think Mr Gardelle had been bold with her; and I did tell my former mistress of this, that I thought she was ashamed to see me, and so turned me off.</p>
               <p>Thomas Pelsey sworn.</p>
               <p>Pelsey. I am servant to Mr. Wright: my master lodged at Mrs. King's in Leicester-square.</p>
               <p>Q. What apartments had he there?</p>
               <p>Pelsey. He had the first floor for himself, and the garret for me to lie in.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember any thing that happened in the month of February?</p>
               <p>Pelsey. My master had taken the lodgings about four or five weeks before this thing happened: he took the lodgings the day after Christmas-day: he was ill, and his mother came to him, and desired he would not stay there, but go home to Grosvenor-square till he was better.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176104010024"></xptr>Q. Did he go home?</p>
               <p>Pelsey. He went home on the 12th of February, and staid till the 19th.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he go?</p>
               <p>Pelsey. To governour Binyon's in Grosvenor-square. On the 19th I was to go in the morning, to let them know we were coming there, to have the beds ready. I went there about one o'clock in the afternoon, and told the maid at the door, but did not go in. Then I went in the evening, and told the maid that my master and I were coming at night, and to have the lodgings ready. Then I went away, and returned to Mrs. King's about seven o'clock at night. When I came to the door, the maid had her box at the door; she had her things packed up.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is that maid?</p>
               <p>Pelsey. The last witness.</p>
               <p>Q. What discourse had you?</p>
               <p>Pelsey. I said, for God's sake, where are you going? She said, she was going away, that the Frenchman had discharged her, and given her five or six shillings over. She said her mistress had been in her bed-room all day, and had had neither victuals nor drink; and if I would stay awhile after she was gone, I might see her come out. The Frenchman said she was gone out to hire a servant. I could not stay, but went out with her when she went out with her box. I came back again to the house that night, about eight or nine in the evening. I went up into my room (the garret) and staid there till ten or eleven: then I came down to the parlour; there I found the prisoner sitting. I asked him if Mrs. King was come home, or who must sit up for her. He said he would stay one hour longer.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. All this may be.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any thing more happen on that Thursday night?</p>
               <p>Pelsey. No, not as I know of.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Now we come to Friday morning.</p>
               <p>Pelsey. When I came down stairs on Friday morning, I asked the prisoner whether Mrs. King was come home, or not. He said, No, she was not come home, but she had been, and was gone again.</p>
               <p>Q. What language did he speak this in?</p>
               <p>Pelsey. He spoke this in broken English, so well as I could understand him. I asked him how he came by that scar on his eye; he said, by cutting some wood, to light the fire in the morning, something had fell against his eye and cut it. Then I left him, and went about my master's business; I was mostly out in the day time, and came back in the evening (this was Friday) I did not see any thing more that evening.</p>
               <p>Q. Who let you in, when you came home?</p>
               <p>Pelsey. The prisoner did; there was no body in the house but he.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any conversation with him that night?</p>
               <p>Pelsey. I cannot say I had; I went to bed directly. I came down usually to ask him, whether he sat up to wait for Mrs. King.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you that night?</p>
               <p>Pelsey. I did; and he said, he would set up for Mrs. King, or something of that sort.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the prisoner on the Saturday morning?</p>
               <p>Pelsey. I did; and asked him where Mrs. King was gone too; he said, to Bath or Bristol.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any thing more happen that day?</p>
               <p>Pelsey. I came back at night, and I believe he let me in; but I cannot say I had any conversation with him that night. I went as usual to bed; but I cannot be sure whether he let me in, or whether I took the key with me, to let my self in on the Saturday night.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any lady in the house on the Saturday night?</p>
               <p>Pelsey. I cannot say, there often were people came to see him or Mrs. King.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Now we come to Sunday morning, what happened then?</p>
               <p>Pelsey. Nothing the whole day, till I came home on the Sunday night; then the door was open, and there were three or four of those gentlemen that used to go backwards and forwards. Soon after I looked back, and saw two women come in; they went up stairs, and supped in his room.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any conversation with him that night?</p>
               <p>Pelsey. No; I had not.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Now what happened on the Monday morning.</p>
               <p>Pelsey. On the Monday morning I came down stairs, his room door stood open. I look'd in, and saw a pair of ruffles and a necklace laying on the table in his room.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was his room?</p>
               <p>Pelsey. His room was up two pair of stairs. I had been down stairs a little while, and I heard the woman, that I supposed lay with him, in the parlour. The chair-woman went up to her; she said to her, if the footman should ask who I am, tell him I am come to be in the house in the room of Mrs. King, or for Mrs. King.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176104010025"></xptr>Q. Had you any conversation with the prisoner on the Monday morning?</p>
               <p>Pelsey. I believe I had not.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any at night?</p>
               <p>Pelsey. On Monday night I asked him where Mrs. King was; he said, Bath or Bristol, he did not know where, or something to that purpose. I went down as usual, to ask him if Mrs. King was come home, or whether he would sit up; then he told me that. I saw a knife lying on the table, I asked him what that was for, he made me no answer; (he always differed at times about where she was) then I went to bed as usual.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Now on the Tuesday morning?</p>
               <p>Pelsey. Going up stairs to my master's room, I asked him what that was that smelt so; (he was going to shove up the sash of the window on the stair-case) he said, somebody had put a bone in the fire. I asked him again at night, when Mrs. King came home, or whether he knew any thing of her. He said, Me know not Mrs. King, she gives me a deal of trouble, but me shall bear of her Wednesday or Thursday.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. In that confusion, I do not know what I said myself.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the prisoner any part of the day on Tuesday?</p>
               <p>Pelsey. I really cannot say what time I saw him; but I asked him if Mrs. King was come home, or if he had heard from her. He said, Mrs. King come home on Thursday or Friday. He said nothing more about her on Friday; but, as usual, I asked him about sitting up.</p>
               <p>Q. What was his answer?</p>
               <p>Pelsey. That was as usual; he would sit up; then I went to bed as usual.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Then, on Wednesday morning, had you any conversation with him.</p>
               <p>Pelsey. Nothing happened on the Wednesday.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Then what on the Thursday.</p>
               <p>Pelsey. I might see him on the Thursday. Thursday night I came home as usual, there was the chair-woman; I heard her say something about blankets, that were in the tub. I asked her if she had examined them; she said no. I asked her if the prisoner was at home; she said no. Then I said we will go and look at those blankets; we both went. She pulled one blanket partly out; and said, she was afraid of pulling a child out. I set down the candle, and said, if she could not, I must. I pulled out two blankets, two sheets, a coverlid, and a bed-curtain.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this tub?</p>
               <p>Pelsey. In the back wash-house; this was on Thursday night.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know to what those blankets, sheets, and curtains belong?</p>
               <p>Pelsey. I said to the chair-woman, this is very odd, how these things should come into the tub; this curtain is none of his curtain, for his bed-curtains are blue and white, and these are red and white; my master's were red and white, but they are all up. But I will go and ask the maid, that he discharged, if I can find her, whether she put these in the tub.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the water appear like?</p>
               <p>Pelsey. The water stunk, and was so thick that we could not perceive what stains they were. We put them all in the tub again, and left them in it; this was the Thursday night.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Now on Friday morning.</p>
               <p>Pelsey. On Friday morning I came down about half an hour after ten, thinking to let the chair-woman in. When I came to the kitchen-stairs, the curtain was hanging on the bannister.</p>
               <p>Q. What curtain was that?</p>
               <p>Pelsey. That was the curtain that I had taken out, and put into the tub again, the overnight. I looked down stairs, and saw the prisoner just come out at the washhouse-door, where the tub stood. Then I went back again, and went up stairs, and staid till the chair-woman came and knocked at the door. I opened the door, and asked her, whether she had hung the curtain there, or meddled with it after we went to bed. She said no. She went down stairs, and looked in the tub; and said, some body had been wringing out the sheets. Then I went soon afterwards, to see for 
               <persName id="t17610401-27-person242">
                  Ann 
                  Windsor 
               <interp inst="t17610401-27-person242" type="surname" value="Windsor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person242" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person242" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and asked her whether she knew any thing of putting those things in the tub, and told her what they were. She said, she did not put them in, and knew nothing of them. After I foun d she was frighted as much as I. I went and told my master of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was your master then?</p>
               <p>Pelsey. He was at a gentleman's in Castle-street.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he laid in the house of Mrs. King since your return there?</p>
               <p>Pelsey. No, he had not, never a night; then my master came and examined the prisoner. I know nothing more of my own knowledge.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I put them in, and I myself did take them out.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176104010026"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17610401-27-person243">
                  Sarah 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17610401-27-person243" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person243" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person243" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner at the bar, when he lodged at Mrs. King's?</p>
               <p>S. Walker. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you lodge there?</p>
               <p>S. Walker. I did, from Saturday till Thursday.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you go first?</p>
               <p>S. Walker. I went on Saturday night.</p>
               <p>Q. What day of the month was that Saturday?</p>
               <p>S. Walker. I cannot tell that, it was when the prisoner was in the house.</p>
               <p>Q. Give an account of your first going there?</p>
               <p>S. Walker. I met two gentlemen in the Hay-market, they asked me to go and drink tea; I said, I was going to look for a lodging; coming cross Leicester-fields, the two gentlemen said, madam, the gentlewoman is gone out of town, will you go in and drink tea here? I went in and drank tea with them.</p>
               <p>Q Was you acquainted with them before?</p>
               <p>S. Walker. No, I never saw them before; there was application made to me to stay with Mr. Gardelle. The other gentleman said, Mrs. King had discharged the servant; the prisoner made an apology, and said, the house was very much in confusion, as there was no servant; and Mr. Mozier asked me, if I would take care of the house.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is he?</p>
               <p>S. Walker. That is the gentleman that was the first evidence.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner present and consenting?</p>
               <p>S. Walker. He was; and he said, he would make up a bed for me. He asked me what my business was. I said, I worked plain work; he said he had some shirts to mend, and he would make me amends, if I would stay, and mend them for him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any agreement of any particular sum of money?</p>
               <p>S. Walker. No, none at all; that night I lay there. On the Sunday morning the prisoner got up between seven and eight, and left me in bed.</p>
               <p>Q. In what room did you lie?</p>
               <p>S. Walker. In his room, up two pair of stairs: he said, it was too soon for me to rise, and I fall asleep again, and slept till almost ten. I got up, and put my cloaths on, and went down stairs; then the prisoner was making the parlour-fire. He spoke to me the night before, to get a chair-woman; and said, Mrs. King was gone out of town. I told him, I thought it was very odd she should go out of town, and leave no servant. He desired me to get a chair-woman, and said, he would allow one a shilling a day; I believe he was so confused he never asked me to stay breakfast. I went home and spoke to the woman of the house where I was a lodger, and asked her, if she could tell me of any body of a good character, to go a chairing; she said, she did not know any; at last I hired Mrs. Pritchard.</p>

               <p>Q. Did he give you any directions what to say to Mr. Wright's servant?</p>
               <p>S. Walker. That was I believe on the Monday.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. It is true.</p>
               <p>S. Walker. I carried Pritchard to the house, and there she was till the Saturday following.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she lie there on nights?</p>
               <p>S Walker. No, she never lay there. On the Sunday or Monday he brought me some new cloth, to make some shirts I sat down and made them. He told me, if Mr. Wright's footman should ask the chair-woman who I was, she was to say, I was some relation of Mrs. King's; this I was to tell the chair-woman, to tell him so.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I do not know that I did say so; because I do not understand English enough to express it. May be I did make her understand it.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Now on the Tuesday.</p>
               <p>S. Walker. On the Tuesday I went on mending his shirts; but on the Tuesday night he said to me, Is it not time to leave work? He said, he should sit up till Mrs. King came home, and he would have me go to bed, which I did. On the Tuesday night I went to bed, and slept till about two. I awaked, and found he was not in bed. I went down stairs, and saw him standing on the stairs. He looked up to me; I said, Sir, I thought you had been asleep; he said, No madam, me ben to tak a walk. And said something he had been like to have been taken up by the watch, or something that had happened.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. This is true; I had been hiding part of the limbs of that poor creature.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Now on the Wednesday.</p>
               <p>S. Walker. He gave me directions on the Wednesday morning; he said, If any body comes, me will not be at home. I was at work in the parlour,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176104010027"></xptr> and he sent for me up stairs, and asked me if I was going into the City; he sat as if he was drawing something. He gave me two shifts, and said, there were two shifts for me; then I went down stairs. On Thursday morning I went out, and when I came back, he told me he expected Mrs. King in the evening, and he bid me get myself a lodging.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I recollect giving her something, but I cannot tell what. [Two shifts produced in court.]</p>
               <p>S. Walker. These are the shifts he gave me.</p>
               <p>Q. to A. Windsor. Look upon these shifts, do you know them?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. I cannot particularly say, but I believe they are Mrs. King's shifts; they are very like the shifts that I have washed and ironed for her.</p>
               <p>Q. to S. Walker. Were they clean when he gave them to you?</p>
               <p>S. Walker. They were.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610401-27-person244">
                  Martha 
                  Pritchard 
               <interp inst="t17610401-27-person244" type="surname" value="Pritchard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person244" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person244" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>M. Pritchard. Mrs. Walker sent a washerwoman to me, to come to be hired. I went to her on Sunday in the afternoon, there were two or three gentlemen, and two gentlewomen, when I came in. The prisoner made the bargain with me for 12 d. a day, victuals and drink. I told him, I could not do any thing that day, but asked him if he had any beds to make. He went up stairs with me, and staid by me while I made his bed. They all went out together, after he came down with me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was 
               <persName id="t17610401-27-person245">
                  Sarah 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17610401-27-person245" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person245" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person245" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             one of them?</p>
               <p>M. Pritchard. She was.</p>
               <p>Q. What room was that bed in?</p>
               <p>M. Pritchard. It was in the two pair of stairs room; they went out to dine, and bid me take care of the house, till they came back again. He came back again in a little time, and said, has any body been enquiring for me. I said no, Sir; he went out again, and did not return till past ten o'clock I believe. Then I asked him if he had any thing more to do with me; he said no. I asked what time I should come in the morning; he said, eight o'clock will be time enough. I went away, and returned on Monday morning, and went about cleaning the house, and made a fire in the parlour, and another in the kitchen, and set the tea-kettle on; by that time he got up. Then I went about cleaning the kitchen.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any conversation about any thing on the Monday?</p>
               <p>M. Pritchard. No. On the Tuesday I wanted water. The water was gone out of the cistern; I took a candle, and went into the back-kitchen, and saw a water-tub; I went back again, and fetched a pail out of the fore-kitchen. I pulled the spiggot out, it ran a little; I got upon the ledge and put my hand in, and felt something soft. I went and fetched the poker and pushed it in, and had water.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is the cistern?</p>
               <p>Pritchard. That is in the fore-kitchen.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you feel something soft?</p>
               <p>Pritchard. In the water-tub. I asked the footman what sort of a gentlewoman this was that kept the house, and told him there were a great many things in the tub.</p>
               <p>Q. What footman was this?</p>
               <p>Pritchard. Mr. Wright's footman. The first opportunity we had, I don't know whether it was Wednesday or Thursday night, Mr. Gardelle being out, the footman and I took two candles and a chair, and got these things out of the water-tub.</p>
               <p>Q. What things were they?</p>
               <p>Pritchard. There were three blankets, a pair of sheets, and a curtain. We shook them, and looked at them, and put them into the tub again. The next day he found the maid that had liv'd there.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of the things afterwards?</p>
               <p>Pritchard. They were wrung out of the tub by degrees.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of the curtain? Was it like any other curtains you had seen there?</p>
               <p>Pritchard. When I came on the Thursday morning, that was hanging on the bannisters of the kitchen stairs. It was not like any that I had seen, to take notice of.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. All this is true.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610401-27-person246">
                  John 
                  Barron 
               <interp inst="t17610401-27-person246" type="surname" value="Barron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person246" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Barron. I was present when the prisoner was apprehended.</p>
               <p>Q. What past before the justice?</p>
               <p>Barron. That was on Saturday the 28th of February. We suspected, from the information Mrs. King's maid and Mr. Wright's footman had given, that Mrs. King had been murdered; I thought proper to take the maid, A. Windsor, before the justice, to make her deposition, in order to get a warrant to apprehend Mr. Gardelle. The<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176104010028"></xptr> day before I had called to ask Mrs. King how she did, and he told me she was gone to Both. He trembled when I spoke to him; then, what strengthened my suspicion that she was murdered, upon our going into the house with the warrant we charged him with the murder, and soon after he dropped down in a swoon. We demanded of him the key of her bed-chamber; he said, Mrs. King has the key with her in the country. A little after that Mr. Gardner went in at the window into the bed-chamber, and then he opened the door which opened into the fore-parlour; then we all entered into the bed-chamber. Upon the bed we found a pair of blankets wet, and a pair of sheets, seemingly never laid in, and the curtain that Mr. Wright's man had seen the day before hanging on the bannister, put up in its place wet. There we found the bed bloody, and other marks of violence, and the blankets bloody, and marks of blood about. From the bed-chamber we went up into his room, that is the two pair of stairs room. In a bag under the prisoner's bed there we found a shift. We pull'd out one of the drawers of his bureau, there we found a shirt that I suppose he had on when he did the mischief; that and the shift were both bloody; and, soon after that, we found the key, which we believed belonged to her bed-chamber, which key we found opened the door in the entry out of the bed chamber. The door could not be opened on the outside, there being no key-hole on the out side.</p>
               <p>Q. Was his bureau lock'd?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610401-27-person247">
                  Barron 
                  It 
               <interp inst="t17610401-27-person247" type="surname" value="It"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person247" type="given" value="Barron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was. Upon searching the prisoner the keys of his bureau were in his pocket. I will not be positive, but I believe the constable took them out.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I believe all this to be true.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of that shift?</p>
               <p>Barron. It was brought before justice Fielding on the Saturday night, with the rest of the things, that is, blankets, sheets, curtain, and the shirt, they were put in the coach with the prisoner, and carried there together. [A shift bloody produced. ] I swear this is the shift that was found in his room. [ A shirt bloody produced. ] I swear this is the shirt I took out of his bureau.</p>
               <p>Q. to A. Windsor. Look at the shift, did you ever see it before?</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. I aired this shift for Mrs. King to put on, on Wednesday night, when she went to bed, to lie in.</p>
               <p>Barron. On Monday Mr. Fielding desired I would attend some people that were to examine about the house. We had a carpenter with us. He pulled down a place, and I saw taken out the contents of the bowels of a human body from the necessary.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Barron. This was on Monday the 2d of March.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Barron. I am an apothecary.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Then you can tell whether they were the bowels of a human body or not?</p>
               <p>Barron. I am sure they were what came out of, or was part of a human body. Upon searching farther, in the cock-lost there were the parts of generation; there was a breast, part of a body and bones, this was between the garret and the cieling.</p>
               <p>Q. What else did you find in the garret?</p>
               <p>Barron. I saw, where there had been a fire, there were many pieces of human bones burnt. I know them to be such; and I handled several other bones of a human body. I both handled and saw them.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>Barron. This was in the garret in the fireplace.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I shall have several things to say with regard to these linnens.</p>
               <p>Mr. Perronneau sworn.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the prisoner at the bar?</p>
               <p>Perronneau. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he at any time send a box to you?</p>
               <p>Perronneau. He brought a box to me under his coat on the Thursday before he was taken up, at about eleven in the morning. [Producing an oval chip or shaven box. ] He said to me, sir, will you be so kind as to keep this box for me, because I am uneasy to leave it at Mrs. King's, because she is gone to Bath.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say was in it?</p>
               <p>Perronneau. He said it contained colours of great value, and which he was very careful of.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it tied down?</p>
               <p>Perronneau. No, it was not. I did not look into it till the Sunday morning that I heard he was taken up; then I opened the box, and there I found a glove, in which was a gold watch, a chain to it, a pair of bracelets, and ear-rings. Produced in court.]</p>
               <p>Q to A. Windsor. Look at this glove.</p>
               <p>A. Windsor. I saw Mrs. King wear such gloves as this; but I can't swear this is one of her gloves.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176104010029"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17610401-27-person248">
                  James 
                  Gardner 
               <interp inst="t17610401-27-person248" type="surname" value="Gardner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person248" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this gold watch.</p>
               <p>Gardner. This I believe to be the property of Mrs. King. I have seen it many times hanging up in her chamber.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17610401-27-person249">
                  John 
                  Mozier 
               <interp inst="t17610401-27-person249" type="surname" value="Mozier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person249" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-person249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the watch, bracelet, and ear-rings, to be the property of Mrs. King, the deceased.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>When I told the maid to go for the snuff, I came down and thought she had been gone. She came up to me, and told me, her mistress said, who shall open the door while you are gone? I wanted snuff, I had not any; I had given the last to Mrs. King. This was the only cause of my sending her out that morning; and, perhaps, I pressed the maid the more earnestly to go as I had none, and was desirous of having some; Mrs. King never having objected to my sending the maid out in the morning, I thought it the more extraordinary and hard in her to hinder her from going out, I imagined she would not be out long, as the messages I sent her on were not a great distance, the two messages being within a door or two of one another. Being in the parlour I took up a book, intending to read, I found it to be English, I laid it down, and went to take up another, which was a French grammar. Mrs. King hearing me walk, as I went from one end of the room to the other, she called out, Who is there? and, at the same time, she opened the door. The grammar lying on the table near her room-door, at the time she opened it I was just by the door, going to take up the grammar. When first she opened the door she seemed rather to be on the smile, and said something to me, and said some harsh thing to me; for w ant of other words, I said to her, impertinent woman, in English, for want of understanding the language. Upon that she grew in a passion, grew red in the face, and gave me a blow here (putting his hand to his side below his left breast) which was more violent than I could have expected from the hand of a woman. Having struck me that blow she drew back again, and I gave her push, rather out of contempt than intending to give her a blow; the push that I gave her, tho' not violent enough to throw her down, but her foot hitch'd in the oil-cloth that was nailed to the floor, and she lost her perpendicular posture, she was still within the door between one and the other, she had a violent fall, not keeping an equilibrium, and her head hit against the corner of the bed. My next motion was to stoop to her to raise her up; I gave her all the tokens I could of being sorry that accident happened; but by the motions of her arms, and by her voice, which was very weak, she refused my assistance, and by her cry she seemed to accuse me of something criminal that frightened me; but, notwithstanding that, I again offered to assist her to raise her up. With the thoughts of appearing criminal frighted me to a great degree. I thought I should be brought before judges to be tried for a criminal act. I endeavoured, by divers means, to raise her up, because she bled a great deal at her mouth. The bleeding was not continued, but like as a person reaches from different returns of the stomach. I then tried, finding that she continued to oppose me in that manner, by threats, to see if I could prevail with her to let me assist her; I then took from the table an ivory or horn, or something or other, it was a broken thing; I threatened her with that; she still continued bawling, notwithstanding my threats. I held it in my left-hand in a kind of despair. I thought within myself, was it possible a woman could bear such malice, and be in the condition she was! That blow was given with so little force, so little strength, so little vigour, that it would be only as letting my hand fall upon the part, that was the reason, as I had no such intention, I was almost mov'd to aggravate my own crime. I look upon even that motion as criminal, but I ought not to have attempted to have lifted up my hand against her; but, that blow did not pierce the skin, for there was no point to that thing that I held in my hand; it was something very thin, but the blood gushing from her mouth stifled her crying, for her cry grew fainter and fainter. Before I let my hand fall upon her, her cry began to be much fainter than at first. To be sure I had a criminal thought, for, after I had done this here, the only thought I had in my mind was, should I have been the cause of this woman's death, there could be no crime in it, for she is a bad woman in herself. I don't disguise any thing at all, for I tell every thing as it was. I found myself giddy, and ready to faint away, and my eyes grew dim, and I lost my understanding. I drawed the bed cloaths and the sheet from off the bed, to put them under her, to stop the effusion of blood, and at the same time I swooned away. I came to myself again, and then I went out of the room; and, being staggering and reeling, my head hit against every thing that I came near. From that moment all the thoughts of my mind have been disturbed, and in the hurry of my mind I don't know what I did, or what I said. Sometimes I thought of flying, and sometimes of not flying. I was in such a condition I did not know what to do; and that night I tried<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176104010030"></xptr> to put her on the bed, because she was quite dead. It was then that my shirt and linnen was bloody, for I had no blood on me till then. I remained 3 days without touching the body, till the Saturday night, then that extraordinary thought came into my mind, that was, to dispose of her by parts, as I could not dispose of the body whole. I was a long while wavering in my mind, how I should do, how I should dispose of it. When I carried the box to Mr. Perronneau's, I did not recollect that the watch was in it. I have no witnesses, because, unfortunately, I was alone when that great accident happened. Mr. Perronneau has known me about 15 years, and he is welcome to say all he can of me, either good or harm.</p>

               <p>Court. Do you desire he should be called?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Yes. I desire he will say all he knows, either good or bad.</p>
               <p>Perronneau. About 15 years ago I knew the prisoner in Paris, he came and lodg'd where I did, he was a very good-natured humane man when I knew him</p>
               <p>Q Have you been acquainted with him within these 15 years.</p>
               <p>Perronneau. I went some time ago to France, then he was there, and I saw him very frequently. He had copied some things that I had done. I am in the same way as he is, an enamel painter.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I should have many things to say since the accident.</p>
               <p>Court. Have you any thing to say with regard to the accident itself?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. No. I think I have explained the whole affair.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610401-27-verdict149" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-verdict149" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17610401-27-punish150" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-punish150" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-punish150" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="hangingInChains"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610401-27-defend222 t17610401-27-punish150"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Being asked what he had to say why sentence of death should not be past upon him, he answered,</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have no reason to offer; but, that the accident was not voluntary. I had no intention to murder this woman, it came by accident. What I did afterwards with the body I look upon to be more wicked than what I did by giving her the blow.</p>
               <p>He received sentence immediately, this being Thursday, to be executed on the Saturday following, being the 4th of April, and his body to be dissected and anatomized.</p>
               <p>After the sentence the prisoner said, Collecting all together, I acknowledge I deserve what I have inflicted upon me. <rs id="t17610401-27-punish151" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-punish151" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-27-punish151" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="executed"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610401-27-defend222 t17610401-27-punish151"></join>
               He was executed in the Hay-market, near Panton street
            </rs>, and his body hang'd in chains on Hounslow-heath.</p>
            </div1>
