<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660903-30">
               <interp inst="t17660903-30" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-30" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-30" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660903"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-30" type="date" value="17660903"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660903-30-off166-c202" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-30-defend263 t17660903-30-off166 t17660903-30-verdict170"></join>
         
               <p>427. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660903-30-defend263" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Newman 
                  <interp inst="t17660903-30-defend263" type="surname" value="Newman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-30-defend263" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-30-defend263" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17660903-30-off166" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660903-30-off166" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-30-off166" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a silver mug, value 30 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17660903-30-victim265" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17660903-30-victim265" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-30-victim265" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-30-victim265" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-30-off166 t17660903-30-victim265"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17660903-30-cd167" type="crimeDate">July 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-30-off166 t17660903-30-cd167"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-30-person266">
                  John 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17660903-30-person266" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-30-person266" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-30-person266" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I <rs id="t17660903-30-viclabel168" type="occupation">keep a public-house in <placeName id="t17660903-30-crimeloc169">Darkhouse-lane</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-30-crimeloc169" type="placeName" value="Darkhouse-lane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-30-crimeloc169" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-30-off166 t17660903-30-crimeloc169"></join>
                  </rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-30-victim265 t17660903-30-viclabel168"></join>. On the 8th of July, between nine and ten in the evening, I missed the mug; on the 9th I advertised it, and on the 10th a gentleman sent to me, to let me know he had the mug and the prisoner in his possession; I went and found it was my mug.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Smith. I have seen him six or seven times in my house: he was in my house an hour, or an hour and a half the evening it was lost, and had a tankard of beer, but it was a mug that was lost; it was taken from the table he went to last; the prisoner was examined by my Lord Mayor; he said he knew nothing of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-30-person267">
                  Roger 
                  Flavel 
               <interp inst="t17660903-30-person267" type="surname" value="Flavel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-30-person267" type="given" value="Roger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-30-person267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to the prosecutor; I served the prisoner with some ham and beer that afternoon that the mug was lost; to the best of my knowledge, it was taken from the table where the prisoner sat.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-30-person268">
                  Mary 
                  Leech 
               <interp inst="t17660903-30-person268" type="surname" value="Leech"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-30-person268" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-30-person268" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Mr. Sawrey's the White-horse, Fleet-market; the prisoner lay at our house; I found the mug under his bed on the 9th of July.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any other bed in the room?</p>
               <p>M. Leech. No, there was not; I called my master and mistress, and they both looked at it, and put it in the place again, and the next morning it was there; the prisoner lay in that bed that night; when we came down stairs, we found by the Daily Advertiser it was advertised: (the mug produced in court.)</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. This is my property.</p>
               <p>Q. By what do you know it?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Here is engraved round the bottom part of it, John Hills, at Darkhouse-lane, Billingsgate, the person's name that owned it before I bought it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-30-person269">
                  Anthony 
                  Sawrey 
               <interp inst="t17660903-30-person269" type="surname" value="Sawrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-30-person269" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-30-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the White-horse-inn in the Fleet-market; my maid informed me of this mug being under the prisoner's bed, and called my wife and me to look at it; I said it belongs to the gentleman that lodges here, put it where you had it, it is not mine, which they did; the prisoner lay there the next night also; in the morning, by looking into the Daily Advertiser, I found it answered the descriptions exactly; I then sent for Mr. Smith the prosecutor; when he came, I said, have you advertised a mug? he said, yes: I had a constable ready; we went into the room where the prisoner was; we looked for the mug but could not find it; I enquired of the prisoner where the mug was; he said he knew nothing of it; I said, my maid informed me of it yesterday, and I saw it, and she said it was standing in the same place this morning; I desired the maid to examine the bed; she removed some of the bed cloaths, and it was found betwixt the quilt and the blanket; then the prisoner said he knew nothing of it; it was not bruised when she saw it at first, but when it was found in the bed it was in this bruised condidion it is in now: (it was very much bruised.)</p>
               <p>M. Leech. When I found it, it had only one very little bruise.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>The room is upon a public stair-case that leads to a public yard; I never was in the room but when I went to bed; I do not know how the mug came there; Mr. Sawrey knows me, please to ask him my character.</p>
               <p>Mr. Sawrey. The prisoner came up by my machine; I have known him two or three years; he first came with a person from Bedfordshire; all I know of him is, he behaved as a gentleman with me till this affair; he might have robbed me of a thousand times the value.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660903-30-verdict170" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660903-30-verdict170" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
