<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660903-37">
               <interp inst="t17660903-37" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-37" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-37" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660903"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-37" type="date" value="17660903"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660903-37-off198-c243" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-37-defend318 t17660903-37-off198 t17660903-37-verdict201"></join>
         
               <p>434. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660903-37-defend318" type="defendantName">
                     Patrick 
                     Maloye 
                  <interp inst="t17660903-37-defend318" type="surname" value="Maloye"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-37-defend318" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-37-defend318" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17660903-37-off198" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660903-37-off198" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-37-off198" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a metal watch, value 30 s. and one brass key, value one penny
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17660903-37-victim320" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Lee 
                  <interp inst="t17660903-37-victim320" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-37-victim320" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-37-victim320" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-37-off198 t17660903-37-victim320"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17660903-37-cd199" type="crimeDate">July 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-37-off198 t17660903-37-cd199"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-37-person321">
                  William 
                  Lee 
               <interp inst="t17660903-37-person321" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-37-person321" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-37-person321" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 15th of July I went to see one Mr. Jackson, in Curzon-street, May-fair; after I had been there about an hour, I was sitting in a window, and Mr. Maloye came by; a person with me called him Maloye; I said, what is it that Maloye that belonged to the Irish Carabineers in Germany? the gentleman said yes. I said I should be glad to speak with him, I had not seen him for four years, since the peace was made. He came in, we shook hands, he sat down; I was glad to see him; we had a shilling's worth of rum and water; after that we might have two or three or more. He being going my way home, we agreed to go together; coming down Half-moon-street, Piccadilly, he asked me if I would go and drink a glass of wine with him at <placeName id="t17660903-37-crimeloc200">the White-horse cellar, Piccadilly</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17660903-37-crimeloc200" type="placeName" value="the White-horse cellar, Piccadilly"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660903-37-crimeloc200" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-37-off198 t17660903-37-crimeloc200"></join>; I said, I did not know whether I should have time to stay, but I would go with him; we went in, and were in a room by ourselves; we called for a bottle of wine; we drank that and had another; he sat at one end of the table and I the other; at the second bottle I was rather a little sleepy; I laid my hand down upon the table, with my head upon my hand; he came to me and said, Halloo! Lee! why you are drunk; said I, I am not very sober; I believe; said he, will you have a post-chaise and go home? I said no, but I must have something. I believe I got up from my chair, and put my hand to my pocket, and found my watch was gone. I said, Maloye, I have lost my watch. Lost your watch! No, Sir, said he; said I, I have, and since I came into this room; and out of the room you shall not go, before I know what is become of it; upon that he rose up immediately, and wanted to go out of the room; I went to the door and said he should not, for if the watch was fifty degrees under ground I would know what was become of it: then he was for fighting me, and wanted to go out; I still persisted he should not go out; thus we continued a good while; then a constable was sent for: when he came, he asked me if I charged the man with any thing; I said with stealing my watch; I said I had it when I went into the room, and I had lost it since, and nobody has been here but him. The constable said to him, have you got the gentleman's watch; he said no, and out he pulled his own, and said, I have no other watch but this. A coach was sent for, and we went in it to Sir J. Fielding; the constable, the landlord of the house, and I believe another man went with us. When we came there, I related the whole story as now. The Justice asked if he had been searched: I said, not to my knowledge; he ordered the constable to search him, and he took my watch out of the prisoner's right hand coat pocket; the glass was broke, and the minute hand off; I had told the prisoner I would give him six guineas for it, if he would deliver it to me, before the constable came, but he would not. The Justice asked him how he could think of robbing his friend; his answer was, he<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176609030024"></xptr> took it in point of honour. The Justice said, it was a very odd sort of a point of honour.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you been often in the prisoner's company before?</p>

               <p>Lee. I had been about three times in his company in Germany; I looked upon him to be a very polite and a very honest man.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you not very fuddled?</p>
               <p>Lee. I was so sober as to know what I was doing.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you your watch out at Mr. Jackson's?</p>
               <p>Lee. I had, and the prisoner took it out of my hand there, and said, your's is a very pretty watch, and I looked at his watch-chain, I had none to mine; I asked him what he gave for his; he said 18 d. I said I should be glad of such a one; then we put our watches in our pockets again.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you give him your watch to get a chain to it?</p>
               <p>Lee. No, I did not; I would not have parted with it for ten times the value of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober when you took out your watch?</p>
               <p>Lee. I was, we had not drank a shilling's worth of liquor at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see it after you came out of Mr. Jackson's house?</p>
               <p>Lee. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go to sleep?</p>
               <p>Lee. I did; he gave me a knock on my shoulder, and gave me a jostle; and if I may be allowed to speak plain, I believe he took my watch at that time; I will not pretend to say it was so. While I was in a confusion with him, there came a fellow and gave me a knock on the side of my head, and knocked me down, and the prisoner got out, and got into another room, and the constable followed him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he drunk or sober?</p>
               <p>Lee. I believe he was not quite sober.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body come in the room while you were together drinking?</p>
               <p>Lee. No, none but the waiter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-37-person322">
                  William 
                  Trouton 
               <interp inst="t17660903-37-person322" type="surname" value="Trouton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-37-person322" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-37-person322" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable. I was sent for on this occasion on the 15th of July; when I came there, there were a great number of people on the outside and in the inside the house; Mr. Lee was in the kitchen; he said, are you a constable? I said, I am; he said he had been robbed of his watch; he pointed to the prisoner, who sat upon a chair with his elbow upon the table, seemingly asleep. I went to him, and asked him if he had the gentleman's watch; he said no. I said, you must go before a magistrate and clear this thing up; a coach was called for; there was a great concourse of people; he was unwilling to go in at first; when we got there, Mr. Lee was examined; Sir John asked whether the prisoner had been searched; somebody said no; I was ordered to search him, and in his right hand coat pocket I found this watch: (produced in court and deposed to by the prosecutor.)</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember it was asked him how he came to rob his friend?</p>
               <p>Trouton. I do; he said something that he did it out of a point of honour.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he mean by that?</p>
               <p>Trouton. I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he not seem to be surprized how it should come into his pocket?</p>
               <p>Trouton. He was desired to search his own pockets by the landlord and others before, but he refused it; Mr. Lee said he would have his watch, and if the prisoner was distressed he would lend him five or six guineas.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they both in liquor?</p>
               <p>Trouton. They were.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-37-person323">
                  William 
                  Billing 
               <interp inst="t17660903-37-person323" type="surname" value="Billing"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-37-person323" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-37-person323" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a waiter at the White-horse cellar; I remember the prosecutor and prisoner coming to our house; they both appeared to be in liquor at coming in; they called for a bottle of wine, I carried it in; after that another; they drank pretty freely; Mr. Lee was drowsy; he laid his arm down upon the table and went to sleep; he turned sick and cast his stomach: Mr. Maloye said he would have a post chaise; I went and ordered it, he got into it: the ostler said, Sir, please to pay for the chaise now, it is customary so to do; he refused it, so the ostler did not chuse to let him have the chaise; then he came out, and the chaise went back; when he came into the room, Mr. Lee was still drowsy; Mr. Maloye had his cane in his hand; he struck him gently, and said, Lee, get up. Mr. Lee stood up and looked about him, and said, I'll have something to go home in. I said, Sir, we have never a chaise at home: said he, I will have a post-chaise, and if you will not go for one I will; he would have one if it cost him a guinea a mile; he went out to see for one; he spoke to the post-boy; the boy said there was none at home; Mr. Lee put his hand to his pocket in the street and said, by G - d I have lost my watch, to the post-boy; he came directly into the room and said, I charge Maloye with stealing my watch; he rang the bell and went into the room, and charged Maloye with taking it, and said he should not go out of the room till he had it; Mr. Maloye denied having it: I wanted to go out upon business:<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176609030025"></xptr> I went out, but he still kept Maloye; there was a scuffle between them; Maloye was rather the weakest; my mistress was sent for into the room; Maloye said to her, Madam, will you let Mr. Lee lie down upon a bed, he is very sick; Maloye lodged one night in the house, he was to have laid there a fortnight; she said he might lie down where he had laid, but she would not have her beds spoiled so.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did Maloye order the chaise to?</p>
               <p>Billing. To Twickenham, he lived servant with my Lord Kerry: my mistress seeing this scuffle, desired the company to get Maloye from Mr. Lee, and he was brought into the kitchen, and put into a chair; Mr. Lee said to him, Maloye, give me my watch, for you have it, and I will have it; give it me, I'll give you five or six guineas if you are distressed: Maloye denied having it, and pulled out his own watch, and said it was all he had; Mr. Lee said that was not his watch. The constable was charged with Maloye, and they went before Sir 
               <persName id="t17660903-37-person324">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17660903-37-person324" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-37-person324" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-37-person324" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in the room when Maloye hit Mr. Lee with his cane, and said, Come, Lee, get up?</p>
               <p>Billing. I was.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>Your Lordship knows I must be very much in liquor, to go to awake the man if I had stole any thing; I had time enough to get away; and when I went out to ask for a post-chaise, whether I had not time enough to convey the watch away; the prosecutor says he never was out of the room, and the waiter says to the contrary. I know nothing of the watch, no more than I do of my dying hour; I said before Sir 
               <persName id="t17660903-37-person325">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17660903-37-person325" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-37-person325" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-37-person325" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , if I took the watch, I should take it out of a point of honour, to keep it for him; but I was so much in liquor, I do not know what I said.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>Thomas Street. I have known the prisoner about two years and four months; he lived with my Lord Kerry, I believe he was his footman; I never heard any thing bad of him before; I always looked upon him to be a well-behaved man. I was coming by the White-horse inn, and saw him and Mr. Lee sitting together, with about half a bottle of wine. Maloye said he had met with an acquaintance that he had known in Germany; they were very joyous together; I recommended Maloye to go to bed, that he might be clear of liquor; he insisted on my drinking a glass. Mr. Lee got hold of me, and desired I would sit down, saying he would make much of any friend of Maloye's.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you know Mr. Lee before?</p>
               <p>Street. I never saw him before to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17660903-37-person326">
                  Welch
               <interp inst="t17660903-37-person326" type="given" value="Welch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-37-person326" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I have known Maloye about three years; I live at my Lady Kerry's; I know my Lord places great confidence in him; his Lordship took Maloye's wife into his service, they have 60 l. a year between them; he had money due to him at that time; had he not, he might have had 20 guineas of my Lord or me either, had he been distressed. I know him to be a very faithful servant.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660903-37-verdict201" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660903-37-verdict201" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
