<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17631207-10">
               <interp inst="t17631207-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-10" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17631207"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-10" type="date" value="17631207"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17631207-10-off51-c89" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-10-defend110 t17631207-10-off51 t17631207-10-verdict55"></join>
         
               <p>12. (L) 
               
                  <persName id="t17631207-10-defend110" type="defendantName">
                     Jacob 
                     Cordoza 
                  <interp inst="t17631207-10-defend110" type="surname" value="Cordoza"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-10-defend110" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-10-defend110" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17631207-10-off51" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631207-10-off51" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-10-off51" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he, on the King's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17631207-10-victim112" type="victimName">
                           Joseph 
                           Williamson 
                        <interp inst="t17631207-10-victim112" type="surname" value="Williamson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17631207-10-victim112" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17631207-10-victim112" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-10-off51 t17631207-10-victim112"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and stealing from his person one man's hat, value 12 d. his property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17631207-10-cd52" type="crimeDate">Nov. 25</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-10-off51 t17631207-10-cd52"></join>. *</p>

               <p>Jos. Williamson. On the 24th of November I was coming from the Mitre Tavern in Fleet street; I am not sure whether the clock had gone 12 or not (I am <rs id="t17631207-10-viclabel53" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-10-victim112 t17631207-10-viclabel53"></join> at that tavern). I met the prisoner<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176312070010"></xptr> at the bar at the bottom of <placeName id="t17631207-10-crimeloc54">Ludgate-hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17631207-10-crimeloc54" type="placeName" value="Ludgate-hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17631207-10-crimeloc54" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-10-off51 t17631207-10-crimeloc54"></join>, I was going towards St. Pauls, he was without a hat. About eight or ten yards before he came to me, he clapt his hand cross his breast, and gave a shove with his elbow, I suppose with intent to shove me down, as he came by me. I did not fall by that shove. He said to me, D - n you, you son of a bitch, what do you mean by that? as much as if I had shoved him; and before he gave me leave to speak, he up with his fist, and hit me under my left ear, and knocked me cross the kennel; he took my hat, and ran cross the way: it was some time before I recovered myself; I got up, and heard somebody on the other side the way, cry, Stop thief. I called the same; the watchman immediately pursued him; my hat was taken up at the lower end of Fleet market. A gentleman that cried, Stop theif, came from the other side the way, and said, Young man, you seem to be very much slury'd by the blow, and he took me into the Punch-house; he went out, and came in again, and brought me my hat.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he here?</p>
               <p>Williamson. No, he is not. I was told the man was taken; then I went to the watch-house door; the prisoner was there: he said, D - n you, you rascal, if you have lost your hat, pray where is mine? (the hat produced, and deposed to) I rather think this hat fell from my head by the blow, than that he took it from my head.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober?</p>
               <p>Williamson. I was very sober. I thought he might be somebody in the neighbourhood, seeing him without a hat.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure he had not a hat in his hand?</p>
               <p>Williamson. I saw both his hands, he could not have a hat in his hand: he struck me with his left fist.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-10-person113">
                  John 
                  James 
               <interp inst="t17631207-10-person113" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-10-person113" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-10-person113" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watchman upon Ludgate-hill; I past by the china-shop there, and saw the prisoner that night standing at the door without a hat.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the night was this?</p>
               <p>James. This was as I began to go upwards, calling the hour twelve: returning again, I saw him and Mr. Williamson tusling together, and Mr. Williamson fell. I was at some distance, and did not see the blow given: I saw the prisoner take up the hat, and pursued him directly, and collar'd him; he threw the hat away behind him: I said, I had seen him without a hat. He asked me whether ever I had seen him without one before? I said no, not till then.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you seen him before?</p>
               <p>James. I had seen him before about the hill.</p>
               <p>Q. What distance of time between seeing him standing without a hat, and his taking up the prosecutors?</p>
               <p>James. It was about 3 minutes distance.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure he had no hat in his hand when standing at that door you mention'd?</p>
               <p>James. He had no hat on his head, nor in his hand neither. I went close by him with my lanthorn.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he wig on, or his own hair? ( note his hair appeared of some length under his wig).</p>
               <p>James. He had a wig on when I took him; he said, where is my hat: said I, you have taken the gentleman's hat. Said he, I have lost mine, then I looked, where I observed his hand to have moved, and saw the prosecutor's hat lying 5 or 6 yards from him, it was a little dirty; this was at the bottom of the market. The Gentleman that took it up, is not here.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-10-person114">
                  John 
                  Spendilow 
               <interp inst="t17631207-10-person114" type="surname" value="Spendilow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-10-person114" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-10-person114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was constable of the night. About the hour 12, I was in the watch-house, I heard the cry, Stop thief, I looked over the hatch, and saw the people run cross the way; I ran over, and asked which was the thief? they shewed me the prisoner, they brought him into the watch-house. A gentleman took up the hat, his name is Ismay; he is not here, he lives in Lower-Thames-Street, he delivered it to the prosecutor at the punch-house.</p>
               <p>Q. How was the prosecutor as to liquor?</p>
               <p>Spendilow. The prosecutor and prisoner were both sober, as I am now.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I lost my hat, I saw that hat lie there, I was going to take it up, but seeing it was not mine, (mine was a slapt one, and that was not) I did not take it; they called Stop thief: I was laid hold on, and taken into the watch-house.</p>
               <p>To his Character.</p>
               <p>Hen. Keys. I have known the prisoner from an insant. I never heard any thing bad of him in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. What is he?</p>
               <p>Keys. He is a snuff-maker.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he been in that business lately?</p>
               <p>Keys. I cannot take upon me to say he has, because I have been abroad, I was steward to the British hospital in Germany.</p>
               <p>Myer Abraham. I served my time with the prisoner's father, in the tobacco and snuff way. I always knew the prisoner to be a good-behaved<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176312070011"></xptr> young fellow. If he was out now, I would employ him in my business.</p>
               <p>Q. What business has he been in lately?</p>
               <p>Abraham. I believe he has followed the tobacco and snuff-trade. I have sent him on errands, and he has brought me both money and goods within this six months.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-10-person115">
                  Isaac 
                  Fonsecco 
               <interp inst="t17631207-10-person115" type="surname" value="Fonsecco"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-10-person115" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-10-person115" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner's father lives in Hounsditch. I live in Petticoat-Square, I always heard a very good character of him; I could not believe this, till I saw him, in Wood-street compter.</p>
               <p>Q. What business has he followed lately?</p>
               <p>Fonsecco. He has not followed any business lately. I believe he has lately been at sea.</p>
               <p>Saunders Aaron. I served my time with his father. I never knew any harm of him; he always did work for his father, as far as I find.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-10-person116">
                  Abraham 
                  Cordoza 
               <interp inst="t17631207-10-person116" type="surname" value="Cordoza"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-10-person116" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-10-person116" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am his uncle, he is a very honest young lad, as far as I know.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known him?</p>
               <p>Cordoza. I knew him from a child.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17631207-10-verdict55" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631207-10-verdict55" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
