<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17620421-16">
               <interp inst="t17620421-16" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620421-16" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620421-16" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17620421"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620421-16" type="date" value="17620421"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620421-16-off80-c159" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-16-defend181 t17620421-16-off80 t17620421-16-verdict83"></join>
         
               <p>131. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17620421-16-defend181" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Allen 
                  <interp inst="t17620421-16-defend181" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-16-defend181" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-16-defend181" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17620421-16-deflabel79" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-16-defend181 t17620421-16-deflabel79"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17620421-16-off80" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620421-16-off80" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-16-off80" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing one half guinea and three shillings and sixpence in money, numbered, the money of 
                     <persName id="t17620421-16-victim182" type="victimName">
                        Thomas 
                        Charlton 
                     <interp inst="t17620421-16-victim182" type="surname" value="Charlton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620421-16-victim182" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620421-16-victim182" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-16-off80 t17620421-16-victim182"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17620421-16-cd81" type="crimeDate">April 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-16-off80 t17620421-16-cd81"></join>.~</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-16-person183">
                  Thomas 
                  Charlton 
               <interp inst="t17620421-16-person183" type="surname" value="Charlton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-16-person183" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-16-person183" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Shoemaker-row, Black friers. Last Friday night I went down to <placeName id="t17620421-16-crimeloc82">Nightingale-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17620421-16-crimeloc82" type="placeName" value="Nightingale-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17620421-16-crimeloc82" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-16-off80 t17620421-16-crimeloc82"></join>. I got into company till the gentleman I wanted came; after I had done with him, I met with two or three of my acquaintance; we sat and drank till about half an hour after twelve; after I parted with them, I met with this woman at the bar; she pretended to be a country girl; she asked me to go along with her to see her apartment; through persuasions I went to her house; when I came there, she wanted something to drink. I said I had been drinking, and would not drink any more. She said this is only my lower apartment, I should go up stairs and see that above. I went up with her; I did not want to stay all night, but through persuasions I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you give her any thing?</p>
               <p>Charlton. I gave her a shilling to stay with her all night. She said, there is another girl in the house who was a partner with her; she gave the other girl the shilling; then she and I went to bed. I had then half a guinea in gold and the rest in silver, about 17 or 18 shillings. She saw it as well as I; we put off our things, and I laid my breeches on the head of the bed, not quite under the pillow; we had not laid above twenty minutes, before she snatched hold of my breeches, and put her hand into the pocket, and gave the money to the other woman, who ran down stairs directly; I not having any thing on did not follow her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the other girl come into the room?</p>
               <p>Charlton. I saw her come in. I took care to secure the prisoner; and then took a candle, and looked under the bed and pillow, to be sure whether she had got it or not. I found no money. I called the watch directly, and had her secured and taken to the watch-house. I went before justice 
               <persName id="t17620421-16-person184">
                  Scott
               <interp inst="t17620421-16-person184" type="given" value="Scott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-16-person184" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the next morning about nine o'clock; as soon as the justice saw her, he called her by her name, and said, are you come again? I missed half a guinea and three shillings in silver; she had left me three shillings and sixpence.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176204210013"></xptr>Q. What condition was you in for liquor?</p>
               <p>Charlton. I was not drunk; I knew as well all about it as I do now. She threatened to cut my throat if she had an opportunity, and cut my nose off.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you been asleep?</p>
               <p>Charlton. No, I had not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner confess any thing?</p>
               <p>Charlton. No, she did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any money in her hand?</p>
               <p>Charlton. No, I saw her hand come out of the pocket, and she put it to the other woman's hand.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>He came into my house between eleven and twelve at night, and sent for some gin; he gave the girl a shilling to sleep with me all night. He was excessively immodest: I did not chuse to be in the room with him: I came down out of the room; he came down and called the watch; the constable searched me, but I had none of his money; he sent the other girl to Bridewell for six weeks to hard labour.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were the prisoner's lodgings?</p>
               <p>Charlton. They were in Swan-alley, St. Catharine's.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17620421-16-verdict83" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620421-16-verdict83" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
