<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680224-45">
               <interp inst="t17680224-45" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680224-45" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680224-45" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680224"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680224-45" type="date" value="17680224"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680224-45-off290-c381" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-45-defend482 t17680224-45-off290 t17680224-45-verdict295"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680224-45-off290-c382" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-45-defend484 t17680224-45-off290 t17680224-45-verdict295"></join>
         
               <p>209, 210. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17680224-45-defend482" type="defendantName">
                     Anne 
                     Griffith 
                  <interp inst="t17680224-45-defend482" type="surname" value="Griffith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-defend482" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-defend482" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17680224-45-defend484" type="defendantName">
                     Jane 
                     Dixon 
                  <interp inst="t17680224-45-defend484" type="surname" value="Dixon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-defend484" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-defend484" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             were indicted for <rs id="t17680224-45-off290" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-off290" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-off290" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing twenty pair of silk stockings, fifteen pair of silk gloves, six pair of silk mits, two pair of worsted hose, four pair of thread hose, and eight pair of cotton hose
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17680224-45-victim486" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Yerbury 
                  <interp inst="t17680224-45-victim486" type="surname" value="Yerbury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-victim486" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-victim486" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-45-off290 t17680224-45-victim486"></join>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17680224-45-cd291" type="crimeDate">Jan. 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-45-off290 t17680224-45-cd291"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-45-person487">
                  John 
                  Yerbury 
               <interp inst="t17680224-45-person487" type="surname" value="Yerbury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person487" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person487" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17680224-45-viclabel292" type="occupation">hosier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-45-victim486 t17680224-45-viclabel292"></join>, and live in <placeName id="t17680224-45-crimeloc293">Lombard-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17680224-45-crimeloc293" type="placeName" value="Lombard-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17680224-45-crimeloc293" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-45-off290 t17680224-45-crimeloc293"></join>; 
               <persName id="t17680224-45-person488">
                  Anne 
                  Griffith 
               <interp inst="t17680224-45-person488" type="surname" value="Griffith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person488" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person488" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was my <rs id="t17680224-45-deflabel294" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-45-defend482 t17680224-45-deflabel294"></join> about four months, the other prisoner was her frequent visitor; they used to call sisters, but I find they are not related at all; on Friday the 15th of January, Mr. Bruin, a pawnbroker, came to my house, and left word (I was not at home) he had four pair of silk hose, and two pair of cotton, and he believed from the account he had received they were my property; there came Mr. Sherman, who lives in Cloth-fair, and the person that lives at the Jack of Newbury in Chiswell-street; they informed me that Dixon had received several sundry goods in my way, and they believed her husband to be a very honest man, and knew nothing of the matter, and they would endeavour to get the goods and let me have them; they told me they were going to the pawnbroker, I said I would meet them there; I went, there was Sherman at the door of a public-house; he desired I would walk in, saying the parties were all there; there was Dixon and her husband; she said she had been recollecting what goods she had received of my maid, and the believed most of them could be got again, and hoped I would not prosecute her; I asked her how she came by them; she said she received them of my maid Griffith; I told them I believed it was not in my power to make the affair up, but I should examine my maid; Mr. Bruin was there, and produced the stockings which he had stopped, four pair of silk and two of cotton; I came here to the Old-Bailey, and got a warrant of Mr. Alderman Turner, being the 15th of January, the time of sessions; I took up my maid, and brought her here before Sir 
               <persName id="t17680224-45-person489">
                  Richard 
                  Glyn 
               <interp inst="t17680224-45-person489" type="surname" value="Glyn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person489" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person489" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; she said Mrs. Dixon used to come to see her, and the goods used to be taken away by her chiefly on Sundays in the forenoon, when she was at home alone; Mr. Bruin produced some stockings, which I then swore to; I then endeavoured to find Mrs. Dixon, but she absconded; Sir 
               <persName id="t17680224-45-person490">
                  Richard 
                  Glyn 
               <interp inst="t17680224-45-person490" type="surname" value="Glyn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person490" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person490" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             granted a warrant to take her, and another to search the house; there we found four pair of white silk mits, two pair of worsted hose, four pair of cotton and one pair of thread hose; I desired Mr. Dixon, if he was clear of the affair, to give me an account where his wife was; he said he would consider of it; I heard nothing of it till the Monday morning, then the husband and Sherman came to the constable, and brought fifteen pair of silk gloves, and an odd one, two pair of silk mits, and five pair of marble silk hose; she was apprehended on the Wednesday following, and examined before my Lord Mayor with 
               <persName id="t17680224-45-person491">
                  Anne 
                  Griffith 
               <interp inst="t17680224-45-person491" type="surname" value="Griffith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person491" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person491" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; the goods were all produced; my Lord asked whose property they were; Dixon said she believed they were mine; he then asked her how she came by them; she said she received them of 
               <persName id="t17680224-45-person492">
                  Anne 
                  Griffith 
               <interp inst="t17680224-45-person492" type="surname" value="Griffith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person492" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person492" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in my house; 
               <persName id="t17680224-45-person493">
                  Anne 
                  Griffith 
               <interp inst="t17680224-45-person493" type="surname" value="Griffith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person493" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person493" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was present, she said she did not give her them herself, but Dixon used to go behind the counter, and take what goods she had a mind to.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-45-person494">
                  James 
                  Bruin 
               <interp inst="t17680224-45-person494" type="surname" value="Bruin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person494" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person494" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a pawnbroker, and live on Snow-hill; one 
               <persName id="t17680224-45-person495">
                  Sarah 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17680224-45-person495" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person495" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person495" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             brought two pair of cotton and four pair of silk hose, on the 15th of January in the evening; she first produced one pair of cotton, and asked half a crown upon them; I said I would let her have 2 s. which I did; then she produced a pair of silk ones; I asked whose they were; she said they were her husband's; I said you must give a better account; then she said she had them from the country to sell by commission; I asked her how long she had been a broker; she did not understand the word, and could not cleverly make me an answer; I desired her to produce a letter of advice, or bill of parcel, or I should stop them; she said if I did, it would be the worst day's work that ever I did; then she said, stop these, and opened a bundle; in the whole were four pair of silk and two of cotton; she was very saucy; I said, if I did not know you I would<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176802240031"></xptr> send you to the Compter; I jumped over the counter, and stopt her, and sent for a constable; then she said she came from Mrs. Dixon, who she said had married a merchant's clerk: when the constable came, I said if you will send for Mrs. Dixon, and she will come, I will let you go; she sent; then Mrs. Dixon and Griffith came together; Dixon said to Smith, what do you mean by pawning my stockings, I gave them you to sell; said I to Dixon, are the stockings your's; she said, yes, they are; said I, you must give me an account how you came by them, or I will send you to the Compter; she said she bought them in Wood-street of a stranger, a good clever looking man; that she gave three guineas for eighteen pair; I said, do you often carry three guineas in your pocket; she said yes, and more; I asked her where her husband lived, and desired her to send for him; she said she did not chose to go where he worked, but if I pleased to go into her neighbourhood, there was one Mr. 
               <persName id="t17680224-45-person496">
                  Sherman
               <interp inst="t17680224-45-person496" type="given" value="Sherman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person496" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a smith knew her; we went there, he was out; we went to two public-houses, but could not find him; when the two prisoners were gone into a public house, a person said they believed Griffith lived with Mr. Vaux, a haberdasher in Cornhill; I took Dixon's word till the morrow; then I went to Mr. Vaux, he told me he did not sell stockings; I described Griffith; he said I should see his chambermaid; I could get no intelligence, and was got as far as the 'Change, a young fellow came after me, and desired me to step back; I did; then I was told the person I described it was thought lived at Mr. Yerbury's in Lombard-street; I went there, he was not at home, I left word with his man of what had passed; he came and saw the stockings; about nine the next morning came Mr. Dixon, Mr. Gold, and Mr. Sherman, with Mrs. Dixon; she said she bought the stockings in Wood-street; then I said I am very sorry to tell you these stockings are stole, I suppose you know Mr. Yerbury; then she turned as pale as death, and was very much frightened; I told her friends she must be transported; they went, and met at the Three Tuns on Snow-hill; there came Mr. Yerbury, I was sent for; they offered to pay any money for what things were missing I was before my Lord Mayor, and heard the prisoner Dixon say she had the stockings of Griffith, and Griffith said Dixon took them herself.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-45-person497">
                  Sarah 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17680224-45-person497" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person497" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person497" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a black-milliner, and live in Foster-lane, Mrs. Dixon brought the six pair of stockings to me, and told me they were the property of a gentlewoman that had kept an hosier's shop; that she had married an extravagant man, a clerk to a merchant; she asked me if I could dispose of any of them; I told her I would try; I did dispose of eleven pair; she brought some to me at three different times, the first was the 29th of December, four pair of women's silk hose; after that she brought seven pair more, I disposed of them; the next was the 11th of January, there were these six pair; she said the gentlewoman was very ill, going to lie in, and could not come herself; I went to Mr. Bruin's on the 15th (the rest as Mr. Bruin had deposed.)</p>
               <p>Griffith's defence.</p>
               <p>I never took any.</p>
               <p>Dixon's defence.</p>
               <p>These stockings I bought in Wood-street, of a man that said he was the manufacturer of them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-45-person498">
                  Sarah 
                  Clegg 
               <interp inst="t17680224-45-person498" type="surname" value="Clegg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person498" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person498" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17680224-45-person499">
                  Anne 
                  Forecast 
               <interp inst="t17680224-45-person499" type="surname" value="Forecast"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person499" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person499" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17680224-45-person500">
                  Mary 
                  Lost 
               <interp inst="t17680224-45-person500" type="surname" value="Lost"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person500" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person500" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , gave 
               <persName id="t17680224-45-person501">
                  Griffith
               <interp inst="t17680224-45-person501" type="given" value="Griffith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person501" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a good character; and 
               <persName id="t17680224-45-person502">
                  Thomas 
                  Gold 
               <interp inst="t17680224-45-person502" type="surname" value="Gold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person502" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person502" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17680224-45-person503">
                  James 
                  Pullin 
               <interp inst="t17680224-45-person503" type="surname" value="Pullin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person503" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person503" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17680224-45-person504">
                  William 
                  Moreman 
               <interp inst="t17680224-45-person504" type="surname" value="Moreman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person504" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person504" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17680224-45-person505">
                  William 
                  Hare 
               <interp inst="t17680224-45-person505" type="surname" value="Hare"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person505" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person505" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17680224-45-person506">
                  William 
                  Humphreys 
               <interp inst="t17680224-45-person506" type="surname" value="Humphreys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person506" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person506" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17680224-45-person507">
                  Mary 
                  Burton 
               <interp inst="t17680224-45-person507" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person507" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person507" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17680224-45-person508">
                  Francis 
                  Rosamond 
               <interp inst="t17680224-45-person508" type="surname" value="Rosamond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person508" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person508" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17680224-45-person509">
                  James 
                  Bayton 
               <interp inst="t17680224-45-person509" type="surname" value="Bayton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person509" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person509" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17680224-45-person510">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Goff 
               <interp inst="t17680224-45-person510" type="surname" value="Goff"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person510" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person510" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , gave 
               <persName id="t17680224-45-person511">
                  Dixon
               <interp inst="t17680224-45-person511" type="given" value="Dixon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-person511" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the same.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17680224-45-verdict295" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-verdict295" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17680224-45-punish296" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680224-45-punish296" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-45-defend482 t17680224-45-punish296"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-45-defend484 t17680224-45-punish296"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
