<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670715-5">
               <interp inst="t17670715-5" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670715-5" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670715-5" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670715"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670715-5" type="date" value="17670715"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670715-5-off22-c45" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-5-defend52 t17670715-5-off22 t17670715-5-verdict27"></join>
         
               <p>339. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17670715-5-defend52" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Mary 
                     Calf 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17670715-5-alias-2" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-5-defend52 t17670715-5-alias-2"></join>Bringhurst</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-5-defend52" type="surname" value="Calf"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-5-defend52" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-5-defend52" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17670715-5-off22" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670715-5-off22" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-5-off22" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing eight guineas, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17670715-5-victim55" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Roberts 
                        <interp inst="t17670715-5-victim55" type="surname" value="Roberts"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670715-5-victim55" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670715-5-victim55" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-5-off22 t17670715-5-victim55"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling-house of the said William
            </rs>, <rs id="t17670715-5-cd23" type="crimeDate">June 11</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-5-off22 t17670715-5-cd23"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670715-5-person56">
                  William 
                  Roberts 
               <interp inst="t17670715-5-person56" type="surname" value="Roberts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-5-person56" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-5-person56" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I <rs id="t17670715-5-viclabel24" type="occupation">keep a public-house</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-5-victim55 t17670715-5-viclabel24"></join>, <placeName id="t17670715-5-crimeloc25">the Noah's Ark, Clerkenwell</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17670715-5-crimeloc25" type="placeName" value="the Noah's Ark, Clerkenwell"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17670715-5-crimeloc25" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-5-off22 t17670715-5-crimeloc25"></join>; the prisoner was my <rs id="t17670715-5-deflabel26" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-5-defend52 t17670715-5-deflabel26"></join>; she came on the 11th of June, and went away the Saturday following; she did not stay three days. I never knew her before.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you a character with her?</p>
               <p>Roberts. I had, by a woman that was with her when she was taken up; after she was gone, I missed about 17 or 18 l. but I swear to about half that sum; the morning she went away she came down, and while I was busy, she stood loitering; I said, she might find something to do; she grumbled, and still did nothing; my wife being ill, I desired her if she could, to get up and help; she came down, then the prisoner went away while I was in the cellar; after that, a neighbour came, and wanted change for a guinea; I sent my wife to get half a guinea out of the bag; she came and said, there is but one half guinea, and 10 or 12 s. in it; then we suspected the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the bag kept?</p>
               <p>Roberts. It was kept in the bureau locked up, that is in the back parlour below; we in general take the bag up stairs when we go to bed, but we did not<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176707150004"></xptr> that night; the money was missing in the morning; to the best of my knowledge we left it locked over night; we were suspicious of the prisoner; we searched about, and found her at the Stationer's Arms in St. John's street; I begged of her to give me an account of my money, and said I would be as favourable as I could, having money to pay the Saturday morning; there was an old woman with her; she and the prisoner called me all the rogues in the world; we took her in custody; the constable took her into another room, after that I was called in; then the prisoner confessed to me, she had taken two guineas and a half in gold, and a handful of silver; we took her before the Justice; there she confessed she took the money in the afternoon, when my wife went out; we found upon her a little brass thing, which I can swear to, which was in a pigeon hole by the money.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670715-5-person57">
                  William 
                  Sheldon 
               <interp inst="t17670715-5-person57" type="surname" value="Sheldon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-5-person57" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-5-person57" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable for the upper liberty of St. John's-street. I was sent for on the 13th of June to the Stationers Arms; the prosecutor gave me charge of the prisoner, for robbing him; she had this bundle with her, (producing a pair of men's black stockings, a pair of women's purple ditto, some handkerchiefs, some silk, some cotton, and a silk hat;) there was an old woman with her; the prisoner said, she had robbed her master of two guineas and a half in gold, and a handful of silver, about 20 s. with which she had bought these things; I summed up the money she said each cost, and found they did not amount to the money; I asked her what was become of the rest of it; then she took out of her pocket a pair of gold ear-rings, a pair of new brass nut-crackers, half a guinea, and two six-pences, (one of them was copper ) which all together made up about three guineas and a half, within a trifle; she always denied taking any more.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body promise her favour if she would confess?</p>
               <p>Sheldon. I heard the prosecutor many times promise her to be as favourable as he could.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Roberts. I am wife to the prosecutor; I cannot particularly say what money there was in the bag, there was a good deal of silver and gold together; after the prisoner was gone, my husband sent me to the bag to fetch half a guinea, then I missed the money.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you or your husband promise her any favour if she would confess?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Roberts. My husband promised her, if she would return him five or six guineas, he would forgive her.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>My master said he would let me go, if I would own I took some; so I thought I had better wrong my conscience than to be confined; my mother had the money by her with which I bought the things, she gave it me.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. She hired herself to me by the name of 
               <persName id="t17670715-5-person58">
                  Mary 
                  Calf 
               <interp inst="t17670715-5-person58" type="surname" value="Calf"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-5-person58" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-5-person58" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and when we came before the Justice, she said her name was 
               <persName id="t17670715-5-person59">
                  Mary 
                  Bringhurst 
               <interp inst="t17670715-5-person59" type="surname" value="Bringhurst"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-5-person59" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-5-person59" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670715-5-person60">
                  Mary 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17670715-5-person60" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-5-person60" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-5-person60" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the prisoner's mother.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you give your daughter money to buy these things here produced?</p>
               <p>M. Clark. No, she had money in her box, she came and took it out; I cannot say how much there was of it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17670715-5-verdict27" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670715-5-verdict27" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
