<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17630914-61">
               <interp inst="t17630914-61" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630914-61" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630914-61" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17630914"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630914-61" type="date" value="17630914"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17630914-61-off338-c358" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630914-61-defend483 t17630914-61-off338 t17630914-61-verdict341"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17630914-61-off338-c359" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630914-61-defend485 t17630914-61-off338 t17630914-61-verdict341"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17630914-61-off338-c360" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630914-61-defend487 t17630914-61-off338 t17630914-61-verdict341"></join>
         
               <p>428, 429, 430. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17630914-61-defend483" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Mary 
                     Cavenhan 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17630914-61-alias-5" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630914-61-defend483 t17630914-61-alias-5"></join>Davis</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-61-defend483" type="surname" value="Cavenhan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-61-defend483" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-61-defend483" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17630914-61-defend485" type="defendantName">
                  Robert 
                  Dickinson 
               <interp inst="t17630914-61-defend485" type="surname" value="Dickinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-61-defend485" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-61-defend485" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17630914-61-defend487" type="defendantName">
                     Margaret 
                     Burgess 
                  <interp inst="t17630914-61-defend487" type="surname" value="Burgess"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-61-defend487" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-61-defend487" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted, <rs id="t17630914-61-off338" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630914-61-off338" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-61-off338" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               the first for that she with a certain poker made of iron, which she had and held in both her hands, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17630914-61-victim489" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Watson 
                        <interp inst="t17630914-61-victim489" type="surname" value="Watson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630914-61-victim489" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630914-61-victim489" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630914-61-off338 t17630914-61-victim489"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did strike on the fore-part and back part of his head, giving him several mortal wounds and bruises, of which he instantly died; and the other two for aiding, abetting, and assisting her to commit the said murder
            </rs>; they stand charged in the like manner by the Coroners Inquest, <rs id="t17630914-61-cd339" type="crimeDate">July 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630914-61-off338 t17630914-61-cd339"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630914-61-person490">
                  George 
                  Callen 
               <interp inst="t17630914-61-person490" type="surname" value="Callen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-61-person490" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-61-person490" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a publican, deposed, he was standing at his own door, at the corner of Shug-lane, on the Tuesday after the murder was committed at Marybone Turnpike, the prisoner Davis coming by in a great hurry, when she came opposite him, she made a full stop; he looking at her, she said, Ay, you may look, for I am in trouble enough. She called for a pennyworth of twopenny, before his servant could bring it she burst out crying, saying, she was the person concerned in the murder of <rs id="t17630914-61-viclabel340" type="occupation">the turnpike-man</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630914-61-victim489 t17630914-61-viclabel340"></join>; he said, you are not well in your head, child, you talk wild; she said, I never have been well since the fact was committed, being disturbed in my mind, or something to that purport; she added, and here is an instance of it, the deceased, after I gave him the first blow, took the poker and wrenched it out of my hand, and here has the black of the poker remained ever since; he looked and there was some black on her hand, but what it was done with he did not know, it seemed something like sut. Then she desired, he would either take her before a Magistrate, or send for a constable; he sent for a constable, and went with her to Justice Welch, but he heard nothing that passed there; that he never saw her before, and her account and manner of behaviour in crying and taking on, it shocked him so that he was not well for a quarter of an hour afterwards. She said, there was a man concerned, but she would not mention his name.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630914-61-person491">
                  John 
                  Bidiford 
               <interp inst="t17630914-61-person491" type="surname" value="Bidiford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-61-person491" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-61-person491" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, she confessed the same to him, with this addition, she was shewed the poker which was found by the deceased, she said she did it with that, and afterwards wrenched a cupboard-door open with it and took out a quantity of halfpence, and Dickenson was with her, that he hit the deceased with a broom-stick, but she did not think that murdered him; that she took the poker and hit him several blows on his head, and did the murder herself. She said, she gave the halfpence to a man whom she would never discover; the end of the poker was compared with the marks on the cupboard, and they exactly agreed. When she saw the body of the deceased lying in a shell, she said, I am the unhappy creature that killed that tollman that lies there; poor soul! you'll have a coffin, I'll have none, to Tyburn I must come.</p>
               <p>Davis's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was at a house when I heard of the murder of the man; I might say I murdered the man. I am sometimes out of my senses, and if any mischief is done, I take it upon myself. I never saw the man or poker before to my knowledge, I never was at Marybone till I was carried there.</p>
               <p>To inquire into the fanity of her mind, 
               <persName id="t17630914-61-person492">
                  Richard 
                  Pierce 
               <interp inst="t17630914-61-person492" type="surname" value="Pierce"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-61-person492" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-61-person492" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the turnkey of Clerkenwell Bridewell, was called, who deposed, she had been about a month or five weeks in his custody; that a little after she was committed by the Coroner, she hanged herself, and was cut down when very near dead; that between two or three years ago she was brought there for the murder of a bastard-child; that he heard her then before Sir 
               <persName id="t17630914-61-person493">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17630914-61-person493" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-61-person493" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-61-person493" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             say, she was tired of her life; that she had cut her child's throat, and was very sorry for what she had done, and desired she might be in custody, and be tried for it; that she had done it in the Grange-walk in Surry, and tied it up in her handkerchief and carried it to Billingsgate and thrown it into the river Thames. Mr. Fielding asked her several questions, and bid her take great care what she said; she said, she would shew them were the blood lay; he ordered him and the constable to take her to Grange-walk, they went in a coach, she bid the coachman stop, they got out, she had them about forty yards up a ruined place, where was some sprinklings of<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176309140030"></xptr> blood, which she said was the blood of the child; she was tried for it at Kingston Assizes and acquitted, but he was not there; and she went to Gloucester and there said she had murdered her child, and was tried there and acquitted; it could not be proved that she ever had a child.</p>
               <p>All three <rs id="t17630914-61-verdict341" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630914-61-verdict341" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
