<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17661217-37">
               <interp inst="t17661217-37" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-37" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-37" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17661217"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-37" type="date" value="17661217"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17661217-37-off197-c310" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-37-defend395 t17661217-37-off197 t17661217-37-verdict200"></join>
         
               <p>48. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17661217-37-defend395" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Collins 
                  <interp inst="t17661217-37-defend395" type="surname" value="Collins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-37-defend395" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-37-defend395" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for that <rs id="t17661217-37-off197" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-37-off197" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-37-off197" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he, on the King's highway, did make an assault upon 
                     
                        <persName id="t17661217-37-victim397" type="victimName">
                           Walter 
                           Cope 
                        <interp inst="t17661217-37-victim397" type="surname" value="Cope"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17661217-37-victim397" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17661217-37-victim397" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-37-off197 t17661217-37-victim397"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , putting him in corpoal fear and danger of his life, and violently taking from his person a silver dollar, value 4 s. and 16 d. in money numbered
            </rs>, his property, <rs id="t17661217-37-cd198" type="crimeDate">November 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-37-off197 t17661217-37-cd198"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176612170032"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-37-person398">
                  Walter 
                  Cope 
               <interp inst="t17661217-37-person398" type="surname" value="Cope"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-37-person398" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-37-person398" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Monday the 24th of November, about half an hour after six in the evening, I was going home from Stratford in a postchaise, and before I came to the two mile stone, the prisoner at the bar came up on the left side of me on horseback, and bid my man stop; it was dark, we had no light but what came from the lamps on the road; my man paid no regard to him, but drove on; in about an hundred yards. he came up with the man again, and presented a pistol, and bid him stop; I saw his hand in that direction, but did not see the pistol; I saw his face by the light of the lamp, we were on that side which the lamps were; the second time he bid the man stop, there appeared two men on the left side, on the bank, whether they belonged to him I do not know; then I let down one of the windows, and called to the man to stop, and called to the prisoner, and said, what do you want my friend; he answered, your money and your watch. I bid him come round to the side window, and I let down that also; he came; I said, what do you say friend; your life or your money, said he; he came close, and said, don't detain me, don't keep me here, make haste. I had an intention of taking him myself, but seeing the two men, I put my hand in my pocket and dropped some of my money, and as I thought kept some halfpence in my hand, and the dollar which I gave him; his right-hand was leaning over the neck of his horse, with the pistol in it. Whether he looked at the money or how, I cannot tell, but he said, this is not enough, give me some more; I told him I had no more, but I had a watch if he chose it; he refused it; then he bid me a good night, and went away: he was pursued by a person that was on horseback behind the chaise; he turned back, and alarmed the watch at the turnpike, at Mile-end: I heard of him in about an hour after I got home; I did not go to him that night, but did the next morning; he was in the watch-house at Mile-end; I swore to his person, and am very positive that is the man.</p>
               <p>Q. How long might he be by the side of the coach?</p>
               <p>Cope. About five minutes, or not quite so much; I could see his face very plain by the lamp; I could not speak to the colour of his cloaths, I thought he had something white before him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-37-person399">
                  Abraham 
                  Sangunetty 
               <interp inst="t17661217-37-person399" type="surname" value="Sangunetty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-37-person399" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-37-person399" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 24th of November I was going to Stratford, betwixt six and seven o'clock in the evening; I came up to the chaise, but did not know that Mr. Cope was in it. I rode behind it; it was a very dark night; I saw the prisoner at the bar pass me two or three times, while I was riding after the chaise; I took him to be a little boy; (note, the prisoner was a very small deformed person) I saw he had something buckled before him, which proved afterwards to be a great coat; I saw him go up to Mr. Cope's man, and bid him stop; he not complying directly, went up to him again, and said, stop, or I will blow your brains out; I did not see the pistol at first; immediately I thought it the best I could do to return back. I met a watchman conducting a gentleman along; I said, a gentleman had been robbed just before; then he said he would go back with me; before we got quite up to the chaise, we met the prisoner, he came close by me; I knew him again, he was upon a low horse, and sat very comically on the horse; I am sure it was the same person; I said to the gentleman, that was the same man: accordingly the watchman alarmed with his rattle, and frightned my horse; I desired him to stop the rattle, which he did. The watchman asked the turnpike man whether such a man had gone through; he said, no. While we were talking, in about a quarter of an hour the prisoner came riding through; I said, that was he, so they stopped him: he was searched, and a pistol found upon him: I was near the lamp when I saw him first, and was within two or three yards of him; I could swear to him by his face, as well as by his appearance.</p>
               <p>Q. What money was found upon him?</p>
               <p>Sangunetty. There were some halfpence and a shilling found upon him, but no dollar; the pistol was loaded, and there was a charge of powder, and two or three balls.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-37-person400">
                  Thomas 
                  Manley 
               <interp inst="t17661217-37-person400" type="surname" value="Manley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-37-person400" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-37-person400" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When the last witness came up to the watchman, I was coming from London, riding my horse a foot pace; he gave the alarm of a highwayman robbing a post-chaise; I turned back and endeavoured to take him; the prisoner came by; Mr. Sangunetty said, that is the man; I stopped my horse, and thought from his diminutive appearance, and being so poorly mounted, he could not be the man: he was galloping when the centinel came up; we followed him: we came to the turnpike before him, and enquired whether such a person had gone through; they said, no: we staid and talked about it; then the prisoner came riding to the gate, going a canter on his little horse: then Mr. Sangunetty called out, that was the man; then I rode after him, and laid hold on his collar; he said he had paid the toll; I said I did not stop him for that, but a robbery; he said he knew of no robbery.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176612170033"></xptr>Q. Did you know him to be the same person you had been shewn before?</p>
               <p>Manley. I believe he was the same, but I cannot swear to his face, but as to his appearance it was the same. He had a shilling in his pocket; Mr. Sangunetty said he had pistols, and bid me take care, so I quitted my own horse and took him to the turnpike-house; I found a pistol loaded with powder and ball, and three more balls and powder, and one flint, and 1 s. 4 d. in halfp ence found upon him; there was no dollar.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-37-person401">
                  Thomas 
                  Hartlett 
               <interp inst="t17661217-37-person401" type="surname" value="Hartlett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-37-person401" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-37-person401" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am one of the collectors of the turnpike. Mr. Sangunetty came up to the gate, and said there as a highwayman on the road; while we were talking, a person said this is he, and he was soon takes; I went to see who it was; I clapped my hand to his pocket and took out this pistol; (a pocket pistol produced in court) the prisoner said, take care of it, it is loaded; I endeavoured to snap it, but it would not go off; he was charged with the fact by Mr. Sangunetty, the next morning we had him before the bench of Justices.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I never care what I do; if any body will give me a pot of beer, then I am well enough.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>He called 
               <persName id="t17661217-37-person402">
                  John 
                  Chetwind 
               <interp inst="t17661217-37-person402" type="surname" value="Chetwind"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-37-person402" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-37-person402" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a victualler at Woodford, who had known him between three and four years, 
               <persName id="t17661217-37-person403">
                  William 
                  Watkins 
               <interp inst="t17661217-37-person403" type="surname" value="Watkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-37-person403" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-37-person403" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a baker, 
               <persName id="t17661217-37-person404">
                  Thomas 
                  Drew 
               <interp inst="t17661217-37-person404" type="surname" value="Drew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-37-person404" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-37-person404" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a carpenter, 
               <persName id="t17661217-37-person405">
                  Thomas 
                  Spicer 
               <interp inst="t17661217-37-person405" type="surname" value="Spicer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-37-person405" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-37-person405" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a gardener, and 
               <persName id="t17661217-37-person406">
                  Thomas 
                  Priest 
               <interp inst="t17661217-37-person406" type="surname" value="Priest"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-37-person406" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-37-person406" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a farrier, all of Woodford, and 
               <persName id="t17661217-37-person407">
                  George 
                  Wiley 
               <interp inst="t17661217-37-person407" type="surname" value="Wiley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-37-person407" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-37-person407" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             of Denmark-street, in the Strand, who said he was a <rs id="t17661217-37-deflabel199" type="occupation">journeyman taylor</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-37-defend395 t17661217-37-deflabel199"></join> of good character.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17661217-37-verdict200" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-37-verdict200" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17661217-37-punish201" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-37-punish201" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-37-defend395 t17661217-37-punish201"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
