<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670715-17">
               <interp inst="t17670715-17" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670715-17" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670715-17" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670715"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670715-17" type="date" value="17670715"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670715-17-off95-c123" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-17-defend156 t17670715-17-off95 t17670715-17-verdict100"></join>
         
               <p>352. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17670715-17-defend156" type="defendantName">
                  Catherine 
                  Goadson 
               <interp inst="t17670715-17-defend156" type="surname" value="Goadson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-17-defend156" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-17-defend156" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17670715-17-deflabel94" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-17-defend156 t17670715-17-deflabel94"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17670715-17-off95" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670715-17-off95" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-17-off95" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing forty seven pieces of silk ribbon, value 10 s. one pair of stuff pumps, value 2 s. three pair of leather pumps, value 1 s. fourteen pieces of silk lace, containing fifteen yards, value 8 s. one pair of silk gloves, value 2 s. and two pair of yarn stockings
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17670715-17-victim158" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Roworth 
                  <interp inst="t17670715-17-victim158" type="surname" value="Roworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-17-victim158" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-17-victim158" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-17-off95 t17670715-17-victim158"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17670715-17-cd96" type="crimeDate">July 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-17-off95 t17670715-17-cd96"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670715-17-person159">
                  William 
                  Roworth 
               <interp inst="t17670715-17-person159" type="surname" value="Roworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-17-person159" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-17-person159" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I <rs id="t17670715-17-viclabel97" type="occupation">keep a haberdasher's shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-17-victim158 t17670715-17-viclabel97"></join> at <placeName id="t17670715-17-crimeloc98">Islington</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17670715-17-crimeloc98" type="placeName" value="Islington"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17670715-17-crimeloc98" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-17-off95 t17670715-17-crimeloc98"></join>; last Monday I came home about half an hour after twelve o'clock at noon, my wife<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176707150011"></xptr> met me, and said, we have found a thief, and said it was our <rs id="t17670715-17-deflabel99" type="occupation">maid</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-17-defend156 t17670715-17-deflabel99"></join>, the prisoner; she took me up stairs, and turned up the bed, and between the bed and sacking lay a great many pieces of ribbon, concealed in her clothes; I went down stairs, the prisoner was in the kitchen; my wife said, take care she does not get away backwards; I went out, and saw a bundle lying in the coal-shed; my wife went and brought them in; there were more ribbons and other things; there were about eight yards of blond lane, about seven yards of black lace, some gauze, a pair of callimanco pumps, three pair of leather pumps for children, two red Morocco and one black, a pair of silk gloves, and a pair of child's stockings.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were the greatest quantity, in the coal-shed or under the bed?</p>
               <p>Roworth. I believe the greatest quantity was under the bed; I charged the prisoner with taking them, and asked her if she had any body concerned with her; she said, no, but would not say any thing more.</p>
               <p>Q. Does any body else live in your house?</p>
               <p>Roworth. Yes, there is Mr. Stark, a hair-merchant in Bartholomew-close, has a lodging there, but neither he nor any of his family were in the house at that time. I took the prisoner before Justice Girdler; he asked her where she had the things; she made no answer a good while, but at last she said she bought the shoes in Coleman-street; two of the shoes have the maker's name on them that works for me, he lives in Newgate-street; as to the other things she could give no account at all.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had she lived with you?</p>
               <p>Roworth. She had lived with me two months that day; the pair of shoes that are not marked, I know well to be my property.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670715-17-person160">
                  Mary 
                  Roworth 
               <interp inst="t17670715-17-person160" type="surname" value="Roworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-17-person160" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-17-person160" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the prosecutor; I missed a pair of silk shoes; I went up with intent to search the prisoner's clothes, and found several trifling things of mine not worth mentioning; in searching the bed I found between the bed and the sacking some ribbon, some lace and stockings, a good many of them were in the prisoner's pocket which lay there. When Mr. Roworth came home, I told him of it, and shewed him them. I said after that, she might get out backwards; he went to see, and came back, and said he had found a bundle in the coal-hole; I said to the prisoner, Kitty, you are a sad girl, what you have done will transport you; she made me no answer, nor owned to any thing. I had a good character with her, but I had given her warning above a month, and she was to have left me as last night; these things were found but last Monday. She had no box to lock any thing up in at my house</p>
               <p>Q. What was the reason you gave her warning?</p>
               <p>M. Roworth. I had a young child, and she did not like nursing.</p>
               <p>The prisoner said nothing in her defence.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17670715-17-verdict100" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670715-17-verdict100" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17670715-17-punish101" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670715-17-punish101" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-17-defend156 t17670715-17-punish101"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
