<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17620114-7">
               <interp inst="t17620114-7" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620114-7" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620114-7" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17620114"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620114-7" type="date" value="17620114"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620114-7-off32-c65" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620114-7-defend75 t17620114-7-off32 t17620114-7-verdict36"></join>
         
               <p>55. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17620114-7-defend75" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Godfrey 
                  <interp inst="t17620114-7-defend75" type="surname" value="Godfrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-7-defend75" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-7-defend75" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17620114-7-off32" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620114-7-off32" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-7-off32" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one silk purse, val. 6 d. and 13 guineas, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17620114-7-victim77" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Featherby 
                        <interp inst="t17620114-7-victim77" type="surname" value="Featherby"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620114-7-victim77" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620114-7-victim77" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620114-7-off32 t17620114-7-victim77"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling-house of the said William
            </rs>, <rs id="t17620114-7-cd33" type="crimeDate">Nov. 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620114-7-off32 t17620114-7-cd33"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620114-7-person78">
                  William 
                  Featherby 
               <interp inst="t17620114-7-person78" type="surname" value="Featherby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-7-person78" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-7-person78" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am <rs id="t17620114-7-viclabel34" type="occupation">a balance-man</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620114-7-victim77 t17620114-7-viclabel34"></join>, and live in <placeName id="t17620114-7-crimeloc35">Shadwell</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17620114-7-crimeloc35" type="placeName" value="Shadwell"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17620114-7-crimeloc35" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620114-7-off32 t17620114-7-crimeloc35"></join>. The prisoner lodged in my house about 10 months; he came in on the 3 d of November, about one o'clock in the day, and went up into his own room; my wife and I were coming to the other end of the town, but my wife returned back again a little before four o'clock, and I returned between seven and eight. She found the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176201140006"></xptr> window open. She told me somebody had been getting in at the window, and my money was gone; that was 13 guineas in a purse which lay in a chest in my bed-chamber; there were a pair of silver buckles lying on the purse, that were not taken away; nor my watch, that lay on the mantle-piece.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you seen your purse last?</p>
               <p>Featherby. I had seen it there about 9 o'clock that morning: my bed chamber is up one pair of stairs; I left the prisoner alone in the house when we went out, he could let himself out. He came home about 9 o'clock. I asked him if he had taken my purse and money? He denied it. I turned him out of my lodging directly; I took him before justice Fielding; then we were to have another hearing. When we went there again, he still denied it. Mr. Fielding said I could not make plain proof against him, and he advised me to let him go. I did; on the 28th of November I was going up stairs, I imagined he might have hid the money somewhere in the house, as he had left his cloaths here.</p>
               <p>Q. How came he to leave his cloaths behind him?</p>
               <p>Featherby. I don't know; he owed me sixteen shillings.</p>
               <p>Q. What things did he leave?</p>
               <p>Featherby. Two frocks, a pair of breeches, five or six pair of shoes, and a gun; they were in the garret where he lay. I searched his frock, and found a hole in the pocket, and in the corner of the bottom of the lining I found my purse which my money was in [Producing a green silk purse.] This is it. Then I went to Hicks's Hall, and shewed it before the grand jury. They asked me what I knew it by? I said, by a bit of hatband that I had tied upon it about a year ago. I got a certificate of his indictment, and took him up again; and took him before Mr. Fielding, and he committed him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell the prisoner you had found the purse in his pocket?</p>
               <p>Featherby. No, I did not; he was threatening to kill me, and I don't know what.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever speak of it to him since?</p>
               <p>Featherby. No, not a word.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever found your money?</p>
               <p>Featherby. No, not a farthing. When I told him I suspected him by his not taking the watch and buckles; he said, They can be sworn to, and money cannot.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your chest locked?</p>
               <p>Featherby. I think it was, but I am not certain.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your room-door locked?</p>
               <p>Featherby. There is no lock upon the door?</p>
               <p>Q. If a person could go in at that window which was found open, is there a way up to your bed-chamber?</p>
               <p>Featherby. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Could the prisoner go out of the house without going out at the window?</p>
               <p>Featherby. We locked the door, and he could let himself out.</p>
               <p>Q. Might he have taken these things away, had he paid the 16 shillings?</p>
               <p>Featherby. He might.</p>
               <p>Q. When you first declared that you had been robbed, did not you declare you had no suspicion of the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Featherby. No, never in my life. I told all the neighbours that he must have it, and nobody else; nobody would go in at that window at that time of the day?</p>
               <p>Q. Did he ever come to your house for his cloaths before the 28th of November.</p>
               <p>Featherby. He did; and I said to my wife, It is to no purpose to keep his cloaths, and bid her fetch down his great coat and hat, and what he wanted, and gave him them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he ask for the other things?</p>
               <p>Featherby. No, he asked for his working cloaths.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any-body with you when you found the purse?</p>
               <p>Featherby. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Has the prisoner ever heard that you found the purse in the lining of his coat, before this minute?</p>
               <p>Featherby. No, not as I know of.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether the prisoner has not been in your house, where he has had an opportunity of taking money?</p>
               <p>Featherby. He has, but we were generally in the house.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I am not guilty of the fact that I am charged with.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620114-7-person79">
                  Henry 
                  Quarrington 
               <interp inst="t17620114-7-person79" type="surname" value="Quarrington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-7-person79" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-7-person79" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner two years; he has a very good character to the best of my knowledge, and an industrious man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620114-7-person80">
                  William 
                  Hunt 
               <interp inst="t17620114-7-person80" type="surname" value="Hunt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-7-person80" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-7-person80" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him pretty near two years; he has bore a good character for all ever I know. I do not think the prosecutor has a good character.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it a good or a bad one?</p>
               <p>Hunt. A bad one. - </p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176201140007"></xptr>William Underwood. I am a piece of a blacksmith. I believe the prisoner is a very honest man; he has a very good character, as far as I know.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he bear a good character in the neighbourhood?</p>
               <p>Underwood. I can't be accountable for neighbours.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620114-7-person81">
                  Ann 
                  Underwood 
               <interp inst="t17620114-7-person81" type="surname" value="Underwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-7-person81" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-7-person81" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner better than a year and half; I never heard a dishonest character of him till Mr. Featherby gave him a bad character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620114-7-person82">
                  Robert 
                  Fox 
               <interp inst="t17620114-7-person82" type="surname" value="Fox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-7-person82" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-7-person82" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about a year and three quarters; he lodged in my house about three quarters of a year, he behaved as well as any man in the world.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620114-7-person83">
                  Alexander 
                  Adams 
               <interp inst="t17620114-7-person83" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-7-person83" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-7-person83" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live near the prisoner; I have known him ever since the 1st of March 1760; I never knew any thing of him but what was very good; he was always a careful industrious man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620114-7-person84">
                  Robert 
                  Sain 
               <interp inst="t17620114-7-person84" type="surname" value="Sain"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-7-person84" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-7-person84" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him from his infancy; he always bore a very good character; I believe he deserved it; he was born at a place called Borham, near Chelmsford in Essex.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17620114-7-verdict36" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620114-7-verdict36" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
