<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17661022-40">
               <interp inst="t17661022-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661022-40" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661022-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17661022"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661022-40" type="date" value="17661022"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17661022-40-off203-c310" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661022-40-defend395 t17661022-40-off203 t17661022-40-verdict206"></join>
         
               <p>516. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17661022-40-defend395" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Felton 
                  <interp inst="t17661022-40-defend395" type="surname" value="Felton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-40-defend395" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-40-defend395" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-40-defend395" type="age" value="18"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17661022-40-off203" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661022-40-off203" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-40-off203" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a bank note, value 25 l. and a bank post bill,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176610220028"></xptr> value 10 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17661022-40-victim397" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Eversdale 
                        <interp inst="t17661022-40-victim397" type="surname" value="Eversdale"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17661022-40-victim397" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17661022-40-victim397" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661022-40-off203 t17661022-40-victim397"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling house of 
                     <persName id="t17661022-40-person398">
                        Aaron 
                        Eaton 
                     <interp inst="t17661022-40-person398" type="surname" value="Eaton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17661022-40-person398" type="given" value="Aaron"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17661022-40-person398" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17661022-40-cd204" type="crimeDate">June 14</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661022-40-off203 t17661022-40-cd204"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661022-40-person399">
                  James 
                  Eversdale 
               <interp inst="t17661022-40-person399" type="surname" value="Eversdale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-40-person399" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-40-person399" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 14th of June last, I inclosed a bank bill of 25 l. and a bank post bill in a letter, and carried the letter to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17661022-40-person400">
                  Aaron 
                  Eaton 
               <interp inst="t17661022-40-person400" type="surname" value="Eaton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-40-person400" type="given" value="Aaron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-40-person400" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's; in <placeName id="t17661022-40-crimeloc205">Chancery-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17661022-40-crimeloc205" type="placeName" value="Chancery-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17661022-40-crimeloc205" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661022-40-off203 t17661022-40-crimeloc205"></join>, and put it in with my own hands; the bank note was No H. 243, payable to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17661022-40-person401">
                  Henry 
                  Hoare 
               <interp inst="t17661022-40-person401" type="surname" value="Hoare"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-40-person401" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-40-person401" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Co. dated May 22, 1766; I saw two young fellows at work in the shop when I delivered it; the letter was directed to Mr. Western; I paid 8 d. for it; I not receiving a letter from the country of the receiving it, as I desired for a post or two, I sent another letter giving an account of this of the 14th; Mr. Western informed me he had not received it; I then went to Mr. Eaton's, and told him I had put a letter in such a day, and paid for it, and it had not been received; he advertised the letter, and shewed me the paper; he asked me the value of the notes; I told him one was 25 l. the other 10 l. he said there was a note of 25 l. found, and shewed me the prisoner; I desired him to take care of him till I had been at the Post-office, to know how to proceed; I went, and had orders to go and bring the prisoner there; I went to Mr. Eaton's, and told him what a commission I had from the office; I was going out with him, turning round I heard something of a whimpering; Mr. Eaton desired me to come back; I did; then the boy at the bar said, I acknowledge the thing, I had the letter and the two notes, that was one of them; I changed it at Newport-Pagnel, and the other of 10 l. I lost out of my pocket coming from Newport-Pagnel to London; when I searched at the Bank, I found the letter H. No 243, May 22, 1766, payable to Hoare and Co. signed by G. Tomlison, the description of my note; when the prisoner was at the office, he confessed the taking it several times to Mr. Secretary 
               <persName id="t17661022-40-person402">
                  Potts
               <interp inst="t17661022-40-person402" type="given" value="Potts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-40-person402" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661022-40-person403">
                  Aaron 
                  Eaton 
               <interp inst="t17661022-40-person403" type="surname" value="Eaton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-40-person403" type="given" value="Aaron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-40-person403" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a house in Chancery-lane, and receive letters for the General Post-office; I remember being in the shop on the 14th of June last; the prisoner was at work in the shop that evening, and on the 15th, being Sunday, he went out, and returned the Monday se'nnight following, being the 23d; I received a letter from Newport-Pagnel, on Friday the 20th, that he was there; I went and found him; he had bought cloth for a suit of cloaths, a watch, and a pair of sleeve buttons, and changed the bank note for 25 l. to pay for them, and he had ten guineas about him; I confined him as a run-away apprentice, and brought him to town. On the 3d of July, being Thursday, Mr. Eversdale came to enquire about this letter with the notes; I shewed him the advertisement which I had put in the papers and shewed him the prisoner; the prisoner said he found the note of 25 l. when Mr. Eversdale said he must go to the Post-office; then as we were going out of the shop, the prisoner desired him to come back and he would tell the truth; then he confessed he took the two notes out of a double post letter, which was put in in my shop, and at the Post-office he confessed the same.</p>
               <p>Mr. Potts. I am secretary to the Post-office; the prisoner was brought to the office, charged with taking two notes out of a letter, put in at Mr. Eaton's; he confessed he took them both out of a letter; Mr. Eaton and Mr. Eversdale were by at the time; he said one was 25 l. and the other 10 l. the 25 l. he had changed, and the other he had.</p>
               <p>The prisoner said nothing in his defence.</p>
               <p>Q. to Eaton. How old is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Eaton. He is about 18 years of age.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17661022-40-verdict206" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661022-40-verdict206" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17661022-40-punish207" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661022-40-punish207" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661022-40-defend395 t17661022-40-punish207"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
