<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17611021-13">
               <interp inst="t17611021-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611021-13" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611021-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17611021"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611021-13" type="date" value="17611021"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17611021-13-off62-c62" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-13-defend86 t17611021-13-off62 t17611021-13-verdict66"></join>
         
               <p>297. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17611021-13-defend86" type="defendantName">
                  Mary, <rs id="t17611021-13-deflabel61" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-13-defend86 t17611021-13-deflabel61"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17611021-13-person87">
                        James 
                        Maynard 
                     <interp inst="t17611021-13-person87" type="surname" value="Maynard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17611021-13-person87" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17611021-13-person87" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
                     <interp inst="t17611021-13-defend86" type="surname" value="Maynard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-13-defend86" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-13-defend86" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17611021-13-off62" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611021-13-off62" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-13-off62" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing six pounds weight of worstead, value 15 s. and two ounces of silk, value 4 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17611021-13-victim89" type="victimName">
                     Robert 
                     James 
                  <interp inst="t17611021-13-victim89" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-13-victim89" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-13-victim89" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-13-off62 t17611021-13-victim89"></join>
                  </persName>
                
             
                  <rs id="t17611021-13-viclabel63" type="occupation">the younger</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-13-victim89 t17611021-13-viclabel63"></join>, <rs id="t17611021-13-cd64" type="crimeDate">Sept. 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-13-off62 t17611021-13-cd64"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-13-person90">
                  Robert 
                  James 
               <interp inst="t17611021-13-person90" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-13-person90" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-13-person90" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the younger. I am in a separate business from my father, <rs id="t17611021-13-viclabel65" type="occupation">I am in the weaving-branch in the lace way</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-13-victim89 t17611021-13-viclabel65"></join>, I employ several people: I missed small parcels time after time out of my warehouse, but could not tell but what I might have made mistakes. About the beginning of September my boy saw my servant-girl, who is daughter to the prisoner, in my warehouse. I being informed of it, examined the girl; she told me she got in by opening a trap-door, from off a heap of coals in my cellar, and took goods away, and buried them under the dirt, in a corner of the cellar, and the mother used to come and take them away: she has been examined by her mother's friends, and gives the same account, that none but her mother perswaded her to it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was her mother (the prisoner) by at the time?</p>
               <p>James. She was, but she said it was a falsity. The girl declared the same in the presence of her mother, before my lord mayor.</p>
               <p>Q. What quantity did you lose?</p>
               <p>James. It is impossible to say that, it may be an hundred-weight, or it may not be a pound. I have missed goods for above a year, but will not swear to any particular quantity. I asked the girl before her mother, how much she had taken away: said she, it has been going on for above 12 months. Said I, have you been and taken goods two, three, or four times? She said, Sir, I am sure it is above twenty; sometimes one, two, or three bundles at a time; that is, half-pound bundles.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the value of a half-pound bundle?</p>
               <p>James. I'll say a shilling value. The woman was examined before my lord -mayor; she declared she was innocent; my lord would have had me taken out a search-warrant; but I said, as she was employed at tassel-making, I supposed it was all work'd up immediately.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-13-person91">
                  Robert 
                  James 
               <interp inst="t17611021-13-person91" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-13-person91" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-13-person91" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the elder. The prosecutor is my son; I know nothing more but by the girl's confession,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176110210009"></xptr> in the presence of her mother, the prisoner. My son had complained he missed goods, and afterwards he told me that the girl was seen in the warehouse, and which way she got in. I examined her, and she said, indeed it was my mother that persuaded me to get in, and take the worsted, to make a few tassels. She told me how she got in, and took the goods out, and hid them till the mother came, to take them away.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say the mother took them from the place where she put them, or that the girl gave them to her?</p>
               <p>James. She said the girl used to give them to her.</p>
               <p>Q Was this in the presence of the mother?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-13-person92">
                  James 
                  It 
               <interp inst="t17611021-13-person92" type="surname" value="It"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-13-person92" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-13-person92" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was.</p>
               <p>Q. How old is the girl?</p>
               <p>James. She is in the 14th year of her age.</p>
               <p>Q to Prosecutor. How did the girl say her mother came by them?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. She said she used to take them out of the cellar, and deliver them to her in my kitchen, when she came to see her. The girl declared before the lord-mayor, she never took an ounce of goods out of my house in her life, but she delivered all to her mother in the house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-13-person93">
                  Margaret 
                  Maynard 
               <interp inst="t17611021-13-person93" type="surname" value="Maynard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-13-person93" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-13-person93" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am in the 14th year of my age. I lived with Mr. 
               <persName id="t17611021-13-person94">
                  James
               <interp inst="t17611021-13-person94" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-13-person94" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the younger. I used to get worsted for my mother, by getting up a trap door out of the cellar, into the warehouse.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be so wicked?</p>
               <p>M. Maynard. My mother bid me get some.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is your mother?</p>
               <p>M. Maynard. That is my mother at the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. What quantity might you have got for her?</p>
               <p>M. Maynard. Sometimes a bundle, sometimes two at a time.</p>
               <p>Q. How many bundles, upon the whole, do you think you have taken?</p>
               <p>M. Maynard I cannot tell; I hid them in the cellar till my mother came to fetch them.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. At what particular times had I any worsted of you?</p>
               <p>M. Maynard. On Sundays in the afternoon I have delivered some to you very often.</p>
               <p>Q. How long since you delivered her the last parcel?</p>
               <p>M. Maynard. I believe it is about two or three months ago.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. When was it that the boy saw the girl in the warehouse, and told you of it?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I believe that might be about the 14th or 15th of September last.</p>
               <p>Q. to M. Maynard. How long was the last time you got some worsted, before you was seen in the warehouse?</p>
               <p>M. Maynard. It was some time before that time, it may be about three weeks before that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Did your master promise you any reward on the account of being a witness.</p>
               <p>M. Maynard. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I am as innocent as any person in court.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mr. Crosdale. I am a lace-man, this good woman at the bar formerly worked for me, for about 18 months.</p>

               <p>Q What is her character?</p>
               <p>Crosdale. Upon my word I put a good deal of confidence in her, I trusted her considerably, I never had any suspicion of her, or found any thing amiss by her.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is it since she work'd for you?</p>
               <p>Crosdale. It is about 18 months ago.</p>
               <p>Mr. Armstead. I have known her about twelve years. I am a fringe and tassel-maker. I employed her about three months ago, and I employed her husband in turning moulds for me. I never found that she wrong'd me, I believe her to be an honest woman, for any thing that I know. I have trusted her with work in the Compter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-13-person95">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Marlow 
               <interp inst="t17611021-13-person95" type="surname" value="Marlow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-13-person95" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-13-person95" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner a great many years.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>E. Marlow. I live in Aldersgate-street, and am a milliner. I have had her in my house for five or six weeks together; she has had a great opportunity of robbing me had she had a mind so to do. I believe her to be as honest a woman as can be.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-13-person96">
                  Thomas 
                  Newbury 
               <interp inst="t17611021-13-person96" type="surname" value="Newbury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-13-person96" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-13-person96" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her about 14 years, I never knew any thing amiss of her before this in my life.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17611021-13-verdict66" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611021-13-verdict66" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-13-person97">
                  Margaret 
                  Giles 
               <interp inst="t17611021-13-person97" type="surname" value="Giles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-13-person97" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-13-person97" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             insulted the prosecutor as soon as he was got into the Court-yard, and struck the evidence Maynard. She was secured, and brought into Court by the city-marshal, and committed by the lord mayor to Newgate.</p>
            </div1>
