<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17600227-18">
               <interp inst="t17600227-18" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600227-18" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600227-18" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600227"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600227-18" type="date" value="17600227"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600227-18-off79-c117" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600227-18-defend150 t17600227-18-off79 t17600227-18-verdict83"></join>
         
               <p>96 (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17600227-18-defend150" type="defendantName">
                     Catherine 
                     Beard 
                  <interp inst="t17600227-18-defend150" type="surname" value="Beard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-18-defend150" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-18-defend150" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17600227-18-deflabel78" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600227-18-defend150 t17600227-18-deflabel78"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17600227-18-off79" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600227-18-off79" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-18-off79" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one guinea
            </rs>, the money of 
               
                  <persName id="t17600227-18-victim152" type="victimName">
                     Charles 
                     Day 
                  <interp inst="t17600227-18-victim152" type="surname" value="Day"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-18-victim152" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-18-victim152" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600227-18-off79 t17600227-18-victim152"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17600227-18-cd80" type="crimeDate">Jan. 26</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600227-18-off79 t17600227-18-cd80"></join>. *</p>
               <p>Ann Day. My husband's name is Charles. We <rs id="t17600227-18-viclabel81" type="occupation">keep a publick house</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600227-18-victim152 t17600227-18-viclabel81"></join>. called <placeName id="t17600227-18-crimeloc82">the Crown and Sieve, in Clare market</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17600227-18-crimeloc82" type="placeName" value="the Crown and Sieve, in Clare market"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17600227-18-crimeloc82" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600227-18-off79 t17600227-18-crimeloc82"></join>. Mr. Masckall, a bricklayer, pays his men at our house every Saturday night. I had told him out thirty-six shillings, and then he wanted silver for a guinea more. He laid down his guinea on the bar, and walked towards the fire. I said to him, this is a very plain guinea; his answer was, it is a very good one My husband then knock'd for me to come down stairs. Then Catherine Beard came in for half a guinea in silver, and I said I would change her none, because she had brought me no silver all the week. [She used to bring me silver for gold.] Then she said, if you will give me silver for this half guinea, you shall have all the silver I take next week, so I said I would change it. She took the guinea that Mr. Masckall had laid upon the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her take it?</p>
               <p>A. Day. I did, and saw her put it to her bosom. I said, don't play the fool, you have got the guinea, give it me. She said, Geago.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she mean by that?</p>
               <p>A. Day. I don't know the meaning of the word. Then she walked towards the fire-place, and I insisted on searching her for the guinea. She would not be searched, but hit me on the breast, and I let her go. She got to the door, and broke the pully of it to get away. After she was gone we fetch'd a warrant for her. She staid away for about half an hour, when she came in again, and desired we would search her.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>A. Day. This was on Saturday the 26th of January, about eight at night.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Did not you ask Mr. Masckall for the guinea?</p>
               <p>A. Day. No, I did not</p>
               <p>Ann Pool. I was sitting by the fire in Mrs. Day's house, when the prisoner at the bar came in, and asked Mrs. Day for half a guinea in silver. I turn'd my head round, and saw her hand on the bar. The prisoner ran to the fire, and said Geago. After that she broke the pully of the door, and away she went. I might say Geago too.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the meaning of that word?</p>
               <p>A. Pool. I don't know.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600227-18-person153">
                  Sarah 
                  Higinbottom 
               <interp inst="t17600227-18-person153" type="surname" value="Higinbottom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-18-person153" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-18-person153" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went into Mrs. Day's house for a pennyworth of beer. Mr. Masckall laid down a guinea on the bar, and Mrs. Day said it was a plain one. After that, Mrs. Day said, Mrs. Beard, you have got my guinea. Mrs Beard ran out at the door and broke the pully of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600227-18-person154">
                  Nicholas 
                  Masckall 
               <interp inst="t17600227-18-person154" type="surname" value="Masckall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-18-person154" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-18-person154" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a bricklayer. About eight at night on the 26th of January, I was paying my father's men, and wanting a guinea in silver, I went to the bar, and laid down a guinea. Mrs. Day looked at in and said it was a very plain one. I said it was a very good one, and went to the fireside. The prisoner came in for half a guinea worth of silver, and Mrs. Day said she would not or could not give her any. Presently Mrs. Day said to her, you have got my guinea, and insisted on her being searched, but she ran to the door, broke the pully, and went out.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her take the guinea?</p>
               <p>Masckall. No, I did not. After we were gone to the justice's, I was told she came in again, and wanted to be searched.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner Whether Mrs. Day did not go to you and say, Mr Masckall, where is my guinea, when you said you gave it her, and said you did not?</p>
               <p>Masckall. She might say I did not give it her, but I can't recollect it; if she did, I know she owned that I gave it her.</p>
               <p>Mr. Shipley. I am a constable. When prisoner in charge, I heard her offer to pay half a guinea down, and 18 d. a week till the remainder of the money was paid.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I never saw the guinea, Mrs. Day charged Mr. Masckall with having it, and I never offered to give her half a guinea, or any money at all.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600227-18-person155">
                  George 
                  Foster 
               <interp inst="t17600227-18-person155" type="surname" value="Foster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-18-person155" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-18-person155" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On a Saturday we were ordered to be paid at Mr. Day's house.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Foster. I have work'd for Mr. Masckall five years. We sat down, and drank beer and hot. My master came in about a quarter of an hour after us, and asked for change for a guinea, but whether he carried any money or not to Mrs. Day, I know not; I suppose it was for change to pay us, there being four or five of us to be paid. My master then turned his back to the bar. Mrs. Day<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176002270011"></xptr> went to call her husband, as I suppose; but the case was this, she went back again into the bar, and said she missed a guinea, and said, Mr. Masckall, you have not given me the guinea. Yes, said he, I did. Another man said he saw Mrs. Day take it up. Then she said, d - n her blood, he never gave her the guinea, search me; it was not found. Then she went directly, and said this old woman (which was the prisoner) had got the guinea. Said the prisoner, I know nothing of it, I wish you would give me change for half a guinea, for I have a customer at my stall. The prisoner went and sat down by the fire for the space of four or five minutes. After that Mrs. Day swore, G - d d - n you, you have got my guinea, and I will swear you took it up; that is all I have to say.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600227-18-person156">
                  James 
                  Rolfe 
               <interp inst="t17600227-18-person156" type="surname" value="Rolfe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-18-person156" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-18-person156" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I work for Mr. Masckall, and we went there to be paid. There being words about a guinea, I said to my master, I wish you would pay us as soon as you can. As I was going away the prisoner came in, and said she wanted change for half a guinea. Mrs. Day said, you brought me no silver last week. Then the prisoner said she would bring her all the silver she could the next week. Then Mrs. Day said, Mr. Masckall, you did not give me the guinea. I did, said he. You did not, and I'll swear it, said she. Then she turn'd herself round, and said to this woman at the bar, you have taken the guinea, if you have don't fright me; the prisoner said I have not I declare.</p>
               <p>- Randall. I saw the prisoner come into the house in the first place, and ask for change for half a guinea. The other said she would not let her have any, went from out of the bar to the stairs, which are facing the bar, turned back again, and said she missed a guinea, which is all that I have got to say.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600227-18-verdict83" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600227-18-verdict83" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
