<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610625-15">
               <interp inst="t17610625-15" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-15" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-15" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610625"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-15" type="date" value="17610625"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610625-15-off81-c100" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-15-defend123 t17610625-15-off81 t17610625-15-verdict87"></join>
         
               <p>192. (L) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610625-15-defend123" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     de Beaupain 
                  <interp inst="t17610625-15-defend123" type="surname" value="de Beaupain"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-15-defend123" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-15-defend123" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17610625-15-deflabel80" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-15-defend123 t17610625-15-deflabel80"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17610625-15-off81" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610625-15-off81" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-15-off81" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one silver shoe-buckle, value 5 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17610625-15-victim125" type="victimName">
                     Sarah 
                     Lamb 
                  <interp inst="t17610625-15-victim125" type="surname" value="Lamb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-15-victim125" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-15-victim125" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-15-off81 t17610625-15-victim125"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17610625-15-viclabel82" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-15-victim125 t17610625-15-viclabel82"></join>, <rs id="t17610625-15-cd83" type="crimeDate">June 20</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-15-off81 t17610625-15-cd83"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-15-person126">
                  Sarah 
                  Lamb 
               <interp inst="t17610625-15-person126" type="surname" value="Lamb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-15-person126" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-15-person126" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17610625-15-crimeloc84">Crutched-Friars</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17610625-15-crimeloc84" type="placeName" value="Crutched-Friars"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610625-15-crimeloc84" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-15-off81 t17610625-15-crimeloc84"></join>, <rs id="t17610625-15-viclabel85" type="occupation">I keep a day-school</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-15-victim125 t17610625-15-viclabel85"></join>, the prisoner lived 14 months as <rs id="t17610625-15-deflabel86" type="occupation">a French teacher</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-15-defend123 t17610625-15-deflabel86"></join> with me. I have lost abundance of things since she has been with me, but the buckle is the only thing that I choose to swear to, (she produced a pair of silver shoe-buckles, one of<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176106250012"></xptr> them had a string tied on it to distinguish it) this with the string upon it, I found in the prisoner's bureau; they are fellows, my property. She said, when she came, it would cost her 4 l. a year for a room to put her goods in; so I gave her leave to bring her goods to a room in my house. She had taken a man up to remove her goods unknown to me. I intreated her to have the bureau opened, and she refused it for about a quarter of an hour. Then I sent for a gentleman in the neighbourhood, who told her she must open it; she would not. After that I sent for a constable, she then refused opening it, she took her hat and went away, and said, she would go and fetch some gentlemen to vouch for her honesty. I never saw her that day after, till about 10 o'clock, then she returned and humbled herself.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you gave her warning, or was she going away of her own accord?</p>
               <p>S. Lamb. I gave her warning two months ago; she used to want to go out every week or ten days, and we missing so many things in the family, almost every week; she was very much altered, and very irregular.</p>
               <p>Q. How came her bureau opened at last?</p>
               <p>S. Lamb. I went to my lord mayor, and got a special warrant, but I did not open it till she was by, she being gone out the next day, she returned, and desired I would let her take the things away. She said, she did not understand the English laws, but she would open it. She opened it, we found a number of things in it, I think must be my property. She offered to give me any satisfaction, if I would not expose her; and this buckle, which I am confident is mine, was found in it.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>S. Lamb. She is a clergyman's widow.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember when you lost this buckle?</p>
               <p>S. Lamb. It was about three months ago, I cannot tell the day of the month.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know where you lost it?</p>
               <p>S. Lamb. I lost it in my own house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not lose it when you was out a visiting.</p>
               <p>S. Lamb. No, I did not; I made some inquiry one night, and talked whether I did not drop it in the court or not, but I never believed I lost it out of my own house.</p>
               <p>Q. Where had you been that night?</p>
               <p>S. Lamb. I had been to visit a neighbour. The next morning I went to put my shoes on as usual, and then I missed my buckle out of my shoe. The maid look'd for it under my bed; it was known in the family that it was lost at that time.</p>

               <p>Q. Did the prisoner know you had lost it?</p>
               <p>S. Lamb. She did, and talk'd of it many times, and said she was very sorry for the loss of my buckle.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the locks easily opened?</p>
               <p>S. Lamb. They were, all but one drawer.</p>
               <p>Q. Who opened that?</p>
               <p>S. Lamb. That she opened herself, I never touched her keys; she made a great hampering at one lock.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was it from your missing the buckle, to the opening of the bureau?</p>
               <p>S. Lamb. It was about a quarter of a year</p>
               <p>Q. Was any body, by when the buckle was found?</p>
               <p>S. Lamb. My daughter was.</p>

               <p>Q. Was the buckle found in the drawer that was difficult to open?</p>
               <p>S. Lamb. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it possible for any other person to put the buckle into her bureau?</p>

               <p>S. Lamb, No; or at least I should think it not probable.</p>
               <p>Q. Who took the buckle out of the drawer?</p>
               <p>S. Lamb. My daughter did.</p>
               <p>Q. Have there been any mistakes in your house?</p>
               <p>S. Lamb. Yes, a great many, where two or three dozen of things have been lost; there were found a cambrick handkerchief, ear-rings. starch, thread, candles, and other things.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you once charge her with a crown piece?</p>
               <p>S. Lamb. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray had the room where the bureau stood a lock upon the door?</p>
               <p>S. Lamb. No; there was a lock upon the door, but the key had been insensibly lost, and then I had a carpenter to nail up the door, to prevent her or any body else from slipping up.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you know the buckle by?</p>
               <p>S. Lamb. I know it by its matching with the other.</p>
               <p>Q. When was that blue string tied upon it?</p>
               <p>S. Lamb. I tied that upon it when before the grand jury, when the bill was found.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you keep it before?</p>
               <p>S. Lamb. I had it before in a paper by itself; my daughter and my servant knew it at first sight to be my buckle.</p>
               <p>Q. Is there any mark upon it?</p>
               <p>S. Lamb. There is the silversmith's mark upon it.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176106250013"></xptr>Mr. Gurling. Mrs. Lamb is a neighbour of mine: a night or two nights before she sent to me about putting an advertisement in the paper, about a silver mug she had lost.</p>
               <p>Court. Apply yourself to the present indictment.</p>
               <p>Gurling. Last Friday morning she sent for me; when I came, there were several bundles tied up. Mrs Lamb said, my tutor is going away unknown to me, and as I have lost a silver mug, I think I have a right to search her box. When we came to the bureau, she would not let us look into it, on no account; I reasoned with her; she said no, she would not open it. The constable was then sent for, she said the same before him, she would not suffer it to be opened. In about half an hour she went down stairs, and went out. It was opened the next day, but I was not there till after the opening, then I was told the buckle was found.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-15-person127">
                  Mary 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17610625-15-person127" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-15-person127" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-15-person127" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mrs. Lamb, in French Ordinary court, Crutched-Friars; I was at the opening of the prisoner's bureau.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>M. Johnson. I do not know the day of the month.</p>
               <p>Q. What day of the week?</p>
               <p>M. Johnson. It was last Saturday My mistress desired the prisoner to open the bureau, and she refused it several times.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see it opened?</p>
               <p>M. Johnson. I did; she opened every drawer but one, and that she agreed to let a carpenter open, and he opened it immediately.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any buckle?</p>
               <p>M. Johnson. Yes, I saw the buckle taken out, which I knew to be my mistress's property; my mistress lost it about nine or ten weeks ago: as soon as I saw it, I went and fetched the other, that was the fellow to it, out of a china bowl. I sincerely believe it to be my mistress's property.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it talked on in the family, as being lost before you found it?</p>
               <p>M. Johnson. It was a great deal; it was the morning it was missing, it was universally known in the family to be lost.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say upon its being taken out of her bureau?</p>
               <p>M. Johnson. I think she said it was her own buckle.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she attempt to match it?</p>
               <p>M. Johnson. No, she did not.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the drawer locked where the buckle was?</p>
               <p>M. Johnson. There was a key to it, it was found in a little drawer.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner give full consent to deliver it, to have the drawer opened?</p>
               <p>M. Johnson. She did.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of any mark upon the buckle?</p>
               <p>M. Johnson. No, I did not; but I know it to be the same as the other, and have the greatest reason in the world to believe, from circumstances, that she had several things there that were not her own property.</p>
               <p>Q. Who unlocked that drawer to take the buckle out?</p>
               <p>M. Johnson. Miss Lamb did.</p>
               <p>Q. Who kept the key to the prisoner's room door?</p>
               <p>M. Johnson. She never had a key while I lived there.</p>
               <p>Miss Lamb. I opened the inward drawer of the escrutore, and took the buckle out of it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610625-15-verdict87" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610625-15-verdict87" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
