<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17620421-4">
               <interp inst="t17620421-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620421-4" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620421-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17620421"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620421-4" type="date" value="17620421"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620421-4-off16-c51" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-4-defend57 t17620421-4-off16 t17620421-4-verdict20"></join>
         
               <p>119. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17620421-4-defend57" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Clark 
                  <interp inst="t17620421-4-defend57" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-defend57" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-defend57" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17620421-4-off16" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-off16" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-off16" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               committing a rape on the body of 
                     <persName id="t17620421-4-person58">
                        Sarah
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person58" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620421-4-person58" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   the <rs id="t17620421-4-viclabel17" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-4-victim60 t17620421-4-viclabel17"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17620421-4-person59">
                        Charles 
                        Denman 
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person59" type="surname" value="Denman"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620421-4-person59" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620421-4-person59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17620421-4-cd18" type="crimeDate">February 20</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-4-off16 t17620421-4-cd18"></join>.*</p> 
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-4-victim60" type="victimName">
                  Sarah 
                  Denman 
               <interp inst="t17620421-4-victim60" type="surname" value="Denman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-victim60" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-victim60" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-4-off16 t17620421-4-victim60"></join>
                  </persName>
             . On the 20th of February last, near 11 at night, the prisoner came to me in my room, and asked for pots (he <rs id="t17620421-4-deflabel19" type="occupation">keeps an alehouse</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-4-defend57 t17620421-4-deflabel19"></join>, and served us with beer); he asked me if my husband was come home? I said, I did not expect him till the next day or day after. He said, he had something particular to say to me; he shut the door, and came and tore me about in the kitchen from one place to another; he forced me upon a chair by clapping his knee upon my belly; he confined both my hands behind me, and then got his ends of me; that is, he was concerned with me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that by force?</p>
               <p>Denman. It was.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you a married woman?</p>
               <p>Denman. I am, and have had four children.</p>
               <p>Council. You must be more particular?</p>
               <p>Denman. He had carnal knowledge of my body to all intents and purposes. I come here to say nothing but the truth.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you resist him?</p>
               <p>Denman. I did all in my power to resist him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you cry out?</p>
               <p>Denman. He did all in his power to keep his mouth over mine, and endeavoured to prevent my speaking or crying out.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he stay after this?</p>
               <p>Denman. He staid but a very little while after; I believe not three minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any application made to you afterwards?</p>
               <p>Denman. No.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you say to him?</p>
               <p>Denman. I told him I would acquaint my husband with it as soon as came home; which I did. Mr. Clark sent three gentlemen, and after that two gentlemen to me: they asked me, if I would make this affair up?</p>
               <p>Q. Who were they?</p>
               <p>Denman. I know the last two, one was Mr. Gofton in Rosemary-lane, the other Doctor 
               <persName id="t17620421-4-person61">
                  Bare
               <interp inst="t17620421-4-person61" type="given" value="Bare"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person61" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in Nightingale lane.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know the prisoner sent them?</p>
               <p>Denman. They told me they came from Mr. Clark.</p>
               <p>Q. Did th e prisoner himself make application to you?</p>
               <p>Denman. I never spoke to him since. I have seen him at a distance.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any body with you when the two men came to you?</p>
               <p>Denman. Two women were in the house at the time, 
               <persName id="t17620421-4-person62">
                  Elizabeth 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17620421-4-person62" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person62" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person62" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Isabella Bowling.</p>
               <p>On her cross examination she said, she had known the prisoner 19 years - she cried out as loud as possible for help a great many times - that she told her husband on the Tuesday following - that Mr. Plunket the attorney came to her house on the Wednesday, and she told him of it, and on the Thursday made affidavit of it - that she went to Hicks's Hall, and found a bill of indictment against the prisoner on the Thursday - that she never did apply to the prisoner, or any other person, to propose if a hundred pounds were paid there should be no prosecution - that she never consented to take any sum of money in order to stop the prosecution - that the court she lives in is no thoroughfare - that the prisoner keeps an alehouse in Norris's-court.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-4-person63">
                  Thomas 
                  Baldwin 
               <interp inst="t17620421-4-person63" type="surname" value="Baldwin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person63" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person63" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I made application on the prisoner's account to 
               <persName id="t17620421-4-person64">
                  Sarah 
                  Denman 
               <interp inst="t17620421-4-person64" type="surname" value="Denman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person64" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person64" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Clark send you?</p>
               <p>Baldwin. I had no discourse with him about it; but his brother and one Mr. Baker came to my house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did his brother live with him?</p>
               <p>Baldwin. I do not know that he did.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176204210005"></xptr>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I am intirely innocent of the charge against me. I believe it is done with intent to extort money from me. I was at the house backwards and forwards about my business, but no otherwise.</p>
               <p>Q. to S. Denman. Explain the situation of the chair on which you say the fact was done?</p>
               <p>Denman. There were two or three chairs standing together. I was hardly in the chair; I was partly in it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you upon the ground?</p>
               <p>Denman. No, I was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it an elbow or a common chair?</p>
               <p>Denman. A common chair.</p>
               <p>Q. Does your husband owe the prisoner any money?</p>
               <p>Denman. He does, a trifle of money.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-4-person65">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Waite 
               <interp inst="t17620421-4-person65" type="surname" value="Waite"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person65" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person65" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live next door to the prosecutrix; they are wainscot houses; we can very well hear common conversation in her house as we sit in our own, partly any thing they say. My mother was with me this same night. I remember it by my child being christened the next day; if there had been the least crying out in the world we must have heard it; we heard none at all.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-4-person66">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Macone 
               <interp inst="t17620421-4-person66" type="surname" value="Macone"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person66" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person66" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             her mother deposed to the same purport.</p>
               <p>Sarah Hall, her nurse, deposed she was absent that night, and the mother supplied her place, and that it was easy to hear common talk or walking about in the prosecutrix's room, when in the house of Waite.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-4-person67">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Chambers 
               <interp inst="t17620421-4-person67" type="surname" value="Chambers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person67" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person67" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, she lived at the next door to the prosecutrix, up one pair of stairs; that she was at home that night, but heard nothing of the crying out, which might easily be heard had it been so; and that the prisoner was a married man, and lived well with his wife; and is a very honest industrious man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-4-person68">
                  Martha 
                  Powell 
               <interp inst="t17620421-4-person68" type="surname" value="Powell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person68" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person68" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, she lived next door to the prosecutrix, that she was at home, and if there had been any calling out she must have heard it; but she heard none: that the prosecutrix told her the prisoner had used her very ill; he had put his hand up her body: that she asked her, if she did not cry out? and the prosecutrix answered, she did not cry out at all: She was asked, if the prosecutrix did not tell her he had ravished her? she answered, no; and that no man can force a woman without she be willing: that she had seen him kiss and play with her, but no farther.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-4-person69">
                  Ann 
                  Howell 
               <interp inst="t17620421-4-person69" type="surname" value="Howell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person69" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person69" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, she lived in Norris's-court within four doors of the prisoner; that a plate cannot be taken out of the cupboard, but it is heard from one house to another; and that if the prosecutrix had called out, she must have heard her in her house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-4-person70">
                  Susanna 
                  Titcome 
               <interp inst="t17620421-4-person70" type="surname" value="Titcome"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person70" type="given" value="Susanna"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person70" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, she lived within one door of being opposite to the prosecutrix; that if she had called out she must have heard her, but she heard no such thing that night.</p>
               <p>Jos. Bare. I am an apothecary and surgeon; upon hearing this charge, I went to the prosecutrix on the 19th of March. I asked her, how this affair stood between her and Mr. Clark? She said; there was to have been a meeting at Mr. Hill the officer's to make it up. I said, is the meeting to be by your consent? She said, yes. I said, I heard Mr. Plunket had said, if Mr. Clark would pay forty pounds, you would stop all prosecution; is that true? She said, yes. Mr. Gofton went with me. He said, who is it to be paid to, to Mr. Plunket your attorney? She said, no, it must be paid to me. Mr. Gofton said, suppose Mr. Clark was to pay that money to you, will you prosecute him hereafter? No, said she, it shall be all void for ever; then she called down a woman: the woman said, do not make it up without your husband.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Bare. I live in Nightingale-lane, East Smithfield.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner send for you?</p>
               <p>Bare. No, I went as a neighbour; nobedy had desired me to go; and asked this out of my own head. I believe him to be as innocent as a newborn babe.</p>
               <p>Jos. Gofton. I went with Mr. Bare to the prosecutrix.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to go?</p>
               <p>Gofton. He gave me a beckon to go, and said Mrs. Clark had said to me, if it lay in his way to get somebody to go along with me to see if it was by her consent that she was to make it up for forty pounds: she desired me to see if she had given her attorney power so to do.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you mention this to Bare?</p>
               <p>Gofton. I did going along, and got him to go with me. Mr. Bare asked her at going in, how she did? She said, pretty well. Said he, how does this affair stand between you and Clark? Said she, I do not know, there was to have been a meeting at Mr. Hill's in Rosemary-lane. Said I, was it by your consent? She said, yes. I asked her, if Mr. Plunket was her attorney? She said, yes. I said, he has made a demand of forty pounds, was it by your consent? She said, it was; and if he had made any other proposal since, she would not stand to it. I said, is it to be paid to you or your attorney? She said, to her, for he had had money enough. I said, if it be paid you, you do not mean to prosecute Mr. Clark? She said, no; then there will be an end<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176204210006"></xptr> of the whole affair. Then a woman called down stairs, and said, do not do any thing without the consent of your husband. Then we went away. Mr. Plunket had spoke to me about it, and when I talked to Mr. Clark, he said he was innocent, and would not give her a farthing.</p>
               <p>Mr. Rogers. I was drinking at Mr. Clark's on the 7th of March. Mr. Bare said he was going to the prosecutrix, and asked me to go with him. I went; he joked about the matter; he asked her if it could not be made up? She said, she did not care to hurt a hair of his head. I said, it is a sad thing a man should be kept from his family so. She replied, he should not be out of his family many days.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she mention any terms upon which she would make it up?</p>
               <p>Rogers. No; she did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say what the prisoner had been guilty of?</p>
               <p>Rogers. No.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-4-person71">
                  John 
                  Booth 
               <interp inst="t17620421-4-person71" type="surname" value="Booth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person71" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person71" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the prisoner's house on the 20th of February, with five or six of my shopmates. I went about ten, and staid till 12 at night. He was about as usual. I did not miss him at all. He is a man of a very good character, as far as ever I heard.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-4-person72">
                  Wm 
                  Stapleton 
               <interp inst="t17620421-4-person72" type="surname" value="Stapleton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person72" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person72" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I was at the prisoner's house on the 20th of February; it was a pay night. I came about 20 minutes after 10, and staid till about five minutes after 11. I saw him backwards and forwards very busy with his customers.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he seem in any confusion, as if he had been struggling with any body?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-4-person73">
                  Wm 
                  Stapleton 
               <interp inst="t17620421-4-person73" type="surname" value="Stapleton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person73" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person73" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . No, he did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-4-person74">
                  William 
                  Allen 
               <interp inst="t17620421-4-person74" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person74" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person74" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who had known the prisoner 20 years; 
               <persName id="t17620421-4-person75">
                  Joseph 
                  Stoaks 
               <interp inst="t17620421-4-person75" type="surname" value="Stoaks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person75" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person75" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 14; Mr. Lakehorn, who had his son in-law apprentice, and had known him many years; Mr. Anderson, 11; 
               <persName id="t17620421-4-person76">
                  William 
                  Warren 
               <interp inst="t17620421-4-person76" type="surname" value="Warren"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person76" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person76" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 20; and 
               <persName id="t17620421-4-person77">
                  Martin 
                  Long 
               <interp inst="t17620421-4-person77" type="surname" value="Long"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person77" type="given" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-person77" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             about six years; all gave him the character of an honest, industrious, well-behaved man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17620421-4-verdict20" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620421-4-verdict20" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
