<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17631207-36">
               <interp inst="t17631207-36" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-36" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-36" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17631207"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-36" type="date" value="17631207"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17631207-36-off197-c267" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-36-defend341 t17631207-36-off197 t17631207-36-verdict200"></join>
         
               <p>40. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17631207-36-defend341" type="defendantName">
                  
                     William 
                     Hanlow 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17631207-36-alias-4" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-36-defend341 t17631207-36-alias-4"></join>Handle</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-36-defend341" type="surname" value="Hanlow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-36-defend341" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-36-defend341" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17631207-36-off197" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631207-36-off197" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-36-off197" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one thickset coat, value 30 s. one cloth waistcoat, value 15 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17631207-36-victim344" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Soaper 
                        <interp inst="t17631207-36-victim344" type="surname" value="Soaper"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17631207-36-victim344" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17631207-36-victim344" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-36-off197 t17631207-36-victim344"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling-house of 
                     <persName id="t17631207-36-person345">
                        Burton 
                        Cadwalider 
                     <interp inst="t17631207-36-person345" type="surname" value="Cadwalider"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17631207-36-person345" type="given" value="Burton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17631207-36-person345" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17631207-36-cd198" type="crimeDate">Nov. 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-36-off197 t17631207-36-cd198"></join>. *</p>
               <p>William Soaper. I live at Welton, near Darkin, in Kent; I lodged four nights in the house of 
               <persName id="t17631207-36-person346">
                  Burton 
                  Cadwalider 
               <interp inst="t17631207-36-person346" type="surname" value="Cadwalider"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-36-person346" type="given" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-36-person346" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in <placeName id="t17631207-36-crimeloc199">Carey-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17631207-36-crimeloc199" type="placeName" value="Carey-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17631207-36-crimeloc199" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-36-off197 t17631207-36-crimeloc199"></join>, three weeks ago yesterday; I had the things in a bundle mentioned in the indictment; I laid them down on the table, about three o'clock in the day, in Mr. Cadwalider's house, while I went to pay for my lodging, and when I returned again to my bundle, in about five or six minutes time, my bundle was gone.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any body in that room at the time?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176312070032"></xptr>Soaper. There was the prisoner and two or three more men there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Soaper. I never saw him before, to my knowledge. When I missed the things, I enquired of the people of the house; the prisoner was then in the room: Somebody said he had the things: I went and took him by the collar, and shook him, and said, You dog, you have got my bundle; he stooped down, and dropped the bundle down behind him: he got out at the door, and ran away, while I was stooping for it; I pursued him, and took him, in about 30 or 40 yards running; as he ran he drew his knife, and opened it, carrying it with the point behind him; but he did not strike me with it; he had a companion there with him; he ran away also.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-36-person347">
                  John 
                  Field 
               <interp inst="t17631207-36-person347" type="surname" value="Field"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-36-person347" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-36-person347" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mr. Cole, at Hampstead. On the 17th of Nov. I went into that house, to see for my master. I heard the prosecutor enquire for a bundle as we were in the tap-room by the bar; there was the prisoner and one Buckeridge; the prosecutor was a little in liquor: I saw the prisoner had the bundle behind him, under his great coat, the coat stood out; I said, I believed that man has got it, pointing to the prisoner. I went behind him; there was then nothing lying on the ground. The prisoner said, I got it, I have not got it, and made a sort of hobble in his speech; he went back, and stooped down, and dropped it; after Soaper took him by the collar, the prisoner paid for a glass of rum or brandy, and went out at the door; and ran down Bell-yard.</p>
               <p>Q. How soon did he run away after the bundle was taken up?</p>
               <p>Field. It was in the space of a minute or two after; we followed him; he ran with a naked knife in his hand, with a picked point to it; he put it to his side and shut it, before we took him: a man came and took it out of his hand. The prisoner's companion got out of the house, and ran away as fast as he could; there was Mr. Buckridge there at the time: he is not here.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-36-person348">
                  John 
                  Rainbow 
               <interp inst="t17631207-36-person348" type="surname" value="Rainbow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-36-person348" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-36-person348" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 17th of last month, about half an hour after 4 o'clock, going up Bell-yard, I met the prisoner, and just after him, the prosecutor and Field. Seeing the prosecutor in liquor, finding he had been robb'd, I laid hold of the prisoner; the prosecutor said the prisoner had a knife in his hand; I took and turned up his hand, and took it from him; we took him to the publick-house, and from thence to Sir 
               <persName id="t17631207-36-person349">
                  John 
                  Fieldings 
               <interp inst="t17631207-36-person349" type="surname" value="Fieldings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-36-person349" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-36-person349" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            : I asked him what he did with that knife in his hand? he said he had it to cut his nails.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I met these men, in the street, both drunk. I was looking at a stranger in the street, then I went into a house and got a glass of rum at the bar; the man came out crying and swearing, and asked for his bundle; there were four or five people in the room; he looked at me, and Field said he saw me drop the bundle. I had a bit of cheese; I took it out, and was eating it, with my knife in my hand; I went out at the door and walked very softly; he came up to me as I was just shuting my knife: they took hold of me, and had me before the justice.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17631207-36-verdict200" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631207-36-verdict200" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-36-verdict200" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder40s"></interp>
               Guilty. 39 s.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17631207-36-punish201" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631207-36-punish201" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-36-defend341 t17631207-36-punish201"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
