<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660219-35">
               <interp inst="t17660219-35" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660219-35" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660219-35" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660219"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660219-35" type="date" value="17660219"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660219-35-off196-c301" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-35-defend387 t17660219-35-off196 t17660219-35-verdict199"></join>
         
               <p>156. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17660219-35-defend387" type="defendantName">
                  
                     William 
                     Wyatt 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17660219-35-alias-5" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-35-defend387 t17660219-35-alias-5"></join>Wyett</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-35-defend387" type="surname" value="Wyatt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-35-defend387" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-35-defend387" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted, for that <rs id="t17660219-35-off196" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660219-35-off196" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-35-off196" type="offenceSubcategory" value="housebreaking"></interp>
               he, on the <rs id="t17660219-35-cd197" type="crimeDate">28th of November</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-35-off196 t17660219-35-cd197"></join>, in the day time, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17660219-35-victim390" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Foster 
                        <interp inst="t17660219-35-victim390" type="surname" value="Foster"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660219-35-victim390" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660219-35-victim390" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-35-off196 t17660219-35-victim390"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , did break and enter, no person being therein, and stealing one silver table spoon, value 8 s. four silver tea spoons, value 8 s. a pair of silver shoe buckles, a silver stock buckle, four gold rings, a diamond ring set in gold, an iron pencil case, a 3 l. 12 s. piece, and 23 guineas
            </rs>, the property of the said 
               <persName id="t17660219-35-person391">
                  William 
                  Foster 
               <interp inst="t17660219-35-person391" type="surname" value="Foster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-35-person391" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-35-person391" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660219-35-person392">
                  William 
                  Foster 
               <interp inst="t17660219-35-person392" type="surname" value="Foster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-35-person392" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-35-person392" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at <placeName id="t17660219-35-crimeloc198">Hayes</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17660219-35-crimeloc198" type="placeName" value="Hayes"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660219-35-crimeloc198" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-35-off196 t17660219-35-crimeloc198"></join>. The prisoner lives at Southall, about 3 miles distant from me. I left my house about 6 in the morning on the 28th of November, and my wife in it. She came to me about half an hour after 6 to my master's, where I work. I returned home about 8. I unlocked my door, and went in and found my back door a little way open. I went out and found my back window broke open, which we left key'd with an iron key in the inside: then I went and found my chamber door open; the lock was broke, and my chest of drawers broke open. I missed 30 l. in money. There was a 3 l. 12 s. 23 guineas, and the rest in half crowns, money I had been saving all my life time almost; it was in a purse, wrapped up in a rag: the rag was found in the room. I lost a pair of silver shoe buckles, a table spoon, and four tea spoons. The spoons and buckles were found buried in a common field about two shots length from the prisoner's house, but a little way in the ground. I lost a steel pencil case, which I had cleaned a little before with brick dust and leather, which was found in the prisoner's drawers with brick dust in it (produced in court). I can swear this is my property; it was in my chest among my other things.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Foster. He works upon the road. I never found any thing else. The prisoner denied it, when charged with doing it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660219-35-person393">
                  Robert 
                  Hare 
               <interp inst="t17660219-35-person393" type="surname" value="Hare"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-35-person393" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-35-person393" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Brentford with Mr. Drinkwater, a grocer. The prisoner came into our shop the 5th of January for two pounds of sugar, and wanted change for a 36 s. piece: I gave him change for a 36 s. piece: he took it and went away. I took the piece up when he was gone, and found it to be a 3 l. 12 s. I had other customers to serve. When I had done with them I went to look for the prisoner, but he was gone. I informed Mr. Drinkwater of it: he bid me let him know when the person came again. The prisoner came the Thursday following for a quarter of a pound of tea for a man in the neighbourhood. Saying I knew what tea that man always had, I weighed a quarter of a pound: the prisoner threw down half a crown, the price of it: he took the tea, and went out of the shop; then I went and told Mr. Drinkwater, and he had him called back. What questions he asked him, he will tell the court.</p>
               <p>Mr. Drinkwater. When the prisoner came the second time, I had him called back, and asked him whether he had not been at my shop before; he said he could not tell whether he was or not. I said there was a parcel left at my house, and I thought it was his; then he said he was at my house, and had two pounds of sugar, and change for a 36 s. piece: I told him that was a bad 36 s. piece; he appeared a good deal confused, and said, the next time he came he would change it. I asked him where he took it, he told me he knew very well, but I could not get out of him the person's name: after that he told me he went to a linen draper's shop in London to buy his wife a gown, and a man came in and asked the gentleman of the shop to change a 36 s. piece: the gentleman said he could not, and that he said he had so much money in his pocket, and he gave him a guinea, and the rest in silver, and took the piece. When he had taken it, he went out; I sent after him to let him know I would shew him the very piece: he sent word he would return immediately; he turned round. Seeing the boy watching him, he turned back and went to Mr. Cook's. In the afternoon, about 4 or 5, he came to my house; this, I believe, was on the 10th of January, he had then changed his dress: I then shewed him the 3 l. 12 s. and said, I should not deliver it to him till my apprentice was there, to assure me as well as my man, that he was the very person that brought it. Upon this he said, he was very much obliged to me, and went about his business: he came again, then my boy was in the shop; he assured me he was the person, then I delivered it to him, and he gave me 36 s. then I told him my reason for asking him these questions<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176602190023"></xptr> was to be sure that he was the right person that brought it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660219-35-person394">
                  John 
                  Noaks 
               <interp inst="t17660219-35-person394" type="surname" value="Noaks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-35-person394" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-35-person394" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the prisoner before Sir 
               <persName id="t17660219-35-person395">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17660219-35-person395" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-35-person395" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-35-person395" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he was charged with this offence, he said the money was his own; on the last examination he said he had found ten pounds in a garret in a rag.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say what garret?</p>
               <p>Noaks. No, he did not; coming up from Southall he said he got the money by hard labour.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660219-35-person396">
                  Thomas 
                  Clarke 
               <interp inst="t17660219-35-person396" type="surname" value="Clarke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-35-person396" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-35-person396" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When the prisoner was committed to the Gatehouse, I was ordered by Sir 
               <persName id="t17660219-35-person397">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17660219-35-person397" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-35-person397" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-35-person397" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             that no person should have any conversation with him in private; two days afterwards I found out this letter by a Stratagem (producing one) it was carried before Sir John, and read out to the prisoner, there he acknowledged he did dictate it, and it was wrote by his direction. by one Cavenaugh.</p>
               <p>It was read to this purport, directed to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17660219-35-person398">
                  Robert 
                  Croft 
               <interp inst="t17660219-35-person398" type="surname" value="Croft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-35-person398" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-35-person398" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Silver-street, Golden-Square.</p>
               <p>'Send word to my wife that they are going to</p>
               <p>'take her up, and she must swear we have been</p>
               <p>'married these 6 years, if any one ask you about</p>
               <p>'the watch ~, tell them I had it these four years</p>
               <p>'and upwards; bring all the friends you can;</p>
               <p>'don't be afraid you are my wife, for if you</p>
               <p>'don't it is all over with me. I desire you not</p>
               <p>'to let any one know I wrote to you.'</p>
               <p>~ Mr. Julian, a watchmaker, was in court, and gave an account of a watch the prisoner bought lately of his father, who was ill and could not attend, but not being by at the time, it was only hearsay, and not evidence.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660219-35-verdict199" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660219-35-verdict199" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I took the 36 s. piece in Russell-Court.</p>
            </div1>
