<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17621208-11">
               <interp inst="t17621208-11" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17621208-11" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17621208-11" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17621208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17621208-11" type="date" value="17621208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17621208-11-off69-c133" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-11-defend153 t17621208-11-off69 t17621208-11-verdict72"></join>
         
               <p>11. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17621208-11-defend153" type="defendantName">
                  Sarah, <rs id="t17621208-11-deflabel68" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-11-defend153 t17621208-11-deflabel68"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17621208-11-person154">
                        Gregory 
                        Meers 
                     <interp inst="t17621208-11-person154" type="surname" value="Meers"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17621208-11-person154" type="given" value="Gregory"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17621208-11-person154" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17621208-11-alias-5" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-11-defend153 t17621208-11-alias-5"></join>Sarah, wife of 
                        <persName id="t17621208-11-person155">
                           Gerrat 
                           Meers 
                        <interp inst="t17621208-11-person155" type="surname" value="Meers"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17621208-11-person155" type="given" value="Gerrat"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17621208-11-person155" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        </persName>
                     
                     </rs>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-11-defend153" type="surname" value="Meers Meers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-11-defend153" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-11-defend153" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17621208-11-off69" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17621208-11-off69" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-11-off69" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 5 silver tea-spoons, value 12 s. and one pair of silver tea-tongs, value 9 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17621208-11-victim157" type="victimName">
                     Robert 
                     Hanks 
                  <interp inst="t17621208-11-victim157" type="surname" value="Hanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-11-victim157" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-11-victim157" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-11-off69 t17621208-11-victim157"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17621208-11-cd70" type="crimeDate">Nov. 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-11-off69 t17621208-11-cd70"></join>. ~.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-11-person158">
                  Robert 
                  Hanks 
               <interp inst="t17621208-11-person158" type="surname" value="Hanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-11-person158" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-11-person158" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I live in <placeName id="t17621208-11-crimeloc71">Virginia-street, Numb. 24, Ratcliff-high-way</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17621208-11-crimeloc71" type="placeName" value="Virginia-street, Numb. 24, Ratcliff-high-way"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17621208-11-crimeloc71" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-11-off69 t17621208-11-crimeloc71"></join>; on Tuesday night, the last of November, my wife came on board to me, and went on shore again; after that she return'd to me again, and said our room door was broke open; I went home, we missed 5 silver tea spoons, a pair of tea tongs, a pair of silver paste buckles, and a blue silk gown; I got a search-warrant to search the prisoner's house; I lodge in her house; we began at the bottom and searched to the top, we found these 5 spoons and tongs in her garret, lock'd up in a deal box, the prisoner had the key of it; first she took a wrong key that would not open it, then she took out another key, then it opened easy; then she clap'd her hands together, and said, You'll swear my life away.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the garret door lock'd?</p>
               <p>Hanks. No, it was not, it was a lumber room.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say about the spoons before the justice?</p>
               <p>Hanks. She said somebody put them there.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you lived in this house?</p>
               <p>Hanks. Three months the 15th of last month.</p>
               <p>Q. Is not the prisoner a house-keeper that lives in credit and reputation?</p>
               <p>Hanks. She is a house-keeper, I don't know but she does in reputation.</p>
               <p>Q. Had there been any disputes between your wife and she?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176212080015"></xptr>Hanks. There were some disputes several times.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she not put your wife into Doctor's Commons for calling her whore?</p>
               <p>Hanks. I don't know. I know there was a letter come?</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath, did she not threaten your wife to put her in the Commons?</p>
               <p>Hanks. She did threaten my wife for abusing her. We never lived in peace and quietness since we have been in the house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never threaten to have the prisoner in goal before it was long?</p>
               <p>Hanks. No.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Hanks. I am mate of a ship.</p>
               <p>Q. In what part of the box did you find the spoons?</p>
               <p>Hanks. As high as I can remember, about the middle part of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe a mark set on the box, as if made with a chissel, or some instrument?</p>
               <p>Hanks. I do not know of any such thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Were those words you mention the prisoner said, said to your wife.</p>
               <p>Hanks. No; I suppose that was said to the young woman who lives with the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Had that young woman made any charge against her?</p>
               <p>Hanks. No; but as soon as she said it, the girl fell a crying, and she turn'd from the girl when she spoke.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you did not say to 
               <persName id="t17621208-11-person159">
                  Mary 
                  Isley 
               <interp inst="t17621208-11-person159" type="surname" value="Isley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-11-person159" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-11-person159" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             your chairwoman, that you would have the prisoner in a strong hold before the Monday.</p>
               <p>Hanks. No; I did not say any such thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-11-person160">
                  Jane 
                  Hanks 
               <interp inst="t17621208-11-person160" type="surname" value="Hanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-11-person160" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-11-person160" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lay on board with my husband, and returned home on the 31st of Dec. about seven in the morning. I went to put the key into my door, and the door came open. I had left it lock'd over night; I believe the lock had been pick'd with a nail, as one was found on the floor by the door; I examined, and found I had lost things, among them were five silver tea spoons, and a pair of tea tongs, I had seen them about a quarter of an hour before I went out; then I went on board the ship and told my husband; the prisoner was at home at the time I missed them, my husband came on shore, and went to the justice, and got a search warrant; there was no reason to suspect any body but she. We began the search first in the parlour. We went on and search'd all the rooms regularly. When we came to the garret, the constable found the spoons and tongs. At first she took a wrong key, and scrupled opening the box. The constable insisted on having the box open'd; upon these words she put her hand into her pocket and took out a single key, and open'd it directly. There lay the spoons and tongs.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know in what part of the box they lay.</p>
               <p>J. Hanks. I did not look into the box, but before the lid of the box was open, she turn'd about to the other side of the room, and said, you bitch, you'l swear my life away; the constable desired us to take notice of these words.</p>
               <p>Q. Had there been disputes between you and the prisoner?</p>
               <p>J. Hanks. No disputes, only words.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know she was to put you in the Commons.</p>
               <p>J. Hanks. I never heard she was, I never heard her say such a thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never hear your husband say, he had heard her say, she would put you in the Commons for words you had said?</p>
               <p>J. Hanks. No, I never did; I never heard any thing of that till since she was taken up.</p>
               <p>Q. What rooms had you in that house?</p>
               <p>J. Hanks. We had one room, up one pair of stairs, and a garret over head.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did capt. Burton lodge?</p>
               <p>J. Hanks. He lodg'd in a room equal to mine.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there a lock on the garret door, where the spoons were found?</p>
               <p>J. Hanks. I do not know whether there was or not; it always appear'd to be shut.</p>

               <p>Q. When you came home from on board where did you go?</p>
               <p>J. Hanks. I went into my own room where I lie.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that the only room you went into?</p>
               <p>J. Hanks. When I missed the spoons, I went into the garret.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go there to see for the spoons?</p>
               <p>J. Hanks. No; I was sure they were in the one pair of stairs room when I went out.</p>
               <p>Q. What was your business in the garret.</p>
               <p>J. Hanks. To know what else I had lost.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was you in the garret?</p>
               <p>J. Hanks. Not above 10 or 13 minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever been in the garret in which the spoons were found?</p>
               <p>J. Hanks. Never but once, then I had liberty to hang my cloaths there.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you lose there?</p>
               <p>J. Hanks. A pair of buckles set in silver, a blue silk gown, and a piece of cheque.</p>
               <p>Q. Were those words the prisoner spoke, spoke to you?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176212080016"></xptr>J. Hanks. I do not know who it was spoke to.</p>
               <p>Q. Were you not then upon ill terms?</p>
               <p>J. Hanks. No; We had had a quarrel; she would not allow people that come to our room the privilege of coming up and down.</p>
               <p>Q. When the spoons were found did you immediately go away?</p>
               <p>J. Hanks. Yes; that was the last box we opened.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any thing taken out in order to look for the spoons?</p>
               <p>J. Hanks. I did not see the inside of the box.</p>
               <p>Q. to R. Hanks. Was the box emptied before you finished the search?</p>
               <p>R. Hanks. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you not search to the bottom in order to find the other things?</p>
               <p>R. Hanks. Because the box was not big enough in appearance to contain the gown.</p>
               <p>Q. You might have look'd farther for the buckles?</p>
               <p>R. Hanks. The things were not all taken out.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was your gown taken from?</p>
               <p>R. Hanks. That was in a trunk in the garret, and the buckles in a drawer in the same room.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-11-person161">
                  Joseph 
                  Constable 
               <interp inst="t17621208-11-person161" type="surname" value="Constable"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-11-person161" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-11-person161" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable, I was applied to by Mr. Hanks to search the prisoner's house last Wednesday evening, they said they had lost 20 yards of linnen curtain cloth, a pair of paste buckles set in silver, five tea spoons, and a pair of tongs. We began the search in the fore room on the first floor; then the back room; then we went to the garret; the prisoner was with us; when she open'd the last chest we found five tea spoons, and a pair of tea tongs, (produced in court tied up together in a piece of cloth, with both ends to be seen.) There was something lay upon the corner of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the box full of linnen?</p>
               <p>Constable. I don't think it was a quarter full, the prisoner unlock'd the box, and took them out herself, there was nothing in it but rags and chings, it was captain Burton's box.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you see the spoons as soon as the box was open?</p>
               <p>Constable. We might see part of the spoons at opening it.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs. Hanks. Look at that piece of linnen, wrapt about the spoons.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Hanks. That belongs to me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-11-person162">
                  Mary 
                  Barnaby 
               <interp inst="t17621208-11-person162" type="surname" value="Barnaby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-11-person162" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-11-person162" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was with them at the search; first the ground floor, then the one pair of stairs, and then the garret. When the prisoner opened the box, she took the key, and turn'd round, and said to her servant, you'l swear my life away. To the best of my knowledge this was before the box was opened.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I don't know any thing how the spoons came there; when Mrs. Hanks came home that morning, she went up into the garret; my girl said she was going to make a fire; she heard something snap in the garret. She believed she was breaking of sticks. He came down and said nothing to me, and went out and return'd between twelve and one with the constable. They went up stairs, and said nothing to me. Presently they came all down together, and said, they had lost some things, and must have a search. I opened every place. When we came to the chest, Mr. Hanks said, this is the chest, if there is any thing. I opened the chest; there lay the spoons at one end of it. He said, O Lord, these are my spoons. I turned to Mrs. Hanks, and said, you jade, that did this, will not scruple swearing any body's life away. Then they took me before Justice Scott.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-11-person163">
                  Mary 
                  Isley 
               <interp inst="t17621208-11-person163" type="surname" value="Isley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-11-person163" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-11-person163" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Mrs. Meers a great while; she bears a very good character; I was chairwoman there; I remember a dispute between Mrs. Hanks and she; it was a fortnight ago last Saturday. I was by, Mrs. Hanks sent for me up into her room, and wanted some stuff which I have for a cough; (this was at night) she began to mention some words Mrs. Meers and she had had before. She called Mrs. Meers worse than that of a common woman; said, she had had a bastard child, and used her very ill. Mr. Hanks and his wife too threatened Mrs. Meers; they said, they would do for her by Monday; this was on the Saturday, before the tea spoons were lost. There were many words past; they said, they would confine her before she was much older; this was when they were scolding. Mrs. Meers was below and Mrs. Hanks above, she in bed, and he walking up and down the room. They said, they would bring 5 people to prove Mrs. Meers had had a bastard child; and Mrs. Hanks said, she knew more law, than any body about the other, and she would give Mrs. Meers a guinea to swear falsely, and me another if I would swear false for her.</p>
               <p>Q. What was this upon?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-11-person164">
                  Mary 
                  Isley 
               <interp inst="t17621208-11-person164" type="surname" value="Isley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-11-person164" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-11-person164" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mrs. Meers intended to take out<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176212080017"></xptr> a citation for Mrs. Hanks upon the account of the quarrel.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-11-person165">
                  Eleanor 
                  Hutchinson 
               <interp inst="t17621208-11-person165" type="surname" value="Hutchinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-11-person165" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-11-person165" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am between 14 and 15 years of age. I live with Mrs. Meers. Mrs. Hanks came into the house that morning from on board a ship between 7 and 8; she went up stairs into her own room, and then into the garret. We heard her go up; but I don't know which garret she went into. When in the garret, I heard some sticks crack. I thought she was going to light a fire. I went in and told my mistress, that Mrs. Hanks was going to light her fire. (A large deal box produced in court.) I saw the tea spoons lying within about 4 inches off the end of the box upon the other things, when the lid was open. This is Captain Burton's box.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any lock upon the garret door where this box was?</p>
               <p>E. Hutchinson. No, there was not. When the box was opened, my mistress turned about to Mrs. Hanks, and said, you jade, if you can do these things, you will swear my life away. Mr. Hart went to try if he could get the spoons into the box when it was looked on the Wednesday night; and either Mr. Hanks or one of the headboroughs took it out of his hand, and said, you shall not have them, that is not the right way. I heard Mr. Hanks threaten my mistress on the Saturday night before, ( when they had some words about a fishwoman) that he would bind her in a faster place before a month was at an end.</p>
               <p>Captain Burton. On the 25th of Nov. I was at change. I came home to dinner. (I lodge at Mrs. Meers's) Mrs. Meers said, there had been a little difference about a fishwoman going up stairs. There was a girl crying chesnuts in the streets, as I was at dinner. Mrs. Hanks called her to come up into her room. I stept out and said, ours is a clean house; I don't like people should make the stairs so dirty. Mrs. Hanks came and abused Mrs. Meers, and had I not been there, I believe she would have struck her; her husband came down and abused her too. This box is my property; it has been in my custody ever since Mrs. Meers has been in custody. I observed these marks on it when I first looked at it, after the spoons were found; they seem to be done by some instrument in forcing the lid up, by which means it was easy to put them in without unlocking the box. (The Jury inspect it, and found it easy for a man to get the palm of his hand in.)</p>
               <p>Q. What is Mrs. Meer's character?</p>
               <p>Captain Burton. I have known her a good while. She bears a good character. I look upon her to be a very honest, decent, orderly good woman; She is a person well to pass in the world.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Langley. I was present when Mr. Hart desired to try if he could not get the spoons in by lifting up the box lid. Mr. Hanks, the constable, and Eleanor Hutchinson were present. Mr. Hanks, or the constable, said, nobody should try any more. I desired to try, and he would not let me.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hart. I was at Mrs. Meers's house when the constables were there; I had the spoons in my hand, I desired to try if I could not get them into the box. I began to try, and said I believ'd I could get them in, was I to strain the place. They said it must not be strained. One of them took them from me. I then observed a mark upon the box, and told it to the constable, and said there was a vacancy enough to put the spoons in. The box appeared in the very same manner as now.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known Mrs. Meers?</p>
               <p>Hart. I have known her between 12 and 13 years; she once lived servant with me; she behaved extraordinary well. I always looked upon her to be a faithful, honest, sober person; there cannot be an honester person in the world.</p>
               <p>Mr. and Miss Winter, who had known her between 10 and 11 years; Mr. Smith and Mr. French about 4; Mr. Merryman 12 or 14; 
               <persName id="t17621208-11-person166">
                  Dorothy 
                  Kelly 
               <interp inst="t17621208-11-person166" type="surname" value="Kelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-11-person166" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-11-person166" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             almost 2; Mr. Seabrook 7; all gave her the character of an honest sober person. There were many others ready to appear to her character, but the Jury declared they were satisfied.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17621208-11-verdict72" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17621208-11-verdict72" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>. A copy of the indictment was granted to the prisoner.</p>
            </div1>
