<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640113-42">
               <interp inst="t17640113-42" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640113-42" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640113-42" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640113"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640113-42" type="date" value="17640113"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640113-42-off220-c293" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-defend370 t17640113-42-off220 t17640113-42-verdict224"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640113-42-off220-c294" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-defend372 t17640113-42-off220 t17640113-42-verdict224"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640113-42-off222-c297" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-defend378 t17640113-42-off222 t17640113-42-verdict226"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640113-42-off227-c294" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-defend372 t17640113-42-off227 t17640113-42-verdict224"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640113-42-off233-c294" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-defend372 t17640113-42-off233 t17640113-42-verdict224"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640113-42-off235-c293" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-defend370 t17640113-42-off235 t17640113-42-verdict224"></join>
         
               <p>111, 112, 113. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17640113-42-defend370" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Nokes 
                  <interp inst="t17640113-42-defend370" type="surname" value="Nokes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-defend370" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-defend370" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17640113-42-defend372" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Brown 
                  <interp inst="t17640113-42-defend372" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-defend372" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-defend372" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted, for <rs id="t17640113-42-off220" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-off220" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-off220" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               that they, on the <rs id="t17640113-42-cd221" type="crimeDate">7th of November</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off220 t17640113-42-cd221"></join>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off222 t17640113-42-cd221"></join>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off227 t17640113-42-cd221"></join>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off233 t17640113-42-cd221"></join>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off235 t17640113-42-cd221"></join>, about the hour of eight in the night, did break and enter the dwelling-house of Robert Cook, and stealing one silk and stuff-gown, one linnen gown, two linnen handkerchiefs, two linnen sleeves, two linnen caps, two pair of ruffles, a pair of silver shoe-buckles, six gold-rings, eight linnen shifts, six linnen aprons, and a thirty-six shillings piece of gold, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640113-42-victim374" type="victimName">
                           Jane 
                           Rouglidge 
                        <interp inst="t17640113-42-victim374" type="surname" value="Rouglidge"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640113-42-victim374" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640113-42-victim374" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , and one coverlid, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640113-42-victim376" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Cook 
                        <interp inst="t17640113-42-victim376" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640113-42-victim376" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640113-42-victim376" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling-house of the said Robert
            </rs>; and 
               
                  <persName id="t17640113-42-defend378" type="defendantName">
                     Jane 
                     Chamberlayne 
                  <interp inst="t17640113-42-defend378" type="surname" value="Chamberlayne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-defend378" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-defend378" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , for <rs id="t17640113-42-off222" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-off222" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-off222" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving two linnen handkerchiefs, part of the said goods, well-knowing them to have been stolen
            </rs>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640113-42-person379">
                  John 
                  Ivis 
               <interp inst="t17640113-42-person379" type="surname" value="Ivis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-person379" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-person379" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a printer, and now live in Long-lane near Smithfield. I have known the two men at the bar about three or four months; I became<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176401130030"></xptr> acquainted with them at the Jolly Sailor, a publick-house in Chick lane; some time in November, Brown and I were going out together; we said, we might as well take Jemmy with us.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you been out together before?</p>
               <p>Ives. We had, two or three times: this was in the evening between six and nine: we did not agree upon any place in particular; our intent was to get into some person's house, and rob it: we went into <placeName id="t17640113-42-crimeloc223">Bedford-row</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640113-42-crimeloc223" type="placeName" value="Bedford-row"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640113-42-crimeloc223" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off220 t17640113-42-crimeloc223"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off222 t17640113-42-crimeloc223"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off227 t17640113-42-crimeloc223"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off233 t17640113-42-crimeloc223"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off235 t17640113-42-crimeloc223"></join>; there was a house a building; there were two or three boards put up against a cellar-window; I went in there and opened the outward door: Brown came in to me; Nokes stood at the door: we went up to the top, and over the houses, and found a garret-window open; we went in at it: I have since found it to be the house of Mr. Cook, an apothecary. I had a thing like a screw-driver, with which I broke open a box in one of the garrets, and took out two suits of cloaths; then I went into another garret, and broke two more boxes, and took out several books, but I did not take them away: we took a linnen gown, a silk and stuff gown, ruffles, aprons, caps, shifts, and several things, and tied them up in a rug upon the bed: I never saw the ring, buckles, or thirty-six shillings piece, that are laid in the indictment: we went out with the bundle at the window again, and down to Nokes, and delivered them to him, and he carried them on his back to my room in Long-lane: we got there by 9 o'clock; the next day, or day after, we sold the two gowns, coat and breeches, to one Levi that is here; he lives in Hounsditch: we kept one brown waistcoat, that I had.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to meet with him?</p>
               <p>Ives. Nokes was out, and met with him, and brought him to my room; I had never seen him before: Brown breakfasted and dined with me every day. When Nokes brought the Jew to us; he said he was a good honest fellow; he had known him a great many years, and was what they call an Old Fence: we agreed for two guineas; he paid us half a guinea, and said he would bring us the remainder the next day. He took them away in a bag, but we never could get any more money of him: the women's wearing apparel we divided into three parcels; I laid them out, Nokes chose one parcel; he had two shifts, two pair of ruffles, and two or three white handkerchiefs; I am not certain whether he had not an apron. Brown did not want any; he said, I might have his part; so he gave them to me. I think we divided them the day after Levi was gone. Nokes wanted money, so I gave him fourteen shillings, which is one third of two guineas, 10 l was three shillings and sixpence out of pocket. This was at the Nag's-head in Hounsditch; the Jew met us there. I was taken up the 27th or 28th of November, for another fact, and examined before Sir 
               <persName id="t17640113-42-person380">
                  William 
                  Stevenson 
               <interp inst="t17640113-42-person380" type="surname" value="Stevenson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-person380" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-person380" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , there I told every thing. Chamberlayne passes for Nokes's wife.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she know how you came by the things?</p>
               <p>Ives. I don't believe she knew any thing of the affair; I know Nokes took the things from my apartment.</p>
               <p>Q. From Brown. Did you know me break or open any locks?</p>
               <p>Ives. No, you did not.</p>
               <p>Q. From Brown. Whether I ever took any money, only a shilling or two that you was pleased to give me?</p>
               <p>Ives. When Brown asked me for money, I used to give him some.</p>
               <p>Q. From Nokes. Have you any witness to prove that I sold the things?</p>
               <p>Ives. There was Brown and I, my wife and my mother, and Nokes, all in the room at the time the Jew bought them.</p>
               <p>Q. From Nokes. How big is your room?</p>
               <p>Ives. It is a large room; we were by the window, and my wife and mother were sitting by the fire.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640113-42-person381">
                  Jane 
                  Rouglidge 
               <interp inst="t17640113-42-person381" type="surname" value="Rouglidge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-person381" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-person381" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Cook: the house was robbed between seven and eleven at night, on the 7th of November; our shop-man's chest was broke as well as mine: my door was broke open; he went up, and came down and told me, he saw some books and things lying about the room; then I went up and found my box broke, and all my things gone. Eight shifts, two gowns, eleven pair of sleeves, five pair of ruffles; I cannot tell the number of head-cloaths; a gold-ring marked J. R. a pair of silver shoe-buckles, a thirty six shillings piece, and a good many handkerchiefs, and a good many other things. I have only got again three pair of sleeves, two pair of ruffles, the apron I have on, and two white handkerchiefs. (Produced in court, and deposed to.)</p>
               <p>Mr. Oakes. I am constable; these things I found in a box in Nokes's lodging, over against Mr. Gifford's brew-house, on the 29th of November. Nokes was then in confinement.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640113-42-person382">
                  Hyman 
                  Levi 
               <interp inst="t17640113-42-person382" type="surname" value="Levi"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-person382" type="given" value="Hyman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-person382" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have lived in Hounsditch seven or eight years. I am an old cloathsman, and dress old hats. I was crying old cloaths in Bread-street in the city; Nokes called me behind, and said, will you buy a parcel of cloaths? I said, where? he took me to an ale-house, we had two pints of beer, I paid for them; he had a woman with him; he said to her, you may go about<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176401130031"></xptr> your business; I shall go with the man, and let him see the cloaths, I went with him to Ives's room; he opened a chest, and took out a linnen gown, and another gown made of silk and stuff, and a camblet coat with silver-buttons and button-holes, and breeches; he asked me three guineas for them. Ives had a brown coat on, which he gave into the bargain: we agreed for two guineas; I paid half a guinea in hand: I took them away with me, and sold them in a day or two after. Some to a woman that came out of the country to buy things; and some to another person where I could get the best money for them.</p>
               <p>Q. When was you to pay the remainder of the money?</p>
               <p>Levi. I was to pay it the next day; Brown and Ives was to come to my house for it. They did come, but I had not the money, nor could I get it. I told them, they took me in, they were not worth half so much. They all three came to my house three or four days after; I said, I could not pay them, I had no money; I have got four small children, and, if I paid them all the money, my children must die; I have enough to say against Brown, but nothing more about these cloaths.</p>
               <p>Q. From Nokes. Whether you did not say you paid two guineas for these cloaths before Sir 
               <persName id="t17640113-42-person383">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17640113-42-person383" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-person383" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-person383" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Levi. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Mr. Cook. There were many things taken away, the property of a servant of mine, named Mark-
               <persName id="t17640113-42-person384">
                  Anthony 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17640113-42-person384" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-person384" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-person384" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; he is since gone from me, so we did not put them in the indictment.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640113-42-person385">
                  Mary 
                  Ives 
               <interp inst="t17640113-42-person385" type="surname" value="Ives"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-person385" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-person385" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am mother to the evidence Ives. I have known the two prisoners about ten weeks; they used to come to my son. This Jew came twice; I saw him buy some cloaths of them once, but the particular time I cannot tell; he took the cloaths away; he came the next day, and asked them, why they did not tell him they were in the Chant, that is, the News Papers.</p>
               <p>Brown's Defence.</p>
               <p>I have been drawn in, in a cruel manner, by Ives. I came home from the Havanna; and was sitting at a public-house; he came and asked me, if I would drink any beer, and then to take a walk with him; we went round Bedford-row: he said he would give me a coat, he bought one, and gave nine shillings for it: he gave me some dinner; I did not know his design when I went with him. When we came near Lincoln's Inn fields, he gave me some purl, and a welch rabbet; he pulled out a small dark lanthorn and a wax-candle; I said, I did not like it; he bid me give myself no concern; so I went on with him in four or five robberies. I recommend myself to the mercy of the court: I have been nine years in his Majesty's service. Ives told me, he has been several years a house-breaker. If any favourable sentence can be for me, I hope I shall have it.</p>
               <p>Nokes's Defence.</p>
               <p>I have such a bad set of people to deal with, and I have nobody that will come nigh me; I have been so long in confinement, that I am incapable to subpoena people to come for me. I know nothing of the charge; this is done to swear my life away to save themselves.</p>
               <p>Nokes and Brown acquitted of the burglary. <rs id="t17640113-42-verdict224" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-verdict224" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-verdict224" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder40s"></interp>
               Guilty. 39 s.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17640113-42-punish225" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-punish225" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-defend370 t17640113-42-punish225"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-defend372 t17640113-42-punish225"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Chamberlayne, <rs id="t17640113-42-verdict226" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-verdict226" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>(L.) Brown was a second time indicted, for <rs id="t17640113-42-off227" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-off227" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-off227" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               that he, on the <rs id="t17640113-42-cd228" type="crimeDate">27th of November</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off220 t17640113-42-cd228"></join>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off222 t17640113-42-cd228"></join>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off227 t17640113-42-cd228"></join>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off233 t17640113-42-cd228"></join>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off235 t17640113-42-cd228"></join>, about the hour of 9 in the night, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640113-42-victim387" type="victimName">
                           Giles 
                           Hanwell 
                        <interp inst="t17640113-42-victim387" type="surname" value="Hanwell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640113-42-victim387" type="given" value="Giles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640113-42-victim387" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did break and enter, and stealing one gold watch, value 6 l. one silver pint mug, weight 13 oz. 11 dwts. value 4 l. one child's coral, and green string, value 1 l. 1 s. one diamond hoop ring, value 15 l. one amythist, ditto, value 1 l. 16 s. one amythist motto ring, with two roses, value 2 l. 2 s. one crystal motto ditto, value 8 s. two double motto rings, not finished, and one urn ditto, value 1 l. 10 s. two grains of sundry small diamonds, value 2 l. 10 s. four ditto, amythists, value 15 s. three ditto, garnets, value 7 s. 6 d. one pair of cluster garnet ear-rings, value 1 l. 11 s. 6 d. one pair of paste ditto, value 1 l. 1 s. one other pair of night ditto, value 7 s. 6 d. one pair of crystal shoe-buckles, value 2 l. 2 s. one pair of knee, ditto, value 10 s. one silver stock-buckle, one pair of knee-buckles, and three stay-hooks, unset, value 12 s. one cornelian ring, set in gold, value 18 s. two other gold broken stone rings, value 5 s. twenty-four silver rings, value 7 s. one thimble, value 1 s. two white bead necklaces, value 6 s. four red and white handkerchiefs, value 4 s. three brown silk ditto, value 12 s. eighteen crystal waistcoat buttons, and silver lace, value 18 s. one pair of brown crystal shirt buttons, set in gold, value 1 l. 1 s. two pair of silver shoe-buckle, value 1 l. 5 s. one pair of gold cane pipes, value 5 s. three silk handkerchiefs, a silver medal, a piece of foreign gold coin, value 12 d. and 25 shillings in money, numbered, the property of the said Giles, in his dwelling-house
            </rs>. ||</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176401130032"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17640113-42-person388">
                  Giles 
                  Hanwell 
               <interp inst="t17640113-42-person388" type="surname" value="Hanwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-person388" type="given" value="Giles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-person388" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17640113-42-viclabel229" type="occupation">gold ring-maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-victim387 t17640113-42-viclabel229"></join>, and live in <placeName id="t17640113-42-crimeloc230">Gutter-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640113-42-crimeloc230" type="placeName" value="Gutter-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640113-42-crimeloc230" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off220 t17640113-42-crimeloc230"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off222 t17640113-42-crimeloc230"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off227 t17640113-42-crimeloc230"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off233 t17640113-42-crimeloc230"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off235 t17640113-42-crimeloc230"></join>. On the 27th of November, about half an hour after nine at night, the maid was ordered to go up and warm the bed: when she got upon the stairs, she was frighted; she came down, and said she saw a light, and thought she discovered the flap of a man's coat go up the three pair of stairs, before her; she said, she believed there were thieves in the house. Her Mrs. being big with child, I said, don't pretend to fright your mistress, go up again; she did, and the boy with her, and came down more frighted than before: then I went up, and I found the things all about in the two pair of stairs room, from out of a chest of drawers. I said to my boy, go and get me some assistance, I'll go no farther, at present; he went, and got a person, who came with a poker; we went up, and found the thieves had got out at an end window, in the garret; it was made to go out, in case of a fire; they had broke a pane of glass to put their hand in, to unhasp it; that we found open. My shop where we work above, was tumbled all about; they had broke a hole there, and took out many valuable things. I missed from there, and in a closet, and from drawers, the things mentioned in the indictment (mentioning them by name); I have got some of them again, which were found in the street. Ives was taken in the pursuit, and brought back; he dropped many things in the street, and some were found upon him. I have here two pair of buckles, which I received from Ives, and the constable has some effects which he found upon Ives.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640113-42-person389">
                  John 
                  Ives 
               <interp inst="t17640113-42-person389" type="surname" value="Ives"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-person389" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-person389" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 27th of November, Brown and I went out of my room, and went in at an empty house, in Gutter-lane, within two or three doors of Mr. Hanwell's house; we went to the top of the house, and upon the ridges, till we came to his house; there I broke a pane of glass, and put my hand in, and opened the casement; I went in first, and he followed me: we took the things mentioned in the indictment; I put some in my pockets, and he some in his. I had the gold watch and some of the rings, and some gold ear-rings, and the money; two crown pieces, some half crowns, shillings, pence, two-pences, three-pences, and four-pences. Brown had the pint silver mug, the coral, and all the rest of the things. Brown said he sold the pint mug for 3 l. at Chatham; the maid came up stairs, just as we were going away, and put us in a fright; said she, is that you above? (I suppose she thought it was her master); Brown said, yes, my dear: we went out-there again, and came down the empty house, we were pursued; Brown ran towards the end of Friday-street, and I towards the end of the Old 'Change. I was taken with some of the things. I dropped the watch in the street, as they were carrying me to the Compter; I was taken before Mr. Alderman Stevenson, and there made my confession.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have nothing to say in my behalf; only I leave myself to the mercy of the court. Ives was the first that brought me in, and now he is going to take my life away; he knows what he did at Martinico, when he threw the dice to save his life. I hope you will detain the Jew; he has been the ring-leader of us all, as well as Ives; he bought the things belonging to Dr. Askew, for two guineas, that were worth many pounds.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640113-42-verdict231" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-verdict231" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17640113-42-punish232" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-punish232" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-defend372 t17640113-42-punish232"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a third time indicted for <rs id="t17640113-42-off233" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-off233" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-off233" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a crape gown, value 10 s. a bombazine sack and coat, ten shirts, three linnen pillow-cases, five napkins, a cornelian seal, set in gold, a linnen shift, a petticoat, two silk handkerchiefs, a linnen handkerchief, a gold watch, and a gold watch chain, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640113-42-victim391" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Temple 
                        <interp inst="t17640113-42-victim391" type="surname" value="Temple"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640113-42-victim391" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640113-42-victim391" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17640113-42-viclabel234" type="occupation">clerk</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-victim391 t17640113-42-viclabel234"></join>, in the dwelling-house of the said John
            </rs>. And James Noakes (a second time) for <rs id="t17640113-42-off235" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-off235" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-off235" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving the gold watch, and gold watch chain, part of the said goods, knowing them to have been stolen
            </rs>, <rs id="t17640113-42-cd236" type="crimeDate">November 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off220 t17640113-42-cd236"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off222 t17640113-42-cd236"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off227 t17640113-42-cd236"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off233 t17640113-42-cd236"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off235 t17640113-42-cd236"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640113-42-person392">
                  John 
                  Temple 
               <interp inst="t17640113-42-person392" type="surname" value="Temple"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-person392" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-person392" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17640113-42-crimeloc237">Charter-House-square</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640113-42-crimeloc237" type="placeName" value="Charter-House-square"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640113-42-crimeloc237" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off220 t17640113-42-crimeloc237"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off222 t17640113-42-crimeloc237"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off227 t17640113-42-crimeloc237"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off233 t17640113-42-crimeloc237"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-42-off235 t17640113-42-crimeloc237"></join>. On the 18th of November, in the morning, Mrs. Temple went up into the garret, and came down frightened, and said, she was robbed; after she recovered, I went up three pair of stairs with her, into the garret: I found a chest was open, out of which were taken several things, mentioned in the indictment, sheets, napkins, a gown, and 10 shirts, taken from off a line that hung up to dry; and my wife's gold watch was taken from our bed-room. I have got the gold seal again, which Ives's wife, as he calls her, gave me. There were petticoats of my wife's, and a crape gown, and other things, taken out of a trunk: the gold watch and watch chain cost me 30 guineas. I went to see Ives in the Poultry-compter: he told his wife to go home with me, and give me all the things that were marked with his name. I know nothing of Nokes having any thing, and I know nothing of Brown.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640113-42-person393">
                  John 
                  Ives 
               <interp inst="t17640113-42-person393" type="surname" value="Ives"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-person393" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-person393" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Brown and I went into an empty house, joining to this gentleman's house, and got in at his garret window, which was open, to dry the linnen; we took the linnen and gowns; we went down one pair of stairs, and took a gold watch and chain, and carried them home.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Ives. I cannot say the day; it was about a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176401130033"></xptr> week before I was taken up. Noakes said, he knew a person that would buy the gold watch and chain: he came to my room, and took me into Hounsditch; he left me at the Nag's-Head, and went and returned, and said, he sold the watch and chain to a Jew, for 6 l. 15 s. we gave Nokes half a guinea for his trouble. He would not let me see the Jew; I believe he cheated us.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17640113-42-verdict238" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640113-42-verdict238" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
