<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17600227-34">
               <interp inst="t17600227-34" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600227-34" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600227-34" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600227"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600227-34" type="date" value="17600227"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600227-34-off181-c247" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600227-34-defend307 t17600227-34-off181 t17600227-34-verdict182"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600227-34-off183-c247" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600227-34-defend307 t17600227-34-off183 t17600227-34-verdict182"></join>
         
               <p>115. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17600227-34-defend307" type="defendantName">
                  Toussaint
                   Felix Urvoy, otherwise <rs id="t17600227-34-alias-4" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600227-34-defend307 t17600227-34-alias-4"></join>Felix All-Saints Happy Urvoy</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-34-defend307" type="surname" value="Felix Urvoy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-34-defend307" type="given" value="Toussaint"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-34-defend307" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17600227-34-off181" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600227-34-off181" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-34-off181" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 3 china dishes, value 3 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17600227-34-victim309" type="victimName">
                           Peter 
                           Legee 
                        <interp inst="t17600227-34-victim309" type="surname" value="Legee"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600227-34-victim309" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600227-34-victim309" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in a certain lodging room let by contract
            </rs>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600227-34-person310">
                  Peter 
                  Legee 
               <interp inst="t17600227-34-person310" type="surname" value="Legee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-34-person310" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-34-person310" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I let the prisoner a lodging-room about a week after last Midsummer, it was ready furnished, for some time, but he had no bed there, having a house of his own; he did not lay there, but came three days in a week to give people advice.</p>
               <p>Q. What furniture was there let with the room?</p>
               <p>Legee. There were a few chairs, and three china dishes, that cost me five shillings riveting. After some little time he was to have the house, so I did not let him my goods, but let them stand in his possession.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you deny him the use of the china dishes?</p>
               <p>Legee. No, I did not; but I did not let them to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Who set you on to prosecute him?</p>
               <p>Legee. I threaten'd I would indict him if he would not give me my dishes again, he did not deny having them. After I had made affidavit about them, I was forced to go thro' with it, and then he sent me the dishes again.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you owe him any money?</p>
               <p>Legee. If we come to account I believe I owe him money.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600227-34-verdict182" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600227-34-verdict182" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>(L.) He was a second time indicted by the same names, for <rs id="t17600227-34-off183" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600227-34-off183" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-34-off183" type="offenceSubcategory" value="fraud"></interp>
               obtaining, by false pretences, two pictures in gilt frames, value 3 l. 3 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17600227-34-victim312" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Peirt 
                        <interp inst="t17600227-34-victim312" type="surname" value="Peirt"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600227-34-victim312" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600227-34-victim312" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , with intent to defraud the said John thereof
            </rs>, <rs id="t17600227-34-cd184" type="crimeDate">December 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600227-34-off181 t17600227-34-cd184"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600227-34-off183 t17600227-34-cd184"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>The prisoner being a foreigner, an interpreter was sworn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600227-34-person313">
                  John 
                  Peirt 
               <interp inst="t17600227-34-person313" type="surname" value="Peirt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-34-person313" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-34-person313" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am <rs id="t17600227-34-viclabel185" type="occupation">an haberdasher and cabinet-maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600227-34-victim312 t17600227-34-viclabel185"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Peirt. I live in Queen-Street, Cheapside.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Peirt. By profession he is <rs id="t17600227-34-deflabel186" type="occupation">a quack doctor</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600227-34-defend307 t17600227-34-deflabel186"></join>; he got acquainted with a friend of mine at a coffee-house in the city, and told him he had got some particular nostrums, by which he could cure several disorders, and said he wanted a house to be furnish'd, but as he was not known he desired my friend to recommend him. My friend came and told me of him, he said he was a foreigner, and that he had seen many notes of hand that he had got of people, and believed he could pay ready money. Upon this<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176002270032"></xptr> the prisoner applied to me for beds and furniture, and I gave him credit. As I was scrupulous of trusting him, he said this is my way of doing business, here is a note of hand for 40 guineas, I'll pay you that. I took it, and inquired where the man lived that had given it to him. I found there was such a man in being, and that he lived in a creditable house. I deliver'd him some goods as quick as I could, on the credit of that note. I deliver'd him goods to the amount of about 100 l. before I got the money. When this note was due I apply'd to the person for payment, and he quibbled with me, and said the covenant of the note was not performed; he said, I'll tell you the truth, it is for a core 16 and so, that the prisoner engaged to cure him in such a time, and had not perform'd the cure, but said, as I have given the note I must pay it. I bid him let his time and I would stay, and at last I recover'd my money. After that the prisoner came to me with another pretence, he told me he wanted his first floor furnished, for he had got a nobleman and a lady to take into his house as patients, that he was to have four guineas a week, and would pay me the money as it arose, adding, you see I live in creadit; you see I have forty guineas for a cure at a time, and I'll pay you honestly. I gave him credit in the whole for 244 l. This being a great deal of money I push'd him from time to time, and got of him fifteen guineas, ten guineas and two notes upon a minor, but could get no more of him. I then heard he had had several trials at Westminster, which appear'd very black. He had bespoke several other goods of me, particularly a Sopha, which he said he could not do without in his parlour. He came once to my house and saw two pictures, drawn by Mr. Worlidge, said he, what shall I give you for them? I said three guineas, but I would not part with them without ready money. He said, me pay you ready money for them, but he did not offer to pay me any, so I did not deliver them. After that, I did not see him for some time. I was going out of town to Canterbury, with a funeral. Then I thought proper to call upon him, to tell him I was going out of town, and wanted a little cash, but I could not get any of him. He said nothing about the pictures then. I told him I should be in town about Friday or Saturday, and desired him to pay me some then; he said at Christmas he would pay me all. Before I came back again he had been at my house and got the two pictures, which my servant can give a further account of. I had desired my servant not to deliver them to him without the money.</p>

               <p>Q. Where did the prisoner live at that time?</p>
               <p>Peirt. He lived in a house in Bream's Buildings.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he pay you by bills and money?</p>
               <p>Peirt. He paid me a hundred and fifteen or sixteen pounds; two of the notes in part I have in my pocket now.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you first hear of the prisoner's having these pictures?</p>
               <p>Peirt. As soon as I came to town (I came to town on the Friday following; I can't recollect the day of the month, but it was in the month of December, about the middle) I went directly to Tower Hill, where he directed my servant to come; it was at a house where he attended three days a week.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600227-34-person314">
                  William 
                  Philips 
               <interp inst="t17600227-34-person314" type="surname" value="Philips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-34-person314" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-34-person314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to the prosecutor. The prisoner came to my mistress, when my master was absent, for two pictures in gilt frames, and said he wanted them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he give you any reason why?</p>
               <p>Philips. No; but he wanted to have them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you deliver them to him?</p>
               <p>Philips. I did. My mistress being below, he went to her, and what agreement they made, I know not; but I was called down stairs to deliver the pictures to him?</p>
               <p>Q. Who called you down?</p>
               <p>Philips. My mistress did. She told me to reach the two pictures from off the nail, for the prisoner to take away with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this in his presence?</p>
               <p>Philips. It was, and I took them down and delivered them to him. He told me when my master came to town, if he would call at such a house on Tower Hill, he would pay him three guineas for them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600227-34-person315">
                  Sarah 
                  Scott 
               <interp inst="t17600227-34-person315" type="surname" value="Scott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-34-person315" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-34-person315" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner came several times after the pictures (I believe three times) when my master was out of town, and said he wanted the pictures. I told him my master was not in town, and the third time he came, he had them delivered to him.</p>
               <p>Q. By whose order were they delivered?</p>
               <p>S. Scott. By my mistress's order.</p>
               <p>Q. Give an account of the conversation that past between the prisoner and your mistress?</p>
               <p>S. Scott. I heard my mistress bid Philips take them down; but as I was at work at some distance. I cannot tell all that past.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600227-34-verdict187" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600227-34-verdict187" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
