<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17671209-14">
               <interp inst="t17671209-14" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17671209-14" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17671209-14" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17671209"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17671209-14" type="date" value="17671209"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17671209-14-off72-c85" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671209-14-defend110 t17671209-14-off72 t17671209-14-verdict75"></join>
         
               <p>16. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17671209-14-defend110" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Lorimer 
                  <interp inst="t17671209-14-defend110" type="surname" value="Lorimer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-14-defend110" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-14-defend110" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17671209-14-off72" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17671209-14-off72" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-14-off72" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 200 pounds weight of sugar, value 36 s.
            </rs> the property of a person or persons unknown, <rs id="t17671209-14-cd73" type="crimeDate">Nov. 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671209-14-off72 t17671209-14-cd73"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671209-14-person111">
                  John 
                  Summerfield 
               <interp inst="t17671209-14-person111" type="surname" value="Summerfield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-14-person111" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-14-person111" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a King's officer; on the 3d of November there was a lighter of sugar lay at <placeName id="t17671209-14-crimeloc74">Fresh-wharf</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17671209-14-crimeloc74" type="placeName" value="Fresh-wharf"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17671209-14-crimeloc74" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671209-14-off72 t17671209-14-crimeloc74"></join>; a brother officer came and told me some body had robbed it (I was not in charge of that lighter;) I, and two or three more went; the lighter lay on the side the ship; I got into the lighter; there were three men jumped out of her, and threw three bags of sugar into a boat; they made off in her; we went on shore, and consulted what to do; we went there again, and found the prisoner in the lighter; he said, he belonged to her, he was the ship's man; we asked him where he had been; he said he had been with the lighter-man to drink a pint of beer; I said, your lighter has been robbed; he said it had not; I said I was sure it had; then we went back again, and consulted whether we should take him in custody or not; we thought we had a right to take him up: then we went again, and went on board, and found the vessel had been robbed of about 100 and a half of sugar, three bags, and two large handkerchiefs full; when we said we should take him up, he said, let me alone, I will pay for the sugar that is taken away, do not say any more about it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671209-14-person112">
                  Thomas 
                  Towse 
               <interp inst="t17671209-14-person112" type="surname" value="Towse"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-14-person112" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-14-person112" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was with the witness Summerfield at the time, he gave the same account.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was not in the lighter when she was robbed; I went to get more tarpauling to cover the sugar, and when I came back again the sugar was gone.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671209-14-person113">
                  John 
                  Knight 
               <interp inst="t17671209-14-person113" type="surname" value="Knight"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-14-person113" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-14-person113" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was captain of the Trent, the ship the lighter was loaded from; the prisoner belonged to the ship, he was sent up to watch the lighter all night; he has been with me two voyages; I always found him very honest; I looked upon him to be one of the best on board.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671209-14-person114">
                  John 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17671209-14-person114" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-14-person114" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-14-person114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I worked this lighter; she was made fast at Bottle-wharf; between eight and nine we left her there with the prisoner in her; the King's watchman came down afterwards; then I went to the Dolphin alehouse with my fellow-servant; the prisoner came up afterwards, in about a quarter of an hour, as we told him where we were going; he staid better than an hour with us; then he, I, and my fellow-servant, went all down to the vessel together, and she was then carried up to Fresh-wharf.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17671209-14-verdict75" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17671209-14-verdict75" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
