<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17631207-51">
               <interp inst="t17631207-51" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-51" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-51" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17631207"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-51" type="date" value="17631207"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17631207-51-off281-c378" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-51-defend483 t17631207-51-off281 t17631207-51-verdict285"></join>
         
               <p>54. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17631207-51-defend483" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Routh 
                  <interp inst="t17631207-51-defend483" type="surname" value="Routh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-51-defend483" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-51-defend483" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for <rs id="t17631207-51-off281" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631207-51-off281" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-51-off281" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he, on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17631207-51-victim485" type="victimName">
                           Samuel 
                           Phipps 
                        <interp inst="t17631207-51-victim485" type="surname" value="Phipps"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17631207-51-victim485" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17631207-51-victim485" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-51-off281 t17631207-51-victim485"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and stealing from his person 3 s. in money, numbered, his property, and against his will
            </rs>, <rs id="t17631207-51-cd282" type="crimeDate">Oct, 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-51-off281 t17631207-51-cd282"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-51-person486">
                  Samuel 
                  Phipps 
               <interp inst="t17631207-51-person486" type="surname" value="Phipps"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-51-person486" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-51-person486" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17631207-51-viclabel283" type="occupation">weaver</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-51-victim485 t17631207-51-viclabel283"></join>, and live in Spittalfields: coming through <placeName id="t17631207-51-crimeloc284">Church-Lane, Whitechapel</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17631207-51-crimeloc284" type="placeName" value="Church-Lane, Whitechapel"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17631207-51-crimeloc284" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-51-off281 t17631207-51-crimeloc284"></join>, on the 16th of October, three men came up to me, and said, Yo ho! I being a little in liquor, said, Yo ho! again: they all three looked in my face; I was not daunted, and went to shake hands with one of them, which I take to be the prisoner; they all three went away directly. I saw a light at a public-house, and thought somebody was up, knocked at the door, but found there was not: just as I turned from the corner (the public-house is the corner) the three men came up to me again; one of them clapt a pistol to my breast, and with an oath said, Give me the money. I said, gentlemen, what do you want? they said all your money; I had the precaution to slip my watch into the back part of my breeches. I lifted up the flap of my waistcoat, and bid 'em take all they could find in that pocket, for I had none in any other: the man that held the pistol, put his hand into my pocket, and took out 3 s. he asked me if. I had any more? I said no, without it might be a few half pence in my other pocket, I could not tell; he put his hand into my pocket, and took out two little knives and a farthing which they returned me again. He then stooped down, and took one of the buckles out of my shoes, and said, what are they silver? I said no, gentlemen, they are copper, but if you choose, you shall have them: they returned the buckle, and went towards Whitechapel.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you be certain the prisoner is one of the men that robb'd you?</p>
               <p>Phipps. I believe him to be the man that held the pistol: I was something in liquor, and will not be positive. I was going home, and held my hand to my breeches where my watch was, but did not take it out for fear of losing it: they came up to me again, and said, what are you here? they bid me a good night, and shook hands with me, and I wished 'em good success. I thought I must be as good-natured as I could to them. Just after we parted, they met another man, and robbed him of his watch, money, and buckles. I heard a noise, I went to look what it was, and met a man; he said, you may look at me, I have been robb'd. I said to have I. I said I believed I should catch them in the New Road, or towards Ragg Fair: he said, he could not go, for he was obliged to go a milking. I said, if they would give me some watchmen, I would go myself; they let me have six men, I went in pursuit of the thieves, till the watchmen would go no farther; there was fifteen watchmen went all round. On the 27th October, 11 days afterwards, Mr. Champlain, another officer, and myself, went to Saltpetre-bank: I went into a house there, and saw the prisoner; he looked white, and his countenance turned different colours. Mr. Champlain asked me what I thought of him? I said I believed he was the man that robbed me, but that I would not be sure till I see him in the light. He said to the officer, B - d and Z - ds, what do you want with me? he said he knew nothing of the matter; we searched him, but found nothing; we asked him how he came into the public-house, as he had no money?</p>
               <p>The prosecutor not being able to swear to his person, and having no other witness, the prisoner was <rs id="t17631207-51-verdict285" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631207-51-verdict285" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
