<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680224-42">
               <interp inst="t17680224-42" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680224-42" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680224-42" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680224"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680224-42" type="date" value="17680224"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680224-42-off272-c360" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-42-defend456 t17680224-42-off272 t17680224-42-verdict275"></join>
         
               <p>206 (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17680224-42-defend456" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Robinson 
                  <interp inst="t17680224-42-defend456" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-42-defend456" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-42-defend456" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17680224-42-deflabel271" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-42-defend456 t17680224-42-deflabel271"></join>, was indicted for the <rs id="t17680224-42-off272" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680224-42-off272" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-42-off272" type="offenceSubcategory" value="infanticide"></interp>
               wilful murder of her female bastard child
            </rs>; she was charged likewise on the coroner's inquest for the said murder, <rs id="t17680224-42-cd273" type="crimeDate">Feb. 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-42-off272 t17680224-42-cd273"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-42-person457">
                  Mary 
                  Adams 
               <interp inst="t17680224-42-person457" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-42-person457" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-42-person457" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodge at 
               <persName id="t17680224-42-person458">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Cooper 
               <interp inst="t17680224-42-person458" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-42-person458" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-42-person458" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, in <placeName id="t17680224-42-crimeloc274">Horton-street near Clare-market</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17680224-42-crimeloc274" type="placeName" value="Horton-street near Clare-market"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17680224-42-crimeloc274" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-42-off272 t17680224-42-crimeloc274"></join>; I had known the prisoner about three weeks before the 7th instant, she and I lay together; she went out a washing and ironing; she was sick on the 7th, being Sunday morning, she went down stairs, and staid some time, I believe an hour; when she came up again, she said she was sick, and must go down again; she did not stay at all, but turned and went down again; I fell asleep, I do not know how long she staid that time; it was not light when she went down, and it was light when she came up; she then said she was better.</p>
               <p>Q. Had not you perceived her to be with child before that night?</p>
               <p>M. Adams. No, I had not, she went for a single woman; it being Sunday morning, I lay a little longer than usual, I left her in bed; I went down to the necessary-house, I found it bloody; I went up to her, and asked her how she did; she said, not well; she got up, and went up into Mrs. Townsend's room, who lodges up two pair of stairs, and staid there all the day. On the Monday morning Mrs. Townsend and I searched the necessary, and found the after-burden; the prisoner was in her room at the time; Mrs. Townsend and I went up, and informed her of it; I staid in the yard; the prisoner went to her brother-in-law in Wardrobe-court, Doctors-commons, in the evening; we desired her to come home with us, she did; when at home, we asked her after the child, saying she had had one; soon after she went up with Mrs. Townsend to Mrs. Townsend's room; I did not go up with them, but I went up after the child was found, and laid upon a table; I saw no marks of violence upon it; I asked the prisoner whether it was born dead or alive; she said it was not born alive.</p>
               <p>Winefred Townsend. I was a lodger in the same house, I have known the prisoner ten or eleven years; I had no suspicion of her being with child till the 7th of this instant; she came up to me in my room that Sunday morning, between ten and eleven, and staid with me all the afternoon, she made no complaint; on the Monday Mrs. Adams came and told me there was something in the vault; I went down with her, and there I saw the after-burden, I took it out; the prisoner was then in my room; I went up to her, and told her what I had found; she said, what do you mean; I bid her come down and see; she did not; I went down, and looked in the vault for the child, I could not see any; I went up again, then the prisoner was gone to Doctors Commons; I and Mrs. Adams went there to her; I asked her to go home with us, she did; then we went into Mrs. Adams's room, we found nothing there; then we asked her about the child; she bid me go up stairs, and she would follow me; she went to her box, and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176802240029"></xptr> took the child out; it was clean, it seemed to have come to its full growth, there were no marks of violence upon it; I asked her if it was born alive or dead; she said it was born dead; she did not tell me where she was delivered.</p>
               <p>Mr. Patch. I am a surgeon; I made the usual experiment upon the lungs.</p>
               <p>Q. Is that held to be a certain evidence of the child having drawn breath?</p>
               <p>Patch. I should consider it as a very inconclusive evidence; there were no marks of violence upon it; I observed that the navel-string was not tied, the child might have bled to death from thence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-42-person459">
                  Anne 
                  Bright 
               <interp inst="t17680224-42-person459" type="surname" value="Bright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-42-person459" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-42-person459" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a glove-maker; I went to see the child on the 8th of February; the prisoner sent me to her box for a piece of flannel, there I found some baby-things, (several produced in court.)</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>The child was born dead.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17680224-42-verdict275" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680224-42-verdict275" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
