<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17600521-12">
               <interp inst="t17600521-12" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600521-12" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600521-12" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600521"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600521-12" type="date" value="17600521"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600521-12-off62-c114" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600521-12-defend138 t17600521-12-off62 t17600521-12-verdict66"></join>
         
               <p>185. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17600521-12-defend138" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Rowney 
                  <interp inst="t17600521-12-defend138" type="surname" value="Rowney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-defend138" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-defend138" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17600521-12-deflabel61" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600521-12-defend138 t17600521-12-deflabel61"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17600521-12-off62" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-off62" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-off62" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               that she together with 
                     <persName id="t17600521-12-person139">
                        John
                         Robertson, otherwise <rs id="t17600521-12-alias-1" type="alias">
                           <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600521-12-person139 t17600521-12-alias-1"></join>John Brown</rs>
                        <interp inst="t17600521-12-person139" type="surname" value="Robertson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600521-12-person139" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600521-12-person139" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   not taken, on the <rs id="t17600521-12-cd63" type="crimeDate">7th of March, 1759</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600521-12-off62 t17600521-12-cd63"></join>, about the hour of 2 in the night on the same day, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17600521-12-victim141" type="victimName">
                           Sidney 
                           Thornhill 
                        <interp inst="t17600521-12-victim141" type="surname" value="Thornhill"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600521-12-victim141" type="given" value="Sidney"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600521-12-victim141" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600521-12-off62 t17600521-12-victim141"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17600521-12-viclabel64" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600521-12-victim141 t17600521-12-viclabel64"></join>, did break and enter, and stealing one pair of stays, value 20 s. 2 gowns, one calimanco petticoat, one shalloon petticoat, 2 white petticoats, 2 scarlet cloaks, one bed-gown, 4 linnen aprons, 2 linnen caps, 4 silk and cotton handkerchiefs, one linnen sheet, 2 silver tea spoons, one coat and one waistcoat, the property of the said Sidney, in her dwelling-house
            </rs>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600521-12-person142">
                  Sidney 
                  Thornhill 
               <interp inst="t17600521-12-person142" type="surname" value="Thornhill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person142" type="given" value="Sidney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person142" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17600521-12-crimeloc65">Somerset-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17600521-12-crimeloc65" type="placeName" value="Somerset-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17600521-12-crimeloc65" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600521-12-off62 t17600521-12-crimeloc65"></join> in the city; my house was broke open about 2 in the morning, on the 6th of March was twelve months, and I was robb'd of the things mentioned in the indictment.</p>
               <p>Q. Name them?</p>
               <p>S. Thornhill. There were 2 gowns, one damask lined with silk, 2 black petticoats, 4 aprons, one pair of stays, 2 caps, one coat, one waistcoat, one sheet, and 2 silver tea spoons.</p>
               <p>Q. Why do you charge the prisoner?</p>
               <p>S. Thornhill. I had information given me by one Thompson on the 9th of this month; she told me, she know'd the prisoner that broke my house open, and robb'd me; and said it was one John Brown, who is not taken, and 
               <persName id="t17600521-12-person143">
                  Ann 
                  Rowney 
               <interp inst="t17600521-12-person143" type="surname" value="Rowney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person143" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person143" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the prisoner at the bar; I ask'd her how she came to know of it; she said, she was not a yard and a half from my house when John Brown gave her a bundle that he had taken out of my house. So upon this information I had the prisoner secured.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take the prisoner before a magistrate?</p>
               <p>S. Thornhill. I took her before Justice Fielding, and heard her examined there twice; there 
               <persName id="t17600521-12-person144">
                  Ann 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17600521-12-person144" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person144" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person144" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             mentioned every one of my things that I had lost, as well as I could myself.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the prisoner confess any thing?</p>
               <p>S. Thornhill. No; she own'd to nothing.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you found any of your things again?</p>
               <p>S. Thornhill. I have found one cap, which 
               <persName id="t17600521-12-person145">
                  Ann 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17600521-12-person145" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person145" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person145" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             took from off her own head, and deliver'd it to me; and said, she had it of 
               <persName id="t17600521-12-person146">
                  Ann 
                  Rowney 
               <interp inst="t17600521-12-person146" type="surname" value="Rowney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person146" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person146" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never found any of the other things.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600521-12-person147">
                  Ann 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17600521-12-person147" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person147" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person147" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . It was some time this month that I ask'd Mrs. Thornhill, if she was not robb'd. She had been crying, and saying she had lost some things; so I told her of it.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known of it?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. I knew of it ever since is was first done.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you not speak of it sooner?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. Because I was afraid of being murdered, there is such a terrible gang.</p>
               <p>Q. What way of life are you in?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. An unhappy way of life.</p>
               <p>Court. Go on, and tell your story.</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. This Brown that has been mentioned gave me the bundle in my room, and ask'd me if I would take care of it.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. It is more than 12 months ago.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was it after the robbery was committed?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. It was about 5 or 6 minutes after.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you present when the robbery was committed?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. I was, and so was the prisoner at the bar, she took and opened the bundle, there were 2 caps in it, she took one, and gave it to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176005210012"></xptr>A. Thompson. This was in my room, after Brown had brought it up.</p>
               <p>Q What did you see of the robbery?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. I saw Brown come out of Mrs. Thornhill's kitchen window, and the prisoner come out afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was you to the window then?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. I was not 4 yards from it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the prisoner go in?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. No, I did not; I can mention all the things in the bundle, which bundle I saw in Brown's hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Mention them.</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. There were 2 brown gowns, one a damask gown, lined with a silk Persian read, 2 black petticoats, 2 under petticoats, one dimity, and the other callico, 4 aprons, 3 of them colloured, one white, one pair of stays, 2 caps, one coat, and one waistcoat.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutrix. Have you a husband?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. No; I was a widow then, but the coat and waistcoat are my son's, which I bought for him; he was an apprentice, and I found him all his cloaths.</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. There were 4 handkerchiefs also (the linnen cap produced) this cap the prisoner took from out of the bundle, and gave it to me.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutrix. Look at this cap?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. This cap is the property of 
               <persName id="t17600521-12-person148">
                  Esther 
                  Miller 
               <interp inst="t17600521-12-person148" type="surname" value="Miller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person148" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person148" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , she was out of place, and lodg'd then at my house, and was lost at that time; I lost many more things than I have laid in the indictment.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600521-12-person149">
                  Esther 
                  Miller 
               <interp inst="t17600521-12-person149" type="surname" value="Miller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person149" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person149" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lost 9 caps at that time, and as many handkerchiefs; this cap is one of mine which I lost then.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. When was you before Justice Fielding?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. On the 10th of this month.</p>
               <p>Q Did you give any account to the Justice that you saw either Brown or Rowney come out of the prosecutrix's window?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. No; I was so frustrated that I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What night was the robbery on?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. It was on a Thursday, I don't know what month; the goods were brought to my room that night.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to know of the house being broke open?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. I was coming over the waste ground, and he bid me take hold of the bundle; and I took it as she was coming out at the window.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you in your information to say, you heard the day after these things were brought to your apartment, that Mrs. Thornhill's house had been broke open and robb'd? (I have your information in my hand)</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. I was frustrated, I did not know what I said.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you have had any conversation with any person concerning any reward that in to be had on the conviction of the prisoner?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. I never heard that there is a reward.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you have not had such conversation with the person that took the prisoner up?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever had any quarrel or dispute with the prisoner?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know one 
               <persName id="t17600521-12-person150">
                  Jane 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17600521-12-person150" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person150" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person150" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never desire her to swear against the prisoner at the bar?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you never a quarrel with the prisoner about cutting out a pocket?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. No; I never had any quarrel with her.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the reason, that at this great distance of time, from the 6th of march was twelvemonths, to the 9th of this instant, that you never went to acquaint Mrs. Thornhill with what you knew?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. I dare not, there is such a gang of them.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to do it now?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. Because she wanted to bring me into a robbery, and I would not do it; she wanted to bring me into a worse than this.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know who took her up?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you not present when she was taken up?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. No, I was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never consult any body, or acquaint any body with this affair, before you told Mrs. Thornhill of it?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. Yes, I told one Buckling, at the Queen's-head in Harrow alley, White Chappel.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say to it?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. He said, go and tell the truth to the poor woman that has lost her things.</p>
               <p>Q. How long ago is that?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. I believe it is about a month ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go immediately?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176005210013"></xptr>A. Thompson. I did as soon as he advised me.</p>
               <p>Q. When was that?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. I can tell the exact time, because I have been in goal and can neither write nor read.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you in goal?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. I was committed by Mr. Fielding as an evidence in this affair.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Buckling say to you there would be a reward?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. No, he did not; he gave me the best advice he cou'd to go to the poor woman.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after this that you told Mr. Buckling that you told Mrs. Thornhill?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. I went directly and told her that very day.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you acquainted with 
               <persName id="t17600521-12-person151">
                  Richard 
                  Stevens 
               <interp inst="t17600521-12-person151" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person151" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person151" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>A. Thompson. No; I do not know such a person.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600521-12-person152">
                  Richard 
                  Stevens 
               <interp inst="t17600521-12-person152" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person152" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person152" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Surveyor, I know nothing of the robbery, nor ever saw that creature (meaning the last evidence) in all the world to my knowledge: Mrs. Thornhill told me of the robbery, and show'd me the place where her house was broke; it was a sash that slides by another, they had broke the glass to put a hand in, so as to unscrew it, that it might slide back.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutrix. How was your house broke?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. The kitchen window a glass was broke, as Mr. Stevens has mentioned, and the cross bar was taken quite away, and room for any body to get in.</p>
               <p>Stevens. I lived next door but one to Mrs. Thornhill for 17 years; I was going that way some time after, and she was crying and telling me how she had been robb'd; she show'd me also how her trunks were broke open, by cutting the leather which was over the hasps, and wrenching the hasps off. I know that neighbourhood to be a notorious bad place; I was robb'd there once just by my own door, and afterwards some of them threatned to shoot me *; and I was forc'd to remove out of the neighbourhood.</p>
               <p>* See the trials of 
               <persName id="t17600521-12-person153">
                  John 
                  Benson 
               <interp inst="t17600521-12-person153" type="surname" value="Benson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person153" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person153" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17600521-12-person154">
                  Ann 
                  Parrot 
               <interp inst="t17600521-12-person154" type="surname" value="Parrot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person154" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person154" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , No. 315, 316, in Mr. Alderman Janssen's Mayoralty.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>Brown and I had a good many words, he call'd me a good many names, and I did not chuse to live with him; this 
               <persName id="t17600521-12-person155">
                  Ann 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17600521-12-person155" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person155" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person155" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             laid hold on some of my words, and she had me before my Lord Mayor. I have been by Mrs. Thornhill's house many a time since; she has said, if I wou'd give her a note for 10 l. or 5 l. she would make it up with me; she cry'd, and said the same at justice Fielding's.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutrix. Did you ever make such a proposal?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No, never in my life-time.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. They said, they wou'd carry me to justice Fielding. I begg'd they wou'd not carry me there, for he is a very dangerous man.</p>
               <p>Counsel for Prisoner. Do you remember the prisoner being taken up soon after your house was broke open, and carry'd before Sir 
               <persName id="t17600521-12-person156">
                  Richard 
                  Glyn 
               <interp inst="t17600521-12-person156" type="surname" value="Glyn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person156" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person156" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. Yes, I do; that was on the 9th of July: she was taken in custody by the constable for a riot, and swearing in a blasting manner; that was in Harrow Alley; she turn'd her petticoat back, and said to Brown, blast you. you rogue, I'll have you scragg'd, for you robb'd the poor old woman over the ground (there is a piece of waste ground between there and my house) for you broke open her house, pulling out a chissel and hammer from out of her pocket, saying, my house was broke open with them; I hearing she had said this several times, but she was not committed for breaking and robbing my house, my Lord Mayor committed her there for her rioting and wicked talk.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she not committed for this offence?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. Not then she was not.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600521-12-person157">
                  Jane 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17600521-12-person157" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person157" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person157" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know 
               <persName id="t17600521-12-person158">
                  Ann 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17600521-12-person158" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person158" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person158" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , one day we had a few words.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>J. Edwards. I live just by White Chapel, in Petticoat lane, my husband is a seafaring man, and allows me a trifle a week to live upon; he belongs to the Royal George.</p>
               <p>Q. What conversation had you with Thompson?</p>
               <p>J. Edwards. I was going through Aldgate for some snuff. 
               <persName id="t17600521-12-person159">
                  Nancy 
                  Rowney 
               <interp inst="t17600521-12-person159" type="surname" value="Rowney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person159" type="given" value="Nancy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person159" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was going by, Thompson said, Bitch.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>J. Edwards. This was about 3 or 4 days after she made herself an evidence. 
               <persName id="t17600521-12-person160">
                  Nancy 
                  Rowney 
               <interp inst="t17600521-12-person160" type="surname" value="Rowney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person160" type="given" value="Nancy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person160" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said Hussey; they had had a quarrel in the day; Thompson went and cut her own cloaths with a knife, to lay it to 
               <persName id="t17600521-12-person161">
                  Nancy 
                  Rowney 
               <interp inst="t17600521-12-person161" type="surname" value="Rowney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person161" type="given" value="Nancy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person161" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She said, if I would not go and smack it along with her before my Lord Mayor, she would take my life away, and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176005210014"></xptr> stick me; I never was well since that minute to this, nor have had a halfpennyworth of bread in my mouth since; I have a lame arm by a fall on a bottle, and she said she wou'd make my other arm as bad, and she wou'd murder and kill me, if I wou'd not; she went and got a warrant, and so went to swear a street robbery before my Lord Mayor.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say any thing of a reward?</p>

               <p>J. Edwards. She said, do not you know, that if you come along with me, and sware right or wrong, you shall have a reward, but said she wou'd not sware by herself; she went and pump'd the prosecutrix out of every word she said.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did she want you to smack it against?</p>
               <p>J. Edwards. Against 
               <persName id="t17600521-12-person162">
                  Nancy 
                  Royney 
               <interp inst="t17600521-12-person162" type="surname" value="Royney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person162" type="given" value="Nancy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person162" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600521-12-person163">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Lovell 
               <interp inst="t17600521-12-person163" type="surname" value="Lovell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person163" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person163" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The night that the prisoner was taken up, which was last monday was a week, she was coming down the Minories, the prosecutrix's son and daughter were holding the prisoner, one by one arm, the other by the other, while the city marshal conducted her to the watchhouse. I went and followed them to the Compter; going along, as the son and daughter were following her at a distance, they wrangled about the reward.</p>
               <p>Q. What did they say?</p>
               <p>E. Lovell. One said I shall have 40 l. No, the other said, I shall have it. I follow'd them to the Compter, and went in, and came out with them.</p>
               <p>Q. Was 
               <persName id="t17600521-12-person164">
                  Ann 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17600521-12-person164" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person164" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person164" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             there?</p>
               <p>E. Lovell. No, she was not; Thompson used me monstrous ill; she said, you impudent whoring flut, you drink with 
               <persName id="t17600521-12-person165">
                  Ann 
                  Rowney 
               <interp inst="t17600521-12-person165" type="surname" value="Rowney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person165" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person165" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , but I'll be up with you. I served a warrant upon her; after that, she went and made herself an evidence after she was my prisoner; (my husband is a custom-house officer) she said, for spight she would be up with me; I have eat and drank with 
               <persName id="t17600521-12-person166">
                  Ann 
                  Rowney 
               <interp inst="t17600521-12-person166" type="surname" value="Rowney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person166" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person166" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and never saw no harm by her.</p>
               <p>Q. How does she get her living?</p>
               <p>E. Lovell. A Butcher in White Chapel indulges her with what he gets, he gets his bread very hard.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear Thompson say any thing about the reward?</p>
               <p>E. Lovell. No.</p>
               <p>Mr. Buckling. Thompson was drinking in my house, I heard her say she would have Rowney taken up, and mention'd this affair. I said, what she know'd of it, it was a pity she did not acquaint the old woman with it.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is this ago?</p>
               <p>Buckling. It is about a fortnight ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she mention any thing about the reward?</p>
               <p>Buckling. No, not as I heard of.</p>
               <p>Mr Miller. I live within a few doors of Mrs. Thornhill.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the evidence Thompson?</p>
               <p>Miller. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her character?</p>
               <p>Miller. She has but a very indifferent character, she is a disorderly girl.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you believe she is to be credited upon her oath?</p>
               <p>Miller. I think she is not.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever had any dealings with her?</p>
               <p>Miller. I have dealt with both the prisoner and she.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Miller. I am a pawnbroker.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Miller. I live in Mansell-street, Goodman's Fields, next door to the Fleece.</p>
               <p>Q. What character has the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Miller. She lives with a young man a butcher; she has been a customer to me 6 or 7 years; I never heard of any robberies by her before this, I have heard of some little trifling things.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath, did the prisoner ever pledge any of these goods mention'd in the indictment with you?</p>
               <p>Miller. No; neither she, nor any body else that she sent.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there a warrant granted upon Thompson's information to search your house for these goods?</p>
               <p>Miller. Yes; and the constable examin'd my book.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600521-12-person167">
                  Esther 
                  Hatchet 
               <interp inst="t17600521-12-person167" type="surname" value="Hatchet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person167" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-person167" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner between 5 and 6 years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her way of life?</p>
               <p>E. Hatcher. She us'd to take in a little plain work, and a young man a butcher is her husband I dare say. I never knew any thing dishonest of her in the days of my breath.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600521-12-verdict66" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600521-12-verdict66" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
