<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17620421-2">
               <interp inst="t17620421-2" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620421-2" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620421-2" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17620421"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620421-2" type="date" value="17620421"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620421-2-off6-c42" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-2-defend43 t17620421-2-off6 t17620421-2-verdict9"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176204210003"></xptr>117. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17620421-2-defend43" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Edward 
                     Jewen 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17620421-2-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-2-defend43 t17620421-2-alias-1"></join>Chambers</rs>, otherwise <rs id="t17620421-2-alias-2" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-2-defend43 t17620421-2-alias-2"></join>Gordon</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-2-defend43" type="surname" value="Jewen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-2-defend43" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-2-defend43" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17620421-2-off6" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620421-2-off6" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-2-off6" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one silver tankard, value 10 l. one silver mug, value 40 s. one silver soup spoon, value 3 l. six silver table spoons, value 3 l. and one linen apron, value 1 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17620421-2-victim46" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Currie 
                        <interp inst="t17620421-2-victim46" type="surname" value="Currie"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620421-2-victim46" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620421-2-victim46" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-2-off6 t17620421-2-victim46"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling house of the said Robert
            </rs>, <rs id="t17620421-2-cd7" type="crimeDate">October 25, 1759.</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-2-off6 t17620421-2-cd7"></join>
               </p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-2-person47">
                  Robert 
                  Currie 
               <interp inst="t17620421-2-person47" type="surname" value="Currie"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-2-person47" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-2-person47" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17620421-2-crimeloc8">St. Martin's-street, Leicester-fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17620421-2-crimeloc8" type="placeName" value="St. Martin's-street, Leicester-fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17620421-2-crimeloc8" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-2-off6 t17620421-2-crimeloc8"></join>. The prisoner at the bar lodged at my house in October 1759; there was a bureau in the room where he lay, in which were the tankard, mug, and large soup spoon; it was kept locked. The six table spoons were in a case with some knives on a shelf in the same room.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you let the room ready furnished to the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Currie. No, he only paid for the bed.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see these things there last?</p>
               <p>Currie. I saw them in the bureau in the day time on the 24th of October 1759. I had a suspicion that he was not honest; and that night I double locked the street door, and took the key up to bed. In the morning we found the window upon the stairs open that looked into the street, and a lamp iron just by it, which was bent, I suppose, by his holding by it to let himself down. We went up to his room, and found the bureau door open, and he was gone; then I missed the things laid in the indictment, and have found neither of them since. After I had searched for him and could not find him, I went to justice Fielding, and had him described in the Public Advertiser, which was about the 26th. About a year, or a year and a half after, the prisoner sent me a letter,</p>
               <p>"That if I would</p>
               <p>"send for him from Doncaster gaol, and secure him</p>
               <p>"in any other gaol, he would make me satisfaction</p>
               <p>"for the injury he had done me; and the</p>
               <p>"sooner I sent the better." I found he was sentenced to be shot as a deserter.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the prisoner's hand writing?</p>
               <p>Currie. I do not, but my wife can speak to that. Justice Fielding has the letter; there was the prisoner's name to it; and I know not who could direct such a letter to me but himself. After that he was brought to the Savoy, I saw him on the last fast day in the morning, and charged him with taking the things here mentioned: he denied it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-2-person48">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Currie 
               <interp inst="t17620421-2-person48" type="surname" value="Currie"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-2-person48" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-2-person48" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the prosecutor. I was in the prisoner's room on the 24th of October 1759, and brought the candle down, and he locked the door after I went out of the room; this was about 10 o'clock, or a little after when he went to bed. I had been to the bureau; he saw me lock it: I then saw the silver tankard, mug, and soup spoon; they were all together: the silver table spoons were in a case on a shelf in the same room; he saw me examine them. I locked up the case which they were in, and took away the key which used to hang to it. Our dwelling-house door was double locked, and there was no other way out of the house, but by that door. In the morning I was up first to get the irons ready against the men came to work. I went up to the shop (the room above the prisoner's) he laid up two pair of stairs, his door stood a jar; I saw the bureau open; I missed the things mentioned; then I came down, and saw the window open over the door, and the lamp iron pulled down. He might go from that window upon the leads, and by the lamp iron get down easy; there had not been a living soul in the room but himself.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the letter your husband speaks of?</p>
               <p>Eliz. Currie. I did, and know it to be the prisoner's own hand writing. I have heard him dispute with another man who could write best. The contents of the letter were, if my husband would take him from that gaol to any other of his majesty's prisons, he should have the things again, or else satisfaction for the injury he had done us.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I acknowledge I lodged in the prosecutor's house, but I know nothing at all about the things.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. He said when before justice Fielding, he never lodged in my house.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was not in the house that night they speak of.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17620421-2-verdict9" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620421-2-verdict9" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17620421-2-punish10" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620421-2-punish10" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-2-defend43 t17620421-2-punish10"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
