<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17620114-3">
               <interp inst="t17620114-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620114-3" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620114-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17620114"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620114-3" type="date" value="17620114"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620114-3-off12-c40" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620114-3-defend45 t17620114-3-off12 t17620114-3-verdict14"></join>
         
               <p>51. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17620114-3-defend45" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Wright 
                  <interp inst="t17620114-3-defend45" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-3-defend45" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-3-defend45" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17620114-3-off12" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620114-3-off12" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-3-off12" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 40 pound weight of tobacco, value 20 s.
            </rs> the property of a certain person or certain persons unknown, <rs id="t17620114-3-cd13" type="crimeDate">Dec 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620114-3-off12 t17620114-3-cd13"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620114-3-person46">
                  James 
                  Mitchel 
               <interp inst="t17620114-3-person46" type="surname" value="Mitchel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-3-person46" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-3-person46" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am master of the ship Mary. There has been tobacco missing from on board at sundry times; I believe to the amount of four or five hundred pounds weight in the whole. I think there were some missing on the 18th of December; but I cannot particularly say whose property it was.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620114-3-person47">
                  Robert 
                  Pitt 
               <interp inst="t17620114-3-person47" type="surname" value="Pitt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-3-person47" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-3-person47" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a custom-house officer, and boarded on this ship on the 8th of December. On the 17th there came a coal lighterman with some coals, and asked for the custom-house officers. I and one of my partners were by the steerage; he did not know either of us by our names. He asked for 
               <persName id="t17620114-3-person48">
                  Thomas 
                  Scott 
               <interp inst="t17620114-3-person48" type="surname" value="Scott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-3-person48" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-3-person48" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I suppose, for he said, Tom, Tom, Tom, and he wanted 
               <persName id="t17620114-3-person49">
                  Robert 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17620114-3-person49" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-3-person49" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-3-person49" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; he said he had brought them some coals, and that they had spoke to him to bring them some; and said, if they did not answer, he would carry them back again. The mate and other people seemed to be pleased with them, as it was cold weather; they were hoisted over the ship side. Soon after 
               <persName id="t17620114-3-person50">
                  Robert 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17620114-3-person50" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-3-person50" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-3-person50" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17620114-3-person51">
                  Thomas 
                  Scott 
               <interp inst="t17620114-3-person51" type="surname" value="Scott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-3-person51" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-3-person51" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came on board; the lighterman knew them, and they knew him. They were asked into the cabbin, and drank a mug or two of slip; I left them in the cabbin, and went upon deck to take the marks and numbers of the tobacco. Nothing material happened that day. The next day, being Friday, about two or three in the afternoon, the ship was at work. I said to Wright and Scott, seeing tobacco<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176201140004"></xptr> lying about the hold, to go down and put it to-rights; sometimes a hogshead is broken.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Pitt. He was one of my partners, and so was Scott. 
               <persName id="t17620114-3-person52">
                  Thomas 
                  Scott 
               <interp inst="t17620114-3-person52" type="surname" value="Scott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-3-person52" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-3-person52" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             pulled off his coat, and went down into the hold for about an hour. I happened to go and fit upon a chest at the steerage; somebody knocked at the hatch; Wright was at the opposite hatch. He said, Take hold, Pitt. He took hold and lifted up one end of the hatch, that is, one half of it; up started Mr. Scott, with some hands of tobacco in his hands, holding them by his sides. I said, Scott, what is all this? what are you going to do now? He turned about, and said, D - n you, don't you think the men that brought you coals must not have a bit of tobacco. I said, I do not like these proceedings; I went to take the marks, and left Scott and Wright in the steerage. After the labourers had left work, 
               <persName id="t17620114-3-person53">
                  Robert 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17620114-3-person53" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-3-person53" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-3-person53" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             went on shore; it was then duskish; I was settling my book on the table in the cabbin; Scott came and sat by me, but he went out before I had done, The mate said to me, Mate, where are your partners? I went out and called Scott, but he did not answer. He and Wright came on board about 11 o'clock; they went to bed. I made up my bed in the boatswain's cabbin, there I found two slips of tobacco. The next morning the mate found the fore-hatch was broke open; I was called up; there was upwards of 40 pounds weight of tobacco missing; I taxed Mr. Scott pretty much with it; he said he knew nothing of the matter, and went on shore, and 
               <persName id="t17620114-3-person54">
                  Robert 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17620114-3-person54" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-3-person54" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-3-person54" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came on board. Scott at last did own to me, that he and Wright did carry a little tobacco on shore, and sold it; and said, Hold your tongue, Wright has got six shillings for you. I said, I know nothing of your affairs, I have no business with it. Scott said to Wright. Have you got any silver? Wright said, Yes, he believed he had: Because, said he, give Pitt six shillings. I said to them, If you have done any thing of this sort, be it to yourselves; I am surprized you should run the hazard of my bread and your own too?</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Pitt. This was on Saturday the 19th. Scott was taken up by a Warrant, and examined about some Indico. On the Tuesday morning two little boys, that were come from the Foundling Hospital, were in bed, one was telling the other what he had heard. Mr. Wright sprang out of bed, and came to me, and said, Pitt, what did you hear the boys say? They said, the captain and officer had been talking of taking up one other officer out of the ship. I said I can't tell what you must do, I would not be in your case for 500 l. He said, I have a good mind to go home. About two or three hours after, he seemed to be very uneasy, and said, One thing vexed him more than all the rest, and that was, that Scott saw him take the money for the tobacco. I said, You li e intirely under Scott's lash, and it will certainly come upon you. I asked him who bought the tobacco of him? He said, Darby Kerwick (I never saw the man). I said, As soon as he is taken, he will declare against you. He said, Kerwick is far enough out of the way.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Wright say he had taken any tobacco out of the ship.</p>
               <p>Pitt. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Whether Mr. Pitt did not know of my going from the ship that day about four o'clock?</p>
               <p>Pitt. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I went on shore about four, with the captain's servant and boy, and never returned till between seven and eight the next morning; and when I returned, they told me the hatches had been broke open; they never were locked but one night before that.</p>
               <p>Mitchell. When I came on board, I saw nobody but the evidence Mr. Pitt. I said, Where are your partners? Said he, There are Wright and Scott on the deck, and one is on board the lighter. Then he went on the deck, and called Scott. Then I asked for a light, and looked at the hatches, and saw them bolted, locked, and secure. I said, Keep a good look-out, for I am afraid something will happen. Then I went about my business.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mr. Bland. I belong to the custom-house: I have known the prisoner about 10 years: We are very nice about characters; we have had no complaint come before us against him before this affair, and we have examined a good deal into it, and am sorry to say things have appeared to us bad against him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620114-3-person55">
                  Henry 
                  Meriden 
               <interp inst="t17620114-3-person55" type="surname" value="Meriden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-3-person55" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-3-person55" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am captain of a ship; the prisoner has been on board me as an officer, and has very often had my keys; I always found him an honest man.</p>
               <p>Benjamin Hill. I have known him 12 or 14 years, I never heard any ill of him before this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620114-3-person56">
                  John 
                  Dolley 
               <interp inst="t17620114-3-person56" type="surname" value="Dolley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-3-person56" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-3-person56" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him ten or a dozen years; he has a very good character, I never heard any ill of him in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620114-3-person57">
                  Richard 
                  Kingdom 
               <interp inst="t17620114-3-person57" type="surname" value="Kingdom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-3-person57" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620114-3-person57" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have been acquainted with him eight or ten years; I always looked upon him to be a very honest sober man.</p>
               <p>Mr. Wallis. I have known him about 12 years; his behaviour has been that of an honest man.</p>
               <p>Mr. Nightingale. I have known him six or seven years; I never knew any thing of him but what was very honest.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17620114-3-verdict14" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620114-3-verdict14" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
