<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610506-15">
               <interp inst="t17610506-15" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610506-15" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610506-15" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610506"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610506-15" type="date" value="17610506"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610506-15-off79-c153" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-15-defend178 t17610506-15-off79 t17610506-15-verdict81"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610506-15-off79-c154" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-15-defend179 t17610506-15-off79 t17610506-15-verdict81"></join>
         
               <p>171, 172. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610506-15-defend178" type="defendantName">
                     David 
                     Morgan 
                  <interp inst="t17610506-15-defend178" type="surname" value="Morgan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-defend178" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-defend178" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               <persName id="t17610506-15-defend179" type="defendantName">
                  William 
                  Dupuy 
               <interp inst="t17610506-15-defend179" type="surname" value="Dupuy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-defend179" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-defend179" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , were indicted, for <rs id="t17610506-15-off79" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-off79" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-off79" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that they, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17610506-15-victim181" type="victimName">
                           Ralph 
                           Dobinson 
                        <interp inst="t17610506-15-victim181" type="surname" value="Dobinson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610506-15-victim181" type="given" value="Ralph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610506-15-victim181" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-15-off79 t17610506-15-victim181"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , on the king's highway, did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and taking from his person one silver watch, gilt, value 40 s. and one 36 shilling piece of gold, the property of the said Ralph, against his will
            </rs>, <rs id="t17610506-15-cd80" type="crimeDate">April 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-15-off79 t17610506-15-cd80"></join>.*</p> 
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-15-person182">
                  Ralph 
                  Waayne 
               <interp inst="t17610506-15-person182" type="surname" value="Waayne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person182" type="given" value="Ralph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person182" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Since I have been confined in Newgate, to be an evidence here, Mrs. Degoe, a prisoner, has given me a stab in my side.</p>
               <p>Q. Were any of the prisoner's present?</p>
               <p>Wayne. They were not.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you look upon it to be done by their instigation?</p>
               <p>Wayne. I cannot say it was.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you first become acquainted with the prisoners?</p>
               <p>Wayne. I became acquainted with Mr. Dupuy about the 6th of February last, and with Morgan the latter end of that month. We were several times together at 
               <persName id="t17610506-15-person183">
                  Bob 
                  Derry 
               <interp inst="t17610506-15-person183" type="surname" value="Derry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person183" type="given" value="Bob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person183" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is that?</p>
               <p>Wayne. It is a house in Charles-street, Covent-garden, a very bad house.</p>
               <p>Q. Give an account what happened on the eighth of October?</p>
               <p>Wayne. On the eighth of October, about two o'clock, or between two and three, the two prisoners and I all set out from Morgan's cousin's in the city. We had not money enough to buy pistols, Dupuy pawn'd my coat to a pawnbroker, Morgan and I staid at a publick-house the while in St. Paul's Church-yard. I sold a bible in Fleet-street, to a bookseller, on the right hand side, which made 12 s. we went up Holbourn, and on Holbourn-hill Dupuy bought a pistol for 5 s. of a man that kept a little stall in the street, and at a cloath's shop on the other side of Red-lion-street, in Holbourn, Morgan bought another pistol, I laid down the money for it, that cost 5 s.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was Dupuy at that time?</p>
               <p>Wayne. He was then with us in the shop; then we went to Mr. Bulcock's, and hired two horses, we said we were going to Blackwall.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of horses were they?</p>
               <p>Wayne. One was a roan horse, the other a dark bay gelding; we were all three together in the yard, Mr. Bulcock himself let us them.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to hire but two horses, and you were three persons?</p>
               <p>Wayne. Because we did not think it proper to hire all at one place. We directly proceeded into Gray's inn-lane, to the Queen's head, and ordered them to be got ready by four in the afternoon of that day. I hired another horse at the Queen's-head. it was a light bay one, with cropped ears. I left the two prisoners at the head of the yard, while I ordered the ostler to saddle him, and took him away to an alehouse, by Holbourn-bars; they followed me there; we then left Morgan there with the cropt horse, and I and Dupuy went directly to Mr. Bulcocks', and fetched the other two horses.</p>
               <p>Q. What time might this be?</p>
               <p>Wayne. This might be about half an hour past three in the afternoon.</p>
               <p>Q. What was your intention in buying the two pistols, and hiring the horses?</p>
               <p>Wayne. To go out a robbing, that was agreed upon by us all. Dupuy and I came to the corner of Red-lion-street, where is another publick house, and I left Dupuy with the horses there, and went and fetched Morgan with the other horse; then we all joined company directly, we went through Gray's-inn-lane.</p>
               <p>Q. Who had the pistols?</p>
               <p>Wayne. Morgan had a long pistol, like a horse-pistol; and Dupuy had the other. I had no pistol, we went through the turnpike, and up to Islington, and there at the Cock and Crown we stopt, and had a shillingsworth of punch, and some biscuit and cheese, and a two-penny glass of brandy each; and at the same place, Morgan<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176105060020"></xptr> and Dupuy loaded their pistols; and Morgan borrowed three or four pins of the gentlewoman of the house, to pin their crapes with into their hats.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by crapes?</p>
               <p>Wayne. That they had over their faces when they robbed, to conceal.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any crape in your hat?</p>
               <p>Wayne. No, I had none.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you stay at this house?</p>
               <p>Wayne. About half an hour, we set out from thence about five o'clock, and took the road through Highgate, and strait to Finchley-common, on the common the two prisoners stopt a young lady in her chariot.</p>

               <p>Court. Keep to the robbery they are now charged with.</p>
               <p>Wayne. After that, there were two post-chaises coming along, one about 300 yards before the other. Morgan rode up to the first, and ordered the boy to stand, I was then a little behind.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was Dupuy?</p>
               <p>Wayne. He was riding up with Morgan, the boy was going down a sort of a hill, and he could not stop the chaise directly. Morgan being at the horses heads, the end of the shaft ran against him, and tore his breeches, and tore him from his horse, and daubed his coat, I believe that chaise was empty; the boy drove on, the blinds were up. Morgan got up, and said, he would stop the other chaise, be the consequence what it would, and Dupuy and he rode directly up to the other chaise, and bid them to stop.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>Wayne. This might be six, seven, or eight o'clock, it was just dusk?</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you when they stopt that chaise?</p>
               <p>Wayne. I was behind it, may be 50 or 60 yards.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you nigh enough to see what past?</p>
               <p>Wayne. I was, the boy stopt, and Mr. Dobinson directly put a blunderbuss out of the window, and directed it to Morgan's breast. When the chaise stopt, Morgan was on one side, and Dupuy on the other.</p>
               <p>Q. Which side was morgan on?</p>
               <p>Wayne. He was on the right-hand as we met the chaise, our backs being towards Highgate, so properly he was on Mr. Dobinson's left hand as he came towards London.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you take upon you to say, who it was that presented the blunderbuss?</p>
               <p>Wayne. I can't say; it was on that side that Morgan was on, I believe it was Mr. Dobinson, the person ordered Morgan to keep off, or else he would shoot him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you near enough to hear that?</p>
               <p>Wayne. I was, Morgan answered, d - m you, shoot away.</p>
               <p>Q. Had Morgan any crape over his face then?</p>
               <p>Wayne. No, he had not put his crape down, Dupuy had his over his face, the gentleman seeing Morgan would not go off, pull'd the trigger, and it flashed in the pan, but did not go off. With that I rode up quite close to the chaise, and as soon as I came up to the chaise, the person that had the blunderbuss was down on his knees in the chaise, and begged he would not take his life away. Then the two gentlemen in the chaise delivered each a watch, and a light 36 s piece, and some other money to Morgan. One of the watches was a mettal one, with a shagreen case, with a ribband to it. The other silver gilt, with a steel seal ingraved.</p>
               <p>Q. Should you know the watches again was you to see them?</p>
               <p>Wayne. I should. After this, we directly proceeded the nearest way for London, all three over Enfield-chase. We came about two miles and a half, or three miles, and asked a man the nearest way to Edmonton, it was before we came to the chaise we met that man. He told us to go over the chase, and shewed us the way; and said, as it was dark, and such a wet night, we should have difficulty in finding the way, there had been a great deal of rain that day; we was on the chase an hour and a half, having lost our way, it rained very hard all the time. At last we saw a light at a window of a little house, we went to the light; it happened to be at a farmer's house, we hallooed, a man came out; we told him if he would show us the way into the road for Edmonton, we would give him a shilling a piece; he came with us about a hundred yards, we asked if there was ever a publick house near; he said, there was one very nigh; we all went to it, and he along with us; this house was at the side of the chase.</p>
         
               <p>***The Last Part of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17610506-15">
                  <interp inst="t17610506-15" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610506-15" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610506-15" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610506"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610506-15" type="date" value="17610506"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176105060021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commission of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 6th, Thursday the 7th, and Friday the 8th of MAY.</p>
                  <p>In the first Year of His MAJESTY's Reign. Being the Fifth SESSION in the MAYORALTY of The Right Honble Sir 
                  <persName id="t17610506-15-person184">
                     Matthew 
                     Blakiston 
                  <interp inst="t17610506-15-person184" type="surname" value="Blakiston"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610506-15-person184" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610506-15-person184" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Knt. LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>NUMBER V. PART II. for the YEAR 1761.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by J. SCOTT, at the Black-Swan, in Pater-noster Row.</p>
                  <p>M. DCC. LXI.</p>
                  <p>[Price FOUR-PENCE.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176105060022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commission of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery held for the City of London, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Q. WHAT was the sign?</p>
               <p>Wayne. I cannot justly say what sign, we called for the ostler, and put up the three horses, and went into the house, and had a shilling or 18 d. in punch, and some bread and cheese, and a glass of brandy a piece; and the man that shewed us the way from the farmer's house, we gave him six-pence and a pint of beer for his trouble, he staid the time we did.</p>
               <p>Q. How long might you all stay?</p>
               <p>Wayne. I believe we staid three quarters of an hour; after that, there was a fisher-man there that said, if we would take him behind us, he would shew us the way to Edmonton. At that house the maid scraped Morgan's coat, which was daubed when the chaise pulled him off his horse, and throwed him down in the dirt; it was not dry enough to be brushed. We ordered the horses to the door, it may be about nine o'clock, the fish-man got up on the roan horse behind Dupuy; then we proceeded along Enfield-chase, and went thro' the Chase gate, a woman opened it. The fish-man said to us, this is a friend of mine, give her a few halfpence; then we went into the main road, and going along to Edmonton, we met a lady's coach. Dupuy rode by it, and Morgan and I stopped the coach, and took from the people four purses: Dupuy was about a hundred yards before us, we overtook him and the fish-man in about 300 yards farther, then we joined company again. Dupuy said, how fare you? to us. We said, never better. Then we went on a little farther, and when we got near the fishman's house, he got off from behind Dupuy, and as he was going away, Dupuy called him back, and said, let's shake hands with you pilot before you go; the fish-man turned again, and shook hands with him. Then we came directly the main road to London, and got to the Queen's head in Gray's-inn-lane, about a quarter past 11 o'clock, there I left my horse, the two prisoners staid at the door while I delivered him. After that, I walked on foot to Mr. Bulcock's in Theobald's-row with them; as soon as I came within 20 yards of his house, I took Morgan's horse from him, and rode into the yard on him, and delivered him to the ostler, and Dupuy delivered his horse, which was the roan one. After that, we went to Robinson's bagnio in Prince's-street, Covent-garden, there we had a supper together, and a girl a piece. There Morgan sent out his coat to be scoured by the waiter, and ordered the same waiter to buy him a pair of breeches in the morning. We sat up till about 12 o'clock, then went to bed; the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176105060023"></xptr> waiter took Dupuy's coat to clean, and there came some powder and shot out of his pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. How came Dupuy to pull off his coat?</p>
               <p>Wayne. Because we were all very wet.</p>
               <p>Q. Who had the two watches?</p>
               <p>Wayne. Dupuy had one, and Morgan the other; I had one in my pocket when I first went in, but Dupuy took it, and had it all night, and in the morning he wound it up in the bed, as we had coffee by the bed side. After that, I pawned them both the next day in the evening, one in Bedford-row, near Featherstone-buildings. the other at a pawnbroker's in Holbourn. I pawned them for a guinea and half each.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body go with you?</p>
               <p>Wayne. Morgan did, Dupuy was detained at the bagnio for something; he had been at the bagnio the Tuesday before, and he ran up a bill; but he knew of my going to pawn them; we went to get money to release him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-15-person185">
                  Ralph 
                  Dobinson 
               <interp inst="t17610506-15-person185" type="surname" value="Dobinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person185" type="given" value="Ralph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person185" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the eighth of April last, I and Mr. Aukland were in a post chaise coming over Finchley-common toward London, in the dusk of the evening, about seven or eight o'clock, I sat on the right side the chaise, the windows were up, something jostled against the window. Mr. Aukland called halloo, what is the matter. I saw immediately a man ride by the horses from the right hand side, Mr. Aukland let down his glass, the person went back from the right, and came on the other side (it rained, and was a very wet and dirty night) he rode to the sash with a pistol in his hand. I presented a loaded plunderbuss at him, and bid him keep off; his pistol I saw plain, it was a pretty long one, he did not at all attempt to ride off; I pulled the trigger, the blunderbuss flashed in the pan, but did not go off.</p>
               <p>Q. How many men did you see?</p>
               <p>Dobinson. I saw but one man; seeing fire, he rather went towards the hind wheel of the chaise, and came up again immediately, and put his pistol in the chaise, and demanded our money and watches. He took from me a silver watch, gilt, with a steel chain and seal, a 36 s. piece, and some silver. He took from Mr. Aukland a shagreen metal watch, and 16 or 17 shillings in silver. The blind on my side was up all the time, I believe it was a small pane of glass in the blind, as many post-chaises have.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any thing over the person's face?</p>
               <p>Dobinson. I cannot take upon me to say whether there was or not. I remember he had no boots on, he had a dark coloured horse, and the man was very dirty, as if he had fell down.</p>
               <p>Q. to Wayne. Had either of you boots on?</p>
               <p>Wayne. Morgan and Dupuy had not, only I myself had; Morgan had then the same cloaths on, as he has on now.</p>
               <p>Dobinson After he had taken my money, he put the pistol to my breast, and said, you fired a blunderbuss at me, and I have a good mind to shoot you. I said, I beg your pardon, and desire you would desist. He went off, and I saw no more of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Which way did he ride?</p>
               <p>Dobinson. He went off towards Barnet, on the farther side the common.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-15-person186">
                  John 
                  Ashburnham 
               <interp inst="t17610506-15-person186" type="surname" value="Ashburnham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person186" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person186" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . (He produces a watch.)</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. Look at this watch.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. This is my property, the watch I was robbed of that night; when I lost it, there was a seal to it, with a coat of arms on it, which is not here now.</p>
               <p>Ashburnham. It is in the same condition I received it in.</p>
               <p>Mr. Aukland. I was in company with Mr. Dobinson in the post-chaise, on the eighth of April.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you heard the account he has given in court.</p>
               <p>Aukland. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any more persons than one at that time?</p>
               <p>Aukland. I saw the other two at the other window.</p>
               <p>Q. On which side was you?</p>
               <p>Aukland. I was on the left-side the chaise, the first I saw was a man looking in at the window, I cried halloo, what do you want? I apprehended he was bidding the boy stop, I saw him pull a pistol out of his right-hand coat pocket. I heard him say to the boy, he would shoot him; the boy stopt, he went round the horses heads, and came to the side I was on.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe his horse?</p>
               <p>Aukland. He was on a dark bay or brown horse, the darkest colour of the three; I saw all three very plain Mr. Dobinson attempted to fire, and it only flashed in the pan; then the man came immediately, and put his pistol past my face to Mr. Dobinson's head, and said, he would shoot him for endeavouring to fire a gun. I endeavoured to keep the pistol from Mr. Dobinson's head, and desired he would take it away. He cried, your watch, your watch; I said, take your pistol away, and you shall have all I have.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176105060024"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-15-person187">
                  Joseph 
                  Watson 
               <interp inst="t17610506-15-person187" type="surname" value="Watson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person187" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person187" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . [Produced a watch in a shagreen case.]</p>
               <p>Wayne. I pawned this watch to Mr. Watson.</p>
               <p>Q. to Aukland. Look at this watch?</p>
               <p>Aukland. This is what I was robbed of that evening, my property.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the man's face covered?</p>
               <p>Aukland. No, it was not. He came close to me, when he e ndeavoured to come to get to Mr. Dobinson's head. He was very dusty, and looked to me as if he had had a tumble a little before. He had no boots on but a pair of dusty breeches.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know that person?</p>
               <p>Aukland. I can't take upon me to say who it was; he was then very dirty, and it rained very hard at the time. The other two persons were both on horseback. One of them had a pistol I am sure.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe their horses?</p>
               <p>Aukland. One of them I took to be a gray. I saw them all three riding at a great rate.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-15-person188">
                  Joseph 
                  Tompson 
               <interp inst="t17610506-15-person188" type="surname" value="Tompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person188" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person188" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . In April last I lived at a bagnio in Prince's-street, Covent garden. I know the two prisoners and evidence very well.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see them altogether in company before the 8th of April last?</p>
               <p>Tompson. Yes, I saw them all together the Monday before that.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they appear to be acquainted with one another?</p>
               <p>Tompson. They did. They all supped together that Monday night as companions together, and lay at our house, and went away together in the morning.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-15-person189">
                  William 
                  Bulcock 
               <interp inst="t17610506-15-person189" type="surname" value="Bulcock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person189" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person189" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Theobald's-row. On the 8th of April, about three in the afternoon, there came three persons to hire two horses, to go to Blackwall.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at the prisoners.</p>
               <p>Bulcock. I cannot recollect either of their faces. I never saw them before that time to my knowledge. They hired the horses for seven shillings, and desired them to be got ready by four o'clock. I was not at home when they were delivered.</p>
               <p>Q. What coloured horses were they?</p>
               <p>Bulcock. One was a brown, and the other a roan. I was in bed when they returned. I remember one of the men said his name was Wayne, and he would see me paid. I said I know your mother very well. When I saw them the second time, I thought I could recollect him.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your belief now?</p>
               <p>Bulcock. Now I believe him to be one of the three men.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-15-person190">
                  George 
                  Litton 
               <interp inst="t17610506-15-person190" type="surname" value="Litton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person190" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person190" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I remember three persons coming to hire two horses of my matter, Mr. Bulcock. I cannot recollect but one of them, and that is the evidence.</p>
               <p>Q. What time were the horses called for?</p>
               <p>Litton. They were called for about 5 o'clock. One was a roan, and the other a brown one.</p>
               <p>Q. Who took them away?</p>
               <p>Litton. The evidence was one of them. I do not recollect the other.</p>
               <p>Q. What reason have you to recollect him better than the other two?</p>
               <p>Litton. Because he had been at our house before, to hire a horse?</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember the return of the horses in the evening?</p>
               <p>Litton. I do. It was a little before twelve at night. The evidence was one that brought them back. They were in a great hurry to get away, that I did not observe them. I remember it was a very rainy night, and they appeared to me to be very dirty when they came home.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they hot?</p>
               <p>Litton. No; they were not very hot.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-15-person191">
                  Mary 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17610506-15-person191" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person191" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person191" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Cock and Crown, at Islington. I remember three men coming to my house, on the 8th of April, on horseback.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day?</p>
               <p>M. Wright. It was about 5 or 6 in the afternoon, as near as I can guess.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you recollect any of them?</p>
               <p>M. Wright. I can't say that I remember any of them?</p>
               <p>Q. What coloured horses did they ride?</p>
               <p>M. Wright. I did not take particular notice of their horses. They had some brandy and water, biscuits and cheese, and a quartern of brandy.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any of them ask you for any thing, can you recollect?</p>
               <p>M. Wright. I gave one of them two or three pins. He came out of the other room to me, into the kitchen, for them.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what use he made of them.</p>
               <p>M. Wright. I do not. He went again into the other room with them, to his company, and shut the door to.</p>
               <p>Q. How long might they stay at your house?</p>
               <p>M. Wright. They might stay at my house about half an hour.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-15-person192">
                  Ann 
                  Nash 
               <interp inst="t17610506-15-person192" type="surname" value="Nash"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person192" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person192" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the crown on Enfield-chase.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember three men coming to your house, on the 8th of April, on horseback?</p>
               <p>A. Nash. I do. They were wet and dirty. It was on a Wednesday night.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176105060025"></xptr>Q. What time of the night?</p>
               <p>A. Nash. To the best of my knowledge it was between 8 and 9 o'clock. They offered a shilling each man for a man to go with them, to shew them the way to the London road.</p>
               <p>Q. What is that man's name?</p>
               <p>A. Nash. His name is 
               <persName id="t17610506-15-person193">
                  Thomas 
                  Sheffield 
               <interp inst="t17610506-15-person193" type="surname" value="Sheffield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person193" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person193" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He came with them to my house.</p>
               <p>Q. How did the men appear?</p>
               <p>A. Nash. They appeared very dirty. One of them was a shortish man, in a lightish coloured coat. Whether it was a surtout coat, or not, I cannot say, it was buttoned close about his body.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at the evidence Wayne. Do you know him?</p>
               <p>A. Nash. If he was there he had then a wig on.</p>
               <p>Q. to Wayne. Did you wear your own hair then? [His hair was just long enough to go without a wig.]</p>
               <p>Wayne. I then had a wig on.</p>
               <p>A. Nash. To the best of my knowledge they were the same three persons, the two prisoners and evidence. I cannot be sure, but I really believe them to be the same.</p>
               <p>Q. What liquor had they?</p>
               <p>A Nash. They had a glass of brandy each, and a shilling in punch.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did they stay;</p>
               <p>A. Nash. They staid about three quarters of an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body go with them from your house?</p>
               <p>A. Nash. Yes; one 
               <persName id="t17610506-15-person194">
                  William 
                  Brice 
               <interp inst="t17610506-15-person194" type="surname" value="Brice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person194" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person194" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a fish-man.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was your servant at that time?</p>
               <p>A. Nash. Dorothy Crowther was.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-15-person195">
                  Dorothy 
                  Crowther 
               <interp inst="t17610506-15-person195" type="surname" value="Crowther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person195" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person195" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lived at Mrs. Nash's, at the Crown, on Enfield-chace.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you on the 8th of April last?</p>
               <p>D. Crowther. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember what happened on that day?</p>
               <p>D. Crowther. There came three men together on horseback.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what colour their horses were?</p>
               <p>D. Crowther. I did not take notice of that?</p>
               <p>Q. Do you recollect the colour of any of the mens cloaths?</p>
               <p>D. Crowther. One of them gave me a coat to clean. It was a blackish colour, or a dark-gray.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at the prisoners.</p>
               <p>D. Crowther. I remember something of that man's face. (Pointing at Dupuy.)</p>
               <p>Q. Was it his coat that you cleaned?</p>
               <p>D. Crowther. No, it was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at the evidence Wayne. Do you know him?</p>
               <p>D. Crowther. He had then a wig on if he was one of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember enough of Dupuy's face to be sure he was one of them?</p>
               <p>D. Crowther. I do verily believe he was one of them.</p>
               <p>Q. How was the dirt upon the coat?</p>
               <p>D. Crowther. It seemed to me as if it was dirt got by a fall.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you clean it?</p>
               <p>D. Crowther. I scrap'd it, and cleaned it as well as I could.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body go with them when they went away?</p>
               <p>D. Crowther. One 
               <persName id="t17610506-15-person196">
                  William 
                  Brice 
               <interp inst="t17610506-15-person196" type="surname" value="Brice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person196" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person196" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             did. He went behind one of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was ostler at your house at that time?</p>
               <p>D. Crowther. Jos. Freeman was.</p>
               <p>Jos. Freeman. I was ostler at the Crown, at Enfield, in April last.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember any body coming to your house, on the 8th of April, in the evening?</p>
               <p>Freeman. I do. I remember the evidence's face, he was one of them; and I remember that person being another of them. (Pointing to Dupuy.) There were three of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at the other-prisoner Morgan. Do you remember ever seeing him?</p>
               <p>Freeman. I do not recollect him.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they on foot, or on horseback?</p>
               <p>Freeman. They were on horseback. I took their horses in when they dismounted.</p>
               <p>Q. What colour were their horses?</p>
               <p>Freeman. To the best of my remembrance, one was a bay cropped gelding, the other a gray, the other a dark colour, but I cannot particularly speak to him. They came together, and went away together, and 
               <persName id="t17610506-15-person197">
                  William 
                  Brice 
               <interp inst="t17610506-15-person197" type="surname" value="Brice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person197" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person197" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             went with them, in order to put them into the high road.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-15-person198">
                  William 
                  Brice 
               <interp inst="t17610506-15-person198" type="surname" value="Brice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person198" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person198" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a fish-man. I remember I went away with three persons on horseback, from the Crown, at Enfield, on the 8th of April, at night.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you recollect either of them?</p>
               <p>Brice. I cannot recollect one of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you drunk or sober?</p>
               <p>Brice. I was a little in liquor. I rode behind one of them. His hair was tied with a pig-tail, and he rode a gray or a roan horse.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe the man's face?</p>
               <p>Brice. I do not know that I minded his face.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176105060026"></xptr>Q. from a Juryman. Whether you remember your parting with the other two after you mounted behind that man?</p>
               <p>Brice. Yes, I do, that was, the other two stopped behind; the gentleman that I rode behind always kept first. We met a coach on Palmer's Green. The other two that were behind rode about 200 yards down Hedge-lane, and came back again: I believe they had made a mistake in the way. I hallooed as loud as I could, when we came up on the top of the lane; then I saw the other two come galloping from where the coach went; and when they came to us, the gentleman that I was behind said, How do you do? They said, Never better.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17610506-15-person199">
                  Joseph 
                  Tompson 
               <interp inst="t17610506-15-person199" type="surname" value="Tompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person199" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person199" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Do you remember seeing the two prisoners and evidence on the 8th of April?</p>
               <p>Tompson. I saw them on the Thursday morning, the 9th, at our house; they came in on the 8th at night, but I did not let them in, but they lay there that night. I went to dun Dupuy for a reckoning that he had left before. The evidence and he lay together. The evidence told me when I went to them, if I would have patience, he would see me paid before he went away. Dupuy had given me a note of hand for it the day before. Dupuy was then winding up this silver gilt watch. [He takes it in his hand.] This is the same, I took particular notice of it as he turned it over and over. To the best of my remembrance there was a little padlock-key on the watch. The other watch, with a shagreen case, lay on the ground: I took it up. [He looks at the metal watch in a shagreen case.] There may be two things like one another, but I think this is the same watch. Mr. Dupuy bid me go down to Mr. Morgan, and ask him what he would have for dinner. I went to Mr. Morgan, and there I saw it lying on the ground. I took it up, and laid it on his bed; it was just as now, with a black ribbon and key. I remember they had no watches the night before, the 8th.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did they go away?</p>
               <p>Tompson. The other two went away about four o'clock, Dupuy staid; they promised me, upon their honour, they would come and pay me the money that he owed. I remember Morgan's cloaths hanging to dry by the fire, and he desired me to clean them, but they were not dry enough to brush. His coat seemed all over dusty, as if he had been down in the dirt. I took Dupuy's coat to clean, and I remember there were some shot fell out of the pockets.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any gunpowder?</p>
               <p>Tompson. No, I did not observe that, but the pockets were black, as if there had been powder in them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-15-person200">
                  Alexander 
                  Watts 
               <interp inst="t17610506-15-person200" type="surname" value="Watts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person200" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person200" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know all the three prisoners very well.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Watts. I am servant at the bagnio.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the prisoners and evidence ever all together, and when?</p>
               <p>Watts. I saw them all at the bagnio on the Monday night before the 8th of April.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they appear to be acquainted with one another?</p>
               <p>Watts. They did, they appeared to be acquaintance, and were all in one company.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember seeing them on the 8th?</p>
               <p>Watts. I do, they came altogether in the evening.</p>
               <p>Q. What time in the evening?</p>
               <p>Watts. As near as I can remember between 12 and one at night. I think the evidence and Morgan came in first, and Dupuy about five minutes after. The evidence had boots on, but the other two had not.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the evidence a wig on?</p>
               <p>Watts. He had at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. How did their cloaths appear?</p>
               <p>Watts. Morgan was very dirty; I believe he had on the same coat as now. He desired it to be cleaned. I took it to dry by the fire, but could not get it clean, and was obliged to send it to the scowerer's. His breeches were torn on the left-thigh, and very dirty. I bought him a pair of breeches.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he stay at the bagnio?</p>
               <p>Watts. They staid all night.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they say where they had been?</p>
               <p>Watts. They said they had been at Blackwall; I heard them all three say so: they said they had been on board a ship, drinking of punch; and I think Morgan said, he had had a fall from his horse.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any watches they had?</p>
               <p>Watts. I saw two of them pull out watches, but I had them not in my hand.</p>
               <p>Q Which had watches?</p>
               <p>Watts. I think the evidence had one, but I am not sure.</p>
               <p>Q. to Ashburnham. How came you by this silver-gilt watch?</p>
               <p>Ashburnham. The evidence Wayne brought and pledged it with me.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176105060027"></xptr>Q. to Watson. How came you by the shagreen watch?</p>
               <p>Watson. It was brought by a slender young man~ on the 9th of April.</p>
               <p>~ Such was 
               <persName id="t17610506-15-person201">
                  Wayne
               <interp inst="t17610506-15-person201" type="given" value="Wayne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person201" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the evidence.</p>
               <p>Q. What name was it pledged in?</p>
               <p>Watson. It was left in the name of Wayne.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he any body with him, or was he alone?</p>
               <p>Watson. He was alone.</p>
               <p>Matthew Odell. I know both the prisoners and Wayne. Dupuy's uncle lived just by me, and he often came to see his uncle. I remember he was tried at Kingston assizes.</p>
               <p>Court. Confine yourself to the present indictment.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen them all three together since Kingston assizes?</p>
               <p>Odell. I have, but cannot say the time to a week or two: I remember he once told me his two conforts were in Hertford goal.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know who he meant?</p>
               <p>Odell. He told me their names, Morgan and Wayne. I said, What the gentlemen that were over with you at Mr. Silvester's, where your uncle lodged? He said, yes.</p>
               <p>Q. When was it he told you this?</p>
               <p>Odell. This was the Tuesday before he was taken. He was pressed on board a ship the next day, being Wednesday.</p>
               <p>Q. How long ago?</p>
               <p>Odell. I believe about a month ago.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-15-person202">
                  Robert 
                  Dabage 
               <interp inst="t17610506-15-person202" type="surname" value="Dabage"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person202" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person202" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was my lord-mayor's officer. I went and fetched Dupuy from on board of a ship on the 18th of April.</p>
               <p>Mr. Beckworth. I belong to the army, we were told by two gentlemen, that they had been robbed; I think it was between five and six o'clock on the Monday, the 10th of April last. We went as directed after them, and took Morgan and Wayne. We overtook them between Hertford and Ware: they were both committed to Hertford goal.</p>
               <p>Morgan's Defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing of what I am charged with.</p>
               <p>Dupuy's Defence.</p>
               <p>I never robbed Mr. Dobinson; I did go out with them, but I went a head of them a considerable way.</p>
               <p>For Dupuy.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-15-person203">
                  William 
                  Steward 
               <interp inst="t17610506-15-person203" type="surname" value="Steward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person203" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-person203" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a shipwright in his majesty's yard at Portsmouth, I knew Dupuy ever since he was born.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Steward. I never heard any misdemeanor of him before this affair happened.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you known him lately?</p>
               <p>Steward. I have not seen him before last Tuesday these five years.</p>
               <p>Q. What was he?</p>
               <p>Steward. He was purser of a man of war.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17610506-15-verdict81" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-verdict81" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17610506-15-punish82" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610506-15-punish82" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-15-defend178 t17610506-15-punish82"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-15-defend179 t17610506-15-punish82"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
