<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640912-46">
               <interp inst="t17640912-46" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-46" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-46" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640912"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-46" type="date" value="17640912"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640912-46-off258-c342" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-46-defend434 t17640912-46-off258 t17640912-46-verdict262"></join>
         
               <p>529. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17640912-46-defend434" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Robinson 
                  <interp inst="t17640912-46-defend434" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-46-defend434" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-46-defend434" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for that <rs id="t17640912-46-off258" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-46-off258" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-46-off258" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he, on the King's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640912-46-victim436" type="victimName">
                           Charles 
                           Downs 
                        <interp inst="t17640912-46-victim436" type="surname" value="Downs"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640912-46-victim436" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640912-46-victim436" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-46-off258 t17640912-46-victim436"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and violently taking from his person, one silk handkerchief, value 2 s. eleven guineas, and three shillings in money, his property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17640912-46-cd259" type="crimeDate">September 6</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-46-off258 t17640912-46-cd259"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-46-person437">
                  Charles 
                  Downs 
               <interp inst="t17640912-46-person437" type="surname" value="Downs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-46-person437" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-46-person437" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17640912-46-viclabel260" type="occupation">sea-faring man, in the merchant's service</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-46-victim436 t17640912-46-viclabel260"></join>. I never knew the prisoner before last Thursday was se'nnight; that day I was coming from Ratcliff-highway, and going towards Saltpetre-bank, in the night, between eleven and twelve o'clock, alone: the last house I was in, was the Boatswain and Call, in Ratcliff-highway. When I came on the Bank, at the corner of the house, by a post, there was the prisoner and three women; they asked me where I was going? I told them to the Black-boy, to get some beer.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was this from the Black Boy?</p>
               <p>Downs. It was about half a furlong, or not so far: they asked me if I would give them any beer? I said, yes, if they would go along with me: one of the women took me by the arm, and the prisoner walked after me. He stepped before me; I went to stop at the second door, facing the Glasshouse, but they would not let me: that woman and he pulled me down; I cried out, and the woman clapped her hand over my mouth, that I should not make a noise; he had hold on me at the time; I got up again, and we walked along till we came to the <placeName id="t17640912-46-crimeloc261">Black-Boy</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640912-46-crimeloc261" type="placeName" value="Black-Boy"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640912-46-crimeloc261" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-46-off258 t17640912-46-crimeloc261"></join>; and, instead of letting me go into the house, they dragged me into the alley, that goes into the yard, on the back part of the house: they got me into the necessary-house, and got me down: they were all in company.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is it from the enterance of the alley, to the necessary-house?</p>
               <p>Downs. It is about as far as this court-room is wide: they would have pulled my breeches off, but I would not let them. The prisoner put his hand into my right side pocket, and took out eleven guineas and some silver, three or four shillings.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176409120033"></xptr>Q. How near the enterance of the alley is the door of the house?</p>
               <p>Downs. That is close to the corner.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you perceive the door to be open?</p>
               <p>Downs. No; but I saw a light in the front of the house: I did not go by the window; the alley is before I came to the window.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you seen the eleven guineas last?</p>
               <p>Downs. I had them about nine o'clock the same night; I put them in a piece of paper, and put them into my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you by so much money?</p>
               <p>Downs. I was just come from a voyage, and had received 6 l. of it for wages that day, of 
               <persName id="t17640912-46-person438">
                  John 
                  Ware 
               <interp inst="t17640912-46-person438" type="surname" value="Ware"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-46-person438" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-46-person438" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I have the note here to shew. I had the other money along with me: I use the coal trade. After he got my money, he took me by the waistband of my breeches and the collar, to put me down the necessary-house: I catched hold of his hair, and pulled him down, and got upon him: the women turned me off again, and he got up, and he and the women walked away.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be so passive while he was taking the money?</p>
               <p>Downs. The women got hold of me, and held me.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is the necessary house from the alehouse?</p>
               <p>Downs. It is not the length of this room from it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you cry out, when you was by the side of the house?</p>
               <p>Downs. No, I did not. I did not think they were going to take my life then.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you call out, when in the necessary-house?</p>
               <p>Downs. Yes, I did; but then they clapped their hands upon my mouth.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you suppose were their intentions when they had you under them upon the ground, before you came there?</p>
               <p>Downs. I thought they were some whores, and that they wanted to get me into their house to lodge.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober?</p>
               <p>Downs. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do after they left you?</p>
               <p>Downs. Then I went into a house facing the back part of the Black-boy, and pulled my breeches and stockings off, and the people took and washed them. I did not go in at the Black-boy, till I had been in bed, and got my things cleaned: that might be about ten hours after. The next day, I took the prisoner in White Lyon street, Rosemary-lane; there was another man along with him, and two women: I took hold of him, and said, he was my prisoner. He went to strike at me, and asked me what I wanted with him? I said, he had robbed me. I let him go, and bid a man take care of him, while I went and got a constable: the people cry'd, Hold him fast, for he is an old offender. I went and got 
               <persName id="t17640912-46-person439">
                  Oliver 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17640912-46-person439" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-46-person439" type="given" value="Oliver"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-46-person439" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who took him into custody, and carried him to Justice Pell, who said, Are you come again? Pray where was you that night this man was robbed? he said, he was in a public house, and had a pint of beer; and after that, he walked about the streets all night: the prisoner asked me what cloaths he had on at the time? I said, he had on a white frock: he said he bought some cloaths the day after I said I was robbed. The justice asked him how he got the money? to which he made no answer.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it light or dark?</p>
               <p>Downs. The moon shone very bright, and it was star-light: I observed the face of the prisoner; I took great notice of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not the woman that led you along pick your pocket?</p>
               <p>Downs. No, she did not offer to do it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Downs. I believe I have seen him many times before, but I cannot be certain of that; yet I could have known him, was I to have seen him in the farthest part of the world, be he in what dress he would.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any of the women?</p>
               <p>Downs. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-46-person440">
                  Oliver 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17640912-46-person440" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-46-person440" type="given" value="Oliver"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-46-person440" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable. The prisoner was given in charge to me by the prosecutor last Friday: I carried him to Justice Pell; I searched him, and found but two-pence three farthings about him: he was committed, is all I know.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was drinking in Whitechapel. Coming down Red-lion-street, I met a couple of girls, and they ran down to this sailor: this gentleman came to me, and five or six sailors; they began to use me very ill: I said, can't you take me before the justice, or a constable. He took me to a house, where were five or six constables; they would not take me in charge. Mr. Smith took me in custody, and carried me before Mr. Pell.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640912-46-verdict262" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-46-verdict262" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty of the robbery in the necessary-house
            </rs>. <rs id="t17640912-46-punish263" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-46-punish263" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-46-defend434 t17640912-46-punish263"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>See him tried last Sessions, No. 415. for robbing 
               <persName id="t17640912-46-person441">
                  Robert 
                  Wittingdale 
               <interp inst="t17640912-46-person441" type="surname" value="Wittingdale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-46-person441" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-46-person441" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             on the highway.</p>
            </div1>
