<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660702-2">
               <interp inst="t17660702-2" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660702-2" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660702-2" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660702"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660702-2" type="date" value="17660702"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660702-2-off7-c36" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-2-defend39 t17660702-2-off7 t17660702-2-verdict11"></join>
         
               <p>333. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660702-2-defend39" type="defendantName">
                     Alexander 
                     Bourk 
                  <interp inst="t17660702-2-defend39" type="surname" value="Bourk"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-2-defend39" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-2-defend39" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for that <rs id="t17660702-2-off7" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660702-2-off7" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-2-off7" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               he on the <rs id="t17660702-2-cd8" type="crimeDate">17th of May</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-2-off7 t17660702-2-cd8"></join>, about the hour of one in the morning, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17660702-2-victim41" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Robinson 
                        <interp inst="t17660702-2-victim41" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660702-2-victim41" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660702-2-victim41" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-2-off7 t17660702-2-victim41"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did break and enter, and steal five hats, value 40 s. the property of the said Richard, in his dwelling-house
            </rs>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-2-person42">
                  Richard 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17660702-2-person42" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-2-person42" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-2-person42" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I <rs id="t17660702-2-viclabel9" type="occupation">keep a hatter's shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-2-victim41 t17660702-2-viclabel9"></join> upon <placeName id="t17660702-2-crimeloc10">Holborn-hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17660702-2-crimeloc10" type="placeName" value="Holborn-hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660702-2-crimeloc10" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-2-off7 t17660702-2-crimeloc10"></join>: on Saturday night the 17th of May, I went to bed a little after twelve o'clock, after fastening the doors and windows. On the Sunday morning about eight o'clock, I had occasion to go down into the cellar; I observed the cover of a box full of books was loose; then I went to see my hats, and found five were gone: I went to look at the street-door, and found the staples were drawn, and the door open. The next morning my next door neighbour's house was broke open and robbed, upon which Bourk was taken up; then the evidence Ashbridge was apprehended, said he had no concern in my neighbour's but he had in breaking mine; upon which to the prisoner, who was in custody, and said, I understand you have my hats, let me know where they are: he said he knew nothing of them; I offered him half a guinea, in case I could have them again. That evening he sent me a letter, mentioning, if I would come to him, he would let me know something about them; I went to him; he said, do you remember what you said last night; I said I would give him the half guinea, in case I had my hats, and offered him a shilling of it; he said, that will not do; I said, he should have the rest of the money when I had the things; he said it would do, and took the shilling: then he took me on one side, and told me, one of my hats was sold to a baker in Golden-lane for 4 s. 6 d. which was a hat that I made for a clergyman, and worth above 15 s. he told me, the other four were sold to a man named Cantrell, that buys stolen handkerchiefs, in Field-lane, for half a guinea; two were worth 15 s. each, and the other two 12 s. each. Then I applied to my Lord-Mayor for a search-warrant, to search his house; but before I got there, he was got off, and not to be found since; I went to the baker, and he readily delivered that hat up: (produced and deposed to, by a brand mark on the inside the crown.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-2-person43">
                  John 
                  Ashbridge 
               <interp inst="t17660702-2-person43" type="surname" value="Ashbridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-2-person43" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-2-person43" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner and I went together from the Globe on Saffron-hill, between eleven and twelve that Saturday night: we walked about till almost one; then we went to the prosecutor's street-door; he broke a piece of wood from the top of the door, and put his hand in, but could not reach the bolt: then he went to work and forced the door open; I was with him; then he went in, and staid there about a quarter of an hour, and brought out five hats and five books; the books were sold to a bookseller in Long-lane, by one 
               <persName id="t17660702-2-person44">
                  John 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17660702-2-person44" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-2-person44" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-2-person44" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who was to have all he got over a shilling for selling them. Davis and the prisoner carried the hats out, and would not let me go with them; I said at the Globe; when they came back, Bourk said they had sold one to a baker, and brought the other four back again: Bourk said, he had a good mind to cut them all to pieces; then he desired 
               <persName id="t17660702-2-person45">
                  William 
                  Welch 
               <interp inst="t17660702-2-person45" type="surname" value="Welch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-2-person45" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-2-person45" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to carry them, and sell them to Cantrell; Welsh came back, and brought in half a guinea, and said, he had sold them all four for that to him; we had 5 s. each, and Welch had 6 d. for his trouble.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know Cantrell?</p>
               <p>Ashbridge. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you been acquainted with Bourk?</p>
               <p>Ashbridge. About five weeks before we did this thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you first become acquainted with him?</p>
               <p>Ashbridge. At the Hog in Armour. There were 
               <persName id="t17660702-2-person46">
                  George 
                  Trotman 
               <interp inst="t17660702-2-person46" type="surname" value="Trotman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-2-person46" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-2-person46" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17660702-2-person47">
                  Samuel 
                  Trotman 
               <interp inst="t17660702-2-person47" type="surname" value="Trotman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-2-person47" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-2-person47" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17660702-2-person48">
                  William 
                  Scales 
               <interp inst="t17660702-2-person48" type="surname" value="Scales"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-2-person48" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-2-person48" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             with him. Bourk then wanted to persuade us to go upon the highway.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. How have you got your living?</p>
               <p>Ashbridge. Since I got into their company, I did as they did; but I'll go to my parents in Cumberland, as soon as I get clear here.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I never saw the baker in my life.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660702-2-verdict11" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660702-2-verdict11" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-2-verdict11" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder40s"></interp>
               Guilty of stealing the hats, value 39 s
            </rs>. <rs id="t17660702-2-punish12" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660702-2-punish12" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-2-defend39 t17660702-2-punish12"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>See him tried with 
               <persName id="t17660702-2-person49">
                  John 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17660702-2-person49" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-2-person49" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-2-person49" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , for forging an order for the delivery of plate at Goldsmiths-Hall, the property of a silversmith, to whom Bourk was apprentice, No 580, 581. in Mr. Alderman Bridgen's mayoralty.</p>
            </div1>
