<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17620526-19">
               <interp inst="t17620526-19" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620526-19" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620526-19" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17620526"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620526-19" type="date" value="17620526"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620526-19-off96-c167" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620526-19-defend198 t17620526-19-off96 t17620526-19-verdict99"></join>
         
               <p>172. 
               
                  <persName id="t17620526-19-defend198" type="defendantName">
                     Francisco 
                     Wilkins 
                  <interp inst="t17620526-19-defend198" type="surname" value="Wilkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-19-defend198" type="given" value="Francisco"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-19-defend198" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for the <rs id="t17620526-19-off96" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620526-19-off96" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-19-off96" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               wilful murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17620526-19-victim200" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Tomlin 
                        <interp inst="t17620526-19-victim200" type="surname" value="Tomlin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620526-19-victim200" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620526-19-victim200" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620526-19-off96 t17620526-19-victim200"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>; he stood charged on the coroner's inquest for the said murder, <rs id="t17620526-19-cd97" type="crimeDate">Jan. 14</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620526-19-off96 t17620526-19-cd97"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>The prisoner being a foreigner, an interpreter was sworn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620526-19-person201">
                  Thomas 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17620526-19-person201" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-19-person201" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-19-person201" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep <placeName id="t17620526-19-crimeloc98">the Black Boy alehouse on Saltpetre Bank</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17620526-19-crimeloc98" type="placeName" value="the Black Boy alehouse on Saltpetre Bank"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17620526-19-crimeloc98" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620526-19-off96 t17620526-19-crimeloc98"></join>. About half an hour after 10 at night, some time in January last, the deceased, whom I had never seen before, came into my house; he fell against the bar; I was in the bar. He said, I am stabbed; the prisoner followed him in. As soon as he spoke the word, the prisoner ran out of the house; he was taken the next night. I saw the deceased's guts hang out a great way; I helped to push them in again; and we tied him round, and put him on a window-shutter, and four people carried him to the hospital. After that, we carried two foreigners to him; he said neither of them wa s the man; he described the prisoner's person, and said, the man that stabbed him had a blue ribband in his hat; the prisoner had such a one on his hat, which I have now by me.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176205260027"></xptr>Q. Was either of the other two men in company with the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Evans. I am not sure of that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620526-19-person202">
                  Robert 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17620526-19-person202" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-19-person202" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-19-person202" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I took the prisoner to the deceased, at the hospital in Whitechapel, the next day. The deceased looked at him, and said, That was the man that stabbed him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the deceased then sensible?</p>
               <p>Clark. He was quite sensible; I asked him twice; and he answered twice, That is the man.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was this? was it light enough to see his face?</p>
               <p>Clark. It was about four o'clock; I could see their faces very plain, it was light enough.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620526-19-person203">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Bateman 
               <interp inst="t17620526-19-person203" type="surname" value="Bateman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-19-person203" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-19-person203" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am nurse at the hospital; I had the care of the deceased; I remember his being brought to the hospital, but can't tell the day of the month, I believe it was in January; he told me he went to a public house, and a young man, a Portuguese, gave him the wound with a knife; I was by when the prisoner was brought to his bed-side; there were several people came with him?</p>
               <p>Q. Was it light enough to see his face?</p>
               <p>E. Bateman. It was; our ward is very long and very light As soon as the deceased saw him coming up the ward, he said, That is the man that gave me the wound; I saw the wound dressed, he died of that wound; there were two others brought before him; he said neither of them was the man; I said to the prisoner, How could you do such a cruel action? you have killed this poor young fellow. He said in broken English, Madam, I was with them, but I had no knife.</p>
               <p>Evans. There was a bloody clasp knife picked up near my door by somebody, I know not who; soon after the prisoner ran away.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620526-19-person204">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Miles 
               <interp inst="t17620526-19-person204" type="surname" value="Miles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-19-person204" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-19-person204" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the deceased come into Mr. Evans's house; he said he was wounded; I took hold of his hand, it was bloody: I wiped it; he said, My hand is not cut, my bowels are cut. I said, By whom? he said, By one of the Portuguese. The prisoner came in, and went out directly.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say the prisoner cut him?</p>
               <p>E. Miles. No, he did not. I heard him clear the other two at the infirmary; and, when this man was carried, he said, this was the man that cut him; this was two days before his death.</p>
               <p>Evans. The deceased and three Portuguese were drinking together at the next door to me.</p>
               <p>E. Bateman. The deceased said, He went to a public house; there were some girls, and he drank to one of them, and the Portuguese pulled out his knife and stabbed him. The deceased was very calm and serene, he was never delirious from the time he came in to that of his death.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620526-19-person205">
                  Margaret 
                  Murphy 
               <interp inst="t17620526-19-person205" type="surname" value="Murphy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-19-person205" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-19-person205" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The deceased was my son; he was at my house on the Monday night; this thing happened on the Wednesday following; he was in a good state of health before, he was 28 years of age. I went to see him after the prisoner had been carried to him; he told me the man had been there that hurt him, and was sent to Newgate; this was done the 14th of January, and he died on the 18th.</p>

               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>One of the men that made their escape certainly killed the man; the deceased, the week before, had beat that man with a stick, so in revenge he killed him; I had no knife upon me; and the man that did it, did not do it with that knife that was found in the street, he did it with a Dutch knife.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17620526-19-verdict99" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620526-19-verdict99" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
