<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17620421-11">
               <interp inst="t17620421-11" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620421-11" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620421-11" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17620421"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620421-11" type="date" value="17620421"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620421-11-off50-c135" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-11-defend151 t17620421-11-off50 t17620421-11-verdict54"></join>
         
               <p>126. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17620421-11-defend151" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17620421-11-defend151" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-11-defend151" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-11-defend151" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17620421-11-off50" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620421-11-off50" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-11-off50" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               committing a rape on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17620421-11-victim153" type="victimName">
                           Elizabeth 
                           Treadway 
                        <interp inst="t17620421-11-victim153" type="surname" value="Treadway"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620421-11-victim153" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620421-11-victim153" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-11-off50 t17620421-11-victim153"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17620421-11-viclabel51" type="occupation">spinster, an infant, under the age of six years</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-11-victim153 t17620421-11-viclabel51"></join>
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17620421-11-cd52" type="crimeDate">April 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-11-off50 t17620421-11-cd52"></join> ||.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-11-person154">
                  Eliz 
                  Treadway 
               <interp inst="t17620421-11-person154" type="surname" value="Treadway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-11-person154" type="given" value="Eliz"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-11-person154" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the elder. 
               <persName id="t17620421-11-person155">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Treadway 
               <interp inst="t17620421-11-person155" type="surname" value="Treadway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-11-person155" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-11-person155" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is my daughter. I live at Hammersmith. My child complained to me on Friday the 14th of this month that she was sore. I examined her, and found a great running, of what I take to be the venereal disease. The parts were swelled very much.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you judge that her body had been entered?</p>
               <p>E. Treadway. The midwife told me he had just entered her: I think within myself, some man had entered her body. I was in London when it happened. The prisoner is a <rs id="t17620421-11-deflabel53" type="occupation">shoe-maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-11-defend151 t17620421-11-deflabel53"></join>, and lives one door from me, and the child used sometimes to be at his house. My child is five years and a half old.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-11-person156">
                  Samuel 
                  Treadway 
               <interp inst="t17620421-11-person156" type="surname" value="Treadway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-11-person156" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-11-person156" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am father to the child. I am a gardener, and was at work at the time. I know nothing more than what the child said before the justice.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-11-person157">
                  Benedict 
                  Duddle 
               <interp inst="t17620421-11-person157" type="surname" value="Duddle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-11-person157" type="given" value="Benedict"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-11-person157" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prosecutor brought the child to me last Saturday was se'ennight. I found three venereal shankers on the labia, and a swelling upon each groin, with an ulcer of matter issuing through the virginale: it appeared by all circumstances that a man had entered her body. When I talked to the prisoner about it, he asked me how could shankers come since last Tuesday? I apprehend she had the venereal disease.</p>
               <p>Q. If there were only the venereal disorder about his private parts, and he was only to attempt it, would not there be the same symptoms?</p>
               <p>Duddle. Certainly he entered her, for there was a laceration on the parts.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think shankers could come between the Tuesday and the Sunday?</p>
               <p>Duddle. I do think they could.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I asked him, if he would examine me, whether I had the venereal disorder or not?</p>
               <p>Duddle. He did. I did not examine him; it is impossible to examine those things, except we take a proper catheter.</p>
               <p>Q. If he had been so infected so as to have given<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176204210011"></xptr> her shankers in that time, would there not have been a running on him?</p>
               <p>Duddle. I might not have seen it, except I had pressed the instrument along the said tube.</p>
               <p>The Child examined, but not sworn.</p>
               <p>Child. I went to carry my grandmother's shoe to the prisoner, He put me upon the table.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>Child. This was in the prisoner's shop below in the kitchen.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he do to you?</p>
               <p>Child. He said I must not tell my mamma. He laid me down on my back and hurt my groin, and put his cock to me.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was he doing this to you?</p>
               <p>Child. I don't know.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he put any thing into you?</p>
               <p>Child. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you cry out?</p>
               <p>Child. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you not generally cry out when you are hurt? Did you not shed tears?</p>
               <p>Child. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you not frighted?</p>
               <p>Child. No.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after this did you complain and tell your mother?</p>
               <p>Child. I told my mamma on the Sunday. I do not know how long that was after.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he do any any thing to your cloaths?</p>
               <p>Child. He pulled up my petticoats when he laid me on the table. But he laid me cross his lap after that.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure he put something into your body?</p>
               <p>Child. I am not sure.</p>
               <p>Q. from the Prisoner. Was any body in the room at the time?</p>
               <p>Child. There was Mrs. Barnard, the prisoner's grand-mother in another room, not in that room.</p>
               <p>Q. to the Mother. Did the girl complain to you?</p>
               <p>The Mother. She did, in the same way she does now.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she complain before you asked her?</p>
               <p>Mother. She complained of her groin being sore first.</p>
               <p>The prisoner in his defence said, this was done out of spite, because he would not deliver the shoes when he had done them without the money.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Barnard. I was in a room over head when the child came in with the shoes to be mended. I never saw or heard any disturbance.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17620421-11-verdict54" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620421-11-verdict54" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was detained to be tried at Hicks's-hall for an assault, with an intent to commit a rape on the child.</p>
            </div1>
