<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640912-39">
               <interp inst="t17640912-39" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-39" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-39" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640912"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-39" type="date" value="17640912"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640912-39-off223-c278" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-39-defend350 t17640912-39-off223 t17640912-39-verdict227"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640912-39-off223-c279" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-39-defend352 t17640912-39-off223 t17640912-39-verdict227"></join>
         
               <p>519, 520. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17640912-39-defend350" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Castle 
                  <interp inst="t17640912-39-defend350" type="surname" value="Castle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-defend350" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-defend350" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17640912-39-defend352" type="defendantName">
                     Matthew 
                     Farmer 
                  <interp inst="t17640912-39-defend352" type="surname" value="Farmer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-defend352" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-defend352" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-defend352" type="age" value="16 years of age"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted for <rs id="t17640912-39-off223" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-off223" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-off223" type="offenceSubcategory" value="shoplifting"></interp>
               stealing one gold lac'd hat, value 10 s. four other plain hats, value 17 s. and one linen handkerchief, value 6 d. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640912-39-victim354" type="victimName">
                           Nathaniel 
                           Warner 
                        <interp inst="t17640912-39-victim354" type="surname" value="Warner"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640912-39-victim354" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640912-39-victim354" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-39-off223 t17640912-39-victim354"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately in his shop
            </rs>, <rs id="t17640912-39-cd224" type="crimeDate">August 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-39-off223 t17640912-39-cd224"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-39-person355">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Warner 
               <interp inst="t17640912-39-person355" type="surname" value="Warner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-person355" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-person355" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17640912-39-crimeloc225">St. John's-Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640912-39-crimeloc225" type="placeName" value="St. John's-Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640912-39-crimeloc225" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-39-off223 t17640912-39-crimeloc225"></join>, and am a <rs id="t17640912-39-viclabel226" type="occupation">pawnbroker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-39-victim354 t17640912-39-viclabel226"></join>. On the 7th of August, about the hour of 11 in the forenoon, the evidence Delvin, with another man, came in and demanded a shirt, that they said lay for 3 s. I sent my daughter up to look for it; the hats mentioned in the indictment were all hanging upon a nail: I saw Delvin pointing up to them: I found there was no such thing as they came for; it was a fiction of theirs. I asked who brought the shirt? they mentioned a woman's name whom I knew nothing of: I bid them go and ask her about it: they went away, and between the hours of one and two, and in the same fictitious manner, demanded a silk handkerchief, which, they said, lay for two shillings. I had no such thing in my house. I had a jealousy they came for my hats: the moment I stept from off the compter, I missed them: I immediately seized Castle. In endeavouring to get away, he left part of his coat, waistcoat, and shirt, in my hands. He was on one side of the compter, and I on the other: he got from me: I stepped to the door, and cried, Stop thief: the next witness crossed the way upon him: I saw him drop a handkerchief; this is it; it is my property. (Producing a blue and white handkerchief.) Castle ran into a chandler's shop and Mr. Rushton took him. We carried him to the Justices at Hicks's Hall, and he was committed. After that I was sent for to Sir 
               <persName id="t17640912-39-person356">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17640912-39-person356" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-person356" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-person356" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's: I described the hats before they were opened: there was Delvin and the two prisoners; as to the former, I can only say, there was one of them about his size, but I cannot take upon me to say he is the person.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-39-person357">
                  Charles 
                  Rushton 
               <interp inst="t17640912-39-person357" type="surname" value="Rushton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-person357" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-person357" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going up to Islington on the 7th of August, to dinner: I saw Castle come running out of Warner's shop in a torn condition; his clothes were hanging about: Mr. Warner came running out, and cried, Stop thief: I ran; the prisoner dropt the handkerchief at the corner of Aylesbury-street, and ran into a tallow-chandler's shop, where I took him: I took him into a public house in that street, he turned about and would have pushed me back again; then I struck him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-39-person358">
                  Samuel 
                  Lee 
               <interp inst="t17640912-39-person358" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-person358" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-person358" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw Castle with his clothes torn: the handkerchief was put into my charge: that is all I know.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-39-person359">
                  Henry 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17640912-39-person359" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-person359" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-person359" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 7th of August, about four in the afternoon, I was told some boys had some hats in the old ruins of St. Giles's; Delvin came out with this hat in his hand, from the Two Brewers. I touched him on the shoulder, and said, How came you by this hat? he said he had it of two young men, and was going to pawn it for them; and that they were at 
               <persName id="t17640912-39-person360">
                  James 
                  Boswell 
               <interp inst="t17640912-39-person360" type="surname" value="Boswell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-person360" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-person360" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, that is, the two brewers. I took him before Sir 
               <persName id="t17640912-39-person361">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17640912-39-person361" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-person361" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-person361" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and he was committed upon suspicion. The next day he was brought up, and admitted evidence against the prisoners. On the last execution day I met Farmer, and brought him to Sir John's; and there Mr. Warner was bound over to prosecute.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-39-person362">
                  William 
                  Delvin 
               <interp inst="t17640912-39-person362" type="surname" value="Delvin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-person362" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-person362" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 7th of August, the two prisoners and I met in Chick-lane: we agreed to go and rob this pawnbroker's shop: we went; I pulled out three shillings, and asked for a shirt in a woman's name. I went into a back place, where were a parcel of hats: while I was looking to get this gold lac'd hat, Farmer was trying to get some hats that were at the going in at the door: we did not get any thing then; we went out, and met with Castle in Turnmill-street: he asked us where we had been? we told him: he said, where is the pawnbroker's? we told him: we agreed to go back: I said, he will know me, if I go in again: so I went, and stood at the door, till they went in. I had not staid a minute. before Farmer came out with a parcel of hats under his arm; and Castle came out after him with his collar torn: the man came after him, and called,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176409120028"></xptr> Stop thief; I walked on the other side of the street, and saw him taken: then I went to a house in Thatch'd-Alley in Chick-lane; there I met Farmer: he brought the hats, and we agreed to go and sell them as fast as we could: there were four plain ones and a gold lac'd one; we went to the sign of the Castle; there were four men playing at skittles: he knew where to sell them: we went to the Broad-way St. Giles's: they went and pawned one or two: I sat in the house the time. Then we went to the Two Brewers and had a pot of beer; there were a parcel of young fellows; they wanted to buy them: I had the gold lac'd one in an apron. The thief-catchers came in. I went out, and this 
               <persName id="t17640912-39-person363">
                  Harry 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17640912-39-person363" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-person363" type="given" value="Harry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-person363" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came and touch'd me on the shoulder, and asked me what I had got there? he took me to Sir 
               <persName id="t17640912-39-person364">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17640912-39-person364" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-person364" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-person364" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and I was committed to the Gatehouse.</p>
               <p>Castle's Defence.</p>
               <p>I went into this man's house to ask for a shirt; he said, I was a rascal, he had no such thing in pawn. He took hold of me, and said I wanted to rob the house. I was born in America, and have been here but seven months.</p>
               <p>Farmer's Defence.</p>
               <p>Delvin came to me in the morning, as soon as I was up; he had committed a robbery that morning upon one 
               <persName id="t17640912-39-person365">
                  John 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17640912-39-person365" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-person365" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-person365" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , just below: he told me he had been to the pawnbroker in St. John's-street: I went along with him in the morning; he asked for a shirt for three shillings; the pawnbroker said he had it not in his house: we went out; and between one and two we went again; he went into the shop, and I stood at the door: he took the things and brought them out to me; he pawned one and sold another. I am but 16 years of age.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17640912-39-verdict227" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-verdict227" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-verdict227" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder5s"></interp>
               Guilty, 4 s. 10 d
            </rs>. <rs id="t17640912-39-punish228" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-39-punish228" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-39-defend350 t17640912-39-punish228"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-39-defend352 t17640912-39-punish228"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
