<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660219-58">
               <interp inst="t17660219-58" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660219-58" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660219-58" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660219"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660219-58" type="date" value="17660219"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660219-58-off337-c498" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-58-defend642 t17660219-58-off337 t17660219-58-verdict343"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660219-58-off339-c501" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-58-defend647 t17660219-58-off339 t17660219-58-verdict345"></join>
         
               <p>187, 188. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660219-58-defend642" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Stanley 
                  <interp inst="t17660219-58-defend642" type="surname" value="Stanley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-58-defend642" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-58-defend642" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17660219-58-deflabel336" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-58-defend642 t17660219-58-deflabel336"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17660219-58-off337" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660219-58-off337" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-58-off337" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 8 guineas, 4 half guineas, 9 quarter guineas, one 36 s. piece, and 16 s. and 8 d. in money numbered, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17660219-58-victim644" type="victimName">
                           Anne Christophera 
                           Cole 
                        <interp inst="t17660219-58-victim644" type="surname" value="Cole"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660219-58-victim644" type="given" value="Anne Christophera"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660219-58-victim644" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                     
                  , <rs id="t17660219-58-viclabel338" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-58-victim644 t17660219-58-viclabel338"></join>, in the dwelling-house of the said 
                     <persName id="t17660219-58-person645">
                        Anne 
                        Christophera 
                     <interp inst="t17660219-58-person645" type="surname" value="Christophera"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660219-58-person645" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660219-58-person645" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, and 
               
                  <persName id="t17660219-58-defend647" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Stanley 
                  <interp inst="t17660219-58-defend647" type="surname" value="Stanley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-58-defend647" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-58-defend647" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , her father, as <rs id="t17660219-58-off339" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660219-58-off339" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-58-off339" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               accessary before and after the fact, for feloniously enticing, procuring, counselling, and commanding her to do and commit the same, and receiving and harbouring her, well knowing she had committed the same
            </rs>, <rs id="t17660219-58-cd340" type="crimeDate">Feb. 9</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-58-off337 t17660219-58-cd340"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-58-off339 t17660219-58-cd340"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>Anne Christophera Cole. <rs id="t17660219-58-viclabel341" type="occupation">I keep a public house</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-58-victim644 t17660219-58-viclabel341"></join> in <placeName id="t17660219-58-crimeloc342">Jewin-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17660219-58-crimeloc342" type="placeName" value="Jewin-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660219-58-crimeloc342" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-58-off337 t17660219-58-crimeloc342"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-58-off339 t17660219-58-crimeloc342"></join>; 
               <persName id="t17660219-58-person648">
                  Sarah 
                  Stanley 
               <interp inst="t17660219-58-person648" type="surname" value="Stanley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-58-person648" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-58-person648" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was with me to fetch in pots and draw beer. On the 9th of this month, I went to the fire side to give change to a person, and did not take the key out of my drawer, but turned it; I had left a quarter guinea on the table, she took it up and gave it me, and I put it and a guinea into the drawer, when I turned the key just before. I missed her in about a quarter of an hour after.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is your till?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660219-58-person649">
                  Anne 
                  Cole 
               <interp inst="t17660219-58-person649" type="surname" value="Cole"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-58-person649" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-58-person649" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . That is in the bar, I saw her in the bar when I was giving change. I felt in my pocket apron, and found my key was gone; I went to the till and opened it, and my bag was gone, eight guineas, four half guineas, nine quarter guineas, a 36 s. piece, and a silver twopence, three half crowns, and other silver. I went to the watch-house with a gentleman that was in my house, but heard nothing of her; at break of day we had intelligence her father lodg'd in Golden-lane, behind the Black Raven; we went there about half an hour after six; we called, the mother came to the window, I went into the room, she had her under petticoat on, there was a great fire; I said, Nanny, where is my money? Said she, what is the matter? where is Sall? I said, you know; my money is gone. She began to cry, and said she knew nothing of it; we took her till such time we found the two prisoners. She equivocated a great deal, and said she knew nothing of it; at last she said, they were at the foot of the bridge; in going, they met them both together accidentally by Cripplegate church; I was not there. They went in at the Ship-ale-house, in Whitecross-street, and I and the constable were sent for. The father used me there in a very abrupt manner; he pushed me down flat on my face, and threw beer over me and another. I called for a coach, and foolishly ventured my life with him; when we came to Wood-street Compter, he said, that was the place he wanted to go to. He smashed the glasses all to pieces, which I had to pay for, and behaved in a very bad manner. I carried them before the Lord Mayor, and my Lord committed him to Newgate, and the girl to the Poultry Compter. There was 12 l. and upwards found upon the man, there was a 36 s. piece, three half crowns, a silver two-pence, two half guineas, 8 guineas and some trifle of silver.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the father say for himself?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660219-58-person650">
                  Anne 
                  Cole 
               <interp inst="t17660219-58-person650" type="surname" value="Cole"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-58-person650" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-58-person650" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He had nothing to say. The girl said to him, father, give my mistress the money, for you know you have got it in your pocket. I heard her say this two or three times. He was so audacious and abusive that no body<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176602190040"></xptr> could bear to be near him; all he said was to very little purpose: I believe he was the occasion of her taking the whole from me. She confessed the whole.</p>
               <p>Q. How old is she?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660219-58-person651">
                  Anne 
                  Cole 
               <interp inst="t17660219-58-person651" type="surname" value="Cole"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-58-person651" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-58-person651" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She was 17 years of age the day I took her up.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660219-58-person652">
                  Charles 
                  Bull 
               <interp inst="t17660219-58-person652" type="surname" value="Bull"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-58-person652" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-58-person652" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at Mrs. Cole's house on that Sunday evening about a quarter after 9, I had a pint of beer; I said to the girl, put a bit of toast in it, which she did, and turned herself round and went into the bar. Mrs. Cole went into the bar about twenty minutes after, and said, I am ruined, I am robbed of all I got; it is not mine, it is the brewer's money. The maid said, madam, do you know where Sally is gone? The mistress said, no, I do not; she said, it gives me reason to think she had got it, saying, the father came to the house the day before, and demanded money of the girl. They were told the father lived in Beech-lane; I went to enquire, and found he was moved to Golden-lane, by the Black Raven; the next morning Mrs. Cole and I went there; the man at the Black Raven called Mrs. Stanley. She opened the window, then we went up; Mrs. Cole desired me to run for an officer, I went and got one, and we took her to Mrs. Cole's house; there we asked her several questions. She had five or six shillings and six-pence in her pocket. About eleven o'clock we went to go before my Lord Mayor with her, coming to the steps of the Mansion-house, she said, If Mrs. Cole would go home, and leave it to me, she would tell where they were. Mrs. Cole consented to it; then she said her husband and daughter were over the bridge at a public house, and she would speak to him to let us have the money back. Coming by Cripplegate, the father and daughter were coming from towards London-wall; the wife said to him, so John; then I took hold of him, and said, you are all three prisoners. The man said, he knew nothing of the matter. The girl said, father, we are found out, give Mr. Bull the money, you know it is my mistress's. People coming about us, I said, we will go into Mr. Durant's till Mrs. Cole comes. No, said the father, I'll go into the Ship-ale-house; I sent for an officer, and called for a tankard of beer; he threw it over me, and was striving to get out at the door; I laid him on the ground, and kept him there. When Mrs. Cole came in, the girl directly said, father, give my mistress the money; you persuaded me to do it, and you have got it between your shirt and your breeches. He said, I know not what money you mean. She said, you know you have it; for when I was at home in the afternoon to clean myself, you desired me to take my mistress's bag that the gold and silver was in, and you would wait in Jewin-street till I did it; and I took it and brought it to you, and you took and turned the money out into a paper, and put the key belonging to my mistress's till into the bag, and threw the bag away, and now you know that you have it, and here is six-pence that my father gave me out of the bag, and gave it into my hand. When we came before my Lord Mayor, he ordered him to be searched; we took him into a room, and I searched him; he put his hand into his pocket and took out three half crowns, and some silver, and put it into my hand; my Lord desired he should be searched closely; he pulled off his breeches; I took hold of them, and clapped my hand on the fob, and said here is something hard; Mr. Brown took out a parcel tied with a piece of pockthread: before we opened it Mr. Brown said, there is one particular guinea there, it is very smooth on one side, and the impression on the other very plain; we opened them, and it was the first guinea we saw; there were eight guineas, two half guineas, one 36 s. piece, one quarter of a guinea, and a silver two-pence (produced in court. The particular one inspected by the Court and Jury.) The money was sealed up in my Lord's presence. When we were bringing the father to Newgate, he desired me to get them to make it up as she had got the money, and hoped she would not prosecute him.</p>
               <p>Maynard Brown. This guinea (taking the remarkable one in his hand) I borrowed of Mrs. Cole. I was at her house on Sunday in the afternoon drinking a pint of beer; some gentlemen there asked me to take a walk, when I came to feel in my pocket I had no money; I said to Mrs. Cole, lend me a few shillings. She fetched me this guinea: when we came to the Blue Last at Islington, they would not change it; I turned it over and over, and said, this is a comical sort of a guinea, plain on one side, and smooth on the other. When I came back again, I returned it to Mrs. Cole, and in the morning I heard she had been robbed. When I heard the prisoners were taken, I went to them to the Ship-ale-house; I asked the girl how she could be so cruel as to rob her poor mistress; she burst out crying very vehemently indeed, and said, Sir, when I went<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176602190041"></xptr> home to clean myself in the afternoon, my father said to me, Sall, you must take the bag where your mistress's money is, out of the till, and bring it to me. She said, I cannot do such a thing: said he, I insist upon your doing it, and if you don't, I'll beat you. She said, she took an opportunity in the evening, when her mistress was gone out of the bar, and took the bag, with her mistress's gold and silver in it, and her father was then waiting for her in Jewin-street.</p>
               <p>Q. Was all this in his hearing?</p>
               <p>Brown. It was, and he made no reply to it: she said he took it from her, and they went and walked about the other end of the town all night, and he took the money out of the bag, a nd put the key in the bag, and threw it away in some lane, I think about Drury-lane. After that, he made reply and said, none of your mistress's money, you never gave me none. Said she, don't say so father, you know the money is my mistress's money, you have the silver in your pocket, and the gold is concealed in a paper somewhere about your shirt, or in your breeches. He made no more reply, but was very audacious: we took coach, and went before my Lord-Mayor at the Mansion-house; the girl made the same confession there, as near as can be spoke. My Lord ordered him to be searched in another room; there were three half crowns, and a silver 2 d. and other silver taken out of his pocket: he was very loth to pull off his breeches; we insisted upon having them quite off. I felt a knob in his fob, and took it out and delivered it to the officer. I said, before you open this paper, there is a very remarkable guinea, if it is not gone, and described it: they untied the packthread, and opened the paper, and the first guinea was that.</p>
               <p>Daughter's defence.</p>
               <p>I never saw nothing about it. There was another maid in the house as well as I. I was frighted, and did not know what to say. I went from my mistress, because we had words.</p>
               <p>Father's defence.</p>
               <p>I was in bed at the time, and knew no more of it than your Lordship does. I went out in the morning about my business, about 6 o'clock. I am a buckle maker. Coming home about half an hour after 1 o'clock, they stopped me in the street, and charged me with having this woman's money. I said, I had none, I never was near her house. They took me before my Lord-Mayor, and took 8 guineas, 2 half guineas, a 36 s. piece, 3 half crowns, and other silver out of my pocket, money of my own. I got it by my own hand labour. I sell buckles to the Jews.</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. He came out of Newgate but the other day. He had no money of his own. I was a good friend to him. I can swear to that silver 2 d. very safely, it is my child's.</p>
               <p>Sarah <rs id="t17660219-58-verdict343" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660219-58-verdict343" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17660219-58-punish344" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660219-58-punish344" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-58-defend642 t17660219-58-punish344"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>John <rs id="t17660219-58-verdict345" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660219-58-verdict345" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.  <rs id="t17660219-58-punish346" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660219-58-punish346" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-58-punish346" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-58-defend647 t17660219-58-punish346"></join>
               B
            </rs>. <rs id="t17660219-58-punish347" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660219-58-punish347" type="punishmentCategory" value="imprison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-58-punish347" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="newgate"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-58-defend647 t17660219-58-punish347"></join>
               Imp
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>When the father was gone from the bar, the girl confessed her father ordered her to make her defence in the manner which she did.</p>
            </div1>
