<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650417-62">
               <interp inst="t17650417-62" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650417-62" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650417-62" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650417"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650417-62" type="date" value="17650417"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650417-62-off346-c444" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend569 t17650417-62-off346 t17650417-62-verdict347"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650417-62-off346-c445" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend571 t17650417-62-off346 t17650417-62-verdict347"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650417-62-off346-c446" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend573 t17650417-62-off346 t17650417-62-verdict347"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650417-62-off346-c447" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend575 t17650417-62-off346 t17650417-62-verdict347"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650417-62-off346-c448" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend577 t17650417-62-off346 t17650417-62-verdict347"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650417-62-off346-c449" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend579 t17650417-62-off346 t17650417-62-verdict347"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650417-62-off346-c450" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend580 t17650417-62-off346 t17650417-62-verdict347"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650417-62-off346-c451" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend581 t17650417-62-off346 t17650417-62-verdict347"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650417-62-off346-c452" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend583 t17650417-62-off346 t17650417-62-verdict347"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650417-62-off346-c453" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend585 t17650417-62-off346 t17650417-62-verdict351"></join>
         
               <p>282, 283, 284, 285, 286, 287, 288, 289, 290, 291. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17650417-62-defend569" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Milbourn 
                  <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend569" type="surname" value="Milbourn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend569" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend569" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17650417-62-defend571" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Macham 
                  <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend571" type="surname" value="Macham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend571" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend571" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17650417-62-defend573" type="defendantName">
                     Patrick 
                     Manning 
                  <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend573" type="surname" value="Manning"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend573" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend573" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17650417-62-defend575" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Cannon 
                  <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend575" type="surname" value="Cannon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend575" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend575" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17650417-62-defend577" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Garrick 
                  <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend577" type="surname" value="Garrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend577" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend577" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17650417-62-defend579" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Jones 
                  <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend579" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend579" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend579" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               <persName id="t17650417-62-defend580" type="defendantName">
                  Alexander 
                  Sparks 
               <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend580" type="surname" value="Sparks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend580" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend580" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , 
               <persName id="t17650417-62-defend581" type="defendantName">
                  John 
                  Dobson 
               <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend581" type="surname" value="Dobson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend581" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend581" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , 
               
                  <persName id="t17650417-62-defend583" type="defendantName">
                     Walter 
                     Berry 
                  <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend583" type="surname" value="Berry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend583" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend583" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17650417-62-defend585" type="defendantName">
                     William
                      Johnson
                  <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend585" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend585" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-defend585" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17650417-62-deflabel345" type="occupation">journeymen taylors</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend569 t17650417-62-deflabel345"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend571 t17650417-62-deflabel345"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend573 t17650417-62-deflabel345"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend575 t17650417-62-deflabel345"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend577 t17650417-62-deflabel345"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend579 t17650417-62-deflabel345"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend580 t17650417-62-deflabel345"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend581 t17650417-62-deflabel345"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend583 t17650417-62-deflabel345"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend585 t17650417-62-deflabel345"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17650417-62-off346" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-off346" type="offenceCategory" value="miscellaneous"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-off346" type="offenceSubcategory" value="conspiracy"></interp>
               conspiring together against the masters. in order to raise their wages, and lessen their hours of working
            </rs>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650417-62-person586">
                  James 
                  Blood 
               <interp inst="t17650417-62-person586" type="surname" value="Blood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-person586" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-person586" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a taylor: in the years 62 and 63, there was an agreement made betwixt the journeymen taylors: I belonged to a body of them, and was chose out to represent them at the Hand-and-Shears, in Cloth-fair.</p>
               <p>Q. How many did that society consist of?</p>
               <p>Blood. That society consisted of about thirty.</p>
               <p>Q. Were either of the prisoners members of that society or club?</p>
               <p>Blood. No, they were not: That house the journeymen used to meet at is a house of call.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you come to a resolution to raise money?</p>
               <p>Blood. We came to the resolution to raise money in the year 1762, the week before Easter; then we came to a resolution, through the town, to leave our masters, if they would not give us three shillings a day. This was done in the committees first, and then carried to each house.</p>
               <p>Q. What is a representative?</p>
               <p>Blood. That is a person chose in order to go and meet at a general meeting.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you know there was to be a general meeting?</p>
               <p>Blood. We gave it out in secret where we were to meet again: there was notice of it left at every house of call, in the year 1762, to meet at such a house; we could never discover who these letters came from; but the signification of them was, that each society should send two men to meet at a particular house.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the first house of this meeting?</p>
               <p>Blood. I believe that was the Green-Dragon, in Fleet street.</p>
               <p>Q. What did your particular society do, in consequence of that?</p>
               <p>Blood. Notice was laid before the club, and they agreed (so did most of the houses in town) to meet: our society sent me, and another man named Howard: we there might be thirty or forty of us that met from other clubs. Sparks was one that met there; he represented the Brown-Bear, in the Strand.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do when there?</p>
               <p>Blood. We had the letter read to us; there was no name to it: we consulted to have another meeting; that was all that was done then. We met again the week following, at the Sun in Devereux-court; we had a particular reason for varying the house, fearing we should be known; they apprehended it was not lawful for them to meet: when we met in Devereux-court, we did not know whether all the houses had agreed to have 3 s. a day. The letter was to stir up all the journeymen taylors to insist upon 3 s. a day: we were to represent it to our respective bodies, and see what they said. That night we agreed to meet the week following, then we should have a club night in the mean time.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you represent to your club what had passed at the Green-Dragon?</p>
               <p>Blood. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you from your society any authority to consent, or join in any acts, to raise your wages?</p>
               <p>Blood. They were agreeable to my going, to see whether the others would agree.</p>
               <p>Q. How many houses were there?</p>
               <p>Blood. There were forty-two houses, and we went two from a house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you enter upon any business at the Sun, in Devereux-court?</p>
               <p>Blood. We represented what our members were agreeable to, and agreed to continue our meeting till the spring of the year; and then, at a proper<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176504170043"></xptr> time to raise our wages. When we strike, the masters cannot help themselves. Then we were at the spring to leave work, unless our masters would give us three shillings a day.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any dispute about the hours of work?</p>
               <p>Blood. No; they made no dispute about that then: the masters had then submitted to the hours, to leave off at 7 o'clock; the hour had been taken off and laid on again, and the men would not work it: the only consideration we had was the wages: I acquainted the body that I represented of these resolutions.</p>
               <p>Q. Were any of the prisoners there then?</p>
               <p>Blood. There were Mr. Sparks and Mr. Manning there then: this was in Devereux-court; we met every week.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you come to any uniform agreement concerning fixing this three shillings a day, or to strike at the soring?</p>
               <p>Blood. We continued from February till a fortnight before Easter, then the whole town agreed to strike.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you meet next?</p>
               <p>Blood. I believe it was at the Queen's Arms in Newgate-street: Sparks and Manning were there then. I believe there were near fourscore of us. The city and the other end of the town did not agree: the city fell off from the agreement rather: every house was not willing to strike; the other side Temple-bar signalized themselves from this side; they said, If the city would not agree with them, they would have a meeting themselves, and would strike on the Monday morning. They wanted to have 3 shillings and three halfpence a day: the city did not come to a resolution that day.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was chosen speaker of the house of representatives?</p>
               <p>Blood. Every one had liberty to speak. Mr. Sparks was the principal man that did speak commonly: we were always ruled a great deal by him, because he had been in former schemes; we looked upon him as one of the principal persons. This division was on a Thursday night; but on the Sunday night we had a meeting among ourselves. On the Monday night the other end of the town struck: the city disagreed one among another. On the Tuesday night, about 8 o'clock, came two men to us, and said, We hear the other men have struck, and we are willing: they came from the Shepherd and Goat, Fleet-ditch. They said, Let us go round and see if the others will agree. I was chose out of my society to go to three more houses in the city, I went to the Ship in Lime-street, and the Crown in Duke's Place: we had word brought they were agreeable in Black Friars; there are two or three houses of call there. At the Ship in Lime-street I told them the resolution of our house, and that we had come to a resolution to strike: they were agreeable if the Crown in Duke's Place and two others would. I went to the Crown in Duke's Place on a club night, when the members were all present: they consented to it: there was 
               <persName id="t17650417-62-person587">
                  Walter 
                  Berry 
               <interp inst="t17650417-62-person587" type="surname" value="Berry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-person587" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-person587" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             at the Crown. I went to the Faulcon in Duke's Place that was near it, and made the proposal to them, and they were agreeable; (our meetings were all on one night). I returned back to my society, and they sent about; they were all agreeable; every representative went to his own club, and every body were to strike in the morning. We did in general through the city all strike. I can't say where our next general meeting was: it was the week after Easter. Tuesday is the club-night of the society, and on Wednesday they all struck from work: the week after we met a representative for the city and county all together: Mr. Sparks always attended.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the house of representatives agree to confirm and abide by what had been done?</p>
               <p>Blood. Yes, they did. Our meetings continued once a week all the year. They came to a resolution at the other end of the town to raise six-pence a week in the year 1762; towards the latter end of the summer we apprehended the masters might object to the wages, and turn the men off: so we thought proper to have a stock to supply the men in the vacation from July to Michaelmas, (then the trade falls off); this was to be continued till every man had paid in six shillings, or they might pay it all at once: that was complied with and raised; it was sometimes lodged in the landlord's hands, sometimes with the members; which we thought proper. This was also to be applied to support an opposition to the masters: every house kept their own stock. I believe there were between three and four thousand of us embodied; and if any man was not agreeable to pay this money, there were orders given he should not be worked with. If a man was at work, if he had not paid the money, we would tell the master he must not keep him; we would not work with him; and if the master continued him in work, that master was not to be work'd for; this was at the latter end of 1762, and beginning of 1763. All the prisoners were present at these committees a different times. Milbourn represented the Shepherd and Goat, Fleet ditch; Manning and Cannon, the One Ton in the Strand; Sparks, the 
               <persName id="t17650417-62-person588">
                  Brown 
                  Bear 
               <interp inst="t17650417-62-person588" type="surname" value="Bear"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-person588" type="given" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-person588" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in the Strand; Macham,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176504170044"></xptr> the ship in Lime street; Berry, the Crown in Duke's Place; Jones, the India House, Fenchurch-street; Garrick, the Rising Sun, Black Friars; Dobson, the Horseshoe, Black Friars. I have seen all these persons at their meetings. In February 1763 the masters began to take it up; they came to a resolution to make the journeymen submit to Rule of Court, to work from six to eight, at 2 s. 6 d. a day one quarter of the year, and 2 s. 2 d. the rest of the year: the journeymen agreed still to continue at 3 s. a day, and work no longer than to seven o'clock. The city consented to raise 12 s. each member raised 6 s. more, to defend all causes. If a journeyman was to be prosecuted, we were to support him. We all did refuse to submit to a Rule of Court, and we regularly did communicate the resolution to the houses; and if any member met with a refractory journeyman, he gave an account of him to the committee; then that was carried to the general committee. Each representative took his name to their respective clubs, and that man was not to be worked with. If the master insisted on keeping him, he was to lose all the others. They that were agreeable to our rules we called Flints, and those that were not were called Dungs. When our troubles came on, there was an order of the committee for every member to pay 6 d. and the representatives were to bring it to the committee. Sparks was the man that raised the money: we raised in the whole I believe to the amount of fifteen or sixteen hundred pounds. We fixed upon men to go and consult Mr. Hewlate the attorney upon matters of difficulty, and so reported his opinion. About the beginning of the year 1763, we looked upon it that Mr. Dove, Mr. Fell, and Mr. Mason, three masters, were stirring up strife against us: so we fixed upon them, th at they should not be served. We insisted upon the men that worked for them to come away and leave them: it was a general resolution they should have no men work for them. The master of the House of Cail sends the men, and if he sent any there, the body of men in that house would be fined so much money for serving contrary to rule: Johnson has not been with us these 12 months.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650417-62-person589">
                  Thomas 
                  Chappel 
               <interp inst="t17650417-62-person589" type="surname" value="Chappel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-person589" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-person589" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a journeyman taylor; I belonged to the Joyner's Arms on the other side of the water: when I first was a committee man in the year 1762, the first house I met at was the Red Lion, in Bull and Mouth-street; this was only a city meeting. Our society had paid no money at that time, and they agreed that I should go to know what resolutions they had come to: I found they had collected 4 s. a man. I brought that resolution to our body of people, and told them the town was very much dissatisfied that we had paid no money in: we agreed to pay in 6 s. at 2 s. a week, from our house. The money was collected: this was to enable us to defend ourselves, if the masters brought on any prosecutions. It was resolved, that they should not work under 3 s. and 3 halfpence a day. When the order of sessions was in the year 1764, we came to a resolution to oppose it: we on the other side of the water subscribed 12 s. a man, and this side the water was but 6 s. If any man thought proper to comply with the order of sessions, he was scratch'd out of the society he belonged to; and in case we found out any man that worked contrary to our resolutions, he was represented to the general committee, and the representatives were to report him to their separate body; so that all journeymen throughout the town were not to work with him if the master continued him; and such masters were to be without men from our houses. The city raised above seven hundred pounds in the years 1762 and 1763: I do not know what was raised in the county; I believe the sum raised at the other end of the town came to that sum, or rather more. I remember the men leaving Mr. Dove, Mr. Fell, and Mr. Mason: they left Mr. Dove on account of one Breary working for him; and I remember the men leaving Mr. Mason on account of one Hollyday working with him; and the people belonging to the Crown in Duke's Place were not to be worked with, because they did not come into the scheme at that time. I have been in company with all the men trying now. I was at a meeting in the year 1763, at the Hole in the Wall, Fleet-street: then we had a general meeting of the whole town by the representatives, both of the city and suburbs. I was last at a meeting in April 1764, then I saw Jones, Milbourn, and Macham. Mr. Dobson has not been a committee man these two years. I have not been with Manning, Cannon, Sparks, Dobson, Berry, and Johnson for a year and a half, or better; since I was with Garrick it is rather longer.</p>
               <p>Blood. I do not imagine Cannon has left off acting three months: there was a striking last March. Cannon acted all last summer. I was in company with him at the One Ton, in the Strand, last March; he delivered to me three letters to three houses, for the society to come into the body again: these letters were to invite the houses to send representatives to contract with them again.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176504170045"></xptr>Q. to Chapel. For what purpose was the 6 s. a man collected?</p>
               <p>Chappel. That was to defend the law suit; or, in case a man was out of work, it was left to the representatives to do as they thought proper. We were still to bring our proportion to the law, if required; the men that did not work were supported with 6 s. a week; I paid 2 l. 12 s. 6 d. to Sparks from the society, at the Joyner's arms, Oct. 19, 1763. (The receipt which Sparks gave to him, produced and read in court.</p>

               <p>Berry's Defence.</p>
               <p>I work'd for a man for 3 s. a day; I left him; he saw me after that, and asked me to come again, and he would give me as much as any man; he gave me 3 s. 6 d. a day; I worked for him for half a crown a day: if I have done amiss, I am sorry for it; the order was given out no man should work with us; we were all turned about our business; I do not believe any master can lay to my charge that I asked them for any wages; I have never been near these societies since the charge was given out at Guildhall.</p>
               <p>Milbourn, Machan, Manning, Cannon, Garrick, Jones, Sparks, Dobson, and Berry,</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17650417-62-verdict347" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-verdict347" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17650417-62-punish348" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-punish348" type="punishmentCategory" value="imprison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-punish348" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="newgate"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend569 t17650417-62-punish348"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend585 t17650417-62-punish348"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend571 t17650417-62-punish348"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend573 t17650417-62-punish348"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend575 t17650417-62-punish348"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend577 t17650417-62-punish348"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend579 t17650417-62-punish348"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend580 t17650417-62-punish348"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend581 t17650417-62-punish348"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend583 t17650417-62-punish348"></join>
               Imp
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17650417-62-punish349" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-punish349" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-punish349" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="fine"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend569 t17650417-62-punish349"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend585 t17650417-62-punish349"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend571 t17650417-62-punish349"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend573 t17650417-62-punish349"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend575 t17650417-62-punish349"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend577 t17650417-62-punish349"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend579 t17650417-62-punish349"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend580 t17650417-62-punish349"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend581 t17650417-62-punish349"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend583 t17650417-62-punish349"></join>
               
                     <note>[Fine. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17650417-62-punish350" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-punish350" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-punish350" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="sureties"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend569 t17650417-62-punish350"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend585 t17650417-62-punish350"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend571 t17650417-62-punish350"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend573 t17650417-62-punish350"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend575 t17650417-62-punish350"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend577 t17650417-62-punish350"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend579 t17650417-62-punish350"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend580 t17650417-62-punish350"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend581 t17650417-62-punish350"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-62-defend583 t17650417-62-punish350"></join>
               
                     <note>[Provide sureties for good behaviour. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
               <p>Johnson, <rs id="t17650417-62-verdict351" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650417-62-verdict351" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
