<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680706-60">
               <interp inst="t17680706-60" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680706-60" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680706-60" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680706"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680706-60" type="date" value="17680706"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680706-60-off324-c526" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-60-defend663 t17680706-60-off324 t17680706-60-verdict326"></join>
         
               <p>490. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17680706-60-defend663" type="defendantName">
                     Susannah 
                     Haselton 
                  <interp inst="t17680706-60-defend663" type="surname" value="Haselton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-60-defend663" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-60-defend663" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17680706-60-deflabel323" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-60-defend663 t17680706-60-deflabel323"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17680706-60-off324" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680706-60-off324" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-60-off324" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing three guineas and three half guineas
            </rs>, the money of 
               
                  <persName id="t17680706-60-victim665" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Blacklock 
                  <interp inst="t17680706-60-victim665" type="surname" value="Blacklock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-60-victim665" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-60-victim665" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-60-off324 t17680706-60-victim665"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17680706-60-cd325" type="crimeDate">July 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-60-off324 t17680706-60-cd325"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680706-60-person666">
                  Thomas 
                  Blacklock 
               <interp inst="t17680706-60-person666" type="surname" value="Blacklock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-60-person666" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-60-person666" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Monday se'nnight between twelve at night and two in the morning, I was in the house of Mrs. Mills in King's-court, facing Drury-lane Play-house, I had been spending the evening with some friends; coming home I met with two girls by Drury-lane Play-house; I took them into this house, they showed us up into a room; after we had been there a little time the girls and I did not agree, so I went down stairs again; I said to Mrs. Mills, as I did not make use of the bed, you should return my money, I had paid a shilling before I went up; she would not; I said as she would not return it I had a right to make use of the bed; I whipped up stairs again, and was going to bed with my clothes on, she would not let me; in the time we were talking this girl at the bar came up, how she came I cannot give any account; the landlady complained she was dry, and proposed having a pot of beer, so she was two-pence and I three half-pence; this girl went for it, and in the time she was gone the landlady said, if you want a girl I would recommend that girl to you; I said, is she clean; she replied she would be bound for her cleanness and honestly; she said if you have 50 l. about you, if you leave it with me I will take care of it; I offered the girl the same price which I gave for the bed; the landlady told her that was a shilling, the girl agreed to it; so I undressed myself and she undressed herself; the landlady left us when we were going into bed; my coat and waistcoat I put in a chair or in the window by the bed-side; the money mentioned in the indictment was in my breeches; I put my hand in my pocket and felt it in my pocket, I laid my breeches under my pillow on that side I intended to lay; the girl swore she would not lie down if she did not lie on that side; I let her lie on that side, but moved my breeches to the other side; when I had done what I wanted I went to sleep; I desired the landlady to call me when she said her husband got up in the morning; I got up and saw my breeches lying on the pillow, the girl was gone; I put my hand in my pocket where the silver was, and found very little there; then I put my hand in the pocket where the gold was, and found there was a 27 s. piece left, and three guineas and three half guineas were gone; just as I missed my money the girl put her head in at the door; I hallooed out to her, and said I wanted to speak with her; I ran down without any more clothes on besides my breeches; there was the woman's servant in the passage, I asked her if she saw the girl that went to bed with me; she said she was gone out; I said she put her head in at the door where I lay; I asked her where her mistress was; she said she was gone to Convent-garden market; I went into a room and saw a bed and a man; I asked him if he was the master of the house, I am not clear whether he made an answer; I told him I was robbed of so much money; I went up and dressed myself, and waited till the mistress came home; then I told her I had lost so and so; she said she would not believe that I had lost any thing; another girl came in afterwards, they called me fifty names; then the prisoner came in while we were arguing about it, she abused me the same; they threatened me if I did not go about my business, they would send for their husbands and they should baste me; I told the mistress of the house, that I have been robbed in your house, and the girl that robbed me is in your house, and I would have you take care of her till I get a warrant for her; as soon as I had an opportunity I went and got a warrant, then the girl was not there; the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176807060063"></xptr> Justice granted a warrant to take up the woman of the house, he committed her to Newgate; the same night this girl was taken she confessed to part of the money, and that she gave the landlady of the house a guinea; this I heard her confess before the Justices in Bow-street; she did not own she took all that money from me, I am not quite clear whether she said she took two guineas and a half or three guineas and a half; the landlady upon her examination denied it; the girl was committed to Newgate.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I had but a shilling of his money; and he had two girls before; I was very much in liquor when I was before the Justice, I don't remember what I said.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680706-60-person667">
                  Mary 
                  Conner 
               <interp inst="t17680706-60-person667" type="surname" value="Conner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-60-person667" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-60-person667" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a country woman, the prisoner served me a year and a half honestly and truly, and never wronged me of a shilling in her life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680706-60-person668">
                  Mary 
                  Whitehead 
               <interp inst="t17680706-60-person668" type="surname" value="Whitehead"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-60-person668" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-60-person668" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her between three and four years, I can give an honest character of the girl; I have left her in the care of a good many clothes and things, I never heard any thing amiss of her.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17680706-60-verdict326" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680706-60-verdict326" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
