<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610916-18">
               <interp inst="t17610916-18" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-18" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-18" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610916"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-18" type="date" value="17610916"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610916-18-off91-c140" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-18-defend167 t17610916-18-off91 t17610916-18-verdict96"></join>
         
               <p>237. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610916-18-defend167" type="defendantName">
                     Philip 
                     Heans 
                  <interp inst="t17610916-18-defend167" type="surname" value="Heans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-18-defend167" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-18-defend167" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17610916-18-off91" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-18-off91" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-18-off91" type="offenceSubcategory" value="shoplifting"></interp>
               stealing one paste ring, set in gold, value 8 s. four plain gold rings, value 1 l. one tortoi-shell handle penknife, value 2 s. two steel watch-chains, value 6 s. and one silk purse, value 1 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17610916-18-victim169" type="victimName">
                           Nathaniel 
                           Jefferys 
                        <interp inst="t17610916-18-victim169" type="surname" value="Jefferys"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610916-18-victim169" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610916-18-victim169" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-18-off91 t17610916-18-victim169"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the shop of the said Nathaniel, privately
            </rs>, <rs id="t17610916-18-cd92" type="crimeDate">June 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-18-off91 t17610916-18-cd92"></join>.*</p>
               <p>Nathaniel Jefferys. The prisoner was a <rs id="t17610916-18-deflabel93" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-18-defend167 t17610916-18-deflabel93"></join> of mine from last October; he was very bare in cloaths when he came to me, and I had a suspicion of him some time on the account of his puting more on his back than I could account for, he having had two suits of cloaths this year; I had lost things out of my shop several times.</p>
               <p>Q. What shop do you keep?</p>
               <p>Jefferys. <rs id="t17610916-18-viclabel94" type="occupation">I keep a toy-shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-18-victim169 t17610916-18-viclabel94"></join>, at the corner of <placeName id="t17610916-18-crimeloc95">Villars-street, York-buildings</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-18-crimeloc95" type="placeName" value="Villars-street, York-buildings"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-18-crimeloc95" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-18-off91 t17610916-18-crimeloc95"></join>, in June last. I had a customer that bought some goods, and they were to be carried home on the next morning, out of which, when I came to look over them, I missed two rings, one a brilliant hoop ring, and the other a paste hoop. On the Saturday night, at half an hour past ten at night, the 27th of June, the prisoner came to me, and asked leave to go out on the Sunday to Uxbridge: I asked him how he was to go; he said on horseback: I then thought he wanted to get away. I told him he should lie no longer in my house, for I verily believed him to have taken things from time to time.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was this after the rings were missing?</p>
               <p>Jefferys. I had missed these rings that Saturday morning. I turned him out of my house, he would sain have gone up to his box, but I would not let him. As soon as he was gone, I took my servant-maid and my wife into the room where he lay, and tryed with all the keys I could find to open his box, but could not. I broke one key in the lock: after that, I forced the box open; there I found one paste gold ring and four plain gold rings, one steel watch chain, a penknife, and a silk purse, which I gave into the care of the maid-servant, who saw me take them out.</p>
               <p>Q. Whose property were they?</p>
               <p>Jefferys. They were my goods.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you found the two rings that you missed that Saturday morning?</p>
               <p>Jefferys. No, I have not.</p>
               <p>Q. Are these part of the goods that you sell in your shop?</p>
               <p>Jefferys. They are: the next morning, when he thought I was gone out, he came for his cloaths, then I secured him, and he had got a steel chain to his own watch, my property, and he also acknowledged it was my property. He said he had taken it out of my shop, he would not make any discovery of the other two rings. I had missed a great many pair of silver-buckles; he owned he had sent two pair into the country, and sold another pair to a person at Salt-petre-bank; but they are not in the indictment. Upon this, I took him before the justice, and he was committed.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you value the goods laid in the indictment at?</p>
               <p>Jefferys. I value the two chains at 6 s. the paste ring at 8 s. the four plain rings at 5 s. each, the penknife at 2 s. and the silk purse at one shilling. The prisoner confessed he took them all from me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say from where?</p>
               <p>Jefferys. He said from out of the shop.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-18-person170">
                  Henry 
                  Jefferys 
               <interp inst="t17610916-18-person170" type="surname" value="Jefferys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-18-person170" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-18-person170" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was sent for on Monday the 28th of June to the prosecutor's, to take the prisoner into custody, for robbing his master of these things mentioned in the indictment [Produced in court, and deposed to by the prosecutor.] The goods were laid upon the dresser, I think by the maid, for me to take into custody. The prisoner was charged with taking them; he acknowledged he took them out of his master's shop, all but one watch-chain, which was taken from his watch.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any thing said to him, at that time, in order to induce him to confess?</p>
               <p>Jefferys. There was no promise made him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence. I took them out of the shop, but thought to put them in their place again. I beg the mercy of the court.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160019"></xptr>Q. to prosecutor. Did you ever trust him with the removal of goods out of your shop?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Never, without I sent him home with goods to a customer.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you contracted sale for any of these goods?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No, I had not.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610916-18-verdict96" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-18-verdict96" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-18-verdict96" type="verdictSubcategory" value="withRecommendation"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17610916-18-punish97" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-18-punish97" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-18-defend167 t17610916-18-punish97"></join>
               Death
            </rs>. Recommended to mercy.</p>
            </div1>
