<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670715-4">
               <interp inst="t17670715-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670715-4" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670715-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670715"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670715-4" type="date" value="17670715"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670715-4-off19-c43" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-4-defend50 t17670715-4-off19 t17670715-4-verdict21"></join>
         
               <p>338. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17670715-4-defend50" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Wykes 
                  <interp inst="t17670715-4-defend50" type="surname" value="Wykes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-4-defend50" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-4-defend50" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17670715-4-off19" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670715-4-off19" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-4-off19" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing twelve pounds weight of lead, value 12 d. and a large iron chain, value 18 d.
            </rs> the property of persons unknown, <rs id="t17670715-4-cd20" type="crimeDate">May 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-4-off19 t17670715-4-cd20"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670715-4-person51">
                  John 
                  Moore 
               <interp inst="t17670715-4-person51" type="surname" value="Moore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-4-person51" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-4-person51" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a paviour. On the 27th of May, about six in the morning, I was at work in Pear-tree-street, I saw the prisoner coming along; I said, I believe you are going on the same game you used to do; (he had worked for me, but did not behave well so I discharged him;) he turned round very short and went off; he had a bag with something in it; I followed him; he turned and looked at me, then he went another way; I still followed at a distance; at last he ran into a little house in Goswell-street; it is a chandler's shop. and they sell old iron; he soon came out into the street again; I pushed into the house; he had set his bag behind the door; I took it; there was the lead and chain mentioned in the indictment, in it; (produced in court;) he ran up Compton-street; I having the things, could not run after him; the lead is cock pipe; I advertised it; after he was taken, he told me he had it out of Cherry-tree-alley, Blue-anchor-alley, and Chequer-alley; I went and enquired in the places, the people would not trouble themselves about it; he said he found the chain in the fields.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he bought the lead?</p>
               <p>Moore. No, he did not; he said two men were concerned in taking the lead; they were taken up; then he said they had no concern in it, and they were discharged.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he stole it?</p>
               <p>Moore. No, he said he had it in them places.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I found the things; they hauled words out of my mouth for me to bring these men in.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17670715-4-verdict21" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670715-4-verdict21" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acq.
            </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
