<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650522-6">
               <interp inst="t17650522-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-6" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650522"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-6" type="date" value="17650522"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650522-6-off34-c69" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-6-defend78 t17650522-6-off34 t17650522-6-verdict38"></join>
         
               <p>297. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17650522-6-defend78" type="defendantName">
                     Catharine 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17650522-6-defend78" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-6-defend78" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-6-defend78" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17650522-6-deflabel33" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-6-defend78 t17650522-6-deflabel33"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17650522-6-off34" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-6-off34" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-6-off34" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing a pair of silver shoe buckles, value 14 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17650522-6-victim80" type="victimName">
                           Charles 
                           Newman 
                        <interp inst="t17650522-6-victim80" type="surname" value="Newman"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650522-6-victim80" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650522-6-victim80" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-6-off34 t17650522-6-victim80"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17650522-6-cd35" type="crimeDate">May 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-6-off34 t17650522-6-cd35"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-6-person81">
                  Charles 
                  Newman 
               <interp inst="t17650522-6-person81" type="surname" value="Newman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-6-person81" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-6-person81" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Swede: I am a <rs id="t17650522-6-viclabel36" type="occupation">sailor</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-6-victim80 t17650522-6-viclabel36"></join>. Last Sunday night I went into an ale-house, the <placeName id="t17650522-6-crimeloc37">Three Tuns in Cable-Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17650522-6-crimeloc37" type="placeName" value="Three Tuns in Cable-Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17650522-6-crimeloc37" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-6-off34 t17650522-6-crimeloc37"></join>; the prisoner was there; she asked me for some beer: I had been drinking, but was sober; there were other people in the room; a public room: I refused to give her any beer; I said, I have none for you; she said she would set down in my company; I said, no, she should not.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the night was this?</p>
               <p>Newman. It was near nine o'clock: I paid for my beer and went out; she overtook me when I was eight or ten yards from the door; there was another woman with her: she said, she wanted to speak to me; I said, then speak; she said, she could not there; they came round me; some pulled me by my sleeves, some pushed me, and by partly frighting me, got me up into an alley, and got me up into some room, up one pair of stairs: there was a candle on the table; there were five or six women in the room; I was frighted almost out of my life: the prisoner was at the head of the gang. They insisted upon my staying all night; I said, I had no money, and must go: they began to come close to me; they got some halfpence from me; I had 4 s. and 6 d. in another pocket; they got it all away, I can't tell how; they were for getting my hat and wig; then they wanted my buckles, they were silver; I took them out and put them into my left side breeches pocket: they insisted upon my staying: I was afraid to fight: I said, let me go and tell my ship-mates, and I'll come again; they would not let me, they<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176505220006"></xptr> pulled me down on the bed, and two or three pulling me about for five or six minutes, the prisoner asked me what I was doing; I said God help me, I wished I was below. Presently they said, young man, you are welcome to go: I felt for my buckles, they were gone: I went to the alehouse, there was the prisoner again: I asked her for my buckles; she said, I might drink some of the beer, but should not have them without I would give her a crown; I said, what must I give you a crown for, I never sat down in your house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever get them again?</p>
               <p>Newman. No. She said she had the buckles: I said to the master of the house, must I have no help; he said, it was not done in his house: then she said, I should have them for half a guinea; but if I was saucy I should not have them at all. She said, if I would go back with her, I should have them in the morning. I went and staid there; she pulled my cloaths off against my will, and lay by the side of me in the bed: in the morning she asked me for a shilling for my lodging. She took my hat and wig from me: I took them and went away. I took her up next day about 11 o'clock: she said, the buckles were sold for 14 s. but did not say to whom. 
               <persName id="t17650522-6-person82">
                  Peter 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17650522-6-person82" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-6-person82" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-6-person82" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was by at the time.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He lay with three women, two at one time, and me the last.</p>
               <p>Q. What makes you think she took your buckles?</p>
               <p>Newman. She took the most liberty; and she owned it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-6-person83">
                  Peter 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17650522-6-person83" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-6-person83" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-6-person83" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the Three Tuns: this man came in and called for a pint of beer; she came and asked to drink with him; he would not let her; he went out, and she after him. She came back in about half an hour, and said, she had robbed a man of a pair of buckles; this she said to some other women: then the man came in and asked her for his buckles; he had a candle in his hand; she said she had got them and he should have them for a crown; he offered her that: then she said, she had sold them for half a guinea; he asked my master to borrow the money, and when it was offered him, she would not let him have them at all.</p>

               <p>Q. What is your master's name?</p>
               <p>Smith. His name is 
               <persName id="t17650522-6-person84">
                  Oliver 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17650522-6-person84" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-6-person84" type="given" value="Oliver"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-6-person84" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>He took me into the ale-house to drink; it is a night-house, where hundreds of unfortunate girls resort; he had but a shilling, which he gave me to get some brandy: there were two other girls which he liked; he went to my room and went to bed with them, and gave me the buckles to pawn; out of the money he gave them 4 s. 6 d. a piece; I saw him give it them when they got up: I left them; and went and treated him with a pint of beer: then he asked me if I would let him lie with me; I said, I would if he would pay me the same he had the other girls; he gave me the same, and I let him go to bed with me.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17650522-6-verdict38" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-6-verdict38" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
