<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17620526-14">
               <interp inst="t17620526-14" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620526-14" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620526-14" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17620526"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620526-14" type="date" value="17620526"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620526-14-off63-c95" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620526-14-defend113 t17620526-14-off63 t17620526-14-verdict67"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620526-14-off63-c96" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620526-14-defend115 t17620526-14-off63 t17620526-14-verdict67"></join>
         
               <p>165, 166. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17620526-14-defend113" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Wilson 
                  <interp inst="t17620526-14-defend113" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-14-defend113" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-14-defend113" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17620526-14-defend115" type="defendantName">
                     Jane 
                     Buckley 
                  <interp inst="t17620526-14-defend115" type="surname" value="Buckley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-14-defend115" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-14-defend115" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17620526-14-deflabel62" type="occupation">spinsters</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620526-14-defend113 t17620526-14-deflabel62"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620526-14-defend115 t17620526-14-deflabel62"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17620526-14-off63" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620526-14-off63" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-14-off63" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one half-guinea and fourteen shillings in money, numbered
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17620526-14-victim117" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Castelli 
                  <interp inst="t17620526-14-victim117" type="surname" value="Castelli"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-14-victim117" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-14-victim117" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620526-14-off63 t17620526-14-victim117"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17620526-14-cd64" type="crimeDate">May 14</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620526-14-off63 t17620526-14-cd64"></join>.*</p> 
               <p>John Castelli. I am an <rs id="t17620526-14-viclabel65" type="occupation">Italian</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620526-14-victim117 t17620526-14-viclabel65"></join>; I live in Knaves-acre, my business is stocco-work. I met with 
               <persName id="t17620526-14-person118">
                  Mary 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17620526-14-person118" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-14-person118" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-14-person118" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in a public house in <placeName id="t17620526-14-crimeloc66">St. Giles's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17620526-14-crimeloc66" type="placeName" value="St. Giles's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17620526-14-crimeloc66" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620526-14-off63 t17620526-14-crimeloc66"></join>, the sign of the Running Horse, from thence I went to the 13 cantons.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was it when you first met her?</p>
               <p>Castelli. It might be about 9 o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in liquor?</p>
               <p>Castelli. I was not in liquor; but I had drank a little, yet I knew what I did.</p>
               <p>Q. How long were you at the Running Horse?</p>
               <p>Castelli. Not above half an hour, or three quarters; there was an acquaintance of hers lived in the neighbourhood of the 13 cantons; she would call her in. She came from Lincoln's-inn-fields, and was going into her own country again; that was 
               <persName id="t17620526-14-person119">
                  Jane 
                  Buckley 
               <interp inst="t17620526-14-person119" type="surname" value="Buckley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-14-person119" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-14-person119" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She called her in; then they gave me an invitation to go to Jane Buckley's apartment. I went with them, and said, if they would drink any thing, I would pay for it.</p>

               <p>Q. What might you drink at each of these houses?</p>
               <p>Castelli. We had but a pint of beer at each house; Buckley's apartment was in St. Giles's, not a great way from the church. I sent for a pint of beer; they gave me an invitation to stay, I was weak enough to comply with it. I asked Buckley what she wanted for her room. She asked me a shilling; a shilling I gave her, and had the liberty to stay as long as I liked. I pulled my cloaths off, and went to bed with 
               <persName id="t17620526-14-person120">
                  Mary 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17620526-14-person120" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-14-person120" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-14-person120" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I had lain in bed I think about half an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of Buckley?</p>
               <p>Castelli. She went down stairs; Wilson got out of bed twice in the half-hour (I had left my cloaths upon two chairs at a distance from the bed). I saw her go that way that my cloaths were, but I cannot positively say I saw her take the money out of the cloaths.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you a light after you went to bed?</p>
               <p>Castelli. No, we had not.</p>
               <p>Q. How much money had you when you went to bed?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176205260009"></xptr>Castelli. Fifteen Shillings in silver, and half guinea in gold, and a shilling I gave to Buckly. It was in my breeches pocket. At last Buckley came up and made a noise at the door. She had fastened the door on the outside after she went out, and said, if I wanted to go away I must call her. I had bolted the door in the inside, and put my hand out of bed to pull the lock back; but it went very hard. I could not pull it open. Then Mary Wilson got out of bed, and let Buckley in. I saw them both go where my cloaths were: I suspected something.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Buckley bring up a light with her?</p>
               <p>Castelli. She did - I got out of bed and took my breeches in my hand, and felt the pockets, and found the silver and gold was gone: they left some half pence. I demanded my money of them, and was angry at the affair. Buckley said, it was likely Wilson might have taken my money out of my pocket; but she said, you must go out and bring the watch and a constable with you, and I'll lock her into the room, and take care that she shall not go out. I went out and called the watch; but when I came back they had both left the room, and I could not find them. The watchman and I went into a night-house in St. James's-street: there I found Buckley, and charged the watch with her. She was carried to the watch-house - She charged the watch with me. There I say 
               <persName id="t17620526-14-person121">
                  Mary 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17620526-14-person121" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-14-person121" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-14-person121" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and charged her; but I got none of my money again. They were searched, and about five or six shillings found upon them both. Wilson threatened to charge me with all manner of scandalous things at the Justice's, and said I had stole her handkerchief from her. Seeing such wickedness in them induced me the more to prosecute them.</p>
               <p>Wilson's Defence.</p>
               <p>He came and asked this young woman and I to drink a pint of beer: we went to her room: he asked her if she would oblige him to go of an errand to fetch him some rods. She went and got one; I have it here.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. This is what she threatend me she would say. It is all false.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. After that he asked her, if she would go and fetch a pot of beer: when she came in again I was obliging him.</p>
               <p>Buckley's Defence.</p>
               <p>This gentleman met us at the Running-Horse, and asked us to drink a pint of beer. We went in and drank there. The young woman asked me, if she could go home to my room: I said she could. Then he asked me if I would oblige him with a favour to go for a peny-worth of rods. Said I, in the name of G - d, what are you going to do with them? I fetched them. As soon as I got into the room they asked me to go for a pot of beer and a peck of coals. I came again in about half an hour, and then this girl was obliging of him.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. This, upon my oath, is all false.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17620526-14-verdict67" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620526-14-verdict67" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>See Wilson tried for the wilful murder of Ann Bourke. No XIV. of Sir 
               <persName id="t17620526-14-person122">
                  Matthew 
                  Blackiston 
               <interp inst="t17620526-14-person122" type="surname" value="Blackiston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-14-person122" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620526-14-person122" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's mayoralty.</p>
            </div1>
