<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680114-36">
               <interp inst="t17680114-36" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680114-36" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680114-36" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680114"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680114-36" type="date" value="17680114"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680114-36-off238-c367" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-36-defend454 t17680114-36-off238 t17680114-36-verdict243"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680114-36-off238-c368" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-36-defend456 t17680114-36-off238 t17680114-36-verdict243"></join>
         
               <p>146. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17680114-36-defend454" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Mitchiner 
                  <interp inst="t17680114-36-defend454" type="surname" value="Mitchiner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-defend454" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-defend454" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , a second time, and 
               
                  <persName id="t17680114-36-defend456" type="defendantName">
                     Charles 
                     Davis 
                  <interp inst="t17680114-36-defend456" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-defend456" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-defend456" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17680114-36-off238" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-off238" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-off238" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               breaking and entering the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17680114-36-victim458" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Wilkinson 
                        <interp inst="t17680114-36-victim458" type="surname" value="Wilkinson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680114-36-victim458" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680114-36-victim458" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17680114-36-viclabel239" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-36-victim458 t17680114-36-viclabel239"></join>, and 
                     
                        <persName id="t17680114-36-victim460" type="victimName">
                           Samuel 
                           Wilkinson 
                        <interp inst="t17680114-36-victim460" type="surname" value="Wilkinson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680114-36-victim460" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680114-36-victim460" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , on the <rs id="t17680114-36-cd240" type="crimeDate">27th of November</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-36-off238 t17680114-36-cd240"></join>, about the hour of three in the night, and stealing a mahogany tea-chest with tin canisters therein, value 3 s. a silver milk pot, value 8 s. a silver table-spoon, value 8 s. three silver tea-spoons, value 3 s. a damask table-cloth, two napkins, and eight pounds weight of loaf sugar, the property of the said Mary and Samuel, and a great coat, the property of the said Samuel, in their dwelling-house
            </rs>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-36-person461">
                  Samuel 
                  Wilkinson 
               <interp inst="t17680114-36-person461" type="surname" value="Wilkinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person461" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person461" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17680114-36-crimeloc241">Lawrence-lane, Cheapside</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17680114-36-crimeloc241" type="placeName" value="Lawrence-lane, Cheapside"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17680114-36-crimeloc241" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-36-off238 t17680114-36-crimeloc241"></join>; I am a <rs id="t17680114-36-viclabel242" type="occupation">box-maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-36-victim460 t17680114-36-viclabel242"></join>, in partnership with my mother, 
               <persName id="t17680114-36-person462">
                  Mary 
                  Wilkinson 
               <interp inst="t17680114-36-person462" type="surname" value="Wilkinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person462" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person462" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; our house was made fast on the 26th of November at night, and on Thursday the 27th about half an hour after three in the morning, the watchman alarmed us, and told us our door was open; I desired him to go for the constable and come in, and come up to my door; when they came we went all over the house; we found the dining-room window-shutter, which had been barred over night was thrown open, and the bar taken down; I missed out of that room a tea-kettle, a large table-spoon, and napkin; the constable informed me he had seen several persons about in the morning, and had taken a man into custody on suspicion, and carried him to the Compter, and he was to be examined before my Lord-Mayor at eleven o'clock; he desired me to attend; he made no confession; my Lord advised me to advertise my things, I did; on the Thursday morning the man was discharged, his name is Trusler; on the 14th of December I received word from Justice Fielding, that the persons that got into our house were in custody, and desired me to attend him at eleven o'clock; there I found Trusler and 
               <persName id="t17680114-36-person463">
                  Margaret 
                  Mitchel 
               <interp inst="t17680114-36-person463" type="surname" value="Mitchel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person463" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person463" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , they are both here to give evidence; I never found any of our goods; I went to see Davis in prison, he is our apprentice, he confessed the whole to me.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has he to serve?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. He would have been out of his time next April, he has been gone from us from the 31st of July; I asked him in what manner he got in; he said he took a shutter down in the front of our shop and got in at the window, and after that put the shutter in again; our shutters are rather too short for the groove.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you make him any promise?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. No, I did not; he heard Trusler tell the whole before the Justice, and therefore he did not scrup le acknowledging it to me; the woman Mitchel acknowledged selling the tea kettle for 18 d.</p>
               <p>Q. What did Mitchiner say?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. I do not remember he said any thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you examine your shutters to see if they could be taken down?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. No, I did not; we apprehended they had concealed themselves over night in our cellar, as Davis knew every part of the house, he might have done it without the knowledge of any of our family.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-36-person464">
                  John 
                  Trusler 
               <interp inst="t17680114-36-person464" type="surname" value="Trusler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person464" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person464" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Mitchiner about three months, and Davis about two; we went to Mr. Wilkinson's one night with intent to get a stock and bit, that is a carpenter's tool, and we found we could take the window shutter down, so we went from the window till such time that we could take it down; when we came there again, I went and talked to the watchman while Davis took it down, then Mitchiner and he went in; when I came there the door was shut; then I stood at a corner, the constable came and took me to the watch-house, so I know no farther than what the prisoners told me of what they took from the house.</p>
               <p>Q. How many were there of you?</p>
               <p>Trusler. There were only the two prisoners and I; I saw Davis go in after he had opened the shutter.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176801140034"></xptr>Q. How near was the watchman to the prosecutor's house?</p>
               <p>Trusler. He was not above half a dozen doors off; I was talking with him all the while.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-36-person465">
                  Margaret 
                  Mitchel 
               <interp inst="t17680114-36-person465" type="surname" value="Mitchel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person465" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person465" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I sell fish; I did live with Mitchiner about six years ago, but lately with Davis; one Friday morning, it might be in November, they came home in the New-way Westminster to me; Davis pulled out a tea-spoon to stir his tea, after that he pulled out the other two; then he took out a large table-spoon; then Mitchiner said to him, you may as well show her the other thing, that was a cream-pot; one of them brought a tea-chest and set it on the drawers, there was some tea in it; one of them said it must be sold; there was a tea-kettle that I sold for 18 d. a table-cloth, two napkins, and a piece of sugar, all these they brought between them; I was in bed when they brought them in; they said they had been at a house and got them, but did not tell me where.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known Trusler?</p>
               <p>M. Mitchel. I have known him a great while, he was a companion of the prisoners; they all three went out of my room together that time.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did they go from your room?</p>
               <p>M. Mitchel. I parted with them when I went out with my oysters that night; Trusler not coming home with them, they told me they supposed he was taken up; I went the next day to the Compter, and found him there, and carried him some money.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of the things?</p>
               <p>M. Mitchel. A Jew came by; he was called in, and the spoons were sold to him for 12 s. the tea-chest for 2 s. the cream-pot for 7 s. 6 d. I sold the tea-kettle for 8 d. I was ordered to get what I could for them; the sugar and table-cloths were sold to another person, I do not know who, nor what the things were sold for; I think I sold the table-cloths and two-napkins for 2 s. there was a cloth coat that was pawned for half a guinea, and taken out again; I never saw it at all but upon Davis's back; it was a blue one.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you carry to Trusler?</p>
               <p>M. Mitchel. I carried him two shillings; the two prisoners sent me with it to him at the Poultry Compter.</p>
               <p>Q Was you taken up?</p>
               <p>M. Mitchel. I was, that was above a week after the robbery.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-36-person466">
                  John 
                  Noaks 
               <interp inst="t17680114-36-person466" type="surname" value="Noaks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person466" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person466" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About the 5th or 6th of December I had a warrant from Sir 
               <persName id="t17680114-36-person467">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17680114-36-person467" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person467" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person467" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to search in the Almonry, there we found Mitchiner; then we went to Mitchel's room, and found Trusler and Davis with her there; we took them before Sir 
               <persName id="t17680114-36-person468">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17680114-36-person468" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person468" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person468" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in the morning, and they were committed the Bridewell; Tresler desired he might be admitted an evidence, saying they had given him but 2 s. out of these goods; then Mitchel, otherwise Nash, desired to be admitted an evidence; she said she would discover the Jew she had sold the things to; I was desired to go and wait with her in the Almonry for the Jew; we went and waited thereabout four hours, he did not come; she told me she had sold the spoons for 12 s. and the tea-kettle for 18 d.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-36-person469">
                  Joseph 
                  Stevenson 
               <interp inst="t17680114-36-person469" type="surname" value="Stevenson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person469" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person469" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was along with Mr. Noaks at the taking the prisoners and evidences; I can say no more than what he has said.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-36-person470">
                  John 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17680114-36-person470" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person470" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person470" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable of Cheap-ward. On the 26th of November at night, was my night to sit up; a little before twelve I saw a man sitting at the corner of Lawrence-lane; then I saw two men and a woman near Mr. Wilkinson's door; I said to the woman, what do you do here; she said it is a thoroughfare, I am going home; I said take care I see you no more, and let her go; a little after twelve I went again with my staff, there were people there but they all dispersed; a little after one I went again, then I saw Trusler leaning against a post, at the corner of the alley, upon that side near Bow-Church; I did not chuse to speak to him, but went through the alley; then I got a watchman, and we went to him and asked what he did there; he said he was locked out of his lodging; I asked him where he lived; he said he lived with Mr King, a poulterer in Corn-hill; I took him to the watch-house, and said he must give a better account of himself; I knowing no poulterer there, I asked him what his master's name was; he could give me no account, but said he would show me where he lived; I would not go, but asked him what was the number; he said it was No 119, the numbers do not amount to so many; I put him in the Compter, and the next day took him before my Lord-Mayor, then he said his friends lived at Westminster; he told me where his father and sister lived; I went there, his father was not at home, his sister said he was a very great rogue, and told me his haunts, and that there was a waterman was one of his companions *.</p>
               <p>* Mitchiner is a waterman.</p>
               <p>Mitchiner's defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing about it.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176801140035"></xptr>Davis's defence.</p>
               <p>I have a witness in court to my character; pray Mr. Wilkinson did I ever wrong you?</p>
               <p>Wilkinson. I never suspected him before he left me; he has been linked in with lewd women, I believe that has brought him into the situation he is now in.</p>
               <p>To Davis's character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-36-person471">
                  John 
                  Adams 
               <interp inst="t17680114-36-person471" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person471" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person471" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known 
               <persName id="t17680114-36-person472">
                  Davis
               <interp inst="t17680114-36-person472" type="given" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person472" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             some time; I live at the Indian King, Monmouth-street, I am a salesman; I never heard any thing amiss of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know he had left his place?</p>
               <p>Adams. No, I did not know that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-36-person473">
                  John 
                  Rice 
               <interp inst="t17680114-36-person473" type="surname" value="Rice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person473" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person473" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known 
               <persName id="t17680114-36-person474">
                  Davis
               <interp inst="t17680114-36-person474" type="given" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person474" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a year and a half, I never knew any thing bad of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-36-person475">
                  John 
                  Leicester 
               <interp inst="t17680114-36-person475" type="surname" value="Leicester"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person475" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person475" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him from a lad, I look upon him to be about twenty-three years of age; I never knew no harm of him in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-36-person476">
                  William 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17680114-36-person476" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person476" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-person476" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Hammersmith; I have known him eight or nine years; I never heard any thing amiss of him in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what was become of him after he left his master in July last?</p>
               <p>Brown. I know he was in the country, they could not agree. Both <rs id="t17680114-36-verdict243" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-verdict243" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17680114-36-punish244" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680114-36-punish244" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-36-defend454 t17680114-36-punish244"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-36-defend456 t17680114-36-punish244"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
