<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17611209-23">
               <interp inst="t17611209-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611209-23" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611209-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17611209"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611209-23" type="date" value="17611209"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17611209-23-off134-c240" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-23-defend282 t17611209-23-off134 t17611209-23-verdict138"></join>
         
               <p>24. (L) 
               <persName id="t17611209-23-defend282" type="defendantName">
                  Lion 
                  Alexander 
               <interp inst="t17611209-23-defend282" type="surname" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-23-defend282" type="given" value="Lion"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-23-defend282" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17611209-23-off134" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611209-23-off134" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-23-off134" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 116 yards of black silk footing, val. 58 s. and 230 yards of black sattin ribband, val. 6 l. 9 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17611209-23-victim284" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Kent 
                  <interp inst="t17611209-23-victim284" type="surname" value="Kent"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-23-victim284" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-23-victim284" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-23-off134 t17611209-23-victim284"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17611209-23-cd135" type="crimeDate">Nov. 9</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-23-off134 t17611209-23-cd135"></join>.~</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-23-person285">
                  John 
                  Kent 
               <interp inst="t17611209-23-person285" type="surname" value="Kent"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-23-person285" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-23-person285" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . <rs id="t17611209-23-viclabel136" type="occupation">I keep a haberdasher's and Milaner's shop in <placeName id="t17611209-23-crimeloc137">Houndsditch</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-23-crimeloc137" type="placeName" value="Houndsditch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-23-crimeloc137" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-23-off134 t17611209-23-crimeloc137"></join>
                  </rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-23-victim284 t17611209-23-viclabel136"></join>. My shop was robbed on the 9th of November, between six and seven at night; I missed a drawer of ribbands. A person came to me on the Tuesday sevennight following, and informed me a person had been with his wife the evening before, and offered such ribbands to sell; his name was Jones. I went to his house. I was informed by his wife who he was. I went and got a warrant; and, before I took him, he had surrendered himself. I charged a constable with him, and went and searched his house, but found nothing. Then I came back to him, and desired him to produce the person that he had them of. He did. I charged the constable with them both: I desired the constable to take care of them: He let both of them<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176112090021"></xptr> go, upon their promising to appear the next morning before my lord mayor; which they did, and were committed. He that offered the goods to sale was Saunders Joseph; he said he had them of the other man, which was the prisoner at the bar. Saunders Joseph said he had them of a German, an acquaintance, but did not know his name. I asked him how that person came to trust him with goods without knowing him? he said, an acquaintance recommended him at a public house. I asked him where that public house was? he said it was somewhere in Holborn, but could not tell where; he said he met the person as he was going along.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see any of your ribbands again?</p>
               <p>Kent. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Jones. Saunders Joseph offered me a parcel of black ribbands to sell in November last, some single taffety, double taffety, pearl double, and broad edged ribband.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I lost quantities of such.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Jones. He offered them at fourpence halfpeny a yard, and the worst of them were worth more money; I would not buy any of it. After he was taken up, he produced the prisoner, and said he employed him to sell them for him.</p>
               <p>Saunders Joseph. I live with Mr. 
               <persName id="t17611209-23-person286">
                  Isaac 
                  Mendez 
               <interp inst="t17611209-23-person286" type="surname" value="Mendez"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-23-person286" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-23-person286" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            : I had the ribband, that I offered to sell to Mrs. Jones, of Lion Alexander.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Joseph. He is a poulterer by trade; he desired me to dispose of them as cheap as I could.</p>
               <p>Q. What is it that you deal in?</p>
               <p>Joseph. In snuff; my master does.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever deal in ribbands before?</p>
               <p>Joseph. No. The prisoner bid me take 5 d. a yard, but, if I could not, to take 4 d. halfpeny, for he wanted ready money.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner bring them to you in?</p>
               <p>Joseph. In a paper.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you tell Mrs. Jones they came from?</p>
               <p>Joseph. I told her they came from out of the country, for I had not asked the prisoner where they came from.</p>
               <p>Q. Where are they now?</p>
               <p>Joseph. I do not know; my spouse delivered them when I was not at home.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Jones. He told me they were a particular friend's of his, and they came out of the country; and another time he said he did not know the man.</p>
               <p>Q. to Joseph. Did you tell Mrs. Jones you did not know the man?</p>
               <p>Joseph. I did; I am no particular acquaintance of the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Kent. I remember the box of ribbands being lost about six o'clock, on the 9th of Nov. I was in the parlour at the time, there was nobody of our people in the shop; we saw a man go out of the shop so suddenly, we thought him to be a thief.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-23-person287">
                  Samuel 
                  Lambert 
               <interp inst="t17611209-23-person287" type="surname" value="Lambert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-23-person287" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-23-person287" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Mr. Kent's servant. On the Tuesday sevennight after my lord mayor's day Mr. Jones came to our shop, and asked if we had lost any black ribband? I said we had. He said he lived in Petticoat Alley, and kept a Haberdasher's shop; and, if I went there, his wife could tell me further about it. He said, there were about 90 yards of different sorts of black ribband offered to her by a man. My mistress and I went there; Mrs. Jones told us where the man lived. I sent for him (that is, Saunders Joseph) to a public house, and told him I kept a little shop, and had an order for some ribbands more than I had got, and said, I was recommended to him by Mrs. Jones. He said, the man took them away last night; they are a particular friend's of mine, that lives at the other end of the town; I am going there, and I will inquire if he has sold them, and I'll let you know.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17611209-23-verdict138" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611209-23-verdict138" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
