<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17671021-47">
               <interp inst="t17671021-47" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17671021-47" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17671021-47" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17671021"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17671021-47" type="date" value="17671021"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17671021-47-off266-c396" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-47-defend501 t17671021-47-off266 t17671021-47-verdict270"></join>
         
               <p>578. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17671021-47-defend501" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Pentecost 
                  <interp inst="t17671021-47-defend501" type="surname" value="Pentecost"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-47-defend501" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-47-defend501" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17671021-47-off266" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17671021-47-off266" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-47-off266" type="offenceSubcategory" value="fraud"></interp>
               obtaining divers goods, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17671021-47-victim503" type="victimName">
                           Charles 
                           Bartrum 
                        <interp inst="t17671021-47-victim503" type="surname" value="Bartrum"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671021-47-victim503" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671021-47-victim503" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-47-off266 t17671021-47-victim503"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , by false pretences
            </rs>, <rs id="t17671021-47-cd267" type="crimeDate">Feb. 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-47-off266 t17671021-47-cd267"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-47-person504">
                  Charles 
                  Bartrum 
               <interp inst="t17671021-47-person504" type="surname" value="Bartrum"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-47-person504" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-47-person504" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I <rs id="t17671021-47-viclabel268" type="occupation">keep a hardware-shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-47-victim503 t17671021-47-viclabel268"></join> on <placeName id="t17671021-47-crimeloc269">Fish-street-hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17671021-47-crimeloc269" type="placeName" value="Fish-street-hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17671021-47-crimeloc269" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-47-off266 t17671021-47-crimeloc269"></join>; on the 2d of February the prisoner came into my shop, between the hours of eleven and one, and said he wanted some plaited buckles; he said he was a merchant, and traded to America; he said I must charge them upon the very lowest terms, for he always paid ready money, and if I used him well he should be a very good customer to me; he came round my counter to my show-glass, and was pulling out some metal buckles, and was taking out two or three dozen of a pattern; I said, you had better have one dozen of a pattern, that will suit that country best; he said, very well, then let it be so; he chose out to the amount of 14 l. 1 s. in goods; he gave me this card, and said, that was his name upon it, that is, 
               <persName id="t17671021-47-person505">
                  James 
                  Pontry 
               <interp inst="t17671021-47-person505" type="surname" value="Pontry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-47-person505" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-47-person505" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (producing the card from a good engraving on copper-plate;) he said there was his name on the door; the card was, 
               <persName id="t17671021-47-person506">
                  James 
                  Pontry 
               <interp inst="t17671021-47-person506" type="surname" value="Pontry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-47-person506" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-47-person506" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at No 18, Fish-street, near Friday-street, Cheapside; he pretended he should be an exceeding good customer if I used him well; I was to send the goods the next morning to his house, by nine o'clock, and he said he would pay the money upon delivery; accordingly I went with my boy, 
               <persName id="t17671021-47-person507">
                  James 
                  Sims 
               <interp inst="t17671021-47-person507" type="surname" value="Sims"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-47-person507" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-47-person507" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at the time.</p>
               <p>Q. What goods had he agreed for?</p>
               <p>Bartrum. Three dozen of buckles plaited with silver, two dozen of plaited spurs, nineteen dozen of metal buckles, which is 228 pair; I was informed the person was a new comer; I found the house with the name on the door, and a boy waiting at the door; I asked if the gentleman was at home; the boy said, no; I said, when will he be at home; he said, it will be an hour first. Upon this, I having a little business to do at the Bank, I said to my boy, be sure you receive 14 l. 1 s. for these goods before you deliver them, and do not you stir till I come back again, and left the bill with him; upon this I went up Friday-street, and fearing the prisoner should not be a good man, I returned to his house in about a quarter of an hour, and when I came there my boy was gone; I asked the prisoner's boy if his master was come home; he said he was; I said, has my boy received the money; he said, no; I said, where are the goods; he said, they were locked up stairs; I followed my boy, and said, you rascal, you are cheated, this fellow is a cheat; said he, the man tore the receipt off the bill, and gave me that.</p>
               <p>Q. Should you have trusted him had he come in his true name?</p>
               <p>Bartrum. I was to have ready money.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you find that he is a merchant trading to America?</p>
               <p>Bartrum. No; when I was before Sir 
               <persName id="t17671021-47-person508">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17671021-47-person508" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-47-person508" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-47-person508" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , they said he was a common thief, after I had described him; my boy told me he said, give my compliments to your master, and I will call upon him at two o'clock, and tore the receipt off the bill, and gave it him; he came at two o'clock, and ordered more goods to be sent the next morning, that was three dozen of plaited buckles, twelve dozen of knives, and three dozen of razors, all to the amount of 7 l. 11 s. and said he would pay both together; I packed them up, and went the next morning with the box of goods; when I came there, I had for answer much the same as the day before from the boy in waiting; upon that I ordered my boy back with the goods; and I went backwards and forwards several times, till I was thoroughly convinced he had cheated me out of my goods; he left that house three or four days after, and I never saw him till I saw him in New Prison.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Here is Mr. Bartrum's bill (producing a bill.)</p>
               <p>Bartrum. This is my hand-writing, it is the bill of the goods, the receipt is torn off.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176710210032"></xptr>It is read in court, the contents 14 l. 1 s.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. What passed at Hickes's-hall?</p>
               <p>Bartrum. The prisoner called out to me, and said, I shall get rid of this presently (meaning what he was then to be tried there for;) I shall move this into the King's-Bench, and put you into the Exchequer; I will pay you, said he, when this is over, come to me when this is over, but I never did go to him after that.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Did you not tell me, if I would pay you seven guineas, you would not prosecute?</p>
               <p>Bartrum. He never offered me a farthing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-47-person509">
                  James 
                  Sims 
               <interp inst="t17671021-47-person509" type="surname" value="Sims"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-47-person509" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-47-person509" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I am servant to Mr. Bartrum; on the 3d of February my master left me at No 18, in Fish-street, with the box of plaited buckles, spurs, and metal buckles, and ordered me not to deliver the box without the money, 14 l. 1 s.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was you to deliver it to?</p>
               <p>Sims. I was to deliver it to Mr. Pontry, at No 18, Fish-street; this is the bill here produced, there was a receipt at the bottom, but that the prisoner tore off; my master left me, and went to the Bank; in about ten or twelve minutes the prisoner came in, who had said his name was Pontry; I told him I had brought the goods, and showed him the bill, and said they came to 14 l. 1 s. I delivered the bill, he tore the receipt off, and gave it to me, and said, give my compliments to your master, and tell him I shall want more goods, and shall call upon him at two o'clock; I never saw him after till I saw him at Sir 
               <persName id="t17671021-47-person510">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17671021-47-person510" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-47-person510" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-47-person510" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. What time did you deliver them?</p>
               <p>Sims. I delivered them about nine in the morning.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Are you sure you delivered them to me, or to a porter in his own hair?</p>
               <p>Sims. I am sure it was to you.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-47-person511">
                  John 
                  Noaks 
               <interp inst="t17671021-47-person511" type="surname" value="Noaks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-47-person511" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-47-person511" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was apprehended for a fraud; I was before Sir 
               <persName id="t17671021-47-person512">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17671021-47-person512" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-47-person512" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-47-person512" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he told Sir John if he would admit him an evidence, he would have 
               <persName id="t17671021-47-person513">
                  Francis 
                  Parsons 
               <interp inst="t17671021-47-person513" type="surname" value="Parsons"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-47-person513" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-47-person513" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and all the rest taken; I have known him six or seven years, he is no merchant, he gave in his name Pentecost, and showed me where some of these buckles were, and I have them here (produced in court;) the prosecutor deposed he believed them to be some of the same in the parcel.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-47-person514">
                  John 
                  Everit 
               <interp inst="t17671021-47-person514" type="surname" value="Everit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-47-person514" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-47-person514" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am deputy-keeper of Wood-street Compter; the prisoner, and his father before him, went by the name of Pentecost; he is no merchant.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>Mr. Bartrum came to me at Hickes's-hall, and said, if I would give him seven guineas, he would not indict me; my name is Pontry.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17671021-47-verdict270" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17671021-47-verdict270" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17671021-47-punish271" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17671021-47-punish271" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-47-defend501 t17671021-47-punish271"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>See him tried, No 513, in last Sessions Paper.</p>
            </div1>
