<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640222-20">
               <interp inst="t17640222-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640222-20" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640222-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640222"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640222-20" type="date" value="17640222"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640222-20-off107-c127" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-20-defend168 t17640222-20-off107 t17640222-20-verdict110"></join>
         
               <p>147. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17640222-20-defend168" type="defendantName">
                     Margaret 
                     Simpson 
                  <interp inst="t17640222-20-defend168" type="surname" value="Simpson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-20-defend168" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-20-defend168" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17640222-20-deflabel106" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-20-defend168 t17640222-20-deflabel106"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17640222-20-off107" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640222-20-off107" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-20-off107" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing a 36 s. piece, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640222-20-victim170" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Cole 
                        <interp inst="t17640222-20-victim170" type="surname" value="Cole"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640222-20-victim170" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640222-20-victim170" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-20-off107 t17640222-20-victim170"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17640222-20-cd108" type="crimeDate">Jan. 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-20-off107 t17640222-20-cd108"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640222-20-person171">
                  William 
                  Cole 
               <interp inst="t17640222-20-person171" type="surname" value="Cole"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-20-person171" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-20-person171" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Sunday night, the 15th of January, I was coming from St. James's end of the town to Billingsgate, I met the prisoner on Ludgate-hill, a little after eight at night; she took hold of me, and asked me if I would go along with her; I asked her where she lived, she said, Just by; I went along with her to <placeName id="t17640222-20-crimeloc109">Addle hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640222-20-crimeloc109" type="placeName" value="Addle hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640222-20-crimeloc109" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-20-off107 t17640222-20-crimeloc109"></join>, into a private house up one pair of stairs; there was another woman in the room some time; she went out for something to drink, while my pocket was picked by the prisoner of a 36 s. piece, and a brass pocket-piece was put into my pocket in the room of it.</p>
               <p>Q. How came she to have an opportunity to do it?</p>
               <p>Cole. We were upon the bed at the time; I was going to be familiar with her, but after I found that I declined; upon the other coming in with what we sent for to drink, I got from the bed, and felt in my pocket and found it out.</p>
               <p>Q. Then what spoiled your familiarity?</p>
               <p>Cole. That was the other woman coming in.</p>
               <p>Q. Where had you spent that day?</p>
               <p>Cole. I had been with my Brother that lives with Esquire Castle in Spring-gardens.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober?</p>
               <p>Cole. I was quite sober, I had drank only one pot of beer with my brother.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you seen your 36 s. piece?</p>
               <p>Cole. I took it out of my pocket and looked at it after the other woman was gone out of the room: I had that, a sixpence, and half-a-guinea; I charged the prisoner with it, she said she knew nothing about it; I asked her if she knew any thing of the brass piece, she said she did, and that it was her own; she stript off some of her cloaths to let me see she had it not; I searched the bed but could not find it; I kept her in the room till 10 o'clock; then I charged the watch with her; I offered her half-a-guinea if she would return it, but she would not own that she had it; she was carried before Mr. Alderman Rawlinson the next day, but she said nothing there.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>The prosecutor seemed to be very much in liquor; I know nothing of his money; I buy and sell old cloaths; I was at that house, he took hold of me and charged me; I never was upon Ludgate-hill that night.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640222-20-verdict110" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640222-20-verdict110" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
