<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640607-13">
               <interp inst="t17640607-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640607-13" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640607-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640607"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640607-13" type="date" value="17640607"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640607-13-off80-c109" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-13-defend137 t17640607-13-off80 t17640607-13-verdict83"></join>
         
               <p>332. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17640607-13-defend137" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Patrick 
                     Medley 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17640607-13-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-13-defend137 t17640607-13-alias-1"></join>Mealey</rs>, otherwise <rs id="t17640607-13-alias-2" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-13-defend137 t17640607-13-alias-2"></join>James Gray</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-13-defend137" type="surname" value="Medley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-13-defend137" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-13-defend137" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17640607-13-off80" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640607-13-off80" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-13-off80" type="offenceSubcategory" value="shoplifting"></interp>
               stealing a gun, value 20 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640607-13-victim140" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Blewet 
                        <interp inst="t17640607-13-victim140" type="surname" value="Blewet"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640607-13-victim140" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640607-13-victim140" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-13-off80 t17640607-13-victim140"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the shop of the said William
            </rs>, <rs id="t17640607-13-cd81" type="crimeDate">February 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-13-off80 t17640607-13-cd81"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640607-13-person141">
                  William 
                  Blewet 
               <interp inst="t17640607-13-person141" type="surname" value="Blewet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-13-person141" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-13-person141" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am <rs id="t17640607-13-viclabel82" type="occupation">a gun-maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-13-victim140 t17640607-13-viclabel82"></join>, and live in Whitechapel-road, facing the Mount. On the 29th of February, between ten and eleven in the forenoon, the prisoner came to my house; the witness and another sailor were with him. I not being at home, was sent for, and told to go to the Red-lion alehouse to them. I went to them; the prisoner said, Do you not know me? I said yes; you are come to pay me 4 s. the difference between a gun and a pistol, which we agreed for last night: he had came to me; I was in bed; he came up stairs without With-your-leave, or By-your-leave, and asked me what I would give for an old gun? and he brings a pistol of mine in his hand, which he had in the shop: he asked what he must give me in exchange? we agreed for him to give me 4 s. he carried the pistol away, and left the gun, and was to come again to pay me. When at the Red Lyon, he said he wanted to speak with me: I went into the yard with him; he said an officer belonging to an Indiaman wanted a pair of pistols, and wanted me to let him carry them to him; I told him he could not expect that, as I did not know him: then he shewed me a note, which he said he had, which was an order of the captains, to bring some things. I let him have the pistols, and agreed to have a guinea for them. Dinner was getting ready; he and the sailor staid and dined: at going away, the prisoner and sailor went through the shop; Harding whom they hired for a porter, did not. As they were got cross the way, Harding said, that<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176406070009"></xptr> man has got a gun; I had seen it in the shop about ten minutes before: Harding went after him, and I thought would have brought him back, but I saw no more of them at that time. On the first of March, I had orders from the Justices at Greenwich, to come there; I went, and found the prisoner in the cage: he was taken before the justice; there I saw my gun lying on the justice's table; so it was flung upon poor Will to prosecute. ( The gun produced in court.) This gun was delivered to me to be cleaned.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640607-13-person142">
                  James 
                  Harding 
               <interp inst="t17640607-13-person142" type="surname" value="Harding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-13-person142" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-13-person142" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Spittal-fields. The prisoner came to a public-house that day, and told me he had some goods at Deptford, and he would give me half a guinea if I would go and bring them safe, but I must be careful how I carried them: he said he had been to the Indies, and the things came from thence: he bid me put on my regi mentals. The note mentioned so many dozen of handkerchiefs, and so many dozen of china cups and saucers, and the like; and at the bottom of the note, was put, That the waterman had a bottle of slip: this was to be for a token that I came from the right person. I was to go for the things to the lower water-gate, at Deptford, and he went up Whitechapel, saying, he wanted to speak with a man, to whom he sold a gun: the prosecutor not being at home, we went to the Red Lyon, and he came there to us; he desired me to shew the prosecutor the note, which I did. After we had been at the prosecutor's house, I saw him going away with a gun in his hand; I said to the prosecutor, he has taken a gun; he had got a brace of pistols in his bosom: I went after him, and said, What do you do with that gun? he said he was going to make a present of it to a captain that was going to the Indies: we went all three of us to Deptford; there he went into a public-house, and called for a pint of beer; then he said, do you make all the speed you can to Mr. Butler's, and give him that note, and give it to none but him. I set out with a basket, and went to Mr. Butler's, at the Baptist-Head, at the Lower Water-gate, and delivered the note to him, expecting he would have delivered the things mentioned in it; he looked at it, and said it was a fraud, and I was the third porter that he had sent with such notes. I had lent the prisoner my silk handkerchief coming along, and made all the haste back I could to see for him; Mr. Butler said, if I could bring him to him, he would give me a crown. I had two or three men went with me: he was gone from the alehouse, but a gentleman's servant told us he had seen a man with a gun coming with two men on the back of Greenland-dock; we went, and met with him: I demanded my handkerchief from his neck, and we brought him and the gun to Mr. Butler's: he had sold the pair of pistols to one of the persons with him, but had not received the money: they are now at the justice's.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I owned the prosecutor 4 s. we agreed for a gun for 18 s. but I know nothing of this gun.</p>
               <p>Q. to Harding. Was there any agreement between the prosecutor and prisoner about a gun?</p>
               <p>Harding. While the prosecutor was doing something to a flint, the prisoner then stood with this gun in his hand, and they talked together in the back yard, but what they said I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640607-13-verdict83" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640607-13-verdict83" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
