<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680224-15">
               <interp inst="t17680224-15" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680224-15" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680224-15" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680224"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680224-15" type="date" value="17680224"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680224-15-off89-c130" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-15-defend160 t17680224-15-off89 t17680224-15-verdict92"></join>
         
               <p>169. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17680224-15-defend160" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Knight 
                  <interp inst="t17680224-15-defend160" type="surname" value="Knight"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-15-defend160" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-15-defend160" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17680224-15-off89" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680224-15-off89" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-15-off89" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing a gold watch, value 20 l. a cornelian seal set in gold, value 4 s. two guineas, and a piece of foreign gold, value 3 l. 7 s. 6 d. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17680224-15-victim162" type="victimName">
                           David 
                           Mitchell 
                        <interp inst="t17680224-15-victim162" type="surname" value="Mitchell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680224-15-victim162" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680224-15-victim162" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-15-off89 t17680224-15-victim162"></join>
                     </persName>
                     
                  , privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17680224-15-cd90" type="crimeDate">Jan. 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-15-off89 t17680224-15-cd90"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-15-person163">
                  David 
                  Mitchell 
               <interp inst="t17680224-15-person163" type="surname" value="Mitchell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-15-person163" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-15-person163" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17680224-15-viclabel91" type="occupation">merchant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-15-victim162 t17680224-15-viclabel91"></join>, and live in Crutched-friars; on the 23d of January, between twelve and one in the morning, I was going home, after having spent the evening, where I had drank very freely, I was accosted by the prisoner at the bar, and in her company was another woman, whom I did not take notice of; she was in Corn-hill, near the corner of Gracechurch-street; she took hold of my arm, and wanted to go along with me; I turned down Gracechurch-street, but could not disengage myself from the prisoner; she still persisted to go along with me, till we came to the corner of Fenchurch-street; she had address enough to continue by me till I came into Fenchurch-street; sometimes she had hold of my arm, and sometimes I disengaged myself, so as to make her quit her hold; she continued importuning me to go with her some where or other,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176802240010"></xptr> saying, she wanted to speak with me; she prevailed upon me to stop at a court in Fenchurch-street; we went a little way into the court, out of mere curiosity, to see what the woman could mean; she began to be very amorous, and got one arm round me, and began to be very loving: in the mean time, with her other hand, I found her fumbling about my breeches; she had art enough to address me for about ten minutes; I disengaged myself from her, and found she had taken my watch, a gold one, and all I had out of my right-hand pocket; there was a pocket-piece, value about two moidores and a half, and about three guineas; it was done like slight of hand; she did all she could to get me to be concerned with her, which I absolutely refused; I looked about upon the ground, and kept hold of her; at the same time I saw the other woman just behind her; I could find nothing; I carried the prisoner to the watch-house, and kept her in custody till the next morning, then I carried her before my Lord Mayor; he knowing her to be an old offender, desired me to prosecute her; she was very willing to be searched; the other woman went directly away when I missed my watch and money, I am sure the prisoner must give them to her; I believe that other woman never touched me; I do really think it was impossible for the other woman to pick my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you had your watch and money when you met with the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Mitchell. I had at that time felt them in my pocket; I did not perceive her hand within side my breeches.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in liquor?</p>
               <p>Mitchell. I was not very much in liquor; I cannot say but this affair brought me more to myself than before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Mitchell. I never saw her before that night to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you found your watch again?</p>
               <p>Mitchell. No, I have not.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Whether you did not make that other woman a present of a couple of shillings, she being first with you?</p>
               <p>Mitchell. No, I did not, she was not first with me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was along with a woman; he wanted me to go along with him; I said, excuse me, I am going home; he said he would make me a present of 5 s. 3 d. he put his hand in his pocket, and wanted to make me a present of 3 d. to buy half a quartern of brandy; I said I could put my hand in my pocket and find 3 d. at any time, I would not take it; I was going away; he said, my dear, stop, and let me talk to you; he wanted me to go and drink a glass of wine with him; he said he had no money about him, but he would make me a present of a 5 s. 3 d. I said, if you want to see me another night, you may; the watchman came past, and said, what are you doing; the gentleman said, I am only talking to this lady; the other woman stood by all the while; he said he would treat the watchman with something; we stood talking a quarter of an hour; the watchman came again, and said, you are a long while talking, and desired we would go along about our business; I said, we were about no harm; he said, if you do not go along I will make you; then I set out, and stopped at the corner, and the gentleman came to me, and said he had lost seven guineas; then he said he had lost three or four guineas; he took me to the watch-house, and they stripped me to my smock, and found nothing upon me.</p>
               <p>Q to prosecutor. What say you to this?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. This is all real invention, there is not a tittle of it true; she told the magistrate a different story; I neither offered her a 5 s. 3 d. not 3 d. I did not mean to stay with either of them, it was really a piece of simple curiosity in me.</p>
               <p>To her character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-15-person164">
                  Mary 
                  Chapman 
               <interp inst="t17680224-15-person164" type="surname" value="Chapman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-15-person164" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-15-person164" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner served her time with me; I know her to be a very honest person.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did she serve you?</p>
               <p>M. Chapman. She served me five years, and worked for me since.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>M. Chapman. I live in Bishopsgate-street; I never heard any thing dishonest of her in my life-time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-15-person165">
                  Joseph 
                  Magleshan 
               <interp inst="t17680224-15-person165" type="surname" value="Magleshan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-15-person165" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-15-person165" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . In live in Holywell-lane, Shoreditch.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Magleshan. I am an apothecary and surgeon; the prisoner used to come and bring home work from Mrs. Chapman to my wife.</p>
               <p>Q. What is Mrs. Chapman?</p>
               <p>Magleshan. She is a mantua-maker; my wife used to leave the prisoner in her room, where were many things of value; we never lost any thing.</p>
               <p>For the prosecution.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-15-person166">
                  William 
                  Pain 
               <interp inst="t17680224-15-person166" type="surname" value="Pain"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-15-person166" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-15-person166" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was a constable for the city about two years since; the prisoner is a common<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176802240011"></xptr> street-walker, and well known in all the prisons in the city.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17680224-15-verdict92" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680224-15-verdict92" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>See her tried before for a fact of the same nature, by the name of Mary Cluse, No 98, in the last mayoralty.</p>
            </div1>
