<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650522-24">
               <interp inst="t17650522-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-24" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650522"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-24" type="date" value="17650522"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650522-24-off149-c238" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-24-defend286 t17650522-24-off149 t17650522-24-verdict152"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650522-24-off153-c238" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-24-defend286 t17650522-24-off153 t17650522-24-verdict152"></join>
         
               <p>321. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17650522-24-defend286" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Crew 
                  <interp inst="t17650522-24-defend286" type="surname" value="Crew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-defend286" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-defend286" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for that <rs id="t17650522-24-off149" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-off149" type="offenceCategory" value="breakingPeace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-off149" type="offenceSubcategory" value="wounding"></interp>
               he, with a certain gun, value 10 s. loaded with gun-powder and a leaden bullet, wilfully, maliciously, and feloniously, did shoot at 
                     
                        <persName id="t17650522-24-victim288" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Thomas 
                        <interp inst="t17650522-24-victim288" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650522-24-victim288" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650522-24-victim288" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , then being in the dwelling house of the said William Crew
            </rs>, <rs id="t17650522-24-cd150" type="crimeDate">May 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-24-off149 t17650522-24-cd150"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-24-off153 t17650522-24-cd150"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-24-person289">
                  Thomas 
                  Nuthall 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person289" type="surname" value="Nuthall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person289" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person289" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esquire. I have known the prisoner a great many years; he lived in a house on <placeName id="t17650522-24-crimeloc151">Enfield Chase near Clay-Hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17650522-24-crimeloc151" type="placeName" value="Enfield Chase near Clay-Hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17650522-24-crimeloc151" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-24-off149 t17650522-24-crimeloc151"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-24-off153 t17650522-24-crimeloc151"></join>. In the year 1757, an information was filed against him and many others in the Duchy court of Lancaster, in the name of the Attorney General of that Duchy, on his Majesty's behalf, for erecting buildings, and inclosing great quantities of land, belonging to his Majesty, without any authority or right whatsoever, upon Enfield Chase, which is parcel of the Duchy of Lancaster, and the inheritance of the crown. The cause came on to be heard before the Chancellor of the Duchy, and Lord Mansfield and 
               <persName id="t17650522-24-person290">
                  Baron 
                  Smythe 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person290" type="surname" value="Smythe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person290" type="given" value="Baron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person290" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , as Judges assistant of that court, on the 3d of March 1764, and the decree was afterwards exemplified under the seal of the court. The defendants were ordered and decreed forthwith to deliver up to me, as his Majesty's Surveyor, possession of the buildings and lands claimed by them, for his Majesty's use, which the court, by the decree, declared to be incroachments upon Enfield Chase, and made in derogation and infringement of his Majesty's right and title. (The exemplification of the decree produced.) The prisoner had time given him to shew cause against this decree; for which purpose this subpoena, (a subpoena produced) under the seal of the court, was served on him, as will appear in evidence, on the 21st of April; but on his not shewing cause , the decree was made absolute against him, by an order of the court made the 16th of May 1764, and that order, together with the decree, were exemplified on the 23d of that month. Upon the prisoner's being served with a copy of this exemplification, and his refusal to obey the decree, on the fourth of July the court made an order that an attachment should issued against him unless he delivered up possession of the premisses mentioned in the decree, by a certain day, which he still refusing to do, an attachment issued against him on th 7th of August, for a contempt of the court. Upon the return of that writ by the Sheriff, that the prisoner could not be found, the court ordered an injunction to issue against him, which bore date the 21st of November 1764. The prisoner was by that writ commanded and enjoined to quit possession, immediately, of the premisses, upon pain of five thousand pounds, and to permit me to enter, and to hold the same for his Majesty's use, without any interruption or molestation. (The injunction produced.) This injunction was served on the prisoner, as will appear, on the 26th of November, and upon his refusing to obey it, on the 28th of November the court ordered a writ of assistance to issue, which bore date that day, directed to the Sheriff of Middlesex, and the Sheriff's warrant upon that writ to his officers is dated the 20th of December. (Both produced.) The Sheriff is by the writ of assistance commanded to put me in quiet possession of the premisses therein mentioned for his Majesty's use, and to attach the body of the prisoner for his disobedience to the decree, and contempt of the court. Previous to the filing of the information against the Prisoner and the other defendants, who were eleven in number, I had directions to let them know, they were at liberty to take down their buildings upon the King's Chase, and sell the materials for their own use. The prisoner told me he would never quit the house he lived in as long as he lived; that he would be carried dead out of it, and set the court at defiance. He afterwards put in his answer to the information, but examined no witnesses. Several of the defendants agreed to throw open their incroachments, others agreed to abide by the event of the suit, so that witnesses were examined on the part of the crown, and the cause heard against the prisoner and four other defendants only. The prisoner told me he would give himself no more trouble about looking for witnesses; he swore he would be at no more expence in the cause, and would never quit possession. It was on the 19th of June 1764, I served him with the exemplification of the decree; I told him, I believed it was not then too late to throw himself on the mercy of the court, and that if he would apply, the court would probably give him leave to sell the materials of his house, and put the money in his pocket; he said, the court might as well pretend to pull the King's palace down; I must take care how I came there; it should be the worse for any body that came there for any such purpose; he always kept that in his house which would defend him; he would never give up the premisses to the crown, nor any one living; that he would knock any man's brains<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176505220025"></xptr> out, that came to take his house from him, and used all manner of abusive language. I represented to him the consequences of his obstinacy, and told him the Sheriff of the county would be directed to take possession of the premises, and send him to prison for his contempt of the court. His answer was, that, The court and all their officers might be d - d: he wished he could see any body come into his house without his leave, to take any thing he had from him; that was the sport he wanted to be at.</p>

               <p>Q. In what manner did you serve him with this exemplification?</p>
               <p>A. I delivered a true copy of it into his own hand, at his house; told him the contents of it, and at the same time shewed him the exemplification under the seal of the court, and demanded the possession according to the decree, which he refused to give, with many oaths and imprecations. The other defendants in that decree have delivered up possession, and now hold of the crown at small yearly rents.</p>
               <p>After the attachment issued against the prisoner, several attempts were made to apprehend him, but to no purpose: when the writ of assistance issued, other officers were added, belonging to the Sheriff of Middlesex, viz. 
               <persName id="t17650522-24-person291">
                  William 
                  Norden 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person291" type="surname" value="Norden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person291" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person291" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17650522-24-person292">
                  Miles 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person292" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person292" type="given" value="Miles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person292" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 13th of this present month of May I went with these officers, and five or six men they brought with them as assistants. 
               <persName id="t17650522-24-person293">
                  John 
                  Thomas 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person293" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person293" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person293" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             mentioned in the indictment was one of them. They were to give me possession of the premises claimed by the prisoner, and mentioned in the decree and the Sheriff's warrant, for the use of his Majesty. I took my servant with me. We got to the prisoner's house about six in the morning: I went to the back-door, whilst the officers went to the fore-door. Within a very few minutes, I heard a gun go off. I then rode round to the fore-door, got off my horse, and went into the house: the officers had brought the prisoner down stairs into the kitchen; as soon as he saw me he said, G - d d - n your blood, this is your doing. He was then putting on his clothes, and put himself in a great passion, and swore incessantly. The officers gave me a gun, which they said he had shot off at them. The prisoner said, D - n you, what business had you in my house? (or my room). I perceived it was a rifle-barrel'd gun, that would carry a bullet only, and not shot. I was then desired to go up stairs to examine the room where the gun had been shot off. The room was on the right hand of the stair-case; I found the key in the door, which easily turned the lock: it was a spring lock: there was no latch, nor handle to the lock. I examined the door, and found there was nothing broke, nor any appearance of force used. The room was in a sinother from the gun powder, and I think the window was shut. I went towards the bed, which is opposite to the dco, and found the gun had been shot off from the bed; the ball had gone through a wooden mantle piece over the chimney, on the right-hand side of the room from the bed, had broke a glass all to-pieces, which appeared to have hung above the mantle-piece, then graz'd the wall on that side, and had struck against another wall facing the bed, which was a plaister wall, at some distance from the door, and on the same side of the room. I found one bullet on the mantle-piece, but that was not the bullet shot out of the gun, for it had not received any difference in shape Afterwards I sent my servant, 
               <persName id="t17650522-24-person294">
                  John 
                  Barratclough 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person294" type="surname" value="Barratclough"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person294" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person294" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , to search in the room for the bullet, which he will produce. When I returned down stairs, one of the officers asked the prisoner how he could be guilty of a thing of this nature; he answered, It was good enough for him. I told him I believed it was a capital offence; he made the same kind of answer, swore as many oaths as he could utter, and was extremely violent and turbulent. I observed to him, this rifle-barrel'd gun was only for killing deer, and asked him what he did with it; he said he had got his living by it these twenty years. He was afterwards carried to London by the officers.</p>
               <p>The exemplification of the decree read in court: the decree was made the 3d of March; the exemplification was dated the 23d of May 1764: Also the subpoena to shew cause against the decree dated the 3d of April. The injunction also was read, dated the 21st of November.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-24-person295">
                  John 
                  Barratclough 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person295" type="surname" value="Barratclough"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person295" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person295" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Nuthall.</p>
               <p>Court. Look at this (the subpoena put into his hand.)</p>
               <p>Barratclough. I served a copy of this upon the prisoner on the 21st of April 1764, at his own house, and shewed him the original.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any conversation with him about his quitting the possession.</p>
               <p>Barratclough. He abus'd me very much, and d - d me, and the court, and said we might all go and be d - d together, when I told him this was for quitting his house. I examined it with the original; it was a true copy.</p>
               <p>(The injunction was then shewn Barratclough.)</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176505220026"></xptr>Barratclough. I served him with a copy of this on the 26th of November. I met with him just by his house: he went in and shut the door, and call'd to me out at the window, and swore he had a good mind to shoot at me. I was at his house with my master, Mr. Norden, 
               <persName id="t17650522-24-person296">
                  Miles 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person296" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person296" type="given" value="Miles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person296" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17650522-24-person297">
                  John 
                  Thomas 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person297" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person297" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person297" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and others, on the 13th of this month: I believe we got there by six in the morning. I was not in the house till he was taken. I heard the gun go off: I know Thomas and Pawlet were both in the house at the time the gun went off. The prisoner was coming away to prison when I went in; I went up stairs and looked at the place where the bullet went through the mantle-piece. It went into the wall, about half an inch deep in the brick-work, and returned from thence and struck another wall, and broke a china cup; here is some of the china in the ball now: it went into the wall near the door, and made a good deal of impression there. I found the ball within three or four inches of the wall, upon the floor. (The bullet and gun produced in court.) The officers brought the gun down stairs when the prisoner was brought down; it was delivered to me by 
               <persName id="t17650522-24-person298">
                  John 
                  Thomas 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person298" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person298" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person298" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            : I took it to my master's house; it has been in his custody ever since.</p>
               <p>The writ of assistance read, dated the 28th of November 1764. The Sheriff's warrant read, dated the 20th December.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-24-person299">
                  William 
                  Norden 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person299" type="surname" value="Norden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person299" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person299" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an officer to the Sheriff of Middlesex.</p>
               <p>Court. Look at this writ.</p>
               <p>Norden. This is our Sheriff's seal, (touching it) the seal of the office: this writ was delivered to me by Mr. Nuthall. I went accordingly to execute it in company with 
               <persName id="t17650522-24-person300">
                  Miles 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person300" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person300" type="given" value="Miles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person300" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I and 
               <persName id="t17650522-24-person301">
                  Miles 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person301" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person301" type="given" value="Miles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person301" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             are two persons mentioned in that writ: We had six assistants; we went to the prisoner's house on Enfield Chase; we got there a little before six in the morning, on the 13th of this instant: we had given directions to our men, and divided them, that they might not go all in together: the house was open. One of our assistants went in with a strange man; they were to go and call for a pint of beer as two strangers going by, and as soon as they were got in they call'd for a pint of beer; the prisoner's wife went down to draw it; they gave a signal, and Pawlet and Thomas went in: I followed them as fast as I could: I was on horse-back: when I got in they were up stairs or going up: I saw them going up while I was getting off my horse: I was up stairs, I believe, within two seconds after the gun was fired: I found Thomas and Pawlet in the room: Thomas had hold of the muzzle of the gun, and the prisoner had hold of the but-end, sitting on the bed, and they had hold of him: they had shov'd him back; he was rather lying, and in his shirt; they were struggling for the gun; I could hardly distinguish any thing for the smoke; it was a little room; I ran and opened the window: we led him down stairs: this is the gun here produced. He d - d us, and used us with a great deal of ill language, and wished he had killed two or three of us, after he was come down stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. How many persons did you find in the room?</p>
               <p>Norden. There were only Thomas, Pawlet, and the prisoner; by this time Mr. Nuthall came in; the prisoner grin'd at him, and d - d him, and said he wished he had killed him; he said if he had killed him he would not have minded being hang'd directly. Mr. Smith came to London with him. After they were gone, Mr. Nuthall's man and I went up into the bed-chamber, and examined which way the ball went. I saw the dent in the wall; we saw the ball lying on the floor; he stooped down and took it up; it had gone thro' the chimney-piece, and graz'd the wall, and went back to another wall, where it lay. I put it to the place in the wall, it fitted the place exactly: I said I was sure that ball made the mark: the key of the door was on the out-side when it was shut.</p>
               <p>Q. Did there appear any violence used on the door?</p>
               <p>Norden. No, there did not.</p>
               <p>Q. How large was the room?</p>
               <p>Norden. It is but a small room; it will hold a bed, a small table, and half a dozen chairs. The door opens directly facing the foot of the bed: the mantle-piece was to the left hand at going in: the ball struck last on that part of the wall behind the door, about two feet from the edge of the door: It is a square room, about 12 feet by 14 or 16; the door opens to the left hand.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How far from the door is the feet of the bed?</p>
               <p>Norden. I suppose the door does not open above three feet from it; the room will not hold a table on each side of the bed; I believe there was a table in the room, but I did not take particular<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176505220027"></xptr> notice: there was a chair in the room, for I sat down in one.</p>
               <p>Q. What part of the bed did the prisoner sit upon?</p>
               <p>Norden. He was sitting on the left hand side of the bed when I went into the room, that side next the mantle-piece.</p>
               <p>Q. Who had the Sheriff's writ when the gun went off?</p>
               <p>Norden. I had that in my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. Before that time had you told the prisoner who you was?</p>
               <p>Norden. There had not been time for it, but I told him before those expressions came out from him, who I was, and what was my errand. I told him this was what I expected; for the country all round had told me what I might expect.</p>
               <p>Court. Look upon this name upon this warrant. (He takes it in his hand.)</p>
               <p>Q. When was your name put to it?</p>
               <p>Norden. My name was not put to it when I first saw it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the seal to it when you first saw it?</p>
               <p>Norden. It was; my name was put to it after the seal was to it; that is what is done every day.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was Smith when you went into the house?</p>
               <p>Norden. He was along with me, he followed me in.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Smith's name to it when you first saw it.</p>
               <p>Norden. No, it was not; that was put in by order of the Sheriff; Mr. Grigg said he had recommended me to Mr. Nuthall, and I was present when my name was put in by one of our clerks at the office; and 
               <persName id="t17650522-24-person302">
                  Miles 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person302" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person302" type="given" value="Miles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person302" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's name was put in at the same time.</p>
               <p>Q. Whose hand-writing is your name and 
               <persName id="t17650522-24-person303">
                  Miles 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person303" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person303" type="given" value="Miles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person303" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's?</p>
               <p>Norden. I believe, Mr. Benson's hand-writing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-24-person304">
                  John 
                  Thomas 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person304" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person304" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I act occasionally as assistant to Mr. Norden and 
               <persName id="t17650522-24-person305">
                  Miles 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person305" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person305" type="given" value="Miles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person305" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was with them on the 13th of May, at the prisoner's house on Enfield Chase, at six in the morning; we went to execute a warrant upon him. I went into the house as soon as the door was open, and another man followed me: I do not know his name; he belonged to Mr. Smith, and I belonged to Mr. Norden: when I came into the house I did not see any thing of the prisoner; I went up stairs, there was the key in the door, I turned that; there I saw the prisoner sitting on the side of the bed: the door opened without any noise at all; the other man was at my back: the prisoner presented this gun, and made a level at me the moment I came in at the door: he had nothing but his shirt on: I took hold of the muzzle and turned it off with my hand.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was you to him when you opened the door?</p>
               <p>Thomas. I believe I was about three yards from the muzzle of the piece, or hardly so much: he never said a word till after the piece went off; I put my right hand to it, and laid hold of him; he said, if I did not loose him, he would kill some of us: I secured him as well as I could, and Mr. Norden was just at my heels: in the struggle the prisoner received some blow; the room was in a smother on firing the piece: the piece went off immediately as soon as I touched it.</p>
               <p>Q. What instrument had you in your hand?</p>
               <p>Thomas. I had nothing in my hand but a cane.</p>
               <p>Q. What had the person that was with you?</p>
               <p>Thomas. He had an iron crow, in order, if the door had not been opened, to open it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he strike the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Thomas. I did not see him strike him.</p>
               <p>Q. How many people were there in the room at the time?</p>
               <p>Thomas. There were nobody there but the prisoner and us two.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the prisoner's daughter?</p>
               <p>Thomas. I saw her by the side of the bed, in a room on the left hand, in her shift; the prisoner swore he would murder some of us: he swore below stairs a great many oaths he should have been pleased if he had but killed some of us; then he had not minded if he was hanged up directly.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you run up stairs very fast.</p>
               <p>Thomas. We did as fast as we could.</p>
               <p>Court. Then it must make some noise.</p>
               <p>Thomas. I ran in as quick as I could.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-24-person306">
                  Francis Lascoe 
                  Pawlet 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person306" type="surname" value="Pawlet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person306" type="given" value="Francis Lascoe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person306" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in company with Mr. Norden and Smith at the time they went to the prisoner's house. I went into the house with 
               <persName id="t17650522-24-person307">
                  John 
                  Thomas 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person307" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person307" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person307" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I followed him as quick as possible; we first went into the kitchen or tap-room; then we went up stairs; he turned the key, and put his knee against the door, and threw it open on the right hand. We used no force as I know of, only turning the key that was in the door: when we were in I perceived the prisoner with one<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176505220028"></xptr> leg entirely out of bed, and the other almost out. I saw him level the gun at us. Thomas was so near him, he shoved it on one side, and it went off: the ball went through the mantle-piece, and broke a glass all to pieces; it went into the brickwork, and rebounded, and struck against the other side of the room, where it was picked up: I conceive it went off under Thomas's arm, and close to my head. Thomas said he had a warrant against him; we seized him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say that before, or after the gun went off.</p>
               <p>Pawlet. To the best of my recollection it was before it went off; but it was so soon I cannot be positive; the gun went off as quick at our opening the door as I could go three or four steps. Thomas closed upon him, and bid him deliver the gun. He answered,</p>
               <p>"God d - n you, I</p>
               <p>"will not." After he came down into the kitchen, he said,</p>
               <p>"I wish I had shot that rascal,</p>
               <p>"that scoundrel, that Nuthall; I am only sorry</p>
               <p>"I did not kill two or three of you; if I had shot</p>
               <p>"that scoundrel, I should not care if I was</p>
               <p>"hang'd." Going along he used many words to the same effect.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he assign any reason why he shot at you?</p>
               <p>Pawlet. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was in the room when you first went in?</p>
               <p>Pawlet. There was nobody but the prisoner and Thomas when I went in.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-24-person308">
                  Miles 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person308" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person308" type="given" value="Miles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to the prisoner's house on the 13th of May, with others, to take him, by order of the Sheriff; Thomas and Pawlet had been in the house before me; I was on horseback, and hearing the explosion of a gun, I quitted the horse, and ran up stairs: there I saw the prisoner on his bed, on his back, struggling with Thomas. Thomas was endeavouring to wrest the gun out of his hand; the prisoner would not part with it: Pawlet said, Mr. Smith, lo ok under the bed, and see that there is no more fire arms; I did; then we endeavoured to bring him down stairs; after which he was asked how he came to do so rash an action; he swore, and said, he was very sorry he did not kill three or four of us; then he did not care if he was hanged directly. As I was on the landing-place I saw the prisoner's daughter in a room on the left hand side, tying her petticoat on: It was opposite to where her father was; I think she was in her shift. I went into the room where her father was, and presently she came into that room to us. I came away with the prisoner that morning to London, and two other men. Most of the conversation was this, that he was very sorry he had not killed some of us; he was sorry he did not kill Mr. Nuthall: he said he had had the gun by his bedside for that purpose six months; for he knew of our coming. That he said also at Sir 
               <persName id="t17650522-24-person309">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person309" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person309" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person309" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was within the hearing of this?</p>
               <p>Smith. He said it several times in the room below, and coming along the road.</p>
               <p>Q. What did Mr. Nuthall say to him?</p>
               <p>Smith. Mr. Nuthall said, you are an obstinate old man; now you have finished your business, for if there was a ball in this gun you will be hanged for it.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you see him shew the prisoner a rope, and say, you shall be hanged up to dry with it?</p>
               <p>Smith. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Nuthall. How long is it since the prisoner was a keeper?</p>
               <p>Mr. Nuthall. He has not been a keeper this 22 years.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was awake in bed, and heard a thundering up stairs, before they broke the door; they had an iron crow; I heard the door burst open; my gun commonly stands by my bed-side; they came with the iron crow and knocked me down dead; I lay so some time bleeding: some time afterwards I heard a small bounce of a gun; I was stunn'd; it was like hearing it at a great distance: they kept paying me about the head with a stick; there was five or six of them paying me: the first I saw was one searching my breeches. I had four shillings and two six-pences, which were gone; I saw my clasp-knife in one of their hands; they were carrying me down stairs all over blood; they would not let me put my things on; they said, let us throw him in the cart as he is; they tied my hands behind me, and threw me into a cart; Mr. Nuthall said, Now you shall hang up in chains against your own door.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-24-person310">
                  Daniel 
                  Bentley 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person310" type="surname" value="Bentley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person310" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person310" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lived with Mr. Crew when the officers were at his house. I saw them above<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176505220029"></xptr> stairs; I saw them come up stairs; I saw them wrench the door open with an iron crow; I saw one of them try to open the door; he took the key and turned it round, and they could not open it; and because it did not come open, he put his hand with the crow to the door, and pushed the door with the crow, and the door went open; then they went in; I went and put my clothes on; the gun went off; I saw them striking my master with the crow on the forehead; he was bloody when they brought him down stairs; I heard Mr. Nuthall say, Crew, you will be hang'd at Tyburn, and brought down and hanged on that oak-tree to dry.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you up, or in bed at the time?</p>
               <p>Bentley. My Mrs. had call'd me up, and I was getting my things on.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they hit him with the crow before, or after the gun went off?</p>
               <p>Bentley. It was after the gun went off.</p>
               <p>Q. Who heard Mr. Nuthall speak these words besides you?</p>
               <p>Bentley. My mistress, and my young mistress both.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-24-person311">
                  Richard 
                  Brough 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person311" type="surname" value="Brough"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person311" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person311" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Monday I went to the house upon Enfield Chase, where the prisoner lived: I thought, by the marks I saw on the room-door, that it was burst open: there were two marks above the lock seemed to have been done by a crow; they were about the same breadth from each other: I looked upon the mantle-piece, and observed the ball went through it, and went up slanting, not quite perpendicular: I think the gun must be rather grounded, by it's going up aslant.</p>

               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Brough. I am a master-brewer, and live at Enfield.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any crow there?</p>
               <p>Brough. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you ever up stairs there before?</p>
               <p>Brough. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell which way the gun went off?</p>
               <p>Brough. No, I cannot.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you look to see if it had broke the cieling?</p>
               <p>Brough. No, I think it could not reach the cieling, being not quite upright. I have known the prisoner about three years; he bears the character of a very honest man, as far as I know; he dealt with me for beer.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-24-person312">
                  John 
                  Curtice 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person312" type="surname" value="Curtice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person312" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person312" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about fifty years; he is a very honest man; but when he gets fuddled he will swear.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-24-person313">
                  Nicholas 
                  Young 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person313" type="surname" value="Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person313" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person313" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him almost fifty years; he bears the character of a very honest man: I never heard to the contrary.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-24-person314">
                  Richard 
                  Fletcher 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person314" type="surname" value="Fletcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person314" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , (senior.) I have known him above forty years: I never heard any harm of him; but he will get fuddled now and then.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-24-person315">
                  James 
                  Jervice 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person315" type="surname" value="Jervice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person315" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person315" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him above thirty years: I know nothing of him but that of a very honest man; he has brought up twelve or fourteen children, and paid his way honestly.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-24-person316">
                  Thomas 
                  Lord 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person316" type="surname" value="Lord"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person316" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person316" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him between twenty and thirty years; he has a very good character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-24-person317">
                  William 
                  Graygoose 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person317" type="surname" value="Graygoose"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person317" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person317" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him forty years; he is a very industrious man.</p>
               <p>Q. to Norden. Did you see this boy Bentley in the bed-chamber?</p>
               <p>Norden. He was not in the room till after the prisoner was brought out of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear Mr. Nuthall speak such words as the boy has mentioned.</p>
               <p>Norden. No, I never did; nor I don't believe he did say any such thing: I was near him; I don't believe we were five yards asunder all the time, till the prisoner was sent away.</p>
               <p>Q. to Thomas. Did you see the boy in the bed chamber?</p>
               <p>Thomas. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear Mr. Nuthall make use of such an expression as the boy has mentioned?</p>
               <p>Thomas. No, I did not; and I was present with Mr. Nuthall the time he was there.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner struck with the crow?</p>
               <p>Thomas. No, he was not; but the hurt he received on his forehead might be done by the crow, as far as I know.</p>
               <p>Norden. It was done thus; Pawlet held the crow in his hand, and the prisoner struggling ran his head against it; as soon as I saw the blood I challenged Pawlet with striking the prisoner: he said he did not, but the prisoner ran his head against it.</p>
               <p>Q. to Pawlet. Did you see the boy in the bed chamber?</p>
               <p>Pawlet. No: the first time I saw him was in the kitchen.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you force open the door with the crow?</p>
               <p>Pawlet. No, I did not: 
               <persName id="t17650522-24-person318">
                  John 
                  Thomas 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person318" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person318" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person318" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had hold of the gun: the prisoner flung his head up, as the crow was in my hand, and the top of the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176505220030"></xptr> claws went against his forehead; had I struck him with it, it must have smash'd his head to pieces.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear Mr. Nuthall say such words as the boy has mentioned?</p>
               <p>Pawlet. No, I did not: I heard Mr. Nuthall say, You are an obstinate old man; see what you have brought yourself to: I believe you will be hanged: I don't believe Mr. Nuthall made use of any thing tending to what the boy has mentioned.</p>
               <p>Q. to Smith. Did you hear Mr. Nuthall make use of such an expression as the boy has mentioned?</p>
               <p>Smith. I was present with Mr. Nuthall from the time the prisoner was brought down, till his being put into the cart: I never heard Mr. Nuthall make use of such an expression: he told the prisoner he was an obstinate old man, and he was afraid he would be hanged for what he had done.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Nuthall. Did you not mention a tree near the prisoner's house; and say, You should have the hanging him up on one of these trees.</p>
               <p>Mr. Nuthall. No, I never did; no such thing ever pass'd: I am sure I could not say any such thing: I told him he would probably be hanged for what he had done.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you make mention of a string on that occasion?</p>
               <p>Mr. Nuthall. No: on his being put in the cart he was extremely violent; he seemed as if he intended to do me a mischief, as he always did: he was tied with a string, and his hands were fastened when he was in the cart.</p>
               <p>Mr. Alderman Tregothick. Last Monday was a week this thing happened, and on the Monday following I took a walk to the prisoner's house; there I saw a wretched old woman, and her daughter equally wretched, and that boy: I went up into the room and examined it; I observed the room was about fourteen feet from the door to the bed's head, and, I think, about twelve feet from the window to the chimney; the bed was taken down, by the mark on the wall it was about four feet from that side the room: the ball had entered the mantle-piece; it was a bit of deal, with a kind of a cornice under it: the ball went upwards about four inches, and beat off a large piece of plaister: I did not trace it any farther. I observed the bolt of the lock was not affected at all; the outside of the door had a mark upon it, two inches and five eighths from each other; they appeared to have been made by an instrument of that kind as mentioned: from the situation of the hole made in the mantle-piece I should imagine, if fired from the bed, it must have been about two feet from the ground. My idea of the matter was, there was some struggling (having heard the prisoner was a good marksman) to have directed the ball in that manner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-24-person319">
                  Richard 
                  Fletcher 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person319" type="surname" value="Fletcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person319" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person319" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , junior. I have known the prisoner twelve or fourteen years: I never heard but he behaved very well.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-24-person320">
                  John 
                  Austin 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person320" type="surname" value="Austin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person320" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person320" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about seven years: I always took him to be an honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-24-person321">
                  Thomas 
                  Atkins 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person321" type="surname" value="Atkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person321" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person321" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him forty years: I never knew any thing but that he was a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-24-person322">
                  Richard 
                  Tidmarsh 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person322" type="surname" value="Tidmarsh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person322" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person322" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him upwards of thirty years: I look upon him to be a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-24-person323">
                  David 
                  Fry 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person323" type="surname" value="Fry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person323" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person323" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him twenty years; he is a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-24-person324">
                  Lomeworth 
                  Dean 
               <interp inst="t17650522-24-person324" type="surname" value="Dean"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person324" type="given" value="Lomeworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-person324" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him near thirty years; he is a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17650522-24-verdict152" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-verdict152" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>There was a second indictment against him, for <rs id="t17650522-24-off153" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-off153" type="offenceCategory" value="breakingPeace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-off153" type="offenceSubcategory" value="wounding"></interp>
               shooting the gun at 
                     <persName id="t17650522-24-victim325" type="victimName">
                        Pawlet
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-victim325" type="given" value="Pawlet"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650522-24-victim325" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, on which he was also <rs id="t17650522-24-verdict154" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-24-verdict154" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
