<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670115-22">
               <interp inst="t17670115-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670115-22" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670115-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670115"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670115-22" type="date" value="17670115"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670115-22-off123-c192" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670115-22-defend233 t17670115-22-off123 t17670115-22-verdict128"></join>
         
               <p>109. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17670115-22-defend233" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Rutter 
                  <interp inst="t17670115-22-defend233" type="surname" value="Rutter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-22-defend233" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-22-defend233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17670115-22-off123" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670115-22-off123" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-22-off123" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               stealing twelve brass ferrels for angling-rods, four cocoa-nut heads for canes, four brass screw ferrels, four bamboo canes, one walking-cane, and four metal heads
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17670115-22-victim235" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Emory 
                  <interp inst="t17670115-22-victim235" type="surname" value="Emory"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-22-victim235" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-22-victim235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670115-22-off123 t17670115-22-victim235"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17670115-22-cd124" type="crimeDate">Dec. 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670115-22-off123 t17670115-22-cd124"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670115-22-person236">
                  William 
                  Emory 
               <interp inst="t17670115-22-person236" type="surname" value="Emory"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-22-person236" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-22-person236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17670115-22-viclabel125" type="occupation">fishing-rod maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670115-22-victim235 t17670115-22-viclabel125"></join>, and live in <placeName id="t17670115-22-crimeloc126">Holbourn</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17670115-22-crimeloc126" type="placeName" value="Holbourn"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17670115-22-crimeloc126" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670115-22-off123 t17670115-22-crimeloc126"></join>; the prisoner worked two months with me as a <rs id="t17670115-22-deflabel127" type="occupation">journeyman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670115-22-defend233 t17670115-22-deflabel127"></join>; some time after he had been at work, I gave him a quantity of sheet-brass to make ferrels; I thought the brass would have made more ferrels than what he said it did. Some time after I gave him another quantity to make some more; I took particular notice of that, and cut them out at half a dozen at a time; it would have made at least sixteen dozen; when he had finished the brass, he told me it made but eleven dozen and a half; then I was fully convinced he had wronged me; I took no notice to him about it; he worked but about three days in a week. On Friday the 19th of December, I counted a drawer of nut heads, and a drawer of screw ferrels, and my apprentice counted them likewise; he carried them up into the work-shop, and I ordered him to call me down, which he did, in order to leave the prisoner alone; I staid below about an hour, and then went up into the work-shop; I had the drawers carried down; I counted them over again, and there was deficient four nut heads and eight screw ferrels; I contrived to keep him all day at work, that he might not go out to dinner; I told him, I had a job to do for a gentleman that must go out of town early, and if he would stay and do it, he should dine with me, and have some of my ale; I got a warrant to apprehend him, and another to search his lodging, and Mr. Morgan an officer there; when the prisoner came down stairs, I said I wanted to speak with him; I took him into the kitchen, and asked him what he had done with the nut heads and screw ferrels; at first he said he had none; I said I had marked them, and missed so many of them; then he was all in a tremble.</p>
               <p>Q. How had you marked them?</p>
               <p>Emory. I marked them with a black pencil on the inside: he then at separate times took out four heads and four ferrels from his pocket, and he took out a key of a door; I took that, and said, I supposed it was the key of his lodgings; he said he hoped I would go to his lodgings, and take the things of mine away, and not say any thing to his landlord; Mr. Morgan found in the lining of his coat four bamboo canes and a walking-cane; I took him before Justice Girdler, and he was committed the next morning; I went to his lodgings, and found a number of things, I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176701150017"></xptr> believe my property, which I have not laid in the indictment.</p>
               <p>The things found produced in court, and what were laid in the indictment be deposed to as his property.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670115-22-person237">
                  Wilson
               <interp inst="t17670115-22-person237" type="given" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-22-person237" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the apprentice confirmed the account he had given, as to marking the things, and their being found upon the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>The canes, heads, and ferrels, I brought with me that morning; I was a master in Lancashire, and brought these things up when I came to London.</p>
               <p>He called to his character 
               <persName id="t17670115-22-person238">
                  James 
                  Philipson 
               <interp inst="t17670115-22-person238" type="surname" value="Philipson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-22-person238" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-22-person238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a shoemaker, who had known him a dozen years; 
               <persName id="t17670115-22-person239">
                  Mary 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17670115-22-person239" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-22-person239" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-22-person239" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at the Shepherd and Goat, Fleet-ditch, his countrywoman, at whose house he had lodged five weeks; and 
               <persName id="t17670115-22-person240">
                  Esther 
                  Rawlinson 
               <interp inst="t17670115-22-person240" type="surname" value="Rawlinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-22-person240" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-22-person240" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who had known him from a youth; who all gave him a good character.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17670115-22-verdict128" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670115-22-verdict128" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17670115-22-punish129" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670115-22-punish129" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670115-22-defend233 t17670115-22-punish129"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
