<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660702-10">
               <interp inst="t17660702-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660702-10" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660702-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660702"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660702-10" type="date" value="17660702"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660702-10-off53-c89" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-10-defend108 t17660702-10-off53 t17660702-10-verdict58"></join>
         
               <p>342. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660702-10-defend108" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Smithson 
                  <interp inst="t17660702-10-defend108" type="surname" value="Smithson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-10-defend108" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-10-defend108" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17660702-10-off53" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660702-10-off53" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-10-off53" type="offenceSubcategory" value="other"></interp>
               stealing twelve pair of leather breeches, two pair of velvet ditto, two shirts, three petticoats, one yard of baize, one cloth cloak, five aprons, one neckcloth and one cap
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17660702-10-victim110" type="victimName">
                     James 
                     Alefounder 
                  <interp inst="t17660702-10-victim110" type="surname" value="Alefounder"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-10-victim110" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-10-victim110" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-10-off53 t17660702-10-victim110"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17660702-10-cd54" type="crimeDate">May 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-10-off53 t17660702-10-cd54"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-10-person111">
                  James 
                  Alefounder 
               <interp inst="t17660702-10-person111" type="surname" value="Alefounder"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-10-person111" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-10-person111" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17660702-10-viclabel55" type="occupation">pawnbroker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-10-victim110 t17660702-10-viclabel55"></join>. On the 21st of May my house was on fire, in <placeName id="t17660702-10-crimeloc56">Petticoat-lane, near Aldgate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17660702-10-crimeloc56" type="placeName" value="Petticoat-lane, near Aldgate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660702-10-crimeloc56" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-10-off53 t17660702-10-crimeloc56"></join>; the fire was only in the top part of the house; I lost a great number of things; two days after, 
               <persName id="t17660702-10-person112">
                  Jane 
                  Kelley 
               <interp inst="t17660702-10-person112" type="surname" value="Kelley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-10-person112" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-10-person112" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came and informed me, the prisoner had thirteen pair of leather breeches, which he had offered her to sale; that in looking over them she saw a ticket upon one of them; (we put a ticket upon our pledges as we take them in) and as there had been a fire at my house, she suspected they were stolen from me; I went with an officer and Mrs. Kelley to the prisoner's lodgings; we found but twelve pair, five aprons, a petticoat or two, and some other things that had tickets on them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-10-person113">
                  Thomas 
                  Parker 
               <interp inst="t17660702-10-person113" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-10-person113" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-10-person113" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I belong to the Fire-office. The old cloaths-woman having told the prosecutor of her seeing a number of leather breeches at the prisoner's house, I went with her, an officer, and the prosecutor, to the prisoner's lodgings; he lives up two pair of stairs; he was not at home, but his wife was; we found in a closet twelve pair of leather breeches, and other pledges, some aprons, and a cap or two, with the tickets on them; we were informed the prisoner was in a skittle-ground; the officer went and fetched him; he was asked how he came by that bundle of things; he said, a strange man had left them there; he said we might take them all; he seemed much confused, and trembled very much; he went to a closet, and took out some more things, and said to the prosecutor, you may take them all home, they are all your's, Sir. The prosecutor asked him where the buckskin breeches were that Kelley had given him information of; he said he never had any; we brought the things away, and did not take the prisoner up then.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the breeches any tickets upon them?</p>
               <p>Parker. No, they had not; at dinner time we had information the prisoner was taken up, he having pawned a pair of buckskin breeches; then we went to the pawnbroker, where he had pawned them for 7 s.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-10-person114">
                  Daniel 
                  Thomas 
               <interp inst="t17660702-10-person114" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-10-person114" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-10-person114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner at the bar brought a pair of buckskin breeches on the 23d of May, and pledged them with me for 7 s. (produced in court.)</p>
               <p>Q. Was there a ticket on them?</p>
               <p>Thomas. No, there was not.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I cannot swear to them, there being no ticket on them.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176607020008"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-10-person115">
                  Jane 
                  Kelley 
               <interp inst="t17660702-10-person115" type="surname" value="Kelley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-10-person115" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-10-person115" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The breeches were offered to another woman, and she came to me, to go with her to buy them; I went, and saw thirteen pair; there was a pair of buckskin breeches among them; the man was in bed in his shirt. I should not know him again; I believe it was the prisoner, but will not swear it. It was in Wingfield-street, up two pair of stairs, the same room which we found them in afterwards; he asked a guinea for the thirteen pair; the pair of buckskin ones were worth half a guinea: I seeing a ticket on one of them, did not buy them, but went and told the prosecutor of what I had seen. (The things produced in court.)</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Here are four aprons, two boy's shirts, and a neckcloth; they have all my tickets on them; these were found in the prisoner's room; I am very certain to these.</p>
               <p>Q. to Parker. Did you observe the tickets on these things?</p>
               <p>Parker. I did, and put them in my bag, and brought them all to Mr. Alefounder's house; after that, they were carried before my Lord-Mayor. The tickets are now upon them; I knew by the tickets they belonged to a pawnbroker.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-10-person116">
                  Edward 
                  Heacock 
               <interp inst="t17660702-10-person116" type="surname" value="Heacock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-10-person116" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-10-person116" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I bought a pair of buckskin breeches of the prisoner on the Thursday in Whitsun-week, being the 22d of May; I have them on now; I gave him 9 s. for them.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Have you looked at them?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I have; but there being no ticket, I could not swear to them.</p>
               <p>Q. to Heacock. What is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Heacock. He cries greens and things about the streets in Whitechapel.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>They came to me, and I was fetched up into my room; I said, there is a bundle which does not belong to me, and I delivered the things to them; I was not at home when the bundle was brought to my house.</p>
               <p>Q. to Parker. How far distant is it from the prosecutor's house to the prisoner's lodging?</p>
               <p>Parker. It is about a quarter of a mile distant.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Did you direct people to carry your goods at the time of the fire to any particular place?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I directed them to carry what things they could get out to a tallow-chandler's, about ten doors from me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you employ only particular persons?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you send any goods to Wingfield street?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No, I did not; I have no acquaintance in that street.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-10-person117">
                  Hannah 
                  Savage 
               <interp inst="t17660702-10-person117" type="surname" value="Savage"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-10-person117" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-10-person117" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner between four and five years; he is very honest hard-working man; I never knew any ill of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever know him to sell old cloaths?</p>
               <p>H. Savage. No, I never know him sell any thing, only greens and potatoes in a barrow. </p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-10-person118">
                  Esther 
                  Lawrence 
               <interp inst="t17660702-10-person118" type="surname" value="Lawrence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-10-person118" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-10-person118" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him four or five years; I never knew any more of him but that of a very hard working man, <rs id="t17660702-10-deflabel57" type="occupation">selling, fruit and things in the streets</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-10-defend108 t17660702-10-deflabel57"></join>.</p>
               <p>Jos. Scales. I have known him a considerable time; I live next door but one to him; I never heard or saw any thing bad of him before this.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660702-10-verdict58" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660702-10-verdict58" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
