<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17611209-36">
               <interp inst="t17611209-36" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611209-36" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611209-36" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17611209"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611209-36" type="date" value="17611209"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17611209-36-off198-c316" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-36-defend384 t17611209-36-off198 t17611209-36-verdict201"></join>
         
               <p>38. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17611209-36-defend384" type="defendantName">
                     Cicily 
                     Hicky 
                  <interp inst="t17611209-36-defend384" type="surname" value="Hicky"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-36-defend384" type="given" value="Cicily"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-36-defend384" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17611209-36-deflabel197" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-36-defend384 t17611209-36-deflabel197"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17611209-36-off198" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611209-36-off198" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-36-off198" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing a silver watch, value 4 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17611209-36-victim386" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Piercy 
                        <interp inst="t17611209-36-victim386" type="surname" value="Piercy"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17611209-36-victim386" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17611209-36-victim386" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-36-off198 t17611209-36-victim386"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17611209-36-cd199" type="crimeDate">Dec. 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-36-off198 t17611209-36-cd199"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-36-person387">
                  John 
                  Piercy 
               <interp inst="t17611209-36-person387" type="surname" value="Piercy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-36-person387" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-36-person387" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Wednesday was sevennight, about one at night, as I was going home to the Butcher-row, near St. Clement's church, I met with the prisoner at the bar near the <placeName id="t17611209-36-crimeloc200">Fleet-market</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17611209-36-crimeloc200" type="placeName" value="Fleet-market"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17611209-36-crimeloc200" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-36-off198 t17611209-36-crimeloc200"></join>. She asked me if I would give her any thing to drink. I said with all my heart. She took me to a public house about 20 yards from where I met with her. She said she had been there before. I asked her what she would drink. She said, a glass of Usquebaugh. There was a man with me, that was to see me part of my way home. We had a glass each, which cost me four pence halfpeny. I pulled out my watch to see what o'clock it was; the landlord pulled out his; there were five minutes between them. I put it into my pocket, and came out of the house, and about ten yards from the door the prisoner took my watch out of my pocket with her right hand. I took hold of her by the left. I am very sure of it; for I felt her pull it out. I charged her with the watch. The watchman came, and took hold of her hand. She said, pray don't take me to the watch-house, I'll tell you where the watch is. The watchman took her a little farther; she said, for God's sake, don't take me any farther; and I'll let the young man have his watch. He said he would confine her first. She was taken to the watch-house, and searched; but it was not found. Then the watchman said I should be confined as well as she. The watchman and I went back together; there was no person about; we could not find the watch. I was confined in Bridewell till morning.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176112090027"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-36-person388">
                  John 
                  Arnold 
               <interp inst="t17611209-36-person388" type="surname" value="Arnold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-36-person388" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-36-person388" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watchman. The gentleman called out watch; so did the prisoner: She said she was going home to her husband, and the gentleman stopped her, and wanted to be rude with her. He insisted upon it she had robbed him of his watch, and insisted upon my taking her in charge. In going to the watch-house. She said hold of my partner. I desired him to follow me close. She said, If you will not take me to the watch-house, I will tell you where the watch is. I said I would not trouble my head, now we are so near the watch-house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take her back to the place where the watch was?</p>
               <p>Arnold. No.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. Did you use her as she said?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I did not attempt to be rude with her; she put her hand two or three times to the waistband of my breeches.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-36-person389">
                  Peter 
                  Pearson 
               <interp inst="t17611209-36-person389" type="surname" value="Pearson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-36-person389" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-36-person389" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watchman. On Tuesday morning, the 2d of this instant, between one and two o'clock, I heard watch called; I ran to see what was the matter. Said the prosecutor, A woman has picked my pocket of my watch. How shall I know that? said I; search your pocket. I held up my lantern, and looked him in the face, and found him to be a sober man. Said I, What would you have me do in this case? He gave me charge of her. I charged the other watchman with the man. Said the other man, Let's go back, and see for the watch. No, said I, let's go first to the watch-house, then we will go and see for the watch. Going along, she plucked me by the arm, and said, Watchman, for God's sake, don't let me go to the watch-house; call them back, and I'll tell you where the watch is. I called them; they would give no heed to me. She hung back, and begged and promised to shew where it was. When we came to the watch-house, she was sulky, and would not say where it was. We went to look for it, but could not find it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-36-person390">
                  Thomas 
                  Enion 
               <interp inst="t17611209-36-person390" type="surname" value="Enion"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-36-person390" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-36-person390" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was with the prosecutor and prisoner in the public house; I saw his watch out there.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I bought the watch in Nov. last of Mr. Hailey, son to Mr. Hailey in Tyburn Road, and gave five guineas for it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I had been as far as Oxford Road, and happened to call in Drury Lane, and stopped till about half an hour after 11 o'clock. I came from there very near the bottom of Fleet-street. I went in at the Red Lion in Popping's Alley; and just at the turning the corner I met the prosecutor and another man; he asked me if I could tell him of a public house where the people were up. I said I believed I could, that I just came out of. I stepped back with him; he insisted upon my drinking a dram with him. I did not chuse it, but drank a glass of usquebaugh. He and the other man drank each one; they went away up Fleet-street, and I down. There is a turning into Black Horse Court. When I came to the lowest lamp the prosecutor came and put his hand upon my shoulder, and asked me where I was going. I said, Home. He said, I'll go along with you, and insisted upon going, and put his hand under my petticoats. I said I had a husband at home, he was mistaken in me. He threw me upon the ground, and my coats were all over my mouth. He set his foot on me to keep me down; I belive we struggled a quarter of an hour. I called watch; he called watch. He said if I would not let him do as he pleased (and spoke in a very rude manner), he would do for me. The watchman came up; and he said, I had taken his watch. The watchman said, Look in your pocket, may-be you may be mistaken. Going to the watch-house, I said, I think it would be a great deal properer to go back and look for it; for very likely, as he had opened his breeches, he may have dropped it in tussling about. The constable took me in and searched me. They went out to look for the watch, but found none. After that, he wanted to go away. The constable said, As you have given no proper account of yourself, it is proper to commit you as well as he, and so we were both sent to Bridewell. I never saw any thing at all of his watch.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. When she was taken into custody, her cloaths were not dirty at all, the watchmen know it.</p>
               <p>Q. to Arnold. How were the prisoner's cloaths? did she seem as if she had been rolled in the dirt?</p>
               <p>Arnold. I saw no dirt at all upon her cloaths, neither did she complain of any-thing of that sort.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17611209-36-verdict201" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611209-36-verdict201" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-36-verdict201" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               Guilty of stealing, but not privately from his person
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17611209-36-punish202" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611209-36-punish202" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-36-defend384 t17611209-36-punish202"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
