<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610401-33">
               <interp inst="t17610401-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610401-33" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610401-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610401"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610401-33" type="date" value="17610401"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610401-33-off176-c239" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610401-33-defend305 t17610401-33-off176 t17610401-33-verdict178"></join>
         
               <p>153. (M) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610401-33-defend305" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Harwood 
                  <interp inst="t17610401-33-defend305" type="surname" value="Harwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-33-defend305" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-33-defend305" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17610401-33-deflabel175" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610401-33-defend305 t17610401-33-deflabel175"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17610401-33-off176" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610401-33-off176" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-33-off176" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one flock bed, value 2 s. two linnen sheets, value 9 d. one pair of bellows, value 6 d. one tin pot, value 3 d. and one iron pot, value 1 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17610401-33-victim307" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Holmes 
                        <interp inst="t17610401-33-victim307" type="surname" value="Holmes"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610401-33-victim307" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610401-33-victim307" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610401-33-off176 t17610401-33-victim307"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , the same being, in a certain lodging-room, let by contract, to be used by the said Sarah
            </rs>, &amp;c. <rs id="t17610401-33-cd177" type="crimeDate">Nov. 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610401-33-off176 t17610401-33-cd177"></join>. ++.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610401-33-person308">
                  John 
                  Holmes 
               <interp inst="t17610401-33-person308" type="surname" value="Holmes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-33-person308" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610401-33-person308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner lodged in my house.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did she lodge there?</p>
               <p>Holmes. I believe about nineteen weeks.</p>
               <p>Q. Who let her the lodgings?</p>
               <p>Holmes. She agreed with me for the lodgings, ready furnished.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you let her these goods mentioned in the indictment, with the lodging?</p>
               <p>Holmes. I did. Last Sunday morning I sent my house-keeper to the apartment where the prisoner lodged; she came again, and said, the door was left open, and the things were gone. I sent her for the prisoner to her father's house. She came, and said she had taken them away for conveniency.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176104010038"></xptr>Q. How for conveniency?</p>
               <p>Holmes. Because she worked on the other side Moorfields. At that time she owed me 9 s. She said she would bring them all again on the morrow. I asked her for the key, she said it was at her father's; she went and fetched it. This being Sunday, I took no farther notice then, because I would not have a disturbance on that day. On the Monday I got a warrant, and went and took her up, and then I found she had pawned the things.</p>
               <p>Q. Where had she pawned them?</p>
               <p>Holmes. At one Ellis's, in Winfield-street, near George-yard. I went there the next morning: they denied them. Then I got a search-warrant, and found one sheet only. I carried the sheet to justice Fielding, he said I should have brought the pawnbroker too. I went back for them, but they were gone.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. It was but a pint tin-pot. I acknowledge my fault, and crave your mercy. I lately had my arm broke, or I had not been necessitated. Mr. Holmes made an agreement to take them again if I would put them in the room again.</p>
               <p>Q. to Holmes. Did you make such agreement?</p>
               <p>Holmes. I never agreed with her for any such a thing.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He said, let her alone, if she will put the things in their places again, it will be all well.</p>
               <p>Holmes. My house-keeper wanted me to secure her that Sunday-night, but I was not for making an uproar then; but I took her up the next day. [The headborough produced a sheet.]</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. This is my property, and what I let to the prisoner with the room.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610401-33-verdict178" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610401-33-verdict178" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610401-33-punish179" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610401-33-punish179" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610401-33-defend305 t17610401-33-punish179"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
