<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17630518-36">
               <interp inst="t17630518-36" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630518-36" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630518-36" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17630518"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630518-36" type="date" value="17630518"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17630518-36-off204-c259" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-36-defend331 t17630518-36-off204 t17630518-36-verdict206"></join>
         
               <p>244. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17630518-36-defend331" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Clements 
                  <interp inst="t17630518-36-defend331" type="surname" value="Clements"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-36-defend331" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-36-defend331" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17630518-36-off204" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630518-36-off204" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-36-off204" type="offenceSubcategory" value="fraud"></interp>
               obtaining the sum of one guinea of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17630518-36-victim333" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Houghton 
                        <interp inst="t17630518-36-victim333" type="surname" value="Houghton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630518-36-victim333" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630518-36-victim333" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-36-off204 t17630518-36-victim333"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   under false pretences, by pretending to him he was head clerk to 
                     <persName id="t17630518-36-person334">
                        Richard 
                        Horn 
                     <interp inst="t17630518-36-person334" type="surname" value="Horn"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630518-36-person334" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630518-36-person334" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , who belongs to the ticket-office in the Navy-office
            </rs>, <rs id="t17630518-36-cd205" type="crimeDate">Jan 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-36-off204 t17630518-36-cd205"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630518-36-person335">
                  Richard 
                  Horn 
               <interp inst="t17630518-36-person335" type="surname" value="Horn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-36-person335" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-36-person335" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I belong to the ticket-office in the Navy-office; there was due to the widow Cherry, at the time of her death, 15 l. her husband had served on board the Devonshire man of war, in the capacity of a purser. There was a fund established for that purpose, to pay to the widows of the royal navy; Mr. Houghton had applyed to me for the payment of it, I told him very likely I should have the money in my hands in two or three months time, then I would pay it; it is my business to pay it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner ever apply to you?</p>
               <p>Horn. No, he is a person I know not; the money is paid by virtue of an order from the court of assistants, which, generally speaking, is the first lord of the admiralty, and three or four of the commissioners of the Navy, there must be seven to make a quorum; they sent down the order to me to pay it, I have the order here in my hand, it is dated Admiralty-office 3d Feb. 1763, in which is a list of all their names that receive, and the sums over against them, and over against her name is the sum of 15 l. 2 s. 6 d. Here is a certificate of 
               <persName id="t17630518-36-person336">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Cherry 
               <interp inst="t17630518-36-person336" type="surname" value="Cherry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-36-person336" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-36-person336" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's death, (producing it) she was widow to 
               <persName id="t17630518-36-person337">
                  Edward 
                  Cherry 
               <interp inst="t17630518-36-person337" type="surname" value="Cherry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-36-person337" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-36-person337" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who was purser on board the Devonshire man of war.</p>
               <p>Q. Does your clerk solicit business in that office?</p>
               <p>Horn. I keep no clerk at all.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630518-36-person338">
                  Thomas 
                  Houghton 
               <interp inst="t17630518-36-person338" type="surname" value="Houghton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-36-person338" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-36-person338" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 5th of Jan. I took these papers, in order to go and receive some money; (the will of 
               <persName id="t17630518-36-person339">
                  Edward 
                  Cherry 
               <interp inst="t17630518-36-person339" type="surname" value="Cherry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-36-person339" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-36-person339" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and a probate granted to 
               <persName id="t17630518-36-person340">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Cherry 
               <interp inst="t17630518-36-person340" type="surname" value="Cherry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-36-person340" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-36-person340" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , his widow, and the will of Elizabeth Cherry, with the administration annexed to it granted to 
               <persName id="t17630518-36-person341">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Newell 
               <interp inst="t17630518-36-person341" type="surname" value="Newell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-36-person341" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-36-person341" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , delivering them in) I went to the Navy-office in Crutched-friars, and asked which was Mr. Horn's office, the porter at the gate told me; when I came in I found the prisoner there, he made as if he was coming out, then he went in again, and gave the pen and ink a shove, he asked me what I wanted? I said, I wanted Mr. Horn; he said, he was his head clerk; then I said, you may do as well, I want to receive some money on these writings, I am told there is 25 l. due: said he, there is 27 l. due, you may come twenty or thirty times after it and not get it, said he, I'll get it you this afternoon, but our hours are broke up now, and we are going to dinner, go to the Navy coffee house, and I'll come to you; he overtook me before I got there, sir, said he, I suppose you understand the nature of our office; I said, I am quite a stranger to it; said he, our see is a guinea; I said, rather than come twenty times I'll pay it; I gave him two half guineas, and let him have the writings, in order to have them signed, this was in the street. Then I went into the coffee-house, he came there to me again, and said, sir, I have quite forgot our under clerk, he will expect his see; said I, what is that? that, said he, is only 6 s. 8 d. I having but 6 s. gave him that, and said, I live at such a place, I'll give you a bottle of wine if you'll call upon me. Never mind the 8 d. said he, and away he goes again. I had a little suspicion of him, and said to the landlady, do you know Mr. Horn's clerk? said she, I know some of the clerks; said I, when that man comes in again if you know him let the word be yes, if not, say no. He came the third time and said, I beg your pardon, I cannot get it done to night, but I will in the morning. My landlady said, No. I said, let me know your name; he said, 
               <persName id="t17630518-36-person342">
                  William 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17630518-36-person342" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-36-person342" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-36-person342" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I said, you'll further satisfy me that you are Mr. Horn's clerk; he said, O yes, if you'll walk along with me into the office. He led me there, he said, this is our office; he went through, and said, if you'll stop here I'll call a gentleman out of this house that shall soon satisfy you. I seeing wrote over the place, no thoroughfare, and the porter pulled off his hat to him, and let him through, I staid a little while, and said to the porter, do you know that gentleman? he said, no; I said, let me through; he did, then I found myself on Tower-hill, but could see no more of my gentleman. I staid till Mr. Horn returned to the office, I described the prisoner, and some of the clerks said they had seen such a person, and when they saw him again they would take him up, and some time after that he was taken up.</p>
               <p>Q. from the prisoner. Was I not in liquor?</p>
               <p>Houghton. I believe the prisoner was in liquor.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176305180023"></xptr>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I never had any intent to defraud any person in my life. I attended the office several and several times; they took me up, whether guilty or not, I cannot say; for at the time I am charged with doing this, I was very full of liquor. I have solicited a great while in getting R's off, and was going to set up an office for that purpose.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17630518-36-verdict206" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630518-36-verdict206" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17630518-36-punish207" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630518-36-punish207" type="punishmentCategory" value="noPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-36-punish207" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="sentenceRespited"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-36-defend331 t17630518-36-punish207"></join>
               
                     <note>[No punishment. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
