<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650522-23">
               <interp inst="t17650522-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-23" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650522"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-23" type="date" value="17650522"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650522-23-off143-c233" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-23-defend279 t17650522-23-off143 t17650522-23-verdict148"></join>
         
               <p>320. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17650522-23-defend279" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Heydon 
                  <interp inst="t17650522-23-defend279" type="surname" value="Heydon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-23-defend279" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-23-defend279" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for that <rs id="t17650522-23-off143" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-23-off143" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-23-off143" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               he, being a <rs id="t17650522-23-deflabel144" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-23-defend279 t17650522-23-deflabel144"></join> to Thomas Wildman, who did intrust and deliver to him 13 l. 14 s. the money of the said 
                     
                        <persName id="t17650522-23-victim281" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Wildman 
                        <interp inst="t17650522-23-victim281" type="surname" value="Wildman"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650522-23-victim281" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650522-23-victim281" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-23-off143 t17650522-23-victim281"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , safely to keep for the use of the said Thomas Wildman, and that he afterwards did withdraw himself from his said master, and go away with the money, with intent to steal the same
            </rs>, <rs id="t17650522-23-cd145" type="crimeDate">April 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-23-off143 t17650522-23-cd145"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-23-person282">
                  Thomas 
                  Wildman 
               <interp inst="t17650522-23-person282" type="surname" value="Wildman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-23-person282" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-23-person282" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I <rs id="t17650522-23-viclabel146" type="occupation">keep a public house in Albemarle-street</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-23-victim281 t17650522-23-viclabel146"></join>: the prisoner had been under my book-keeper; and when he died I made him <rs id="t17650522-23-deflabel147" type="occupation">book-keeper</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-23-defend279 t17650522-23-deflabel147"></join>: I delivered 13 l. 14 s. to him for change, on the 15th of April, and went to New-market; and when I returned he was not to be found: that was last Monday five weeks: he was trusted with my books; the cellar-man was trusted with my other cash: I always give the book-keeper a certain sum to give change to the waiters: I broke open the scrutore in the compting-house, for he was gone away with the key; there were only five pennyworth of halfpence: there I found a letter, by which means I found where he was: he was at Bath: there he was taken; he was sent up in the machine, by the Mayor of Bath; he was carried before Sir 
               <persName id="t17650522-23-person283">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17650522-23-person283" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-23-person283" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-23-person283" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; there he said, he was very sorry he had robbed me, who had used him so well: I have sent him victuals and drink since he has been in confinement, and he has sent me several handsome letters: Sir John took from him seven guineas and a half; which was delivered to me. The course of our business is thus: I never take any money myself; but the drawers receive the money of the company, and deliver it to the book-keeper: I keep a regular account of all: the book-keeper gives security; for I used to trust the book-keeper two or 300 l. at a time: I had no security from the prisoner; therefore I gave him injunctions to pay the money every night, to a servant that I can put confidence in.</p>
               <p>Q. from the Prisoner. How did I behave the time I lived with you?</p>
               <p>Wildman. He behaved very decent and very regular; that was the reason I took him into my service at the death of my book-keeper: my business is large; I have taken 145 l. in a day: my other book-keeper hired him, and paid him his wages. The money I left with him was the balance of money on the former account; I settled before I went out; and this was the balance due to me: I told it over, and pushed it to him to take for change in the course of the business; he acknowledged there was so much due to me on the former account: there was the daily account under his own hand-writing: he had balanced the account, and had taken 21 l. that day: I went away when I delivered the 13 l. 14 s. he set it down in the book: I told him he was to deliver what money he took every night to the cellar-man; he said, he would; and I gave the cellar-man directions to deliver money to him every morning, as I had done, for change.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-23-person284">
                  Richard 
                  Rogers 
               <interp inst="t17650522-23-person284" type="surname" value="Rogers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-23-person284" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-23-person284" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a waiter at the prosecutor's; I delivered the money I took in the day to the prisoner, before he absconded; I did the day before he absconded; which he never delivered to the cellar-man: he continued in the house till the very day my master came home; when he expected my master to come he absconded: I paid him several sums of money during my master's absence; part of which he accounted for; I have seen the book since: I gave him 8 s. 3 d. a few minutes before he went away: I can't recollect what money I paid him in the whole; I gave it him. I received it: I know I delivered to him above 50 l. in the whole, while my master was gone to New-market; the greater part he accounted for with the cellar-man. I went to Bath; I went with the Mayor of Bath to him in gaol: we came up both together in the basket behind the machine: he said he was too well convinced of the folly he had been guilty of, and offered to deliver to me what money he had when in gaol: I did not take it: he said, he believed there was about 10 l. of it, it was in a piece of paper.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. By his own books he was indebted to me about 25 l. odd money.</p>
               <p>The prisoner said nothing in his defence.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176505220024"></xptr>As he had accounted with the cellar man, it was probable he had paid in that money laid in the indictment. He was therefore <rs id="t17650522-23-verdict148" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-23-verdict148" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
