<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670218-29">
               <interp inst="t17670218-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670218-29" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670218-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670218"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670218-29" type="date" value="17670218"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670218-29-off166-c195" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670218-29-defend247 t17670218-29-off166 t17670218-29-verdict169"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670218-29-off166-c196" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670218-29-defend249 t17670218-29-off166 t17670218-29-verdict169"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670218-29-off166-c197" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670218-29-defend251 t17670218-29-off166 t17670218-29-verdict169"></join>
         
               <p>160, 161, 162. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17670218-29-defend247" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Warren 
                  <interp inst="t17670218-29-defend247" type="surname" value="Warren"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-29-defend247" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-29-defend247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17670218-29-defend249" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Wheeler 
                  <interp inst="t17670218-29-defend249" type="surname" value="Wheeler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-29-defend249" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-29-defend249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17670218-29-defend251" type="defendantName">
                     Isaac 
                     Long 
                  <interp inst="t17670218-29-defend251" type="surname" value="Long"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-29-defend251" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-29-defend251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted, for <rs id="t17670218-29-off166" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670218-29-off166" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-29-off166" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               that they, on the <rs id="t17670218-29-cd167" type="crimeDate">2d of February</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670218-29-off166 t17670218-29-cd167"></join>, about the hour of two in the night on the same day, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17670218-29-victim253" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Sideaway 
                        <interp inst="t17670218-29-victim253" type="surname" value="Sideaway"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670218-29-victim253" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670218-29-victim253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670218-29-off166 t17670218-29-victim253"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did break and enter and stealing one diaper table-cloth, two yards of Irish cloth, one pillow-case, one pair of girl's pumps, one pair of worsted stockings, two tin cannisters, one silver table-spoon, one silver punch-ladle with a whalebone handle, and 3 s. in money numbered, the property of the said John, in his dwelling-house
            </rs>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670218-29-person254">
                  John 
                  Sideaway 
               <interp inst="t17670218-29-person254" type="surname" value="Sideaway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-29-person254" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-29-person254" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at <placeName id="t17670218-29-crimeloc168">the Barking Dogs, near Moorfields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17670218-29-crimeloc168" type="placeName" value="the Barking Dogs, near Moorfields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17670218-29-crimeloc168" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670218-29-off166 t17670218-29-crimeloc168"></join>. Last Monday fortnight, early in the morning, near six o'clock, my man 
               <persName id="t17670218-29-person255">
                  Joseph 
                  Trussel 
               <interp inst="t17670218-29-person255" type="surname" value="Trussel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-29-person255" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-29-person255" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came early to brew; he knocked at the door; I looked out of my one story window; he told me one of my shutters was down, and the sash up; I went down and found it so; I took a rush-light that was burning, and my wife and I came down, and went into the bar, and saw several things lying on the floor; I found the till was gone, with about 3 s. in farthings and two pocket-books in it, a diaper table-cloth, a pair of girl's new pumps, a pillow-case, a cannister of tea, a tin case of lump sugar, a silver table-spoon, a silver punch-ladle with a whalebone handle, were all missing; I observed the groove of the window-shutter had been cut.</p>
               <p>Q. How had you left your house when you went to-bed?</p>
               <p>Sideaway. I came home about twelve o'clock that night, and found my wife and maid up alone; the window-shutter was then up.</p>
               <p>Q. How did they fasten?</p>
               <p>Sideaway. They slide in and out; we went to bed within about five minutes after I came home, and my maid went to bed very soon after; she goes by my chamber-door to her bed; I suspected the evidence Norbury, and two other boys that accompanied together; he lives in the neighbourhood; I laid hold of one of them, (not either of the prisoners) and locked him up in the stable; he had not been there long, before he broke a pane of glass, and got away; that made me suspect him more than before; then I got Norbury, and put him in my back parlour, and kept him there some time; I sent for his mother, and he agreed to let me know at seven o'clock at night, where to come at the other two, who, he said, were to meet him at the Tabernacle-gate; on that condition I let him go, he was to bring them to me; but the next morning one Mr. Caster, that lives about 50 yards from m secured the prisoners, and brought them all three to me; Norbury owned he was concerned in robbing me, and that he took as many things out as were worth 10 l. but did not sell some of the things for above a penny piece: I took them before the Justice, and he was committed to Bridewell, the others were set at liberty; Norbury was brought up again the next day: then he gave a description of the three prisoners at the bar, we went and apprehended them, and the Justice thought proper to admit Norbury an evidence.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever find any of your things again?</p>
               <p>Sideaway. N o.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670218-29-person256">
                  Joseph 
                  Trussel 
               <interp inst="t17670218-29-person256" type="surname" value="Trussel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-29-person256" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-29-person256" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I came in the morning between five and six to brew, and found the window shutter down and sash up; that is all I know.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670218-29-person257">
                  Edward 
                  Norbury 
               <interp inst="t17670218-29-person257" type="surname" value="Norbury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-29-person257" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-29-person257" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I shall be 14 years of age next Christmas.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what will be the consequence if you forswear yourself?</p>
               <p>Norbury. Yes, I shall go to the d - l when I die if I do.</p>
               <p>Court. See and be careful, and say nothing but the truth.</p>
               <p>Norbury. I was coming along on a Saturday night; I saw Warren raise up the shutter of Mr. Sideway's window with an iron bar.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the night was this?</p>
               <p>Norbury. This was about half an hour after twelve o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be out so late that night?</p>
               <p>Norbury. Because my mother would not let me in.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you go after seeing this?</p>
               <p>Norbury. My sister let me in slily; I am an apprentice; my master had been licking me, and I ran out at the door.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he beat you for?</p>
               <p>Norbury. Because I did not clean his shoes as soon as he came home.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does your master live?</p>
               <p>Norbury. He lives in the Tabernacle-walk, and my mother lives in the same house.</p>
               <p>Q. What are the two boys names that you keep company with?</p>
               <p>Norbury. They are Bill and 
               <persName id="t17670218-29-person258">
                  Jack 
                  Rice 
               <interp inst="t17670218-29-person258" type="surname" value="Rice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-29-person258" type="given" value="Jack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-29-person258" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the other two prisoners with Warren?</p>
               <p>Norbury. Yes; said 
               <persName id="t17670218-29-person259">
                  Isaac 
                  Long 
               <interp inst="t17670218-29-person259" type="surname" value="Long"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-29-person259" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-29-person259" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I'll be d - d if I have not got a large knife in my pocket, let us cut the groove.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176702180017"></xptr>Q. Was it light or dark?</p>
               <p>Norbury. It was pretty lightish: said Wheeler. there is the watch at the bottom of the ditch; let us go away, and come again to-morrow night then they all went away up the walk.</p>
               <p>Q. How near to Mr. Sideaway do you live?</p>
               <p>Norbury. I live next door to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you not go and tell him what you had seen the next morning?</p>
               <p>Norbury. I was afraid I should be brought into some scrape. On the Monday morning, Mr. Sideaway's man went into the garden, and shut too the window; I looked out, and saw the shutter was down.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner see you that Saturday night?</p>
               <p>Norbury. I went into the alley, fearing they should see me, and make me go along with them; and they were looking one way to see if the watchman came, and I came the other way?</p>
               <p>Q. Could you hear them plain, when they said they would come again the next night?</p>
               <p>Norbury. They talked pretty loud, I could hear them plain.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was you to them?</p>
               <p>Norbury. He described it, by pointing to a place about six or seven yards distance.</p>
               <p>Warren's defence.</p>
               <p>I am innocent of the affair; I have witness to prove where I was at the time.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>


               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670218-29-person260">
                  Esther
                   O'Neal
               <interp inst="t17670218-29-person260" type="surname" value="O'Neal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-29-person260" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-29-person260" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Warren has lived at my house this last twelve months almost; he has behaved true and honest.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was he on the first of this month at night?</p>
               <p>E. O'Neal. I know he was at home in his lodgings; he has last been out on a night after ten o'clock for this month past, and better.</p>
               <p>All three <rs id="t17670218-29-verdict169" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670218-29-verdict169" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
