<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640607-11">
               <interp inst="t17640607-11" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640607-11" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640607-11" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640607"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640607-11" type="date" value="17640607"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640607-11-off69-c98" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-11-defend124 t17640607-11-off69 t17640607-11-verdict72"></join>
         
               <p>330. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17640607-11-defend124" type="defendantName">
                     Anne 
                     Potter 
                  <interp inst="t17640607-11-defend124" type="surname" value="Potter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-11-defend124" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-11-defend124" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17640607-11-off69" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640607-11-off69" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-11-off69" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing two tin lanthorns, glazed with crown glass value 8 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17640607-11-victim126" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Wesley 
                  <interp inst="t17640607-11-victim126" type="surname" value="Wesley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-11-victim126" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-11-victim126" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-11-off69 t17640607-11-victim126"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17640607-11-viclabel70" type="occupation">Clerk</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-11-victim126 t17640607-11-viclabel70"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640607-11-person127">
                  William 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17640607-11-person127" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-11-person127" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-11-person127" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a carpenter, and was repairing Mr. 
               <persName id="t17640607-11-person128">
                  John 
                  Wesley 
               <interp inst="t17640607-11-person128" type="surname" value="Wesley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-11-person128" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-11-person128" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, house, upon <placeName id="t17640607-11-crimeloc71">Windmill-hill, called the Foundery, in Upper Moor-fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640607-11-crimeloc71" type="placeName" value="Windmill-hill, called the Foundery, in Upper Moor-fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640607-11-crimeloc71" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-11-off69 t17640607-11-crimeloc71"></join>; these lanthorns were taken away about the latter end of March, at two separate times; one hung up on the stairs, and the other in the public preaching place, on night.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that lanthorn all that was in that room?</p>
               <p>Wilson. There is one more. I cannot tell who took them, nor the time when, exactly, but I missed them after they were gone; I had a strong suspicion of the prisoner at the bar, she is a poor creature, lying about the place, asking charity, and we could hardly keep her out of the place. I taxed her with taking them, about a fortnight or three weeks after, she acknowledged she took them, and said, if I would give her two shillings, she would fetch them back again, but did not tell where they were. I told her if she would go with me, I would go and pay for them and gave her something for herself; so she went with me to a broker's shop, by London-wall, where I found them; she had eight-pence on one and nine-pence  on the other.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I am a person that has gone on a long while, and have lost all my friends, and am fatherless; I have followed these people 20 years, and have been brought to utter destruction for them: I was in destruction 12 months, and that made me pawn my cloths. I went to Mr. Wesley, to see if he would recover my cloths; then he promised to let me have my cloths: then he carried me on for about 12 months. I went to his wife, and told her I could not get my living, being let to perish without mercy. I was one day walking very solitary in the Foundery; I met a man who took me down these lanthorns, and I went and pawned one for 8 d. and the other for 9 d. but who that man was, I do not know. I went to my Lord Mayor, and the Justices, to try if I could recover my cloths: I told them what I was drove to; they sent me to Mr. Wesley, to go and require of him to let me have my cloths: they took me up. and put me in Clerkenwell, where I lived upon a poor bit of bread and a little water.</p>
               <p>Q. to Wilson. Is this account she has given, true or false?</p>
               <p>Wilson. It is all a false story. I do believed the poor creature to be a little out of her mind.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640607-11-verdict72" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640607-11-verdict72" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
