<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670715-22">
               <interp inst="t17670715-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670715-22" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670715-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670715"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670715-22" type="date" value="17670715"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670715-22-off130-c180" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-22-defend225 t17670715-22-off130 t17670715-22-verdict134"></join>
         
               <p>360. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17670715-22-defend225" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Rutter 
                  <interp inst="t17670715-22-defend225" type="surname" value="Rutter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-22-defend225" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-22-defend225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17670715-22-off130" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670715-22-off130" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-22-off130" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one bamboe joint for a fishing-rod, with a brass ferril, value 18 d. six hazel joints for tops of fishing rods, value 6 d. six other joints for tops of fishing-rods, value 6 d. and half an ounce of spelter solder
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17670715-22-victim227" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Emory 
                  <interp inst="t17670715-22-victim227" type="surname" value="Emory"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-22-victim227" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-22-victim227" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-22-off130 t17670715-22-victim227"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17670715-22-cd131" type="crimeDate">May 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-22-off130 t17670715-22-cd131"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670715-22-person228">
                  William 
                  Emory 
               <interp inst="t17670715-22-person228" type="surname" value="Emory"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-22-person228" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-22-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17670715-22-viclabel132" type="occupation">fishing-rod maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-22-victim227 t17670715-22-viclabel132"></join>; I employed the prisoner in the capacity of a <rs id="t17670715-22-deflabel133" type="occupation">journeyman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-22-defend225 t17670715-22-deflabel133"></join>, from October to November; I prosecuted him here +, and I took him again after he came out of Newgate. On the 15th of May I missed a bamboe butt, with a screw ferril, out of my workshop; I had seen it a day or two before; and on the 26th of June, my apprentice told me the prisoner had been concealing some hazel joints for fishing-rods under his work bench; I ordered him to see if they were there after the prisoner was gone, and he said they were gone. The next day I saw six pieces under his bench, there I left them; when he was gone, I went and examined, and they were gone; after that I had information the prisoner had been offering a fishing-rod in Crooked-lane, and after that I was informed he had sold it to Mr. Worthington; I charged the prisoner with it; he acknowledged he had sold him one. On the 7th of this month the prisoner went out with his coat very bulky; I called him back, and ran my hand into the lining of his coat, and pulled out a great piece of charcoal, and two hazel sticks; then I got a friend to go to Mr. Worthington's, and I abode without; he went in, and asked for such a rod; it was showed him; then I went into the shop, and asked Mr. Worthington how long he had sold fishing-rods, and who served him; he said Mr. Collins; I said, did he make this rod; he said, yes, I bought it of him; I said, you did not, you bought it of somebody that stole it; then he paus'd and said, he bought it of a young man that lodged in Wych-street; I said he did, but now he lodges in Bridewell.</p>
               <p>See No 109 in this Mayoralty; he was cast for transportation, but received his Majesty's pardon.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it your property?</p>
               <p>Emory. I can't positively swear to the joints, I verily believe them to be mine; the prisoner acknowledged he sold a rod to Mr. Worthington.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he own it to be your's?</p>
               <p>Emory. He said I had given him leave to do it; he lodged at the house of one Murphy, who was his bail; when I took him again, there I found a work-bench done up; I asked Murphy how he came to encourage him to six up tools, when he was bound that the prisoner should not neglect my business for three years.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you value the tops at?</p>
               <p>Emory. The hazel and bamboe tops I value at a penny a piece.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670715-22-person229">
                  Francis 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17670715-22-person229" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-22-person229" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-22-person229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am apprentice to Mr. Emory, the prisoner was his journeyman; he was going out last Tuesday se'nnight, he came down, and asked me for a screw-ferril; I reached the drawer, and he fitted one to a bamboe butt; I thought it had been for my master's use; he took the bamboe butt away; I went up into the workshop about the 16th of June; I saw him have a hazel stick in his hand; I was called down, and I went up again, and looked under the bench, and saw three or four hazel sticks lying, and as soon as he was gone they were gone; and on the Saturday following there were six pieces of bamboe tops lay under his bench; I told my master of them, he came and looked at them, and as he was going out of the shop, my master called him back, and took him by the collar, and brought him into the shop, and there were two hazel sticks in his coat, and some charcoal; he said the sticks were none of my master's; then my master sent me for a constable; then the prisoner went on his knees, and said he would never do so no more.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670715-22-person230">
                  Alice 
                  Emory 
               <interp inst="t17670715-22-person230" type="surname" value="Emory"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-22-person230" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-22-person230" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the prosecutor; I saw the prisoner a fortnight ago last Wednesday, as I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176707150017"></xptr> I was in my own room facing the work-shop, take some spelter folder out of the box, I believe he took out ten knife points full, and he put it in his pocket, and went out immediately.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. What do you value that quantity Mrs. Emory has mentioned?</p>
               <p>Emory. I value it at two-pence.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>My master gave me leave to do jobs; an acquaintance of mine gave me a fishing-rod to repair; I asked my master about the butt, he sa id I might take it; I finished three fishing-rod tops for him, and after that, I asked him what I must go about; he said I might stay and do that butt; I did, and asked Frank for a ferril, and he gave me one; I fixed it on, and varnished the rod; my master said to me, you have blistered the butt; I said I did not take a deal of pains about it: all this is spite, because I have a set of tools of my own to do jobs, he is afraid I should take his customers away; I have between 2 and 3000 hazel tops now in my lodging, which I bought at the Horse shoe and Magpie in Holbourn.</p>
               <p>He called 
               <persName id="t17670715-22-person231">
                  Joseph 
                  Murphy 
               <interp inst="t17670715-22-person231" type="surname" value="Murphy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-22-person231" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-22-person231" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at whose house he lodged, who said he was a very industrious man, was commonly at work before he went out to his master's, and when he came to dinner, and after he left his master at night.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670715-22-person232">
                  Richard 
                  Crow 
               <interp inst="t17670715-22-person232" type="surname" value="Crow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-22-person232" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-22-person232" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave the same account of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670715-22-person233">
                  George 
                  Bowles 
               <interp inst="t17670715-22-person233" type="surname" value="Bowles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-22-person233" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-22-person233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never saw the prisoner before he was committed; when they were before the Justice, the prisoner said to his master, do not you know such a time, I stained a butt in your shop, and a gentlewoman was there, and I said, she must not lay her hand upon it, for it would burn her; the prosecutor did not deny that circumstance, but said nothing to it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17670715-22-verdict134" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670715-22-verdict134" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
