<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17651016-5">
               <interp inst="t17651016-5" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651016-5" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651016-5" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17651016"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651016-5" type="date" value="17651016"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17651016-5-off24-c57" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651016-5-defend65 t17651016-5-off24 t17651016-5-verdict26"></join>
         
               <p>517. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17651016-5-defend65" type="defendantName">
                  Amey 
                  Pinhorn 
               <interp inst="t17651016-5-defend65" type="surname" value="Pinhorn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-5-defend65" type="given" value="Amey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-5-defend65" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17651016-5-deflabel23" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651016-5-defend65 t17651016-5-deflabel23"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17651016-5-off24" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651016-5-off24" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-5-off24" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing fifteen shillings in money, numbered, the property of 
                     <persName id="t17651016-5-victim66" type="victimName">
                        Smith 
                        Dalton 
                     <interp inst="t17651016-5-victim66" type="surname" value="Dalton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651016-5-victim66" type="given" value="Smith"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651016-5-victim66" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651016-5-off24 t17651016-5-victim66"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17651016-5-cd25" type="crimeDate">October 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651016-5-off24 t17651016-5-cd25"></join>. +</p>
               <p>Smith Dalton. Last Monday was sen'night, I went into the Tun and Bull, in Oxford-road, about eight in the morning, and call'd for a pint of beer; I saw a shop mate going by, and call'd him in; we had a couple of rolls for breakfast: the prisoner came in, and sat down by my shop-mate; she asked him for a piece of bread? he said, here is a roll, you are welcome to it. She came in with a complaint, that a man had robbed her, and taken some money and a spoon out of her pocket: one of the men went out, and fetched some roast pork: she wanted bread and mustard; I went out and got some; we drank, I believe, two or three pots of beer. She went out and came in again, and asked who would lend her a shilling? I thought she was in distress, and so lent her a shilling. She went out and came in again, and said she was a captain's widow, that she had money enough, and a very fine house; she made choice of me, and said if I would go home with her, she would marry me, and give me all she was worth. I went with her to the Coach and Horses, not far off: I asked a soldier at the Tun and Bull to go with me; I thought if there was any body with me, she could do me no harm. She said, my dear, send out for some victuals for the poor man, he has not eat any thing all day; she shewed her money at the Tun and Bull. I said, you have got plenty of money, you might send for something. She said, do my dear; so I sent out for some stakes. While the soldier was gone for them, she put her hand into my breeches pocket; I took her by the wrist, and said, don't take any thing out of my pocket: she took her hand out, and I had my money then; the money was wrapped up in a piece of paper (half a guinea, and a five and three pence). The soldier and I went to the Tun and Bull again; she followed us. An oyster-woman came in; she wanted me to have some oysters: she said, Do, my dear, eat some oysters; she would have some, right or wrong, and I eat one or two. She said she would have me home with her, to this fine house: then she met a man with a laced hat like a gentleman's servant; she said to him, Cousin, this man I have got, I am to marry to-morrow, and said, get a coach. I said, madam, I suppose you have walked London streets before, and can walk home without a coach, and if you get a coach you must pay for it; she said she would. The fellow went for a coach; we got into it, she and I on one side, and the man on the other. I had not been long in the coach, before she unbuttoned my breeches, and laid her hands upon my private parts, that was the time she took my money; then she went to the other side of the coach, where the other man was: she laughed and sung. When we came to the fine house, which I saw was a bawdy-house, I went in, and unbuttoned my breeches pocket, and found my money gone; I thought with myself now she has flung me sure enough: she did not come nigh me afterwards. She said, my dear, what is the matter with you? I said, matter enough, you have picked my pocket. She went out, and this fellow followed her: then he came in again, and asked what that woman did to me? I said, did not I tell you she had pick'd my pocket: he said, God d - n the whore, I would have hang'd her, if you had told me of it. He went out again, and I thought it was my best time to make off from this bawdy-house, as they were both at the door talking together. I said, madam, you must go with me to the watch-house; she said, yes, my dear, you shall lie with me all night. I said, give me my money; she said, if you say any thing about the money, I'll swear a rape against you; and the man said he would swear I ravished her in the coach: I thought it was time to make off, and I got to my lodgings about twelve o'clock. I went to Justice Wright's, he granted me a warrant, and she was taken the next day: when I took her before the justice, she offered me twenty guineas to make it up: I told her it was out of my power.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know she took your money?</p>
               <p>Dalton. Before I went into the coach, I buttoned up my pocket, and I had my money then, it was about 10 o'clock at night. I am a carpenter, and came from Bristol but ten weeks ago.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651016-5-person67">
                  James 
                  Matthews 
               <interp inst="t17651016-5-person67" type="surname" value="Matthews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-5-person67" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-5-person67" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The warrant being brought to me, I took her up: when she was before the justice, she offered twenty guineas to make it up: while the justice was writing her mittimus, she offered a hundred guineas for ball. As we went in the coach with her to Newgate, she said she would give any money to make it up, for she had so many different causes in hand, that they would ruin her. I saw them together all the day before this affair happened, in the Tun and Bull, which is next door to my house, and I was afraid something would happen, as I knew her to be an infamous woman: she was discharged here last sessions.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176510160006"></xptr>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>He was to be sure in the coach with me, and had I the man here, he would be upon oath, that he never complained from the beginning to the end; I believe he did not lose any thing; he staid drinking. After he got out of the coach, he never said a word; he said he wanted to find a rich brother that lived in the city, and said he would be 6 d. towards a coach: he was very angry, because I would not let him go home with me. It is very hard to have my life swore away, when I have witnesses, that if they were here, would prove the contrary.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17651016-5-verdict26" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651016-5-verdict26" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>See her tried before, No. 375. in this mayoralty.</p>
            </div1>
