<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17651016-32">
               <interp inst="t17651016-32" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651016-32" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651016-32" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17651016"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651016-32" type="date" value="17651016"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17651016-32-off181-c284" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651016-32-defend348 t17651016-32-off181 t17651016-32-verdict184"></join>
         
               <p>550. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17651016-32-defend348" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Jones 
                  <interp inst="t17651016-32-defend348" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-32-defend348" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-32-defend348" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, <rs id="t17651016-32-off181" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651016-32-off181" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-32-off181" type="offenceSubcategory" value="fraud"></interp>
               together with 
                     <persName id="t17651016-32-person349">
                        James 
                        Gawl 
                     <interp inst="t17651016-32-person349" type="surname" value="Gawl"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651016-32-person349" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651016-32-person349" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , not taken, for acquiring to themselves two guineas, one half guinea, and nine shillings, in money numbered, the money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17651016-32-victim351" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Davis 
                        <interp inst="t17651016-32-victim351" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651016-32-victim351" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651016-32-victim351" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651016-32-off181 t17651016-32-victim351"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , by fraudulently cozening and cheating him, at a game called hiding under a hat
            </rs>. <rs id="t17651016-32-cd182" type="crimeDate">February 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651016-32-off181 t17651016-32-cd182"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651016-32-person352">
                  John 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17651016-32-person352" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-32-person352" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-32-person352" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 21st of February, as I was going up Holbourn, the prisoner met me, and asked me if I wanted a place? I told him I did; he said, a gentleman had a misfortune with his man, he had broke his leg, and if I would go with him, he would take me to the gentleman; that there was nothing to do, but only to look after a couple of hunting horses. He took me to the <placeName id="t17651016-32-crimeloc183">Blue-posts, in Holbourn</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17651016-32-crimeloc183" type="placeName" value="Blue-posts, in Holbourn"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17651016-32-crimeloc183" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651016-32-off181 t17651016-32-crimeloc183"></join>, and said a kinsman of the gentleman's was to meet him there: he went in, and called for a pint of wine, and gave me a glass. Presently, in came the kinsman, as he called him, and asked him how he came off the night before, about tossing up? the kinsman said he lost 25 or 26 with the butcher, but did not say of what. The prisoner asked him if he would have a toss again? he said, he had had very bad luck the night before, and he would not: he at last agreed to toss up with him; they tossed for a guinea. They put a halfpenny under a hat, and tossed at what they call the best two in three. The prisoner won the guinea; the kinsman went out, and said he had had very bad luck; he got five or six guineas of him, and the kinsman went out between every time. While he was out, the prisoner wanted me to go his halves; I said, I have no money to sport with: he said, it was only venturing, there was no danger but that I should get money; so I agreed, that if he lost, I was to give him 6 d. and if he won, he was to give me 6 d. The man came in again; they tossed, and the prisoner won, and gave me 6 d: they tossed up two or three times more; the prisoner won every time, but gave me only one 6 d. the prisoner wanted me to go more, and said, if you come to London, you must not mind a trifle; what is six-pence? you may as well get as much more: this was while the other was out. I put my hand in my pocket, but did not know how much silver I had: I pulled my money out, and said. I would not go any more than a shilling; he put his hand upon mine, and said, this is the very thing; he took my money out of my hand, and said, go my halves: I said, I would not go all that, it is all the money I have: he said, you will be sure to get as much more. The man came in again, but I did not consent to it: they tossed up; then the prisoner said, it is all gone, I have lost 10 l. he would not give me my money; the other man took the money up. Then the landlord came in, and said, I understand you are gambling, I would have you get out of my house; the kinsman paid for the wine, and paid something over the reckoning. I was frightened, and did not know what to do; it was all done in an instant; they went away, and I soon lost sight of them when they got into the street.</p>
               <p>Q. What money did you lose?</p>
               <p>Davis. He took out of my hand two guineas, one half guinea, and nine shillings in silver.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651016-32-person353">
                  William 
                  Pain 
               <interp inst="t17651016-32-person353" type="surname" value="Pain"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-32-person353" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-32-person353" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last sessions but one, Mr. Alderman Harley desired me to go to Hicks's-hall, because this man was indicted there for the same offence. I got a warrant which the alderman granted, back'd by the justices: about a fortnight after, I took the prisoner, and carried him before my Lord Mayor; he owned there he had the money by gaming, and that he had a right to it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I said the money was won, and I was in company the time it was won; but I had no part of it, nor no connection with him: I lost my money with the man. It is a malicious prosecution carried on by Mr. Pain; he has taken my liberty away, and would have taken my life away, if he could. I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176510160032"></xptr> was capitally tried on this offence last sessions: though this man tells his tale with such simplicity as he does, he is a monstrous villain to swear I took his money; he wanted to make it up for a guinea. Mr. Fielding's man came to me four or five times before I was taken up, and said this man would make it up for a guinea. I said I had a right to demand of him, and not him of me.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. What is that about a guinea?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. He got four guineas of a countryman of my acquaintance, and he made it up with the prisoner afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. Whether you was not offered twenty five shillings in a cellar in the Strand, by the man that had won your money, and you said, take it back again; if you can give twenty-five shillings, you can give me fifty.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. One of Justice Fielding's men, named Wright, took me to meet a friend of the prisoner's, to make it up; he said, I should have all the money again, and I must come before Justice Fielding, and say I was satisfied, and I would not say so; then he said I might go about my business.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. This young man, named Wright, belonging to Sir John Fielding's office, came to me, and said, I hear there is a warrant out against you, and rather than you shall come to any trouble, I will make any satisfaction. He went over to the prosecutor, who had given the man that took me up, orders to make it up, if he could have any reasonable satisfaction: the man that won the money, offered him twenty-five shillings, and he said, take it back; if you can give that, you can give fifty.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17651016-32-verdict184" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651016-32-verdict184" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17651016-32-punish185" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651016-32-punish185" type="punishmentCategory" value="imprison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-32-punish185" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="newgate"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651016-32-defend348 t17651016-32-punish185"></join>
               Imp
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17651016-32-punish186" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651016-32-punish186" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-32-punish186" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="fine"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651016-32-defend348 t17651016-32-punish186"></join>
               
                     <note>[Fine. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17651016-32-punish187" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651016-32-punish187" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-32-punish187" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="sureties"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651016-32-defend348 t17651016-32-punish187"></join>
               
                     <note>[Provide sureties for good behaviour. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
               <p>See him tried before, No. 460. in the Second Part of September Session's-Paper.</p>
            </div1>
