<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640607-49">
               <interp inst="t17640607-49" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640607-49" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640607-49" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640607"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640607-49" type="date" value="17640607"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640607-49-off280-c307" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-49-defend408 t17640607-49-off280 t17640607-49-verdict284"></join>
         
               <p>373. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17640607-49-defend408" type="defendantName">
                  
                     James 
                     Mannen 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17640607-49-alias-5" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-49-defend408 t17640607-49-alias-5"></join>Manning</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-49-defend408" type="surname" value="Mannen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-49-defend408" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-49-defend408" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17640607-49-off280" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640607-49-off280" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-49-off280" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing a brown mare, value 8 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17640607-49-victim411" type="victimName">
                     Daniel 
                     Chase 
                  <interp inst="t17640607-49-victim411" type="surname" value="Chase"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-49-victim411" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-49-victim411" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-49-off280 t17640607-49-victim411"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17640607-49-cd281" type="crimeDate">May 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-49-off280 t17640607-49-cd281"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640607-49-person412">
                  Daniel 
                  Chase 
               <interp inst="t17640607-49-person412" type="surname" value="Chase"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-49-person412" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-49-person412" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17640607-49-crimeloc282">Church-street, Hackney</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640607-49-crimeloc282" type="placeName" value="Church-street, Hackney"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640607-49-crimeloc282" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-49-off280 t17640607-49-crimeloc282"></join>; I am partner with Mr. 
               <persName id="t17640607-49-person413">
                  James 
                  Mitchell 
               <interp inst="t17640607-49-person413" type="surname" value="Mitchell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-49-person413" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-49-person413" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I am a <rs id="t17640607-49-viclabel283" type="occupation">brewer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-49-victim411 t17640607-49-viclabel283"></join>. On the 9th of May our horsekeeper came to me about five in the morning, and told me my mare was lost. I went to the brewhouse, and found she was gone, and a bridle and saddle also. I had seen her in the stable about ten over night: this mare is my own property, which I had before I entered into partnership: there was a sorrel horse, the property of my partner and me, missing at the same time, from the same stable, which is in the dray-yard.</p>
               <p>Q. What colour was your mare?</p>
               <p>Chase. She was a brown saddle mare: we used our best endeavours to find them again; we had them advertised, and printed hand-bills. On the Friday morning I was informed by Mr. Blackwell, that my mare was at Walthamstow, and the man that took her in custody. I went, and found the horse and mare at Lea-bridge, standing at the foot of the bridge, and the prisoner in custody at a public house there. I was told the prisoner had sold the saddle to a barge-man; I asked the prisoner if it was true; he said, he had; I asked him, how he came by the horse and mare? he said, he found them in the marshes tied together, with the bridle and saddle on one of them. When we came before the Justices at the Angel and Crown, he said he found them in a close. I said, You first said you found them in the marshes; he said then, he found them in a close by the marshes. After that, he said he found them in a close near the Bell at Laytonstone, where he had left my mare: he never acknowledged taking them from the stable; he owned he went to the Bell at Laytonstone, and had three pints of beer; and having no money, he left the mare with 
               <persName id="t17640607-49-person414">
                  Joseph 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17640607-49-person414" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-49-person414" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-49-person414" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , which we found to be true.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640607-49-person415">
                  James 
                  Mitchell 
               <interp inst="t17640607-49-person415" type="surname" value="Mitchell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-49-person415" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-49-person415" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was told the mare and gelding were lost out of the stable; I sent to the turnpikes, and could get no information of them; we advertised them, and had hand-bills delivered about.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see them last?</p>
               <p>Mitchell. I saw them both in the stable about ten o'clock the evening before. Mr. Hillier's son came to me on Thursday evening, about eleven o'clock, and called me out of bed, and said his father had got the man that had the horse and mare. I went, and found the horse at the King's head at Walthamstow: there was the prisoner drinking in a room; I asked him, how he came by the horse and mare? He said, he found them tied together. I asked him, what was become of the mare? he said, she was at the Bell at Laytonstone. He equivocated about them: first he said he found them in the marsh; then, in a close; then, in a close by the side of the marsh: then he said, he found one at one place, and the other at another. I went over again on the Friday morning, and sent for the mare; she was brought to us where the horse was, and we brought them and the prisoner home.</p>

               <p>Q. Was the stable locked up?</p>
               <p>Mitchell. No, it was not, because we are fetching the horses out almost all hours of the night.</p>
               <p>Sacheverel Hillier. I live at the ferry-house at Walthamstow; the prisoner came to my house, and had three pints of liquor on Thursday the 10th in the morning: I had been out, but found him there about 11 o'clock; he slept, I believe, five hours; he had the sorrel horse with him; I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176406070030"></xptr> observed two sacks upon his horse; I asked him whose they were? he said, I knew better than he did; they were mine; I took them; he brought the saddle into the house, and offered it me for a shilling; I said I would have nothing to do with it; he said he would sell it; then John Phips bought it of him for four shillings; then he offered to sell the horse to Phips; I desired he would have nothing to do with him, for I suspected he stole him.</p>
               <p>Q. Whose horse did he say he was?</p>
               <p>Hillier. He said it was his horse; after that he said it was Mr. Trueman's servant's horse. After that, he wanted a pint of brandy-hot; I would not let him have any thing; then he wanted a pint of beer; I said, You shall have nothing; and bid him go out of the house. I watched him, and after he was got a pretty way, he was returning; I went and met him, and saw he had got a sack under his arm; then I searched him, to see he had no fire-arms, and took him before Mr. Barties, a Justice of the Peace, and had him examined about the horse: he gave a very lame account; I took him to the King's Head, and offered him a pot of beer. A young man there was looking in the news-paper, and saw the horse and mare advertised: the horse was described properly. I went and told the Justice of it; then the prisoner owned the horse was Mr. Mitchell's property, and said he had left the mare at Mr. Taylor's, at the Bell. I sent for Mr. Mitchell, and was present when the horse and mare were delivered to Messrs. Mitchell and Chase.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. That man has one of the bridles; I do not know what business he has with it; he would have had the horse, if I would have let him; he would have had the whole tote; he is no better than he should be, for all he has got a curled wig on.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640607-49-person416">
                  John 
                  Phips 
               <interp inst="t17640607-49-person416" type="surname" value="Phips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-49-person416" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-49-person416" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a barge-man; I bought this saddle of the prisoner for 4 s. (Produced in court, and deposed to by Mr. Chase.)</p>
               <p>Mitchell. I saw the saddle in the stable the day before the horse and mare were taken away.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I did not steal them; I thought to take them home again, and should have done so, if they had not stopped me.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mitchell. Did you know the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Mitchell. He did live servant with me about three years ago.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640607-49-verdict284" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640607-49-verdict284" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-49-verdict284" type="verdictSubcategory" value="withRecommendation"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17640607-49-punish285" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640607-49-punish285" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-49-defend408 t17640607-49-punish285"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Recommended by the jury and prosecutor.</p>
            </div1>
