<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17620714-34">
               <interp inst="t17620714-34" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620714-34" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620714-34" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17620714"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620714-34" type="date" value="17620714"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620714-34-off152-c242" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620714-34-defend312 t17620714-34-off152 t17620714-34-verdict159"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620714-34-off152-c243" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620714-34-defend314 t17620714-34-off152 t17620714-34-verdict159"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620714-34-off152-c244" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620714-34-defend316 t17620714-34-off152 t17620714-34-verdict159"></join>
         
               <p>213, 214, 215. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17620714-34-defend312" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Sullivan 
                  <interp inst="t17620714-34-defend312" type="surname" value="Sullivan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-defend312" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-defend312" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17620714-34-defend314" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Caswell 
                  <interp inst="t17620714-34-defend314" type="surname" value="Caswell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-defend314" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-defend314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17620714-34-defend316" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Fitzgerald 
                  <interp inst="t17620714-34-defend316" type="surname" value="Fitzgerald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-defend316" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-defend316" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted, the first for <rs id="t17620714-34-off152" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-off152" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-off152" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               committing a rape on the body of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17620714-34-victim318" type="victimName">
                           Ann 
                           Ward 
                        <interp inst="t17620714-34-victim318" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620714-34-victim318" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620714-34-victim318" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620714-34-off152 t17620714-34-victim318"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17620714-34-viclabel153" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620714-34-victim318 t17620714-34-viclabel153"></join>, and the other two for aiding, abetting, comforting, and assisting the said Sullivan to commit the said rape
            </rs>, <rs id="t17620714-34-cd154" type="crimeDate">June 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620714-34-off152 t17620714-34-cd154"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>Ann Ware. About 9 o'clock in the evening on the 29th of June, I was coming from Mrs. Cockshed's in Lambeth Marsh.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. I live opposite North Audley street, Oxford Road, at the house of Mr. Bezley, a cheesemonger: I have lodged there about half a year.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. I have been a <rs id="t17620714-34-viclabel155" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620714-34-victim318 t17620714-34-viclabel155"></join>; I take in <rs id="t17620714-34-viclabel156" type="occupation">plain work</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620714-34-victim318 t17620714-34-viclabel156"></join>, <rs id="t17620714-34-viclabel157" type="occupation">milliners work</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620714-34-victim318 t17620714-34-viclabel157"></join>, and <rs id="t17620714-34-viclabel158" type="occupation">wash small cloaths</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620714-34-victim318 t17620714-34-viclabel158"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you been a servant?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. I lived in one place a year and threequarters in Pall Mall, and a year at squire Hickey's in St. Albans street.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you born?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. I was born in Warwickshire; my father and mother live there.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you go out from your lodgings that day?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. I went out at 4 o'clock, and got to Lambeth Marsh about 8: I returned home through the Horse Guards into the Park; there the prisoner Caswell asked me to drink a glass of wine, which I refused at first.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see him before?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. No, never to my knowledge, nor any of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Whereabouts was you when he accosted you?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. As I was coming out at Spring Gardens; I was not got out of the park; he told me he would take me to his lodgings in Great Suffolk street, to the house of one Mrs. Allen.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he alone at this time?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. He was; I went with him there; he knocked at the door and drew back, and bid me ask for Mr. Sullivan: he did not go in with me. I asked for Sullivan; Sullivan was at the door, and took me up stairs; there was nobody in the room when I was first taken in. Sullivan went down again, and left me along a good while. Then Cas well came up; after he had been up a little time there came another young woman; she came by her self. They had got a bottle of rum, and made rum and water; we sat till near 11 o'clock, drinking rum and water. Then I wanted to come away, and they refused it; and, upon my being obstinate, they put me into a back room; they all of them wanted to hinder my coming away. They locked the back room door, and were all three with me in the room They put the other young woman in another room there I heard a crying out. Caswell lay with me and the other two assisted him the while.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he enter your body?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. He did.</p>
               <p>Q. What did Fitzgerald do?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. He lay on the bed with me at the same time; and when I made any resistance, he held me.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176207140022"></xptr> I arose up, and thought I was got clear of them, but Caswell knocked me down on the floor; and when I cried out for assistance, he beat me about the head and arms, and told me nobody would come to my assistance; and I believe he would have murdered me, if Fitzgerald had not said, Do not murder the poor creature; remember, you came of a woman yourself; do not use her ill. Though Fitzgerald took my part, yet he lay with me the same as the others did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you make any resistance?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. I did not make a great deal; I was not able. He entered my body too, then Caswell picked my pocket of 1 s. and 4 1/2 d. After that Sullivan lay with me in the same manner as the others did; then they left me, I believe; but I do not know when, for they left me senseless. When I came to myself, I found nobody in the room; I called, and they said the door should not be opened; I opened the window with intent to jump out, but I found it too high: I cried to get out; it was up two pair of stairs. I looked round the room, and found another door; I went down another pair of stairs: then it was light; I believe it was about five o'clock; I opened the street-door; Mrs. Allen called to me; she said she had been up all night, and had heard such a violent noise in the house, she was afraid of being murdered. She said one of them came down to her with a sword: she said she knew I had been very ill used by my being beat and bruised about the head and face. I had not a shilling to get a warrant; she said she would lend me one. I staid with her in her room near two hours; then I went to Justice Garnoa at Charing-cross for a warrant: I took up Mrs. Allen, the woman of the house, that morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you take her up?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. Because she said he heard me crying out all night.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you call the watch?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. No, I did not: the men were taken the night following, or the morning after; it was on the Tuesday night I was taken to that house, and on the Wednesday night Sullivan was taken at the same house; and the other two the next morning.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you, who had never seen these men before in your life, to go along with one of them there alone?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. He told me he would use me extremely well: he appeared in the character of an officer. I did not expect to be used any other way than well.</p>
               <p>Q. Did those men lie with you against your will and consent, or no?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. Yes, they did.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you go with Caswell for to this house?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. I had no other apprehension than that he took me there but to lie with me; but when I saw there were two more, I was not willing that any of them should lie with me.</p>
               <p>Q. Before you was locked up in that room, was there any proposal made by any of them to lie with you?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. No.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Then he pick'd you up in the Park, and you went with him, intending to lie with him?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. Yes.</p>
               <p>Counsel. That was very odd to lie with a stranger.</p>
               <p>A. Ward. It was, to be sure.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you make any opposition to going with him at first?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620714-34-person319">
                  A.
                   Ward I
               <interp inst="t17620714-34-person319" type="surname" value="Ward I"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person319" type="given" value="A."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person319" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             did; but he said I should be well used, and might go away when I would.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know who the woman was that came up to you?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. No.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did she go away?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at all in bed with Caswell?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Were his breeches off?</p>
               <p>A.. That I cannot swear: the candle was out, and it was dark.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there not a charge upon you that you was got to his pocket?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. Yes, he d - d me and said, What is your hands doing in my breeches? this he said when I challenged him with picking my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this before or after the violence offered to your person?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. This was after that.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you produced any money before them?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620714-34-person320">
                  A.
                   Ward I
               <interp inst="t17620714-34-person320" type="surname" value="Ward I"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person320" type="given" value="A."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person320" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had only 2 s. 5 1/2 d. and one of the shillings was got into my glove, so they missed that.</p>
               <p>Q. When you went before the justice, what information did you make at first?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. The same that I have said here.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you set your name to one paper or two?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. I set my name to two.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this [ producing a paper]; Is this the first or last?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. The first, I believe; but cannot be certain.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Here is no mention made of having been robbed.</p>
               <p>A. Ward. I believe there is not, but I told the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176207140023"></xptr> justice of it: my information there was the same as now.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Allen. I live in Suffolk-street, and have for five years past: it is a house of lodgings for quality, that is, people of fashion. My husband was a cabinet maker; he is dead. The three prisoners at the bar took lodgings at my house on the 25th or 26th of last June.</p>
               <p>Q. Which took the lodgings?</p>
               <p>Allen. Caswell did; and said, Mr. Fitzgerald was his guardian, and that he must have another bed for his guardian in the same room: it was a two pair of stairs floor. I never saw him in my life before he came to my house, or either of the others.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you desire to know their characters?</p>
               <p>Allen. I never dispute the character of an officer, if he has a sword by his side and a lac'd hat on.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did they take the lodgings for?</p>
               <p>Allen. For a week: I never let them but from week to week. They were in my house but three days: I think they came on the Friday, and I desired them to go out on the Monday, because I did not like their proceedings: they told me they would not go out</p>
               <p>Q. What do you know of the matter?</p>
               <p>Allen. Sullivan came down on the Tuesday night and wanted a tea-kettle of water; I boiled him one at ten, and he came down again for another at eleven. I said, I could not light a fire, my maid was ill; he said, if I would not, he would double me and put me up the chimney, and called me old b - h: he threatened me very much, and said, he would do as he pleased</p>
               <p>Q. Had you heard at that time any noise in your house?</p>
               <p>Allen. To be sure I heard a noise of racketting, and I desired them to be quiet; then they said, Do not molest us; we'll do as we please. I went to bed in the kitchen under ground; I always lie there; that was soon after eleven, and got up rather before six. My servant had scalded her leg, and she was in bed in the garret; some distance from them, not over their heads, but over another part of the house; she had not been down some days.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any cries of a woman?</p>
               <p>Allen. Indeed I could not distinguish the voice of a woman so far off.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any body cry out for help?</p>
               <p>Allen. To the best of my knowledge I did not. I heard a noise between eleven and twelve; but I was weary, and went to bed: when I got up the young woman was standing at my street-door. I hearing the door open, and not shut, I got up, because there were two people in the garret that were to go out at six. I had put my cloaths on, but being very ill, lay down again.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever seen Ann Ward before?</p>
               <p>Allen. No, never to my knowledge. I asked her what brought her there, or to whom she belonged? she told me she was pick'd up somewhere about Spring Garden, and decoyed into the house by one or two gentlemen, and they had ravished her, and robbed her of 1 s. and 4 d.</p>
               <p>Q. What kind of condition did she appear to be in?</p>
               <p>Allen. She seemed to be a little flurried: I did not examine her. She went away after staying about half an hour. She told me she had been very badly used: she went immediately to Justice Garnon, and fetch'd a warrant for me; she had told me she would fetch a warrant for them, and she had no money; I said, if she came to me I would lend her a shilling, because I did not like their proceedings, and I would be gl ad to get them out of my house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you lend her a shilling?</p>
               <p>Allen. No, I did not, because I had no silver I was taken with a warrant before Justice Garnon about two o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the prisoners in your house at the time the girl was with you in the morning?</p>
               <p>Allen. No; Caswell and Fitzgerald went out between five and six.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was Sullivan?</p>
               <p>Allen. I suppose he was in bed; but I did not go up to see, for I dare not. I saw Sullivan about eight at the street door; he came down stairs; the other two never came more into my house They would make me find those gentlemen: Justice Garnon granted a warrant in order to take them up. Sullivan came in between eight and nine at night; we took him: I never saw the other two till I saw them before the justice.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know 
               <persName id="t17620714-34-person321">
                  Jane 
                  Mason 
               <interp inst="t17620714-34-person321" type="surname" value="Mason"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person321" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person321" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Allen. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not see another woman there that Tuesday night?</p>
               <p>Allen. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did an indifferent woman come to you about a week after, and ask you how it happened?</p>
               <p>Allen. Yes: she asked me if I knew 
               <persName id="t17620714-34-person322">
                  Ann 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17620714-34-person322" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person322" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person322" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620714-34-person323">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Stevens 
               <interp inst="t17620714-34-person323" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person323" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person323" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the house when the the young woman the prosecutrix came in.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Stevens. I am an assistant to the maid, because she has scalded her foot. When she went up stairs I saw the skirt of her gown; I did not see her face.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>Stevens. It was about nine o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Who went up with her?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176207140024"></xptr>Stevens. Nobody went up stairs but herself; and Sullivan called to Mrs. Allen for a candle, and in the mean time she went up stairs; when Sullivan had a candle he followed her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Fitzgerald or Caswell that night?</p>
               <p>Stevens. No, I did not: I went out into the street, being willing to see, and I saw two women sitting in the window, and there was no noise among them.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you lie in the house?</p>
               <p>Stevens. I do; in the one pair of stairs room.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you go to bed?</p>
               <p>Stevens. I went to bed about half an hour after eleven.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you get up the next morning?</p>
               <p>Stevens. I got up a little after seven.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you lie in a fore or back room?</p>
               <p>Stevens. I lie in the fore room.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any noise?</p>
               <p>Stevens. No. I did not the least noise as is.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you sleep sound?</p>
               <p>Stevens. No, I never slept sound at all that night. They lay a great way from where I lay; they might have made a noise, and I not heard them: our house is a double house, and the room they were in is three rooms from mine.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you first see your mistress?</p>
               <p>Stevens. She had her cloaths on sitting in the kitchen. I did not see the young woman at all till I saw her at the justice's: her aunt, I believe it was, came between seven and eight o'clock, and said her kinswoman had been ill used; she asked for Mrs. Allen. Soon after Sullivan came in I asked him how they came to use the young woman so; he said he did not use her ill. There were two or three women there, and he turned them down stairs; one of them wanted to pick a gentleman's pocket.</p>

               <p>Caswell to Prosecutrix. Pray, how did I meet with you in the Park? Did you not catch hold of my sword behind, and ask me where I was going?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Caswell. Did you not ask me where I lodged? and I said at Mrs. Allen's; and you said, that was a house that entertained girls.</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. I told you I did not know; and I asked you what a house it was.</p>
               <p>Caswell. Did you not go into the bedchamber willingly?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. No, I never saw the bedchamber till after I was forced into it, after eleven at night.</p>
               <p>Caswell. Did you not lie down on the bed of your own accord?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Caswell. Did I strip?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. That I do not know.</p>
               <p>Caswell. Did I catch your hand in my pocket?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. No, you did not.</p>
               <p>Caswell. Did I not bid you go out of the room?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. No, you locked me into the room.</p>
               <p>Caswell. Did I go to call the watch?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. I believe he did go to call the watch, but there was no watch came.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the watch called for?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. That I do not know.</p>
               <p>Caswell. Did you lay your hands on Fitzgerald's neck and say, pray do not call the watch, for if you do I am ruined for ever.</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. I believe Fitzgerald did hinder me from being murdered.</p>
               <p>Caswell to Allen. What kind of a house do you keep?</p>
               <p>Allen. I keep a very sober house, and I desired them to go out of my house, for I was afraid of my life. I had put off my cloaths, and put them on again; for I was afraid of their coming down and murdering me, that is the truth.</p>
               <p>Caswell's Defence.</p>
               <p>The girl that lay in the next room all the night is here to be examined.</p>
               <p>Sullivan's Defence.</p>
               <p>I have nothing to say. She came to the door, I was getting a bowl and glasses ready, and a gallon of shrub, against my master came home; I said half a gallon would not satisfy them.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoners.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620714-34-person324">
                  Mary Ann 
                  Chandles 
               <interp inst="t17620714-34-person324" type="surname" value="Chandles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person324" type="given" value="Mary Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person324" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at this house in Suffolk-street.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you there?</p>
               <p>Chandles. I had been out, and met Mr. Caswell, and he took me to the room: there were 
               <persName id="t17620714-34-person325">
                  Ann 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17620714-34-person325" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person325" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person325" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and another person in the room when I went in; the other immediately left the room: there was punch proposed, and a gallon of rum drank out that evening. 
               <persName id="t17620714-34-person326">
                  Ann 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17620714-34-person326" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person326" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person326" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             drank glass for glass with the gentlemen.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you fuddled?</p>
               <p>Chandles. No, I was not; I refused to drink.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any of you go to bed?</p>
               <p>Chandles. I did; before I went to bed I saw 
               <persName id="t17620714-34-person327">
                  Ann 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17620714-34-person327" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person327" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person327" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             go with Mr. Caswell into his bed-room; that was just before I went to bed.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go to bed in the same room?</p>
               <p>Chandles. No; I went to bed in another room along with Mr. Sullivan; he never was near 
               <persName id="t17620714-34-person328">
                  Ann 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17620714-34-person328" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person328" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person328" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             all night; he sat opposite the table to her, and he continued in bed with me all night.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any noise in the night?</p>
               <p>Chandles. No, I heard none till Caswell called<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176207140025"></xptr> the watch; he said, she had had her hand in his pocket in order to pick it.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was you to them?</p>
               <p>Chandles. There was the dining room between them and us; she was in the dining room when he called the watch; I could hear what past; they were not long in the bed room together; she was soon in the dining room after that.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say to that charge of having her hand in his pocket?</p>
               <p>Chandles. She said nothing to that, but cried, and made a deal to do, and begged he would not call the watch.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you get up immediately?</p>
               <p>Chandles. No, I did not; they locked her in the room, and went out about four o'clock in the morning; they told me it was with intent to get a constable to take her to the round-house.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was it after you went to bed that he called the watch?</p>
               <p>Chandles. This was about a quarter of an hour after.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they come back?</p>
               <p>Chandles. No, they did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the three prisoners before?</p>
               <p>Chandles. I had known them about a week before.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you come acquainted with them?</p>
               <p>Chandles. I became acquainted with Mr. Caswell in the Park by accident.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever been at this house before that night?</p>
               <p>Chandles. No, I had not; I had been with Mr. Fitzgerald and Mr. Caswell at their lodging in Golden Square; I did not go with them into the lodging, but I went to the place.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was the other woman that was there?</p>
               <p>Chandles. I really cannot say who she was.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was it that Caswell and Ann Ward went together into the bed room?</p>
               <p>Chandles. It was about two o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know 
               <persName id="t17620714-34-person329">
                  Ann 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17620714-34-person329" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person329" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person329" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             before?</p>
               <p>Chandles. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620714-34-person330">
                  Jane 
                  Mason 
               <interp inst="t17620714-34-person330" type="surname" value="Mason"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person330" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person330" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew 
               <persName id="t17620714-34-person331">
                  Ann 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17620714-34-person331" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person331" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person331" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             by fight, not that I spoke to her till last week. I heard of these three gentlemen being confined; I went to enquire whether it was true or not; this was yesterday was a week. I asked her, what was all this that was done in her house? She said, do not come bothering of me about it, I know nothing about her; do not come bothering about a common whore of the town. I know 
               <persName id="t17620714-34-person332">
                  Ann 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17620714-34-person332" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person332" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person332" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , for when I lived at Mr. Wilson's lottery office, she came there about some tickets. Last week I was coming through the Park, I saw her; I stept up to her, and said, how do you do, madam? She said, I dont know you; I have seen you some where; I do not know where. Said I, are you not the gentlewoman that has committed these three men to gaol? Said she, I shall make a fine booty of them; but, she said, her aunt would not appear for her, so there were none that would speak for her. I said, will not Mrs. Allen speak for you? She said, she did not think she would.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the three men before?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620714-34-person333">
                  Jane 
                  Mason 
               <interp inst="t17620714-34-person333" type="surname" value="Mason"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person333" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person333" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never saw them till I saw them in the Gatehouse. I asked their washer-woman to let me go and see them; so she let me, at my request, carry their clean linen to them.</p>
               <p>Q. On what account did you want to see them?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620714-34-person334">
                  Jane 
                  Mason 
               <interp inst="t17620714-34-person334" type="surname" value="Mason"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person334" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person334" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I wanted to see them because they were committed so falsely.</p>
               <p>Q. What could induce you to go to the house of Mrs. Allen to ask about them as you knew none of them?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620714-34-person335">
                  Jane 
                  Mason 
               <interp inst="t17620714-34-person335" type="surname" value="Mason"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person335" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person335" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . It was out of curiosity.</p>
               <p>Q. to A. Ward. Did you go into the dining room after you had been in the bed room?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. No, I never did; I never was out of the bed room till I found the way out myself.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did they stay in the bed room?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. Two of them staid with me; but Sullivan did not stay above a quarter of an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Caswell charge you with having a hand in his breeches?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. I charged him with having a hand in my pocket, and then he charged me; this was after he had laid with me.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember the watch being called?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. There was something about calling the watch, but that was from the dining room.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was that?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. I believe it was about half an hour after two o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you desire them not to call the watch?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did this girl that has been examined come in before or after you?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. She came in after me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know 
               <persName id="t17620714-34-person336">
                  Jane 
                  Mason 
               <interp inst="t17620714-34-person336" type="surname" value="Mason"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person336" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person336" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             before?</p>
               <p>A. Ward. I never saw her before now, to my knowledge, upon my oath.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620714-34-person337">
                  George 
                  Rowen 
               <interp inst="t17620714-34-person337" type="surname" value="Rowen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person337" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person337" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; I live in Poultney-street; I am a student in the Middle Temple, and am a justice of peace in the county of Kerry in Ireland; I was sent for by Caswell to go to justice Garnan's; he was in distress there. I told Mr. Garnan I should be glad to see what was the charge against these young men. He took out the examination which was given against them, he read it to me; when he had gone through them, I asked, what was to be done for these people? I said, by the case they are bailable; because to the best of my judgement I thought so.</p>
               <p>Q. Why do you think so?</p>
               <p>Rowen. There was nothing charged positive; it was rather an attempt to ravish I told them I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176207140026"></xptr> would get the best bail I could. Sir, said the justice, are you a house-keeper. I said, I am not, but I would join with them. I sent for my taylor, and desired he would come down; he accordingly came down. I applied to the prisoners to know if they had any body else to be bail for them. Then the justice said he would do nothing in the affair till he saw the prosecutrix. Sir, said I, is she to think them sufficient, or you? Upon which I waited a considerable time, and found there was nothing to be done in it; I thought there was something singular in it. I went for advice. After that I was told the prosecutrix was come, and was at justice Garnan's. I went to Caswell, and asked what was done? He said, nothing; the door was locked; Mr. Garnan said he was not ready for us yet; and in a quarter of an hour there was word sent he was ready; then there was an absolute rape sworn; then I said, it is an odd affair, and made some little annotations of my own; that this lady's place of abode was not mentioned; and, in the second place, there was a rape sworn only against Caswell; then the girl said the other men had done the same; then that was interlined. I found there was nothing to be done, either good, bad, or indifferent, but they must go to gaol. Said I to Caswell, put it out of your head, you must go to gaol; they were carried to the Gatehouse.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of your own knowledge of this affair?</p>
               <p>Rowen. On Monday the fifth of July 
               <persName id="t17620714-34-person338">
                  Ann 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17620714-34-person338" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person338" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-person338" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came to Mrs. Allen's while I was there. Mrs. Allen had a mind to lock the door; I said, you shall not while I am here. I said, Miss Ward, you see what an unfortunate condition these poor creatures are in, tell me the case. I asked her where Caswell picked her up? She said, in Spring Gardens. I asked her, did she consent to go to his lodgings? She said, she expected genteel treatment; but she had the contrary. She told me Caswell gave her a box, and she got a mark, pointing near her eye; she declared solemnly she had been robbed by these people of one shilling and four-pence; and said, she could swear to a guinea, if she pleased: then she swore she would lose her life or have satisfaction. I asked her, what satisfaction she expected? She bid me go to justice Garman, and he would tell me. I said I had been there, and could not meet with him. I said, in the name of God, can you be so bitter to take those peoples lives, when you confess you was a street-walker? Then she abused me for what I had said before the justice. I beg my lord she may be confronted by me; I know she will not deny a little.</p>
               <p>Q. What are the prisoners?</p>
               <p>Rowen. I have known Caswell from his infancy: he is a man of character.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think he would be guilty of such a thing as this?</p>
               <p>Rowen. Since I see this affair before me, I will not pretend to say.</p>
               <p>Q. What is Caswell's business?</p>
               <p>Rowen. His father is an attorney in Ireland. He came over here to raise forty men for the government's service: he has lodged in three places; the first place he was eaten up with bugs: he left that and came to Mrs. Allen's, and that was not of the best character; there are women of bad character come there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he lodge in Golden Square?</p>
               <p>Rowen. No, he never did; the last lodging he was in was next door to me; he was not there long, for he was sent to the Gatehouse.</p>
               <p>Justice Garnan. I am ready to be sworn, if the court think proper.</p>
               <p>[He is sworn.]</p>
               <p>Justice Garnan. There was but one examination taken of this young woman; this is it [producing one]; she came and made a complaint on the Wednesday morning, and told me the story almost exactly as she has done here.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she complain of an attempt to ravish her, or that she had actually been ravished?</p>
               <p>Garnan. She told the circumstances as now, and I apprehended it a rape; but I was tender, as she had told me of having been picked up in the park, and it made me a little delicate; the circumstances were extreamly strong.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this the first and only examination?</p>
               <p>Garnan. This is the first and only examination which she signed; there were, previous to this, papers taken down, and I ordered my clerk to reduce them into one; there were what she said at first; what she said when I granted my warrant to take up Allen; and then what she said on other examinations: the old woman promised to do the best she could to take them; she said she thought they would come in the evening; and in the evening Sullivan came and was taken; he was brought to me, and I sent him to St. Martin's round-house. Mrs. Allen declared he came down stairs with a drawn sword, and threatened her. The young woman did charge all three with having lain with her.</p>
               <p>All three <rs id="t17620714-34-verdict159" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-verdict159" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17620714-34-punish160" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620714-34-punish160" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620714-34-defend312 t17620714-34-punish160"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620714-34-defend314 t17620714-34-punish160"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620714-34-defend316 t17620714-34-punish160"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
