<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670909-2">
               <interp inst="t17670909-2" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670909-2" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670909-2" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670909"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670909-2" type="date" value="17670909"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670909-2-off12-c131" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-2-defend133 t17670909-2-off12 t17670909-2-verdict16"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670909-2-off12-c132" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-2-defend135 t17670909-2-off12 t17670909-2-verdict18"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670909-2-off12-c133" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-2-defend136 t17670909-2-off12 t17670909-2-verdict18"></join>
         
               <p>407, 408, 409. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17670909-2-defend133" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Tinsey 
                  <interp inst="t17670909-2-defend133" type="surname" value="Tinsey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-defend133" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-defend133" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17670909-2-defend135" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Gibson 
                  <interp inst="t17670909-2-defend135" type="surname" value="Gibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-defend135" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-defend135" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-defend135" type="age" value="eighteen"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               <persName id="t17670909-2-defend136" type="defendantName">
                  William 
                  Mackaway 
               <interp inst="t17670909-2-defend136" type="surname" value="Mackaway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-defend136" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-defend136" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-defend136" type="age" value="eighteen"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , were indicted for <rs id="t17670909-2-off12" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-off12" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-off12" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               breaking into the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17670909-2-victim138" type="victimName">
                           Joseph 
                           Sunshine 
                        <interp inst="t17670909-2-victim138" type="surname" value="Sunshine"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670909-2-victim138" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670909-2-victim138" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-2-off12 t17670909-2-victim138"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , on the <rs id="t17670909-2-cd13" type="crimeDate">8th of July</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-2-off12 t17670909-2-cd13"></join>, about the hour of one in the night, and stealing twenty-six linen shirts, four napkins, nine aprons, four sheets, a table-cloth, four stocks, and a handkerchief, the property of the said Joseph, in his dwelling house
            </rs>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-2-person139">
                  Joseph 
                  Sunshine 
               <interp inst="t17670909-2-person139" type="surname" value="Sunshine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-person139" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-person139" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17670909-2-crimeloc14">Whitechapel</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17670909-2-crimeloc14" type="placeName" value="Whitechapel"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17670909-2-crimeloc14" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-2-off12 t17670909-2-crimeloc14"></join>, am a <rs id="t17670909-2-viclabel15" type="occupation">sugar-baker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-2-victim138 t17670909-2-viclabel15"></join>, and work out, so was not at home when my house was broke open.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-2-person140">
                  Mary 
                  Sunshine 
               <interp inst="t17670909-2-person140" type="surname" value="Sunshine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-person140" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-person140" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the prosecutor, I take in washing, I left my wash-house safe, which is under-ground; this was July the 9th in the morning, between one and two when I went to bed: it was a very slight fastening to the window-shutter, there is no glass, only a shutter and a bar; my garden is even with the window, the wash-house is under my dwelling-house, we have two ways to go into it, out of the yard and out of the house; I left fifty shirts and shifts, and a great quantity of large linen in it; I got up about seven,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176709090020"></xptr> and went into the wash house, the back-door was fast as I left it, the window shutter was taken off, there was no hinges to it, we put it up and take it down; the bar was taken away, we did not find that for three days after, we found it at the bottom of the garden; I found twenty shirts and shifts lost; I missed thirty shirts and eight aprons, two laced caps, a child's jam, four damask napkins, four sheets, three or four stocks, two or three table-cloths, and one handkerchief; I had just washed them. I had them cried about Whitechapel parish; there came a person and told me she had heard Patt Robinson (a woman) was seen with a bundle of things in Prescot-street; I went with Mr. Brebrook to her, after that we had some reason to suspect the prisoners; that day fortnight Gibson and Tinsey were taken, they said they had sold them to a Jew before the Justices, the other was taken a week after the evidence; a Jew came and surrendered, we went and searched his apartment, but found nothing; nine days after that Mackaway was taken, he said he knew nothing of the breaking my place, but the other two met him with the bundle by Whitechapel-bars; he went with them, and Tinsey delivered this bundle to a girl, and then brought him to my place, and brought another bundle away; upon this he, the evidence, brought nine shirts, two pair of stockings, a towel, a white apron, and four sheets, they were part of the goods taken out of my wash-house; I met with a shirt also that was sold (as I was informed) for a shilling; I never recovered any more of my things.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-2-person141">
                  Abraham 
                  Teracona 
               <interp inst="t17670909-2-person141" type="surname" value="Teracona"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-person141" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-person141" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The 9th of July, in the morning, 
               <persName id="t17670909-2-person142">
                  John 
                  Gibson 
               <interp inst="t17670909-2-person142" type="surname" value="Gibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-person142" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-person142" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Mackaway came to my house a little after three o'clock, they threw some soft mud up to the window as a token; they used to come sometimes later and sometimes sooner, I used to buy things of them; I opened the window, 
               <persName id="t17670909-2-person143">
                  John 
                  Gibson 
               <interp inst="t17670909-2-person143" type="surname" value="Gibson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-person143" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-person143" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             took thirteen shirts from round his waist, and a white apron, and threw them in at the cellar window; they were all wet, and were fresh wringed out; Mackaway came up stairs, then he went down with me into my cellar to fetch them up, then I agreed with them, and gave them thirty shillings for them; I asked them where they got them from, they said from Goodman's-fields; I asked if they had broke any place open, they said no; I asked how they came by them, they said Tinsey showed them the place where to get them out of the washer-woman's house; I desired Gibson to go and look for Tinsey, he went and could not find him; he said he knew where to find all the linen. I went with him to Nightingale-lane, he went into a house there, and brought out seven shirts, and delivered them to me; I agreed with him for them, unknown to Mackaway, for fourteen shillings; about nine o'clock the same morning, Tinsey came running up my stairs, and said, where is my share; said Gibson, what can we give you out of fifteen shillings; Mackaway was there at the time; then he said, if you do not give me a share I will go and stag, I understood the word (that is, turn evidence;) Mackaway was going to strike him, they were going to fight, then they gave him a shilling each; I then asked him if he had any thing, he said he had at a house, but was afraid to fetch them; then Gibson said he would go with him, and he borrowed Mackaway's waistcoat to alter his dress; then they went to White-chapel; they brought me two pair of sheets, two pair of stockings, an apron, a towel, which I gave them seven shillings for; I asked him how he got these things; he said he watched the washer-woman from one to almost two o'clock, cross a wall; when he thought she was in bed, he broke her cellar window open; he said Gibson and Mackaway were not with him at the time; he said there were only two lowd women, and two little boys at the time with him: when this information was made against me, I went and surrendered myself, and took one of the little boys, upon which Mackaway was found out; (the goods found, produced, and deposed to.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-2-person144">
                  Anne 
                  Chadey 
               <interp inst="t17670909-2-person144" type="surname" value="Chadey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-person144" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-person144" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mrs. Sunshine washes for me, here are three sheets and one apron of mine (taking them in her hand.)</p>
               <p>Tinsey's defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing of it.</p>
               <p>Gibson's defence.</p>
               <p>I was not at the breaking the house, I am eighteen years of age.</p>
               <p>Mackaway's defence.</p>
               <p>I am eighteen years of age, I was coming along Whitechapel, they asked me to go along with them, I would not for a long while, and at last I did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-2-person145">
                  Michael 
                  Carey 
               <interp inst="t17670909-2-person145" type="surname" value="Carey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-person145" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-person145" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know Mackaway, I never heard any harm of him before this time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-2-person146">
                  Henry 
                  Bolter 
               <interp inst="t17670909-2-person146" type="surname" value="Bolter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-person146" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-person146" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him from a child, I never heard any ill of him before this affair.</p>
               <p>Tinsey <rs id="t17670909-2-verdict16" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-verdict16" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17670909-2-punish17" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-punish17" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-2-defend133 t17670909-2-punish17"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Gibson and Mackaway <rs id="t17670909-2-verdict18" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-verdict18" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-verdict18" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               Guilty of felony only
            </rs>. <rs id="t17670909-2-punish19" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670909-2-punish19" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-2-defend135 t17670909-2-punish19"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-2-defend136 t17670909-2-punish19"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
