<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17620714-9">
               <interp inst="t17620714-9" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620714-9" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620714-9" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17620714"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620714-9" type="date" value="17620714"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620714-9-off39-c61" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620714-9-defend77 t17620714-9-off39 t17620714-9-verdict41"></join>
         
               <p>184. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17620714-9-defend77" type="defendantName">
                     Catherine 
                     Bailey 
                  <interp inst="t17620714-9-defend77" type="surname" value="Bailey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-9-defend77" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-9-defend77" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17620714-9-deflabel38" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620714-9-defend77 t17620714-9-deflabel38"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17620714-9-off39" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620714-9-off39" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-9-off39" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing three linen shirts, value six shillings, one muslin neckcloth, value sixpence, two pair of linen sleeves, value one shilling, three linen napkins, value eighteen pence, two laced caps, value two shillings, one silk handkerchief, value one shilling, one laced handkerchief, value two shillings,
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17620714-9-victim79" type="victimName">
                     Henry 
                     Cooley 
                  <interp inst="t17620714-9-victim79" type="surname" value="Cooley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-9-victim79" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-9-victim79" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620714-9-off39 t17620714-9-victim79"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17620714-9-cd40" type="crimeDate">December 21st</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620714-9-off39 t17620714-9-cd40"></join> + .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620714-9-person80">
                  Ann 
                  Cooley 
               <interp inst="t17620714-9-person80" type="surname" value="Cooley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-9-person80" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-9-person80" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to 
               <persName id="t17620714-9-person81">
                  Henry 
                  Cooley 
               <interp inst="t17620714-9-person81" type="surname" value="Cooley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-9-person81" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-9-person81" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I missed some of my goods on the 20th of December last: I missed two shirts (and caps I lost before), and two muslin neckloius, three napkins, two laced caps, a silk handkerchief, and a laced handkerchief. I gave her warning when I missed some money out of a little box. She made an excuse to go out for water. I told her there was none wanted. She ran away, and told me, I should catch her if I had a lighter pair of heels than her. On the 22d I took her. I charged her with two shirts and laced caps: I could not rightly tell then what I had lost. She told me where they were.</p>
               <p>Robert Hall. I am a pawnbroker; the prisoner at the bar brought a shirt about this time twelve months; she said it was her mistress's property, and that she sent her. I did not know who her mistress was at that time. She told me her mistress's name was Cooley. I have known the prisoner seven years. There were two neckcloths, and two pair of sleeves brought I believe in August.</p>
               <p>A Witness. I am a widow. I went into Mrs. Cooley's for a pint of beer; and the maid and she had had words about the linen. She was going for a pail of water. Her mistress said, there was no need of any. She run out of the door; and Mrs. Cooley cried stop thief. She said, Mrs. Cooley should have a lighter pair of heels than her if she catched her.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>My mistress had set me to clean the house, and used me very ill. I took up the pail to fetch some water. I said, she should not serve me as she did the day before. I said she had better pay me my wages. I was not six yards from the house the whole time. I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176207140005"></xptr> pawned the goods for her, and she redeemed them at her own expence.</p>
               <p>Q. to Cooley. Did you ever send her with any thing to pawn?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620714-9-person82">
                  Ann 
                  Cooley 
               <interp inst="t17620714-9-person82" type="surname" value="Cooley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-9-person82" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-9-person82" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I sent her with one handkerchief, cap, and apron, two years ago, and nothing else.</p>
               <p>Mr. Wilson. I am the constable that took up the prisoner. The fir st time I took her up, they made it up: she was charged at that time with two caps and some shirts: she stood it out that Mrs. Cooley gave her the things to pawn for herself, and on that they made it up; and Mrs. Cooley fetched them out of pawn at her own expence; she lived servant with her at the time, and they turned her away; and finding more things missing, I had a warrant against her; I believe that was two months afterwards. She insisted that her mistress sent her with the things to pawn the first time; but the second time she did not say much about it. I believe she said her mistress sent her with these to pawn; and she said the reason that she did not mention these before was, that in her fright she had forgot them. She did not say she had taken them but by her mistress's consent. She told me there was due forty shillings for wages: she did not mention it before Mrs. Cooley.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17620714-9-verdict41" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620714-9-verdict41" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
