<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17661022-28">
               <interp inst="t17661022-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661022-28" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661022-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17661022"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661022-28" type="date" value="17661022"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17661022-28-off139-c224" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661022-28-defend284 t17661022-28-off139 t17661022-28-verdict143"></join>
         
               <p>504. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17661022-28-defend284" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Walton 
                  <interp inst="t17661022-28-defend284" type="surname" value="Walton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-defend284" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-defend284" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17661022-28-off139" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-off139" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-off139" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing two yards and a half of gauze, value 8 s. a gauze handkerchief, value 2 s. and 16 ounces of thread, value 2 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17661022-28-victim286" type="victimName">
                     Edward 
                     Hewit 
                  <interp inst="t17661022-28-victim286" type="surname" value="Hewit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-victim286" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-victim286" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17661022-28-victim288" type="victimName">
                     Benjamin 
                     Brockhurst 
                  <interp inst="t17661022-28-victim288" type="surname" value="Brockhurst"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-victim288" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-victim288" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17661022-28-cd140" type="crimeDate">Oct. 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661022-28-off139 t17661022-28-cd140"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661022-28-person289">
                  Benj 
                  Brockhurst 
               <interp inst="t17661022-28-person289" type="surname" value="Brockhurst"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-person289" type="given" value="Benj"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-person289" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17661022-28-person290">
                  Edward 
                  Hewit 
               <interp inst="t17661022-28-person290" type="surname" value="Hewit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-person290" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-person290" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and I are partners, we keep a warehouse in <placeName id="t17661022-28-crimeloc141">Newgate-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17661022-28-crimeloc141" type="placeName" value="Newgate-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17661022-28-crimeloc141" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661022-28-off139 t17661022-28-crimeloc141"></join>. and <rs id="t17661022-28-viclabel142" type="occupation">deal in silk and linen thread</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661022-28-victim286 t17661022-28-viclabel142"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661022-28-victim288 t17661022-28-viclabel142"></join>; we parted with a servant who we thought defrauded us, and took the prisoner in his place, and since we have had suspicion of him; on the 15th of October he was employed in tying up coloured thread, as we had a great deal in the warehouse scattered about; on that day I sent him out some business, and bid him call upon customers in his way, to know if they had any particular orders for gauze; I was informed he had received orders; he did not live in the house; when he came the next morning, I desired him to take out these gauzes that had been ordered; after that was done I sent him out, that I might have an opportunity of taking the exact quantity he had put up; I counted them twice over, and set the contents of them down; I staid to see the parcel, till he came and took it into his custody; he went out with it, and returned in the evening; after he was gone, 
               <persName id="t17661022-28-person291">
                  William 
                  Stocker 
               <interp inst="t17661022-28-person291" type="surname" value="Stocker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-person291" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-person291" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and I counted the gauzes; it contained 24 yards and a half, and more, and when he came home there was only 23 yards, so that the quantity of an apron was taken off; it was ell wide, I marked it, and have had it in my custody ever since; then I applied to Mr. Alderman Alsop for a warrant to take up the prisoner, and search his house; on the Saturday night I paid him his wages, and took a receipt in full; as he said he should not go to his new master till the latter end of the week, I said I should be glad if he would come to me on the Monday morning; on the Monday morning I took him into the dining-room with my servant Stocker, and shewed him the two warrants I had got; he said he did not know what I meant; I said to him, I will make you no promises at all, before I ask you any thing, but you must think in letting me know what was become of my property, can be the only means of saving your life; that is, I meant not to indict him capitally; we have strictly forbid our servants from leaving our property in the hands of any person without our knowledge and permission; I shewed him the piece of gauze, and asked him what was become of that which was cut off; he said, I have the money for you, if you will take it; I said, that was a vain excuse, we sell to no body less than six yards; he then fell on his knees, and said he hoped I would forgive him, he would confess all; he said he had sold this to Mrs. 
               <persName id="t17661022-28-person292">
                  Mary 
                  Judd 
               <interp inst="t17661022-28-person292" type="surname" value="Judd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-person292" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-person292" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             for five shilling and six-pence, and he had about a month before sold her some for five shillings, and a handkerchief for two shillings and four-pence, and applied the money to his own use; then he owned he had a pound of coloured thread at home, which he took to sell to a person near Aldersgate-street, and a gauze handkerchief, which he took to sell to a gentlewoman's servant; I put him in custody of an officer, and went to his house, and found the thread and handkerchief; I having a great opinion of his wife, she saying there was nothing else, I did not search any farther; I went then to Mrs. 
               <persName id="t17661022-28-person293">
                  Mary 
                  Judd 
               <interp inst="t17661022-28-person293" type="surname" value="Judd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-person293" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-person293" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and she delivered the piece of gauze, which she had bought of him, to me; she could not find the handkerchief, but said she had bought one of him, and likewise a piece of gauze before; the prisoner confessed the same to Mr. Alderman Alsop, as he had done to me before; he came to be our servant in February 1764.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661022-28-person294">
                  William 
                  Stocker 
               <interp inst="t17661022-28-person294" type="surname" value="Stocker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-person294" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-person294" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirmed the evidence given by the prosecutor; and 
               <persName id="t17661022-28-person295">
                  Mary 
                  Judd 
               <interp inst="t17661022-28-person295" type="surname" value="Judd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-person295" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-person295" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             that of buying the separate articles of the prisoner mentioned by the prosecutor; she likewise said the prisoner told her he was going third partner with his masters. The piece which she bought produced, and compared with the piece it was cut from, and they agreed exactly, it being cut in the middle of a flowered stripe.</p>
               <p>Mr. Turner. About a year ago I bought an apron and handkerchief of the prisoner, and paid he full value for them, but did not know who employed him till this affair.</p>
               <p>Frederic Delaney. The prisoner came to my shop about a month ago, and shewed me a piece of gauze, and said here is a pretty present my master has made me; I said it is a very smart thing, what is the value of it; he said about a crown, and I gave him a crown for it; I did not know who was his master at that time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661022-28-person296">
                  Charles 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17661022-28-person296" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-person296" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-person296" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the officer, produced the thread and handkerchief, which he said he found in a drawer in the prisoner's apartment.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I said to Mrs. Judd, I am going to leave the gentlemen who I live with now, and am going to some other gentleman; and I was to be represented<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176610220019"></xptr> in the papers as copartner, my name not at full length, that was to get custom; I made no confession; I look upon it, as I am going away, they are suspicious I am going to get their customers away.</p>
               <p>He called Mr. Mullings a haberdasher, with whom he had lived servant near twelve months; Mr. M'Carty, a baker; 
               <persName id="t17661022-28-person297">
                  Joshua 
                  Beet 
               <interp inst="t17661022-28-person297" type="surname" value="Beet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-person297" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-person297" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a publican; Mr. Williams, a pattern drawer; 
               <persName id="t17661022-28-person298">
                  John 
                  Bond 
               <interp inst="t17661022-28-person298" type="surname" value="Bond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-person298" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-person298" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17661022-28-person299">
                  John 
                  Bromley 
               <interp inst="t17661022-28-person299" type="surname" value="Bromley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-person299" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-person299" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17661022-28-person300">
                  Joseph 
                  Rhodes 
               <interp inst="t17661022-28-person300" type="surname" value="Rhodes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-person300" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-person300" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17661022-28-person301">
                  Henry 
                  Rhodes 
               <interp inst="t17661022-28-person301" type="surname" value="Rhodes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-person301" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-person301" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who gave him a good character.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17661022-28-verdict143" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-verdict143" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17661022-28-punish144" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-punish144" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-28-punish144" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661022-28-defend284 t17661022-28-punish144"></join>
               B
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
