<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17641212-10">
               <interp inst="t17641212-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641212-10" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641212-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17641212"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641212-10" type="date" value="17641212"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17641212-10-off46-c82" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-10-defend105 t17641212-10-off46 t17641212-10-verdict50"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176412120006"></xptr>11. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17641212-10-defend105" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Miller 
                  <interp inst="t17641212-10-defend105" type="surname" value="Miller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-10-defend105" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-10-defend105" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17641212-10-off46" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17641212-10-off46" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-10-off46" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing two gold rings, with certain stones set therein, value 20 s.
            </rs> the Property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17641212-10-victim107" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Harding 
                  <interp inst="t17641212-10-victim107" type="surname" value="Harding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-10-victim107" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-10-victim107" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-10-off46 t17641212-10-victim107"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17641212-10-cd47" type="crimeDate">October 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-10-off46 t17641212-10-cd47"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641212-10-person108">
                  Ann 
                  Harding 
               <interp inst="t17641212-10-person108" type="surname" value="Harding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-10-person108" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-10-person108" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the prosecutor; he is a <rs id="t17641212-10-viclabel48" type="occupation">goldsmith</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-10-victim107 t17641212-10-viclabel48"></join>; we live in <placeName id="t17641212-10-crimeloc49">the Minories</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17641212-10-crimeloc49" type="placeName" value="the Minories"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17641212-10-crimeloc49" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-10-off46 t17641212-10-crimeloc49"></join>. On the 18th of October, in the evening, the prisoner came and asked to look at a gold ring; I shewed him half a dozen; he draw'd his hand over them, and said none of them would do, and he should not steal above an hundred pounds, if I would show him the glass: I show'd him the glass; he put his hand down upon the rings, and said a guinea was too much; (I asked him that for one) he kept his hands over them for some time; then he said, Your servant, madam, I'll come to-morrow; and was turning to go. I said, Harkee, Sir, and took him by his two hands, and took a ring out of each hand; they seemed as if they stuck there with something; my daughter got hold of him also; he got away and left his cane. After my husband came home, my daughter went up the Minories, and he was taken, I believe in less than a quarter of an hour.</p>
               <p>The rings produced in court, and deposed to by prosecutor and wife.</p>
               <p>Elizabeth, the daughter, confirmed her testimony.</p>
               <p>Mr. Harding. On the 18th of October, I was one of the grand jury; we had a dinner in the Minories; my daughter came and told me they had detected a thief; I ran home; my wife told me the man had left his cane, and ran cross the way; my daughter said she knew him; we went up the Minories, and about forty-doors from my house, we found him in the passage to the Three Kings: I took him by the collar, and asked him how he durst go into my shop to steal rings? he said he never was in my shop, and knew nothing of the matter: there was a sheriff's officer, who is a constable; I gave him charge of him; we searched him, and found but one shilling, fivepence halfpenny, and two farthings upon him: he told me he lived in Stanhope-street, Clare-market.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I had been at Horn-fair, and coming back up the Minories, I went into the gentlewoman's shop, and asked to see a ring of about 12 s. I took a ring, and put it on my finger, and asked the price; she said, a guinea: I had then one in my hand; I said I wanted one at half a guinea; she snatched them from me, and said I came to rob her; my cane was lying on the compter; she seized that, said she, you have no money in your pocket; I took and threw a guinea on the compter; she ran between me and the compter, and in my flurry, I lost my guinea: I went away, and returned again for my cane; she would not let me have it; she said to the girl, go and call your father, he is at the Three Kings. I had drank a little; I went and asked for the Three Kings, and asked for a gentleman that keeps a Silver-smith's shop; they told me he was gone home, they having taken a thief in his shop: I said, I am that person that was in his shop: I staid till he came there; he seiz'd me by the collar, and said, I'll mell you! I said, hear what I have to say: he demanded where I liv'd? I said, in White-Horse-Yard, Catherine-street: they asked me to drink a glass of wine; I sat down: then Mrs. Harding came, and said, Say you took them out of a joke: no, said I, I shall not acknowledge myself a thief. After that, they told me to go about my business, but I would not go without my cane.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Harding. He never show'd any money to me, and he had not the ring on his finger; he did come back for his cane, but I would not let him have it; and he was gone again before my husband came.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17641212-10-verdict50" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17641212-10-verdict50" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
