<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680518-29">
               <interp inst="t17680518-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680518-29" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680518-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680518"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680518-29" type="date" value="17680518"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680518-29-off152-c270" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680518-29-defend337 t17680518-29-off152 t17680518-29-verdict156"></join>
         
               <p>373. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17680518-29-defend337" type="defendantName">
                     Anne 
                     Thomas 
                  <interp inst="t17680518-29-defend337" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-29-defend337" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-29-defend337" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17680518-29-deflabel151" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680518-29-defend337 t17680518-29-deflabel151"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17680518-29-off152" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680518-29-off152" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-29-off152" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing nine guineas, one half guinea, one quarter guinea, one 36 s. piece, and one four guinea piece of gold
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17680518-29-victim339" type="victimName">
                     Archibald 
                     Innis 
                  <interp inst="t17680518-29-victim339" type="surname" value="Innis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-29-victim339" type="given" value="Archibald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-29-victim339" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680518-29-off152 t17680518-29-victim339"></join>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17680518-29-cd153" type="crimeDate">April 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680518-29-off152 t17680518-29-cd153"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680518-29-person340">
                  Archibald 
                  Innis 
               <interp inst="t17680518-29-person340" type="surname" value="Innis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-29-person340" type="given" value="Archibald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-29-person340" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Queen-street, near Well-court, at the house of 
               <persName id="t17680518-29-person341">
                  Alexander 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17680518-29-person341" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-29-person341" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-29-person341" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and <rs id="t17680518-29-viclabel154" type="occupation">deal in cloth, stockings, threads</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680518-29-victim339 t17680518-29-viclabel154"></join>, and the like; about eleven at night last Friday, the prisoner came up to me as I was coming into <placeName id="t17680518-29-crimeloc155">Half-moon-passage</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17680518-29-crimeloc155" type="placeName" value="Half-moon-passage"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17680518-29-crimeloc155" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680518-29-off152 t17680518-29-crimeloc155"></join>; she asked me for a shilling; I told her I had none for her; she clapped her hand upon my pocket, and said, you have got money; I said, I have got none for you; before I knew what I was about, she pulled all my pocket out with her hand, and tore my breeches; I heard my money drop down, there were several guineas; I called the watchman, Mr. Jones came to my assistance first, I desired him to stay with his lanthorn; I picked up one guinea at my foot, I charged him to take hold of the prisoner; he did, and took her to the watch-house; she was searched, but no money found upon her: a little after a boy brought me two guineas, and said he found them at the place where he saw us; when the prisoner came up to me first there was another girl with her, the other girl did not lay hold of me; I never saw the prisoner in my life before, I know the prisoner took my money from me, what she did with it I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her take it?</p>
               <p>Innis. She tore all my pocket, and I lost my money by that; it was by her means that I lost it.</p>
               <p>Court. It does not follow from that that she took it; there was another woman with her, did you observe either of the two women stoop to pick the money up?</p>
               <p>Innis. Not that I saw, I had hold of the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. What money had you in your pocket?</p>
               <p>Innis. I had sixteen guineas and a half, a 36 s. piece, a 5 s. 3 d. and a 4 s. 6 d. I only saved four guineas in my pocket, and one I picked up, and two were brought me.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176805180023"></xptr>Court. If had got your money, you did not let her go out if your custody.</p>
               <p>Innis. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you let the other woman go without searching her?</p>
               <p>Innis. The watchman searched her, but found nothing at all upon her?</p>
               <p>Q. How near was the other woman to the prisoner at the time you lost your money?</p>
               <p>Innis. She was close by her.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any body else near you?</p>
               <p>Innis. No, nobody was when they stopped me first.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you search the ground carefully?</p>
               <p>Innis. The two boys went back to search, but I did not.</p>
               <p>Court. Perhaps all your money would have been found if you had searched there.</p>
               <p>Innis. I was a great deal surprized, and thought they had had the money?</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever had reason since to believe they had your money?</p>
               <p>Innis. No, this woman at the bar was the occasion of my losing my money.</p>
               <p>Mr. Bland. I was coming from Bishopsgate-street at eleven o'clock that night, I was just entering into Leadenhall-market, that part that is the leather market; a gentleman who lodges with me was with me; there were a few people gathered together, curiosity prompted me to go and see what was the matter; there were two women in custody of the constable; I went with them to the watch-house, the young man showed me his breeches, and said he had been robbed of his money; there was charge given of the woman at the bar, and the other; the prisoner did not give any account of herself, she gave charge for charge; they were searched, but no money found; afterwards there was some money brought in, but I know nothing about that; I was very much surprized to find myself bound over on so strange an affair as this, because I knew I was like a chip in porridge, doing neither good nor harm.</p>
               <p>The constable gave an account of his searching the prisoner and other woman, but found no money upon neither.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17680518-29-verdict156" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680518-29-verdict156" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
