<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670115-26">
               <interp inst="t17670115-26" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670115-26" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670115-26" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670115"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670115-26" type="date" value="17670115"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670115-26-off151-c234" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670115-26-defend282 t17670115-26-off151 t17670115-26-verdict154"></join>
         
               <p>114. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17670115-26-defend282" type="defendantName">
                     Timothy 
                     Iredale 
                  <interp inst="t17670115-26-defend282" type="surname" value="Iredale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-26-defend282" type="given" value="Timothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-26-defend282" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for that <rs id="t17670115-26-off151" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670115-26-off151" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-26-off151" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he, on the King's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17670115-26-victim284" type="victimName">
                           George Augustus 
                           Elliot 
                        <interp inst="t17670115-26-victim284" type="surname" value="Elliot"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670115-26-victim284" type="given" value="George Augustus"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670115-26-victim284" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670115-26-off151 t17670115-26-victim284"></join>
                     </persName>
                     
                  , <rs id="t17670115-26-viclabel152" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670115-26-victim284 t17670115-26-viclabel152"></join>; did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and violently taking from his person 29 guineas his property, and against his will
            </rs>, <rs id="t17670115-26-cd153" type="crimeDate">Sept. 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670115-26-off151 t17670115-26-cd153"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670115-26-person285">
                  George Augustus 
                  Elliot 
               <interp inst="t17670115-26-person285" type="surname" value="Elliot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-26-person285" type="given" value="George Augustus"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-26-person285" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; On the first of September last, I was returning to my house in the parish of Ealing; my wife, daughter, and her maid were in the coach; we had four horses and two postilions, and a servant behind the coach; just at dusk, about a quarter before eight, turning off from the high road, beyond the six miles stone, a person passed me on horseback, whom I apprehend to be the prisoner, but do not swear it; he was on a very brisk trot, and looked into the coach; the coach was going pretty fast; when we got about 300 yards further, I found my coach stop suddenly; Mrs. Elliot looked out and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176701150033"></xptr> saw a man present a pistol to the postilion; she fell back, and had not strength to speak; that person came up, and put his pistol across into the coach to me, and said, your money, your money; I said, you shall have mine immediately, don't make a noise; I took my purse out and gave it him; in it was 29 guineas, or 29 guineas and a half; after that, he presented his pistol to the child's maid, who was sitting by her; she gave him some few shillings; he took it, and said, this is not all; you are hiding your money; upon which, he took his pistol out of the coach, and made a great shew of cocking it, and put it close to the maid's breast again. I then told him, you must know women carry very little money in their pockets; he then presented his pistol to the breast of my daughter; I do not know what he said; I said to him, you ought to be ashamed, don't you see that is a child; upon which, he paused a little, and went off. I looked stedfast in his face during the whole time. All the features, that I had in my mind do all resemble and answer the description that I gave the day after to Sir 
               <persName id="t17670115-26-person286">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17670115-26-person286" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-26-person286" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-26-person286" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; the horse was either black or brown, with a rattish tail; he sat very well upon his horse, made me take notice of him; the prisoner answers to the description I gave; I chiresly observed he had a largish month, and a snub nose; and the pistol found, upon him answered to the pistol that was put into the coach.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670115-26-person287">
                  John 
                  Turner 
               <interp inst="t17670115-26-person287" type="surname" value="Turner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-26-person287" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-26-person287" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was the wheel-postilion that drove the General; we had just turned out of the high-road; the prisoner rode by us; he looked into the coach; we were then upon a little common; the prisoner rode up into a lane, and then came back to us, and bid us stop; one slap of his hat was down; I did not stop directly; then he pulled a pistol out of his side pocket, and said, he would blow my brains out if I did not stop. I stopped; he rode up to the side of the coach, and said, your money, Sir, your money. The general said he should have it; he gave him his purse; after that, the prisoner asked the housekeeper for her money; she gave him some; I looked at him all the time; his side was towards me; I was on the near side, and he on the off side, so had a full view of him. Last sessions I was in Newgate; there were three or four men brought down with him; I fixed upon him as soon as I saw him; I am certain he is the man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670115-26-person288">
                  John 
                  Trueman 
               <interp inst="t17670115-26-person288" type="surname" value="Trueman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-26-person288" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-26-person288" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was one of the fore-postilions that drove the general on the first of September, when the prisoner rode back; after he had past us, he held his singer up, and bid me stop; when he was about 15 or 20 yards from me, his hat was stapped before, but I could see his face; we did not stop directly; he pulled a pistol out, and said, if I did not stop directly, he would blow my brains out; then he went up to the coach; I saw him put the pistol into the coach.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe his face?</p>
               <p>Trueman. I did, and really believe the prisoner is the man, but do not positively swear to him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670115-26-person289">
                  William 
                  Milbourn 
               <interp inst="t17670115-26-person289" type="surname" value="Milbourn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-26-person289" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-26-person289" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17670115-26-person290">
                  Thomas 
                  Andrews 
               <interp inst="t17670115-26-person290" type="surname" value="Andrews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-26-person290" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-26-person290" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , two of the patrole, deposed they took the prisoner in custody, on suspicion of a highway robbery, with a brace of pistols upon him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670115-26-person291">
                  John 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17670115-26-person291" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-26-person291" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-26-person291" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the constable that had him in charge after the patrole took him, I had also his pistols, but have left them at Highgate.</p>
               <p>The prisoner said nothing in his defence.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17670115-26-verdict154" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670115-26-verdict154" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17670115-26-punish155" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670115-26-punish155" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670115-26-defend282 t17670115-26-punish155"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>There were four more indictments against him for highway robberies.</p>
            </div1>
