<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17630706-66">
               <interp inst="t17630706-66" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630706-66" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630706-66" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17630706"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630706-66" type="date" value="17630706"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17630706-66-off357-c478" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-66-defend619 t17630706-66-off357 t17630706-66-verdict360"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17630706-66-off357-c479" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-66-defend620 t17630706-66-off357 t17630706-66-verdict360"></join>
         
               <p>350, 351. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17630706-66-defend619" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     West 
                  <interp inst="t17630706-66-defend619" type="surname" value="West"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-66-defend619" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-66-defend619" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , of <placeName id="t17630706-66-defloc353">Monmouth-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17630706-66-defloc353" type="placeName" value="Monmouth-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17630706-66-defloc353" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-66-defend619 t17630706-66-defloc353"></join>, <rs id="t17630706-66-deflabel354" type="occupation">hatter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-66-defend619 t17630706-66-deflabel354"></join>, and 
               <persName id="t17630706-66-defend620" type="defendantName">
                  
                     James 
                     Hinchley 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17630706-66-alias-6" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-66-defend620 t17630706-66-alias-6"></join>Hinchcliffe</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-66-defend620" type="surname" value="Hinchley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-66-defend620" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-66-defend620" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of <placeName id="t17630706-66-defloc355">Tottenham-court-road</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17630706-66-defloc355" type="placeName" value="Tottenham-court-road"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17630706-66-defloc355" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-66-defend620 t17630706-66-defloc355"></join>, <rs id="t17630706-66-deflabel356" type="occupation">watch motion-maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-66-defend620 t17630706-66-deflabel356"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17630706-66-off357" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630706-66-off357" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-66-off357" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one bank note, value 40 l. another 15 l. and another 10 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17630706-66-victim623" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Evans 
                        <interp inst="t17630706-66-victim623" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630706-66-victim623" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630706-66-victim623" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-66-off357 t17630706-66-victim623"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwellinghouse of the said Thomas
            </rs>, <rs id="t17630706-66-cd358" type="crimeDate">March 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-66-off357 t17630706-66-cd358"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630706-66-person624">
                  Thomas 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17630706-66-person624" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-66-person624" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-66-person624" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I did keep <placeName id="t17630706-66-crimeloc359">the George, in the Coal-yard</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17630706-66-crimeloc359" type="placeName" value="the George, in the Coal-yard"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17630706-66-crimeloc359" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-66-off357 t17630706-66-crimeloc359"></join>. On the 1st of March last I was about to move from that house; between 1 and 2 on that day the two prisoners came to my house, and asked me if I could dress them some steaks; I said I was very busy, I could not with conveniency, but if they would partake of the dinner I had on the table (which was roasted beef, not cold) they were very welcome. We lay in that room, and I used to keep my money there, it is a room behind the tap-room; they went into that room, where the cloth was laid, at that time there were the two appraisers, and Mr. Whitebread's clerk, and some other people that has just dined. The two appraisers then left the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176307060033"></xptr> room, and went above stairs to make up their accounts between themselves, and left the two prisoners and Mr. Slater, the clerk, in the room, with nobody else but the girl waiting backwards and forwards. I went up stairs after the two appraisers, where we settled our accounts between myself and the man that came into the house. The man that came into the house paid me for the things in two bank notes, one of 22 l. the other of 30 l. and some cash; I gave my wife the two notes to carry down to lock up among the rest , which she said she accordingly did. On the Sunday morning before this Tuesday I received some bank notes of Mr. 
               <persName id="t17630706-66-person625">
                  James 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17630706-66-person625" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-66-person625" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-66-person625" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , one of 40 l. No. 694, another of 15 l. No. 144, another of 10 l. No. 450, the value of the whole 65 l. I put them together in a box in the cupboard, in the room where these men dined, on the Sunday morning about an hour after I received them; there were six notes in the box after my wife had put in them she carried down. In about an hour and a half after I delivered them to my wife, I wanted 9 l. odd shillings to pay the clerk the discount, I sent my wife for one of these notes, she came back and told me three of these notes were gone; then I directly locked up my house, the two prisoners called out to have every body searched, saying, they had not been out of the house; they were first searched, and nothing found; after the search I sent to Mr. Welch for a constable, (there were some cards found in West's pocket) I took the two prisoners to Mr. Welch, they both denied it, and said they had not been out of the house at all. The person I had these notes of was then upon the circuit; I wrote to him at Winchester, (he is a porter of Sergeant's Inn) he wrote me word the numbers were in town; I advertised them twice without the numbers; when he came to town he delivered the numbers to me, then I advertised them twice more, and hearing nothing of them gave them over. About a fortnight ago John Purcell came with an information to me, and told me that two or three days after I had lost these notes, he was grinding a knife in the street, the two prisoners called to him, and told him they wanted to speak to him; they took him under a gateway, Mr. West pulled out a pocket-book, and took out three bank notes, and gave them to Mr. Hinchcliffe, and he gave them to Purcell, and asked him if he could put them off, as he was acquainted among the Jews in Duke's-place, and they would give him seven or eight guineas for his trouble; he said he refused it, and would have nothing to do with them; they desired he would get them off if it was for less than the value, and they would give him more for his trouble.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630706-66-person626">
                  James 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17630706-66-person626" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-66-person626" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-66-person626" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a porter to Sergeant's Inn. I have the numbers of these bank notes that I paid to the prosecutor, I delivered them to him on a Sunday morning the latter end of February, I kept the numbers by me; they were advertised April 11, in the Daily Advertiser; this advertisement I drawed up for that paper, I put it in ten guineas reward. Lost or mislaid, &amp;c. ( See the Daily Advertiser for February 15.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630706-66-person627">
                  Mary 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17630706-66-person627" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-66-person627" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-66-person627" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the prosecutor. I went up stairs the 1st of March last between 2 and 3 o'clock; I saw my husband receiving money for the goods and good-will, he said, Molly, take these two bank notes and carry them down, and put them away, and bring me up half a guinea to give change. I brought them down by the ends in my hand into the room where the two prisoners were, and unlocked the cupboard door and took out this box, (producing a wash-ball box) and opened it, there were four other bank notes which I took and rolled up all together, and put them into the box, there were then six notes in it; I took out half a guinea, and put the box in the cupboard, then I locked the cupboard, and carried the half guinea up to my husband; the two prisoners were at dinner, and the brewer's clerk sitting by, the prisoners saw me bring the notes and put them up; I came down into the bar directly, and did not go into that room till my husband sent me for a note about an hour and a half afterwards, then he bid me go and fetch a 10 l. bill to pay Mr. Slater. I went into the room, there were then in the room the two appraisers and Mr. Hinchcliffe, the appraisers had not been out of the house to my knowledge. I went to unlock the cupboard door, I put the key in and it would not turn, then I put my two hands to it, it would not turn, I put my hand to the door and snatched the key out, and the door came open; I saw the box lying in the cupboard, then I looked at the lock of the door, and strove to lock it; I took out the box, and locked it, and carried the box to my husband in the tap-room; I opened it, and took out the papers, and in opening the paper I found but three notes; I said, O! Lord, what is become of the notes! there were six here just now, and burst out a crying. Somebody said in the tap-room, shut up the house, and let every body be searched. The door was shut up, the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176307060034"></xptr> two prisoners were searched, and Mr. Slater, I think he had 400 l. about him, I saw a great bag stand in the window, and gold in it, the appraisers also were searched.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630706-66-person628">
                  Samuel 
                  Essex 
               <interp inst="t17630706-66-person628" type="surname" value="Essex"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-66-person628" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-66-person628" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a brewer; on Saturday the 1st of March I was at Mr. Evans's house after the notes were missed. I saw Hinchcliffe come out of the house with a pipe in his mouth as I stood at our brewhouse opposite Mr. Evans's, about three quarters of an hour before the notes were missed; I did not see him return back, he went under the gateway joining, where people frequently go to make water; he came from under the gateway, and went directly out of the coal-yard, I cannot tell where he went to; he flung his pipe down between two sacks of foot, a little distance from the gateway, in the Coal-yard, that goes into Drury-lane, which way he turned I cannot say, I cannot say I saw him go quite out of the Coal-yard, but he went up the Coal-yard that part that goes to Drury-lane.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630706-66-person629">
                  John 
                  Slater 
               <interp inst="t17630706-66-person629" type="surname" value="Slater"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-66-person629" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-66-person629" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was attending at the prosecutor's house on the 1st of March, to settle the account between him going out, and a man coming in; I was to receive between 9 and 10 l. to ballance the account, (I am clerk to Mr. Whitebread the brewer) and had then upwards of 300 l. about me; just as we had dined in the back room, the two prisoners came in, they desired Mr. Evans to get them a steak, he told them he was very busy, and there was some beef left, if they pleased to accept of that they were very welcome; they came and sat down to dinner, the rest of the company were gone all but me; while they were at dinner, Mrs. Evans brought down two bank notes in her hand; and opened a cupboard that opens in the wall, and took out a wash-ball box, which unscrewed, and went to put those two notes in the box, she could not rightly put them in, but she took the other papers out of the box, then folded them up, and put them into the box all together, and screwed the box, and put it in the cupboard, and locked the door, and went up stairs; I seeing the notes brought down, imagined the business was done, upon which I went up stairs to settle the accounts with him, and left the two prisoners in the room, and the maid servant. I said to Mr. Evans, I see you have done, we may as well settle, he told me they had done, then I said if it would be convenient for him, he might go down and settle with me; he came down presently after; the balance due to me was, I believe, between 9 and 10 l. we settled in the fore-room; (that is, Evans, his wife, and I) he ordered his wife to fetch a 10 l. bank-note, she went and fetched the box, she unscrewed it, and took out first a note, I think, of 10 l. the next a 30 l. and the next a 10 l. as soon as she took out the last, she fell into a great surprize, and said she was robbed, Mr. West standing by us. (Hinchcliffe was then in the back room.) West said, fasten the doors, let all the doors be fastened, let every body be searched, he was sure neither Hinchcliffe, nor he, had been out of the house. Accordingly the appraisers were searched, (they had not been in the room all the time) then the two prisoners were searched, and the cooper that attended, and I, were searched; I had not been out of the house, nor had I been in the back room some time; after every body was searched, Mr. Evans insisted upon it, that the two prisoners had the notes, and took them before Justice Welch. The cooper is cooper to Mr. Whitebread, he was out of the room before the two prisoners came in, he went to gauging the beer.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630706-66-person630">
                  Ann 
                  Jewet 
               <interp inst="t17630706-66-person630" type="surname" value="Jewet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-66-person630" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-66-person630" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was servant to Mr. Evans, and eating my dinner at the dresser, Mr. West and Mr. Hinchcliffe were by the fire-side, ( this was the day the notes were lost) Mr. West said to me, where do you wash your dishes? I said, don't you know? I began to gather my dishes up together, (this was after they had dined) Mr. West said, it looks creditable for servants to keep the plates and dishes clean; I gathered them together, and went out to do my dishes, he took the water off the fire, and told me it was boiling hot, and gave it me in my hand, I took it to a little narrow place, a back place, (I went through the tap-room with it) I had taken the dishes all out before: as I was stooping to wash my dishes, West came and opened the little door, which stood a jar before, he opened it a little farther, I thought he wanted to come in, he never spoke to me, nor I to him; then I went out and came round into the tap-room, and went and bolted that door, because the dog was there, as he opened the door, I thought the dog might push out and break the dishes; I never went in afterwards till I had washed my dishes, which I believe was better than half an hour, then I gathered my dishes together and carried them in, and found West and Hinchcliffe in the room where I left them, I stirred the fire, and went out directly, and did not return till the notes were missed and the outcry made.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630706-66-person631">
                  John 
                  Purcell 
               <interp inst="t17630706-66-person631" type="surname" value="Purcell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-66-person631" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-66-person631" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the two prisoners at the bar for years. On the 2d or 3d of March last, it was one of them two days I can swear, that they applied to me to put off three banknotes, they knowing my business lay among the Jews in Duke's-place, and particularly one time<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176307060035"></xptr> of the year, just before the Passover. I am a grinder. I was grinding in Broad St. Giles's the 2d or 3d of March, between 3 and 4 o'clock, they came to me, Hinchcliffe said, you are the man we have been looking for, come here; I said, stop, Mr. Hinchcliffe, while I have done the man's knife, for he is waiting for it; after I had done it, he called me under a gate-way of the George ale-house, St. Giles's, I went there: West said to Hinchcliffe, come under the other gateway, then we went under the second gate-way that was a little farther on. Hinchcliffe said to Mr. West, Lends it. West pulled out his pocketbook and took out three papers, there came out the 6 of the hearts with it, and fell upon the ground; Hinchcliffe said, West, pick up the old gentleman; Hinchcliffe said, he had got three bank-notes, a 40 l. a 15 l. and a 10 l. and if you will get these off in Duke's-place, you shall have 7 guineas; I said, I don't understand any thing about notes; Hinchcliffe said, you shall have 8; I said, I did not understand any thing of the affair of bank-notes, and I would not trouble myself with it; I had them all in my hand, and judged they were not real bank-notes. Hinchcliffe asked me if I could read? I read them; he asked me, why I thought they were not banknotes? I said, I thought bank-notes were better paper, for these were more like gold-beater's-skin than bank-notes, I never had one in my hand before, you might blow it away.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the notes?</p>
               <p>Purcell. I did. Hinchcliffe said, if you will have no hand in it, ask any of your acquaintance in Duke's-place, and they shall be satisfied, and you shall have something for your trouble, and here take down the notes; (he produced a paper) I took these out with my pencil, at Hinchcliffe's own desire, as I always carry paper and a pencil about me to take directions for my work, I wrote this before the two prisoners on the back of the pocket-book. (The paper was read: 694 - 40 l. 144 - 15 l. 450 - 10 l. bank-notes.)</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take notice who they were payable to?</p>
               <p>Purcell. No, I did not take particular notice of that.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Who are you?</p>
               <p>Purcell. I am a grinder, and go about the streets with a barrow.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you before had any transactions with the prisoners about money?</p>
               <p>Purcell. About ten months ago Hinchcliffe and I were together, there was a hundred pound not lost, and 10 l. reward offered, I said, without this comes into honest people's hands, they will never have it, if they are acquainted with any of the Jews they will change it for 10 l. less than the value. I thought they had got these notes by card-playing, I did not apprehend they had stole them.</p>
               <p>Q. If you continued positive you would have nothing to do with the notes, what could induce these men to give you the numbers and value of the notes?</p>
               <p>Purcell. The reason was, Mr. Hinchcliffe bid me speak to some of my acquaintance of the Jews, and said I should have something for myself.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take them down against your will?</p>
               <p>Purcell. I rather did against my will.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know Evans?</p>
               <p>Purcell. No.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you first read the advertisement?</p>
               <p>Purcell. I never did till since I made the information.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you make your information?</p>
               <p>Purcell. That was about last Tuesday was a week.</p>
               <p>Q. What led you to make that information?</p>
               <p>Purcell. The gentlemen alledge it was through spite, but I have two witnesses here, if they may be examined, who will prove to the contrary. About six or seven weeks ago Hinchcliffe called me out of the Two Brewers, Mr. Boswell keeps it, there was a soldier drunk who had pulled out three guineas and a half, or four guineas, and Hinchcliffe said he would get the woman out of the room if I would touch him; I made this reply, If you have a mind to do any thing of that sort, do it yourself, for I'll have no hand in it. He said, if West was along with me he would not give a halfpenny for what is left in the soldier's pocket. As soon as Hinchcliffe was gone I acquainted the two women of this affair, but one of them heard him herself; this came to the knowledge of Hinchcliffe again; the next time I saw him I said, How do you do Mr. Hinchcliffe? he said, d - n your stagging head. I asked him what he meant by that? he said, go along, and would not drink with me.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he any reason at that time to think you would be a man concerned in cheating or robbing the soldier?</p>
               <p>Purcell. I apprehend it was his ignorance more than any thing else, for he knew I refused him in the notes.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176307060036"></xptr>Q. Have you ever had any quarrel with either of them?</p>
               <p>Purcell. No, never, only Hinchcliffe was angry with me for what he called turning stag.</p>
               <p>Q. Had there been any quarrel between you?</p>
               <p>Purcell. He struck me at the Two Brewers without any occasion, he knocked my hat off twice as I lay with my head on the table; I said, you make yourself more free than welcome; then he came and struck me; West was there, he took hold of my hands, and said I should not sight, and Hinchcliffe struck me on the side of my face and cut my eye. One Sunderland said I was used very ill. Then they put me into the Crown Office; all this was for my speaking about the soldier.</p>
               <p>Q. At that time did you speak a word about the three bank notes?</p>
               <p>Purcell. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you this paper in your pocket at that time?</p>
               <p>Purcell. I had, but I did not know who was the man that lost them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never declare you had a revenge against the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Purcell. No, never in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to the knowledge of the Prosecutor?</p>
               <p>Purcell. One Smith, a chimney-sweeper, and I, were drinking just by the Three Canns, and it came in discourse about the quarrels with Mr. Hinchcliffe; he mentioned a man in the Coalyard had lost three notes; I went there, but the man did not live there then, so I was directed to where he did live.</p>
               <p>West's Defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing at all of the matter, I declare I am innocent of all I am charged with.</p>
               <p>Hinchcliffe's Defence.</p>
               <p>So am I; I never was in the room by myself all the whole time.</p>
               <p>The prisoners called Mr. Turner, 
               <persName id="t17630706-66-person632">
                  George 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17630706-66-person632" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-66-person632" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-66-person632" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17630706-66-person633">
                  Thomas 
                  Grenard 
               <interp inst="t17630706-66-person633" type="surname" value="Grenard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-66-person633" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-66-person633" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Mr. Weston, and others, who severally gave them the character of honest industrious men.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17630706-66-verdict360" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630706-66-verdict360" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
