<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17600910-18">
               <interp inst="t17600910-18" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600910-18" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600910-18" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600910"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600910-18" type="date" value="17600910"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600910-18-off93-c155" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-18-defend201 t17600910-18-off93 t17600910-18-verdict96"></join>
         
               <p>260. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17600910-18-defend201" type="defendantName">
                     George 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17600910-18-defend201" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-18-defend201" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-18-defend201" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17600910-18-off93" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600910-18-off93" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-18-off93" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one cloth surtout coat, value 7 s. one fustian frock, value 18 d. one pair of black<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176009100018"></xptr> cloth breeches, value 3 s.
            </rs> the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17600910-18-victim203" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Ward 
                  <interp inst="t17600910-18-victim203" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-18-victim203" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-18-victim203" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-18-off93 t17600910-18-victim203"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17600910-18-cd94" type="crimeDate">August 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-18-off93 t17600910-18-cd94"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600910-18-person204">
                  John 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17600910-18-person204" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-18-person204" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-18-person204" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17600910-18-viclabel95" type="occupation">victualler</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-18-victim203 t17600910-18-viclabel95"></join>; I lost the things mentioned in the indictment, but was not at home at the time they were taken.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Ward. I do; I believe he had been at my house about 8 or 9 times before I missed them; he would call for a pennyworth of beer or a dram of gin as he went by; but never staid to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. In what way of life is he?</p>
               <p>Ward. I do not know; when I came home I was told the things were lost, and that the prisoner had been at my house; I lost them on Saturday was sev'nnight, and on the Monday I saw him in Fleet-street; I took him by the collar, and said he must come along with me home; he made some difficulty of it, and asked me what I wanted with him; I told him I would tell him when he got to my house, we had about 300 yards to go; about the midway there was a gateway; he desired I would let him stop to make water, and ran away; I pursued, and catched him again; when I got him home I charged him with taking my things; he said he knew nothing of the matter; I charged a constable with him, and took him to bridewell; then before an alderman, who committed him to Newgate.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever got your things again?</p>
               <p>Ward. No, nor have I seen him since.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600910-18-person205">
                  Mary 
                  Ward 
               <interp inst="t17600910-18-person205" type="surname" value="Ward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-18-person205" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-18-person205" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the prosecutor, the prisoner came into our house, and called for a pennyworth of beer, between 11 and 12 on a forenoon; the maid went down to draw it; in the mean time he asked me for a pen and ink, I went for a pen and ink; he followed me into the parlour, before I went out of the room I turned myself about, and saw the cloaths mentioned lying upon the chest of drawers, in the parlour; they had laid there some time, the man was there then; a woman came for a pint of beer, and while I was gone down to draw it, the man was gone; I said to the maid, has the man given you the penny for the beer, she said no; then I missed the cloaths; then I asked the woman that came for the pint of beer, if she saw the man go out; she said no; if he was gone out, he must go out at the window, for he did not go by her; the great coat belongs to a gentleman that belongs to a society at our house; the other things are my husband's.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. The fustian frock she speaks of is what I have on my back, and the breeches I can produce in half an hour's time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600910-18-person206">
                  Mary 
                  Baymont 
               <interp inst="t17600910-18-person206" type="surname" value="Baymont"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-18-person206" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-18-person206" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the prisoner in the prosecutor's parlour walking to and fro.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the cloaths?</p>

               <p>M. Baymont. No, I did not, to take notice of them; the landlady brought me the pint of beer while I was standing by the parlour door; I did not see the prisoner come by me; there were 2 sash windows to the parlour, and they were both throwed up.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600910-18-person207">
                  Martha 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17600910-18-person207" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-18-person207" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-18-person207" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Lion in the Wood, in Salisbury-court; I was scowering the things in the yard, I went into the house, and there I saw the prisoner ask a coachman if he would buy a hat band; he then had a pair of black breeches; I took him to be an old cloaths man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600910-18-person208">
                  Abraham 
                  Feling 
               <interp inst="t17600910-18-person208" type="surname" value="Feling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-18-person208" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-18-person208" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live near the prosecutor, I was at the Lion in the Wood reading the newspaper, there was Esq; Henson's coachman, then came the prisoner; I saw in his hand a duffel surtout coat; the prosecutor's house is about 40 yards distance from that house; the prisoner had also a bundle under his arm; the prosecutor came in soon after, and said he had just been robbed; it seemed to be a coat that had been much wore, and was of a dark brown.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. What sort of a coat was that you lost?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Much such a one as this witness described.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs. Ward. What time was it you missed the things?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Ward. About 20 minutes before 12 o'clock.</p>
               <p>Felling. According to the account I had from Mr. Ward, the prisoner must come in immediately from his house.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>The frock I had there I have now on.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600910-18-verdict96" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600910-18-verdict96" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
