<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17620421-26">
               <interp inst="t17620421-26" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620421-26" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620421-26" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17620421"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620421-26" type="date" value="17620421"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620421-26-off139-c241" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-26-defend281 t17620421-26-off139 t17620421-26-verdict141"></join>
         
               <p>141. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17620421-26-defend281" type="defendantName">
                  Sarah 
                  Church 
               <interp inst="t17620421-26-defend281" type="surname" value="Church"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-26-defend281" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-26-defend281" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17620421-26-deflabel138" type="occupation">single woman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-26-defend281 t17620421-26-deflabel138"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17620421-26-off139" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620421-26-off139" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-26-off139" type="offenceSubcategory" value="infanticide"></interp>
               the wilful murder of her male child
            </rs>, <rs id="t17620421-26-cd140" type="crimeDate">April the 7th</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-26-off139 t17620421-26-cd140"></join>. She stood likewise charged on the Coroner's Inquest for the said murder. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-26-person282">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Bowman 
               <interp inst="t17620421-26-person282" type="surname" value="Bowman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-26-person282" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-26-person282" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a midwife. The prisoner was servant to Mrs. Keith: I was sent for after the child was born on the 7th of April: The child was taken out of a trunk and laid upon a large chest; it had no marks of violence upon it; it was in a flannel petticoat. I asked, why she did not send for me before? She said, because her mistress had bolted her into her room, and the child was born at two in the morning. Had it been a married woman's case,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176204210020"></xptr> I should not have been surprized to have found the woman and child both dead.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it born alive?</p>
               <p>E. Bowman. I cannot tell that. It might have died before it came into the world. She had made provision for it. [ The baby things produced.]</p>
               <p>Q. Had the child gone its full time?</p>
               <p>E. Bowman. It had.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-26-person283">
                  Mary 
                  Keith 
               <interp inst="t17620421-26-person283" type="surname" value="Keith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-26-person283" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-26-person283" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Chelsea. The prisoner was my servant for three months. I did not believe she was with child; I had too good an opinion of her. I saw some blood in the room, and I suspected she had had a child. I said, I am afraid there is something in the trunk that should not be. I asked for the key. She gave it me. I then went to a neighbour, and told her; she desired I would not open the trunk till the constable came. When he came we opened it; we found the child at the bottom of it; but I did not examine it, it was a boy; but I am no judge whether it had gone its full time or not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you bolt her into her room?</p>
               <p>M. Keith. I did, as she said, she was very sick, because she should not be disturbed.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear her call in the night?</p>
               <p>M. Keith. No. I did not. I charged her with being with child, but she never would own it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-26-person284">
                  Sarah 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17620421-26-person284" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-26-person284" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-26-person284" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Newington in Surry. I was at Chelsea about the time this woman was brought to bed. I came just as the constable came. I saw the child in a petticoat; it was under some linen in a box: it was taken out of the box, and put upon a chest. I saw no marks of violence upon it.</p>
               <p>Q. Had it gone its full time?</p>
               <p>S. Clark. I do not know that; neither do I know whether it was born alive. I think it might have been smothered in the bed at the time of the birth for want of proper help. She said, it was born about two o'clock.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-26-person285">
                  James 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17620421-26-person285" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-26-person285" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-26-person285" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the constable. I was sent for to open the trunk. I found a dead child in a bit of linen rag, wrapped in a piece of an old petticoat; we took it out and laid it on a chest. I asked the prisoner, how she came to put it there? She said, she was brought to bed about two o'clock, and did not come to herself till about five; she found it dead, and so she put it in her trunk, because her mistress had said, if she was brought to bed there, she would throw her and the child into the street. I found some child-bed linen in the trunk. It might be born alive, but might have died for want of help.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-26-person286">
                  Alexander 
                  Reed 
               <interp inst="t17620421-26-person286" type="surname" value="Reed"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-26-person286" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-26-person286" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I opened the body of the child, and took out the lungs, and made the usual experiment, and found they swam, which shews it had breathed: but it might have been smothered without her having done any thing to it; there was no appearance of any mark or outward design to destroy it. I look upon it, it died for want of proper assistance.</p>
               <p>E. Bowman. I parted the navel string, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>The reason I did not own I was with child was, because I intended to go to my aunt's to lie-in: I intended to have gone away the next day. The reason I put the child in the trunk was, because my mistress had said, if I was brought to bed there, she would throw me and the child in the street. When I was delivered and came to myself, I found it dead. I called out, but nobody heard me; I was spent so much at last that I could call no more.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mr. Wilson, with whom she had lived almost five months, gave her the character of a sober, honest, diligent person.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17620421-26-verdict141" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620421-26-verdict141" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
