<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17630114-22">
               <interp inst="t17630114-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630114-22" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630114-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17630114"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630114-22" type="date" value="17630114"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17630114-22-off113-c144" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630114-22-defend183 t17630114-22-off113 t17630114-22-verdict118"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17630114-22-off115-c149" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630114-22-defend189 t17630114-22-off115 t17630114-22-verdict120"></join>
         
               <p>82, 83. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17630114-22-defend183" type="defendantName">
                     Catherine 
                     Haines 
                  <interp inst="t17630114-22-defend183" type="surname" value="Haines"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-defend183" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-defend183" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , was indicted, for that she, <rs id="t17630114-22-off113" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-off113" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-off113" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               together with 
                     <persName id="t17630114-22-person184">
                        Mary 
                        Holmes 
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person184" type="surname" value="Holmes"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630114-22-person184" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630114-22-person184" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , 
                     <persName id="t17630114-22-person185">
                        Sarah 
                        Edwards 
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person185" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630114-22-person185" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630114-22-person185" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , and 
                     <persName id="t17630114-22-person186">
                        Ann 
                        Thompson 
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person186" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630114-22-person186" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630114-22-person186" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , not taken, did steal 2 bank notes of 50 l. each, and another of an hundred pounds, 7 guineas, 2 duckets, and a silk purse, the property of 
                     <persName id="t17630114-22-person187">
                        James 
                        Colhoun 
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person187" type="surname" value="Colhoun"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630114-22-person187" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630114-22-person187" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , privately from his person
            </rs>. And 
               
                  <persName id="t17630114-22-defend189" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Haines 
                  <interp inst="t17630114-22-defend189" type="surname" value="Haines"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-defend189" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-defend189" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            . her <rs id="t17630114-22-deflabel114" type="occupation">husband</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630114-22-defend189 t17630114-22-deflabel114"></join>, for <rs id="t17630114-22-off115" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-off115" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-off115" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving the 3 bank notes, well knowing them to have been stolen
            </rs>, <rs id="t17630114-22-cd116" type="crimeDate">Dec. 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630114-22-off113 t17630114-22-cd116"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630114-22-off115 t17630114-22-cd116"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630114-22-person190">
                  James 
                  Colhoun 
               <interp inst="t17630114-22-person190" type="surname" value="Colhoun"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person190" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person190" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 13th of Dec. I went to Mr. Colcroft's office in the morning, and received of Mr. Roberts 3 bank notes, one of 100 l. and two 50 l. each; I wrapt them together, one of the 50 l. notes was on the outside, which was indorsed on the back with Mr. Colcroft's name, number 149. Returning into the city about midnight, much in liquor, I went with a woman nam'd 
               <persName id="t17630114-22-person191">
                  Mary 
                  Cartwright 
               <interp inst="t17630114-22-person191" type="surname" value="Cartwright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person191" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person191" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , to the house of the prisoners in <placeName id="t17630114-22-crimeloc117">Fleet-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17630114-22-crimeloc117" type="placeName" value="Fleet-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17630114-22-crimeloc117" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630114-22-off113 t17630114-22-crimeloc117"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630114-22-off115 t17630114-22-crimeloc117"></join>; we remained there about an hour, then 4 women came into the room in a riotous manner, the prisoner 
               <persName id="t17630114-22-person192">
                  Catherine 
                  Haines 
               <interp inst="t17630114-22-person192" type="surname" value="Haines"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person192" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person192" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was one of them, 2 of them pushed down the chair in which I was sitting, and the other 2 forced 
               <persName id="t17630114-22-person193">
                  Mary 
                  Cartwright 
               <interp inst="t17630114-22-person193" type="surname" value="Cartwright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person193" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person193" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             out of the room. A few minutes after this, upon hearing a great disturbance and noise in the lane, I went out of the house into the street, I had not been gone far when I missed my purse; I returned to the house, and there I found 
               <persName id="t17630114-22-person194">
                  Mary 
                  Cartwright 
               <interp inst="t17630114-22-person194" type="surname" value="Cartwright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person194" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person194" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the constable, and watchmen at the door, but we could not get admittance, the door was fast; the watchmen got it open some time after, but there was nobody in the house but an old servant woman, she was taken to Wood-street-compter, and about 10 or 11 o'clock in the morning the 2 prisoners were taken by the constable, and carried before Sir 
               <persName id="t17630114-22-person195">
                  Charles 
                  Asgill 
               <interp inst="t17630114-22-person195" type="surname" value="Asgill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person195" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person195" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sitting Alderman at Guildhall, there I charged them with my notes and money, they both of them denied knowing any thing; after that he was sent for from the Compter before Sir Charles, there I heard him confess he received the 3 notes from his wife in a house in Fleet-lane adjoining to his own, they and my purse had been found upon him before I came there, I think he said he received them of her in the night time; I think he added, that he said to his wife and the others, that they must give back these notes. Sir Charles then committed him to Newgate.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember you on any occasion produced your purse while in the prisoners house?</p>
               <p>Colboun. Yes, I did 2 or 3 different times, to pay for some negus, and some money that the servant demanded of me soon after I went into the room.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you much in liquor?</p>
               <p>Colboun. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. When you was first before Sir 
               <persName id="t17630114-22-person196">
                  Charles 
                  Asgill 
               <interp inst="t17630114-22-person196" type="surname" value="Asgill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person196" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person196" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , did you remember the woman at the bar to be one of the women?</p>
               <p>Colhoun. Yes, I did, immediately upon seeing of her I knew her to be one of the 4 women that came into the room.</p>
               <p>Q. When the constable and you went to apprehend her, did not you say upon seeing her, you did not know that woman?</p>
               <p>Colhoun. I told him then she was one of the 4, and bid him apprehend her, and said she was a person concerned in it, and I swore with great certainty that that was one of the women, before Sir 
               <persName id="t17630114-22-person197">
                  Charles 
                  Asgill 
               <interp inst="t17630114-22-person197" type="surname" value="Asgill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person197" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person197" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Who is this 
               <persName id="t17630114-22-person198">
                  Mary 
                  Cartwright 
               <interp inst="t17630114-22-person198" type="surname" value="Cartwright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person198" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person198" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Colhoun. I know nothing of her but being a girl of the town that picked me up.</p>
               <p>Q. Where has she been since?</p>
               <p>Colhoun. She has been under the care of one of the constables, in order to give evidence here.</p>
               <p>Mr. Sabertine. I am a cashier at the bank of England; this note I signed, (holding the 100 l. note in his hand) and the other two 50 l. notes I believe to be Mr. Tomlinson's writing on them.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen Mr. Tomlinson write?</p>
               <p>Sabertine. I have several times.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176301140015"></xptr>Mr. Atkerson. On the 13th of December this draught was brought to me, for the payment of a thousand pounds; I am cashier for Mr. Hoar, I paid 700 l. in bank notes and 300 l. in money, these 3 notes here produced were part of the 20 l.</p>
               <p>Mr. Roberts. I am cashier to Mr. Calcrost. I received 700 l. in bank notes of Mr. Hoar, on the 13th of Dec. I paid 200 l. of these notes, one of 100 and two of 50 l. each, to Mr. Colhoun.</p>
               <p>The bank notes read.</p>
               <p>N 196, B. signed Tomlinson, for 50 l.</p>
               <p>N 224, C. signed Tomlinson, for 50 l.</p>
               <p>N 130. C. for 100 l.</p>
               <p>Q to the prosecutor. Can you undertake to say when you pulled out your purse you put it into your pocket again?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I am very sure I did. I was not intoxicated so far as not to remember that; I remember it exceeding well.</p>
               <p>Q You say you was very fudled when you went into the house, was you not more so after you was there?</p>
               <p>Colhoun. I was a good deal better after I was there than I was when I went in.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain you did not drop your notes out of your pocket?</p>
               <p>Colhoun. I am very certain I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not James Haines say Mary Holmes gave him the notes?</p>
               <p>Colhoun. He once said one of the women gave them to him, and once he said his wife gave them to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he in liquor at that time?</p>
               <p>Colhoun. He pretended to be in liquor, and I believe he was in liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any particular specie of money about you?</p>
               <p>Colhoun. I had 7 or 8 guineas, and 2 German ducats, these were in my purse; I had some silver in my pocket, but I had given that away, and had occasion to change some gold.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630114-22-person199">
                  Mary 
                  Cartwright 
               <interp inst="t17630114-22-person199" type="surname" value="Cartwright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person199" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person199" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 13th of Dec. last, about 12 at night, I met Mr. Colhoun on Ludgate Hill. I asked him to go and give me a glass of wine, he told me he would; I carried him down Fleet-lane, to 
               <persName id="t17630114-22-person200">
                  James 
                  Haines 
               <interp inst="t17630114-22-person200" type="surname" value="Haines"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person200" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person200" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's house in that lane, we went up into their one pair of stairs room, he called for an 18 d. negus, their servant maid brought it up; Mr. Colhoun gave her a 5 s. 3 d. piece to change, she brought it up very honestly: the gentleman and I made an agreement to go to bed, he gave them half a guinea to change, and they took a crown for the bed: they brought up another negus, we had had several negusses I was undressing myself to go to bed, I had my gown and stays off, and Mrs. Haines and her servant maid 
               <persName id="t17630114-22-person201">
                  Sarah 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17630114-22-person201" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person201" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person201" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17630114-22-person202">
                  Mary 
                  Holmes 
               <interp inst="t17630114-22-person202" type="surname" value="Holmes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person202" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person202" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17630114-22-person203">
                  Ann 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17630114-22-person203" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person203" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person203" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; Holmes goes sometimes by the name of Elizabeth, and Brown goes by the name of Ann Thompson, they 4 came up and rushed into the room upon us, Mrs. Haines and her maid pushed me out of the room, and the other 2 were with Mr. Colhoun, they flung him on the bed before I could well get out of the room. I ran with my gown, apron, and stays, on my arm to the watch-house, and got the constable and watchmen with me, but coming along there was murder cried in the lane, they stopt, and went into the house where it was called, then they came out, and we met the prosecutor, he said he had been robbed of his money, and 3 bank notes. for 200 l. 2 of 50 l. each, and 1 of 100 l.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he mention what money he lost?</p>
               <p>M. Cartwright. He said about 8 l. in cash, and 2 ducats. We went to the door and knocked a great while, and no body at all answered, then we went back again to the watch-house, and about half an hour after 3 I insisted upon the door being broke open, they went and broke it open, and there was only an old woman in bed with a child; I insisted upon her going to the compter along with me; and in the morning came Jemmey Haines to me in the compter, he said, if I would be quiet and easy he would give me snacks, and if I would not be quiet and easy he would lagg me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you understand the meaning of that?</p>
               <p>M. Cartwright. That is, as they told me since, to hang me. I said, I did not care, what I had said I would stand to, and what I was about I would go through with; presently after he and his wife were taken and carried to Guildhall, and I was fetched from the compter, there I gave the same account as here.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Mr. Colhoun in liquor when he and you went into the prisoner's house?</p>
               <p>M. Cartwright. He was.</p>
               <p>Q. What quantity of liquor might you have there?</p>
               <p>M. Cartwright. We might have 4 or 5 bowls of liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was you there together?</p>
               <p>M. Cartwright. It might be 3 quarters of an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he drink pretty plentifully?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176301140016"></xptr>M. Cartwright. We drank to one another.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he better or worse in liquor before you went away?</p>

               <p>M. Cartwright. He was in liquor when he went in, and he was pretty much in liquor when I went away.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you seen him take his purse out of his pocket?</p>
               <p>M. Cartwright. He had drawn his purse out twice.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he reel or stagger?</p>
               <p>M. Cartwright. A little in the drunken way.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he very well capable of knowing what he did?</p>
               <p>M. Cartwright. Yes, he was pretty capable of knowing what he was about.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630114-22-person204">
                  William 
                  Dolman 
               <interp inst="t17630114-22-person204" type="surname" value="Dolman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person204" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person204" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was constable at that time, it was my watch night. On the 13th of Dec. when the last evidence came to the watch-house, we were going to Haines's house, we heard murder cried at the next door, or a door or two from his house; we went in there, but we staid there a very little time, then we went to the watch-house, and then to Haines's house, there we found nothing but an old woman and a child: when it was morning, the prosecutor came to my house, about breakfast, and said, will you go down to see after these people? I went with him, we found Mrs. Haines first, and after that the man; we brought them before the sitting Alderman, and one was put into one compter, and the other in the other. Coming back the beadle asked me for something to drink; somebody said, a very foolish constable not to search them; then we went to Sir 
               <persName id="t17630114-22-person205">
                  Charles 
                  Asgill 
               <interp inst="t17630114-22-person205" type="surname" value="Asgill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person205" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person205" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and asked if we should search them; Sir Charles ordered them to be brought down; the man was searched there, and 2 bank notes were taken out of his mouth, and the other out of his hand; (these are them which are produced here) the 2 bloody ones were taken out of his mouth, Sir Charles's servant say them taken out of his mouth as well as we.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prosecutor certain as to the woman at the bar?</p>
               <p>Dolman. He was, and he swore to her as one of the four.</p>
               <p>Q. When you first apprehended her, was he certain then?</p>
               <p>Dolman. He was, and said, she was one of the women that was in the room.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630114-22-person206">
                  Edward 
                  Draper 
               <interp inst="t17630114-22-person206" type="surname" value="Draper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person206" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person206" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am one of the warders of St. Sepulchre's parish, I was assisting the constable. After the prisoners had been examined and committed by Sir 
               <persName id="t17630114-22-person207">
                  Charles 
                  Asgill 
               <interp inst="t17630114-22-person207" type="surname" value="Asgill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person207" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person207" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , we came to the Red Lion in Fleet-lane, Mr. Dolman told me, he had heard Haines had got the notes about him. We went to Sir Charles again, and he gave orders to have him brought to him again. He was brought. Sir Charles asked him several times to deliver the notes up; he called God to witness, he knew nothing of them. Sir Charles ordered us to take him into another room and search him. I had hold of his breeches, and heard something crime in one of his hands: I forced his hand open, and took out that of 50 l. dated the 18th of Oct. I took out half a guinea from his breeches pocket; at that time one of Sir Charles's servants, or one of the company, said, he has got something in his mouth; I seezed him by his jaw, I saw him turn up his tongue in order to swallow something, I clapt my right hand to his throat and my left behind his neck, and squeezed him till two notes came up out of his throat. (He takes them into his hand, they appeared very bloody.)</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q Did not Mrs. Haines promise to find out the people that were in the room?</p>
               <p>Draper. I do not remember hearing any such thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630114-22-person208">
                  Henry 
                  Lions 
               <interp inst="t17630114-22-person208" type="surname" value="Lions"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person208" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person208" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 14th of Dec. at night. Mr. Dolman came to me and said, he had an order from Sir Charles to bring up the man at the bar to have him searched. I went with him. Sir Charles asked him some questions; after that, we were ordered to search him. We went into another room. The beadle said, he had got something in his mouth like a chaw of tobacco; we catched hold of his mouth, and squeezed his throat, and took two notes out of his mouth, and we found a 50 l. bank note in his hand, and I found this red purse in his waistcoat pocket ( producing one).</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. This is my purse, and it was taken out of my pocket with my money in it that night.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630114-22-person209">
                  Catharine 
                  Haines 
               <interp inst="t17630114-22-person209" type="surname" value="Haines"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person209" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person209" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing at all of the matter, no farther than I was drinking with my friends at the Orange-tree in Fleet-lane. My maid came and told me, there were people in the house. I went up stairs, hearing Cartwright scolding and mobbing in the room; I said, I wish you would go about your business, I do not understand why you should make a noise in my house. She went<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176301140017"></xptr> down and out of the house. I never laid my eyes upon the gentleman; I only went to the room door.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630114-22-person210">
                  James 
                  Haines 
               <interp inst="t17630114-22-person210" type="surname" value="Haines"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person210" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person210" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's Defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing about them, only when I came home between 4 and 5 in the morning, I went to pull the bed-cloths off to look for my watch, these papers fell upon the ground, I took them up and put them into my pocket; looking for a chamber-pot, I saw a purse, I took it up and said, here is a purse, but no money in it. When Sir 
               <persName id="t17630114-22-person211">
                  Charles 
                  Asgill 
               <interp inst="t17630114-22-person211" type="surname" value="Asgill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person211" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person211" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said, if you know any thing of these notes, now is your time to save yourself. I put them into my mouth. 
               <persName id="t17630114-22-person212">
                  John 
                  Miller 
               <interp inst="t17630114-22-person212" type="surname" value="Miller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person212" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person212" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was in the room when I found the notes and purse.</p>
               <p>He called 
               <persName id="t17630114-22-person213">
                  Richard 
                  Young 
               <interp inst="t17630114-22-person213" type="surname" value="Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person213" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person213" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630114-22-person214">
                  Richard 
                  Young 
               <interp inst="t17630114-22-person214" type="surname" value="Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person214" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-person214" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the Fleet market. I have known the prisoners 5 or 6 years; they keep a notorious bawdy house, and are people of very bad character.</p>
               <p>Catharine, <rs id="t17630114-22-verdict118" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-verdict118" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-verdict118" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               Guilty of stealing, but not privately from his person
            </rs>. <rs id="t17630114-22-punish119" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-punish119" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630114-22-defend183 t17630114-22-punish119"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>James, <rs id="t17630114-22-verdict120" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-verdict120" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17630114-22-punish121" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630114-22-punish121" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630114-22-defend189 t17630114-22-punish121"></join>
               T. 14
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>There were three people ordered to be prosecuted for offering money to the evidences for them not to appear, &amp;c.</p>
            </div1>
