<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17600709-22">
               <interp inst="t17600709-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600709-22" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600709-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600709"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600709-22" type="date" value="17600709"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600709-22-off118-c217" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600709-22-defend256 t17600709-22-off118 t17600709-22-verdict121"></join>
         
               <p>231 (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17600709-22-defend256" type="defendantName">
                     Susannah 
                     Hanby 
                  <interp inst="t17600709-22-defend256" type="surname" value="Hanby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-22-defend256" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-22-defend256" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17600709-22-deflabel117" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600709-22-defend256 t17600709-22-deflabel117"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17600709-22-off118" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600709-22-off118" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-22-off118" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 2 cloth coats, value<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176007090035"></xptr> 20 s. one black shag waistcoat, value 5 s. and one pair of leather shoes, value 12 d.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17600709-22-victim258" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Kyle 
                  <interp inst="t17600709-22-victim258" type="surname" value="Kyle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-22-victim258" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-22-victim258" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600709-22-off118 t17600709-22-victim258"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17600709-22-cd119" type="crimeDate">June 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600709-22-off118 t17600709-22-cd119"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600709-22-person259">
                  William 
                  Kyle 
               <interp inst="t17600709-22-person259" type="surname" value="Kyle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-22-person259" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-22-person259" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I am a <rs id="t17600709-22-viclabel120" type="occupation">bricklayer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600709-22-victim258 t17600709-22-viclabel120"></join>; I can only say I lost the things mentioned out of my lodgings when I was out I went out into the street after I came home, and met 
               <persName id="t17600709-22-person260">
                  Ann 
                  Hackney 
               <interp inst="t17600709-22-person260" type="surname" value="Hackney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-22-person260" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-22-person260" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; she told me she had been and lock'd the thief in a room, and gave me the key of the room; but when I came to the room, as she directed, there was nobody in it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600709-22-person261">
                  Thomas 
                  Howard 
               <interp inst="t17600709-22-person261" type="surname" value="Howard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-22-person261" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-22-person261" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prosecutor lodges in my house; I was not at home at the time the things were lost; all that I know is, I made the 2 coats, one for the prosecutor, and the other for 
               <persName id="t17600709-22-person262">
                  Isaac 
                  Jackson 
               <interp inst="t17600709-22-person262" type="surname" value="Jackson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-22-person262" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-22-person262" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , which the prosecutor had in his care ( produced in court, depos'd to by prosecutor)</p>
               <p>Q. to Howard. Did you know the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Howard. She was helping a lodger (the day before the things were miss'd) that lives in my house, up one pair of stairs.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600709-22-person263">
                  Ann 
                  Hackney 
               <interp inst="t17600709-22-person263" type="surname" value="Hackney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-22-person263" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-22-person263" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was lately got acquainted with a woman that lived in Black Horse alley, who was landlady to the prisoner at the bar; I wanted a woman to wash for me, so I had the prisoner; she wash'd very clean, she said, and pleaded a deal of honesty. On the 19th of June I was going to fetch a pennyworth of chips, and met the prisoner and Mrs. Mill together; I no sooner got home, but I met the prisoner coming down stairs; I said, what do you do up them stairs; she said, she thought it was my husband that came in, and she went up there to hide herself; she had the cloaths mentioned in the indictment in her hand; said I, why do not you come into the room; she went away.</p>

               <p>Q. Why was she afraid of your husband?</p>
               <p>A. Hackney. That is what I wanted to know; I went to Mrs. Howard, and ask'd her if her garret door was lock'd; and told her the woman was come down, and gone out with an apron full of cloaths; and said, I had taken hold of one of the button holes; I told her it was the woman that was with me yesterday; she went up and came down again, and said the cloaths were all gone. I ran to 2 pawnbrokers, and bid them stop such things if they should be brought; and went to Mrs. Hill's room, where I found the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does Mrs. Hill live?</p>
               <p>A. Hackney. In Seacoal lane; the prisoner had the cloaths in her lap; I said, you have broke open our lodger's door, and taken away his cloaths; I ran out, and the key was in the door, and lock'd them all 3 in together, and carried the key, and gave it the prosecutor, when I met him, and told him where the prisoner and cloaths were; when we came there they were all got out, and had left the shoes on Mrs. Hill's table, and thrown the cloaths out upon the stairs.</p>
               <p>Sarah Hill. The prisoner is a stranger to me, she came up into my room along with Mrs. Willson, who was formerly a great croney of Mrs. Hackney's; the prisoner had sugar and butter in her hand, and a bundle in her apron, as full as it could hold; I never saw the cloaths till in Mr. Howard's hand. Mrs. Hackney never saw what was in her lap, she only pull'd her apron a little up. I heard the prisoner ask Mrs. Willson to take the cloaths, and go and make 3 l. on them. 
               <persName id="t17600709-22-person264">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Willson 
               <interp inst="t17600709-22-person264" type="surname" value="Willson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-22-person264" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-22-person264" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ask'd whose, cloaths they were; she said, they were a watchmaker's, but what his name was I did not take notice; I said, has any body been in trouble; the prisoner said, yes; it was at a cock-fighting.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you before the Alderman;</p>
               <p>S. Hil. I was; the prisoner was very fuddled, and said nothing.</p>
               <p>Q. to A. Hackney. Was you before the Alderman?</p>
               <p>A. Hackney. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the prisoner say any thing?</p>
               <p>A. Hackney. I did; she had a very saucy excuse.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the cloaths in the prisoner's lap in Hill's house?</p>
               <p>A. Hackney. I did; I saw some part of the coat and waistcoat.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I had been at work on the Tuesday, and on the Wednesday I was to go again; I went, and she gave me these cloaths to make money of; and I carried them to Mrs. Willson's.</p>
               <p>S. Hill. A. Hackney met this woman, the prisoner, in the street, and gave her a hat out of her hand; and said, are you coming to our house; and said, if she did not come then she might as well stay away; and in less than 10 minutes this robbery was done.</p>
               <p>A. Hackney. The prisoner gave me a hatt out of her hand.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600709-22-verdict121" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600709-22-verdict121" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
