<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680706-41">
               <interp inst="t17680706-41" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680706-41" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680706-41" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680706"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680706-41" type="date" value="17680706"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680706-41-off226-c257" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-41-defend340 t17680706-41-off226 t17680706-41-verdict228"></join>
         
               <p>456 (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17680706-41-defend340" type="defendantName">
                     Jane 
                     Haley 
                  <interp inst="t17680706-41-defend340" type="surname" value="Haley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-41-defend340" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-41-defend340" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17680706-41-deflabel225" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-41-defend340 t17680706-41-deflabel225"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17680706-41-off226" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680706-41-off226" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-41-off226" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing a canvas bag, value 1 d. two 36 s. pieces, five half guineas, one 27 s. piece, and one 6 s. 9 d. piece, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17680706-41-victim342" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Slogden 
                        <interp inst="t17680706-41-victim342" type="surname" value="Slogden"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680706-41-victim342" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680706-41-victim342" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-41-off226 t17680706-41-victim342"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17680706-41-cd227" type="crimeDate">June 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-41-off226 t17680706-41-cd227"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680706-41-person343">
                  Richard 
                  Slogden 
               <interp inst="t17680706-41-person343" type="surname" value="Slogden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-41-person343" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-41-person343" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 18th of June I happened to be in liquor; I picked the prisoner up, I do not know the place she took me to; I met with her in Cheapside; I know my money was safe in a canvas bag, buttoned in my pocket, the same as laid in the indictment (mentioning the separate pieces) as we walked together talking of things in our way; I believe I had not been in her company above half an hour, it may be not a quarter of an hour, before my purse and money were gone; I told her she had taken it, she denied it.</p>
               <p>Q. What house had you been in?</p>
               <p>Slogden. We had been in no house, I told her if she would return it, I would give her half a guinea, and let all drop; she still denied it; I took her down to the corner of the street, I was so much in liquor I do not know the street; upon that a watchman that heard the dispute between us came, I told him I had lost my money; he walked back with me to the place in the street where I missed it; we took her with us, we could not find it; I then charged the watch with her, they sent for a woman to search her in the watch-house; the woman found the money and purse upon her; she kicked and scratched a good deal, and was very unwilling to be searched, it was not in her apparel.</p>
               <p>Q. Where had she concealed it?</p>
               <p>Slogden. It was found in her body, the bag and money was all turned out in the watch-house; then the prisoner did not deny taking it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680706-41-person344">
                  Robert 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17680706-41-person344" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-41-person344" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-41-person344" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watchman; this gentleman was talking to the prisoner before I came up to him; he said she had robbed him; she said she had not got his money; I found there was a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176807060019"></xptr> little demur between them; he told us, if we could find his money, he would give her half a guinea, and us another; he said his money was in a canvas bag; she was searched in the watch-house, and the money was found in the canvas bag in her private parts (the bag and money produced in court.)</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>They searched me in a very indecent manner, I picked the canvas bag up not far from the place where the gentleman and I were together; he gave me six-pence, I do not know that he dropped his purse; then he took it out of his purse.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17680706-41-verdict228" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680706-41-verdict228" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-41-verdict228" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               Guilty of stealing, but not privately from his person
            </rs>. <rs id="t17680706-41-punish229" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680706-41-punish229" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-41-defend340 t17680706-41-punish229"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
