<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17630114-23">
               <interp inst="t17630114-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630114-23" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630114-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17630114"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630114-23" type="date" value="17630114"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17630114-23-off122-c175" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630114-23-defend216 t17630114-23-off122 t17630114-23-verdict124"></join>
         
               <p>84. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17630114-23-defend216" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Autenreith 
                  <interp inst="t17630114-23-defend216" type="surname" value="Autenreith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-defend216" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-defend216" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted, for <rs id="t17630114-23-off122" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-off122" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-off122" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               that he on the <rs id="t17630114-23-cd123" type="crimeDate">27th of Oct.</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630114-23-off122 t17630114-23-cd123"></join> about the hour of 2 in the night, on the same day, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17630114-23-victim218" type="victimName">
                           Peter
                            Henry Alexander Laprimaundaye
                        <interp inst="t17630114-23-victim218" type="surname" value="Henry Alexander Laprimaundaye"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630114-23-victim218" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630114-23-victim218" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630114-23-off122 t17630114-23-victim218"></join>
                     </persName>
                     
                  , did burglariously break and enter, and steal 4 silver candlesticks, 1 silver sugar basket, 1 silver cream pot, 3 silver castors, 1 silver stand, 4 silver salt-sellers gilt, 2 other silver salt-sellers, 22 silver table spoons, 1 silver soup ladle, 1 silver mug, 1 silver sauce boat, 5 silver waiters, 1 silver coffee pot, 1 silver strainer, 3 silver soup spoons, 1 piece of silver, being the bottom part of an inkstand, 30 silver handle forks, 30 silver handle knives, and other plate, in the whole to the amount of 177 l. in the dwelling-house of the said 
                     <persName id="t17630114-23-person219">
                        Peter Henry 
                        Alexander 
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person219" type="surname" value="Alexander"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630114-23-person219" type="given" value="Peter Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630114-23-person219" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630114-23-person220">
                  John 
                  Chapman 
               <interp inst="t17630114-23-person220" type="surname" value="Chapman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person220" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person220" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am apprentice to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17630114-23-person221">
                  Wm 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17630114-23-person221" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person221" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Goldsmith, at the Blackmoor's-Head in Cheapside. The prisoner came to our shop on the 6th of December last to sell 3 table spoons; I imagined they were stolen by the marks being erased out. My master bought them, and then sent me with the prisoner to get intelligence of him who knew him, and then to pay for it, and to see; more such spoons, which he said he had at home. He said his name was Reed, and that he lived in Cree-church-lane.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner know the purport of your going with him?</p>
               <p>Chapman. He did. As we were going along Cheapside near Bow church, he said to me, If you'll go back, and tell your master you have seen the 3 spoons, I'll give you a shilling. I said, I could not do that. Then he said, If I saw any people in the room, not to say what I came about, for the people would think him poor to sell his plate. I went with him to the sign of the Cock in Cree-church-lane, there he seemed to be very well known; he took me up stairs into a room, and went from me, and returned again in a few minutes, and brought 3 spoons answerable to ters with the engraving taken out. I did ny them, but paid him for the others, and returned home, and told Mr. Smith what I had learned: (he produced 2 table spoons, the Jury inspect them) these are what we bought of him. There were several people at the Cock that knew him, as appeared by their making obeisance to him; he seemed to be respected as a gentleman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630114-23-person222">
                  William 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17630114-23-person222" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person222" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mr. Crocket now: I did live with Mr. Laprimaundaye at the time of this robbery. I was entrusted with the care of his house. I left the doors and windows fast when I went to bed. I cannot tell the day of the month, but it was the night before we discovered the robbery.</p>
               <p>Q. How long may it be ago?</p>
               <p>Smith. It may be about 2 months ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was your master's plate the overnight?</p>
               <p>Smith. In the pantry, the proper place for it to be in. (A large box full of plate produced in court, with the plate as mentioned in the indictment in it. He looks at the plate.) These are my master's property, and were there at the time I have mentioned. I know them by my master's crest, and the marks on them.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at these 2 spoons. (The spoons produced by Chapman.)</p>
               <p>Smith. I can't swear to these, the engraving being taken out.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was the first person up the morning that the plate was missing?</p>
               <p>Smith. The maid was; she said, you have left the pantry door open; I said, no. I went and found it all in confusion, then I went and found the parlour window open, then I went and called my master, I told him we were robbed; he came down and saw what was done, and sent me directly to the silversmith.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176301140018"></xptr>Q. How many men servants were there of you?</p>
               <p>Smith. There was only one man servant.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630114-23-person223">
                  Peter Henry Alexander
                   Laprimaundaye
               <interp inst="t17630114-23-person223" type="surname" value="Laprimaundaye"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person223" type="given" value="Peter Henry Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person223" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have examined this plate, it is all my property. In the morning my servant came and called me, and told me we had been robbed; upon that I immediately sent him to Mr. Courtwould my silversmith, and to Mr. Bearance, who had been lately robbed in the same manner, to know what steps I should take; after that I went to justice Welch to take his advice, he advised me to have them advertised, which I did, and after that I advertised them in the gazette, and procured a pardon for any one concerned in the robbery that would discover it, with a reward of 50 l. but I could get no intelligence of my plate, till Mr. Smith, the goldsmith in Cheapside, came to my house, and produced to me 3 table spoons, which he said one Mr. Reed sold to him.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you lose your plate?</p>
               <p>Laprimaundaye. I lost it between the 26th and 27th of Oct.</p>
               <p>Q. When did Mr. Smith come to you?</p>
               <p>Laprimaundaye. He came on the 6th of Dec. in the afternoon, he produced the same spoons to me as his servant Chapman has here. I having part of my plate by inheritance from my mother, I knew there was some spoons among my relations of the same make; I sent to a relation, who sent some on the 9th of Dec. I sent them by Mr. Courtwould to Mr. Smith to compare them. He is here, and will give the court his opinion upon them.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you form any judgment whether these 2 spoons are your property?</p>
               <p>Laprimaundaye. They exactly tally'd with them which I sent to Mr. Smith's. I came here on the 9th in the afternoon for a warrant to Sir 
               <persName id="t17630114-23-person224">
                  Thomas 
                  Rawlinson 
               <interp inst="t17630114-23-person224" type="surname" value="Rawlinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person224" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person224" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , to be executed the next morning in searching this Reed's house. Then I, Mr. Bearance, Mr. Courtwould, Mr. Chapman, and Mr. Nash and Mr. Gardner, 2 peace officers, went according to the directions given to find out Mr. Reed in Cree-church-lane: Mr. Bearance went first to enquire, at last we found a shoemaker, that Mr. Chapman had seen to bow to this Mr. Reed, and Mr. Bearance being a German, and by favour of the German language, got out of the shoemaker (who I think was a German too) where this Reed lived, which was near the halfway-house in Stepney fields, the shoemaker said that he went by the name of Autenreith. I went with Mr. Nash to justice Quarrel, and he back'd my warrant. We went and found he lived next door to the half-way-house; then Mr. Bearance went first to get admittance into the house; after he was in, he sent for me and Mr. Courtwould; when we came in we heard a noise, I looked out at a window and saw the prisoner jump out at another window; then I immediately called out he was gone; we ran after him, and cried out, stop thief; Chapman ran and overtook him and brought him back. In looking about his parlour, after we brought him back, we saw in his beaufet a silver salt seller, on which my arms had been, and were then filed off; the silversmith, Mr. Courtwould, said he would swear to it to be my property: after that was found we went up stairs into his bed chamber, there were 2 chests of drawers, Mr. Gardner shook one of the upper drawers in one of the chests, we observed something to rattle in it: I asked for the key of that drawer, his wife and sister-in-law were present, they said they had no key to the drawers, I insisted upon their finding the key, they found it, and on the opening it we found several forks belonging to me, with my crest upon them.</p>
               <p>Q. Who found the key?</p>
               <p>Laprimaundaye. I cannot say who found it. We looked further into the drawers, and found some filings of silver, and files and other instruments made use of by silversmiths, and a small crucible; (the f ilings, tools, and crucible produced in court) after that I opened another drawer, and found all the large plate. I found all my plate again, except 19 table spoons, and 10 tea spoons. After that we brought the plate down, and took an inventory of it; the prisoner seemed very much surprized when we brought the plate down, he asked who it belonged to; I said, to me: he seemed in a very great consternation, and said, he was very sorry any such thing should happen; then we asked him how he came by it, he said one John brought it to him about a month before, and described him as a livery servant, that he became acquainted with him at the house of one Spencer, at the Grey-hound in Grub-street.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he mention a sir name?</p>
               <p>Laprimaundaye. No he did not; he said he had seen him about 10 days before: he said, this John brought it to his house, and begged of him to take it in, and that it belonged to a captain of a ship that was afraid of an execution the next morning, and he wanted to secure it to live upon afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is your house?</p>
               <p>Laprimaundaye. My house is in Angel-court, Throgmorton-street.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176301140019"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17630114-23-person225">
                  John 
                  Bearance 
               <interp inst="t17630114-23-person225" type="surname" value="Bearance"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person225" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was called upon on this occasion. I having before been robbed of a quantity of plate, and living very near the prosecutor, we have taken a great deal of pains to find it out, but unsuccessful, till the 6th of Dec. then he came and told me, two table-spoons had been brought to him by Mr. Smith in Cheapside, and compared them with others that came out of the same family, and found them to be his own. I advised him to go to Sir 
               <persName id="t17630114-23-person226">
                  Thomas 
                  Rawlinson 
               <interp inst="t17630114-23-person226" type="surname" value="Rawlinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person226" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and get a warrant to search the prisoner's house that brought the spoons to Mr. Smith; he said, he betrayed himself to be a German by his language, and lived in Creechurch-lane. I being a German, thought it was probable I might be of use in detecting him. We went, two constables, Mr. Chapman, him and I, to Creechurch-lane. I went first with one of the constables to inquire for him by the name of Reed. The people in the neighbourhood said they knew no such man, but upon Mr. Chapman's saying, he saw him bow to a man that lived thereabouts, I found the house and knocked at the door, I asked the person, if he knew one Reed, and if he lived in that neighbourhood? his answer was, he did not know such a person, but upon finding him a German, I accosted him in that language; he said, if I meant Autenreed, he lived in Stepney fields. Then I inquired about his family, and whether he lived at a public or private house? We then went to Stepney fields to the half-way-house, a public house; there again, upon inquiring after one Reed, whether he lived there, it was told us by the landlord, that he did, and he sent his maid to know, whether Mr. Autenreith was stirring, or not? I thought he might suspect something by seeing a number of people, I said I should be glad to know what apartment he had in his house; then he said, he lived at the next door. Then I desired Mr. Courtwould and Mr. Laprimaundaye to stay there and let me go to the house alone, and not to come to the door till I was got in. I went, the parlour window was open, I saw two women in the room, in their undress, as if just come down from bed. Upon my inquiring, whether he was at home? they said, he was not at home; and as I affected to speak broken English like a German, and speaking something about a letter I had to deliver to him, I prevailed upon the women to let me know he was at home in bed, and was getting up. It being cold, they asked me to come in; when the others saw me make a good entrance into the house, they were to come; Nash was close at my elbow; they all came. The women were surprized, and asked me who Nash was? I said, he was a servant of mine. Then I said, we wanted to speak with Mr. Reed; the women burst out with, Good God, what is the matter? I said, I desired to see him as soon as possible. We went into the parlour. Nash rather pressed me to go up stairs to him; upon this the wife's sister undertook to shew us up stairs to the prisoner's room, but coming to the foot of the stairs, they objected to Nash's coming to his room, as a person not fit in appearance to go up. When I was got upon the landing-place, and Nash half way up, I heard a rushing noise, which was immediately followed by a call below, He is gone! and the cry, Stop thief; upon which Nash went down the stair-case again, and I being left alone within the house, thinking we should have success in the search, I kept possession of the house, and remained there about 10 minutes before they brought the prisoner back. I ordered him to sit down in the parlour, and sat myself near him; I ordered then some paper, pens, and ink, that I might make an inventory of the goods that we should find, and to take down what the man should say upon this occasion. (Which paper I have here.) Before he was brought back, Mr. Courtwould and Mr. Laprimaundaye re-entered the house, and found a silver saltseller which Mr. Laprimaundaye thought to be his own, and Mr. Courtwould said positively it was Mr. Laprimaundaye's, and that he made it for him; I think he said, he never made but one pair of that sort. There was a conversation passed about this saltseller in the presence of the prisoner. He asked, what we came for? and I think to the best of my remembrance, he made an attempt to fall on his knees, and crave our mercy. We said, we had no design to hurt him, and desired him to sit down and compose himself, that he might be able to give a good account of himself. While this passed in the parlour, Mr. Laprimaundaye and Mr. Courtwould, and a constable, went up to search the house, I sat below; in a very little time they brought a large drawer full of plate, the same now produced in court, which I desired them to set down on the parlour-floor; I desired Mr. Courtwould to take it out of the drawer, and set aside what he should find to be Mr. Laprimaundaye's property, thinking in so large a quantity I might find a piece of my own; they proved to be all the property of Mr. Laprimaundaye, and not a single bit of plate in the house but what was his, except some small things not worth notice. I asked the prisoner, how he came by this plate? thinking he would speak to me in his own language. All the account I could get at<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176301140020"></xptr> that time was, that one John had brought it to him more than a month ago, at 3 or 4 in the morning; that he came to his door and knocked two or three times, he being in bed with his wife; he went and opened the parlour-window, and saw this John, and he thought another man was standing at a little distance, but he could not tell who he was; that John rested a bag upon the bench by the door, and desired him to take it in, saying it was some goods belonging to a captain that was afraid of a bond or judgment. This I took in writing; and when I had done, I spoke to him to this purpose, That he must really imagine that story to be inconsistent, that so large a quantity of plate should be left in his house by a man that he knew nothing of but only the name of John. I asked him, what the man was? he said, he called himself a livery-servant. I asked him, what livery he wore? he said, he could not tell. Then I said, what did you take him to be? he said, he rather took him to be a tradesman, not a livery-servant. I told him farther, that a man like himself, that seemed to have a good education, and so good a carriage, could hardly converse with a man so long a time by the name of John only. But all that we could get of him was, that his name was John, and that he got acquainted with him at Mr. Spencer's at the Greyhound in Grub street. Having taken down the inventory and this examination, we proceeded with him and the plate to this place, as the Court was at that time sitting; when he was examined here, and told that the nature of the case was such that he must be committed to Newgate, he then took me a-side, and in the German language said, he was rather surprized that the questions, that were put to him, should be asked him so publicly, because if he was to declare publicly who the person was that brought him the plate, he might get notice of it, and make his escape. Sir 
               <persName id="t17630114-23-person227">
                  Thomas 
                  Rawlinson 
               <interp inst="t17630114-23-person227" type="surname" value="Rawlinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person227" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person227" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             indulged me to speak to him in this language. I told the prisoner, he might give me an account of it, and I would assist him in getting hold of the man. He then told me, the man was one Smith, a leather-breeches-maker, where he lived at that time, he said, he could not tell, but he had lived in the Greyhound-inn-yard, Grubstreet, and that, if I went there, he had not been gone long, I might trace him. I found the description he had given me of the person; though he would not mention the name only by that of John, yet that description came up pretty near to the person of Smith, the breeches-maker. He seemed to have the same idea at home as he had afterwards here; but since that time I have been two or three times with him in prison, I never could get any thing more of him, but that this Smith brought him the plate; he stuck to that story, and in that story he has always remained.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630114-23-person228">
                  Richard 
                  Nash 
               <interp inst="t17630114-23-person228" type="surname" value="Nash"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person228" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable. I was with them at the apprehending the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you heard the account Mr. Bearance has given?</p>
               <p>Nash. I have. I can only add this, That after the prisoner had jumped out at the window, was pursued and taken, we went to searching. I found this crucible, and the silver filings were in the crucible, but in the hurry, it wat spilt in the drawer, we took it up, and it is here; and there was some of the plate with the crests or marks filed out.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630114-23-person229">
                  John 
                  Gardner 
               <interp inst="t17630114-23-person229" type="surname" value="Gardner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person229" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable. I was along with them in the search, there were in all three large draweres, and three small draweres. The drawers in which was the plate were locked. We asked the woman for the keys of the two drawers, we had shook the least of them and found something rattle. She said, she could not tell where the keys were, her husband always kept them two drawers locked. I said, then I'll break the drawers open. Then she took down a black waistcoat that hung by the bedside, and took a key out of the pocket, and unlocked the drawers.</p>
               <p>Q. to Bearance. What account did he give for the silver filings being there?</p>
               <p>Bearance. He said that this John took away most of the spoons, 2 candlesticks, and the coffee-pot, most of which he brought again with those files and filings in the coffee-pot; but there was a salt with the arms taken out, which we found in the parlour in the beaufet at our first going in, that he did not say the man had taken away.</p>
               <p>Q. Might not this salt escape the recollection of the prisoner, he being in a confusion?</p>
               <p>Bearance. I thought upon my oath he was in as little confusion as a man in such a condition could be; we ordered him something to drink, and desired him to sit down, he was then composed a little, and this was after he had sat some time; he asked me whether I was the gentleman that was robbed, I said not, that was Mr. Laprimaundaye that owned the plate; but when he knew this salt-seller was found in the parlour he gave us no account of the remainder of the plate. I asked him what pieces of plate this supposed John had taken away; after he had told me, I wrote them down on my paper, and read it<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176301140021"></xptr> over again to him in the presence of all the other witnesses, to know whether I had taken it right or wrong.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether any thing particular was asked relative to that salt-seller?</p>
               <p>Bearance. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he know that somebody's house had been broke open, and this plate taken away?</p>
               <p>Bearance. Yes.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630114-23-person230">
                  Samuel 
                  Courtwould 
               <interp inst="t17630114-23-person230" type="surname" value="Courtwould"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person230" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a goldsmith. I saw the spoons that were brought by Mr. Smith in Cheapside, I compared them with other spoons at Mr. Smith's house, they answered to them very well. I was present in searching the prisoner's house in Stepney fields, I observed the silver silings which were found in a drawer, there were a great number of forks and spoons with the marks taken out, several of the forks had been lately filed, and some not touched.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you call lately?</p>
               <p>Courtwould. A very few days, may be 4, 5, or 6 days at most.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. This is the salt-seller which we found at going into the parlour. (Holding it in his hand)</p>
               <p>Courtwould. (He takes it in his hand) This at that time seemed to be very lately filed. This is the prosecutor's property, I made it. I have made many salts, but never had an order to gild them in the inside, only this and the other 3 here produced.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you form your judgment from?</p>
               <p>Courtwould. I form it upon the tarnish.</p>
               <p>Q. Then according as it is laid in a damp or dry place, it will be more or less discoloured?</p>
               <p>Courtwould. Very right.</p>
               <p>Councel. Then there is not a positive certainty, because it is possible means may be made use of to tarnish it more or less in the same time.</p>
               <p>Courtwould. There was a coffee-pot seemed to have been filed some longer time than one of the candlesticks. If I file a piece of plate at home, if I look at it immediately I can see no difference at all betwixt that and one of the candlesticks. I look upon it that the candlestick had not been filed above 1 or 2 days.</p>
               <p>Q. Will not one piece of plate tarnish in your shew glass more than another?</p>
               <p>Courtwould. I can't say I have made observation of that, if they are both scraped or filed at the same time I can't suppose any difference.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I am a foreigner, a German, I do not know much about the nature of the laws of England, but what I have read in books. I have told the gentlemen the truth, and so I will tell you again. About a month or 5 weeks before I was taken up. I was once knocked up, somebody knocked at the door, they knocked again a violent knocking, I put my night gown round me, and went to the window and asked, who was at the door? - It is me, please to come down, I have something to tell you; it was very cold, I shut the window, and went and opened the door, he pushed in with a bundle, somebody stood just by him; said he, It belongs to a captain that has made a bond and judgment, and expects an execution, and I know you will keep it here while I call for it again; it was quite dark, he set it down, and away he went, and shut the door. In the morning I got up a little earlier than I used to do, thinking to see what this man had brought, I opened the window shutter and saw some forks stick out, it made a great noise and ratling in the dining room, I thought it was French plate: my wife came down stairs, then I took the parcel up stairs and went to put it in one drawer, it would not go all there, then I put the rest in another, and locked the drawer, and put the key in my pocket: this man came some days after, knocking at the door, I was smoaking a pipe, he said, I am come to fetch some away, I can't fetch it all at once, I'll take my handkerchief full; he took all he could, great spoons and other things: I said, I wish you would fetch them all away, may be I must answer for it. He said, do you never mind, the captain will make you amends; I have not got a lodging to my mind, and he would fetch them as soon as he could. He came again in about 8 or 9 days, and brought in a handkerchief under his coat most of it again. Said I, I thought you would have fetched it all away. - I'll soon fetch it all away. I said, I will keep it in my house no longer: he did not fetch it. After that my wife shewed me a letter that came from a lawyer of whom I had once a house, I could not pay him, he arrested me, I paid him half the money, and gave him a note for the rest; after that he said, if I did not come the next Tuesday he would serve me the same again. I had got some bills out, but I had not so much money; I thought by Christmass time I would pay him. The next Tuesday I was afraid he would arrest me, I did not know what to do; I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176301140022"></xptr> thought as this gentleman would sell his plate, I would take half a dozen spoons, I can but pay him at Christmas when my bills are paid: I took half a dozen. I had a few guineas that I thought would make the money up, so I went to the silversmith's shop, he said, what do you want for the spoons? I said, I wanted 40 shillings, I had a little bill to make up: the young man said, we can't buy silver of strangers, have you any body here that knows you? I said, I am going to Clifford's-inn.</p>
               <p>Chapman. You said to the Temple.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Said the silversmith, my apprentice shall go along with you, and pay you the money. I said, very well. Said I, I have a friend of mine that lives not quite so far, I sometimes come and dine there; so the young man came there with me, they were just at dinner, they asked me to dine with them; said the inaster of the house, there is a fire in the back room; I went there, so he saw I was known in the house. Said he to me, have you got any more of these spoons?. I took them out of my pocket. Said he, if you will sell them my master will buy them. I said, no, I would not sell them, I thought I should have money enough by selling 3. I went then to Butcher-row by Temple-bar, to my landlord Mr. Fosset's chamber, he was out; I sat down, he did not come in, I went away, and told them, I would call again, I went home; the next day I went again, I staid a good while, he was not at home; then I went the next day and enquired, there was nobody there; after that came a letter for me to pay the money: the next day being Friday, my sister came up and said, there were 3 gentlemen come knocking at my door; my wife came up and said, Lord, have you not paid Mr. Fosset? I was afraid, I did not know what to do; I came out at the window, they came directly after me, and brought me back: they said, you have got so and so of plate in your house; I told them this man brought the plate to me. I am innocent of these things, I know nothing about it; I am an innocent man, and every body that knows me will say I never wronged a man of a farthing or a halfpenny; I have been kept miserable in prison for nothing at all, my poor wife is big with child, I know nothing about the law, none can say I stole any thing.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Isabella Grayham. I live in the house with the prisoner, I am his wife's sister.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you lived there?</p>
               <p>Grayham. Ever since July last.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what hours your brother used to keep?</p>
               <p>Grayham. Very good hours, I never remember him being out after 12 o'clock at any time I lived there.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has he been married to your sister?</p>
               <p>Grayham. About 6 years. I came from Berwick in July last.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever seen this plate in his house?</p>
               <p>Grayham. No I never did before it was taken out of the drawers.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of its being brought to your brother's house?</p>
               <p>Grayham. No I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear him speak of it?</p>
               <p>Grayham. I do not remember his speaking of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember a violent knocking at the door?</p>
               <p>Grayham. No I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. How big may the house be you live in?</p>
               <p>Grayham. It is but a small house.</p>
               <p>Q. What room do you lie in?</p>
               <p>Grayham. I lie in a room by myself, next room to his own</p>
               <p>Q. Are they both forwards or backwards.</p>
               <p>Grayham. My room is backwards and theirs forwards, the head of the stair-case parts one room from the other.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that salt-seller in the beaufet in the parlour never used in the house?</p>
               <p>Grayham. It was a little while.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you first see that?</p>
               <p>Grayham. I can't justly say; it was about three weeks, or a month.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you hear about it how it came there?</p>
               <p>Grayham. I did not hear any thing in the least about its coming there; I did not ask about it, that was indifferent to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you look to see whether it had your brother's name, or any arms upon it?</p>
               <p>Grayham. No, I never looked at it to take any notice of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there no other plate used in your house besides that?</p>
               <p>Grayham. Nothing of any consequence; there were a few spoons.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never see a silver coffee-pot or tea-kettle there?</p>
               <p>Grayham. No.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176301140023"></xptr>Q. Did you never see that little mug that stands by you?</p>
               <p>Grayham. No.</p>
               <p>William Burton. I am a Marshall's-court officer. I had a writ to arrest the prisoner at the suit of Mr. Fosset in Clifford's-inn, it was discharged the 6th of May. He had not paid Mr. Fosset all he owed him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any other arrest intended?</p>
               <p>Burton. Yes; Mr. Fosset sent for me, and said, if he did not pay him, he would arrest him again.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630114-23-person231">
                  Peter 
                  Anderson 
               <interp inst="t17630114-23-person231" type="surname" value="Anderson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person231" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person231" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about five years, he is a surgeon, he has always behaved like a gentleman, with a good character as an honest man.</p>
               <p>Q. What countryman are you?</p>
               <p>Anderson. I am a Dane, he is a German,</p>
               <p>Henrich Knust. I have known him about five years, he has dealt with me, and paid me very honestly; I have seen him in company, he behaved like a gentleman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630114-23-person232">
                  John 
                  Medows 
               <interp inst="t17630114-23-person232" type="surname" value="Medows"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person232" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person232" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about five years, I always looked upon him to be a very worthy good-natured man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630114-23-person233">
                  Andrew 
                  Bushman 
               <interp inst="t17630114-23-person233" type="surname" value="Bushman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person233" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him 3 quarters of a year, I looked upon him to be a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630114-23-person234">
                  James 
                  Read 
               <interp inst="t17630114-23-person234" type="surname" value="Read"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person234" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person234" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about two years, I always believed him to be a very honest man: I never saw any low company he kept; I never heard any ill of him before this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630114-23-person235">
                  Charles 
                  Friday 
               <interp inst="t17630114-23-person235" type="surname" value="Friday"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person235" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him I believe five or six years, he kept an apothecary's shop in my neighbourhood; he bears the character of a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630114-23-person236">
                  George 
                  Beardsell 
               <interp inst="t17630114-23-person236" type="surname" value="Beardsell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person236" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about 2 years, he always behaved as an honest man, and I look upon him as such.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630114-23-person237">
                  William 
                  Pitt 
               <interp inst="t17630114-23-person237" type="surname" value="Pitt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person237" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person237" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about 5 or 6 years, I never knew any thing of him but that of an honest man, that is his general character; I have been in his company several times.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630114-23-person238">
                  John 
                  Sheen 
               <interp inst="t17630114-23-person238" type="surname" value="Sheen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person238" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about 18 months, he has attended my family eight or ten times. He has always behaved like a gentleman.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Sheen. I am a merchant.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630114-23-person239">
                  John 
                  Pierpoint 
               <interp inst="t17630114-23-person239" type="surname" value="Pierpoint"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person239" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-person239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live on Tower-Hill; I am a Tobacconist; he lived over-against me; I believe I have known him five or six years; I always thought him to be an honest man; he seemed to be, as most foreigners are, a little gay. I never saw him in any bad company.</p>
               <p>Q. to Smith. How long did you live with Mr. Laprimaundaye?</p>
               <p>Smith. About 8 months.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you live before?</p>
               <p>Smith. I lived before in Mincing-lane.</p>
               <p>Q. There is one Smith a breeches-maker, how long have you known him?</p>
               <p>Smith. I never saw him before he was taken up in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he any relation of yours?</p>
               <p>Smith. No. I have no relations of the name.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you first see the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Smith. I never saw him in my life before he was taken up.</p>

               <p>Court. The night before the robbery was committed your lady went out?</p>
               <p>Smith. She did, a visiting; I came in while she was out.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there one or two maids in the house?</p>
               <p>Smith. There were two.</p>
               <p>Q. Did either one or both of them catch you in the pantry?</p>
               <p>Smith. No, I was in the parlour.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the parlour windows shut or open?</p>
               <p>Smith. They were shut.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you not two of the salvers in your hands?</p>
               <p>Smith. I had.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not desire the maids not to tell your master of that?</p>
               <p>Smith. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you not hid in the pantry?</p>
               <p>Smith. No; I did it with intent to fright them, no otherwise.</p>
               <p>Q. How came they to look after you?</p>
               <p>Smith. Because I made a noise to fright them, and they came into the room. I apprehended they were a good deal frighted, but hearing me laugh in the cupboard, they opened the door, and I came out.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they tell your master?</p>
               <p>Smith. I believe they did.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>Smith. This might be between 4 and 5 o'clock, it was not dark.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure the window was not open?</p>
               <p>Smith. I shut the window before, that is not the shutters, only the sash, the sash had been open. This was the night before the robbery happened.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176301140024"></xptr>Q. How came you to have the two salvers in your hand?</p>
               <p>Smith. I made a noise with them on the marble slab; I thought to make them believe there was something the matter, and they came into the room.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. When did you first hear of this?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I first heard of this about a fortnight or three weeks after the robbery. I have no reason at all to suspect him; I have a good opinion of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you give him a character at his going away?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. My wife did to Mr. Crocket, where he lives now. I have a good opinion of him.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17630114-23-verdict124" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-verdict124" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-verdict124" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               Acquitted of the Burglary. Guilty of stealing the goods in the dwelling-house
            </rs>. <rs id="t17630114-23-punish125" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630114-23-punish125" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630114-23-defend216 t17630114-23-punish125"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
