<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610625-28">
               <interp inst="t17610625-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-28" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610625"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-28" type="date" value="17610625"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610625-28-off162-c204" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-28-defend252 t17610625-28-off162 t17610625-28-verdict166"></join>
         
               <p>207. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610625-28-defend252" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17610625-28-defend252" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-28-defend252" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-28-defend252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17610625-28-off162" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610625-28-off162" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-28-off162" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing one brown gelding, value 40 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17610625-28-victim254" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     London 
                  <interp inst="t17610625-28-victim254" type="surname" value="London"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-28-victim254" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-28-victim254" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-28-off162 t17610625-28-victim254"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17610625-28-cd163" type="crimeDate">June 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-28-off162 t17610625-28-cd163"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-28-person255">
                  John 
                  London 
               <interp inst="t17610625-28-person255" type="surname" value="London"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-28-person255" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-28-person255" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the second of June I put a horse into <placeName id="t17610625-28-crimeloc164">a skittle-ground at the Cock and Bottle in Islington</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17610625-28-crimeloc164" type="placeName" value="a skittle-ground at the Cock and Bottle in Islington"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610625-28-crimeloc164" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-28-off162 t17610625-28-crimeloc164"></join>, while I went in to drink a pint of beer, it being a very hot day, and before I had drank it my horse was gone: I had not put him there above a quarter of an hour, the prisoner was in the house drinking part of the time I was there; a little lad came in, and said a sailor had rode away with him; the prisoner is <rs id="t17610625-28-deflabel165" type="occupation">a sailor</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-28-defend252 t17610625-28-deflabel165"></join>: the horse was found again in about a fortnight and three or four days, upon Walworth-common, on the other side the water, I found him by advertising.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the horse been sold to any body?</p>
               <p>London. No.</p>
               <p>- Gardner. I am fourteen years of age next October, I was by our door, and saw a sailor, it was the prisoner at the bar, bring a horse out of our yard, the horse was a little startlish, I went to hold his bridle, he mounted, and rode away.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know who brought the horse there?</p>
               <p>Gardner. No, I do not: I saw the prisoner again when he was carried before justice Hervey.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a horse was it?</p>
               <p>Gardner. He was a little one, of a brown colour.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Gardner. I live at the Cock and Bottle at Islington, my mother lives in one part of the house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Gardner. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-28-person256">
                  Alice 
                  Owen 
               <interp inst="t17610625-28-person256" type="surname" value="Owen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-28-person256" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-28-person256" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Cock and Bottle at Islington. On the Tuesday before the King's birth-day the prosecutor set in my house to be out of the rain, the prisoner was then in sailor's cloaths, he asked the way out backwards, I shewed him the way, and he never returned. My boy came in, and said, There is a sailor got upon a horse, and he rides faster than the horse: we went out, and the prosecutor's horse was taken out of the skittle-ground.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-28-person257">
                  John 
                  Townsend 
               <interp inst="t17610625-28-person257" type="surname" value="Townsend"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-28-person257" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-28-person257" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am headborough belonging to Islington, I was called up about two o'clock on the fifth of June, to go to the Cock and Bottle, to take charge of the prisoner at the bar. I took him down to Clerkenwell Bridewell, and then before the justice; he denied ever riding a horse away as they had charged him.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17610625-28-person258">
                  A.
                   Owen What
               <interp inst="t17610625-28-person258" type="surname" value="Owen What"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-28-person258" type="given" value="A."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-28-person258" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             time of the day was he horse taken away?</p>
               <p>A. Owen. He took the horse away about five in the afternoon, he came again on the Thursday following, I began talking to him about it and he denied it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-28-person259">
                  John 
                  Panker 
               <interp inst="t17610625-28-person259" type="surname" value="Panker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-28-person259" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-28-person259" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am keeper and driver of Walworth-common.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176106250033"></xptr> a woman and a man came together, he asked me to let a horse go three weeks upon the common, the woman told me she would be a shilling, and pay me on the Sunday; the horse had been about a fortnight on the common.</p>
               <p>Q. Who does the common belong to?</p>
               <p>Panker. It belongs to the lord of the manor, that is, the dean of Canterbury: the parish employs me, and I have so much a head for looking after the cattle.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a horse was he?</p>
               <p>Panker. He was a little brown poney.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of the horse?</p>
               <p>Panker. The horse was advertised, and taken away from me, the prosecutor owned him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-28-person260">
                  Thomas 
                  Adams 
               <interp inst="t17610625-28-person260" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-28-person260" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-28-person260" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I believe the prisoner at the bar is the man that brought the horse to the common keeper, there was a woman with him, he turned the horse upon the common, I do not know the time, I know it was in June, within a day or two of the king's birth-day.</p>
               <p>Q. to Panker. What might the horse be worth?</p>
               <p>Panker. I take the horse to be worth 35 s. I should not have chose to give more.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing at all of this horse that I am accused with, I never saw or heard of any horse, I am lately come from sea, I have been to serve my king and country on board the Liverpool man of war, Capt. Davis; I got my clearance at Hallifax, and came home to Spit-head. I had a fall upon the main-deck, and splintered my arm, and now my arm is entirely well again. I came into this woman's house about nine o'clock at night, and was no sooner come there, but this woman and a man began with me about a horse that was taken out of the yard.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610625-28-verdict166" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610625-28-verdict166" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
