<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650116-39">
               <interp inst="t17650116-39" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650116-39" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650116-39" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650116-39" type="date" value="17650116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650116-39-off252-c324" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650116-39-defend411 t17650116-39-off252 t17650116-39-verdict256"></join>
         
               <p>141. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17650116-39-defend411" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Mary 
                     Bell 
                  
               <interp inst="t17650116-39-defend411" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-39-defend411" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-39-defend411" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17650116-39-deflabel250" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650116-39-defend411 t17650116-39-deflabel250"></join>, otherwise Mary, <rs id="t17650116-39-deflabel251" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650116-39-defend411 t17650116-39-deflabel251"></join> of 
               <persName id="t17650116-39-person413">
                  Robert 
                  Bell 
               <interp inst="t17650116-39-person413" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-39-person413" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-39-person413" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , mariner, was indicted for the <rs id="t17650116-39-off252" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650116-39-off252" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-39-off252" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               wilful murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17650116-39-victim415" type="victimName">
                           Elizabeth 
                           Allen 
                        <interp inst="t17650116-39-victim415" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650116-39-victim415" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650116-39-victim415" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650116-39-off252 t17650116-39-victim415"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17650116-39-viclabel253" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650116-39-victim415 t17650116-39-viclabel253"></join> 
                  <rs id="t17650116-39-cd254" type="crimeDate">December 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650116-39-off252 t17650116-39-cd254"></join>. She stood charged on the coroner's inquest for manslaughter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650116-39-person416">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Fawcett 
               <interp inst="t17650116-39-person416" type="surname" value="Fawcett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-39-person416" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-39-person416" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I cannot recollect the day of the month I was at my father's house: he keeps <placeName id="t17650116-39-crimeloc255">the Cart and Horses, a public-house, in Old-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17650116-39-crimeloc255" type="placeName" value="the Cart and Horses, a public-house, in Old-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17650116-39-crimeloc255" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650116-39-off252 t17650116-39-crimeloc255"></join>: it was more than a month ago; the prisoner and deceased sat seemingly very friendly together; I drawed them two pots of purl; there was a man with them; he drank part of it; he left them about a pint in the second pot, and went away: the deceased, 
               <persName id="t17650116-39-person417">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Allen 
               <interp inst="t17650116-39-person417" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-39-person417" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-39-person417" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was very much in liquor, and she laid her head on 
               <persName id="t17650116-39-person418">
                  Mary 
                  Bell 
               <interp inst="t17650116-39-person418" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-39-person418" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-39-person418" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's shoulder; Bell offered to hit her with her elbow, and said, You<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176501160033"></xptr> whore, don't lay your head upon my shoulder: the deceased said, I am surprized you should call me whore, when you know you are a greater whore than I. Bell said, I am a married woman, and if you call me whore again, I'll split your skull. She got up, and threw some purl in her face; then the deceased got up, and called her whore again: then Bell struck her with the pint pot a very violent blow, and the deceased in endeavouring to get up, fell down on her face, and remained senseless some time, continuing in a sit; I then went on my knees, and took the deceased's head into my bosom: Bell still kept the pot in her hand, till I took it out, and said, you have killed the woman I believe: Bell said, d - n her heretic blood; then some words passed between my mother and she: Bell went out at the door, and when she was gone, I washed the deceased's face, and put a handkerchief on her wound, and another round her head.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the wound?</p>
               <p>Fawcett. No, I did not: she had very thick hair, and I bled terribly: by that time she was pretty well recovered. My mother asked her if she had any friends belonging to her? she said, she had some, but she had been a very bad girl, and thought they would not look on her. My mother desired her to go and fetch a warrant for the prisoner: she went out, in order so to do, and appeared better than I expected: I saw her after that, on Monday, in the hospital.</p>
               <p>Q. What day was this?</p>
               <p>Fawcett. This was on a Friday; she then appeared in very good spirits, and said she should do well again.</p>
               <p>Jane Hall. I am mother to the last witness. I was not up when the prisoner and deceased first came in, but was soon after. I was at breakfast, and saw the deceased loll her head on the prisoner's shoulder; she pushed the deceased with her elbow, and said, d - n you, why do you loll your head on me, you whore. Said the other, if I am a whore, you are a whore as well as me. The prisoner said, I am not: you know I am a married woman, and if you call me whore again, I'll split your skull: the deceased then said, Moll, you are a whore: the prisoner then tossed the purl in her face; the deceased made an offer to get up to resent it, and the prisoner struck her with the pot, and she fell down in a fit. After my daughter had put some sugar into the wound, and bound up her head, I sent for Mr. Webb, the constable, to secure the prisoner: he told me he could not take charge of her without a warrant. When the prisoner came to herself, I persuaded her to go to Hicks's-hall for a warrant; she seemed then pretty well, and went away, and I never saw her afterwards.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650116-39-person419">
                  James 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17650116-39-person419" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-39-person419" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-39-person419" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable. I was sent for. I went and saw the deceased sitting on a bench, with her head bound up: I went home again, and a little before twelve o'clock, the constable from Clerkenwell came into Swan-alley; and seeing the deceased in her blood, he came and desired me to go with him; I went to the sister and brother-in-law of the prisoner; there was the prisoner: she said, what is the matter? I said, I believe you are the woman that has killed a woman. Said she, if I have killed her, I must be hanged for her. I had much ado to get her out of the house, fearing an Irish clan of them: I got two people to guard and help her along: she behaved quite turbulent, and was very loath to go, so that I had a great deal of trouble. I took her to Hicks's-hall, before a magistrate; she was committed to New Prison. When the mob followed her, she said to me, give me your stick, and I'll clear my way of them all.</p>

               <p>Q. Was she sober?</p>
               <p>Webb. She appeared to be sober, and walked as well as a woman could walk.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650116-39-person420">
                  Anne 
                  Wilkinson 
               <interp inst="t17650116-39-person420" type="surname" value="Wilkinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-39-person420" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-39-person420" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going by, by accident, when the deceased fell down in her blood, in Swan-alley; there was a great mob of people, and some said the woman was murdered: she was taken up, and carried to the Man and Compass, a public-house, where she was brought to herself. She had been in a sit, by the loss of blood; she gave an account that 
               <persName id="t17650116-39-person421">
                  Mary 
                  Bell 
               <interp inst="t17650116-39-person421" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-39-person421" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-39-person421" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             did it, and where it was done: then she was brought out, and put into a wooden chair, and carried to the hospital; I went with her there; I covered her with my cloak, and staid there till her head was dressed. The next day being Saturday, I went again, and went four times in all: the last time, I found her dead.</p>
               <p>Mr. Lucas. I am dresser to Mr. Crane, the surgeon to St. Bartholomew's hospital.</p>
               <p>Q. Explain what you mean by dresser.</p>
               <p>Lucas. There are walking pupils and dressing pupils. I was called upon to attend on the deceased on the 7th of December: she was taken into the hospital, for the cure of a wound upon her forehead.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you examine that wound?</p>
               <p>Lucas. I did; and found it about an inch and a half in length, and the bone partly bare, but no fracture: I did not imagine it would prove mortal: she had no bad symptoms, but recovered very fast. It continued well about ten days; at which time she was seized with a fever, for which<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176501160034"></xptr> Mr. Crane ordered her to be put under the physicians care.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think that fever proceeded from the blow?</p>
               <p>Lucas. It is not in my power to tell that.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you been there any time?</p>
               <p>Lucas. I have dressed partly under Mr. Crane, and partly under Mr. Potts: I was an apprentice in the country.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her dead?</p>
               <p>Lucas. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did she live after she was seized with the fever?</p>
               <p>Lucas. She died in a few days after, under the physicians care.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she live regular?</p>
               <p>Lucas. I don't suppose she followed very closely to what was directed.</p>
               <p>Q. In what manner do you mean?</p>
               <p>Lucas. I believe she got up before she was ordered to do it.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your opinion and judgment, and the reason of your belief?</p>
               <p>Lucas. I have seen instances, where a fever has come on, after a blow on the head; but there was a fever stirring in the hospital at that time, but whether this was from that, I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Had she the same species of fever, as others in the hospital?</p>
               <p>Lucas. That should be had from the physicians.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the best account you can give?</p>
               <p>Lucas. I think it impossible to determine, except the head had been examined after she was dead, which it was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think the wound caused the fever?</p>
               <p>Lucas. I believe the wound would rather have prevented a fever, than have caused it: there is a a material difference between the blow and the wound. If this blow was the cause of her death, I suppose it must have been from some disorder on the brain.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17650116-39-verdict256" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650116-39-verdict256" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
