<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610506-25">
               <interp inst="t17610506-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610506-25" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610506-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610506"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610506-25" type="date" value="17610506"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610506-25-off133-c248" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-25-defend291 t17610506-25-off133 t17610506-25-verdict136"></join>
         
               <p>184. (M) 
               <persName id="t17610506-25-defend291" type="defendantName">
                  Thomas 
                  Shepherd 
               <interp inst="t17610506-25-defend291" type="surname" value="Shepherd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-25-defend291" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-25-defend291" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17610506-25-off133" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610506-25-off133" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-25-off133" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               the wilful murder of 
                     <persName id="t17610506-25-victim292" type="victimName">
                        James 
                        Hogan 
                     <interp inst="t17610506-25-victim292" type="surname" value="Hogan"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610506-25-victim292" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610506-25-victim292" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-25-off133 t17610506-25-victim292"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , by striking him on the head with an iron hough
            </rs>, <rs id="t17610506-25-cd134" type="crimeDate">March 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-25-off133 t17610506-25-cd134"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>Walter Croyden. On Monday, the 30th of March, I had business in London.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Croyden. I am a shoemaker.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Croyden. I live at Chelsea, near Jews-row; the deceased was my <rs id="t17610506-25-deflabel135" type="occupation">apprentice</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-25-defend291 t17610506-25-deflabel135"></join>, I left him at work when I went out. I had a son, who has lately enlisted for a soldier in an independent company, come to see me; I left him at home with the deceased; I was uncle to the deceased. When I came home, I was informed he had a wound on his head; I did not see him that night. The next day I arose and went upstairs to him, to know how it happened. He said he had received a blow on his head by a man that he did know his name.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ask him what it came about?</p>
               <p>Croyden. He told me he went into the skittle-ground with my son; he stood looking on, and was not at play. There were others at play, and one man turned round to him, that had been at play, and said to him, he had laid him a penny upon the bowl of a pin. The lad said, he had laid him none, neither had he any to lay. The man insisted upon it once or twice. He said, he neither laid nor betted. Then the man came from the frame, without any words or provocation, to him and laid hold of his collar, and knocked up his heels: he got up again, and the man laid hold of him a second time, and gave him a blow, and then quitted him: that he then took to his heels, and ran eight or ten yards, and fell on his belly, with his heels towards the person; and as he lay, he held up his head, and looked at the person, and the prisoner came with a garden hough, and struck him, and broke the handle of the hough in two. I was advised to carry him to the hospital, and in about ten or eleven days he died.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you he had attempted to strike the person?</p>
               <p>Croyden. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you with the prisoner after he was apprehended?</p>
               <p>C royden. I was with him before justice Welch.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you charge him with this fact there?</p>
               <p>Croyden. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. What answer did he make to it?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176105060054"></xptr>Croyden. He owned he struck him with the hough, and said he was sorry for it, and said he was in liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is your son?</p>
               <p>Croyden. He is now in Germany.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the deceased sensible when he told you this?</p>
               <p>Croyden. He was sensible to a few hours of his death, and always persisted in the same thing.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the prisoner when you first saw him?</p>
               <p>Croyden. He was then in custody.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the deceased tell you what words past between him and the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Croyden. He told me he had no words with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he had struck the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Croyden. He did not say a word of that.</p>
               <p>William Groom. I was in the skittle-ground at the time this thing happened; there was Thomas Shepherd, the prisoner at the bar, Isaac Croyden, and others, playing at skittles.</p>
               <p>Q. Who were the others?</p>
               <p>Groom. I do not know their names; they played a game or two, and then Thomas Shepherd left off; then the losers play'd.</p>
               <p>Q. What was Hogan doing?</p>
               <p>Groom. He was betting; Thomas Shepherd's countryman laid him a penny about going so many pins. The deceased lost it. Shepherd's countryman demanded the penny that he had won. The deceased said, he did not lay.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure he did lay?</p>
               <p>Groom. I was by and heard him; the prisoner was sitting on a bench, he jumped up, and said to the deceased, Why do you not pay me the penny, for I heard you lay? Said the deceased, I did not lay upon this. They had some words. The prisoner catched him by the collar, and again said, Why do not you pay him the money? After that he tripped up the deceased's heels.</p>
               <p>Q. What age was the deceased, and his size?</p>
               <p>Groom. He was a slim person, between 17 and 18; after he got up, then they had two or three words more; then the prisoner gave him a smack in the face; then the deceased catched up an iron-hough, that lay on his right hand side, against the pales, and made a full blow at the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he hit him?</p>
               <p>Groom. Whether he hit him or not, I cannot say; but the prisoner put his hand up, and I believe catched the hough out of his hand by meer strength.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he strike at him with any force?</p>
               <p>Groom. He struck at him with great revenge.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was you to him?</p>
               <p>Groom. I was close by them; when the prisoner had got the hough, the deceased took to his heels, and the prisoner after him. He ran about eight or ten yards, and fell down; then the prisoner made a blow at him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he hit him?</p>
               <p>Groom. Whether he hit him or not I cannot say.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he the hough in his hand?</p>
               <p>Groom. He had: then the deceased got up again, and put on his hat, and took to his heels again, and ran into his master's house. Then I and another went and hit the prisoner for striking the deceased.</p>
               <p>Q. Why were you so angry with the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Groom. Because I did not know the prisoner, and I did the deceased.</p>
               <p>Q. Were any others angry with the prisoner for what he had done?</p>
               <p>Groom. Yes, some of them were. After this the deceased came to the pump to wash himself: the blood ran down his face; he did not know where the wound was. I took off his hat to look at it; he looked brisk then.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you see him after that?</p>
               <p>Groom. Yes, in the house.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there not a scraper near the place where the deceased's head fell?</p>
               <p>Groom. There was.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of one was it?</p>
               <p>Groom. It was the iron of a spade knocked into the ground with the edge upwards, to scrape shoes on.</p>
               <p>Q. By the fall that he had, do you think he hit himself against the scraper?</p>
               <p>Groom. That I do not know, he fell to be sure with great force.</p>
               <p>Q. Did his head lay near the scraper?</p>
               <p>Groom. His head was about half a yard over.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think his head hit against the scraper?</p>
               <p>Groom. He might, or whether the hough did it, I cannot say; I ran after him, but did not see which way it was done; he fell streight to it, and his head went beyond it afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he fall?</p>
               <p>Groom. He fell on his side, and, as it were, he plunged forwards,</p>
               <p>Q. Upon what part of the head did you observe the wound to be?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176105060055"></xptr>Groom. It was upon the right side of the head.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the scraper on that, or the other side of the prisoner, as he lay?</p>
               <p>Groom. The scraper was on that side of his head as he lay, where the wound was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you before the justice of the peace?</p>
               <p>Groom. I was,</p>
               <p>Q. Did you give the same account there as here?</p>
               <p>Groom. I did, and so did Mr. Croyden's son.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say there?</p>
               <p>Groom. He said, if he did do it, he was very sorry; but he went halves with the other man (meaning his countryman.)</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he hit him?</p>
               <p>Groom. He said he hit at him, but could not say that he hit him.</p>
               <p>Q. Which end of the hough did he strike at him with?</p>
               <p>Groom. He struck at him with the handle of it in his hand; I believe he had the handle in both his hands.</p>
               <p>Q. When you came to the deceased, as he was lying on the ground, what part of his body was nearest the scraper?</p>
               <p>Groom. Then the scraper seemed to be near his right-hip; the prisoner struck at him as he ran along.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the scraper raised above the ground?</p>
               <p>Groom. It was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the deceased run very hard?</p>
               <p>Groom. He did, when he found he was got from the prisoner's hands; he had a great blow across his hand.</p>
               <p>Q How do you know that?</p>
               <p>Groom. I saw his hand black and blue afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you look upon that to be done by the bough?</p>
               <p>Groom. Possibly it might.</p>
               <p>Q. Which part of the hough did he strike the deceased with?</p>
               <p>Groom. With the iron part of it.</p>
               <p>Q. What part did the deceased strike the prisoner with?</p>
               <p>Groom. The deceased had the iron part in his hand.</p>
               <p>Sarah Eliment. The deceased said to me, O nurse, I am afraid he has given me my death's wound! I attended him all the time after he was brought into the house, 'till he died.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he name the name of the person?</p>
               <p>S. Eliment. He named no name at all; he said, he had rather he had killed him outright, but said he forgave him.</p>
               <p>Leonard Hercourt. The deceased was brought to St. George's hospital.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Hercourt. I am house surgeon there.</p>
               <p>Q. What hurt had the deceased?</p>
               <p>Hercourt. He had a fracture in his skull, of which fracture he died.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he come into the hospital?</p>
               <p>Hercourt. He came on the 31st of March.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he die?</p>
               <p>Hercourt. He died the 11th of April.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a wound was it, describe it?</p>
               <p>Hercourt. It was on the right-side of the head, pretty near the forehead.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell how it was given?</p>
               <p>Hercourt. No, I cannot; it appeared as if given by a fall, or a blow.</p>
               <p>Q. Which do you think?</p>
               <p>Hercourt. It might be by either.</p>
               <p>Q. Might the deceased have done it by falling against a scraper?</p>
               <p>Hercourt. He might.</p>
               <p>Q. Might he have hurt the skull in the same manner by the scraper?</p>
               <p>Hercourt. I don't doubt but he might, as if he had had a blow given him; it seemed to be made with a kind of a sharp instrument.</p>
               <p>Q. to Groom. Was the edge of the scraper very sharp?</p>
               <p>Groom. It might he as sharp as a gardener's hough, for what I know; I did not take notice of it.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. to Hercourt. How did the wound run?</p>
               <p>Hercourt. It run across.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>He struck me first, and then ran and fell upon the scraper.</p>
               <p>Counsel for prisoner. We have five or six witnesses that were in the skittle-ground at the same time, that are to the same as the witness Groom has related; and as we cannot vary the fact at all, so we shall not take up the time of the court; and as to his character, that is out of the question; he never absconded, so we shall not trouble the court with any other witness.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610506-25-verdict136" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610506-25-verdict136" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-25-verdict136" type="verdictSubcategory" value="accidentalDeath"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>That the deceased died an accidental death.</p>
            </div1>
