<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17631207-55">
               <interp inst="t17631207-55" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-55" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-55" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17631207"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-55" type="date" value="17631207"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17631207-55-off299-c402" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-55-defend514 t17631207-55-off299 t17631207-55-verdict303"></join>
         
               <p>58. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17631207-55-defend514" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Baillie 
                  <interp inst="t17631207-55-defend514" type="surname" value="Baillie"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-55-defend514" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-55-defend514" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17631207-55-off299" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631207-55-off299" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-55-off299" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing two pair of metal-buckles, value 10 d. and one shilling in money
            </rs>; the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17631207-55-victim516" type="victimName">
                     Samuel 
                     Bellamy 
                  <interp inst="t17631207-55-victim516" type="surname" value="Bellamy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-55-victim516" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-55-victim516" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-55-off299 t17631207-55-victim516"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17631207-55-cd300" type="crimeDate">Dec. 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-55-off299 t17631207-55-cd300"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-55-person517">
                  Samuel 
                  Bellamy 
               <interp inst="t17631207-55-person517" type="surname" value="Bellamy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-55-person517" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-55-person517" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17631207-55-crimeloc301">Thames-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17631207-55-crimeloc301" type="placeName" value="Thames-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17631207-55-crimeloc301" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-55-off299 t17631207-55-crimeloc301"></join>; I<rs id="t17631207-55-viclabel302" type="occupation">deal in ironmongery, and other articles</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-55-victim516 t17631207-55-viclabel302"></join>; I keep two porters, the prisoner was one; the other informed me, that I had been wronged by the prisoner; so I marked 10 s. and put it into the drawer where we put the money we take in retail, which may sometimes be to 10 or 12 l. the drawer is kept unlocked. I went out, that he might have no suspicion of me; this was on last Thursday evening, about half an hour after eight o'clock. I left the prisoner at home, and returned in about an hour: I examined the drawer as soon as I came home, and missed a shilling of the marked money; I told a neighbour that I intended to put this in practice to discover the thief: I had got a constable at a public-house within two doors of mine; I went and told them I had lost a shilling, that I had not trusted to my own memory, but put it down in writing: the prisoner was gone to bed, I asked them to go up with me; I asked him how he came to take a shilling out of the drawer; me! says he: yes, says I, you: you must eat your Christmas dinner in Newgate; I know you must have the shilling, and nobody else; he got out of bed immediately, and dressed himself; when he had got on his breeches, his other cloaths were searched, and the shilling found in his coat pocket; he said, he knew nothing of it; he believed it had tumbled out of the till into his coat pocket, for he never put it in; I told him, as the shilling was found, I insisted on seeing his box, that he had his cloaths in, opened; he, himself, gave us the key; on opening the box, there were two pair of buckles, with several other things; I thought the buckles were sufficient, so I left the rest: the buckles were made by a near relation of mine, and never made any for any beside me in London; when I found the buckles, the prisoner said, you gave me these a year ago; I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176312070046"></xptr> said, John, the buckles I gave you were of a different make, you have them in your shoes; he said nothing to that: I took both pairs out of his box together; I am certain they were mine: I told him, he must go to the Compter; he begged to stay till next morning, to see his brother; I took him to the Compter that night, and yesterday I took him before the Alderman, who committed him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-55-person518">
                  Joseph 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17631207-55-person518" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-55-person518" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-55-person518" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the prisoner's hand in the till last Tuesday night; I acquainted my master with it; I heard his hand rattle among the money; he looked in my face all the time; he lifted up his apron, as if he was putting something in his pocket; I found the shilling in his coat pocket; I did not see my master mark it; I did see the box opened, and found the buckles at the bottom of the box.</p>
               <p>Q. From prisoner. Was that it I took out of the drawer?</p>
               <p>Webb. I cannot tell; but I did see you rattle among the money, and put your hand to your pocket.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-55-person519">
                  William 
                  Gough 
               <interp inst="t17631207-55-person519" type="surname" value="Gough"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-55-person519" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-55-person519" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have seen him at the till several times. When I have been writing in the counting house, I have turned round and seen him at the drawer, but could not tell what he took. I saw the silver put into the till, and knew the buckles to be my master's property.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>A customer bought 2000 nails, that came to 7 s. I gave change for half a guinea, and took the silver out of the drawer. I have lived at four good places in town, and never had any thing amiss laid to my charge; I have been entrusted with 2000 l. a day: I have had these buckles by me four or five years.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-55-person520">
                  John 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17631207-55-person520" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-55-person520" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-55-person520" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Nicholas-lane, Lombard-street. I have known the prisoner ten years; when I first knew him, he lived with Mr. Blackden, the ironmonger, and I have known him live at several places; he always bore a good character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-55-person521">
                  John 
                  Pagett 
               <interp inst="t17631207-55-person521" type="surname" value="Pagett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-55-person521" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-55-person521" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him eight years; I was apprentice at Mr. 
               <persName id="t17631207-55-person522">
                  Joseph 
                  Blackden 
               <interp inst="t17631207-55-person522" type="surname" value="Blackden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-55-person522" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-55-person522" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's; the prisoner, porter, always bore a very good character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-55-person523">
                  John 
                  Hayward 
               <interp inst="t17631207-55-person523" type="surname" value="Hayward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-55-person523" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-55-person523" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Mr. Morgan's, ironmonger, in the Borough; I was apprentice at Mr. Blackden's, when he lived there; Mr. Blackden had a great regard for him; he bore a good character in the house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-55-person524">
                  James 
                  Hindmass 
               <interp inst="t17631207-55-person524" type="surname" value="Hindmass"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-55-person524" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-55-person524" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a shoemaker, and live in New-street, Bishopsgate-street: I have known him upwards of ten years; he has dealt with me nine years; he paid me honestly; his general character is that of an honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-55-person525">
                  John 
                  Scott 
               <interp inst="t17631207-55-person525" type="surname" value="Scott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-55-person525" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-55-person525" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Great East-cheap, Cannon-street, and keep a chandler's shop: I have known the prisoner ten or eleven years; I never heard any thing bad of him before.</p>
               <p>Foreman of the jury. I myself have known the prisoner many years, and always heard a good character of him.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17631207-55-verdict303" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631207-55-verdict303" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
