<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680114-24">
               <interp inst="t17680114-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680114-24" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680114-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680114"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680114-24" type="date" value="17680114"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680114-24-off148-c242" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-24-defend293 t17680114-24-off148 t17680114-24-verdict152"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680114-24-off148-c243" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-24-defend295 t17680114-24-off148 t17680114-24-verdict152"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680114-24-off148-c244" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-24-defend297 t17680114-24-off148 t17680114-24-verdict152"></join>
         
               <p>128, 129, 130. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17680114-24-defend293" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Anthony 
                  <interp inst="t17680114-24-defend293" type="surname" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-24-defend293" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-24-defend293" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17680114-24-defend295" type="defendantName">
                     Anne 
                     Claxton 
                  <interp inst="t17680114-24-defend295" type="surname" value="Claxton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-24-defend295" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-24-defend295" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17680114-24-defend297" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Dollanson 
                  <interp inst="t17680114-24-defend297" type="surname" value="Dollanson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-24-defend297" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-24-defend297" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17680114-24-off148" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680114-24-off148" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-24-off148" type="offenceSubcategory" value="shoplifting"></interp>
               stealing seven pair of silk stockings, value 3 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17680114-24-victim299" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Shannon 
                        <interp inst="t17680114-24-victim299" type="surname" value="Shannon"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680114-24-victim299" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680114-24-victim299" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-24-off148 t17680114-24-victim299"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately in the shop of the said James
            </rs>, <rs id="t17680114-24-cd149" type="crimeDate">Dec. 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-24-off148 t17680114-24-cd149"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>The evidences were examined apart.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-24-person300">
                  James 
                  Shannon 
               <interp inst="t17680114-24-person300" type="surname" value="Shannon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-24-person300" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-24-person300" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17680114-24-viclabel150" type="occupation">hosier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-24-victim299 t17680114-24-viclabel150"></join>, and live in <placeName id="t17680114-24-crimeloc151">Smithfield</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17680114-24-crimeloc151" type="placeName" value="Smithfield"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17680114-24-crimeloc151" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-24-off148 t17680114-24-crimeloc151"></join>; on Saturday the 12th of December I was in my back room behind my shop, the two women at the bar came into the shop to my young men; I observed through the glass, 
               <persName id="t17680114-24-person301">
                  Anne 
                  Claxton 
               <interp inst="t17680114-24-person301" type="surname" value="Claxton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-24-person301" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-24-person301" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             looked very sharp at some silk stockings; I came to the middle of the shop, and pulled out my watch, and told my young man it was half an hour past seven, and I would go to the butcher's to buy some meat; 
               <persName id="t17680114-24-person302">
                  Mary 
                  Anthony 
               <interp inst="t17680114-24-person302" type="surname" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-24-person302" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-24-person302" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             asked for a pair of stockings with red clocks; my young man pulled down a parcel; having lost some goods on the 28th of November, I was very desirous to set some of these thieves, for if we make a show in our windows, these people will take them away; I signified by my words that he might have a sharp look out; I went on the outside the door, and there saw 
               <persName id="t17680114-24-person303">
                  James 
                  Dollanson 
               <interp inst="t17680114-24-person303" type="surname" value="Dollanson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-24-person303" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-24-person303" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             standing facing the door, about a step or two from it; I saw this parcel of silk stockings in the window, when I was on the outside the door, among other goods; I had before tied a string to the parcel, and the other end of the string I had fastened to the bolt that fastens down into the threshold of the door; Dollanson turned to the right, and I to the left; I looked back, and saw him come to his former standing by my door; I went still farther, because I saw him look after me, till I went to the corner of Cloth-fair, then a woman met me, and I crept behind her till within two doors of my own shop; then I saw Dollanson creep down towards my door, he took up this parcel in his hand; then I made towards him, I saw him put the parcel under his arm, and make towards me about four steps; when I saw my property invaded, I made towards him; I observed he either turned round to see what stopped him, or the cord turned him round, I know not which, but he turned round; he was got the length of the cord, I took hold of him; then the parcel sell from him towards the wall; the parcel, containing seven pair of silk stockings (produced in court, tied up with a cord about four yards long fastened to it;) it is in the same condition now as it was then; I craved the woman's assistance, she was big with child and gave me none; my young man missing the goods came to the door; he and a carpenter assisted me in bringing him in; the cord was still fastened at the other end at the bolt.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-24-person304">
                  Patrick 
                  Shannon 
               <interp inst="t17680114-24-person304" type="surname" value="Shannon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-24-person304" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-24-person304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My master left me in the shop between seven and eight that night; the two women at the bar came in, I shut the door after them; 
               <persName id="t17680114-24-person305">
                  Mary 
                  Anthony 
               <interp inst="t17680114-24-person305" type="surname" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-24-person305" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-24-person305" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             asked for a pair of blue stockings with scarlet clocks; Mr. Shannon came into the shop, and pulled out his watch, and said he would go to the butcher's; he went out and left the door half open; just as he went out 
               <persName id="t17680114-24-person306">
                  Anne 
                  Claxton 
               <interp inst="t17680114-24-person306" type="surname" value="Claxton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-24-person306" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-24-person306" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             stood by the window, and leaned over; Anthony was looking at the stockings, and seemed to find fault with the colour, she wanted more goods to be pulled down; I looked towards the window; Claxton was between me and the parcel, so I bid her go and shut the door, that the wind might not come in; then I missed the parcel of stockings from the window; I then went to the door, and saw Mr. Shannon and a carpenter struggling with the man at the bar, by the door; we got him in; then the carpenter went and fetched the parcel in: when Dollanson was in the shop, he seemed not to know the women, and Claxton said she did not know him; Anthony looked like as if she was frighted; Claxton said to her, what are you afraid of.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-24-person307">
                  Samuel 
                  Carrol 
               <interp inst="t17680114-24-person307" type="surname" value="Carrol"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-24-person307" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-24-person307" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 12th of December, between seven and eight in the evening, I was behind my counter, and heard a noise at the window; I went towards the window, in about a minute there was screaming out, as if murder was committing; I ran to the door; there was Dollanson, and the two women at the bar, in company; Dollanson was using another woman ill; this I mention, only to prove the three prisoners were no strangers to each another.</p>
               <p>The string connecting the parcel in the position the owner of the parcel had fastened it; had the string broke, or been separated but an inch, it would have been a felony; this was a felony began but not compleated, they were all three <rs id="t17680114-24-verdict152" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680114-24-verdict152" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>This contrivance may be improved in the following manner; place a small weight of lead, with an upright pin, about an inch long on the top, upon the end of a shelf; let a loop at the end of the string be put over the upright pin, which will disengage itself as she lead falls, which fall may either disturb a tell, or full upon any thing that will alarm.</p>
            </div1>
