<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670429-47">
               <interp inst="t17670429-47" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670429-47" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670429-47" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670429"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670429-47" type="date" value="17670429"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670429-47-off259-c309" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-47-defend409 t17670429-47-off259 t17670429-47-verdict261"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670429-47-off259-c310" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-47-defend411 t17670429-47-off259 t17670429-47-verdict261"></join>
         
               <p>242, 243. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17670429-47-defend409" type="defendantName">
                     Samuel 
                     Knock 
                  <interp inst="t17670429-47-defend409" type="surname" value="Knock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-defend409" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-defend409" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17670429-47-defend411" type="defendantName">
                     Jacob 
                     Wood 
                  <interp inst="t17670429-47-defend411" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-defend411" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-defend411" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted, for that <rs id="t17670429-47-off259" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-off259" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-off259" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               they on the 19th of April, about the hour of one in the night, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17670429-47-victim413" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Warren 
                        <interp inst="t17670429-47-victim413" type="surname" value="Warren"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670429-47-victim413" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670429-47-victim413" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-47-off259 t17670429-47-victim413"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17670429-47-viclabel260" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-47-victim413 t17670429-47-viclabel260"></join>; did break and enter, and stealing four-silver spoons, value 10 s. three silver tops for castors, value 2 s. a silver frame for a picture, value 1 s. a silver cream-pot, a silver pepper-box, and divers other goods, the property of the said John, in his dwelling-house
            </rs>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-47-person414">
                  Hannah 
                  Warren 
               <interp inst="t17670429-47-person414" type="surname" value="Warren"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-person414" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-person414" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the prosecutor. The day before Easter Monday at night, my house was made very secure; we went to bed at twelve o'clock. I ordered my maid to get up very early in the morning; she did, and came very abruptly to my door and said, madam, we are broke open, for the bureau is broke; I started up out of my sleep and jumped out of bed, and down stairs I went, and found the bureau was out open and the lock forced, and the bureau risted; we found a place where they had endeavoured to get in, which was a glass door that comes into the garden; but it being a double door, they could not get in there; they had thrown up all the sashes in the parlour, and strove much to get in there, by loosening some of the hinges, but cou ld not get in there; they took off one bar of a window in the garden, and got through. I had a very strong look upon the laundry or dairy-door, they had broke that entirely off; after they had done that, I apprehend they took several things in the kitchen, some of my servant maids silver buckles, and other things; they broke a lock in the parlour, and forced a bolt, and broke my husband's bureau, they broke two or three locks; they broke another lock, and took out a ewer not silver it was French plate; they took three tops to castors, a silver milk-pot, four silver spoons, a silver pepper-box, a silver candlestick gilt with gold. There was a stick found at the bottom of the stairs, which was not there when we went to bed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-47-person415">
                  John 
                  Meridin 
               <interp inst="t17670429-47-person415" type="surname" value="Meridin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-person415" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-person415" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable for the hamlet of Hammersmith. On Monday the 20th instant, Capt. Dagan came to my house, there were some plate found in his hay-loft; he begged of me to come to his house about ten in the evening, saying, by that time he believed his servant, whom he suspected, would be at home; he suspected him, and another that kept company with him. I went about ten o'clock, and rang at the bell: his servant, 
               <persName id="t17670429-47-person416">
                  Jacob 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17670429-47-person416" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-person416" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-person416" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , let me in; I asked him if his master was at home, and told him I should be glad to speak with him; I went into the parlour, and said, Mr. Dagan, I have made hold to wait upon you; he immediately said, that is the man; then I turned to Wood, and said, you are my prisoner; the captain came out, and said, you must pull off your cloaths; the prisoner did. I asked the prisoner, if he had not got a confederate in these things that had been found; he said, he had given leave to 
               <persName id="t17670429-47-person417">
                  Samuel 
                  Knock 
               <interp inst="t17670429-47-person417" type="surname" value="Knock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-person417" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-person417" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to lye in his master's hay-loft; I said, if you don't take care he'll hang you, for I am afraid he is a very wicked person. I asked him if he could tell me where 
               <persName id="t17670429-47-person418">
                  Samuel 
                  Knock 
               <interp inst="t17670429-47-person418" type="surname" value="Knock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-person418" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-person418" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was; he said he could not tell, and refused telling me; but said, he believed he was gone to see his mother in St. Giles's workhouse; said I, if you will not tell the truth you must suffer; he said, he might come by ten o'clock the next morning. Then I took him to my house; there were two or three young men came into the parlour, they pressed him to tell me where Knock was; he would not: then I said, have you a mind to tell any of these men; he said he would speak to a young fellow there; then I took all the rest out; then he said, if I went with him and the young fellow to the Dove coffee-house, and the young man go in and call Sam, he would come to him, and I might take him; then I called in assistance to take care of him, and took a candle and lanthorn, and went to go to the coffee-house; I met Knock, I catched him by the collar, and said, where are you going at this time of night; he said he was going to my house; I said, I have got a warrant against you; there is some little difference between Mr. Dagan's servant and you, I would advise you to go and make it up; he went very quietly to my house; we sat up with them all night, and in the morning Knock asked me to let him go to the vault; I went to the door with him, he was in some time; when he came out, I took him into the parlour again; in the mean time a man wanted to go the vault; he came in again, and said there are some of your pots in the vault; the maid went to see, she came, and said there were some plate there; I went and had it taken out of the vault; there were a silver pepper-box, a silver cream-jug, a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176704290025"></xptr> china snuff-box, enamelled or studded with gold, and a smelling-bottle; I washed them clean, and desired the people not to say any thing of them; then we went in, and with a cord pinioned the two prisoners together; out of Wood's pocket I took two silver spoons, two silver tops of cannisters, two medals, one in a case, the other out; I told them it looked very bad; then I went for the remainder of the things that were found in Capt. Dagan's hay-loft: I had by chance heard thatMr. Warren's house was broke open. I immediately sent 
               <persName id="t17670429-47-person419">
                  William 
                  Bradshaw 
               <interp inst="t17670429-47-person419" type="surname" value="Bradshaw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-person419" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-person419" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the bricklayer, that took the things out of the vault, to let Mr. Warren know what we had found, and for him to come and see if they were his. Mrs. Warren came, and seeing one of the things in my hand, said she would swear that was her property. I said, do not be frighted, the men are safe enough; then I shewed her the other things (produced and deposed to by Mrs. Warren.) We took the prisoners before Sir 
               <persName id="t17670429-47-person420">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17670429-47-person420" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-person420" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-person420" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and he committed them. Knock said, before the Justice, he did not throw the things down the vault, but they dropped out of his pocket. Going along Hyde Park, Wood said, I'll be d - d if I divulge any thing. I was told that Knock said he had found a guinea, which appeared to be a gold medal; I asked Wood about it, he owned he had been to three different men in Hammersmith to have it changed.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Warren. I at the same time a diamond ring, which cost 50 l.</p>
               <p>Meridin. There was a diamond ring advertised; I and the attorney went to Lombard-street about it; I told the woman I had taken two men that had stole a diamond ring; she said it was brought by two men, one a gentleman's servant, the other a mean looking man, who said they found it near the Mansion-house; I came back and called upon Wood, and asked him if he remembered any thing about a diamond ring; he said he did, but did not know where it was. I said, knock will be hanged, and you will share the same sate if you do not tell the truth. He owned he was near Lombard-street, but not in it, that day. I said, do you remember you told the people you found it near the Mansion-house; he said he remembered Sam said so. (The ring produced, and deposed to by Mrs. Warren.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-47-person421">
                  John 
                  Bluck 
               <interp inst="t17670429-47-person421" type="surname" value="Bluck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-person421" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-person421" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am coachman to Mr. Warren; on Friday the 17th instant, Wood came to my master's, and asked me to go and drink a pint of beer with him; I said I would go with him, but could not stay; he seeing Knock, said, Sam, bring a piece of pudding; I said, what Sam is that; he said, Knock; he said he and Knock had been taking a walk together. We went to the George and drank; he cut the pudding in three parts, and we each had some. Knock said, do you live with Mr. Warren; I said, yes: said he, I lived at the same house once; we had fowls stole while I lived there; they kept a great dog then, do you keep one now; I said, yes, two; said Wood, where do you keep them; I said, in the stable-yard; Knock said, it is a d - d strong house of your's; at the same time the landlord said, there is a d - d great stink amongst you; Wood had a rotten egg broke in his pocket. We went out, and when at the door, Knock shook hands with me, and asked me if I went with my master on the morrow to Newmarket; I said I did; he wished me a good journey, and we parted.</p>
               <p>Knock's defence.</p>
               <p>On that Sunday morning 
               <persName id="t17670429-47-person422">
                  Jacob 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17670429-47-person422" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-person422" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-person422" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and I were together; I lay in his hay-loft, being just come out of the workhouse, very bad of an ague and sever; he locked me in, and let me out about six; then we went to Mr. Murphy's, and had two pots of beer; it was a fine morning; I walked out; I went to ease myself by a malt-kiln; there I saw a cane lying, and a bag, and a coffee-pot, and other things tied up in a handkerchief; I brought them away; I came back to Wood between eight and nine; we opened the bag, there were these things.</p>
               <p>Wood's defence.</p>
               <p>Knock lay in our hay-loft; he went out about six, and returned about nine with these things. Please to ask Esquire Dagan my character.</p>
               <p>Mr. Dagan. I have been informed Wood has frequently got out of bed unknown to me; particularly on the 9th of April he went with a waterman down to St. Paul's wharf, and there landed at two in the morning; and he has been at home at Hammersmith again by morning, and had the horse and chaise ready for me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-47-person423">
                  Susanna 
                  Tanner 
               <interp inst="t17670429-47-person423" type="surname" value="Tanner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-person423" type="given" value="Susanna"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-person423" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17670429-47-person424">
                  Anne 
                  Rivers 
               <interp inst="t17670429-47-person424" type="surname" value="Rivers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-person424" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-person424" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , two of Mr. Dagan's servants, confirmed the account of his going out on nights, and other bad behaviour.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17670429-47-verdict261" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-verdict261" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17670429-47-punish262" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670429-47-punish262" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-47-defend409 t17670429-47-punish262"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-47-defend411 t17670429-47-punish262"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
