<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17671021-40">
               <interp inst="t17671021-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17671021-40" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17671021-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17671021"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17671021-40" type="date" value="17671021"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17671021-40-off200-c282" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-40-defend367 t17671021-40-off200 t17671021-40-verdict205"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17671021-40-off201-c284" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-40-defend372 t17671021-40-off201 t17671021-40-verdict207"></join>
         
               <p>566, 567. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17671021-40-defend367" type="defendantName">
                  
                     John 
                     Brass 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17671021-40-alias-2" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-40-defend367 t17671021-40-alias-2"></join>Cade</rs>, otherwise <rs id="t17671021-40-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-40-defend367 t17671021-40-alias-3"></join>Masters</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-defend367" type="surname" value="Brass"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-defend367" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-defend367" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted, for <rs id="t17671021-40-off200" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-off200" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-off200" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               that he, in the dwelling house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17671021-40-victim370" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Hubbard 
                        <interp inst="t17671021-40-victim370" type="surname" value="Hubbard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671021-40-victim370" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671021-40-victim370" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , did make an assault on her the said Mary, putting her in corporal fear and danger of her life, and violently taking from her person a silver watch, value 40 s. a thirty-six shilling piece, a moidore, seven guineas, and five shillings in money numbered, her property
            </rs>; and 
               
                  <persName id="t17671021-40-defend372" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Murphy 
                  <interp inst="t17671021-40-defend372" type="surname" value="Murphy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-defend372" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-defend372" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             for <rs id="t17671021-40-off201" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-off201" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-off201" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving the watch, well knowing it to have been stolen
            </rs>, <rs id="t17671021-40-cd202" type="crimeDate">Sept. 25</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-40-off200 t17671021-40-cd202"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-40-off201 t17671021-40-cd202"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-40-person373">
                  Mary 
                  Hubbard 
               <interp inst="t17671021-40-person373" type="surname" value="Hubbard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-person373" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-person373" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17671021-40-crimeloc203">Chiswell-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17671021-40-crimeloc203" type="placeName" value="Chiswell-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17671021-40-crimeloc203" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-40-off200 t17671021-40-crimeloc203"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-40-off201 t17671021-40-crimeloc203"></join>, and am a <rs id="t17671021-40-viclabel204" type="occupation">pawnbroker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-40-victim370 t17671021-40-viclabel204"></join>; on the 25th of September, about nine at night, my street-door was shut; my maid, 
               <persName id="t17671021-40-person374">
                  Anne 
                  Rimmington 
               <interp inst="t17671021-40-person374" type="surname" value="Rimmington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-person374" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-person374" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , went and opened it; the prisoner came in with a handkerchief in his hand, and asked a groat upon it; I was sitting in a little room; my maid came in with the handkerchief, and was going to show it me; he followed her, and put a pistol over her shoulder, and said to me, make no resistance, your watch and your money; my maid turned round, and clapped her hand upon the pistol, and drove him back into the shop; I got up and followed; then the evidence was standing holding the street door.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his name?</p>
               <p>M. Hubbard. His name is 
               <persName id="t17671021-40-person375">
                  William 
                  Guy 
               <interp inst="t17671021-40-person375" type="surname" value="Guy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-person375" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-person375" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I found I could not make any resistance; the prisoner said to the maid, let go; she said, for God's sake, do not let the pistol off, do not kill my mistress; Guy at the door said, if she does not let the pistol go, blow her brains out: the prisoner<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176710210020"></xptr> then wrenched the pistol out of my maid's hands, and turned round to me (I was got behind the counter;) he presented the pistol to my head, and said, give me your watch and your purse; I said, I carry no watch; then, said he, give me your money; I took out of my pocket a thirty-six shilling piece, a moidore, and about three guineas; he then said, give me your watch; I took it out of my pocket, and gave it him, a silver watch, with box and case in one; then he put his hand over the counter, and said, give me your pocket; then I put my hand in my pocket again, and took out some more money, and threw it at him, and said, there is all; then he put his hand over, and said, open the till; I said, I have no till; he put his hand to it, and found it was a large drawer, then they both ran away.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain to the prisoner?</p>
               <p>M. Hubbard. I believe the prisoner to be the man.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he dressed?</p>
               <p>M. Hubbard. He had a handkerchief tied over his nose, it did not reach over his eyes, nor down to his chin; I think I can take upon me to say he is the real person.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-40-person376">
                  Anne 
                  Rimmington 
               <interp inst="t17671021-40-person376" type="surname" value="Rimmington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-person376" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-person376" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mrs. Hubbard; the prisoner knocked at the door about the time my mistress has mentioned, I opened it; he said he wanted to pledge his handkerchief; I seeing a handkerchief tied over his nose, asked him how he came to be disguised; he said he had a sore nose; I went to my mistress, and he followed me, and clapped a pistol over my right shoulder, and said to my mistress, your watch and your money; I turned round, and clapped hold of the pistol, and pushed him out of that room into the shop, and struggled with him some time; he said let it go, I will not hurt you; he got it away; then he went to my mistress, as she was behind the counter, and said, your watch and your money; she gave him first silver, then gold; then he asked for her watch again; she gave him a silver watch; then he not being contented wanted more money; then she gave him gold again, then he wanted more; she then took out some, and said, here, take all; then he wanted to see the till, and put his hand over, and found it a large drawer, then they went out.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure it was the prisoner?</p>
               <p>A. Rimmington. I am very positive of it that he is the man, I looked very much in his face.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. She would not swear to me till the evidence was sworn before the Justice.</p>
               <p>A. Rimmington. When I went in I looked at 
               <persName id="t17671021-40-person377">
                  William 
                  Guy 
               <interp inst="t17671021-40-person377" type="surname" value="Guy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-person377" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-person377" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and said, that is the man that was at the door, I believed, and I looked at the prisoner, and said, this is the man that robbed my mistress, he had a handkerchief tied cross his nose when he robbed her.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he dressed when he robbed your mistress?</p>
               <p>A. Rimmington. He had a brown wig on, and a flapt hat, and I perceived he had short hair under his wig *.</p>
               <p>* The prisoner, when at the bar, had no wig on, but his own short hair.</p>
         
               <p>*** The last Part of these Proceedings will be Published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17671021-40">
                  <interp inst="t17671021-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17671021-40" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17671021-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17671021"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17671021-40" type="date" value="17671021"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176710210021"></xptr>THE WHOLE PROCEEDINGS ON THE KING's COMMISSIONS of the PEACE, OYER and TERMINER, and GOAL DELIVERY FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the GOAL DELIVERY FOR THE COUNTY of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 21st, Thursday the 22 d, and Friday the 23d, of OCTOBER,</p>
                  <p>In the Seventh Year of His MAJESTY's Reign. Being the Eighth SESSIONS in the MAYORALITY of THE RIGHT HONOURABLE SIR 
                  <persName id="t17671021-40-person378">
                     ROBERT 
                     KITE 
                  <interp inst="t17671021-40-person378" type="surname" value="KITE"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671021-40-person378" type="given" value="ROBERT"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671021-40-person378" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , KNT. LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>LONDON,</p>
                  <p>Printed for J. WILKIE, at the Bible, in St. Paul's Church-Yard.</p>
                  <p>[Price Six-Pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176710210022"></xptr>THE WHOLE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Goal Delivery held for the City of LONDON, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Continuation of the Trial of 
               <persName id="t17671021-40-person379">
                  John 
                  Brass 
               <interp inst="t17671021-40-person379" type="surname" value="Brass"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-person379" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-person379" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-40-person380">
                  William 
                  Guy 
               <interp inst="t17671021-40-person380" type="surname" value="Guy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-person380" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-person380" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>ON the 25th of September I went to Shadwell to ask for work; coming through Wingfield street, at the sign of the Sun, Whitechapel, I heard a tap at the window; I went in, there was the prisoner 
               <persName id="t17671021-40-person381">
                  John 
                  Brass 
               <interp inst="t17671021-40-person381" type="surname" value="Brass"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-person381" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-person381" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I said, are you going to sea; he said, I do not know whether I am or not; they have made a sailor of me, but I will have another suit of clothes before Saturday night; I said, how; said he, I know where to make something to night; I sat down and drank a pint of beer with him; then we went to the Skettle-ground; then he told me of this pawnbroker's house, in Chiswell-street; he said, she wore a purse, and a watch, and has some gold rings, and he would have them; we went to go there, but was rather too soon to go there; then he said we will go and get 2 or 3 s. in picking of pockets; we went and got as many as came to 8 s. in handkerchiefs; we carried them to the prisoner Murphy, and his wife paid me for them; then we said it was too soon, so we staid till about a quarter before nine; then we went to Chiswell-street, and went by the window two or three times; then we slept over to the horse-ride; there I pulled off my coat, a blue one, with brass buttons, and put on his flannel waistcoat, and he put on a brown wig and my coat; then he went to the door, and went in; I held the street door; he went in and demanded her money, and after that came out again, and said, I have got it, and we ran away into Pickax-street; he showed me what money he had, and by all accounts he cheated me out of five guineas; we did the robbery on the Friday night, and on the Sunday in the forenoon I carried it to Mr. Murphy's, the other prisoner at the bar; I asked his wife if she would see it; she called her husband; he asked me how I came by it; I said, we had been robbing a woman of some money, and that watch; he asked what I would have for it; I said, a guinea and a half; at last I came to 27 s. he desired us to call in the afternoon; when I called, he said he could not give us any more than a guinea; then I went to Brass, and told him what Murphy had said; and he said, then let him have it; I went on the Monday, and his wife gave me the guinea.</p>
               <p>Murphy. I never saw this evidence in my life before.</p>
               <p>Guy. I have sold Murphy many a dozen of handkerchiefs.</p>
               <p>Q. How old are you?</p>
               <p>Guy. I am twenty-two years of age, the 3 d of March.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you expect to come to?</p>
               <p>Guy. I hope to get an honest livelihood.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671021-40-person382">
                  James 
                  Brebrook 
               <interp inst="t17671021-40-person382" type="surname" value="Brebrook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-person382" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-person382" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . A man came and told me there was an advertisement of Mrs. Hubbard, a pawnbroker in Chiswell-street, being robbed; he said to me, go directly away, and I should see the person that did it, playing at skettles, at the Sun in Wingfield-street, Whitechapel; I went, and there took the evidence and prisoner, and carried them before Sir 
               <persName id="t17671021-40-person383">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17671021-40-person383" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-person383" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-person383" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Brebrook. This was about a fortnight ago.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutrix. Was the watch ever found?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. No, it never was.</p>
               <p>Guy. Murphy said he would take care that the watch should never come to light.</p>
               <p>Brass's defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing at all of the matter, I never was concerned in such a thing in my life; I was at Chatham at the time of this robbery, on board<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176710210023"></xptr> she Squirrel; I came up on the Monday, and was taken up on the Wednesday; the evidence treated the thief catchers with a bottle of wine, so got himself admitted evidence, and I had no money to treat them with.</p>
               <p>Brass <rs id="t17671021-40-verdict205" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-verdict205" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17671021-40-punish206" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-punish206" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671021-40-defend367 t17671021-40-punish206"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Murphy <rs id="t17671021-40-verdict207" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-verdict207" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>See Brass tried three separate times for picking pockets, No 450 in Mr. Alderman Beckford's, No 222 in Mr. Alderman Blakiston's and No 132 in Sir Richard Glyn's Mayoralty.</p>
               <p>See 
               <persName id="t17671021-40-person384">
                  William 
                  Guy 
               <interp inst="t17671021-40-person384" type="surname" value="Guy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-person384" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671021-40-person384" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             tried for picking a pocket, No 99, 154, in this Mayorality.</p>
            </div1>
