<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650522-34">
               <interp inst="t17650522-34" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-34" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-34" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650522"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-34" type="date" value="17650522"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650522-34-off226-c356" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-34-defend430 t17650522-34-off226 t17650522-34-verdict229"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650522-34-off226-c357" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-34-defend432 t17650522-34-off226 t17650522-34-verdict229"></join>
         
               <p>333, 334. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17650522-34-defend430" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Brian 
                  <interp inst="t17650522-34-defend430" type="surname" value="Brian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-34-defend430" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-34-defend430" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17650522-34-defend432" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Purser 
                  <interp inst="t17650522-34-defend432" type="surname" value="Purser"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-34-defend432" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-34-defend432" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted for <rs id="t17650522-34-off226" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-34-off226" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-34-off226" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a hat, value 5 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17650522-34-victim434" type="victimName">
                     Christopher 
                     Sadgrove 
                  <interp inst="t17650522-34-victim434" type="surname" value="Sadgrove"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-34-victim434" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-34-victim434" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-34-off226 t17650522-34-victim434"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17650522-34-cd227" type="crimeDate">May 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-34-off226 t17650522-34-cd227"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-34-person435">
                  Christopher 
                  Sadgrove 
               <interp inst="t17650522-34-person435" type="surname" value="Sadgrove"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-34-person435" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-34-person435" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live upon Saffron-hill, with Mr. Morris: on the 10th of May, between eight and nine in the evening, I and my brother were coming up <placeName id="t17650522-34-crimeloc228">Field-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17650522-34-crimeloc228" type="placeName" value="Field-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17650522-34-crimeloc228" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-34-off226 t17650522-34-crimeloc228"></join>; I was before him; there came the prisoners and another man; I had said nothing to them; the other man hit me over the head with a stick; Brian ran after me, and swore he would kill me; the other two followed him; I ran in at the sign of the Naked Boy, a sale-shop; they all followed me into the house; Brian kept beating me for about five minutes; I had my hands before my face; how my hat went, I cannot tell; I lost it there; the man and woman of the house were at home; the man of the house laid hold of Brian, but could not stop him; after that, my brother, who was at the door, and I, ran away home.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-34-person436">
                  Thomas 
                  Knowles 
               <interp inst="t17650522-34-person436" type="surname" value="Knowles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-34-person436" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-34-person436" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a clothes shop in Chick-lane; Brian pursued the boy into my house; the boy cried, For God's sake, don't let the man kill me; I saw him strike the boy two blows; I can't say I saw which way the hat went; the three men went out directly after the boy went out.</p>
               <p>Mr. Morris. The boy came crying home, and said he had been almost murder'd and rob'd; some of my neighbours told me they had seen the prisoners go in at the Harrow in Fleet-market. I sent the boy in first, to see if the man was there that us'd him ill; he came out again, and said he was there, and the other that first struck him: I went in, and said, Have you rob'd this lad of a hat? the house was entirely against me: there came two or three hundred people about us, as these fellows had followed the lad almost to my door. Brian was for getting away: I got hold of him: the landlord of the house used me vastly ill. Brian pulled out this knife; (producing one) he cut my coat, and got away, and ran down the middle of the market: I took him at the end of Turn-again-lane: then he denied having a knife, but the constable took it away from him: after that he told us where the other men were to be found.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176505220039"></xptr> When before the Justice, he said Purser had the hat: Purser was there; he said he knew nothing of it; but after it was found at Purser's, then Purser said Brian must have come and put it there while he was asleep.</p>
               <p>Sutton Isaac. I am headborough. About eleven o'clock that night, Brian was brought to me by Mr. Morris. I was oblig'd to tie him in the watch-house he was so unruly: in going along, he told me, If I would let him have a hearing before Justice Girdler, he would inform him of something; and if I went down Thatch'd Alley, I should find Purser and one Lunt, that were in company with him when the hat was taken. I found that was in the city. I went and took 
               <persName id="t17650522-34-person437">
                  Joseph 
                  Hunt 
               <interp inst="t17650522-34-person437" type="surname" value="Hunt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-34-person437" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-34-person437" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a city constable, with me; there we found Purser and the hat. (Produced in court, and deposed to.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-34-person438">
                  Joseph 
                  Hunt 
               <interp inst="t17650522-34-person438" type="surname" value="Hunt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-34-person438" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-34-person438" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed to that of being at the taking of Purser in Thatch'd Alley, and finding the hat in his apartment.</p>
               <p>Brian's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was upon Saffron-hill and met one Lunt; we had three or four pots of Beer; when we came to the lower end of the place, I missed my handkerchief; Lunt made a blow at this boy: he ran away, and I pursued him into this man's house: I never saw any thing of the hat.</p>
               <p>Morris. Brian told me he had not lost his handkerchief.</p>
               <p>Purser's Defence.</p>
               <p>Coming down Saffron-hill, I met Brian and Lunt together; they asked me to go and drink; we went and had three pots of beer, then I went home and met an unfortunate woman; she took me home to bed with her.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17650522-34-verdict229" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-34-verdict229" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17650522-34-punish230" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-34-punish230" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-34-defend430 t17650522-34-punish230"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-34-defend432 t17650522-34-punish230"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
