<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17661217-17">
               <interp inst="t17661217-17" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-17" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-17" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17661217"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-17" type="date" value="17661217"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17661217-17-off90-c126" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-17-defend165 t17661217-17-off90 t17661217-17-verdict92"></join>
         
               <p>23. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17661217-17-defend165" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Trout 
                  <interp inst="t17661217-17-defend165" type="surname" value="Trout"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-defend165" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-defend165" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17661217-17-off90" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-off90" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-off90" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a 36 s. piece, 2 moidores, 21 guineas, 8 half guineas, 2 quarter guineas, and a crown piece, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17661217-17-victim167" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Reed 
                        <interp inst="t17661217-17-victim167" type="surname" value="Reed"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17661217-17-victim167" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17661217-17-victim167" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-17-off90 t17661217-17-victim167"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling-house of 
                     <persName id="t17661217-17-person168">
                        John 
                        Turner 
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-person168" type="surname" value="Turner"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17661217-17-person168" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17661217-17-person168" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, Oct. 16. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-17-person169">
                  John 
                  Reed 
               <interp inst="t17661217-17-person169" type="surname" value="Reed"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-person169" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-person169" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have been a <rs id="t17661217-17-viclabel91" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-17-victim167 t17661217-17-viclabel91"></join> all my lifetime. On the 16th of October, about eleven in the morning, I met a man named 
               <persName id="t17661217-17-person170">
                  James 
                  Gawler 
               <interp inst="t17661217-17-person170" type="surname" value="Gawler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-person170" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-person170" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in Holbourn; he pretended to be a countryman of mine; he asked me where I came from; I said, from Newbury; he asked me if I knew such a man at Spinham-land; I said I did; then we went and drank together; he took me from one house to another, not liking this and the other house; in the last house but one we met with Trout and Manwaring; then we went to the Shoulder of Mutton and White Hart in Brooks-market; in discourse Manwaring said, you countrymen, you cannot all of you produce so much as 40 l. he pulled out a purse of what I thought to be guineas, and said he was just come from the East-Indies; he said he had received 150 guineas, and should receive 300 more; a wager was soon laid, of half a guinea, that amongst us we could not produce 40 l. the prisoner took me by the shoulder, and said, what money have you?</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know him before?</p>
               <p>Reed. No, I never saw either of them before the prisoner said he had six or seven guineas, and if you can raise any, Gawler can make it up; I went to fetch mine from my lodgings, and Gawler went with me; I produced 31 l. 15 s. 6 d. there was a 36 s. piece, 2 moidores, 21 guineas, 8 half guineas, 2 quarter guineas, and a crown piece; after it was told upon the table, the prisoner said, that is enough, he will yield the wager lost.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner or Gawler produce any money?</p>
               <p>Reed. No, they did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was this?</p>
               <p>Reed. This was about two in the afternoon; while my money was on the table, I went out to make water, and when I came in again, my money and they were all gone.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you stay abroad?</p>
               <p>Reed. I did not stay out above three or four minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober?</p>
               <p>Reed. I cannot say that I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any body else in that room?</p>
               <p>Reed. No, there were only us four; then I went out, and sat in a shoemaker's stall, after the landlady told me the liquor was paid for.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you meet with the prisoner afterwards?</p>
               <p>Reed. I met him in Cheapside, on the 20th of October, about ten in the morning; he knew me, and endeavoured to shun me; I ran after him from Cheapside to St. Martin's le grand; there I took him myself, and got him to a constable; the prisoner asked me what I wanted; I said, you are one of the men that robbed me of so much money: there were some linen drapers asked me what money I had lost; I told them as I have here; I described the crown piece, by being bent a little on the edge on one side; the prisoner pulled out seven guineas, one 27 s. piece, and a crown piece, such a one as I described; I knew it to be my property; it had been my mother's, and I had carried it in my pocket ten years; (the money produced in court.) This crown piece is my property; at that time the prisoner said he never was in my company, but before Sir 
               <persName id="t17661217-17-person171">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17661217-17-person171" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-person171" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-person171" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             he owned he had been in my company: as soon as I mentioned what money I had lost, he fainted away, and fell back into a chair.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176612170012"></xptr>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not play at a game called hussel-cap, and lose 17 s.</p>
               <p>Reed. No, I do not know what that is, I never play'd for a farthing.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in at the Blue Lion?</p>
               <p>Reed. I was in at two or three houses, I do not know the signs.</p>
               <p>Q. How far did you go when you went out to make water?</p>
               <p>Reed. I turned on the left hand to a gate-way.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not sleep in the cobler's stall?</p>
               <p>Reed. I might, for about an hour; I believe I had missed my money before I went in there.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you say to the landlady when you went into the alehouse again?</p>
               <p>Reed. I said to her, when she told me they had paid the reckoning and were gone, that I had left above 30 l. upon the table; this was the same minute I went in.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you tell her different stories?</p>
               <p>Reed. All I said was, I had lost about or above 30 l.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to go and fetch the money?</p>
               <p>Reed. Gawler took me to the door, and said, come along, you may soon fetch it; so I went for it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-17-person172">
                  John 
                  Casson 
               <interp inst="t17661217-17-person172" type="surname" value="Casson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-person172" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-person172" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prosecutor delivered the prisoner and money into my charge the 20th of October, about eleven in the morning; he gave an account he had lost 31 l. 15 s. 6 d. and described a crown piece, by saying it was a little bent on one side; such was the crown piece the prisoner produced with the seven guineas and moidore; the prisoner said, he had never seen the prosecutor before.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q Did the prosecutor always mention one sum?</p>
               <p>Casson. He never varied in that; he said he put it down on the table, and went out for about three or four minutes, and when he came in, the men were all gone, and his money too.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I leave it to my council.</p>
               <p>Court. Your council cannot speak for you; you must do that yourself, if you have any thing to say.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I know nothing at all of the money, not the least in the world.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Eliz. Turner. My husband keeps the White Hart and Shoulder of Mutton alehouse, in Brooks-market; there were four men came into our house; I really cannot say the day, it might be some time in October; they went out, I thought they all went away together; one of them came in, and said, he had lost his money; at first he said he had lost upwards of 40 l. then 35 l. then 25 l.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he drunk or sober?</p>
               <p>E. Turner. He was in liquor; he said he had laid it down on the table, and the other men had taken it.</p>
               <p>Q. What room were they in?</p>
               <p>E. Turner. They were in a little room by themselves.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you before the Justice, what did he say he lost there?</p>
               <p>E. Turner. I was; there he said he lost upwards of 30 l. 15 s. 6 d.</p>
               <p>Q. Look upon the prisoner, do you know him?</p>
               <p>E. Turner. I do not recollect him; they were all strangers to me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-17-person173">
                  John 
                  Turner 
               <interp inst="t17661217-17-person173" type="surname" value="Turner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-person173" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-person173" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am husband to the last witness; I was up in my own room at the time; I never saw any of them till the prosecutor came back to my wife; then she called me down stairs; he told me he had lost upwards of 40 l.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs. Turner. What liquor had they had?</p>
               <p>E. Turner. They had had a shilling's worth of brandy and water; they paid me as they went out.</p>
               <p>- Beckley. One day in October, about three in the afternoon, I was at work in my stall, and heard a young woman say to the prosecutor, who do you want; he said, I came out of the house, and I cannot find my way in again; she directed him; presently I heard a woman say, a man had lost his money; he came out and said to me, the men had ran away with his money; so I took him into my stall, and there he slept; I believe the first time he came out was to make water.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-17-person174">
                  William 
                  Yates 
               <interp inst="t17661217-17-person174" type="surname" value="Yates"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-person174" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-person174" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in Mr. Turner's house when the prosecutor came into the tap-room; he said he had lost 40 guineas, or upwards of 40; after that, he said 30 and upwards; and at last he came to 25.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-17-person175">
                  John 
                  Wilcox 
               <interp inst="t17661217-17-person175" type="surname" value="Wilcox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-person175" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-person175" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming through the gateway at Mr. Turner's, the man was giving an account he had been robbed; he first said three and forty guineas, then three and thirty, and thirty.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-17-person176">
                  John 
                  Read 
               <interp inst="t17661217-17-person176" type="surname" value="Read"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-person176" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-person176" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard the prosecutor say, he had lost his money in that house, 40 l. and upwards; one time he said five and thirty, and another time five and twenty.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-17-person177">
                  John 
                  Shepherd 
               <interp inst="t17661217-17-person177" type="surname" value="Shepherd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-person177" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-person177" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about four years, I believe he is a horse dealer; he always behaved well in my company: he bears the character of an honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-17-person178">
                  William 
                  Quarry 
               <interp inst="t17661217-17-person178" type="surname" value="Quarry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-person178" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-person178" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him eight or nine years; I will trust him any time with an hundred pounds; I believe him to be an honest man.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176612170013"></xptr>Geo Smith. I live in Old-street; I have known him five or six years; he bears the character of an honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-17-person179">
                  John 
                  Strong 
               <interp inst="t17661217-17-person179" type="surname" value="Strong"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-person179" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-person179" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him six or seven years; his character is that of an honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-17-person180">
                  James 
                  Barrow 
               <interp inst="t17661217-17-person180" type="surname" value="Barrow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-person180" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-person180" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him four or five years; he is an honest man as far as ever I knew.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-17-person181">
                  William 
                  Jackson 
               <interp inst="t17661217-17-person181" type="surname" value="Jackson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-person181" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-person181" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him eight years; he is a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-17-person182">
                  John 
                  Palmer 
               <interp inst="t17661217-17-person182" type="surname" value="Palmer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-person182" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-person182" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him almost two years; I never knew any thing bad of him.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Where is your lodging from whence you fetched your money?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. It is near Oxford Chapel.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to give different accounts of the sum?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I did not; I never varied in my account; I had not been in London above ten days; I brought it up out of the country with me.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17661217-17-verdict92" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-17-verdict92" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
