<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610916-27">
               <interp inst="t17610916-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-27" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610916"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-27" type="date" value="17610916"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610916-27-off142-c225" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-27-defend270 t17610916-27-off142 t17610916-27-verdict145"></join>
         
               <p>247. (M) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610916-27-defend270" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Ashworth 
                  <interp inst="t17610916-27-defend270" type="surname" value="Ashworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-defend270" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-defend270" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for the <rs id="t17610916-27-off142" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-off142" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-off142" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               wilful murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17610916-27-victim272" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Wager 
                        <interp inst="t17610916-27-victim272" type="surname" value="Wager"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610916-27-victim272" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610916-27-victim272" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-27-off142 t17610916-27-victim272"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  ; he stood charged on the coroner's inquest for the said murder
            </rs>, <rs id="t17610916-27-cd143" type="crimeDate">August 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-27-off142 t17610916-27-cd143"></join>.*</p> 
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-27-person273">
                  Edward 
                  Curcher 
               <interp inst="t17610916-27-person273" type="surname" value="Curcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-person273" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-person273" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the first beginning of the quarrel between the deceased and the prisoner, on the 17th of August, at a place called <placeName id="t17610916-27-crimeloc144">Ayre's-court, in the parish of Kengsinton</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-27-crimeloc144" type="placeName" value="Ayre's-court, in the parish of Kengsinton"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-27-crimeloc144" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-27-off142 t17610916-27-crimeloc144"></join>. There was a hay-fork stood against a chandler's shop door; we were all fellow-workmen together. My fellow labourer, 
               <persName id="t17610916-27-person274">
                  Thomas 
                  Theobalds 
               <interp inst="t17610916-27-person274" type="surname" value="Theobalds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-person274" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-person274" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , said to 
               <persName id="t17610916-27-person275">
                  Philip 
                  Mills 
               <interp inst="t17610916-27-person275" type="surname" value="Mills"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-person275" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-person275" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he saw that man, pointing to the prisoner, cutting the brand mark out of that hay-fork.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the mark?</p>
               <p>Curcher. It was J. H. said Philips Mills, fetch the fork, let me look at it. Then the deceased said to Mills, let me look at it. Then the prisoner came up to the deceased, and asked him what business he had with his fork, and took hold of it; and the deceased struck the prisoner first. Then there were several blows passed after that on both sides. In the quarrel and struggle in taking the fork from the deceased, 
               <persName id="t17610916-27-person276">
                  John 
                  Wager 
               <interp inst="t17610916-27-person276" type="surname" value="Wager"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-person276" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-person276" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the prisoner, made two pushes at him, against his belly, with the prongs of the fork; they both fell down. I think the deceased lived after that about five or six minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the deceased say any thing after the fall?</p>
               <p>Curcher. I think he only said, he has pricked me. After the man was dead, the prisoner stood with the fork in his hand, and said, whoever came to take his part, he would serve him so.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the prisoner and deceased acquainted before?</p>
               <p>Curcher. I do not know that they were.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-27-person277">
                  Thomas 
                  Theobalds 
               <interp inst="t17610916-27-person277" type="surname" value="Theobalds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-person277" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-person277" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was standing at the chandler's shop-door eating my dinner, on the Saturday before this thing happened (this happened on the Monday following) I saw the prisoner cutting the brand-mark out of the fork at the chandler's shop-door. As I was going to breakfast on the Monday, I saw the fork standing there; I told 
               <persName id="t17610916-27-person278">
                  Mills
               <interp inst="t17610916-27-person278" type="given" value="Mills"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-person278" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I saw the prisoner cut the brand-mark, it was J. H. Mills said to me, fetch the fork, and let me look at it. Mills delivered it into the deceased's hands, 
               <persName id="t17610916-27-person279">
                  John 
                  Wager 
               <interp inst="t17610916-27-person279" type="surname" value="Wager"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-person279" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-person279" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; the prisoner, came up, and demanded the fork. The deceased desired he might look at it. The prisoner laid hold on it, to take it from him. The deceased kept hold of it, and they had some blows between them.</p>
               <p>Q. Which struck first?</p>
               <p>Theohalds. I cannot tell; presently after that the prisoner said, if he did not let go the fork, he would run it in him. Soon after they both fell down, and Mills lifted the deceased up.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any thing done with the fork to Wager?</p>
               <p>Theohalds. I did not observe any thing; the deceased walked about five yards; he was asked if he was hurt any where; he put his right-hand to his navel, and said, he has pricked me here, and fell down immediately. I called 
               <persName id="t17610916-27-person280">
                  Philip 
                  Mills 
               <interp inst="t17610916-27-person280" type="surname" value="Mills"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-person280" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-person280" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and said, he is down again. Mills came, and lifted him out of the nettles, and he died immediately.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-27-person281">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Parrot 
               <interp inst="t17610916-27-person281" type="surname" value="Parrot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-person281" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-person281" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the fork stand at the chandler's shop-door, Theobalds went to fetch it to shew it to Mills; to the best of my knowledge 
               <persName id="t17610916-27-person282">
                  John 
                  Wager 
               <interp inst="t17610916-27-person282" type="surname" value="Wager"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-person282" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-person282" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             went up, and took it out of<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160036"></xptr> his hands. The prisoner came up, and said, it is my fork, and said, I will have it. Said the deceased, you shall not have it. The prisoner said, I bought and paid for it, it cost me eight-pence. Still the deceased refused to let him have it. The prisoner said, he would have it; the deceased said, d - n my blood if you shall. The prisoner collared him. Wager struck him the first blow; there were then several blows between them both. The prisoner took and wrung the fork out of the deceased's hand; and the deceased had not hold of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this before the fall?</p>
               <p>E. Parrot. It was; he gave the fork a push against Wager; I saw the hole just by the side of his belly in his shirt; the deceased sell presently after; he lived about five or six minutes after, and then died.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure the fork was clear in the prisoner's hands when he did the fact?</p>
               <p>E. Parrot. I am sure it was; Wager struck him at the same time that he made the offer with the fork. They fell both together. The deceased got up, and clapped one hand to his belly, and the other near his breast, and walked about two or three yards, fell again, and died.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-27-person283">
                  Mary 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17610916-27-person283" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-person283" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-person283" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the fork stand at the chandler's shop-door, and 
               <persName id="t17610916-27-person284">
                  Thomas 
                  Theobalds 
               <interp inst="t17610916-27-person284" type="surname" value="Theobalds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-person284" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-person284" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             took it up, and gave it to Mills; 
               <persName id="t17610916-27-person285">
                  John 
                  Wager 
               <interp inst="t17610916-27-person285" type="surname" value="Wager"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-person285" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-person285" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             went up, and he gave it to him. Then the prisoner came to Wager, and said, it was his fork, and he had paid for it. The deceased would not let him have it, and said he should not have it; then there was a struggle between them. Wager struck the first blow. The prisoner got the fork out of the deceased's hands, during the struggle, and had it clear in his own hands, and gave a push to the deceased.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the deceased strike him at the time?</p>
               <p>M. Smith. No, I did not; the man lived about six or seven minutes, and then died; I saw the wound after this, near his navel, on his right-side.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>Please you, my lord, I went up on the Monday morning to a man that I had worked with three days, and three quarters; I got my money, and went home to my quarters. I came up again in order to go to work, took my fork, and went to this small-beer shop, and left it at the door going in. This lad, Theobalds, took up the fork, and said, I saw him ( meaning me) cut the brand-mark out of it last Saturday. I have an evidence here that saw me pay for it. As I was coming out of the shop with my shirt and stockings, part of a breast of mutton, and a loin of mutton, in a handkerchief ( he saying he saw that dog cut the brand-mark out of it) this poor man that is dead and gone, laid hold of it, and took and twisted this way, and that way, as if he had been at quarter-stuff; and said, You rogue, you stole this from such a person. I never spoke to him, or knew him before. Every body will strive for their own; I stood upon my own defence; he swore he would run the fork in me. I have been 10 years in the late king's service.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610916-27-verdict145" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-verdict145" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-verdict145" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>N. B. The prisoner <rs id="t17610916-27-deflabel146" type="occupation">belonged to Chelsea hospital</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-27-defend270 t17610916-27-deflabel146"></join>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610916-27-punish147" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-punish147" type="punishmentCategory" value="imprison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-punish147" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="newgate"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-27-defend270 t17610916-27-punish147"></join>
               
                     <note>[Imprisonment. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610916-27-punish148" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-punish148" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-27-punish148" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-27-defend270 t17610916-27-punish148"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
