<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17621208-26">
               <interp inst="t17621208-26" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17621208-26" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17621208-26" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17621208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17621208-26" type="date" value="17621208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17621208-26-off141-c232" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-26-defend279 t17621208-26-off141 t17621208-26-verdict143"></join>
         
               <p>28. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17621208-26-defend279" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Haywood 
                  <interp inst="t17621208-26-defend279" type="surname" value="Haywood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-defend279" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-defend279" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17621208-26-deflabel140" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-26-defend279 t17621208-26-deflabel140"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17621208-26-off141" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-off141" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-off141" type="offenceSubcategory" value="infanticide"></interp>
               that she, on the <rs id="t17621208-26-cd142" type="crimeDate">28th of October</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-26-off141 t17621208-26-cd142"></join>, did bring forth a male child alive and in secret, which child, by the laws of the kingdom, was a bastard, on which she did of malice aforethought make an assault, and did cast and throw the said child into a certain privy house belonging to St. Bartholomew's Hospital, by which means it was suffocated
            </rs>. She stood likewise charged, on the Coroner's inquest, for the like murder +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-26-person280">
                  Susanna 
                  Gillis 
               <interp inst="t17621208-26-person280" type="surname" value="Gillis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-person280" type="given" value="Susanna"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-person280" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am sister of Diot's ward in St. Bartholomew's Hospital. The prisoner was six weeks in the Hospital with me, it is about six weeks ago. She was brought there for two sore legs; she had another complaint from getting cold by going into a damp cellar, which occasioned a disorder in her bowels. On the Thursday before the affair happened, she complained that disorder was worse than usual. The doctor ordered her a vomit, and on the Thursday after she complained she was worse, by the medicines that the doctor had ordered her, and said it burnt her inside up.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember the day of the month?</p>
               <p>Gillis. I do not, it was that night she was delivered. I went down to the apothecary, and brought her up a bolus. I went to her bed about a quarter after 8 at night, and missed her out of bed; she had used to keep her bed on the account of her legs being so bad, she only got out to have her bed made; I asked where she was gone, they told me to the necessary house; I sent 
               <persName id="t17621208-26-person281">
                  Mary 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17621208-26-person281" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-person281" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-person281" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the nurse, to see whether she was ill, or had fainted away; she came back and said, she was very bad, and could not come; I bid her go back with somebody with her and bring her in, for she would get cold.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was the necessary from the room where she lay?</p>
               <p>Gillis. It was about 3 or 4 yards from it. The nurse brought her back, and she went into bed. The nurse came to me and said, sister, there is something the matter, go and examine her. I went to her and asked, What was the matter with her? she answered, Nothing.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had she been at the necessary?</p>
               <p>Gillis. I cannot say. I said, I am sure there is something more than ordinary, I am sure Nanney you have had a child, or you have miscarried. She said she had not.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to tax her with that?</p>
               <p>Gillis. Upon the nurse telling me what she saw in the necessary, I desired her to tell me the truth, and I would fetch a midwife, and have her examined; she still denied it, and I went and fetched Mrs. Smith the midwife, and was present when she examined her; the midwife brought the other part into the world, which was a plain proof there had been a child. I made her some caudle, and took proper care of her, and was up in the ward till after 2 in the morning; she said nothing while I was there, but after that she owned it. After the child was found, I saw it in the dead house, where bodies are put; it was a male child.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you had children?</p>
               <p>Gillis. I have had 8.</p>
               <p>Q. Did it appear to be a full grown child?</p>
               <p>Gillis. It did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any marks of violence upon it?</p>
               <p>Gillis. No, I did not, it was as fine a child as could be seen. On the Tuesday night before, when she took the vomit, I challenged her with being big; as she sat in the chair she looked like a woman down lying. I said to her, if you was not a sober woman I should suspect you to be with child. She said, indeed, sister, it is nothing but my petticoats and stays.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she call herself a single or a married woman?</p>
               <p>Gillis. She called herself a single woman,</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-26-person282">
                  Mary 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17621208-26-person282" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-person282" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-person282" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the nurse in the Hospital. When the prisoner was missing from the bed, I was ordered to go to the necessary house to see after her; I went, and pushed the door open, and asked her, How she found herself? she said she was extremely ill; she then was sitting on the seat of the vault.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had she been there?</p>
               <p>M. Evans. I can't justly say how long; I said, sister desires you would come in, she is afraid you will get cold: she said she was in such extreme<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176212080025"></xptr> pain she could not get up: at that time I observed a great deal of blood upon the floor; I said, Nanney, you are very bad indeed (I had a candle in my hand) you seem to be in a very bad condition; said she, Nurse, the stuff that I have taken has forced the blood from me backwards and forwards, so that I can't tell what to do: I went directly from her to tell the sister in what manner she was, then sister ordered me to go back for her directly to have her into bed, fearing she should get cold; when I came back to the vault again she was got up, and had put the flap of the vault down, and was turning round to come out of the vault; I went to support her, she was very weak and tottered; the cloak she had on fell back, and by seeing her hand gave me suspicion something was the matter more than should be; she was half-way up her arm in blood; I said to her, Nanney, Nanney, what have you been at? I am afraid you have been flinging away your life in a very odd manner: she said, No, nurse, there is nothing the matter, I shall be better presently: I led her directly to her bed; as soon as I put her in, with her bed-gown and under petticoat on, I went back to the vault and saw it in a very bad condition, all the seat of the vault, the floor, and the funnel down the vault were bloody: I acquainted the sister with what I had seen and she examined her and went for the midwife; when the sister was gone I said there has certainly been a child: she said it was no such thing, it was only the apothecary's stuff: the other part was brought away afterwards, I was present: she said nothing till towards morning, then one of the patients and I taxed her with it; then she said the child was by a journeyman shoemaker, and owned she had been with child.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-26-person283">
                  Sarah 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17621208-26-person283" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-person283" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-person283" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a midwife, I was sent for about half an hour after 8 at night; the sister said there was a patient that they believed had miscarried; I found the prisoner sitting upright in bed, I desired her to lie down, I examined her and told the sister there was no child there, but soon I brought away the other part, she had been delivered of a child that evening, I thought at its full time by what appeared to me, but I never saw the child; she never spoke one word while I staid there; I saw the vault, and seat, and floor, they were very bloody.</p>
               <p>Q. From any thing you saw upon the vault, can you form any judgment with certainty whereabouts she was delivered?</p>
               <p>S. Smith. My opinion it was as she was sitting on the vault.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-26-person284">
                  Mary 
                  Tharp 
               <interp inst="t17621208-26-person284" type="surname" value="Tharp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-person284" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-person284" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a patient at the hospital; I saw the prisoner go to the vault, and saw nurse load her back again.</p>
               <p>Q. How long might she have been there?</p>
               <p>M. Tharp. I believe about 5 or 10 minutes, I can't say justly: when she was come from the vault the sister examined her, and said she believed there was something the matter; the prisoner said, No, nothing at all: then a midwife was sent for; she bid her turn on one side, and she brought away the other part: in the night I ask'd her if she knew where the child was; she said it slip'd from her as she sat on the vaults: I ask'd her if she knew the father of it; she said, he was a journeyman shoemaker that lived in a court by her master, and that she did not know she was so near her time; I never saw the child: there is but one bed betwixt mine and the vault; I was on my bed, I never heard a child cry, or a groan.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-26-person285">
                  Martha 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17621208-26-person285" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-person285" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-person285" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to the prisoner's bedside the 28th of October, about a quarter of an hour before this happened; I asked her how she did, she complained of a pain in her bowels; presently after I saw the nurse leading her from the vault to the bedside; the sister sent for a midwife.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was you to the vault when she was there?</p>
               <p>M. Clark. About ten or a dozen yards, I was sitting by the fire, the vault is only separated from the room by a wooden partition.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear a child cry while she was there?</p>
               <p>M. Clark. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. to S. Gillis. How near was you to the vault while the prisoner was there?</p>
               <p>S. Gillis. I was sitting by the fire eating my supper; the fire is not so far from the vault as ten yards; I never heard a child cry; if there had been any noise there we must have heard it.</p>
               <p>M. Evans. I was to-and-fro, I heard no noise at all, and when I went to the vault to her I heard no noise nor no groan.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-26-person286">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Chambers 
               <interp inst="t17621208-26-person286" type="surname" value="Chambers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-person286" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-person286" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I asked her one day if she was with child; she said no, no more than I: this was before she was in the hospital, about the latter end of June last.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-26-person287">
                  William 
                  Clutherburg 
               <interp inst="t17621208-26-person287" type="surname" value="Clutherburg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-person287" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-person287" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am porter in the hospital, I was present at the opening the vault, some of the soil was ordered to be taken away, it was three nights work before the child was found; in the night between Sunday and Monday, about half an hour after two o'clock, I saw the child taken out, it was a male child, I thought it a full grown child, I saw no marks of violence upon it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe the navel-string, whether cut or otherwise?</p>
               <p>Clutherburg. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176212080026"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-26-person288">
                  Robert 
                  Young 
               <interp inst="t17621208-26-person288" type="surname" value="Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-person288" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-person288" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am one or the surgeons belonging to the Hospital, the woman was my patient there for a sore leg; she had another complaint, for which she was under the doctor's care, that was a complaint in her bowels: I had not the least suspicion of her being with child. I was directed to observe the body of the infant on the Tuesday, it appeared to be perfect and full grown, there did not appear to me any external marks of any injury having been done to the child: I opened the thorax, and took out the lungs, in order to make the experiment usually made in these cases, that is putting them into water; I did, the lungs did swim, but I was of opinion that that experiment cannot be conclusive in this case, because the body had laid 3 days in the bog house, and I think such a fermentation might have been brought off, that it might gather air.</p>
               <p>Q. to the midwife. Is it possible the prisoner could be delivered sitting on the vault involuntarily?</p>
               <p>Midwife. It is. I imagine from what I saw upon her hands, that might come in endeavouring to bring that part which I brought away.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Young. Did you make any observation on the child, as to the navel string, that might read you to think it might drop from her?</p>
               <p>Young. The navel string did not appear to be cut.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>When I was upon the vault a pain came upon me. and I could not get off, nor I did not know where I was till I was in bed. I was quite insensible when the child came from me; and as soon as the midwife came, I told her the child was down in the vault.</p>

               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-26-person289">
                  Sarah 
                  Rhodes 
               <interp inst="t17621208-26-person289" type="surname" value="Rhodes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-person289" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-person289" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I found this baby linnen in the prisoner's box, since she was in prison. She sent to me to go and get her cloaths from her master's where she lived servant.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was that after she had been in prison?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-26-person290">
                  Sarah 
                  Rhodes 
               <interp inst="t17621208-26-person290" type="surname" value="Rhodes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-person290" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-person290" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This was about a fortnight after she was committed. Here are 2 caps, at waistcoat, sarchead cloth, a biggin, and every thing for a child except a shirt. (Produced in court) I always thought her a sober quiet girl.</p>
               <p>Elz. Riddle deposed she saw the things taken out of the prisoner's box.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-26-person291">
                  Mary 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17621208-26-person291" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-person291" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-person291" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17621208-26-person292">
                  Ann 
                  Harrison 
               <interp inst="t17621208-26-person292" type="surname" value="Harrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-person292" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-person292" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17621208-26-person293">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Short 
               <interp inst="t17621208-26-person293" type="surname" value="Short"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-person293" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-person293" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , gave her the character of a sober honest servant.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17621208-26-verdict143" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17621208-26-verdict143" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
