<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17630706-30">
               <interp inst="t17630706-30" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630706-30" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630706-30" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17630706"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630706-30" type="date" value="17630706"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17630706-30-off180-c264" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-30-defend332 t17630706-30-off180 t17630706-30-verdict183"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17630706-30-off184-c264" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-30-defend332 t17630706-30-off184 t17630706-30-verdict183"></join>
         
               <p>303. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17630706-30-defend332" type="defendantName">
                     Stephen 
                     Blemire 
                  <interp inst="t17630706-30-defend332" type="surname" value="Blemire"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-30-defend332" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-30-defend332" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17630706-30-off180" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630706-30-off180" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-30-off180" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing one black gelding, value 3 l. and one brown gelding, value 3 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17630706-30-victim334" type="victimName">
                     George 
                     Allen 
                  <interp inst="t17630706-30-victim334" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-30-victim334" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-30-victim334" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-30-off180 t17630706-30-victim334"></join>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-30-off184 t17630706-30-victim334"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17630706-30-cd181" type="crimeDate">June 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-30-off180 t17630706-30-cd181"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-30-off184 t17630706-30-cd181"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630706-30-person335">
                  George 
                  Allen 
               <interp inst="t17630706-30-person335" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-30-person335" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-30-person335" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Thursday morning last, my man went to a field near <placeName id="t17630706-30-crimeloc182">Shoreditch</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17630706-30-crimeloc182" type="placeName" value="Shoreditch"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17630706-30-crimeloc182" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-30-off180 t17630706-30-crimeloc182"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-30-off184 t17630706-30-crimeloc182"></join> to feed my horses, and he returned and told me they were stolen. I went out in order to see for them, going up Shoreditch I met a man who told me he saw the prisoner and another man in my field over night; I went and got a search warrant of Justice Fielding. He lives near the Infirmary, he is a weaver by trade, and keeps a chandler's-shop, and has a pleasure cart to carry people about; after a little searching, he said if I would be good natured he would let me know where the horses were, he would go and shew me. Accordingly he went to the Sun, in Gray's-Inn-Lane, there were my horses; he told me he and another man had rode them within a mile and a half of St. Albans in the night. I had seen them on the Wednesday afternoon, they were then clean and washed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630706-30-person336">
                  William 
                  Sherard 
               <interp inst="t17630706-30-person336" type="surname" value="Sherard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-30-person336" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-30-person336" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an officer. Mr. Allen brought a search warrant to me, I and he went to the prisoner's house, we asked his wife if he was at home? at first she said, no, but when she found we came to search, then she said he was laid down on the bed; then the prosecutor went up to him, we begun to search, then he said, we need not give ourselves any farther trouble, he would inform us where the horses were, and he would shew them to us. We all three went to the Sun, in Gray's-Inn-Lane, there the prisoner asked for the horses he left there that morning; they accordingly brought them out, and delivered them to him; a black and a brown one.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630706-30-person337">
                  Edward 
                  Waller 
               <interp inst="t17630706-30-person337" type="surname" value="Waller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-30-person337" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-30-person337" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to the prosecutor. I got up that morning about five, in order to bait the horses; when I came to the field, the horses were gone; I had seen them the evening before between eight and nine o'clock; I found the gate locked at which I used to take the horses in and out; there was a rail broke where the horses must have gone out, I did not perceive it broke over night.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you assist the prisoner, or lend him the two horses, or take them out yourself?</p>
               <p>Waller. No, I did not; neither do I know how they came out.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence. I was going with my own horses to Brook's-market; these 2 horses were astray, bridled and saddled, and a great coat buckled on the saddle, with a hammer in it; I fastened my own horse to a rail, and got them, and led them by my side, and put them into an inn; there I left them till Mr. Allen came to my house; when he came, he told me he had a warrant to search my house and stable, which gave me great surprize; I told him he was very welcome; I told him I had left them at an inn in such a place, but I had forgot the name of the inn; he went along with me, I called the ostler to let me have the horses that I left there that morning; he brought them out, I paid him a shilling for them, and gave him 2 d. for himself; I delivered the horses to Mr. Allen, then he told me I must go before Sir 
               <persName id="t17630706-30-person338">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17630706-30-person338" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-30-person338" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-30-person338" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , to discharge the warrant; when I came there my commitment was wrote, and I was sent to Newgate without examination.</p>

               <p>Prosecutor. I did not know whether I should mention the bridles and saddles which he had with the horses at the inn; when I was searching his house I found my hammer, likewise I found a pistol loaded, the hammer, saddles, and bridles were taken from out of a stable in the field where the horses were, which was broke open.</p>
               <p>The prisoner called 
               <persName id="t17630706-30-person339">
                  Richard 
                  Alwright 
               <interp inst="t17630706-30-person339" type="surname" value="Alwright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-30-person339" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-30-person339" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a rope-maker, in White-chapel, who had known him 16 or 17 years, who said he never knew any harm of him the days of his breath till within 8 or 10 days, when he heard of this affair; and Mr. Haines, of Primrose-street, who had known him about 4 months, said he never heard but that he had an honest good character.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was servant to the prosecutor, please to ask him my character.</p>
               <p>Q. to the Prosecutor. What is the prisoner's character?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. He has not a good character; I never thought him to have a bad character when he lived with me, that is about 5 or 6 years ago, but I think otherwise now.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17630706-30-verdict183" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630706-30-verdict183" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176307060018"></xptr>304. He was a 2d time indicted for <rs id="t17630706-30-off184" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630706-30-off184" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-30-off184" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing two saddles, val. 1 s. two bridles, a cloth great coat, and a hammer
            </rs>, the property of 
               <persName id="t17630706-30-person340">
                  George 
                  Allen 
               <interp inst="t17630706-30-person340" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-30-person340" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-30-person340" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17630706-30-cd185" type="crimeDate">June 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-30-off180 t17630706-30-cd185"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630706-30-off184 t17630706-30-cd185"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630706-30-person341">
                  George 
                  Allen 
               <interp inst="t17630706-30-person341" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-30-person341" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630706-30-person341" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . In searching the prisoner's house I found in his cellar a quantity of leather; I said, Stephen, you go on with your old tricks, I found also a great quantity of buckles and buttons, a pistol loaded, and my hammer; then he said, my dear master, you have been a good friend to me, if you will forgive me I'll tell you of all the things; then he said he went to a public-house in Hogsden fields, there he had left my great coat, saying he was afraid to bring it home in the middle of the day; I asked him what he did with that pistol loaded with stones? he acknowledged that he did go upon the highway, and that there was a man concerned with him, who is since ran away; at that time he said nothing of finding my horses bridled and saddled astray, but cried, and said if I would forgive him he would be very good for the future. My saddles and bridles were upon the horses at the inn. I went to that alehouse by Hogsdon, there I found my great coat, as he had said. (The things produced in court and deposed to.)</p>
               <p>The prisoner, in his defence, said, he was in a good way of business, and served many topping people with butter, in Spittlefields, and sells fowls and eggs; when he has been short of butter he has gone to Mr. Allen for small quantities; and that his pleasure cart was of great use to him in his business; that he charged his pistol, as several neighbours had, with intent to shoot a mad dog, and not having bullets, he must have made use of shot, had he not put in a stone.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17630706-30-verdict186" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630706-30-verdict186" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>See him tried for stealing a basket, and 170 lb. of butter, No 6 in this mayoralty.</p>
            </div1>
