<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650522-17">
               <interp inst="t17650522-17" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-17" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-17" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650522"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-17" type="date" value="17650522"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650522-17-off105-c172" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-17-defend204 t17650522-17-off105 t17650522-17-verdict111"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650522-17-off106-c175" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-17-defend210 t17650522-17-off106 t17650522-17-verdict113"></join>
         
               <p>313, 314, (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17650522-17-defend204" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Whitham 
                  <interp inst="t17650522-17-defend204" type="surname" value="Whitham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-17-defend204" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-17-defend204" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             was indicted for <rs id="t17650522-17-off105" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-17-off105" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-17-off105" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 600 lb. weight of pitch, value 3 l. and 30 gallons of tar, value 15 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17650522-17-victim206" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17650522-17-victim206" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-17-victim206" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-17-victim206" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17650522-17-victim208" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Speck 
                  <interp inst="t17650522-17-victim208" type="surname" value="Speck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-17-victim208" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-17-victim208" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            : and 
               
                  <persName id="t17650522-17-defend210" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Lewis 
                  <interp inst="t17650522-17-defend210" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-17-defend210" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-17-defend210" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             for <rs id="t17650522-17-off106" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-17-off106" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-17-off106" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving the same, well knowing it to have been stolen
            </rs>. <rs id="t17650522-17-cd107" type="crimeDate">April 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-17-off105 t17650522-17-cd107"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-17-off106 t17650522-17-cd107"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-17-person211">
                  William 
                  Speck 
               <interp inst="t17650522-17-person211" type="surname" value="Speck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-17-person211" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-17-person211" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17650522-17-person212">
                  Thomas 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17650522-17-person212" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-17-person212" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-17-person212" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and I are <rs id="t17650522-17-viclabel108" type="occupation">partners</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-17-victim206 t17650522-17-viclabel108"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-17-victim208 t17650522-17-viclabel108"></join>, and <rs id="t17650522-17-viclabel109" type="occupation">wharfingers</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-17-victim206 t17650522-17-viclabel109"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-17-victim208 t17650522-17-viclabel109"></join>, in <placeName id="t17650522-17-crimeloc110">St. John's Southwark</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17650522-17-crimeloc110" type="placeName" value="St. John's Southwark"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17650522-17-crimeloc110" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-17-off105 t17650522-17-crimeloc110"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-17-off106 t17650522-17-crimeloc110"></join>; our wharf is opposite the Tower: on Monday morning. the 22d of April, between eight and nine o'clock, Mr. Dunkin, a Custom-house officer, called upon me, and asked me if I had lost any pitch and tar; in consequence of his information, I went on board Captain Lewis, the prisoner's vessel; she lay at Iron-gate; there I saw a barrel of pitch and a barrel of tar: I took the marks of them, to see if they were mine or not: the tar had a catherine-wheel, with a kind of a triangle in it; and the pitch had a sort of a burnt mark, like the letter S: I came home and examined the tar and pitch, and found the marks exactly tallied; I found four barrels of pitch missing out of 30; I found there were some barrels of tar missing; but to say how many I cannot: the tar was brought at different times from different places. I applied to Justice Pell for a search warrant: the constable went and took possession of the two barrels: the following week, Whitham, who was in the Borough gaol, made a voluntary confession, before a justice in the Borough, of many robberies by him committed, and this among the rest: I took up Lewis at market; he acknowledged he bought them, and did not seem to desire favour: he said, Whitham brought them on board when he was in custody; I asked him what was become of the other pitch and tar that Whitham had brought at different times? he said, he had landed two barrels of pitch at Ipswich, at one Mr. Dimock's, a ship builder's yard: I went to Ipswich and there saw the two barrels, marked with the same mark: I believe Mr. Lewis would have made a very voluntary confession, if we would have admitted him: he said he always received them in the night.</p>
               <p>Jos. Dunkin. I am a Custom-house officer: on the 22d of April I and my partner were upon the river, about one in the morning: just opposite the King's brewhouse above Iron-gate lay two sloops; we heard the tackle of one of them going; I imagined they were hoisting out some goods to run; then I desired my partner to lie upon his skulls till the boat put off: presently I heard the noise of skulls: I soon saw Whitham in a skiff by himself, and nothing in her: I said, Jack, what did you put on board that sloop? said he, what<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176505220018"></xptr> sloop? I said, the sloop on the inside where you came from; he said, nothing: I went on board the sloop; there were two or three sailors on board; it was Mr. Lewis's sloop; I saw the pitch and tar, and said what makes you receive this of Whitham; he has certainly stole it, for he is a bad sort of a man: they said, what is that to us, our master gives us orders to do it: one of them said the captain was in the cabin; upon which I went to the cabin door, and said, Mr. Lewis turn out, I want to speak with you; he said, I am not well; I said, what makes you receive that pitch and tar from Whitham, it is stolen; depend upon it you will be transported: said he, I know nothing of it; I did not see him; but I apprehend it to be his voice, having heard him speak since. I went about my duty; and Mr. Speck being a neighbour, I told him of it in the morning.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-17-person213">
                  Thomas 
                  Bennet 
               <interp inst="t17650522-17-person213" type="surname" value="Bennet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-17-person213" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-17-person213" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I belong to Captain Lewis: Whitham came on board our vessel, and called Mr. Lewis once or twice: he said he had a barrel of pitch and a barrel of tar; very well, said the captain: he bid me turn out and hoist them in: I did; Whitham flung it: then Mr. Dunkin came on board: the captain said, let them stay on deck till morning: when he came on board in the evening, he bid us strike them down into the hold. I believe Mr. Speck came on board about 10 or 11 o'clock; he asked who brought them on board; I said it was Whitham; he said they belonged to him; but Mr. Lewis was not then on board: when he came on board in the evening, I told him there had been a gentleman there that had ordered me to take care of the barrels: there were two barrels of pitch carried down to Ipswich, the last voyage; Whitham brought them on board: they were put into the yard of 
               <persName id="t17650522-17-person214">
                  John 
                  Dimock 
               <interp inst="t17650522-17-person214" type="surname" value="Dimock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-17-person214" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-17-person214" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a builder, by Captain Lewis's order, as we lay along-side the yard. The captain is master of a vessel that trades from London to Ipswich.</p>
               <p>Q. to Dunkin. Is it usual to carry goods on board in the middle of the night?</p>
               <p>Dunkin. Some times they do to ships going to foreign parts, when they cannot finish what they begin in the day: but I never knew them to carry single barrels of pitch and tar in the middle of the night.</p>
               <p>Whitham's Defence.</p>
               <p>I have some more things to discover, if your lordship will grant me my affidavit: it was through my means that the goods were recovered.</p>
               <p>Lewis's Defence.</p>
               <p>If goods are brought in the night, we leave them till the morning before we hoist them down.</p>
               <p>He called 
               <persName id="t17650522-17-person215">
                  James 
                  Bird 
               <interp inst="t17650522-17-person215" type="surname" value="Bird"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-17-person215" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-17-person215" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17650522-17-person216">
                  James 
                  Dimage 
               <interp inst="t17650522-17-person216" type="surname" value="Dimage"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-17-person216" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-17-person216" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , two master of vessels; the first had known him 30. years, and the other almost 50; who gave him the character of an honest man, exclusive of this.</p>
               <p>Whitham, <rs id="t17650522-17-verdict111" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-17-verdict111" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17650522-17-punish112" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-17-punish112" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-17-defend204 t17650522-17-punish112"></join>
               T
            </rs>. </p>
               <p>Lewis, <rs id="t17650522-17-verdict113" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-17-verdict113" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17650522-17-punish114" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-17-punish114" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-17-defend210 t17650522-17-punish114"></join>
               T. 14
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
