<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17600116-14">
               <interp inst="t17600116-14" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600116-14" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600116-14" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600116-14" type="date" value="17600116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600116-14-off66-c97" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600116-14-defend123 t17600116-14-off66 t17600116-14-verdict70"></join>
         
               <p>56. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17600116-14-defend123" type="defendantName">
                     Margery 
                     Eardley 
                  <interp inst="t17600116-14-defend123" type="surname" value="Eardley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-14-defend123" type="given" value="Margery"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-14-defend123" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17600116-14-off66" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600116-14-off66" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-14-off66" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch, value 3 l. one seal, value 1 s. and one other seal, value 1 d.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17600116-14-victim125" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Macdonald 
                  <interp inst="t17600116-14-victim125" type="surname" value="Macdonald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-14-victim125" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-14-victim125" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600116-14-off66 t17600116-14-victim125"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17600116-14-cd67" type="crimeDate">December 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600116-14-off66 t17600116-14-cd67"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600116-14-person126">
                  Thomas 
                  Macdonald 
               <interp inst="t17600116-14-person126" type="surname" value="Macdonald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-14-person126" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-14-person126" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 27th of December last I lost a watch.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you lose it?</p>
               <p>Macdonald. I do not know how I lost it.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you lose it?</p>
               <p>Macdonald. I lost it in the tap-room, at the house of 
               <persName id="t17600116-14-person127">
                  Francis 
                  Egan 
               <interp inst="t17600116-14-person127" type="surname" value="Egan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-14-person127" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-14-person127" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at <placeName id="t17600116-14-crimeloc68">Saltpetre Bank</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17600116-14-crimeloc68" type="placeName" value="Saltpetre Bank"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17600116-14-crimeloc68" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600116-14-off66 t17600116-14-crimeloc68"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know who took it?</p>
               <p>Macdonald. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you drunk or sober?</p>
               <p>Macdonald. I was sober, to the best of my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sober now?</p>
               <p>Macdonald. I am.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you as sober then as now?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176001160011"></xptr>Macdonald. I was sober when I lost it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you drunk soon after?</p>
               <p>Macdonald. No, I was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Why do you charge the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Macdonald. The watch was stopped by Higham Levi, and so I came by the knowledge of it.</p>
               <p>Higham Levi. Last Friday was three weeks, between twelve and one in the day, the woman at the bar came selling apples; said she, will you buy a watch?</p>
               <p>Q. Where did she come to you?</p>
               <p>Levi. To my house in Duke's Place. I said, let me look at it; she shewed it me. I asked her what she ask'd for it. She said forty shillings. I asked her how she knew it was worth forty shillings. She said, what will you give for it? will you give thirty shillings? I said, I do not know whether I will or not, how did you come by it? She said, it belonged to her husband. I said, I must stop the watch and you too, till you give an account how you came by it. I brought her before my Lord-mayor, and there she said her husband was dead. My Lord bid me to inquire who owned the watch. Mr. Egan, hearing I had stopped a watch, came and inquired about it, and said it belonged to his tapster. Then the prosecutor came and told me all the tokens of the watch before I shewed it to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any seals on it?</p>
               <p>Levi. There were two. [The watch produced in court, and deposed to by the prosecutor.]</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. What are you?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I am drawer to Mr. Egan.</p>
               <p>Q. from the prisoner to the prosecutor. Whether I did not send you word that I had your watch, and that it was stop'd at a Jew's?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. After the watch was stop'd I went to the prisoner's room, but she had made off, and I could not see her.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she in the tap room at the time your watch was lost?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. She was drinking there then; but she was gone when I went to her, and I did not see her till I went before my Lord-mayor, after I heard my watch was stop'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600116-14-person128">
                  Francis 
                  Egan 
               <interp inst="t17600116-14-person128" type="surname" value="Egan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-14-person128" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-14-person128" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner fifteen or sixteen years. The prosecutor is my <rs id="t17600116-14-viclabel69" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600116-14-victim125 t17600116-14-viclabel69"></join>, and was drawing beer at about a quarter before ten o'clock; some of the people asked what o'clock it was, when he pull'd out his watch, and said it was about a quarter after ten; he put it in his pocket again, as I believe, being very sober; after that, he came and told me he had lost his watch, so I insisted upon it that nobody should go out of my house till they were searched. I searched, but found nothing. After the watch was stop'd, a woman came and told me the prosecutor should have it again, provided I would not hurt the prisoner. Then I desired her to bring the prisoner to me, but she was gone; however, I found her in a little room in Cross Lane, and brought her before my Lord-mayor, when she said she found the watch in the tap room.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I found the watch by the street door. I went to the Jew's house, and after that I was told by a woman that it was the prosecutor's watch. I thought the right owner was the properest person to have it, but it was the Jews sabbath (Saturday) and I could not get it, so I sent a woman to the prosecutor to tell him it was his watch, and that I would go along with him to the Jew, and he should have it.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600116-14-person129">
                  Luke 
                  Collins 
               <interp inst="t17600116-14-person129" type="surname" value="Collins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-14-person129" type="given" value="Luke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-14-person129" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about seven years; she lodged with me about four years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her character?</p>
               <p>Collins. I have trusted her in my shop and never lost a halfpenny by her, and I have left her to receive money for me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600116-14-person130">
                  Hugh 
                  Macdaniel 
               <interp inst="t17600116-14-person130" type="surname" value="Macdaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-14-person130" type="given" value="Hugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-14-person130" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about two years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her general character?</p>
               <p>Macdaniel. I never heard any thing of her in my life but that of an honest endeavouring woman; she has work'd several times for me, and did my business very honestly; I never found any dishonesty by her.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600116-14-verdict70" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600116-14-verdict70" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600116-14-punish71" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600116-14-punish71" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600116-14-defend123 t17600116-14-punish71"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
