<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680706-28">
               <interp inst="t17680706-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680706-28" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680706-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680706"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680706-28" type="date" value="17680706"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680706-28-off142-c171" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-28-defend230 t17680706-28-off142 t17680706-28-verdict147"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680706-28-off142-c172" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-28-defend232 t17680706-28-off142 t17680706-28-verdict147"></join>
         
               <p>437, 438. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17680706-28-defend230" type="defendantName">
                     Samuel 
                     Craycraft 
                  <interp inst="t17680706-28-defend230" type="surname" value="Craycraft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-defend230" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-defend230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17680706-28-defend232" type="defendantName">
                     Patrick 
                     Bourn 
                  <interp inst="t17680706-28-defend232" type="surname" value="Bourn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-defend232" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-defend232" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted for that <rs id="t17680706-28-off142" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-off142" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-off142" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               they, on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17680706-28-victim234" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Nicholson 
                        <interp inst="t17680706-28-victim234" type="surname" value="Nicholson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680706-28-victim234" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680706-28-victim234" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-28-off142 t17680706-28-victim234"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in fear and danger of his life, and taking from his person one guinea, one 5 s. 3 d. piece, and two shillings in money numbered
            </rs>, his property, <rs id="t17680706-28-cd143" type="crimeDate">June 26</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-28-off142 t17680706-28-cd143"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>At the request of the prisoners the witnesses were examined separate.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680706-28-person235">
                  Robert 
                  Nicholson 
               <interp inst="t17680706-28-person235" type="surname" value="Nicholson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-person235" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-person235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Sunday was se'nnight, about twelve at night, I was going on board (I am a <rs id="t17680706-28-viclabel144" type="occupation">seafaring man</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-28-victim234 t17680706-28-viclabel144"></join>) when I was in <placeName id="t17680706-28-crimeloc145">Black-house-yard, Wapping</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17680706-28-crimeloc145" type="placeName" value="Black-house-yard, Wapping"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17680706-28-crimeloc145" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-28-off142 t17680706-28-crimeloc145"></join>, a little boy, seemingly about 16 years old, came up to me, and took hold of my jacket; said I, what do you want; he said, let me see what you have got in your pocket; I said, you little bastard, what do you want with me, and pushed him from me; then a person came behind me, and knocked me down (to the best<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176807060011"></xptr> of my knowledge it was Craycraft;) he put his hand upon my eyes, and another man came and took my money out of my breeches pocket, a guinea, a quarter guinea, and some silver, I do not know how much; the watchman came just as I was getting up, I did not see which way they went; I could not look up for a considerable time, I took particular notice of the little boy.</p>
               <p>Q. What was you knocked down with?</p>
               <p>Nicholson. I cannot tell whether with a stick or his fist.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see the boy before?</p>
               <p>Nicholson. No, I described him to the watchman, and told him how I had been used; the boy was taken up a little after, that very night, and carried to the watch-house in Wapping; the next morning he confessed the fact, and said one was a tall man, and the other shorter, in a brown coat; that one went by the name of Jack, and the other Castleton; he said they had desired him to go along with them, and he should have better clothes; that he went with them, and they desired him to come over the way to me as I was going along, and ask what I had got in my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there no other people going along at that time?</p>
               <p>Nicholson. I saw none.</p>
               <p>Q. from Craycraft. What house did you come out of at that time of the night?</p>
               <p>Nicholson. I came out of Mr. Jackson's house, the ship in Distress.</p>
               <p>Q. from Craycraft. Whether you did not go into any house where were women?</p>
               <p>Nicholson. No, I did not, I only had a pot or two of beer at Jackson's, and changed a nine shilling piece; I had been with a shipmate.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680706-28-person236">
                  Francis 
                  Sullivan 
               <interp inst="t17680706-28-person236" type="surname" value="Sullivan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-person236" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-person236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I shall be sixteen years of age on the 17th of August next. On Sunday was se'nnight I was at the Black-boy on Saltpetre-bank; I went there with other boys that had been out to pick pockets, one of their names was Terry Tinley; there was Craycraft in that house cursing and swearing, in a lewd woman's company; she was got away, and he swore if he could come at her he would searify her face, so that she should never go into company again; he did not know her name, but I do; the other prisoner sat by Craycraft.</p>
               <p>Q. How many people were in the house?</p>
               <p>Sullivan. There were one man and two women, the man was the waiter, and one of the women was the woman of the house's daughter; Craycraft called me Irishman; he said, here Irishman, drink; they had the Saturday before asked me to go with them; as soon as I had drank, Craycraft put his finger up to his nose and looked to the door, signifying I was to go out; I went out and staid at the corner of Blackboy-alley; he went out at the other door and made a noise after the woman, but could not find her; the other prisoner came out also; we all three went down Saltpetre-bank, about half way, a little below Terry Finley's, we met Terry, he asked me where I was going; I said, down the bank; said Craycraft, come along with us; we all four went down together, and went into Blackhorse-yard; there Craycraft told hold of my arm and searched me for money, and the other prisoner searched Terry Finley, but we had not a farthing about us; then Mr. Nicholson came by; said Craycraft, there is a sucking cull, that is, a drunken gentleman, go and ask him what he has got; he had something white in his pocket; I went up to him and said, what is that coming out of your pocket; he said, get away you little bastard; then Craycraft came behind him and knocked him down with his double fist; after he dropped, Craycraft put his hand to his eyes, and Bourn picked his pocket; the man said he had got but two-pence halfpenny in the world; then Craycraft said, hush, you thief, if you offer to speak a word, I'll cut your throat directly; the constable of the night was in the watch-house, which is close by the turning; I crossed the way, and we went up the bank to Mrs. Evans's at the Black Boy; I stood at the door while they went in and had a quartern of gin or aniseed, it cost two pence halfpenny; they had changed a six-pence, and they gave me the three-pence halfpenny; I returned it to Craycraft again; Craycraft told me the thief (meaning the man they robbed) had but a shilling.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of Terry Finley?</p>
               <p>Sullivan. As soon as Bourn let him go to Craycraft, after he had knocked the man down, Terry ran away; we went after this towards Tower-hill, and met a sailor, and robbed him; after that we came to the watch house, near where we robbed Nicholson; Craycraft put his head into the watch-house, and said, d - n you, blast you all together; when he was at a little distance he said, if they were to come after him he would cut their throats directly; Nicholson was in the watch-house; seeing me, he said, there is the lad; I said I will not run away; the two prisoners ran away, and they took me into the watch-house. The next day they brought me to the bench of Justices in Whitechapel; I confessed the fact and had my liberty, and was sitting in the constable's house;<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176807060012"></xptr> last Monday se'nnight I saw the two prisoners go by, both their hats were flapped; I said there are the two men; I had told the constable one of them had a black patch on the left side his check, which he had when taken; there were two men singing ballads in the street; the two prisoners stopped and stood talking to two sailors; Mrs. Chapman sent for her husband, he came and took them.</p>
               <p>Q. from Craycraft. Whether you are hired, or had the clothes you have on to tell this story?</p>
               <p>Suilivan. I had not a shirt to my back, I was full of vermin; these clothes I have on were then in pawn, and they were got out for me; I worked very hard for this coat, but as for the money that bought the shirt and waistcoat, it was not got honestly.</p>
               <p>Q. from Craycraft. Whether the constable is not to put you apprentice.</p>
               <p>Sullivan. No, the Justices said to the constable, mind after this thing is over, do you take care of this boy, as he says he has friends in his own country, send him over to them, they live at Waterford in Ireland.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you followed picking of pockets?</p>
               <p>Sullivan. I have followed it about two or three months; I have been almost six years from my own country.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680706-28-person237">
                  Margaret 
                  Quist 
               <interp inst="t17680706-28-person237" type="surname" value="Quist"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-person237" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-person237" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The two prisoners came into my mother's house, the Black Boy on Saltpetre-bank, (my mother's name is Evans) about half an hour after nine last Sunday night was a week, Craycraft called for a pint of beer; there was a woman named 
               <persName id="t17680706-28-person238">
                  Margaret 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17680706-28-person238" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-person238" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-person238" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , came in much in liquor; he said to her, you had better be quiet; he began to be very quarrelsome, the woman went through the house and went away; he called for more beer, an unfortunate woman, one 
               <persName id="t17680706-28-person239">
                  Frances 
                  Etherley 
               <interp inst="t17680706-28-person239" type="surname" value="Etherley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-person239" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-person239" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came through the house; he pulled her into a box to sit down; she went out; the prisoner Bourn said she has tipped you the double, to Craycraft; Craycraft said, by the holy Jesus, I'll mark her, she shall not go into company a good while; he went out and came in again, and could not find her; then I went and awaked my mother, she would not draw them any more beer; they went out about a quarter after eleven.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember seeing this boy Sullivan at that time?</p>
               <p>M. Quist. He came in, I served him with a pennyworth of aniseed at better than half an hour after ten.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680706-28-person240">
                  Thomas 
                  Gisby 
               <interp inst="t17680706-28-person240" type="surname" value="Gisby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-person240" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-person240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mrs. Kennedy at the Black Boy on Saltpetre-bank.</p>
               <p>Q. Is that Mrs. Evans do you mean?</p>
               <p>Gisby. It is the same woman, she has two husbands; the two prisoners came in there last Sunday was se'nnight before eleven o'clock and had some beer; they had one pint after eleven; then my mistress cleared the house, and we went to bed before twelve.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoners come again that night and had some gin?</p>
               <p>Gisby. I do not remember that they did.</p>
               <p>Q. to Sullivan. When you went again and they brought you out three-pence halfpenny, what time was that?</p>
               <p>Sullivan. That was about half an hour, or three quarters after eleven.</p>
               <p>Gisby. I give change to so many people, I very seldom take notice to whom.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680706-28-person241">
                  Susanna
               <interp inst="t17680706-28-person241" type="given" value="Susanna"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-person241" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             M'Lean. I heard the two prisoners ask this boy to go along with them, and be a good boy; they said they would give him a new suit of clothes; I was drinking with them then at the Black Boy; it was on a Sunday in the afternoon, the boy was taken up that night.</p>
               <p>M. Quist. This is not the woman that Craycraft made a noise about.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680706-28-person242">
                  Thomas 
                  Chambers 
               <interp inst="t17680706-28-person242" type="surname" value="Chambers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-person242" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-person242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an officer belonging to St. John's; Wapping; last Sunday night was a week about a quarter before twelve, I was at the watch-house door; I saw two men and this lad come down from Saltpetre bank; then I went to the chair; one of them came to the watch-house and said, d - n you, blast your eyes all together; the lad said some bad word to that purpose; then I spoke to one of the watchmen to come along with me, thinking they were going about some bad work; we went down a thoroughfare into Nightingale-lane, and stood at a corner about ten minutes; hearing no disturbance at all we returned to the watch-house; I laid my arm upon the watch-house door, up came the lad and the two prisoners; the lad crossed the way and said, indeed, Sir, I did not go to run away, I did not go to do it, crying and whining, as much as to say he was an apprentice to one of them; one of them talked to him as though he was his master, but I cannot be positive as to the words; then they went up Saltpetre-bank; I said to the watchmen, these people have done something amiss, this was just as the watch was going out twelve; about five minutes after this, one of the watchmen found the prosecutor and brought him in; we asked him what was the matter; he told me he had been robbed; then I took two of my watchmen and went, and searched every corner about Saltpetre-bank, but<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176807060013"></xptr> found nobody; then I went round Well-street and to the watch-house again, then to Nightingale-lane; coming back, one of the watchmen came running to me, and said the man has got the lad, that was one that robbed him; then I went and found him in the watch-house, and was told the other two were run away; I put the lad in the dark hole behind; I asked him some questions, he seemed to deny it at first; then I took him to the cage and locked him up about three. The next morning about eight or nine I took him out, and had him examined before the bench of Justices; he said one of the two men was named Cassady, that the tall one which is Craycraft, had a black patch on his left cheek, and the other went by the name of Jack.</p>
               <p>Q. to Sullivan. Do you remember what was said as you went by the watch-house after the robbery?</p>
               <p>Sullivan. I did sham a cry, and talk as if one of them was my master, that they should not mistrust us.</p>
               <p>Chambers. Then I had a warrant to apprehend them; the lad said he never had been concerned with them before; he told the Justices how the robbery was committed, that the two prisoners stood at a corner, and they said to him, there is a sucking call, go to him; that he went up to Nicholson and asked him what he had in his pocket, and that the tall man came behind him and knocked him down, and put his hand upon his eyes, and said if he spoke he would cut his throat; that Nicholson said, for God's sake, spare my life, take my money, and something about his saying he had but two-pence halfpenny.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was the boy taken?</p>
               <p>Chambers. I believe he was taken a little after one o'clock; I took the two prisoners the same day, being Monday; there were two men singing ballads about Wilkes; the lad was then in my kitchen; he saw the prisoners go by, he told my wife they were the men; my wife sent my apprentice for me, I had a cutlace under my coat; the lad had told me they were blood-thirsty men, and desired me not to go unarmed; I went, they were talking to some paviours and two other people; I with assistance secured them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the lad tell you any thing of another lad being with them?</p>
               <p>Chambers. He did, he said his name was Terry Finley of about twelve years of age, but he ran away when the man was knocked down; that lad follows picking of pockets; I do believe Craycraft was the man that looked into the watch-house and said, d - n you, blast you all together; they had the same coloured clothes on as now; one wore lighter clothes than the other, with flapped hats; I took particular notice of the boy, I can swear to him in particular.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680706-28-person243">
                  Francis 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17680706-28-person243" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-person243" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-person243" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I took up the man that was robbed in the Broad-way, Black-horse-yard, and took him into the watch-house.</p>
               <p>The prisoners said nothing in their defence.</p>
               <p>For Craycraft.</p>
               <p>Honor M'Carty. I have known Craycraft seven or eight years; I was in company with him last Sunday was fortnight in Rosemary-lane, from about five in the afternoon, and continued in company with him till about two in the morning; between eleven and twelve I sent him in at Kennedy's at the Black Boy for a pint of beer, he and the other prisoner came out of that house together; we brought half a gallon of beer from there, and sat and drank it at another house; then they both set out for Deptford, I parted with them at the foot of London-bridge about two in the morning.</p>
               <p>Q. to Quist. Do you remember any thing of this?</p>
               <p>Quist. The woman went out with the beer, the men were turned out at about a quarter after eleven.</p>
               <p>Q. to H. M'Carty. At whose house did you drink the beer?</p>
               <p>H. M'Carty. It was the house of 
               <persName id="t17680706-28-person244">
                  Patrick 
                  Fenning 
               <interp inst="t17680706-28-person244" type="surname" value="Fenning"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-person244" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-person244" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. What is Craycraft?</p>
               <p>H. M'Carty. He is a <rs id="t17680706-28-deflabel146" type="occupation">seafaring man</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-28-defend230 t17680706-28-deflabel146"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680706-28-person245">
                  Mathew 
                  Tanner 
               <interp inst="t17680706-28-person245" type="surname" value="Tanner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-person245" type="given" value="Mathew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-person245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17680706-28-person246">
                  John 
                  Grant 
               <interp inst="t17680706-28-person246" type="surname" value="Grant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-person246" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-person246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Mrs. Newman, - Sullins, 
               <persName id="t17680706-28-person247">
                  Jerrat 
                  Bourn 
               <interp inst="t17680706-28-person247" type="surname" value="Bourn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-person247" type="given" value="Jerrat"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-person247" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17680706-28-person248">
                  William 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17680706-28-person248" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-person248" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17680706-28-person249">
                  Samuel 
                  Cook 
               <interp inst="t17680706-28-person249" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-person249" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-person249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and - Dunn, appeared for Bourn, who had all of them known him about a year, the time he lived with his brother, who keeps a coal cellar in Bedfordbury, who said he was a native of Ireland, and had a good character.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17680706-28-verdict147" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-verdict147" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17680706-28-punish148" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680706-28-punish148" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-28-defend230 t17680706-28-punish148"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-28-defend232 t17680706-28-punish148"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
