<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610916-59">
               <interp inst="t17610916-59" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-59" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-59" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610916"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-59" type="date" value="17610916"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610916-59-off307-c441" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-59-defend544 t17610916-59-off307 t17610916-59-verdict310"></join>
         
               <p>279. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610916-59-defend544" type="defendantName">
                     George 
                     Pettit 
                  <interp inst="t17610916-59-defend544" type="surname" value="Pettit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-59-defend544" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-59-defend544" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17610916-59-off307" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-59-off307" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-59-off307" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch, value 40 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               <persName id="t17610916-59-victim545" type="victimName">
                  Stephens 
                  Dachy 
               <interp inst="t17610916-59-victim545" type="surname" value="Dachy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-59-victim545" type="given" value="Stephens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-59-victim545" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-59-off307 t17610916-59-victim545"></join>
                  </persName>
             . <rs id="t17610916-59-cd308" type="crimeDate">July 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-59-off307 t17610916-59-cd308"></join>.~</p>
               <p>The prosecutor could not speak English, so an interpreter was sworn.</p>
               <p>Stephens Dachy. I was coming out of the Park thro' <placeName id="t17610916-59-crimeloc309">Spring-gardens passage</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-59-crimeloc309" type="placeName" value="Spring-gardens passage"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-59-crimeloc309" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-59-off307 t17610916-59-crimeloc309"></join>, on the 10th of July, about three quarters after eight in the evening, the prisoner came on my right side, and picked my watch out of my pocket, by the chain.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any other people by at the time?</p>
               <p>Dachy. There were not many people.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they so close as to press against you?</p>
               <p>Dachy. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you feel the watch go out of your pocket, or did you miss it as soon as it was gone?</p>
               <p>Dachy. I felt it go out; immediately the prisoner ran away, and gave it to a woman in a red cloak: I ran after him, and he never was out of my sight till taken: he was never above 24 steps from me; he was stopped before he got out of the passage. After the prisoner was brought before the justice, the woman came there, and was stopped. She was released the next day.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the watch in the woman's hand?</p>
               <p>Dachy. No, I did not, neither can I swear that was the woman that he gave it to.</p>
               <p>On his Cross-examination, he said, he was going out of the Park; the prisoner was going the same way; that the prisoner was before him when he lost his watch, and the woman a little way before him: that he lost his watch about the middle of the passage, and the prisoner delivered it to the woman about 20 steps from the place where he lost it, - that it was dusk, neither light nor dark, - that he never got sight of the watch after he felt it go, - that he saw the prisoner stretch out his hand to the woman. - That he believ'd the prisoner, as he turned again, when not past him, took the watch with his right-hand with a sudden motion.</p>
               <p>Mr. Dumain. On Friday, the 10th of July, in the evening, past eight o'clock, I was going to the Park; just, as I turned the corner at the pastry-cook's, the prisoner came running towards me; a tall gentleman, an officer. and I, stopped him. The prosecutor was running after him; he said, that man had taken his watch. When we got him to the Toy-shop, a woman came to him, they were together the space of a minute: the prosecutor said, he had given his watch to her. We searched him, but found nothing upon him; we took him to justice Cox's; there he denied knowing any thing of the watch; that same woman came to the justice's to him. She was committed to Tothill-Fields Bridewell, or the Gate-house, but upon her second examination was cleared.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the woman searched?</p>
               <p>Dumain. After she had been and spoke to the prisoner first, she absented herself, I believe, two minutes. The prosecutor was not able to hold the prisoner himself, and we inadvertently let her go. I don't know that she was searched at all.</p>
               <p>On his Cross-examination, he said, he saw the prisoner running before he was laid hold on: The woman said he was her husband, that the prisoner ran 200 yards, - that when he had the prisoner by the collar, the prosecutor declared to him, the prisoner had given the watch to that woman, - that the prosecutor understood a little English, so as to speak to be understood, - that he and the other evidence understood the prosecutor, - that the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160067"></xptr> prisoner gave the watch to her, while they had hold of his collar, because he was scrupulous of being searched before she came up; from that he thought it the first time they had met.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Whereabout was the prisoner, when he gave the watch to the woman?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. This was about six minutes before he was searched; but I am not certain to the time. He gave it her at going out of the passage, before he came to the pastry-cook's shop; we were there twice; he gave it her before we came there the first time.</p>
               <p>Dumain. There was a soldier come up, and struck the prosecutor on the head, which made me take the prosecutor's part.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-59-person546">
                  John 
                  Dudley 
               <interp inst="t17610916-59-person546" type="surname" value="Dudley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-59-person546" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-59-person546" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going by the pastry-cook's shop at that time. The prisoner and prosecutor had hold of each other by the collar: there came a man, in a red coat, without any lace; the prisoner leaned his head towards him; I could not tell what he said. Then that man struck the prosecutor once or twice: when they got to the coffee-house window, a gentleman looked out, and examined the prosecutor in French. Then that gentleman said to me, hold him fast, he has got the gentleman's watch. I did, and helped to conduct him to justice Cox's; there the prisoner's wife came in. She was charged about the watch, and I believe searched by the justice's maid; but nothing found upon her.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was coming from Westminster; before I came out of the Park, I met a young man that belongs to the company I do: he told me he was going to one Pettit's, in the Strand, and desired me to meet him there: I said, I was to go to the Coach and Horses to insist a young man, and if he does not come, I will meet you. I ran forward thro' the passage; an officer overtook me just as I got to the pastry-cook's shop; he took me by the collar, stop, said he; said I, for what? Said he, a man has lost his watch. The prosecutor never saw me, nor I him, till he brought me back to the Toy-shop: then the prosecutor said, you have got my watch. Then my wife came running and crying. There the gentlemen laid me down on my back, and searched me, and found I had it not. Then the gentlemen said, I believe you are innocent, go about your business: then the prosecutor came, and got hold of me again, and people came about me, and took me to justice Cox's.</p>
               <p>Q. to Dumain. Had the prisoner regimentals on then?</p>
               <p>Dumain. No, he had not.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-59-person547">
                  Richard 
                  Philps 
               <interp inst="t17610916-59-person547" type="surname" value="Philps"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-59-person547" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-59-person547" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at that time just entering the gateway; the prisoner came and tapped me on the shoulder, and said he was going to a name-take of his, in the Strand, to meet a young fellow whom he thought he should inlist; and said, if they had any punch I should have share of it, if I would come. He ran away from me; this was just in the Park, and seemed to blow and be in a hurry; I came very quietly after him, and saw a great crowd of people: I saw two gentlemen had hold of him, going to search him; they said he had no watch about him, and said the people, let him go. I thought he was got from the people: the next I heard they had got hold of him again. I belong to the same regiment; he bears an honest character.</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17610916-59-person548">
                  William 
                  Saxton 
               <interp inst="t17610916-59-person548" type="surname" value="Saxton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-59-person548" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-59-person548" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , musician in the same regiment, and</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-59-person549">
                  Hopefull 
                  Tripp 
               <interp inst="t17610916-59-person549" type="surname" value="Tripp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-59-person549" type="given" value="Hopefull"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-59-person549" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a serjeant, both gave him the character of an honest man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610916-59-verdict310" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-59-verdict310" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
