<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17611021-37">
               <interp inst="t17611021-37" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611021-37" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611021-37" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17611021"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611021-37" type="date" value="17611021"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17611021-37-off191-c444" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-37-defend500 t17611021-37-off191 t17611021-37-verdict193"></join>
         
               <p>320. (L) 
               
                  <persName id="t17611021-37-defend500" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Doudall 
                  <interp inst="t17611021-37-defend500" type="surname" value="Doudall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-37-defend500" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-37-defend500" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17611021-37-off191" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611021-37-off191" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-37-off191" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one gold ring, value 10 s. 6 d.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17611021-37-victim502" type="victimName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Dell 
                  <interp inst="t17611021-37-victim502" type="surname" value="Dell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-37-victim502" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-37-victim502" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-37-off191 t17611021-37-victim502"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17611021-37-viclabel192" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-37-victim502 t17611021-37-viclabel192"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-37-person503">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Dell 
               <interp inst="t17611021-37-person503" type="surname" value="Dell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-37-person503" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-37-person503" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I unfortunately got into company with thi s man at the bar, and he got me to live with him. I had not been with him but a few days, but he was desirous of my goods being sold. I sold them for five guineas, and he had the money of me. Then he said, he would go to Whitehaven, and I should go along with him. I was desirous to be married before we went away. He said, if we were married, our marriage would not stand good where we were going, and he could be married for a crown there; and that money would help to keep us on the road. I agreed to go along with him, and we went to Hempsted in Hertfordshire. I had some money due to me there, that was owing to my husband. The prisoner and I went there. The gentleman said he did not greatly like the prisoner, and he thought the money ought to be for my child; and he did not chuse to part with it, without seeing some of my friends; so he paid me but a guinea. Then the prisoner would come to London again; and he took a lodging for me in Billiter-lane. There I was tired of living with him in that manner; I had very bad usage from him in beating me. If I went into company along with him, if a man did but look at me, he would make me, when I came home, take a book and swear whether I knew the man or not.</p>
               <p>Q. What have you to say concerning a gold ring?</p>
               <p>E. Dell, He asked me to look at it once when we were at a publick-house in Holbourn; he said, there is a posey in it. He took it, and made as if he could not read it; it was dark. He got up, and went to the door; there is a silversmith lives at the corner; he went, and had it stretched, and came in with it on his finger. I wanted my ring; he would not give it me.</p>
               <p>Another time I went into a publick-house to ask him, if he was coming home. He said, come in, and sit down a bit. I stopped, and in came a man with the ring in his mouth; he took it out of his mouth. and gave it to the prisoner backhanded. I saw the prisoner slip it on his finger. I said, Will, what have you been doing with my ring? Said he, I have been putting your name upon it. I said no more to him then. When we came out there, I still wanted my ring. He had silver-buckles in his shoes; and I thought that ring would better become me; and as it was my husband's mother's wedding ring, which he desired before he died. I never would part with; he would not give it me then, but when we were in Billiter-lane, one day when he was washing his hands, I saw it lying by him, took it up, and put it on my finger. He wanted it of me again. No, said I, you asked me to let you look at it; but now I have got it, I will keep it. He had got engraved in it W. D, He swore by G - d he would have it. I said, I would lose my life before I would part with it. Then he said he would leave me; I said do, for I shall be glad of that. He took his stick in his hand, and went down stairs. He asked my landlady if I owed her any thing; she said, no. Then he said I think it is time to go. He went out and came in again; I was below-stairs with my landlady; she said, now girl he is come in again, with a resolution to have the ring from you. He called me up-stairs; I did not go. He came down to call me, and my landlady would have had me left the ring with her. I would not, but said I would keep it on my my finger, and lose my life rather than part with it. I went up-stairs; he said, give me the ring? I sat down on the foot of the bed to blow the fire; he came to the bed side laughing, and said, will you give me the ring? I said I would not. He flung me on the bed, and put both his legs over me, and bent my arm back. I cried out, Will, you will break my arm. Said he, I do not care if I do; will you give me the ring? I said, no. He said, will you give me leave to take it? I said, no, I would lose my life first. He wet my finger, and brought it to the middle joint, took the ring in his mouth, and drawed it off my finger.</p>

               <p>Q. Had he a wife?</p>
               <p>E. Dell. He had another woman; I believe he gave part of the money my goods sold for to that woman. [The ring produced in court.] This is the ring; it is my property.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176110210083"></xptr>Mr. Jefferys. I was at the taking of the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Jefferys. I am the prosecutrix's uncle; after we had apprehended him, as we were coming along, he put the ring into her hand.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say at the time?</p>
               <p>Jefferys. I did not hear him say any thing at all.</p>
               <p>Q from Prisoner. Was it before the officer had served the warrant, or not?</p>
               <p>Jefferys. The warrant was there, but not in a proper officer's hand.</p>
               <p>The prisoner in his defence acknowledged he had debauched the prosecutrix, and received part of the money the goods were sold for; and likewise, that he did take the ring from her finger in the manner she mentioned.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-37-person504">
                  Sarah 
                  Lockwood 
               <interp inst="t17611021-37-person504" type="surname" value="Lockwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-37-person504" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-37-person504" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner some time; I never saw any harm by him in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he a wife?</p>
               <p>S. Lockwood. He has, and two children.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-37-person505">
                  Robert 
                  Gardner 
               <interp inst="t17611021-37-person505" type="surname" value="Gardner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-37-person505" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-37-person505" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner at the bar, and the prosecutrix, came into a publick-house where I was; he asked me to put W. D. into a ring; I told him it was not my business, but I could get it done, which I did; this is the ring here produced.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-37-person506">
                  George 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17611021-37-person506" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-37-person506" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-37-person506" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at Mr. Fisher's, a publick-house in Bull-and-mouth street; the prisoner and that young woman came in. I asked the prisoner if he was married; he said, yes, and she said nothing to the contrary.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17611021-37-verdict193" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611021-37-verdict193" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17611021-37-punish194" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611021-37-punish194" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-37-defend500 t17611021-37-punish194"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
