<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610625-21">
               <interp inst="t17610625-21" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-21" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-21" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610625"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-21" type="date" value="17610625"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610625-21-off122-c141" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-21-defend176 t17610625-21-off122 t17610625-21-verdict126"></join>
         
               <p>199. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610625-21-defend176" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Brice 
                  <interp inst="t17610625-21-defend176" type="surname" value="Brice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-defend176" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-defend176" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17610625-21-deflabel121" type="occupation">esq</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-21-defend176 t17610625-21-deflabel121"></join>; was indicted for the <rs id="t17610625-21-off122" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-off122" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-off122" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               wilful murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17610625-21-victim178" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Jasper 
                        <interp inst="t17610625-21-victim178" type="surname" value="Jasper"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610625-21-victim178" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610625-21-victim178" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-21-off122 t17610625-21-victim178"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17610625-21-viclabel123" type="occupation">esq</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-21-victim178 t17610625-21-viclabel123"></join>; He stood charged on the coroner's inquest for manslaughter, <rs id="t17610625-21-cd124" type="crimeDate">May 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-21-off122 t17610625-21-cd124"></join>.* </p>
               <p>Counsel for the Crown.</p>
               <p>May it please your lordship, and you, gentlemen of the jury,</p>
               <p>I am counsel in this case for the crown, against 
               <persName id="t17610625-21-person179">
                  Joseph 
                  Brice 
               <interp inst="t17610625-21-person179" type="surname" value="Brice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-person179" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-person179" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the prisoner at the bar, who stands charged with the wilful murder of 
               <persName id="t17610625-21-person180">
                  Richard 
                  Jasper 
               <interp inst="t17610625-21-person180" type="surname" value="Jasper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-person180" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-person180" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , esq; by shooting him with a pistol, and thereby giving him a morral wound, of which he died; he stands charged also on the coroner's inquest for manslaughter.</p>
               <p>Gentlemen, As this transaction was entirely between themselves, when no-body else was present, I rather choose it should come from the witnesses mouths, than to make any paraphrase on the evidence, or endeavour to prepossess your minds.</p>
               <p>The case is this: the prisoner and the deceased were acquainted with each other. About two o'clock on the tenth of May they went to the <placeName id="t17610625-21-crimeloc125">Cardigan-head tavern , Charing-cross</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17610625-21-crimeloc125" type="placeName" value="Cardigan-head tavern , Charing-cross"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610625-21-crimeloc125" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-21-off122 t17610625-21-crimeloc125"></join>, whether in a state of reconciliation or enmity I cannot say; they were shewed an upper room, and called for a pint of wine; they had not been there above half an hour before a pistol was heard to go off; enquiry was made by the people of the house, the consequence was, they found Mr. Jasper was shot, and he died the next day of that wound.</p>
               <p>This is the sum of the evidence which I shall call and lay before you, and if it comes out to your satisfaction to be a murder, you will find the prisoner guilty.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-21-person181">
                  Luke 
                  Sullivan 
               <interp inst="t17610625-21-person181" type="surname" value="Sullivan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-person181" type="given" value="Luke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-person181" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was acquainted with Mr. Jasper, the deceased.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him at any time on Saturday the ninth of May?</p>
               <p>Sullivan. On Saturday the ninth of May I met him at Mundy's coffee-house in Round-court,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176106250020"></xptr> there were some other gentlemen there, we supped together.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any thing pass particular?</p>
               <p>Sullivan. Nothing particular. I came away much sooner than any of the rest of them; I left him in company with several gentlemen, there was the best harmony that could be when I left them.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Mr. Brice there?</p>
               <p>Sullivan. He was there to the best of my remembrance.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you doubtful of that?</p>
               <p>Sullivan. I am pretty certain he was there.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see Mr. Jasper afterwards?</p>
               <p>Sullivan. I called about two o'clock the Sunday following, Capt. Jasper was sitting there in the same coffee-house, I believe he was the only person there; he asked me if I dined there, I told him I did; he said he would stay and dine there too; then he proposed to take a walk to amuse ourselves till dinner was ready, but I objected to it, on the account of its being Sunday, and I did not choose to walk in such a publick street as the Strand, so I staid in the coffee-room.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Mr. Brice there?</p>
               <p>Sullivan. Mr. Brice came in some time after, Capt. Jasper was sitting on the table, and I on the bench by him. Upon Mr. Brice's coming in Capt. Jasper leaped from the table, and took him gently by the arm, and they walked to the other end of the room.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that done in anger?</p>
               <p>Sullivan. No, my Lord, far from it; I imagined he was going to make the same request to him as he had done to me, to dine with him: when he asked me, he said he wanted company. They made a very short stay at the other end of the room.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any words pass?</p>
               <p>Sullivan. I did not; they came down the coffee-room together, and went out together at the door, and did not return to dinner.</p>
               <p>Q. Did either of them say any thing to you at going out?</p>
               <p>Sullivan. No, not a word. Just at going out Capt. Jasper was speaking to Mr. Brice, but nothing that I could distinguish.</p>
               <p>Q. Did it appear as if there was anger betwixt them?</p>
               <p>Sullivan. Nothing of that appeared to me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-21-person182">
                  Charles 
                  Dunlop 
               <interp inst="t17610625-21-person182" type="surname" value="Dunlop"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-person182" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-person182" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . It is very little that I know of the matter.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Dunlop. I am a watchmaker, and live in Spring-gardens. On Sunday the tenth of May, between the hours of three and four in the afternoon, as I was going in at the Cardigan-head I heard the report of a pistol, I had just entered the room coming into the centre part of the house, the family was all in a flurry; Mr. Church, the master of the house, told me that two gentlemen had quarrelled, and one had shot the other, and desired I would go up stairs. When I came there I saw Mr. Jasper sitting on a chair, with a wound on his left-breast. Mr. Brice begged I would listen to some questions he should ask Mr. Jasper; he had applied to several, and they did not give attention: he applied to me, and said, You seem to be a little cool, I beg you will attend while I ask him some questions.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know Mr. Brice before?</p>
               <p>Dunlop. I never saw him before that in my life-time, to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know Mr. Jasper before?</p>
               <p>Dunlop. I have known him twenty years, ever since the hard winter in the year 1740.</p>
         
               <p>*** The Remainder of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17610625-21">
                  <interp inst="t17610625-21" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610625-21" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610625-21" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610625"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610625-21" type="date" value="17610625"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176106250021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commission of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Thursday the 25th, Friday the 26th, and Saturday the 27th of JUNE.</p>
                  <p>In the first Year of His MAJESTY's Reign. Being the Sixth SESSION in the MAYORALTY of The Right Honble Sir 
                  <persName id="t17610625-21-person183">
                     Matthew 
                     Blakiston 
                  <interp inst="t17610625-21-person183" type="surname" value="Blakiston"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610625-21-person183" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610625-21-person183" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Knt. LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON. NUMBER VI. PART II. for the YEAR 1761.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by J. SCOTT, at the Black-Swan, in Pater-noster Row.</p>
                  <p>M. DCC. LXI.</p>
                  <p>[Price FOUR-PENCE.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176106250022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commission of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery held for the City of London, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Q. WHAT was Mr. Jasper?</p>
               <p>Dunlop. He had belonged to the navy, but he was broke about five years ago. He was captain of a man of war.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he any family?</p>
               <p>Dunlop. I do not know that, I have not heard of any brother or sister; I knew his father, he was a great agent on Tower-hill, he used to receive prize-money for men of war.</p>
               <p>Q. What were the questions Mr. Brice ask'd Mr. Jasper?</p>
               <p>Dunlop. He said to Mr. Jasper, Have I used you like a gentleman? To which he gave no answer. Mr. Brice then said, Do you forgive me, Mr. Jasper? His answer then was, I was the aggressor, and immediately he slipp'd from the chair upon the floor.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he bleeding at the time?</p>
               <p>Dunlop. Very much. On his coming on the floor he became speechless for some little time, then he began to mutter something, which I could not understand; his voice growing a little louder, I leaned down (he lay then on the floor) the surgeon declared, if Mr. Brice had any more questions to ask him, then was the time, for he believed he could not live five minutes longer. The surgeon had then hold of it's arm, but had not bled him. Mr. Brice repeated the same questions, as near as I can remember: his answer was then, I am the aggressor. There were more people in the room at that time that heard it.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was in the room the first time?</p>
               <p>Dunlop. I can't say, every thing was pretty much in confusion: there were three or four people, waiters and others, when I heard him the first time; I staid about five minutes after, then a coach was got to carry Mr. Brice before justice Fielding.</p>
               <p>Q. When did Capt. Jasper die?</p>
               <p>Dunlop. He died the next day, as I heard.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him bled?</p>
               <p>Dunlop. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-21-person184">
                  John 
                  Medley 
               <interp inst="t17610625-21-person184" type="surname" value="Medley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-person184" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-person184" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep Mundy's coffee-house in Round-court.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember what passed at your house on Saturday the ninth of May?</p>
               <p>Medley. On Saturday evening, the ninth of May, about ten or eleven o'clock, Capt. Jasper came into my house; Mr. Brice, Mr. Sullivan, Mr. Montgomery, Mr. 
               <persName id="t17610625-21-person185">
                  Jones
               <interp inst="t17610625-21-person185" type="given" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-person185" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a jeweller, Mr. Creswick, Mr. 
               <persName id="t17610625-21-person186">
                  Richard 
                  Roach 
               <interp inst="t17610625-21-person186" type="surname" value="Roach"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-person186" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-person186" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and several gentlemen that used the house, were there before: Capt. Jasper joined them, about twelve they called for a bill.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did these other gentlemen you have mentioned come in?</p>
               <p>Medley. They had been there three or four hours before Capt. Jasper came, they came about seven or eight in the evening.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176106250023"></xptr>Q. Did Mr. Brice and Mr. Jasper use your house?</p>
               <p>Medley. They frequented my house very often.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they in the coffee-room, or up stairs?</p>
               <p>Medley. They were in the coffee-room, all at the same table.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Capt. Jasper acquainted with the company?</p>
               <p>Medley. He was with all of them, they were all friends together: when the bill was brought in, they all paid together; then Capt. Jasper said, he was sorry they were all going, he should have been glad to have whipp'd sixpence  more round; upon which, three or four of the gentlemen said they were obliged to go; then he asked Mr. Brice, and he said he would whip six-pence with him; upon which, I made a shilling's-worth of punch: then all the rest were gone, and the door shut up: they sat close together at the end of the table, talking of different things, what I do not know; but I heard Capt. Jasper say to Mr. Brice, you may think yourself a very clever fellow, but d - n me if I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they sober at that time?</p>
               <p>Medley. They had been drinking, but were not quite sober, nor quite drunk. Hearing him say that, I was at the upper end of the room, reading a book.</p>
               <p>Q. How far distant from them?</p>

               <p>Medley. About three or four yards. I looked at them, and I saw Capt. Jasper rub his hand up Mr. Brice's face, and knock his hat off; the hat fell on the table, Mr. Brice took it up, and put it on again, and said, Capt. Jasper, what did you that for? Is it by way of fun, or is it to offend me? Upon which Capt. Jasper said, How can you think I should do it by way of fun to such a fellow as you. Capt. Jasper rubb'd his hand up his face the same way as before, and knocked his hat off again, and got him by the ear with his right-hand. Mr. Brice said, This is too much, and struck Capt. Jasper in the face. Capt. Jasper had his sword on, and he drew it about three parts out.</p>
               <p>Q. Had Mr. 
               <persName id="t17610625-21-person187">
                  Brice
               <interp inst="t17610625-21-person187" type="given" value="Brice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-person187" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             any sword?</p>
               <p>Medley. No, I never saw him with a sword in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. What is Mr. Brice?</p>
               <p>Medley. He is a gentleman belonging to the law. Upon this I went up to Capt. Jasper, and put his sword back again, and begged that he would be quiet. He said, This man has treated me with such indignity, that I cannot live; either his life, or mine, shall pay for it, and bid me leave the room. I told him I should not. Then he took Mr. Brice by the arm, and walked up to the other end of the room, and said to him: Sir, I insist upon your fighting me. Mr. Brice said: Sir, I think we are hardly even, you struck me twice, and pulled my ear, and I only hit you once; I dare say to-morrow you'll think yourself in the wrong. Capt. Jasper said, No, I never can forgive you; I live at Mr. Crow's in Scotland-yard. Mr. Brice said, he might live where he pleased, he never should call upon him. Mr. Jasper said, If he did not either call upon him, or meet him and fight him, he wou ld certainly put him to death wherever he found him. Mr. Brice told him he never wore a sword, and was not used to fighting; and that he would neither call upon him, nor meet him; and if he fought him, he should seek him. I said to Capt. Jasper, Sir, I beg you will go home, and I dare say you will think better of it to-morrow. He went away, and Mr. Brice wished him a good night, and I went to see him to his chair.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of Mr. Brice?</p>
               <p>Medley. He staid, I believe, ten minutes, or a quarter of an hour, and then went home. He said, He wished he had gone with the rest of the company, when he found him so quarrelsome.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he say this?</p>
               <p>Medley. Just after Capt. Jasper was gone; I told him I once saved Capt. Gambier's life, when he drew his sword upon him, by going into the room.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known Capt. Jasper?</p>
               <p>Medley. I have known him ten years.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a man was he for temper?</p>
               <p>Medley. When he had been drinking, he was a very quarrelsome, proud, haughty man, as ever I saw in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he so when he had been drinking only.</p>
               <p>Medley. I have seen him quarrel at other times, when he has been sober, but he was not so bad as when in liquor; he was a very proud man.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he a passionate man in general.</p>
               <p>Medley. Yes, a little hasty and passionate, what we call a hot man.</p>
               <p>Q. Is Mr. Brice of that disposition?</p>
               <p>Medley. I never knew Mr. Brice offend any body in my life; he is a very quiet man as can be.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176106250024"></xptr>Q. Have you seen them very frequently together?</p>
               <p>Medley. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever observe any ill-blood between them?</p>
               <p>Medley. No, I never heard Mr. Brice have any words with any body; he was very quiet and peaceable as any man I ever knew in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you able to give an account of what led Capt. Jasper to this behavour? Had Mr. Brice said any thing to him?</p>
               <p>Medley. I did not hear Mr. Brice say any thing at all to him; Capt. Jasper was talking of forcing of trenches, and such like affairs; he was a military man.</p>
               <p>Bower Church. I keep the Cardigan-head tavern, Charing-cross.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember what past at your house on the 10th of May last?</p>
               <p>Church. That was Whitsunday: a little before three o'clock in the afternoon, I saw Capt. Jasper and a gentleman crossing the way, coming to my house; I was going to dinner behind my bar, I did not see them come in, they seemed to be in a hurry.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you describe the manner of their coming, whether arm in arm, or whether one went before and the other after, or whether side by side?</p>
               <p>Church. That I cannot take upon me to say.</p>
               <p>Q. What happened after?</p>
               <p>Church. I reckon it might be about half an hour after three o'clock, just as I had dined, I heard a pistol go off; upon hearing that, I ran out and called the waiter, and said there are some gentlemen fighting above; going up stairs I met a gentleman coming down; he called the waiter to go up and take care of the gentleman, for he was hurt. He was about half way down.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was that gentleman?</p>
               <p>Church. Upon my word, I was in such confusion, I do not know whether I went upon my hands or my head; I cannot tell who he was.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you know Mr. Brice at that time?</p>
               <p>Church. I never saw him in my life before that time. I ordered my servant to go and call the Tilt-yard guard, which I always do if there is like to be quarrelling. I ran out immediately to call in the neighbours; people came in; when I came back I went up stairs, there Captain Jasper lay on his back bleeding, and as I thought then expiring; he was frothing on each side his mouth.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was there then?</p>
               <p>Church. There was the same gentleman that I met on the stairs, and the guards were come, and I bid them take the gentleman to Mr. Fielding. Some time after that one of the gentlemen bled him, by the advice of a physician then present; upon b'eeding him, and giving him something to drink, he opened his eyes; I asked him if he knew me, he said yes; some time after that the gentlemen of the faculty desired me to send for some chairmen, and get a mattress, and remove him.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was this after he had been wounded?</p>
               <p>Church. I cannot justly tell; then they moved him up stairs; I went up to him in the evening, and asked him how he did, he said indifferent, I have been to blame; this was as he lay in bed. He died the next day, I believe about six in the evening; I never saw him after that time till he was dead.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-21-person188">
                  Edward 
                  Terry 
               <interp inst="t17610625-21-person188" type="surname" value="Terry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-person188" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-person188" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a waiter at the Cardiganhead.</p>
               <p>Q. Give an account of what past at your master's house on Whitsunday?</p>
               <p>Terry. Capt. Jasper was there, and another gentleman, named Brice; I never saw him before.</p>
               <p>Q. Look about; do you see that gentleman here?</p>
               <p>Terry. I do, that is the gentleman. [ Looking to the prisoner.]</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day were they there?</p>
               <p>Terry. I did not see them when they first came into the house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you wait on them?</p>
               <p>Terry. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the first thing that you observ'd?</p>
               <p>Terry. I was sitting in the house, and heard a pistol go off.</p>

               <p>Q. Who is the person that attended them?</p>
               <p>Terry. His name is 
               <persName id="t17610625-21-person189">
                  John 
                  Solomon 
               <interp inst="t17610625-21-person189" type="surname" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-person189" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-person189" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do, upon hearing the pistol?</p>
               <p>Terry. I went up stairs; I was the first person that went into the room, after the report of the pistol. I met Mr. Brice coming down; he desired me to step up stairs, and said, the gentleman was hurt; I said. Sir, by G - d, you must go up with me. I asked him where he was going, he said, for a surgeon; he turned, and went up with me, and the cook went with us. I found Capt. Jasper with the door in his hand, half open; he spoke to me very saintly.</p>
               <p>Q. Who spoke first?</p>
               <p>Terry. He did to me; he spoke very low. I was in a confusion, seeing the wound he had received.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176106250025"></xptr>Q. What did he say?</p>
               <p>Terry. To the best of my knowledge, he said, I hope he is secure. He spoke very low, but I understood it so.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you mean safe?</p>
               <p>Terry. I apprehend he meant secure.</p>
               <p>Q. What were the very words?</p>
               <p>Terry. To the best of my knowledge, the words were, I hope he is secure.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it secured, or secure?</p>
               <p>Terry. Not secured, but secure. Mr. Brice went into the room.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the word secure mentioned before Capt. Jasper had seen Mr. Brice?</p>
               <p>Terry. It was before he had seen him, he was coming behind me. As soon as Mr. Brice came in, he desired a surgeon might be sent for immediately. I went and got one, the first I could find. I heard Mr. Brice say to Capt. Jasper, My dear Jasper, I hope you forgive me.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the answer?</p>
               <p>Terry. I went out of the room for a surgeon, and did not wait for his answer, but went immediately.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you leave in the room?</p>

               <p>Terry. I left the cook, and Mr. Dunlop there, and others; I brought Mr. Wollaston; when I came back there were several people in the room.</p>
               <p>Q. When Capt. Jasper said he hoped he was secure, was any answer given by you to him at that time?</p>
               <p>Terry. I said, here is the gentleman.</p>
               <p>Q. What did Capt. Jasper say to that?</p>
               <p>Terry. He made no answer, but walked from the door; he said something very low, but I being  in a confusion, am not perfect in the words; it was immediately upon that, that Mr. Brice came into the room.</p>
               <p>Q. Recollect yourself about these words; was it I hope he is secure, or I hope you secured him?</p>
               <p>Terry. I have recollected as well as I can; it was, I hope he is secure.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you at that time understand that he wanted to know if he was taken up, so that he might be brought to justice?</p>
               <p>Terry. I have recollected and can make no more of it than what I have said; it was spoke very low.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you apprehend it, that he hoped Mr. Brice was got away and escaped? Which of the two did you understand it?</p>
               <p>Terry. I cannot tell how to recollect it, because he spoke very low.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-21-person190">
                  John 
                  Solomon 
               <interp inst="t17610625-21-person190" type="surname" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-person190" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-person190" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a waiter at the Cardiganhead. The prisoner and Capt. Jasper came in at my master's, and asked for a room; I shewed them a room up stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. Which asked for the room?</p>
               <p>Solomon. I do not know which asked; they called for a pint of wine, and pen, ink and paper.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any pistols with them, when you shewed them the room?</p>
               <p>Solomon. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What was done with the pen and ink?</p>
               <p>Solomon. Afterwards they called for a decanter of water, I carried it up, and saw them both writing, and capt. Jasper drank a glass of water.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any thing pass between them?</p>
               <p>Solomon. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any porter, or any other person come to them?</p>
               <p>Solomon. No; and after about a quarter of an hour, I heard the pistol go off.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-21-person191">
                  Jane 
                  Munroe 
               <interp inst="t17610625-21-person191" type="surname" value="Munroe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-person191" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-person191" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mr. Crow in Scotland yard, where capt. Jasper lodg'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of any thing that past on Whitsunday, at capt. Jasper's lodgings?</p>
               <p>J. Munroe. Yes sir, capt. Jasper did not get up till half an hour after one o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did he come home the night before?</p>
               <p>J. Munroe. He came home in the morning, I believe about three o'clock. When he rang the bell, I went into his room, he asked what o'clock it was; I said, half an hour after one. He desired me to get some water to wash him. I asked him if he would have any breakfast; he said no, he was going to breakfast at Mundy's coffee-house. He called for a waistcoat, I gave it him; and said to him, you never used to go abroad with this waistcoat, and asked him what time he would come in. He told me the waistcoat was good enough, I would never see him alive again. He said, I would either see him dead, or else hanged. I said, God forbid, the gentlemen at the coffeehouse will put you over that thought. He asked me, If I would rather see him dead, or hanged. I told him, I would rather see him dead; he said, A gentleman and he had a quarrel on Saturday night at Mundy's coffee-house, and he could not bear an affront from any man. He went out when it was just upon the stroke of two o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any pistols?</p>
               <p>J. Munroe. He never had pistols in his room in his life, as I know of; he had swords there.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176106250026"></xptr>Q. Did he go out in a chair or on foot?</p>
               <p>J. Munroe. He walked it.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is it from Scotland-yard, to Mundy's coffee-house?</p>
               <p>J. Munroe. The coffee-house is in Round-court, it is not a great way.</p>
               <p>Q. Who let him in, in the morning?</p>
               <p>J. Munroe. I did.</p>

               <p>Q. Did he say any thing to you then, about having any words with any-body?</p>
               <p>J. Munroe. No, he did not say three words to me, he was a little in liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he come home?</p>
               <p>J. Munroe. In a chair.</p>
               <p>Q. to Medley. What time did he go away from your house?</p>
               <p>Medley. He went away from my house, I believe between one and two.</p>
               <p>Q. to Munroe. Was it light or dark, when he came home?</p>
               <p>J. Munroe. It was day-light.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it day-light, or moon-light.</p>
               <p>J. Munroe. It was day-light, I could see to come down three pair of stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. to Sullivan. What time was it, that Mr. Brice came into the coffee-house, that Sunday?</p>
               <p>Sullivan. I came in a good while after two. About a quarter of an hour after, I found Mr. Jasper there; and Mr. Brice came in after I was there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-21-person192">
                  Margaret 
                  Denevel 
               <interp inst="t17610625-21-person192" type="surname" value="Denevel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-person192" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-person192" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I attended Mr. Jasper in his illness.</p>
               <p>Q. What illness?</p>
               <p>M. Denevel. He was wounded.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he make any declarations?</p>
               <p>M. Denevel. I heard him say before several gentlemen, that He was the aggressor, the fault was his, and he freely forgave Mr. Brice with all his hearts and soul by God. These were his words.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>M. Denevel. This was on Sunday night, before the physicians came to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he at any time ever say to the contrary of this, or to a different effect.</p>
               <p>M. Denevel. Never, that I declare before God.</p>
               <p>Mr. Wollaston. I attended capt. Jasper, I came to him on the 10th of May, between three and four in the afternoon, there were several people in the room when I went over to him; I found him lying on his back, with a wound on his left breast.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you bleed him?</p>
               <p>Wollaston. I did, he was quite senseless; and as I thought dying; he spoke before I bled him of his own accord.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say?</p>
               <p>Wollaston. He said, I was the aggressor. There was at that time a great confusion and noise in the room. I said to him, Capt. Jasper, what did you say? He repeated it again; I did not imagine at first he would ever speak again, this was before I bled him. He acknowledged himself greatly to blame, and said, He was intirely to blame.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember Dr. Groat asking him, whether Mr. Brice was to blame?</p>
               <p>Wollaston. Yes; and he said, I was solely to blame, I was intirely the aggressor. He repeated the words with different epithets, and said, It was intirely his own feeling. At another time it was, He was to blame. At another time, He was intirely to blame. At another time, It was his own seeking.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he continue in this?</p>
               <p>Wollaston. He was invariable to the last moment. I was scarce two hours from him, at any one time; I was with him when he died.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember any body asking him, whether Mr. Brice was to blame?</p>
               <p>Wollaston. Dr. Groat asked him, if he believed Mr. Brice had any malice against him, either before, or at the time, or after the affair. Capt. Jasper answered, he did not believe he had.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the occasion of his death?</p>
               <p>Wollaston. His death was in consequence of that wound.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after the time of the wound given, was you called in?</p>
               <p>Wollaston. I apprehend immediately.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any pistol?</p>
               <p>Wollaston. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ask him about them, during the time you attended him?</p>
               <p>Wollaston. I asked him how it came about, that his pistol was not fired. He said, I do n ot know, I did not choose to fire; I laid it down on the table.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what became of the pistols?</p>
               <p>Wollaston. I do not know any thing about them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ask him how he came not to choose to fire?</p>
               <p>Wollaston. No, I did not care to ask him, for fear of hurting him.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Then you had heard his pistol was not discharged.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176106250027"></xptr>Wollaston. I had.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ask him who bought them?</p>
               <p>Wollaston. No, I asked him no question relative to that; I asked him, if Mr. Brice had behaved like a gentleman in the affair; He said, All I knew of the matter is, he fired at me. During the time of his illness, he expressed his concern to me, two or three times, that Mr. Brice was in confinement.</p>
               <p>Dr. Power. On Sunday the 10th of last May, between three and four in the afternoon, Mr. Church of the Cardigan head, came into a coffee-house, near Charing-cross, where I was, and said, a gentleman was shot in his house, and desired I would go up and see him. I went and saw capt. Jasper, he was wounded in the left breast; I thought then he was near dying, that he had not many minutes to live. In about a quarter of an hour after, there being a good many more gentlemen in the room, they wanted to know whether it was proper to bleed him. I felt his pulse, and ordered him to be bled. He was bled, upon which he opened his eyes, and stirred his lips; we gave him two or three spoonfuls of wine and water; he turned his head and looked about him. We met again by appointment, I believe about half an hour after six, when he was put to bed, and his wound dressed.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there more wounds than one?</p>
               <p>Power. Only one wound that past through the body. After having ordered what we thought necessary for him, I mentioned to the gentlemen, Dr. Groat, Mr. Ford, Mr. Wollaston, Mr. Davenport, and I believe one or two more physicians and surgeons, that as Mr. Jasper was then in his senses, and made distinct and sensible answers to every question asked him, I thought it might be proper to ask him some questions relative to the affair, in the presence of us all, as I heard he had made some declarations in favour of Mr. Brice; and Dr. Groat, who was his acquaintance, asked him the following questions. Captain Jasper, do you know me? He answered yes, I do, my dear Johnny, know you very well. Pray Capt. Jasper, how did this happen? He answered, I was in fault, I brought it upon myself. Do you believe Mr. Brice had any malice against you? - No, I do not. Do you forgive him? - - Yes, I do. Who was the aggressor? - I was. You say you was the aggressor. - Yes by G - d I am, Sir I was. Would you have me declare this in favour of Mr. Brice. - Yes, I would by all means.</p>
               <p>Q. You have got it in writing, did you write it down at that time?</p>
               <p>Power. No, not at that time; I wrote it down on the Monday night after he died, while it was in my memory. This was on Whit-sunday.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you ask him any questions about the pistols?</p>
               <p>Power. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the pistols?</p>
               <p>Power. When first I came into the room, I saw pistols lying on the table.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they both of a size, as fellows?</p>
               <p>Power. They were; I did not take them in my hand, they appeared to be so.</p>
               <p>Dr. Groat. I knew capt. Jasper near 20 years. On Sunday the 10th of May, about four o'clock, I was sent for to visit capt. Jasper, who was wounded at the Cardigan head tavern. [He looks on a paper.]</p>
               <p>Q. What are you reading?</p>
               <p>Groat. This I wrote for my own information; I wrote it that very Sunday. I believe I can recollect it without reading.</p>
               <p>Court. You may look on the paper to refresh your memory.</p>
               <p>Groat. When I came into the room, I saw him lying at full length on the floor; his breast exposed, and a wound on the upper-part of the left-breast. I asked Mr. Wollaston, the surgeon, what had been done for him? I was answered, Nothing, because they did not think any thing could do him service. I was of the opinion, at that time, he was in the agonies of death. I stooped down, and felt his pulse labouring hard, seemingly oppressed. I desired Mr. Wollaston might bleed him. I saw Dr. Power in the room, and called to him to give me his opinion. He acquieseed in it, and he was blooded; and by the time six ounces, or less, was taken away, he turned his head about, moved his eyes, and opened his lips. I desired the quantity of blood might be encreased to eight ounces; on which he seemed still to recover. Some wine and water was poured down his throat; and after that I prescribed a warm stimulating cordial, which prescribed was signed by Dr. Power and myself. He was put to bed, and between six and seven I visited him again, in company with Dr. Power, and Mr. Ford, a surgeon, who is a man of eminence, that Mr. Brice had sent to take care of Capt. Jasper. After we had mentioned some things proper for him, coming down stairs, I said to Mr. Ford, it would be necessary (as he was then sensible) to go back into the room, and ask him some particular questions relating to this affair; and at fortyfive minutes after six in the evening, I asked Capt. 
               <persName id="t17610625-21-person193">
                  Jasper
               <interp inst="t17610625-21-person193" type="given" value="Jasper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-person193" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the following questions: I asked him first, if he knew me? His answer was<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176106250028"></xptr> Yes, my dear friend Johnny, I know you very well.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he use to call you by that name?</p>
               <p>Groat. Always; he frequently did, though my name is Robert. I then asked him if he thought Mr. Brice had any malice towards him, either before, at, or after the time of this affair. His answer was, I don't believe he had, for I never thought so. - How came you by this affair? - I was in the fault, it was entirely my own seeking. - Was you really the aggressor? - I was the aggressor indeed; and by G - d I was the aggressor; and I own I have brought this upon myself. - Do you forgive Mr. Brice, who shot you? - I do freely from my soul forgive him; for I say again, I was to blame. - Would you have me declare this for the safety of Mr. Brice? - Yes, I would, by all means. Sitting on the bed by Capt. Jasper, on Monday morning, a little after ten o'clock, I asked him if Mr. Brice had behaved upon the whole like a gentleman, and a man of honour? His answer was, Yes he has; but I could not live with the ignominy of having received a blow, as I was once a captain of a man of war. I knew him a lieutenant of a man of war, and a captain of a man of war.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know Mr. Brice before?</p>
               <p>Groat. I never had the pleasure of seeing Mr. Brice, 'till before Mr. Fielding that night, when he was charged with this affair.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-21-person194">
                  James 
                  Ford 
               <interp inst="t17610625-21-person194" type="surname" value="Ford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-person194" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-person194" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About six o'clock that Sunday evening I received a letter from Mr. Brice, desiring I would go immediately to the Cardiganhead, to Capt. Jasper, who was wounded. I went there immediately, and found several physical gentlemen with him; Dr. Groat, and others. I was introduced to Capt. Jasper, as a person sent by Mr. Brice; he received me with great satisfaction; I thought particular satisfaction; he received me with kindness, being sent by Mr. Brice. This was my own opinion of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he sensible?</p>
               <p>Ford. Quite sensible.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you known him before?</p>
               <p>Ford. I did not know him at all; he had been before that time dressed by the surgeons that attended him, so that I only felt his pulse, and asked him a few questions, as he seemed to be in a weak state. Then I went out with the other gentlemen, who had attended him before, to be particularly informed. It appeared unnecessary to vary the method, and we agreed to meet again that night at ten o'clock. Dr. Groat proposed to me to ask him some questions relative to the affair, and we returned, and they were asked him. The questions and answers were much the same as have been mentioned now. I observed, when the doctor asked him if Mr. Brice was the aggressor, he looked up with great vivacity, and said, No, by G - d, it was not he; I was. He spoke it with such particular emphasis, that conveyed more to me, I think, than the mere words. It was spoke with great earnestness. I observed his countenance at that time, it was exceedingly expressive; he confirmed by his looks, he seemed to have it understood, that Mr. Brice was not to blame. We met again that evening, and the next morning, but there was nothing more particular.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known Mr. Brice?</p>
               <p>Ford. I have long had the honour of knowing Mr. Brice, and all his family.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character as to humanity?</p>
               <p>Ford. I never heard any thing said against Mr. Brice's character in my life, they are as worthy people as any I know; the character of the whole family is unexceptionable: I never in my life heard any thing of his being liable to quarrel, or being of a hot disposition.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-21-person195">
                  Richard 
                  Davenport 
               <interp inst="t17610625-21-person195" type="surname" value="Davenport"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-person195" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-person195" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a surgeon. On Sunday the 10th of May, between three and four in the afternoon, a porter came to my house, from the Cardigan-head tavern, and desired me to come away immediately to a gentleman dangerously wounded. I was in Pall-mall. I believe I got there about ten minutes before four. I was conducted into a room, where I saw several gentlemen, Dr. Groat, and others: Capt. Jasper was lying speechless, and with the countenance of a man expiring. After some little consultation among ourselves, it was agreed to take some blood from him, which was done. Soon after this, in two or three minutes, he began to open his eyes, and had some marks of reviving. A little wine and water was given him; and after that he revived considerably, and began to speak, and some persons in the room began to ask him some questions. They were most of them strangers to me. I remember in his answers, he said he was the aggressor entirely, and seemed to acquit him.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was that him?</p>
               <p>Davenport. I suppose he meant Mr. Brice, he entirely acquitted him from any blame. Somebody<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176106250029"></xptr> in the room asked him if they had each of them their pistols: he said, Each of them had.</p>
               <p>Q. Who asked that question?</p>
               <p>Davenport. I do not know who asked it, they were all strangers to me. I believe at this time the last witnesses were gone out of the room. I remember he said, Each presented his own, and at the same time. I asked this one question, Whether each of them loaded his own pistol? He answered in the affirmative, that they did. I found the questions rather fatigued him, and I desired they would get him to bed as fast as possible. A bed was prepared, and he was carried up to it. Then I assisted in dressing him as he lay on the floor; his breast was bloody. The wound was in the left-breast, which had gone quite through the body.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ask whose pistols they were?</p>
               <p>Davenport. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Nor who brought them there?</p>
               <p>Davenport. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the pistols?</p>
               <p>Davenport. They were not there when I was there; I came in late; I never saw them; I never heard him say any thing material, more than what I mentioned; but he expressed himself, more than once, with great indifference about his recovery, and said, No matter whether  he recovered or not. It was expressed with a great deal of in difference. I was not present at the time these gentlemen asked the questions.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>My Lord, I am extremely sorry that I am obliged to appear before your Lordship in this court, for a crime of this nature. The evidence is such, that I hope will convince the whole world that I could not avoid coming to the extremity that I did, which was owing to the violence of the deceased. I shall not take up your Lordship's time any farther, but leave it upon the evidence that has been given. I have several gentlemen in court that know me, which I shall call to my character.</p>
               <p>Counsel for prisoner. I beg leave to submit to your Lordship, the distinction made by my Lord Hale, the greatest writer on this subject, between murder and manslaughter, and apply this case to that general occasion.</p>
               <p>His Lordship said, There was no doubt at all about it on this evidence.</p>
               <p>Counsel for prisoner. There is no occasion to call any witnesses to his character.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610625-21-verdict126" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-verdict126" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-verdict126" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610625-21-punish127" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-punish127" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-21-punish127" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-21-defend176 t17610625-21-punish127"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
