<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660514-10">
               <interp inst="t17660514-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660514-10" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660514-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660514"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660514-10" type="date" value="17660514"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660514-10-off58-c92" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-10-defend112 t17660514-10-off58 t17660514-10-verdict63"></join>
         
               <p>294. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660514-10-defend112" type="defendantName">
                     Susanna 
                     Garrett 
                  <interp inst="t17660514-10-defend112" type="surname" value="Garrett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-10-defend112" type="given" value="Susanna"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-10-defend112" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17660514-10-deflabel57" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-10-defend112 t17660514-10-deflabel57"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17660514-10-off58" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660514-10-off58" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-10-off58" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 3 linen curtains, value 50 s. 49 yards of worsted damask, 3 worsted bed curtains, 3 vallens, 7 yards of linen and woolen cloth, 13 yards of harrateen, 2 yards of mazarine, 6 breadths of blue china, 2 other pieces of china, 5 yards of linen cloth, one damask table cloth, one diaper ditto, one stewpan, one flat iron, 3 yards of nankeen, 2 pair of cotton stockings, one bed-tick, 2 pair of silver buckles, 2 green window curtains, one head cloth for a bed, one remnant of harrateen, 4 bed-ticks, 3 remnants of linen, 2 pair of silver knee buckles, 2 odd buttons set in silver, 2 pair of stone-studs set in silver, one linen counterpane, 4 linen curtains, one copper drinking-pot, one silver table spoon, one silver tooth-pick case, 10 breadths of green worsted damask, one green china head-cloth, one teaster for a bed, one curtain, 4 other curtains, on sattin waistcoat, 34 pieces of crimson damask, 7 pieces of yellow harrateen, 2 pieces of nankeen, a remnant of crimson damask, 2 linen table cloths, 2 pair of ruffled sleeves, a remnant of gold and silver brocaded silk, a pottage-pot, 2 yards of Manchester velvet, a silver medal, 5 yards of green cloth serge, 4 bound books, one brass sender, and one cloth roquelaure
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17660514-10-victim114" type="victimName">
                     Richard 
                     Chillingworth 
                  <interp inst="t17660514-10-victim114" type="surname" value="Chillingworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-10-victim114" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-10-victim114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-10-off58 t17660514-10-victim114"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17660514-10-cd59" type="crimeDate">April 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-10-off58 t17660514-10-cd59"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-10-person115">
                  Richard 
                  Chillingworth 
               <interp inst="t17660514-10-person115" type="surname" value="Chillingworth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-10-person115" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-10-person115" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an <rs id="t17660514-10-viclabel60" type="occupation">upholsterer and broker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-10-victim114 t17660514-10-viclabel60"></join>, in <placeName id="t17660514-10-crimeloc61">Water-lane, Black-friars</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17660514-10-crimeloc61" type="placeName" value="Water-lane, Black-friars"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660514-10-crimeloc61" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-10-off58 t17660514-10-crimeloc61"></join>; the prisoner was <rs id="t17660514-10-deflabel62" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-10-defend112 t17660514-10-deflabel62"></join> to me about 7 months: about 3 or 4 months ago I began to miss things; when I asked the prisoner if she knew any thing of them, she would say, no; this has been her answer in common. At last, I got a warrant and took her up; she owned she had taken all the things, and begged<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176605140008"></xptr> I would not hurt her; she said they were pawned, and she had friends in the country that would help her to money to take them out. She said one Mrs. Lloyd had prevailed upon her to let her have some of my goods.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is Mrs. Lloyd?</p>
               <p>Chillingworth. She did live in Poppin's-alley, but is since dead; she was an intimate acquaintance of the prisoner's. I kept the prisoner afterward, in hopes she would get the things replaced.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after this did you keep her in your house?</p>
               <p>Chillingworth. I kept her about a month after, and waited upon one of her relations, and asked her if she would be so good as to assist her to fetch the things out; she told me the prisoner had been so expensive to her relations, that she would not do it; then I told the prisoner I would not lose my goods, and if she could not get them out, I must take another method; she said she would write to her aunt in the country, and put it off from time to time, so I was resolved to take her up.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after this relation refused to take the things out was it that you took her up?</p>
               <p>Chillingworth. I believe it was within a fortnight; I took her before my Lord-Mayor, there she acknowledged that she had been guilty of taking every thing mentioned in the indictment, and that they were in pawn; I found out the woman that sent them to pawn, that was Mrs. Lloyd, who acknowledged she sent her servant named Clifford with them to pawn, and the places where they were pawned; some at Mr. Wilmot's, some at the corner of Stonecutter-street in the Fleet-market, and other places, (the goods mentioned in the indictment produced in court.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-10-person116">
                  Jane 
                  Clifford 
               <interp inst="t17660514-10-person116" type="surname" value="Clifford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-10-person116" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-10-person116" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lived servant with Mrs. Lloyd; she sent me with these things to pawn, some to Mr. Wilmot, some to Mr. Patterson, some to Mr. Sclater, and a roquelaure to Mr. Gobbin, pawnbrokers; the prisoner used to be at Mrs. Lloyd's every night, and brought them at separate times; I did not know they were stolen.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-10-person117">
                  John 
                  Piercey 
               <interp inst="t17660514-10-person117" type="surname" value="Piercey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-10-person117" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-10-person117" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , servant to Mr. Wilmot, 
               <persName id="t17660514-10-person118">
                  Thomas 
                  Cotteril 
               <interp inst="t17660514-10-person118" type="surname" value="Cotteril"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-10-person118" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-10-person118" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , servant to Mr. Patterson, and Mr. Sclater, each mentioned the goods they took in of Clifford at separate times, which were deposed to by the prosecutor as his property; 
               <persName id="t17660514-10-person119">
                  William 
                  Pain 
               <interp inst="t17660514-10-person119" type="surname" value="Pain"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-10-person119" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-10-person119" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the constable deposed, he found the goods at their respective houses.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I had not a farthing of the money; this Clifford fetched them from our house at different times; they promised me I should have them again. My master knew of it 3 or 4 months before Mrs. Lloyd died. She had a flattering tongue, and said, I should have them all to be put into their places again.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. If you could have got your goods back again, should you have prosecuted the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No, I should not.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660514-10-verdict63" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660514-10-verdict63" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
