<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17630518-40">
               <interp inst="t17630518-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630518-40" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630518-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17630518"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630518-40" type="date" value="17630518"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17630518-40-off225-c287" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-40-defend367 t17630518-40-off225 t17630518-40-verdict229"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17630518-40-off225-c288" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-40-defend369 t17630518-40-off225 t17630518-40-verdict229"></join>
         
               <p>248, 249. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17630518-40-defend367" type="defendantName">
                     Michael 
                     Ryley 
                  <interp inst="t17630518-40-defend367" type="surname" value="Ryley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-defend367" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-defend367" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17630518-40-defend369" type="defendantName">
                     Jonathan 
                     Dennison 
                  <interp inst="t17630518-40-defend369" type="surname" value="Dennison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-defend369" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-defend369" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted for <rs id="t17630518-40-off225" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-off225" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-off225" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that they, on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17630518-40-victim371" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Smith 
                        <interp inst="t17630518-40-victim371" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630518-40-victim371" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630518-40-victim371" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-40-off225 t17630518-40-victim371"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and stealing from his person one hat. val. 8 s. and one perriwig, val. 10 s. his property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17630518-40-cd226" type="crimeDate">April 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-40-off225 t17630518-40-cd226"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630518-40-person372">
                  Thomas 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17630518-40-person372" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-person372" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-person372" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17630518-40-viclabel227" type="occupation">baker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-40-victim371 t17630518-40-viclabel227"></join>, and live in St. George's, Wapping. I was going home on the 21st of April, about 11 at night, by the <placeName id="t17630518-40-crimeloc228">Butcher-row in East Smithfield</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17630518-40-crimeloc228" type="placeName" value="Butcher-row in East Smithfield"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17630518-40-crimeloc228" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-40-off225 t17630518-40-crimeloc228"></join>, it was a very moon-light night, the two prisoner and the evidence came cross the way, and Dennison gave me a blow on my side with a stick, and got behind me and seized my hat, I put my hand up to save my head, then Roley came and knocked me down, and took my wig; they had all three sticks, (a large stick produced) this is the stick Ryley knock'd me down with. Seeing nothing but death before my eyes, I called out murder and thieves; they never spoke, but laid me on in a violent manner; they ran away, but were all three secured in a few minutes time in the watch-house; I knew them all perfectly. At the Justice's they denied it, and said they did not know one another; soon after Dennison said, how could we rob this gentleman when we were all three in company together at Stepney? Ryley said the same; then they said, if they did do it, I had my wig again.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630518-40-person373">
                  William 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17630518-40-person373" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-person373" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-person373" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was the officer of the night. I had heard a thief's whistle, I went to look towards Tower-hill; coming back into the watch-house, I heard murder and thieves cried towards the Butcher-row, I made what haste I could that way, I saw there two or three men running as fast as possible, they had all got through the posts but one, I jump'd through, and whether I touch'd that man or not, down he fell, and I upon him, I brought him to the watch-house, that was Ryley; other people were pursuing, they soon brought in Dennison and the evidence. The prosecutor there declared, that Dennison and Ryley were the two persons that robbed him; he said, he was not sure whether Mates the evidence used him ill or not, but he was in company with the others. They had each a stick. I took out of Ryley's pocket this clasp-knife. (Producing a knife, the blade about seven inches long.) Before the Justice they all said, they did not know one another; at last they all owned, they came together from Stepney.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630518-40-person374">
                  Abraham 
                  Tilcherry 
               <interp inst="t17630518-40-person374" type="surname" value="Tilcherry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-person374" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-person374" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I and 
               <persName id="t17630518-40-person375">
                  Anthony 
                  Glyn 
               <interp inst="t17630518-40-person375" type="surname" value="Glyn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-person375" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-person375" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             were going from Tower-hill towards East-Smithfield on the 21st of April, about 11 at night, it was a moon-light night, we met with the two prisoners and evidence, they had three club-sticks in their hands, they made a stop and looked at us, I saw their faces plain enough; when they were ten or fourteen yards from us, going towards the May-pole, we heard murder cried, we were then as near the Butcher-row as it is cross this courtyard; these three men came running back again as fast as they could towards Tower-hill we turned and run after them and cried, stop, shipmate! what signifies stopping, said one of them, it is only a drunken man which we ran against and he fell down. Mr. Smith catched Ryley just by the watch-house; Mates the evidence ran up into a corner, I and 
               <persName id="t17630518-40-person376">
                  Anthony 
                  Glyn 
               <interp inst="t17630518-40-person376" type="surname" value="Glyn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-person376" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-person376" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             took him; I left him in Glyn's hands, and ran after Dennison, he ran up a court and got into some small gardens, people out of the windows told us where, then Glyn came, and seeing him upon a place said, if he would not come down, he would knock him down; Dennison said, if he would not hurt him, he would come down, which he did, and Glyn secured him; the other two had not been out of our sight at all, but Dennison might have been out of our sight about ten minutes.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630518-40-person377">
                  Anthony 
                  Glyn 
               <interp inst="t17630518-40-person377" type="surname" value="Glyn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-person377" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-person377" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirmed the evidence given by Tilcherry.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630518-40-person378">
                  George 
                  Comberlidge 
               <interp inst="t17630518-40-person378" type="surname" value="Comberlidge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-person378" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-person378" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I came that evening from Clapham with my master, who lives about a stone's cast from the Butcher-row, East-Smithfield; just as we got into the house, I heard murder cried, I ran, and saw the prosecutor without hat or wig, I ran after the prisoners, the constable immediately took Ryley, and while he was on the ground, I took that stick here produced out of Ryley's hand.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630518-40-person379">
                  John 
                  Branson 
               <interp inst="t17630518-40-person379" type="surname" value="Branson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-person379" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-person379" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17630518-40-person380">
                  Thomas 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17630518-40-person380" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-person380" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-person380" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and I were going from the Custom-House towards Iron-gate, on the 21st of April, about a quarter before eleven at night; the two prisoners and the evidence were upon Little Tower-Hill, they made an attempt upon us; Mates struck Williams, I prick'd Riley in the belly with my tuck, and I believe I prick'd Dennison in the hand. They all appear'd to be of the same company.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630518-40-person381">
                  Thomas 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17630518-40-person381" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-person381" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-person381" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed to the same effect.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630518-40-person382">
                  Joseph 
                  Mates 
               <interp inst="t17630518-40-person382" type="surname" value="Mates"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-person382" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-person382" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 21st of last month, the two prisoners and I were all at Stepney together playing at skettles; we came from thence<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176305180025"></xptr> about seven, and drank from alehouse to alehouse in the back lane till about eight, then we went to the Ship and Star in East-Smithfield by the May-pole, and staid there till about ten; we passed these two officers on Tower-Hill; then we went up Little Tower-Hill, and met the prosecutor in East Smithfield about eleven; Dennison took his hat, Riley knocked him down and took his Wig; we ran away all together towards Tower-Hill, and were all taken. I have been from sea about three months.</p>
               <p>Ryley said nothing in his defence.</p>
               <p>Dennison's Defence.</p>
               <p>I think it is a great imposition put upon me, to let a man swear my life away innocently, I thought the law would remedy this. I defy any man in the world betwixt me and my great God in heaven, to say I ever wronged a man of a shilling; I have many good friends in London, and I have as honest a principle as the best of them.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17630518-40-verdict229" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-verdict229" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17630518-40-punish230" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630518-40-punish230" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-40-defend367 t17630518-40-punish230"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-40-defend369 t17630518-40-punish230"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
