<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17600227-32">
               <interp inst="t17600227-32" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600227-32" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600227-32" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600227"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600227-32" type="date" value="17600227"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600227-32-off173-c224" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600227-32-defend283 t17600227-32-off173 t17600227-32-verdict176"></join>
         
               <p>113. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17600227-32-defend283" type="defendantName">
                  Charles 
                  Cullam 
               <interp inst="t17600227-32-defend283" type="surname" value="Cullam"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-32-defend283" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-32-defend283" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17600227-32-off173" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600227-32-off173" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-32-off173" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               the wilful murder of 
                     <persName id="t17600227-32-victim284" type="victimName">
                        Rose 
                        Cullam 
                     <interp inst="t17600227-32-victim284" type="surname" value="Cullam"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600227-32-victim284" type="given" value="Rose"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600227-32-victim284" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600227-32-off173 t17600227-32-victim284"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , his infant, about five months of age, by throwing her out of a three pair of stairs window
            </rs>, <rs id="t17600227-32-cd174" type="crimeDate">January 20</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600227-32-off173 t17600227-32-cd174"></join>. He stood likewise charged on the coroner's inquest for the said murder. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600227-32-person285">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Barden 
               <interp inst="t17600227-32-person285" type="surname" value="Barden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-32-person285" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-32-person285" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17600227-32-crimeloc175">Rupert Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17600227-32-crimeloc175" type="placeName" value="Rupert Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17600227-32-crimeloc175" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600227-32-off173 t17600227-32-crimeloc175"></join>, almost facing the prisoner at the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. What house does he live in?</p>
               <p>E. Barden. He lives at Mrs. Rook's house, in the same street. I saw the prisoner with a child<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176002270027"></xptr> in his arms, at his chamber window, on the 20th of January last, between the hours of two and three in the afternoon.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you at that time?</p>
               <p>E. Barden. I was at a one pair of stairs window in my own room.</p>
               <p>Q. In what manner did he hold the child?</p>
               <p>E. Barden. He held it in both his hands, and the head of the child was on his right arm.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you observe him standing there?</p>
               <p>E. Barden. It was that minute that I saw him there; he made but one motion and gave it a swing from his arm [ describing in what manner he did it, not much unlike that of flinging a casting net] He came side ways to the window, and so flung it out into the street.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the child alive, can you tell, before he flung it out?</p>
               <p>E. Barden. I cannot tell. I saw its fingers move as it was coming down like a pidgeon.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the child move in his arms before he flung it out?</p>
               <p>E. Barden. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had he lived in that place?</p>
               <p>E. Barden. I cannot tell that.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it his own child?</p>
               <p>E. Barden. He was reputed to be the father of it.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>E. Barden. I am servant to a widow gentlewoman.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever seen him with that child in his arms before?</p>
               <p>E. Barden. No.</p>
               <p>Q. How old was the child?</p>
               <p>E. Barden. The child wanted three days of five months old.</p>
               <p>Q. Has the prisoner any other children?</p>
               <p>E. Barden. No, not to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. What was his general behaviour?</p>
               <p>E. Barden. I never heard any body give him an ill character in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the child after it sell?</p>
               <p>E. Barden. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether or not, when he came to give it that swing, you imagine he did it with an intent to destroy the child?</p>
               <p>E. Barden. It had that appearance to me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600227-32-person286">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Wallan 
               <interp inst="t17600227-32-person286" type="surname" value="Wallan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-32-person286" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-32-person286" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Rupert-Street. I was in my mother's shop below the prisoner, between the hours of two and three, on the 20th of January. I do not know whether by accident or what, but I saw the child fall by the side of our window; I ran out immediately and took it up, but it was then stone dead. It came out at the three pair of stairs window.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you seen the child last before th</p>
               <p>E. Wallan. I had seen it alive and hearty a three hours before.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you imagine was the death of the child?</p>
               <p>E. Wallan. It was the fall that kill'd it.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has the prisoner lived there?</p>
               <p>E. Wallan. My mother has kept the house between eight and nine years, and the prisoner has lived there twelve months last Christmas. The child was born last Bartholomew-day in the morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever observed the prisoner's behaviour to the child?</p>
               <p>E. Wallan. I never saw him behave amiss to it. When it cried he always made a noise about it, and was always tender of it as far as I could see.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him soon after it fell?</p>
               <p>E. Wallan. I did; he came down stairs immediately, and said, my child, my child. I said your child is dead. His wife and he came both crying together.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he seem to be in very great concern?</p>
               <p>E. Wallan. I was so concern'd in taking up the child, that I cannot say as to that; he went to my mother's apartment, and said to his wife, give it the bubby, give it the bubby.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever seen him use this child with any sort of cruelty?</p>
               <p>E. Wallan. No, he always seem'd to be very fond of it.</p>
               <p>Q. What passed after he desired his wife to give it the bubby?</p>
               <p>E. Wallan. He was secured and carried to the round-house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say it had fallen from his arms?</p>
               <p>E. Wallan. He said he was dancing it, and it went out of his arms.</p>
               <p>Q. What highth may that window be from the floor of the room?</p>
               <p>E. Wallan. It is a high window with a casement.</p>
               <p>Q. Might not such an accident happen by playing with a child in a man's arms?</p>
               <p>E. Wallan. I am not a judge of that; it is a great way over from the window, because there is a gutter before it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600227-32-person287">
                  Barnaby 
                  Lord 
               <interp inst="t17600227-32-person287" type="surname" value="Lord"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-32-person287" type="given" value="Barnaby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-32-person287" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the prisoner's room at the time the child went out of the window; his wife was dressing some steaks, and he 
               <persName id="t17600227-32-person288">
                  drew
               <interp inst="t17600227-32-person288" type="given" value="drew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-32-person288" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176002270028"></xptr> cradle towards the fire, from the farther side of the room; the child then was in it, he thought the day was cold.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was that before the child went out at the window?</p>
               <p>Lord. It was about half an hour before:</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was it that it went out?</p>
               <p>Lord. It was between two and three in the afternoon.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did it continue in the cradle before he took it in his arms?</p>
               <p>Lord. Not long; he soon took it up, put it upon his knee, and sat by the fire-side; he seem'd to be fond of it, and made as much of it as ever he could; he put his left-hand under its back-side, hug'd it to his breast, and walked about the room with it.</p>
               <p>Q. Whereabouts in the room was you?</p>
               <p>Lord. I was sitting by the fire-side. I saw him walking backwards and forwards with it in his room, but I did not see how it went out at the window.</p>
               <p>Q. Which way was your face?</p>
               <p>Lord. My face was towards the fire. I heard the prisoner run down stairs and his wife after him. Oh! the child is gone, said he.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he cry out as soon as the child was gone?</p>
               <p>Lord. Yes, yes he did. I ran down after him. He made no stay, but as soon as the child fell he ran down; I believe in my conscience he did not do it wilfully. There was a blanket round the child; he had that in his hand after the child was gone.</p>
               <p>Q. After he ran down, did he seem to be very much concerned?</p>
               <p>Lord. He did; he went into his landlady's shop, and then they took and carried him away to St. James's round-house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say any thing about its being an accident?</p>
               <p>Lord. I did not hear any thing of that.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the breadth of that gutter between the window and the street?</p>
               <p>Lord. It is not a great breadth. The window is just upon a level with the gutter; a body could hardly put one's foot in the gutter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600227-32-person289">
                  Thomas 
                  English 
               <interp inst="t17600227-32-person289" type="surname" value="English"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-32-person289" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-32-person289" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am beadle of the parish, and attended the croner's jury; he sent me to take the dimensions of the window, here it is ( producing a paper.)</p>
               <p>Q. Who wrote that?</p>
               <p>English. I did.</p>
               <p>Court. read it,</p>
               <p>It is read.</p>
               <p>The breadth of the casement is 18 inches. The breadth from the bottom of the window to the outside of the parapet is 19 inches. The parapet is about 2 inches lower than the bottom of the window. The height of the casement is full 33 inches and a half. From the floor to the bottom of the window is about 3 feet.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I loved my child too well to go to throw it out at the window, the child flip'd out of the blanket. I thought the blanket was tied about its cloaths. If I had had a mind to have destroy'd my baby, could I not have had a better opportunity to do it than to throw it out at the window in the middle of the day?</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600227-32-person290">
                  Betty 
                  Askins 
               <interp inst="t17600227-32-person290" type="surname" value="Askins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-32-person290" type="given" value="Betty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-32-person290" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I moved into George-Court on Monday, and this accident happened on the Sunday following. I was at the end of the court, facing the prisoner's window, when this accident happened.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you see the window plain?</p>
               <p>B. Askins. I could see it as plain as I can see this window ( pointing to a window in the court.)</p>
               <p>Q. What did you see at the window?</p>
               <p>B. Askins. I saw the prisoner dancing the child at the window.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know him before?</p>
               <p>B. Askins. I never saw him before to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. In what manner did he hold it?</p>
               <p>B. Askins. He had it on one of his arms, I cannot tell which; it was upright, with a blanket loose about it.</p>
               <p>Q. How near did he stand to the window?</p>
               <p>B. Askins. As near as possibly he could; the child came out at the window, and the man had the blanket in his hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you observed him any matter of time?</p>
               <p>B. Askins. I had my little boy in my hand, and was looking at the prisoner two or three minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you had observed him so long?</p>
               <p>B. Askins. I am certain of that, if not more: I look'd at him all the while.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be looking up?</p>
               <p>B. Askins. Because I heard him cheriping to the child.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176002270029"></xptr>Q. Did it seem to fall from his hand by a slip, or as if flying from him?</p>
               <p>B. Askins. I cannot say whether it fell or whether he flung it, but he had the blanket in his hand, and cry'd out, O Lord! my child is gone. He went backwards from the window, and the mother of the child lean'd out at the window, so that I thought every moment she would have been down. I saw a woman pick the child up, it was kill'd by the fall.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600227-32-person291">
                  Jane 
                  Mullings 
               <interp inst="t17600227-32-person291" type="surname" value="Mullings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-32-person291" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-32-person291" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My husband and I happened to be coming up Rupert-Street on that Sunday. We saw a man playing and dancing, and singing to a child, I saw it fall out at the window.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you looking up at the instant it fell from his arms?</p>
               <p>J. Mullings. No, but I saw the child coming down, and the blanket in the man's arms.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600227-32-verdict176" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600227-32-verdict176" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-32-verdict176" type="verdictSubcategory" value="accidentalDeath"></interp>
               Acquitted. Accidental death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
