<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17600116-21">
               <interp inst="t17600116-21" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600116-21" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600116-21" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600116-21" type="date" value="17600116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600116-21-off111-c157" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600116-21-defend198 t17600116-21-off111 t17600116-21-verdict114"></join>
         
               <p>65. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17600116-21-defend198" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Elizabeth 
                     Warner 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17600116-21-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600116-21-defend198 t17600116-21-alias-3"></join>Betty</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-defend198" type="surname" value="Warner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-defend198" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-defend198" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17600116-21-deflabel110" type="occupation">single woman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600116-21-defend198 t17600116-21-deflabel110"></join>, was indicted for that <rs id="t17600116-21-off111" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-off111" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-off111" type="offenceSubcategory" value="infanticide"></interp>
               she, on the <rs id="t17600116-21-cd112" type="crimeDate">28th of November</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600116-21-off111 t17600116-21-cd112"></join>, was big with a certain male child, and afterwards was privately, and secretly delivered, by the providence of God, of that child alive, which, by the laws of this land, was called a bastard, and as soon as it was born, she, feloniously, wilfully, and of malice aforethought, with both her hands, did throw into a certain necessary house, by which means she, the said male child, did kill and murder
            </rs>; she likewise stood charged on the coroner's inquest for the said murder.*</p>
               <p>John Whitman. I am a nightman, and found a child in a privy belonging to Mr. Welch, in <placeName id="t17600116-21-crimeloc113">Plough-street, near Red-lion-square</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17600116-21-crimeloc113" type="placeName" value="Plough-street, near Red-lion-square"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17600116-21-crimeloc113" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600116-21-off111 t17600116-21-crimeloc113"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. When?</p>
               <p>Whitman. On the 29th of November last. I remember it was on the thanksgiving day.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a male or a female?</p>
               <p>Whitman. It was a male child.</p>
               <p>Tuncella Webb. I am a midwife, and saw this child as soon as it was cleaned, after it was taken out of the privy.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a male or female?</p>
               <p>T. Webb. It was a boy.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it at full growth or otherwise?</p>
               <p>T. Webb. To the best of my knowledge it was at full growth. I know nothing more, only seeing the woman [meaning the prisoner] in her bed in the workhouse.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600116-21-person200">
                  Sarah 
                  Sawyer 
               <interp inst="t17600116-21-person200" type="surname" value="Sawyer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-person200" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-person200" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner came in very uneasy to the alehouse where I live, that is, the Man in the Moon alehouse in Plough street, in the evening before the thanksgiving day.</p>
               <p>Q. What hour?</p>
               <p>S. Sawyer. It was not quite eight at night. I took great notice of her being so uneasy. I went away, and left her there.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you go away?</p>
               <p>S. Sawyer. I went away presently after I took notice of her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you return again that night?</p>
               <p>S. Sawyer. I was gone better than a quarter of an hour, and when I came again, I was told the woman was delivered of a child in the vault.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the child?</p>
               <p>S. Sawyer. I did, after it was taken out; there was a great uprear among the people, and they said the child was there.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a male or female?</p>
               <p>S. Sawyer. It was a male child. I saw a great quantity of blood on the top of the window shutter belonging to that alehouse.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it within the publick house?</p>
               <p>S. Sawyer. No, it is just as you come out at the door; I helped to clean it, and after that I went up to see her.</p>
         
               <p>Note, The Remainder of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17600116-21">
                  <interp inst="t17600116-21" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17600116-21" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17600116-21" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600116"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17600116-21" type="date" value="17600116"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176001160021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON, And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 16th, and Thursday the 17th of JANUARY,</p>
                  <p>In the Thirty-third Year of His MAJESTY'S Reign. NUMBER II. PART II. for the YEAR 1760. Being the Second SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of The Right Honble Sir 
                  <persName id="t17600116-21-person201">
                     THOMAS 
                     CHITTY 
                  <interp inst="t17600116-21-person201" type="surname" value="CHITTY"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600116-21-person201" type="given" value="THOMAS"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600116-21-person201" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Knt. LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by G. KEARSLY (Successor to the late Mr. Robinson) at the Golden-Lion, in Ludgate-Street, 1760.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176001160022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, and Oyer and Terminer, for the City of LONDON, and at the General 
                  <persName id="t17600116-21-person202">
                     Sessions
                  <interp inst="t17600116-21-person202" type="given" value="Sessions"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600116-21-person202" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                     </persName>
                of Gaol Delivery of Newgate, holden for the said City of LONDON, and County of MIDDLESEX, at Justice-Hall in the Old-Bailey, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Q WHERE was she?</p>
               <p>S. Sawyer. She was in an empty room two or three doors beyond, sitting on a basket; I saw something lying by her wrap'd up in a cloth, which I open'd and look'd at, and after I had seen it said, it was very odd that one thing should be there, and not the other, meaning the child.</p>
               <p>Q. What answer did she make you?</p>
               <p>S. Sawyer. She made me no answer at all.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600116-21-person203">
                  Mary 
                  Lawson 
               <interp inst="t17600116-21-person203" type="surname" value="Lawson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-person203" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-person203" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to the Man in the Moon alehouse on the 28th of November, where I saw the prisoner at the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. At what time?</p>
               <p>M. Lawson. It was in the evening, but I can't say the hour; the prisoner was stitching the form of prayer, to have them ready to sell the next day; after that I saw her rise from her seat, seeming not to be well, and asked her if she was not well; she reply'd she was as well as ever, went out of doors, stay'd some short time, and return'd back again. As she was standing by the fire, she turn'd back her apron, and I saw the bottom of it was very bloody. Mrs. Johnson stood by and said to her, what ails your apron? she answer'd, her nose had been bleeding. I think she went out of doors again (but I am not quite sure of that) came in, and made a dispute about the form of prayer with one Walker; they had been at the printing office to buy them together, and one said that the one had five more than the other; then they called 
               <persName id="t17600116-21-person204">
                  Mary 
                  Mitchel 
               <interp inst="t17600116-21-person204" type="surname" value="Mitchel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-person204" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-person204" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             aside, what was said to her I don't know, but 
               <persName id="t17600116-21-person205">
                  Mary 
                  Mitchel 
               <interp inst="t17600116-21-person205" type="surname" value="Mitchel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-person205" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-person205" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             immediately called to me, and I went to her.</p>
               <p>Q. Cannot you recollect some words that she said?</p>
               <p>M. Lawson. No, she whisper'd; 
               <persName id="t17600116-21-person206">
                  Mary 
                  Mitchel 
               <interp inst="t17600116-21-person206" type="surname" value="Mitchel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-person206" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-person206" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said to me, that Betty was very bad, that she had been to the necessary, where something had come from her, and that as I was a mother of children, I might be able to know whether it was a labour or not. I said, that though I was a mother of children, I was not capable of knowing that, for a certainty. Then Mary Mitchel asked me whether I would go and fetch a midwife, and I said that I would.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go?</p>
               <p>M. Lawson. No, she would not give me time to go; and the prisoner said I had no need to go, for the child was down the necessary, and that she either heard it squeak, or cry (I don't know which of the words she made use of.) I told the prisoner she was mistaken, but she said she was not, and that if I would take a candle I might see the child. Then I and another woman went immediately from her.</p>
               <p>Q. What is that other woman's name?</p>
               <p>M. Lawson. Her name is 
               <persName id="t17600116-21-person207">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17600116-21-person207" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-person207" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-person207" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I look'd down, and saw the child half in and half out of the soil; then I had a pair of tongs brought me, with which I caught hold of the child, but being in a flurry it fell out of the tongs; I laid hold of it again, and got it a great heighth, but it slip'd out of the tongs again. fell through the soil, and I could see no more of it; after that I went to Betty (meaning the prisoner) who was in the house, and said, Betty, Lord! what have you done, did you feel no pain when your child came into the world? she reply'd no, and added that she had come at seven months.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600116-21-person208">
                  Richard 
                  Burril 
               <interp inst="t17600116-21-person208" type="surname" value="Burril"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-person208" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-person208" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable. On the 28th of November I was called into Plough street, to take a woman into custody (which was the prisoner at the bar) for the murder of her bastard child, by throwing it into a vault.</p>
               <p>Q. At whose house?</p>
               <p>Burril. At Mr. Welch's, I went, and was given<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176001160023"></xptr> charge of the prisoner. I asked her how she could be so great a brute as to murder her child. She told me she had occasion to go to the vault, and the child drop'd from her, and that she had very little pain.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600116-21-person209">
                  Mary 
                  Mitchel 
               <interp inst="t17600116-21-person209" type="surname" value="Mitchel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-person209" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-person209" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I used to go partners with the prisoner at the bar in fish. I have often taxed her, and said, Betty, you are very big, how long have you got to go? She always said to me, and a great many more, till the latter end of January, or the beginning of February. She went to the printing-office for some thanksgiving prayers on the 28th of November, to sell on the next day, being the thanksgiving day, and did not return again till about half an hour after eight at night, and then she came to the Man in the Moon alehouse, in Plough Street. When she came in I said, Betty, you have staid a great while. The woman that went with her said, if Betty had not been so big with child (by which means she had got her name set down) we must have come away without any papers. The prisoner went out some little time, and came in again. Then there was a dispute about some paper. I stood a little distance from her, and she beckoned me with her finger. I went to her, and understood her that she had been at the necessary house, and talk'd of something coming from her. I did not then understand that any thing had come from her. I went to a neighbour, and said, Betty has been to the necessary, and she is coming before her time; I understood something was coming, not come. I step'd to Mrs. Lawson, and said, I wish you will be so good as to step into our Nanny's house, and see how it is with Betty, for she had a very bad fall the day before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her have that fall?</p>
               <p>M. Mitchel. No, I did not see it, but I heard it by a great many people; they all went out of the house with her except me, so I did not hear any thing of it till half an hour afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at the necessary at the taking up of the child?</p>
               <p>M. Mitchel. I did go at the latter end, to hold the candle for Mrs. Lawson, who said she had hold of it, and I heard something fall. The girl always behaved well; I never heard otherwise by her in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600116-21-person210">
                  Margaret 
                  Watson 
               <interp inst="t17600116-21-person210" type="surname" value="Watson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-person210" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-person210" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . A little better than half an hour after eight o'clock I went in at the Man in the Moon alehouse, in Plough Street.</p>
               <p>Q. What day of the month?</p>
               <p>M. Watson. On the 28th of November. There Betty (the prisoner) sat by the fire-side on the floor. I came out again with a pint of beer for my supper, and I believe I had been at home till very near nine, when Betty came to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is your house?</p>
               <p>M. Watson. I have a room in Mr. Welch's rents.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was it after you went home?</p>
               <p>M. Watson. I believe it was better than a quarter of an hour after I went to my room; I was eating my supper with my husband and two children. She pushed my door a-jar and had it in her hand, and spoke sharper than ordinary as I thought, and said, Peggy. I want to speak with you. I thought by her speaking something ail'd her more than common. She perceived my countenance change, being daunted at her speech. I said, Betty, what is the matter now? She said, nothing ails me Peggy, but I want to speak to you. When I came out I pull'd the door after me, and stood in the passage. She said, Lord, Peggy, what shall I do, I had occasion to go to the necessary house, and in straining my child came from me. I reply'd, Lord, Betty, what will you do for the child, for you will be hanged? She said, hanged for what, she was come before her time. She beg'd of me to give her something of a rag directly or cloth, so I gave her a piece of a rag that hung behind my door, and a skirt of an old gown. She bid me not to be frighted, for she should go about her business on the morrow. She made use of them in my room, and went away from me; I believe she might be gone from me ten minutes, when I went out and turn'd into the passage, to go to the necessary house where the thing was done; there I met Mrs. Lawson and my sister coming out of the necessary house, with a candle. I clap'd my hands together, and said, O wicked wretch, what had she done! Mrs. Lawson said to me, pray Peggy go and see, for you may see the child upon the soil. I went, but could not look down, I was so daunted. Mrs. Lawson said, we will see if we can get it up with a pair of tongs, so I went and borrowed a pair, and brought them to her. She had the child two or three times up, but could not hold it. After we had lost the child in the soil, and could see no more of it, I went up stairs to the prisoner, who was sitting upon a kind of a basket. I looked her in the face and began to talk to her, and said, how could you go to do such a thing? She beg'd I would not reflect, and said she could not help it, she felt no pain.</p>
               <p>Q. to the Midwife. Does not the after-birth usually come away with the child?</p>
               <p>Midwife. Sometimes there is a pretty while distance, an hour or two, and sometimes less; it is not always alike.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176001160024"></xptr>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I did not come to my reckoning, which was the latter end of January, or begining of February; I had every thing provided for the child, I did not want to make away with it; my things were seen by the neighbours, 
               <persName id="t17600116-21-person211">
                  Margaret 
                  Watson 
               <interp inst="t17600116-21-person211" type="surname" value="Watson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-person211" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-person211" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and her mother know that I had things provided.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600116-21-person212">
                  Margaret 
                  Watson 
               <interp inst="t17600116-21-person212" type="surname" value="Watson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-person212" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-person212" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (again.) I saw the prison1er have two child's shirts, a cap, and three forehead cloths.</p>
               <p>Q. How long before this happened?</p>
               <p>M. Watson. I believe she might cut them out about two or three days before; I really saw her cut them out. She had asked a young body, an acquaintance of her's, to give her a blanket.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you present at the time?</p>
               <p>M. Watson. I was, the young body said she would give her one</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>M. Watson. This was about a week before the thing happened.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600116-21-person213">
                  Mary 
                  Mitchel 
               <interp inst="t17600116-21-person213" type="surname" value="Mitchel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-person213" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-person213" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (again.) I know of her preparing som e linen, and I carried them to the workhouse to her; and I know the young woman that promised her a blanket, who asking her how long she had to go, she said, to the latter end of January, or beginning of February; then the other said, it is time enough to give it you.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600116-21-verdict114" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600116-21-verdict114" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted, as delivered by surprise
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
