<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670909-57">
               <interp inst="t17670909-57" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670909-57" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670909-57" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670909"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670909-57" type="date" value="17670909"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670909-57-off337-c502" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-57-defend622 t17670909-57-off337 t17670909-57-verdict341"></join>
         
               <p>474. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17670909-57-defend622" type="defendantName">
                     Christopher 
                     Holland 
                  <interp inst="t17670909-57-defend622" type="surname" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-defend622" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-defend622" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17670909-57-off337" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-off337" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-off337" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing a black gelding, value 18 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17670909-57-victim624" type="victimName">
                     Isaac 
                     Belcher 
                  <interp inst="t17670909-57-victim624" type="surname" value="Belcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-victim624" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-victim624" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-57-off337 t17670909-57-victim624"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17670909-57-cd338" type="crimeDate">August 6</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-57-off337 t17670909-57-cd338"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-57-person625">
                  Isaac 
                  Belcher 
               <interp inst="t17670909-57-person625" type="surname" value="Belcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-person625" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-person625" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at <placeName id="t17670909-57-crimeloc339">Danbury in Essex</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17670909-57-crimeloc339" type="placeName" value="Danbury in Essex"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17670909-57-crimeloc339" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-57-off337 t17670909-57-crimeloc339"></join>; I missed a black gelding out of the pasture on the 7th of August; I found him in Smithfield the same day in the possession of the prisoner; I asked him if he would fell that horse; he said, yes; I said, what do you ask for him; he said, twelve guineas; I asked him how old he was; he said six years old, and that he was his own; I asked him where he brought him from; he said out of Kent; I asked him to give the horse a trot, and lead him to the Half-moon in Smithfield; when he got there, I took him by the collar, and said, that horse was mine; then he said he bought him in Long-lane near Smithfield, but did not know the man he bought him of.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-57-person626">
                  William 
                  Seabrook 
               <interp inst="t17670909-57-person626" type="surname" value="Seabrook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-person626" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-person626" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Belcher, I turned this horse into the pasture on the 6th of August, about six in the afternoon, and in the morning he was gone.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>A man overtook me in Barbican with this horse to sell; I asked him the price; he said twelve guineas; I bid him nine; he went into Long-lane, there he said if I liked him at ten I should have him; I gave him ten guineas for him; he said he brought him from Dartford in Kent; I am a shoemaker, and live in Paul's-alley, near Barbican.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-57-person627">
                  Mary 
                  Physick 
               <interp inst="t17670909-57-person627" type="surname" value="Physick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-person627" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-person627" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Paul's-alley, the prisoner lives on the ground-floor, and I in the first floor; he is a shoemaker, he has nothing else to get his living by but making of shoes.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he any stables?</p>
               <p>M. Physick. I do not know that he has.</p>
               <p>Q. Does he deal in horses?</p>
               <p>M. Physick. I do not know that he does.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was he the last six weeks?</p>
               <p>M. Physick. On the 6th of August he was in the garden.</p>
               <p>Court. You was asked where he was the last six weeks, you run directly to the 6th of August.</p>
               <p>M. Physick. He was there with a child playing a little cannon off; he said to me, please to stop, and you shall see; he let it off, it went like a gun.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has he been in prison?</p>
               <p>M. Physick. He has been in prison a month last Friday.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was he a fortnight before that time?</p>
               <p>M. Physick. I cannot say.</p>
               <p>Q. You can give a particular account of him the 6th of August, cannot you say where he was one day a fortnight before?</p>
               <p>M. Physick. I am from home a great deal; I have a sister at Lambeth that has been ill, and I have been there lately, but she is lately dead; I am sometimes in Bishopsgate-street.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has your sister been dead?</p>
               <p>M. Physick. She has been dead three months, but I have been backwards and forwards with her husband.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell where the prisoner was the week before he was taken up?</p>
               <p>M. Physick. No, I cannot.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you the week before he was taken up?</p>
               <p>M. Physick. I was mostly at Lambeth.</p>
               <p>Q. How long do you generally stay there when you go?</p>
               <p>M. Physick. I sometimes stay a week, and sometimes a fortnight.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you when he was taken up?</p>
               <p>M. Physick. I was at home then.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him any time that day?</p>
               <p>M. Physick. I saw him came home that day at about ten o'clock, with beef stakes for dinner; that was the 7th of August.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you hear of his being taken up?</p>
               <p>M. Physick. I heard of that at night.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you been out since?</p>
               <p>M. Physick. No, I have not much.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was he carried?</p>
               <p>M. Physick. To Woodstreet Compter.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go to him?</p>
               <p>M. Physick. I did one night, but not that night.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was that after he was there?</p>
               <p>M. Physick. That was about a week after.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176709090049"></xptr>Q. Did any of your people go to him that night?</p>
               <p>M. Physick. I cannot say whether any of them did or not.</p>
               <p>Q. By what do you know it was the 6th of August that this gun was fired?</p>
               <p>M. Physick. Because I was there.</p>
               <p>Q. Why may it not be the 5th?</p>
               <p>M. Physick. It was the Thursday, and he was taken up on the Friday.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you see him last that Thursday night?</p>
               <p>M. Physick. He was at home at eight o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. What other people lodge in that house?</p>
               <p>M. Physick. There was one 
               <persName id="t17670909-57-person628">
                  William 
                  Bobit 
               <interp inst="t17670909-57-person628" type="surname" value="Bobit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-person628" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-person628" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             lodges in the kitchen, and 
               <persName id="t17670909-57-person629">
                  William 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17670909-57-person629" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-person629" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-person629" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             lodges up two pair of stairs, and two shoemakers work in the garret; Mr. Bobit has a young woman, named Birmingham, boards with him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-57-person630">
                  William 
                  Bobit 
               <interp inst="t17670909-57-person630" type="surname" value="Bobit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-person630" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-person630" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a porter, and lodge in the house of Mrs. Physick in Paul's-alley; the prisoner is a shoemaker, and lodges there.</p>
               <p>Q. What other business does he follow?</p>
               <p>Bobit. He follows no other business as I know of.</p>
               <p>Q. Does he deal in horses?</p>
               <p>Bobit. I do not know that he does.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you mostly out, or at home?</p>
               <p>Bobit. I am at home every night.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was he a fortnight before he was taken up?</p>
               <p>Bobit. I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the last you saw him before he was taken up?</p>
               <p>Bobit. I saw him within a week of the time; I cannot say I saw him every day; the night before he was taken up I was in the garden with him, between seven and eight o'clock; there was a little boy with us, Mr. Price's son; we were firing off a little cannon; that was the 6th of August at night.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure it was the night before he was taken up?</p>
               <p>Bobit. It was.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you see him last that night?</p>
               <p>Bobit. I saw him till it was full eight o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him after that time?</p>
               <p>Bobit. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him the next morning?</p>
               <p>Bobit. I cannot say I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at home the next morning?</p>
               <p>Bobit. I was, till after ten o'clock; I went out about five, and returned again by nine; I cannot say I saw him that morning.</p>
               <p>Q. What circumstance was he in?</p>
               <p>Bobit. I cannot tell that.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he a journeyman or master?</p>
               <p>Bobit. He works as a master like; I believe he did only jobs, he had no regular shop, he worked in his room.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he a journeyman?</p>
               <p>Bobit. No.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-57-person631">
                  Alice 
                  Bobit 
               <interp inst="t17670909-57-person631" type="surname" value="Bobit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-person631" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-person631" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to 
               <persName id="t17670909-57-person632">
                  William 
                  Bobit 
               <interp inst="t17670909-57-person632" type="surname" value="Bobit"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-person632" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-person632" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I lodge in this house in Paul's-alley; I have known the prisoner about sixteen weeks, he is a shoemaker.</p>
               <p>Q. What family has he?</p>
               <p>A. Bobit. He has a wife, he works at home on the ground-floor.</p>
               <p>Q. Does he constantly work at his business?</p>
               <p>A. Bobit. That I cannot say, because I go out to work; I have heard him at work.</p>
               <p>Q. Did his wife and you associate?</p>
               <p>A. Bobit. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they full of money?</p>
               <p>A. Bobit. That I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was he a fortnight before he was taken up?</p>
               <p>A. Bobit. I do not know, I never missed him.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was he a week before he was taken up?</p>
               <p>A. Bobit. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was he the night before he was taken up?</p>
               <p>A. Bobit. He was at home.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was he on the 7th of August?</p>
               <p>A. Bobit. I saw him on Friday the 7th of August before seven in the morning, going out into the garden.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him any time after that that day?</p>
               <p>A. Bobit. I saw him again, betwixt that and eleven o'clock, in his own apartment, sitting by the fire.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-57-person633">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Birmingham 
               <interp inst="t17670909-57-person633" type="surname" value="Birmingham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-person633" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-person633" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the house where the prisoner does; I come from Cambridge, and live with 
               <persName id="t17670909-57-person634">
                  Christopher 
                  Holland 
               <interp inst="t17670909-57-person634" type="surname" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-person634" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-person634" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I have been there eleven weeks.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>E. Birmingham. He is a <rs id="t17670909-57-deflabel340" type="occupation">shoemaker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-57-defend622 t17670909-57-deflabel340"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Does he work at his trade constantly?</p>
               <p>E. Birmingham. He does, he had pretty business.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he plenty of money?</p>
               <p>E. Birmingham. He has an aunt that has plenty of money, and she often makes him a present to support him; I was in his company the 6th of August; we supped at six, and I was with him till past eleven; I do not lodge there.</p>
               <p>Q. When was he taken up?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176709090050"></xptr>E. Birmingham. He was taken up on the 7th of August, one Friday; on that day I was at his door before six in the morning, and his spouse came and let me in; he was in bed then; there came a woman between five and six to let his spouse know he was in the Compter; his wife went there; then she came back, and let me know of it, and I went then to see him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you before the Alderman?</p>
               <p>E. Birmingham. I was on the Saturday.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the owner of the horse there?</p>
               <p>E. Birmingham. He was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you give an account where he was over night?</p>
               <p>E. Birmingham. I did not hear any thing mentioned in particular, I was not called upon about it; I went, in case I was called upon to say what I knew.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there nothing said when you was with him in the Compter, how he could be guilty of stealing the horse when he was at home at the time?</p>
               <p>E. Birmingham. I heard nothing farther said, but that he was taken up upon suspicion.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at the Mansion-house when he was there?</p>
               <p>E. Birmingham. I was, waiting to give evidence, but I was not called upon; there was none called upon in the least.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you understand about the horse?</p>
               <p>E. Birmingham. I understood he was innocent, by being at home.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see him with a single guinea in gold in your life?</p>
               <p>E. Birmingham. I have seen him with silver, but I cannot say I saw him with a guinea in gold.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have an aunt in the country below Cambridge that has given me money several times.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. How far is Danbury from Smithfield?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. It is about thirty-four miles distance.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-57-person635">
                  Samuel 
                  Cheesewright 
               <interp inst="t17670909-57-person635" type="surname" value="Cheesewright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-person635" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-person635" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a turner in Aldersgate-street, the prisoner lodged in my house about twelve months ago, about three quarters of a year; he is a very honest industrious sort of a man, as far as ever I saw; he had a stall in Redcross-street, and used to mend shoes; he told me he had a little estate in the country, that brought him in about twenty pounds a year.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear about his dealing in horses?</p>
               <p>Cheeswright. No, I never did but once; he went down, as I understood, to receive his rent, and he brought up a horse.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-57-person636">
                  Ruth 
                  Pegg 
               <interp inst="t17670909-57-person636" type="surname" value="Pegg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-person636" type="given" value="Ruth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-person636" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Coleman-street, I have known him ever since he was born, I never knew any harm of him in my life; he was born in a place called Shipdon in Norfolk; there lives what friends he has.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of an aunt of his?</p>
               <p>R. Pegg. I never heard of any aunt he has.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. It is my wife's aunt.</p>
               <p>R. Pegg. I know nothing of his wife's family; his father was a farmer.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he wealthy?</p>
               <p>R. Pegg. He was none of the rich men, he just made a shift to bring up his family.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner in good business?</p>
               <p>R. Pegg. He was only a little chamber-master?</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear of his dealing in horses?</p>
               <p>R. Pegg. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you look upon him to be wealthy?</p>
               <p>R. Pegg. I do not think he is worth any money at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever seen him with a guinea?</p>
               <p>R. Pegg. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think he ever was worth five guineas?</p>
               <p>R. Pegg. I believe he has been worth five and five to that?</p>
               <p>Q. When?</p>
               <p>R. Pegg. About fifteen or sixteen years ago, because his grandfather died, and left him a place worth between thirty and forty pounds.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he that now?</p>
               <p>R. Pegg. No, he has sold that a good while ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Dare you take your oath to say, he is worth thirty of forty pounds now?</p>
               <p>R. Pegg. I should be very loth to do that, he has no estate now as I know of.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-57-person637">
                  William 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17670909-57-person637" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-person637" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-person637" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the same house, I have known the prisoner about a year, he has always behaved as an honest man, by what I observed; I do not work where I live, and I never saw him much out.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thi ng where he was that Thursday night?</p>
               <p>Price. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at home that night?</p>
               <p>Price. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of a little cannon being let off?</p>
               <p>Price. I do, before he was taken up I believe that was.</p>
               <p>Q. How long before?</p>
               <p>Price. I am certain it was not a week before.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you been much in his company?</p>
               <p>Price. No, I have not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever observe him flush of money?</p>
               <p>Price. I never observed any want of money.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176709090051"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-57-person638">
                  Mary 
                  Prentice 
               <interp inst="t17670909-57-person638" type="surname" value="Prentice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-person638" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-person638" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Paul's-alley, next door to him, I know no harm of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know him ever dealing in horses?</p>
               <p>M. Prentice. No, I know nothing of that.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17670909-57-verdict341" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670909-57-verdict341" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acq
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
