<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17611209-26">
               <interp inst="t17611209-26" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611209-26" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611209-26" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17611209"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611209-26" type="date" value="17611209"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17611209-26-off150-c279" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-26-defend328 t17611209-26-off150 t17611209-26-verdict153"></join>
         
               <p>28. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17611209-26-defend328" type="defendantName">
                  Mary, the <rs id="t17611209-26-deflabel149" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-26-defend328 t17611209-26-deflabel149"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17611209-26-person329">
                        John 
                        Hinds 
                     <interp inst="t17611209-26-person329" type="surname" value="Hinds"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17611209-26-person329" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17611209-26-person329" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
                     <interp inst="t17611209-26-defend328" type="surname" value="Hinds"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-26-defend328" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-26-defend328" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17611209-26-off150" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611209-26-off150" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-26-off150" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               the wilful murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17611209-26-victim331" type="victimName">
                           Edward 
                           Mulby 
                        <interp inst="t17611209-26-victim331" type="surname" value="Mulby"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17611209-26-victim331" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17611209-26-victim331" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-26-off150 t17611209-26-victim331"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , an <rs id="t17611209-26-viclabel151" type="occupation">infant</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-26-victim331 t17611209-26-viclabel151"></join>, by throwing it into a pond
            </rs>, &amp;c <rs id="t17611209-26-cd152" type="crimeDate">June 20</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-26-off150 t17611209-26-cd152"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176112090024"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-26-person332">
                  Sarah 
                  Mulby 
               <interp inst="t17611209-26-person332" type="surname" value="Mulby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-26-person332" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-26-person332" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Peter-street by Soho-square. My husband is a taylor. The prisoner lodged in the same room I did. My child Edward was five months old. The prisoner was going to see her brother-in-law in Old Bond-street; she took my child (being seemingly fond of it), and said she should not be gone above half an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. What business was the prisoner?</p>
               <p>S. Mulby. She said she was a servant out of place. She gave me part of a pint of beer when she went out with the child; she went up towards Tyburn Road; she set out a little after five in the afternoon on the 20th of June.</p>
               <p>Q. How was the child dressed?</p>
               <p>S. Mulby. In a brown skirt, an old flannel petticoat, an old white gown, an old laced cap, and a black cap over it; old things, I do not think they were all above a shilling value. I did not see the prisoner till about four months after. I saw the child on the Thursday following, being the 23d of June. I had inquired about the streets, workhouses, and hospitals, and I found it dead at St. George's Hospital; it looked as if it had been drowned; it was naked, but I knew it. I have here some of the things it had on, which were taken off it at the hospital ( producing a pair of stockings, yellow shoes, an old coat, and a black cap).</p>
               <p>Q. How did you and this woman live together?</p>
               <p>S. Mulby. We were not enemies, nor over great. She seemed to be fond of the child. My husband was then in trouble.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say when she was taken up?</p>
               <p>S. Mulby. She said before the justice, that she met with a woman as she was going along that was going to see a place at Kensington. She set the child on the edge of the river, and it gave a spring out of her arms into the water.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-26-person333">
                  Malachi 
                  Mulby 
               <interp inst="t17611209-26-person333" type="surname" value="Mulby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-26-person333" type="given" value="Malachi"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-26-person333" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the father of the child. I took the prisoner in St. James's about a month ago. When she was before Justice Wright she owned she had rested herself upon her elbow, on a bridge in Hide Park, and that the child gave a jump out of her hands into the water.</p>
               <p>Fra. Doby. I was going about business, and I met with the prisoner in Monmouth-street, the same Saturday night that she took the child out from its mother's.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she sober, or otherwise?</p>
               <p>F. Doby. She was sober. I did not speak to her; she was walking along with her hands before her.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17611209-26-person334">
                  Sarah 
                  Mulby 
               <interp inst="t17611209-26-person334" type="surname" value="Mulby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-26-person334" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-26-person334" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Was the prisoner sober when she parted from you with the child?</p>
               <p>S. Mulby. I believe she had not drank before that day; she seemed very sober.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>We lodged in one room. I was an ironer to a landress at 3 s. a week. The poor woman was almost starved, and her child too. I had no money, and made away with an apron for 15 d. then we had some stakes and three pints of beer together. Then I said, if you'll let me take the child to my sister's I'll beg some silk to make it a black cap. She agreed to it. I took the child; and after that I met a young woman going to Kensington. She asked me to go along with her. I said I would, if she would help to carry the child. When we came to a house where are two centinels painted on wood at the door, near the park gate, we had half a pint of beer, and gave the child a crust, and went on towards Kensington. I stopped upon the bridge in the park, and suddenly the child gave a spring into the river. I strove to get it out; but being with child could not; and no foul was coming by at that time; and the woman was gone on. I was affrighted, and did not know what to do. I wished afterwards that I had returned to Mrs. Mulby.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17611209-26-verdict153" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611209-26-verdict153" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-26-verdict153" type="verdictSubcategory" value="accidentalDeath"></interp>
               Acquitted. Accidental Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
