<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660702-18">
               <interp inst="t17660702-18" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660702-18" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660702-18" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660702"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660702-18" type="date" value="17660702"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660702-18-off98-c140" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-18-defend173 t17660702-18-off98 t17660702-18-verdict101"></join>
         
               <p>350. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660702-18-defend173" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Cook 
                  <interp inst="t17660702-18-defend173" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-18-defend173" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-18-defend173" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17660702-18-deflabel97" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-18-defend173 t17660702-18-deflabel97"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17660702-18-off98" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660702-18-off98" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-18-off98" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a pair of silver knee-buckles, value 3 s. and a coral necklace, with a gold locket, value 6 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17660702-18-victim175" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Gray 
                  <interp inst="t17660702-18-victim175" type="surname" value="Gray"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-18-victim175" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-18-victim175" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-18-off98 t17660702-18-victim175"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17660702-18-cd99" type="crimeDate">May 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-18-off98 t17660702-18-cd99"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-18-person176">
                  William 
                  Gray 
               <interp inst="t17660702-18-person176" type="surname" value="Gray"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-18-person176" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-18-person176" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 18th of May, being Whitsunday, the prisoner came to my house about eight in the morning, and asked my wife for some boiling water for tea; she staid and breakfasted with my wife and I; we have two children: she asked my wife after breakfast to dress the eldest child, and she would take a walk round the green with it. We could not dress her directly; the prisoner was contented to take the youngest in her arms; after she had been gone about half an hour, she picked up our eldest child; I heard the child cry under our window; I looked out, and saw her leading the eldest, and carrying the young one in her arms. I went in again thinking no ill, she having used my shop some time: about three quarters of an hour after, some of our neighbours came, and said they heard children crying up stairs, three or four doors off; my wife went up two pair of stairs, and brought our two children in; then we missed a pair of silver knee-buckles, which I had put into the eldest's shoes, but we did not miss the necklace and locket at that time; then I went in search of the prisoner; I got intelligence at a public-house in the neighbourhood which way she was gone, and I overtook her in Chiswell-street. She refused knowing me (she is very <rs id="t17660702-18-deflabel100" type="occupation">deaf</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-18-defend173 t17660702-18-deflabel100"></join>.) I put my mouth to her ear, and made her know me; then she took the buckles out of her pocket and put them into her bosom, and was a good deal pert with her tongue; I took her in at a public-house, and sent for a constable; when he came she was a little unwilling to be searched; and when she found she must; she told the officer if he would be ingenuous, she would let him search; at last she put her hand in her bosom, and took out the buckles, and delivered them to the officer (produced and deposed to.) She confessed before Justice Girdler, that she had taken the buckles; she was committed, and when I went home again, my wife told me she had missed the child's necklace and gold locket, that we have not found again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-18-person177">
                  George 
                  Barraclew 
               <interp inst="t17660702-18-person177" type="surname" value="Barraclew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-18-person177" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-18-person177" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Whitsunday, about eleven o'clock, I was sent for to a public-house in Chiswell-street, to take charge of the prisoner; the prosecutor said she had the buckles in her bosom. I got a woman to search her; the prisoner insisted that I should take them out; I could not get my hand in far enough; I said, she must get the woman to unlace her, and take them out; then she said she would give them if I would be ingenuous; that she only took them to get five or six shillings upon them, and so to return them the next day. She confessed the same before the Justice. She delivered them to me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I had these little children to look after; I took the buckles out of her shoes, and put them into my pocket for safety; I had no thought of wronging them in the least.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660702-18-verdict101" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660702-18-verdict101" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-18-verdict101" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder1s"></interp>
               Guilty, 10 d.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17660702-18-punish102" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660702-18-punish102" type="punishmentCategory" value="corporal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-18-punish102" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="whipping"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-18-defend173 t17660702-18-punish102"></join>
               W
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
