<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17630518-3">
               <interp inst="t17630518-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630518-3" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630518-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17630518"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630518-3" type="date" value="17630518"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17630518-3-off12-c40" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-3-defend45 t17630518-3-off12 t17630518-3-verdict17"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17630518-3-off13-c46" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-3-defend53 t17630518-3-off13 t17630518-3-verdict18"></join>
         
               <p>199, 200. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17630518-3-defend45" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Baylis 
                  <interp inst="t17630518-3-defend45" type="surname" value="Baylis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-defend45" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-defend45" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             was indicted for <rs id="t17630518-3-off12" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-off12" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-off12" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               that he in company with 
                     <persName id="t17630518-3-person46">
                        John 
                        Rust 
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person46" type="surname" value="Rust"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630518-3-person46" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630518-3-person46" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , 
                     <persName id="t17630518-3-person47">
                        Henry 
                        Rabson 
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person47" type="surname" value="Rabson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630518-3-person47" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630518-3-person47" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , and 
                     <persName id="t17630518-3-person48">
                        William 
                        Poulton 
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person48" type="surname" value="Poulton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630518-3-person48" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630518-3-person48" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , not taken, did steal forty bushels of oats, val. 3 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17630518-3-victim50" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Mariot 
                        <interp inst="t17630518-3-victim50" type="surname" value="Mariot"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630518-3-victim50" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630518-3-victim50" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   the Elder, and 
                     
                        <persName id="t17630518-3-victim52" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Mariot 
                        <interp inst="t17630518-3-victim52" type="surname" value="Mariot"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630518-3-victim52" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630518-3-victim52" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   the Younger, secretly in their warehouse
            </rs>. And 
               <persName id="t17630518-3-defend53" type="defendantName">
                  Samuel 
                  Beaden 
               <interp inst="t17630518-3-defend53" type="surname" value="Beaden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-defend53" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-defend53" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
              for <rs id="t17630518-3-off13" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-off13" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-off13" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving the same well knowing it to have been stolen
            </rs>, <rs id="t17630518-3-cd14" type="crimeDate">April 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-3-off12 t17630518-3-cd14"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-3-off13 t17630518-3-cd14"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630518-3-person54">
                  John 
                  Mariot 
               <interp inst="t17630518-3-person54" type="surname" value="Mariot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person54" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person54" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Junior. My uncle 
               <persName id="t17630518-3-person55">
                  John 
                  Mariot 
               <interp inst="t17630518-3-person55" type="surname" value="Mariot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person55" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person55" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and I are partners, we have some warehouses at the end of <placeName id="t17630518-3-crimeloc15">Milford-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17630518-3-crimeloc15" type="placeName" value="Milford-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17630518-3-crimeloc15" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-3-off12 t17630518-3-crimeloc15"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-3-off13 t17630518-3-crimeloc15"></join>, we are in the corn trade; the prisoner Baylis used to be employed as a <rs id="t17630518-3-deflabel16" type="occupation">labourer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-3-defend45 t17630518-3-deflabel16"></join>; I live in Goodman's fields, I attend at the corn market Mondays, Wednesdays, and Fridays, and 
               <persName id="t17630518-3-person56">
                  John 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17630518-3-person56" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person56" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person56" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who is our servant, comes there to us to take orders. On the 9th of April I was at the warehouses in Milford-lane, about 3 in the afternoon, and was in ormed by Jones there had 
               <persName id="t17630518-3-person57">
                  len
               <interp inst="t17630518-3-person57" type="given" value="len"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person57" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             some corn taken away. I took up the prisoner and 
               <persName id="t17630518-3-person58">
                  Burton
               <interp inst="t17630518-3-person58" type="given" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the evidence, they were charged with taking two sacks of malt; they both, before Justice Welch, acknowledged they took each of them one, and they had carried them to Mr. Beaden's stable; he lives in Howard-street, near Norfolk-street, he has stables in Surry-street, and also in Water-lane. We got a search warrant, and in the stables in Surry-street we found a sack marked W. H. a West country sack, of which we have thirty or forty in our warehouse that the owner has not fetched away; ( the sack produced in court) I really believe this is one of the parcel. Beaden hearing there was a warrant against him, came and surrendered<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176305180004"></xptr> to the constable; he was charged with receiving the oats, but he said he was ignorant of any such thing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630518-3-person59">
                  John 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17630518-3-person59" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person59" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am grainery keeper to messrs. Mariots. On Friday the 8th of April I went to the corn market to my masters, and left the keys of the warehouses with 
               <persName id="t17630518-3-person60">
                  George 
                  Burton 
               <interp inst="t17630518-3-person60" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person60" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person60" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Baylis was with him at the time; I returned back, I found Baylis up one pair of stairs in the warehouse; I asked him where the keys were? he said, Burton had them. A person told me he had met Burton with a sack on his back. I went out and met him. I asked him for the keys; he said, Baylis had them. I went into the warehouse, and found the keys in one of the rooms which was locked when I went out, and the bushed was moved from the place where I left it. I asked Burton where he had been? he said he had been carrying a sack for old Price, who is Mr. Dowley's grainery keeper. When I saw Mr. Price I asked him, he said he had carried none for him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner Baylis employed by you that Friday?</p>
               <p>Jones. No, he was not, he worked as a porter for us when we wanted him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ask him what business he had there?</p>
               <p>Jones. No, because at times he used to work there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630518-3-person61">
                  George 
                  Burton 
               <interp inst="t17630518-3-person61" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person61" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person61" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I worked for Mr. Mariot five or six years at times when they had work for me. On the 8th of April I had only my waistcoat on, I said to Baylis, I wish you would take the keys, I having no pockets, 
               <persName id="t17630518-3-person62">
                  John 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17630518-3-person62" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person62" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person62" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had left them in my care. I went up to the Three Horseshoes, and had a pint of beer, and bread and cheese, coming back I met Baylis with a sack of oats on his back; I asked him where he was going? he said, 
               <persName id="t17630518-3-person63">
                  John 
                  Rust 
               <interp inst="t17630518-3-person63" type="surname" value="Rust"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person63" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person63" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is below. I went to Rust, the grainery door was open; Rust said, you may as well take another sack, (he was standing on the wharf) we will share the money between us, you know we all three want it. Rust put up another sack, and I took it upon my back, and carried it into Surry-street, and pitched it on the other which Baylis had left by Mr. Beaden's stable door; the door was shut, I saw nobody there, I know'd the sack that Baylis carried by the red mark upon it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see those sacks again?</p>
               <p>Burton. I saw them burnt at Baylis's mother's house.</p>
               <p>Baylis. You burnt them, you did.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you get them again?</p>
               <p>Burton. I do not know, but I saw them on the same day under Baylis's arm. Jones charged us with taking malt, and we were both taken up on the Sunday night.</p>
               <p>Q. What advantage did you get by all this?</p>
               <p>Burton. Rust and Baylis came to me at the Horse-shoes, and told me they had got 5 s. of Mr. Beaden; they gave me 2 s. and Baylis had 2 s. and Rust kept the other one; the two sacks came to 10 s. but I never had a farthing more of that; but I received of Mr. Beaden 5 s. about four months ago, for a sack of oats; there had been carried two sacks, and Rust had received 5 s. in part, and I went and received the other 5 of him; he was then at the Swan in Arundel-street, when he came to the door and paid me, he said he had rather have no more, because if it was found out it would blast his character, and ruin him for ever.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630518-3-person64">
                  William 
                  Miller 
               <interp inst="t17630518-3-person64" type="surname" value="Miller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person64" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person64" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was constable, I searched the stable of Mr. Beaden, we found this sack, here produced. I was at Justice Welch's when Baylis was charged with being concerned in taking two sacks of malt, the property of the prosecutors, he acknowledged he did carry one of them from the grainery to Mr. Beaden's stable. Mr Beaden was not at home when we went to his house, I left word I wanted to speak with him, and about an hour after he came and surrendered himself to me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630518-3-person65">
                  Samuel 
                  Roberts 
               <interp inst="t17630518-3-person65" type="surname" value="Roberts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person65" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person65" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the landlord of the wharf, and let the graineries to the prosecutors. I was before the Justice, and there heard Baylis confess, he carried one sack of oats from the grainery to Mr. Beaden's stable in Surry-street.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630518-3-person66">
                  William 
                  Barrot 
               <interp inst="t17630518-3-person66" type="surname" value="Barrot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person66" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person66" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mr. Beaden.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see Baylis or Burton at your master's stables?</p>
               <p>Barrot. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not declare to one Humphry Evans, that you shot the oats which they brought into your master's binn?</p>
               <p>Barrot. No, I did not. I said to him, what is all this dispute about? I fancy we are in a bad hole. I never shot any oats but what I weat for myself. I saw Burton in the Round-house, I asked him, if he ever received any money of my master? he said, no, he never did receive any of him during his breath. When we want corn, I or my fellow-servant go to Mr. Dowley's and fetch it; my master trades with him, we have of him about two quarters and a half a week in our stable in Surry-street.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630518-3-person67">
                  Edward 
                  Hodgson 
               <interp inst="t17630518-3-person67" type="surname" value="Hodgson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person67" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person67" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Beaden. Baylis has brought sacks from Mr. Dowley's, as<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176305180005"></xptr> porter, to our stable, I never saw him there upon any other account; I have ordered corn from Mr. Dowley's, then I always go to Mr. Price, his foreman; I kept the key of the stable door, and when I went out I used to leave the key with my wife; I never knew of any oats brought in in secret.</p>
               <p>Baylis's Defence.</p>
               <p>I had no hand at all in the oats, no farther than 
               <persName id="t17630518-3-person68">
                  John 
                  Rust 
               <interp inst="t17630518-3-person68" type="surname" value="Rust"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person68" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person68" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             employed me to carry them; he put them up and brought them to me.</p>
               <p>Beaden's Defence.</p>
               <p>I have my corn of Mr. Dowley, of Milford-lane. I always give orders to my servants when they want to go there for more, which they do, and bring the account to me. I know nothing of what I am here charged with.</p>
               <p>For Beaden.</p>
               <p>Justice Welch. I remember, when Burton was brought before me, he was made an evidence.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether he on his examination gave any account of any money he or they received of Beaden?</p>
               <p>Justice Welch. I did ask that question. Baylis did acknowledge, he did carry some oats to Beaden's stable, but neither he or Burton did give any account of their being present when any money was paid; neither did they give any account of money being received.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630518-3-person69">
                  Robert 
                  Dowley 
               <interp inst="t17630518-3-person69" type="surname" value="Dowley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person69" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-person69" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I serve Mr. Beaden with corn, and have this three years; he has sometimes seven quarters a week, and sometimes ten, sometimes thirty quarters within the month, more or less; sometimes I send the oats in my own sacks, sometimes in other people's sacks. I have now in my custody west-country sacks of the same mark of this here produced.</p>
               <p>There were many evidences to his character, but the court thought it needless to call them.</p>
               <p>Baylis <rs id="t17630518-3-verdict17" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-verdict17" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-verdict17" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder1s"></interp>
               Guilty 10 d.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>Beaden <rs id="t17630518-3-verdict18" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-verdict18" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17630518-3-punish19" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630518-3-punish19" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630518-3-defend45 t17630518-3-punish19"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
