<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670115-11">
               <interp inst="t17670115-11" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670115-11" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670115-11" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670115"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670115-11" type="date" value="17670115"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670115-11-off60-c114" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670115-11-defend133 t17670115-11-off60 t17670115-11-verdict64"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670115-11-off60-c115" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670115-11-defend135 t17670115-11-off60 t17670115-11-verdict64"></join>
         
               <p>96, 97. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17670115-11-defend133" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Merchant 
                  <interp inst="t17670115-11-defend133" type="surname" value="Merchant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-11-defend133" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-11-defend133" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17670115-11-defend135" type="defendantName">
                     Anne 
                     White 
                  <interp inst="t17670115-11-defend135" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-11-defend135" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-11-defend135" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17670115-11-deflabel59" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670115-11-defend135 t17670115-11-deflabel59"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17670115-11-off60" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670115-11-off60" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-11-off60" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one guinea, twelve half guineas, and 30 s. in money numbered, the money of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17670115-11-victim137" type="victimName">
                           Charles 
                           Letterman 
                        <interp inst="t17670115-11-victim137" type="surname" value="Letterman"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670115-11-victim137" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670115-11-victim137" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670115-11-off60 t17670115-11-victim137"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling-house of the said Charles
            </rs>, <rs id="t17670115-11-cd61" type="crimeDate">Dec. 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670115-11-off60 t17670115-11-cd61"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670115-11-person138">
                  Anne 
                  Letterman 
               <interp inst="t17670115-11-person138" type="surname" value="Letterman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-11-person138" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-11-person138" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My husband is named Charles; we <rs id="t17670115-11-viclabel62" type="occupation">keep a <placeName id="t17670115-11-crimeloc63">public-house in Red-lion-street, Whitechapel, the sign of the White-lion</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-11-crimeloc63" type="placeName" value="public-house in Red-lion-street, Whitechapel, the sign of the White-lion"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-11-crimeloc63" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670115-11-off60 t17670115-11-crimeloc63"></join>
                  </rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670115-11-victim137 t17670115-11-viclabel62"></join>: last Saturday fortnight the two prisoners came into our house between nine and ten at night; I stood talking to them about two or three minutes; I gave a person change for a shilling out of a red barrel box, called a Christmas-box, and presently I went out; going cross the way to a butcher's, I put my hand in my pocket and missed my box.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176701150009"></xptr>Q. When you stood talking to the prisoners, how near to them was you?</p>
               <p>A. Letterman. I stood close to them; I ran back and asked the maid in the kitchen if she had seen my box; she said, no, then I said, I am ruined; at my coming in White ran out of the house; the maid came out into the tap-room; the prisoners had called for a pint of brandy hot, but Merchant went out and left the liquor; there was 9 l. within about a shilling in the box; I advertised it.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of money was it?</p>
               <p>A. Letterman. There were twelve half guineas, one whole guinea, and about 30 s. in silver, in such a box as mentioned in the indictment; among the silver there were two half crowns, and half a six-pence. On the Tuesday following 
               <persName id="t17670115-11-person139">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Haines 
               <interp inst="t17670115-11-person139" type="surname" value="Haines"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-11-person139" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-11-person139" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came to my house, and said she heard I had had a great loss; she produced the half six-pence; I said that was what I had lost with my money; she told me she had it of the two prisoners; then they were taken up; these are the rags they had on when they were at my house, (produced in a handkerchief) but they were dressed out when taken up.</p>
               <p>Q. Had they used to use your house?</p>
               <p>A. Letterman. I never saw them there before to my knowledge; Merchant proffered to give me a note to pay 5 s. a week for the money, rather than to part with her new clothes, but at last said she would not, she should stand the chance.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670115-11-person140">
                  Anne 
                  Mills 
               <interp inst="t17670115-11-person140" type="surname" value="Mills"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-11-person140" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-11-person140" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mrs. Letterman; the Saturday night this happened, my mistress went to go to the butcher's; I was called out of the kitchen into the tap-room; my master was in a box by himself; the two prisoners were by the fire; they desired me to make a pint of brandy hot; I put a pint of twopenny on the fire, and broke an egg and put it to the sugar; they wanted change for a shilling; I gave them 5 d. in change; they drank once apiece; my mistress came in; White immediately went out; my mistress said she had lost her box, with about 9 l. in it; she ordered me to light a candle and look about; then Merchant got up and walked out, and left about half the brandy hot behind them. On the Tuesday morning Mr. Brebrook brought the prisoners, and asked me if I should know the people that we suspected; I looked at them and said they were the people, though they were in different clothes, I picked them out from four other young women that were with them, all strangers; they were taken before the Justice; there 
               <persName id="t17670115-11-person141">
                  Anne 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17670115-11-person141" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-11-person141" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-11-person141" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said, Merchant desired her to pick my mistress's pocket for the box and she owned she did it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Merchant prisoner at the time?</p>
               <p>A. Mills. She was.  Merchant said did not value it, they could not hang her. When they were in our tap-room Merchant said she was willing to pay my mistress a crown a week if she would let her have her clothes that she bought with some of the money: they were kept at our house from eight till two; and when going to go before the Justice, she proffered give us the clothes she had on. </p>
               <p>A. Letterman. White would have delivered her clothes up with all her heart. </p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670115-11-person142">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Haines 
               <interp inst="t17670115-11-person142" type="surname" value="Haines"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-11-person142" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-11-person142" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Saturday fortnight, between nine and ten, or thereabouts at night, the two prisoners came to my house; I keep a woman's clothes shop in Rosemary-lane. </p>
               <p>Q. How far is your house from Mrs. Letterman's?</p>
               <p>E. Haines. It is about half a mile distant; the prisoners asked me if I sold gowns; I said, yes; I sold each a gown, a pair of stays, an upper petticoat, a shift, a pair of stockings, a hat, a pair of shoes, and aprons; they had ragged clothes on, but they looked very smart about their heads; I found they had been at a milliner's shop, and got-each a new cap, and a new coloured silk handkerchief.</p>
               <p>Q. What did they lay out with you?</p>
               <p>E. Haines. I think the things came to about 6 l. 7 s. 6 d.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you take them to be?</p>
               <p>E. Haines. I thought they were girls of the town; such often come to clothe themselves at our shop; I thought they had had a good spark.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of money did they pay you with?</p>
               <p>E. Haines. There were some half guineas, and one or two guineas; they paid for the things separate as they bought them, two at a time. One of them had a Christmas-box, such a one as Mrs. Letterman has described; the other took her money out of a housewife; White had half a sixpence in her hand, which she dropped; she said she took it just before and it would not go again; she said she would fling it away; I said, give it to me, it will go among old silver, so she gave it me; this is it which Mrs. Letterman has swore to. I hearing of this robbery let the prosecutrix know of the prisoners, and shewed her the half sixpence.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176701150010"></xptr>White's defence.</p>
               <p>This young woman (meaning her fellow prisoner) and I were coming up Red-lion-street, we went into that house, and called for a pint of brandy hot; I could not stay, and going away by a stocking shop, I kicked a box before me with some money in it; this was in Red-lion-street.</p>
               <p>Merchant's defence.</p>
               <p>I had been drinking with two girls; when I went out of the house, I saw White find the box; I cried, halves.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17670115-11-verdict64" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670115-11-verdict64" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-11-verdict64" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               guilty of stealing, but not in the dwelling-house
            </rs>. <rs id="t17670115-11-punish65" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670115-11-punish65" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670115-11-defend133 t17670115-11-punish65"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670115-11-defend135 t17670115-11-punish65"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
