<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610625-12">
               <interp inst="t17610625-12" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-12" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-12" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610625"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-12" type="date" value="17610625"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610625-12-off63-c82" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-12-defend100 t17610625-12-off63 t17610625-12-verdict68"></join>
         
               <p>189. (M) 
               <persName id="t17610625-12-defend100" type="defendantName">
                  Mary, <rs id="t17610625-12-deflabel62" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-12-defend100 t17610625-12-deflabel62"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17610625-12-person101">
                        John 
                        Dorman 
                     <interp inst="t17610625-12-person101" type="surname" value="Dorman"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610625-12-person101" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610625-12-person101" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
                     <interp inst="t17610625-12-defend100" type="surname" value="Dorman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-12-defend100" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-12-defend100" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ,was indicted for <rs id="t17610625-12-off63" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610625-12-off63" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-12-off63" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing three ribbons, value 3 d. two silk handkerchiefs, value 4 s. three other handkerchiefs, value 1 s. 6 d, one pair of laced ruffles, value 2 s. four linnen caps, value 6 d. one cardinal, value 3 s. one cloth cloak, value 1 s. 6 d. one linnen apron, value 6 d. two cotton gowns, value 5 s. two petticoats, value 5 s. one callimanco petticoat, one pair of leather-breeches, and one row of beads
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17610625-12-victim103" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Cockbill 
                  <interp inst="t17610625-12-victim103" type="surname" value="Cockbill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-12-victim103" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-12-victim103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , the elder, and 
               
                  <persName id="t17610625-12-victim105" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Cockbill 
                  <interp inst="t17610625-12-victim105" type="surname" value="Cockbill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-12-victim105" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-12-victim105" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , the younger, <rs id="t17610625-12-cd64" type="crimeDate">May 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-12-off63 t17610625-12-cd64"></join>. *</p>
               <p>John Cockbill, jun. I am a<rs id="t17610625-12-viclabel65" type="occupation">laceman and broker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-12-victim105 t17610625-12-viclabel65"></join>, and live in <placeName id="t17610625-12-crimeloc66">East Smithfield</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17610625-12-crimeloc66" type="placeName" value="East Smithfield"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610625-12-crimeloc66" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-12-off63 t17610625-12-crimeloc66"></join>: I live with my uncle, he and I are partners. I have known the prisoner above three months, <rs id="t17610625-12-deflabel67" type="occupation">she used to chare</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-12-defend100 t17610625-12-deflabel67"></join> for us. On the 11th of May we left her in trust in the house, and my uncle and aunt and I went out.</p>

               <p>Q. Did the prisoner live near you?</p>
               <p>Cockbill, jun. She lived about 40 yards from us. We returned about nine. She had left the shop, we understood, about seven. The landlord at a public-house, finding nobody at home, went and staid there about as hour, 'till we returned. About two hours after we returned, we missed a waistcoat, a coat, a pair of breeches, a petticoat, and a gown. Then we went and advertised her, and she was taken the next day in a barn by Highgate. I was told she went there in the summer-time to work.</p>
               <p>Q. Who found her?</p>
               <p>Cockbill. jun. I and my aunt. I charged her with taking the things. We found the cardinal, cloak, four handkerchiefs (two silk ones, and two pollicat ones) and a pair of laced ruffles. [ Produced in court, and deposed to.] She had the apron, cloak, and petticoat on. The other things lay by her. She denied having any other things; but before the justice, she said her husband had taken the rest to the Turk's-head.</p>
               <p>Q. Did her husband live with her?</p>
               <p>Cockbill, jun. He did in the neighbourhood.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him that morning that she was left in your shop?</p>
               <p>Cockbill, jun. No, I did not; but I heard him above stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. What is he?</p>
               <p>Cockbill, jun. He is a labouring-man, and works at farmers business. The other things were found at the Turk's-head, and delivered to us. When we asked her how she came to go away, she laid it to her husband. We find he has been a very bad man all his life-time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-12-person106">
                  John 
                  Cockbill 
               <interp inst="t17610625-12-person106" type="surname" value="Cockbill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-12-person106" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-12-person106" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am aunt to the other witness; I know the things to be our property. Some of the things belonged to my husband and kinsman, and some were my wearing apparel; a gown, the ruffles, petticoat, and three ribbons. We all three went out together, when the things were taken away. We left her to to take care of the house. When we came home, I heard her husband had been about our door. I believe the woman to be better than the man.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether any body present told you they saw the man about your door that morning?</p>
               <p>J. Cockbill. He that told me is not here; but had I known he would have been wanted, I could have brought him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-12-person107">
                  Josiah 
                  Riball 
               <interp inst="t17610625-12-person107" type="surname" value="Riball"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-12-person107" type="given" value="Josiah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-12-person107" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable, I was sent for to take charge of the prisoner at the bar; part of these things were found upon her; she cried, and laid it all to her husband.</p>
               <p>Q. What were her words?</p>
               <p>Riball. She said, her husband persuaded her to do it, and that he helped her to take them away.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing of them, any farther than my husband took them; I did not meddle with them. He came in soon after they were gone; he said, he would take my life if I would not let him take them. I have never seen him since I have been taken up.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176106250010"></xptr>J. Cockbill. There were two or three neighbours saw the husband take a bundle from the door, which I could have brought.</p>
               <p>Court. You should secure, and indict him.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610625-12-verdict68" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610625-12-verdict68" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
