<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660219-42">
               <interp inst="t17660219-42" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660219-42" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660219-42" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660219"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660219-42" type="date" value="17660219"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660219-42-off229-c366" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-42-defend467 t17660219-42-off229 t17660219-42-verdict234"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660219-42-off229-c367" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-42-defend468 t17660219-42-off229 t17660219-42-verdict236"></join>
         
               <p>163, 164. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660219-42-defend467" type="defendantName">
                     Francis 
                     Redmond 
                  <interp inst="t17660219-42-defend467" type="surname" value="Redmond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-defend467" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-defend467" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               <persName id="t17660219-42-defend468" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Elizabeth 
                     Webber 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17660219-42-alias-6" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-42-defend468 t17660219-42-alias-6"></join>Redmond</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-defend468" type="surname" value="Webber"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-defend468" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-defend468" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , were indicted, the first for that <rs id="t17660219-42-off229" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-off229" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-off229" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               he, in his own dwelling-house, did make an assault on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17660219-42-victim471" type="victimName">
                           Matthew 
                           Carr 
                        <interp inst="t17660219-42-victim471" type="surname" value="Carr"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660219-42-victim471" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660219-42-victim471" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-42-off229 t17660219-42-victim471"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and violently taking from his person three half guineas, the money of the said Matthew; it was laid also to be done in the dwelling-house of 
                     <persName id="t17660219-42-person472">
                        Elizabeth 
                        Webber 
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-person472" type="surname" value="Webber"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660219-42-person472" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660219-42-person472" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  ; and the other for being present, enticing, procuring, and abetting the said Francis, to do and commit the same in her dwelling-house
            </rs>, <rs id="t17660219-42-cd230" type="crimeDate">Jan. 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-42-off229 t17660219-42-cd230"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660219-42-person473">
                  Matthew 
                  Carr 
               <interp inst="t17660219-42-person473" type="surname" value="Carr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-person473" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-person473" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17660219-42-viclabel231" type="occupation">grocer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-42-victim471 t17660219-42-viclabel231"></join>, and live by Wapping-wall, by King James's stairs. On the 7th of January last, I was out on business in the morning; coming home at near 11 o'clock by the woman's window, in the bottom of <placeName id="t17660219-42-crimeloc232">Spring-street, Shadwell</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17660219-42-crimeloc232" type="placeName" value="Spring-street, Shadwell"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660219-42-crimeloc232" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-42-off229 t17660219-42-crimeloc232"></join>, about an hundred yards from my house, she tapped at the window. I went to the fore door; she asked me if I would walk in. I did: she desired me to go to the fire side, I did. She said her husband (the other prisoner) was gone to Blackwall to work (he is <rs id="t17660219-42-deflabel233" type="occupation">a ballast heaver</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-42-defend467 t17660219-42-deflabel233"></join>). and would not be at home till 11 at night, and desired me to go up stairs with her: she said, she had been at my shop that morning for two ounces of sugar, to ask me to come home to he with her. I went up stairs with her: she shut the outward door; it has a spring lock, and I saw the key hanging on the inside the door. I found the bed was made, and a blind hanging before the window: she said, now if I would go to bed for an hour, she would go to bed with me. I said, could not: she said, I had better pull off my cloaths. I said, I had not time, and could not stay to do that; then she consented to lie down, which she did, and pulled up her cloaths. I was going to - The door opened directly, there I saw the man at the bar: he pretended to be her husband: he locked the door, and directly seized me by the throat. I said, dear Sir, I have not done any thing. He said, I'll make you quiet enough, and took a penknife out, and said, You villain, if you offer to move, I'll rip you up, and kick your guts into the street, unless you will give me a bond of 200 l. I said, I had no such money. Said he, You villain, you blasted rogue, how came you here. I said, that woman enticed me here: she said, O my dear, I'll do so no more. O, you thief, said he, I'll do for you: strip off your cloaths, strip, strip. I begged for mercy, and hoped he would forgive me, and what I had in the world I would give him. Then he said, give me a bond of 100 l. that I said I could not do, and begged on my knees for mercy, and said I would give him all I had in the world, and begged he would abate his passion; then he made an attempt to loose his garter, and threatened to tie me. He took me by the collar, and threw me on the bed. His foot touched the leg of the bed; he tumbled; I got up from under him, and ran to the other side of the room, and begged and said, I would do any thing in the world, if he would let me go: then he said, You villain, you blasted dog, give me a bond for 50 l. I said I could not do that, but I would give him a note for 20 l. He said, 20 l. you blasted rogue, give me your cloaths: then he made an attempt to go to the door, he had the knife in his hand all the time. I begged he would let me have my liberty: he said, You villain, what have you in your pocket. I said, I have got some gold, and some silver, and halfpence, and my watch. Said he, let me see, you thief, you tell me a lye. I said, I have three half guineas in gold, and took<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176602190030"></xptr> it out; then he said, D - n you, you villain, give it me. I gave it him and some shillings. I asked him if he would have my watch: he said, he would not, but I should give him a note for 20 guineas: he locked the door and went down stairs, and fetched some paper up. The woman at the bar sat on the bed all the time. He came up again, and said, now write me a note. I said, I am in such a trembling, it is impossible for me to write it; if you'll write, I'll sign it. He wrote the body of the note, payable to himself or order. I begged he would not pay the note away, and I would get him the money as soon as I could. He said, You villain, you shall give it me to-morrow: he said, you shall swear before you go out. He gave me a book, and said, you must swear never to come here again: said I, that I shall do. The woman bid me kiss the book; I asked for what, he said never to have dealings here again; after that I was permitted to go down stairs. When I was at the fore door, I perceived the key hanging where I had seen it before. He opened the door, and let me out, and I went home. On the Saturday morning he came into my shop as soon as I took the shutters down; he delivered this letter into my hand: the purport of it is,</p>


               <p>SIR,</p>
               <p>"I expect the favour of your company at my</p>
               <p>"house to night, at 3 o'clock precisely. I must</p>
               <p>"move the affair again, which you are no stranger</p>
               <p>"to, &amp;c."</p>
               <p>On the Saturday I went to the Justice, and got a warrant, and on the Monday we took the prisoner before the Justice, and as I was coming back, I was arrested upon this note. The prisoner was committed for robbing me of my money.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660219-42-person474">
                  Anne 
                  Hopkins 
               <interp inst="t17660219-42-person474" type="surname" value="Hopkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-person474" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-person474" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the elder. I live next door to the prisoner. On the 7th of January, about 11 in the day, I heard a surprising noise as I sat in my house. Upon sending my daughter up stairs, she came down and said, she thought the prisoner had found somebody in bed with his wife. I went up stairs, and heard a voice crying bitterly for mercy, and that the prisoner would asswage his passion. I heard the prisoner say, you blasted rogue, I'll punish you another way, I heard the other say, he would satisfy him even to all he had in the world. I heard the prisoner say, how came you there: the other said, his supposed wife had decoyed him there. The partition is very slight between us, and we can hear all that passes, if they speak any thing loud.</p>
               <p>She gave an account of hearing almost all the words the prosecutor had mentioned.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660219-42-person475">
                  Anne 
                  Hopkins 
               <interp inst="t17660219-42-person475" type="surname" value="Hopkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-person475" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-person475" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the younger confirmed the evidence given by her mother, being with her in giving attention to what passed in the prisoner's apartment.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660219-42-person476">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Swinney 
               <interp inst="t17660219-42-person476" type="surname" value="Swinney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-person476" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-person476" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The woman at the bar's maiden name was 
               <persName id="t17660219-42-person477">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Street 
               <interp inst="t17660219-42-person477" type="surname" value="Street"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-person477" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-person477" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I saw her married to 
               <persName id="t17660219-42-person478">
                  William 
                  Webber 
               <interp inst="t17660219-42-person478" type="surname" value="Webber"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-person478" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-person478" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             at Portsmouth August the 2d was twelve months, and I dined with them that day: here is a certificate of their marriage; I examined it with the church book, it is word for word right (producing it.) I saw that Webber last Wednesday morning.</p>
               <p>The mother and daughter said they heard and saw the two prisoners go out in about half an hour after the prosecutor, as loving as ever they saw them in their lives.</p>
               <p>Redmond's defence.</p>
               <p>I was at work that morning, I had no notion of any such thing; I always labour hard for my bread, I came back and catched that man in bed with my wife, in a manner I shall not express now. I stepped back, and threatened him to be sure, but I was first going to tie them together, to turn them out of the door, he catched hold of the door as I was going out, and fell down on his knees, and begged for God's sake not to expose him, and he would give me all he had; he begged for God's sake for me to take the money out of his hand.</p>
               <p>Webber's defence.</p>
               <p>I was married to Mr. Webber at Portsmouth; after that he brought me to London, then I heard he had another wife; I found her out and told her; she said she was very sorry for it; I quitted him, thinking I should be counted an adulteress. Soon after that he came after me, and insisted upon my living with him; we came to an agreement, and he drawed up a writing never to come after me. I used Mr. Carr's shop ever since Michaelmas last; every time I went there he was enticing me. and made very great offers, and said, if ever I wanted money he would assist me. I told him I wanted no other man. He would pull out handfuls of money to induce me to lie with him. When I met him in the street, he would be making me proposals, at last I did agree that he might call; my husband being out at business, I said, I would grant him the favour, when an opportunity served. He came to the house three times before that. I went to his shop that morning for two ounces of sugar; he asked me if my husband was at work? I said he was gone to<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176602190031"></xptr> Blackwall. Said he, may I call, there shall be no money wanting: he came. My husband had taken the key of the door to let himself in: he came in order to lie down to get some rest against he went to work. He was in a great passion with me, and struck me down to the ground, and asked the other what business he had there with his wife, and said he would take the law of him. Mr. Carr desired he would not, for that would expose him and hurt him in his business, and offered him a note of twenty guineas, and three half guineas he had in his pocket, and delivered the money voluntarily, and offered his watch, but my husband refused it.</p>
               <p>Redmond called 
               <persName id="t17660219-42-person479">
                  John 
                  Hesting 
               <interp inst="t17660219-42-person479" type="surname" value="Hesting"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-person479" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-person479" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17660219-42-person480">
                  William 
                  Rawney 
               <interp inst="t17660219-42-person480" type="surname" value="Rawney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-person480" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-person480" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17660219-42-person481">
                  Martin 
                  Mordin 
               <interp inst="t17660219-42-person481" type="surname" value="Mordin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-person481" type="given" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-person481" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , three ballast men. The two first attempted to prove he was by the water-side, in order to go to work at ballast beaving; but the tide not serving, he did not stay. The last said he had known him 18 months in England, and 7 or 8 years in Ireland, where they were bred and born.</p>
               <p>Q. to Hopkins the younger. Did you see 
               <persName id="t17660219-42-person482">
                  Redmond
               <interp inst="t17660219-42-person482" type="given" value="Redmond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-person482" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             that morning before you heard the noise?</p>
               <p>A. Hopkins. As near as I can say, I saw him sitting by his fire side about half an hour before I heard this noise.</p>
               <p>Q. to Carr. Was Webber at your house that morning, and for what purpose?</p>
               <p>Carr. She came that morning about eight o'clock, for two ounces of sugar; and she told me her husband would be at Blackwall, and would not be at home till eleven at night. Redmond</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660219-42-verdict234" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-verdict234" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17660219-42-punish235" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-punish235" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-42-defend467 t17660219-42-punish235"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Webber <rs id="t17660219-42-verdict236" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660219-42-verdict236" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
