<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670429-48">
               <interp inst="t17670429-48" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670429-48" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670429-48" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670429"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670429-48" type="date" value="17670429"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670429-48-off263-c323" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-48-defend426 t17670429-48-off263 t17670429-48-verdict265"></join>
         
               <p>244. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17670429-48-defend426" type="defendantName">
                     John
                      M'Donnell
                  <interp inst="t17670429-48-defend426" type="surname" value="M'Donnell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-48-defend426" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-48-defend426" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17670429-48-off263" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670429-48-off263" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-48-off263" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               forging a certain order for the payment of 50 l. with the name of T. Haydon subscribed thereunto, directed to Hinton Brown and Co. and for publishing the same, with intent to defraud 
                     
                        <persName id="t17670429-48-victim428" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Keyo 
                        <interp inst="t17670429-48-victim428" type="surname" value="Keyo"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670429-48-victim428" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670429-48-victim428" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-48-off263 t17670429-48-victim428"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17670429-48-cd264" type="crimeDate">Jan. 31</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-48-off263 t17670429-48-cd264"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-48-person429">
                  James 
                  Keyo 
               <interp inst="t17670429-48-person429" type="surname" value="Keyo"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-48-person429" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-48-person429" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner at the bar and another person came to my house on the 31st of January, between<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176704290026"></xptr> two and three in the morning; they knock'd at the door, and insisted upon coming in; I said, I let nobody in at that time of the night, but if you'll go quietly to bed I'll let you in; they said they would; I let them in; they insisted upon having something; they drank two bottles of wine and went to bed. In the morning M'Donnell ordered coffee for breakfast; when that was over they rang the bell, I answered; M'Donnell asked me if I would give him change; he took his pocketbook out and gave me this draft (holding it in his hand.)</p>
               <p>It is read to this purport.</p>
               <p>"London, 18 Dec. 1766. No 78.</p>
               <p>"To Messrs. Hinton Brown and son.</p>
               <p>"Pay to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17670429-48-person430">
                  John
               <interp inst="t17670429-48-person430" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-48-person430" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             M'Donnell, or bearer, the</p>
               <p>"sum of 50 l. and place it to the account of</p>
               <p>"T. Haydon."</p>
               <p>I took the draft, with intent to get cash for it; I went to the banker, it was stopp'd; I told them, if they would send a person with me they might get the person that delivered it to me. The prisoner and the other man had ordered a dinner at half an hour after two, they were gone out; the clerk went home to his master to let him know; I sent down to the Blue Anchor in Rosemary-lane, there the prisoner was found; I never saw the prisoner before to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I gave him the draft to get change for it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-48-person431">
                  James 
                  Tumings 
               <interp inst="t17670429-48-person431" type="surname" value="Tumings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-48-person431" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-48-person431" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner and I breakfasted together that morning, he gave a draft out of his pocket to the waiter, but I never had it in my hand.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-48-person432">
                  Charles 
                  Cole 
               <interp inst="t17670429-48-person432" type="surname" value="Cole"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-48-person432" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-48-person432" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am clerk to Messrs. Hinton Brown and Co. this draft was brought to me by a waiter; I suspected it to be a false draft; he said he brought it from the Turk's Head bagnio; I applied to Mr. Brown, he said it was not a good one.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it Mr. Haydon's hand-writing?</p>
               <p>Cole. It is not. When the prisoner was before my Lord-Mayor, he said he had this note of Mr. Haydon, who is now here, and made affidavit of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Has that Haydon money with you?</p>
               <p>Cole. He has; he keeps cash with us. He has a cheque which he draws his bills on, which we cheque in our book; this is not his note, but it is a cheque of our shop; how he came by it I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Mr. Nash. This pocket-book (producing it) was sealed up by my Lord-Mayor, I had it from Mr. Haydon; it came out of the prisoner's pocket, and there are other notes; I have kept it ever since; the pocket-book is letter'd with the name 
               <persName id="t17670429-48-person433">
                  John
               <interp inst="t17670429-48-person433" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-48-person433" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             M'Donnell upon it, here are many notes in it; some are Parrot's notes, payable to M Donnell; and M'Donnell's notes, payable to Parrot.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I did not write it, neither did I know that it was forged; I knew nothing of it till I was taken: I gave goods for it, and thought I could get cash for it at any time; and when I heard it was forged, I thought it was Mr. Haydon's handwriting.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-48-person434">
                  John 
                  Plunket 
               <interp inst="t17670429-48-person434" type="surname" value="Plunket"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-48-person434" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-48-person434" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I have known the prisoner ten or eleven years, he is by trade a hatter. He told me in September last, he was going into business with a gentleman lately come from the West-Indies, who was to find money and he judgment. In two or three days after that, he called upon me in order to ask me a question in regard to a woman; he said he was going into the city, he desired me to take a walk with him; we went to a house in Cheapside. When we came there he went to the bar, and asked if any body had enquired for him; we sat down, and presently Mr. Brown came in. He said the gentleman had been there but was gone; the prisoner said he was sorry for that: Brown gave M'Donnel a draft; I had the curiosity to look at it, it had a banker's cheque, and was for 50 l. drawn upon Mess. Brown and son, Lombard-street, signed T. Haydon, (he looks at the draft) it was very much like this, but I cannot swear to it; this was about the Thursday after the 16th of December. He gave him this note in order to buy goods: they talked about their business. Brown told me he had a will of a relation that died in the East-Indies, and had left him 4000 l. He desired me to go to the Sword-blade coffee-house; I did, but he did not come.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Plunket. I am clerk to Mr. Yapp, an attorney in Clifford's-inn.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did Brown live?</p>
               <p>Plunket. He has lived these five or six years last past in Prince's-street, Drury lane. He talked largely of his fortune; I took him to be a man of fortune.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is he?</p>
               <p>Plunket. I know nothing of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-48-person435">
                  Michael 
                  Welch 
               <interp inst="t17670429-48-person435" type="surname" value="Welch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-48-person435" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-48-person435" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner upwards of seventeen years, I knew him in Dublin; he was looked upon to be an honest fair dealing man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-48-person436">
                  Charles 
                  Brady 
               <interp inst="t17670429-48-person436" type="surname" value="Brady"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-48-person436" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-48-person436" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about sixteen years; he have a good character.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176704290027"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-48-person437">
                  John 
                  Mannell 
               <interp inst="t17670429-48-person437" type="surname" value="Mannell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-48-person437" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-48-person437" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about twelve months; I looked upon him to be an honest just man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17670429-48-verdict265" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670429-48-verdict265" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17670429-48-punish266" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670429-48-punish266" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-48-defend426 t17670429-48-punish266"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
