<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670218-38">
               <interp inst="t17670218-38" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670218-38" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670218-38" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670218"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670218-38" type="date" value="17670218"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670218-38-off215-c294" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670218-38-defend367 t17670218-38-off215 t17670218-38-verdict220"></join>
         
               <p>172. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17670218-38-defend367" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Guy 
                  <interp inst="t17670218-38-defend367" type="surname" value="Guy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-defend367" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-defend367" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for <rs id="t17670218-38-off215" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-off215" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-off215" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he, on the King's highway, on Anne, <rs id="t17670218-38-viclabel216" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670218-38-victim370 t17670218-38-viclabel216"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17670218-38-victim368" type="victimName">
                        Nicholas
                        <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176702180026"></xptr> Kemp<interp inst="t17670218-38-victim368" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670218-38-victim368" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  . <rs id="t17670218-38-viclabel217" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670218-38-victim368 t17670218-38-viclabel217"></join>; did make on assault, putting her in corporal fear and danger and taking from her person a silk purse, value 6 d. a silver dollar, a quarter guinea, a 4 s. 6 d. piece, a half crown, and 2 s. in money numbered, the property of the said Nicholas
            </rs>, <rs id="t17670218-38-cd218" type="crimeDate">Feb 9</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670218-38-off215 t17670218-38-cd218"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
               
                  <persName id="t17670218-38-victim370" type="victimName">
                     Anne 
                     Kemp 
                  <interp inst="t17670218-38-victim370" type="surname" value="Kemp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-victim370" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-victim370" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            . Last Monday se'nnight, between six and seven in the evening, Mr. Kemp. I, and Mrs. Heyman were in a chariot, and got through <placeName id="t17670218-38-crimeloc219">Marybone turnpike</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17670218-38-crimeloc219" type="placeName" value="Marybone turnpike"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17670218-38-crimeloc219" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670218-38-off215 t17670218-38-crimeloc219"></join>; Mrs. Heyman said to me, Mrs. Kemp, there is a highwayman; a man came up on horseback and demanded Mrs. Kemp's money; Mr. Kemp let down the window, and swore he should not rob him, he would not give it him; Mr. Kemp said he knew him; then I pulled out my purse, and gave it the man; he thanked me, and away he went immediately.</p>
               <p>Q. What were his words, as near as you can recollect?</p>
               <p>A. Kemp. He said, your money, Sir, your money, and presented a pistol to Mr. Kemp; I was sitting on the right-hand, the farther side from the man, and handed my purse over Mr. Kemp's shoulder; I gave it him because I was affrighted, and wanted to get rid of him.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a purse, and what was in it?</p>
               <p>A. Kemp. It was a green silk purse; there was a Spanish dollar, a King William and Queen Mary's half crown, a 4 s. 6 d. piece, a 5 s. 3 d. and some silver.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe his person?</p>
               <p>A. Kemp. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the prisoner taken?</p>
               <p>A. Kemp. He was taken the next morning.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670218-38-person371">
                  Martha 
                  Heyman 
               <interp inst="t17670218-38-person371" type="surname" value="Heyman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-person371" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-person371" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the chariot at the time Mrs. Kemp was robbed; I saw the man, and I said, here is a highwayman.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you say so?</p>
               <p>M. Heyman. Because I saw him come up with a pistol in his hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him so as to know him?</p>
               <p>M. Heyman. I saw he was a black; he stopped the chariot, and demanded the money, not of any person particularly; Mr. Kemp said he would not be robbed, and Mrs. Kemp reached over his shoulder, and gave the highwayman her purse, and he rode off immediately.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at the prisoner, do you know him?</p>
               <p>M. Heyman. I cannot be positive that he was the man; it was like him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670218-38-person372">
                  Nicholas 
                  Kemp 
               <interp inst="t17670218-38-person372" type="surname" value="Kemp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-person372" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-person372" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; Last Monday was se'nnight in the evening, about six, or a little more, we came through the turnpike at Marybone; going up to the chapel, a little way beyond that, I heard a person say, stop; I put down the window, and said to the coachman, what are you prisoner came up, and said, your money, your money, in a minute; immediately I asked him how he came to stop me in that manner, and him go about his business, and said, ( which was very imprudently done to a highwayman) I knew him; I could not get the door open, or I believe I should have unhorsed him; he said, what, you will not be robbed; I said, I will not. After that, my wife put her hand over my shoulder, (for I was turned about to him) and he snatched her purse out of her hand, which I did not perceive till after he was gone; he rode off immediately.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell who stopped you?</p>
               <p>Kemp. It was a black man, of the prisoner's stature and size; the pieces of money are remarkable; the King William and Queen Mary's half crown I gave my wife about seven years ago for a pocket-piece.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670218-38-person373">
                  Richard 
                  Bond 
               <interp inst="t17670218-38-person373" type="surname" value="Bond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-person373" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-person373" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the Monday after Mrs. Kemp was robbed, Mr. Kemp came and gave information to Sir 
               <persName id="t17670218-38-person374">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17670218-38-person374" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-person374" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-person374" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             of the man, a black highwayman; I was desired to go in pursuit of him; I went up as far as the Farthing Pye turnpike; I had intelligence he came into Tottenham-court road; I went on, and had intelligence of him till he came into Oxford-road; then I heard no more of him that night; the next day I was going through Ryder's-court, by Cranbourn alley, (there were then bills put up, describing the man) I there saw the prisoner answered the description of the bills; I went and looked at him two or three minutes; after that I said to him, my friend, you must take a walk with me; he seemed to be greatly confused. Coming through Long-acre towards Sir 
               <persName id="t17670218-38-person375">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17670218-38-person375" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-person375" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-person375" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, he stopped once or twice, and said he would not go any farther; I told him he should; he asked me for what; I told him he had assaulted a gentleman, and he must go and ask his pardon; he said, where; I said, at a public-house; (having no person with me, I did not think proper to say where I was going with him) as we were coming through a little alley called Felix-alley, he wanted to put his hand into his left-hand breeches pocket; I said, keep your hand out of your pocket, for you shall not put your hand into your pocket till you come into the public-house; I was on the right side of him; as soon as we came into the public-house, which was the 
               <persName id="t17670218-38-person376">
                  Brown 
                  Bear 
               <interp inst="t17670218-38-person376" type="surname" value="Bear"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-person376" type="given" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-person376" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in Bow-street, I sent over to Sir 
               <persName id="t17670218-38-person377">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17670218-38-person377" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-person377" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-person377" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, to know if he was at home; then I said, now let me put my hand into that pocket; he was unwilling; I said, I will; I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176702180027"></xptr> put my hand in, and took out this purse, with this money in it; (a green silk purse, with money in it, produced in court.)</p>
               <p>Court to Mrs. Kemp. Look at that purse.</p>
               <p>A. Kemp. To the best of my knowledge, this is my purse that I gave the man at that time.</p>
               <p>Court. See what is in it; ( she takes out a Spanish dollar, and a William and Mary's half crown.)</p>
               <p>A. Kemp. I can very safely swear to these two pieces (holding them in her hand.)</p>
               <p>Bond. There were several shillings in the purse, the prisoner was in a great confusion; then I took him over to Sir 
               <persName id="t17670218-38-person378">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17670218-38-person378" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-person378" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-person378" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's; he was then committed till Mr. Kemp came, which was on the next day, being Wednesday.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. What breeches pocket did you take that money out of?</p>
               <p>Bond. I took it out of the prisoner's left-hand breeches pocket.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have no pocket on that side.</p>
               <p>Bond. The prisoner said before Sir 
               <persName id="t17670218-38-person379">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17670218-38-person379" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-person379" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-person379" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he had had that Spanish dollar seven years ago, when on board a man of war.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. That I had, if not more; I brought it from my own country with me, New-York.</p>
               <p>Court. 
               <persName id="t17670218-38-person380">
                  Read
               <interp inst="t17670218-38-person380" type="given" value="Read"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-person380" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the date which is upon it.</p>
               <p>Clerk of the arraigns. It is dated 1764.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670218-38-person381">
                  John 
                  Pilgrim 
               <interp inst="t17670218-38-person381" type="surname" value="Pilgrim"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-person381" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-person381" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a stable-keeper, and live at Chelsea; the prisoner had a horse of me on a Monday; I did not take notice of the time.</p>
               <p>Q. How long before he was taken up?</p>
               <p>Pilgrim. It was not above a day before he was taken; he had him about three o'clock, and he came home about seven, or a little after; I cannot tell to half an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. What business is the prisoner of?</p>
               <p>Pilgrim. I cannot tell that; he was in the same regiment that one of my men was; I only knew him by his coming to see him.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he say he was going when he hired the horse?</p>
               <p>Pilgrim. He said he was going to the Three Conies in Rumford road, that is about four miles from London.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a horse was it?</p>
               <p>Pilgrim. He is a brownish horse, about fourteen hands high, with a rat tail.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670218-38-person382">
                  George 
                  Raleigh 
               <interp inst="t17670218-38-person382" type="surname" value="Raleigh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-person382" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-person382" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I drove the chariot last Monday was se'nnight; the man that stopped us had a black face; I cannot say positively to the prisoner; the horse he was upon was very low in flesh, and he had a rat tail; I know no more of the robbery than what has been given an account of.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670218-38-person383">
                  Thomas 
                  Sadler 
               <interp inst="t17670218-38-person383" type="surname" value="Sadler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-person383" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-person383" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Castle in Jews Row, the prisoner come to my house, and called to Tuesday se'nnight and after that me this 5 s. 3 d. piece I chary'd it oning came to to 8 d. half penny; (Produced in court.)</p>
               <p>Court. Mrs. Kemp. that piece of money.</p>
               <p>A Kemp. (She in her hand) I believe this to be the same that was in my purse that I lost, that time we were stopped, I know it by this little hole almost punched through it.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner to Sadler. What did you say to she when you gave the change?</p>
               <p>Sadler. I said, in the head would cut King George's it was in their power; (the was just in the gullet)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670218-38-person384">
                  Samuel 
                  Thring 
               <interp inst="t17670218-38-person384" type="surname" value="Thring"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-person384" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-person384" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was the footman behind the chariot at the time it was stopped.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the colour of the horse the man rode?</p>
               <p>Thring. I take the horse to be either a black or a brown; the hair was very thin upon his tail, and he was low in flesh.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Whether you think I was the man that robbed your mistress?</p>
               <p>Thring. I cannot say; all that I know is, that he was a black.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>There are a thousand black men in London besides me: last Monday se'nnight I went to see a serjeant's sister that lives at the Three Conies in Rumford road; when I had rode over the stones, and cantered about half a mile, I found my horse would not perform his journey; I turned back again, and got to a house in King-street, Westminster; I got there about ten minutes after five, and gave my horse a feed of corn, and in about half an hour or three quarters after, I went for Chelsea; I have been in England six years.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17670218-38-verdict220" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-verdict220" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17670218-38-punish221" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670218-38-punish221" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670218-38-defend367 t17670218-38-punish221"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
