<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610916-24">
               <interp inst="t17610916-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-24" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610916"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-24" type="date" value="17610916"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610916-24-off129-c181" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-24-defend220 t17610916-24-off129 t17610916-24-verdict133"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610916-24-off130-c182" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-24-defend222 t17610916-24-off130 t17610916-24-verdict133"></join>
         
               <p>244 (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610916-24-defend220" type="defendantName">
                     Ann 
                     Burton 
                  <interp inst="t17610916-24-defend220" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-defend220" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-defend220" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17610916-24-defend222" type="defendantName">
                     Eleanor 
                     Dillon 
                  <interp inst="t17610916-24-defend222" type="surname" value="Dillon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-defend222" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-defend222" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17610916-24-deflabel128" type="occupation">spinsters</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-24-defend220 t17610916-24-deflabel128"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-24-defend222 t17610916-24-deflabel128"></join>, were indicted, the first, for <rs id="t17610916-24-off129" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-off129" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-off129" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch, value 4 l. and one gold ring, value 10 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17610916-24-victim224" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Flannagan 
                        <interp inst="t17610916-24-victim224" type="surname" value="Flannagan"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610916-24-victim224" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610916-24-victim224" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately and secretly from his person
            </rs>, and the other for <rs id="t17610916-24-off130" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-off130" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-off130" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving the same, well knowing them to have been stolen
            </rs>, <rs id="t17610916-24-cd131" type="crimeDate">Aug. 4</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-24-off129 t17610916-24-cd131"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-24-off130 t17610916-24-cd131"></join>.*</p>
               <p>James Flannagan. I happened to go out about my business, on the 4th of August in the morning, to order some coals in. I happened to meet with some acquaintance, and happened to stay some time longer than ordinary. I went also to got oget some wood in, and happened to come into the street where mother Alien keeps this house; I coming by the door, happened to come into this house.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is this house?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-24-person225">
                  James 
                  Flannagan 
               <interp inst="t17610916-24-person225" type="surname" value="Flannagan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person225" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . It is in <placeName id="t17610916-24-crimeloc132">Gerrard street, by Golden-square</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-24-crimeloc132" type="placeName" value="Gerrard street, by Golden-square"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-24-crimeloc132" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-24-off129 t17610916-24-crimeloc132"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-24-off130 t17610916-24-crimeloc132"></join>. I went to order some wood in Princess-street, then in Long-acre; and coming from this street, happened to get into this house; and when I came to the door, I knocked at the door. Says Mrs. Allen, do not let the man in; says 
               <persName id="t17610916-24-person226">
                  Nancy 
                  Burton 
               <interp inst="t17610916-24-person226" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person226" type="given" value="Nancy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person226" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I know the man very well. When I got into the house, they pushed me to the end of the stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did that?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. One Charlotte, a woman that was there, a maiden; she, and 
               <persName id="t17610916-24-person227">
                  Ann 
                  Burton 
               <interp inst="t17610916-24-person227" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person227" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person227" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Says I to them, you pack of bitches, directly to them. I do not know what they did to me.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you imagine they did to you?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. They only pushed me up to the stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. What did they do after that?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. They pushed me into the parlour.</p>
               <p>Q. What was done there?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. 
               <persName id="t17610916-24-person228">
                  Nancy 
                  Burton 
               <interp inst="t17610916-24-person228" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person228" type="given" value="Nancy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person228" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and this Charlotte, that passed for a maid.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you mean the maid-servant of the house?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. Yes; I was not there long, before 
               <persName id="t17610916-24-person229">
                  Nancy 
                  Burton 
               <interp inst="t17610916-24-person229" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person229" type="given" value="Nancy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person229" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             took me out of the house; but we happened to sit down in the parlour window together. Burton carried me to the corner of Queen-street, about 30 yard off. I happened to have occasion to turn about to do what I had occasion for (that is, I made water.) She directly dropped me, and returned back, and knocked at this mother Allen's door, where we came out at. I followed her; mother Allen leaned over the hatch. Said I, you old wretch, let me in, I have been robbed of my watch, give it me? Go along fellow, said she, you never was here.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you charge any body particularly with taking it?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. I charged 
               <persName id="t17610916-24-person230">
                  Ann 
                  Burton 
               <interp inst="t17610916-24-person230" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person230" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person230" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; with that she shut the door against me. I was obliged to go to my own home; mother Allen said, go along you drunken fellow, you never was here.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you drunk?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. I was not so fuddled as that, but I know I had my watch and ring, when I went into that whore's house, and I missed my watch directly. I mistrusted directly when I missed 
               <persName id="t17610916-24-person231">
                  Nancy 
                  Burton 
               <interp inst="t17610916-24-person231" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person231" type="given" value="Nancy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person231" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , then I missed my watch and ring directly at the corner of Queen-street.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know this was a house of bad same?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. I did. After this I went to justice Fielding.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. About two days after, I desired them to deliver the watch, and they would not; and I was obliged to go to the justice.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you go to, to demand your watch?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. To 
               <persName id="t17610916-24-person232">
                  Nancy 
                  Burton 
               <interp inst="t17610916-24-person232" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person232" type="given" value="Nancy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person232" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I went to nobody else. But this Charlotte, they two, and mother Allen, were all about me. Allen and Charlotte were cleared, and the girl that went out with me, was sent to jail; as to what past among themselves, I cannot say, evidence is to prove that.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see your watch again?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. The constable has that, they all three before the justice deny'd knowing any thing of the watch; and laid it on a poor girl, one Bell. Mrs. Allen, told the justice, that I brought a creature into her house, that had not so much nose upon her face, as would make a two-penny mark. I told Mr. Fielding, I had nobody along with me; one Mrs. Eaton, that lives near the lady, happened to see me go in, and said, God help that poor man, if he has any thing in his pocket, he will be sure to be robbed of it. Said Mr. Fielding, bring your evidence in the afternoon, and let them bring theirs.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you by your watch again?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. I got it at Mr. Fielding's, the constable delivered it to me.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160031"></xptr>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. This was the 4th of August.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. It was between four and five when I came into Gerrard street.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you been drinking?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. I had drank a little.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober at that time?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. I cannot say that I was very sober; but capable of knowing what I did.</p>
               <p>Q. What kind of a ring was it?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. A gold ring.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a watch?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. A silver watch, I had it when I went in there.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. Because I had my ring.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you make any observation at going in, that you had your watch?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. No, I did not; but I had my ring on my little finger, and I missed the ring as soon as I came out.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you say who took the ring from your finger?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. I cannot swear that.</p>
               <p>Q. Could it be taken from your finger, and you not know the time when it was taken?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. Yes, Sir, it was very easy to be taken off.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain that you went to Allen's house at all?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. Yes, I am certain I was there.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know one 
               <persName id="t17610916-24-person233">
                  Ann 
                  Heather 
               <interp inst="t17610916-24-person233" type="surname" value="Heather"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person233" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person233" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you not been with her no time that day?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen her to-day?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Where?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. Here in the yard.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at the King's-head in Marybone-street?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you charge any other person with taking your things?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Mrs. Holt?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. I do; she lives opposite to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether the same day you lost your watch, you did not go to the house of 
               <persName id="t17610916-24-person234">
                  Ann 
                  Holt 
               <interp inst="t17610916-24-person234" type="surname" value="Holt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person234" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person234" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , intoxicated with liquor, and charge her with stealing your watch?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. I went to her house about the hour of five, after I had lost my watch; but did not charge her with stealing it. I said, I had lost my watch, but not that I lost it in her house. I told her Nanny Burton had robbed me of my watch and ring; but my wife finding me there, for she came over, and a woman may say something a in passion; but I never said Mrs. Holt robbed me.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever been in any jail to 
               <persName id="t17610916-24-person235">
                  Ann 
                  Heather 
               <interp inst="t17610916-24-person235" type="surname" value="Heather"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person235" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person235" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , since you was robbed.</p>
               <p>Flannagan. No, I never was. I went to her to New Prison.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you present when 
               <persName id="t17610916-24-person236">
                  Ann 
                  Holt 
               <interp inst="t17610916-24-person236" type="surname" value="Holt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person236" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person236" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confessed she had the watch of you?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. Yes, she confessed that at justice Fielding's. She said, I gave the watch out of my pocket, and the ring from my finger, to her.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you say to her, when you saw her in New Prison, after this?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. Nothing at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not tell her, that by such a confession, she was liable to be hanged?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. No, sir, I scorn to be guilty of such a thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not tell her, it would be much better for her to give evidence against the two prisoners, in order to save herself?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. No, no, no, sir.</p>
               <p>Q. For what purpose did you knock at Mrs. Allen's door?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. I had no business with her, nor she with me. I suppose I went there to be robbed.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath, for what purpose did you go there?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. By knowing 
               <persName id="t17610916-24-person237">
                  Nancy 
                  Burton 
               <interp inst="t17610916-24-person237" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person237" type="given" value="Nancy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person237" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; but I had no intentions at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Who charged 
               <persName id="t17610916-24-person238">
                  Ann 
                  Heather 
               <interp inst="t17610916-24-person238" type="surname" value="Heather"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person238" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person238" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. Justice Fielding did, but I said, I had never seen her in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you not vindicate her?</p>
               <p>Flannagan. She had pawned the watch,</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-24-person239">
                  Mary 
                  Eaton 
               <interp inst="t17610916-24-person239" type="surname" value="Eaton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person239" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person239" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the street where Mrs. Allen lives, over-against her. On the 4th of July or August, about five in the afternoon, I saw the prosecutor resting himself over a post by my door, he was in liquor, he crost the way to Mrs. Allen's door. Somebody said, shut the door; it was shut. A few minutes after, they let him in. He went and sat down in the parlour, with his back towards us. Immediately the girls got about him, and jostled him about the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160032"></xptr> house, to the foot of the stairs; one of them goes by the name of Charlotte. Then they came out into the street, and in again; there were three of us at my window, we cou'd see them very plain. Gerrard-street is a very narrow street. After this, 
               <persName id="t17610916-24-person240">
                  Ann 
                  Burton 
               <interp inst="t17610916-24-person240" type="surname" value="Burton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person240" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person240" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             went out, and the prosecutor followed her, and went to the right-hand corner of the street. She soon left him, and in a few minutes after, he returned, and called to Mrs. Allen, and said, he had been robbed of his watch and ring, Allen said, go along, you drunken dirty fellow, you have not been in my house. Hearing this, made me take the man's part.</p>

               <p>[ 
               <persName id="t17610916-24-person241">
                  Rebecca 
                  Pribble 
               <interp inst="t17610916-24-person241" type="surname" value="Pribble"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person241" type="given" value="Rebecca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person241" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , lived in the house with 
               <persName id="t17610916-24-person242">
                  Mary 
                  Eaton 
               <interp inst="t17610916-24-person242" type="surname" value="Eaton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person242" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person242" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and confirmed her account.]</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-24-person243">
                  Mary 
                  Heather 
               <interp inst="t17610916-24-person243" type="surname" value="Heather"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person243" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person243" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming along on Friday, about a quarter after five, and saw 
               <persName id="t17610916-24-person244">
                  Eleanor 
                  Dillan 
               <interp inst="t17610916-24-person244" type="surname" value="Dillan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person244" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person244" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at a publick-house door; we had a pint of beer together. She shewed me a watch, and said, she was going to pawn it. I went with her to the pawnbroker, and he stopped it, and the ring was left for 2 s. in my name. She desired me to tell the pawnbroker, the watch was my master's, because I was cleaner dressed than she was. The gentleman would not take the watch. Then she said, she would sell it to a Jew. So I carried it home, and shewed it to an acquaintance of mine, one 
               <persName id="t17610916-24-person245">
                  Joseph 
                  Radnal 
               <interp inst="t17610916-24-person245" type="surname" value="Radnal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person245" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and said, I had it of Dillan. He said, she did not come honestly by it, and he would keep it till it was advertized; and if not, would advertize it himself. I said the man gave it me; Dillan bid me say so, and then they would be both cleared, and she would allow me a shilling a day in jail.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-24-person246">
                  Richard 
                  Gray 
               <interp inst="t17610916-24-person246" type="surname" value="Gray"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person246" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-person246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had a search-warrant, to search Allen's house, and likewise to take up those people. I found nothing, I brought Allen, Burton, and another woman, to justice Fielding, another person brought Dillan there. Then Dillan told where the things were in pawn. I went by her direction, and found the ring, pawned for 3 s. Then I went with Dillan, and found Heather. I then went, by Heather's directions, to a baker; I think his name is Radnal, just turning into Long-acre, he came and delivered the watch to Heather, in the coach. She was committed on suspicion of stealing the watch. On her second examination, she said, she had the watch and ring of the prisoner Dillan.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17610916-24-verdict133" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-24-verdict133" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
