<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17631207-54">
               <interp inst="t17631207-54" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-54" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-54" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17631207"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-54" type="date" value="17631207"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17631207-54-off294-c396" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-54-defend506 t17631207-54-off294 t17631207-54-verdict297"></join>
         
               <p>57. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17631207-54-defend506" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Johnson 
                  <interp inst="t17631207-54-defend506" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-54-defend506" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-54-defend506" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17631207-54-off294" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631207-54-off294" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-54-off294" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing three pieces of linnen cloth, containing 72 yards, value 7 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17631207-54-victim508" type="victimName">
                     Mark 
                     Ridgway 
                  <interp inst="t17631207-54-victim508" type="surname" value="Ridgway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-54-victim508" type="given" value="Mark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-54-victim508" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-54-off294 t17631207-54-victim508"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17631207-54-cd295" type="crimeDate">December 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-54-off294 t17631207-54-cd295"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-54-person509">
                  Mark 
                  Ridgway 
               <interp inst="t17631207-54-person509" type="surname" value="Ridgway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-54-person509" type="given" value="Mark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-54-person509" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an <rs id="t17631207-54-viclabel296" type="occupation">Irish factor</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-54-victim508 t17631207-54-viclabel296"></join>, and live in Laurence lane. About a month ago, I began a general repair in my house, which required various workmen to be employed. When we got rid of the workmen in general, we took a proper account of our stock, to see if we had lost any thing during the reparation: we found we had lost two fine pieces of linnen. We could not think of any one person to charge them upon, as there were such a number of them there: we made one complete finish last Monday, then took a fresh account (the first account was taken on Thursday the first of this month) we found we had lost two pieces more since. I recollected as carefully as I could, what persons could have had any concern in the warehouse in the intermitting time, and, we were certain, that it could be none but the carpenter and the painter, who were then in the house. I concluded, it must be one of these men, but had no reason to suspect one more than the other; upon which I called them into separate rooms to examine them a part: they both endeavoured to clear themselves. The prisoner (who is the painter) begged I would take direction where he lived, as he was a house-keeper, that I might not hurt his character. I recommended to them both to continue in my house, while I went with a written order from them to their wives to make enquiry: the painter's direction to his house, was at Redmaid-lane, near the Hermitage, which being a considerable way home, I believe about a mile and a half, gave me some suspicion that he did not go home at night. I took my man with me, and went to his house at six o'clock at night: I had some conversation with his wife; I enquired whether her husband had returned every night from his work at my house, and whether he was a good husband and neighbour; I found he had not been at home since the Thursday before (this was Wednesday), so he had not been at home for a week. I endeavoured to inform myself where he had lodged: the most I could learn of her was, that it was at a public-house somewhere near the Mansion house: I returned home again, and found that they had both continued in my house; then I went down Walbrook to see if I could learn where he had lodged. I called at the Bull's-head, Mr. 
               <persName id="t17631207-54-person510">
                  William 
                  Austin 
               <interp inst="t17631207-54-person510" type="surname" value="Austin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-54-person510" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-54-person510" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's; I enquired if one Johnson, a painter, did not lodge there; they told me, he did: I was shown into a room, and, after calling for something, desired the landlady to walk in. I represented myself as a buyer of Irish linnen, and asked if the painter was come home from his business? they told me he was not; I asked, if he had any Irish linnen fine enough for my purpose? she answered, that he had such a thing; I was not willing to hurry it, that I might find out the more, and said, if that is the case, I can wait a little while: says I, perhaps this Johnson, after all his stumping so much of his Irish linnen, has but a piece or two; she said she never saw but two pieces: seeing she spoke so openly, I said, the linnens are stole, he is a thief, and I the person robbed, and you having stolen goods in your possession, is a disagreeable circumstance on your account; but, if you will be candid, give me liberty to go over your house, and show me these linnens, and whatever else I can find, I shall be satisfied that you know nothing of this Johnson's robbing me; she desired me to follow her up stairs, and showed me these two pieces of cloth, (produced in court, and deposed to): I found, by the marks upon them, that one of the pieces was one of the two I first lost, and the other one of the last. I asked if that<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176312070045"></xptr> was the room he lodged in? she said, no, and went to the room he did lodge in; I turned up the bed, but could not discover any thing; there was a box in the room that belonged to the house; we opened it, and, in the back of the box, in a tick pillowbear, was another piece of the linnen, which was the other piece of the two I lost last, so that I had both the two last, and one of the former: I made enquiry of Mr. Austin, and his wife, how he had imposed upon them, in point of deception, in bringing the linnen there? they told me that he had supported it all the time, that he was painting a ship in the river; that the captain was a land-trader, and gave him this in part of payment, and told him he might dispose of them amongst his friends; they said, the cloth was exhibited the night before, in the public-room, for sale, and they thought that he was painting a ship, as he had never been home to dinner all the time he lived there. I went from there to Wood-street Compter, and got a constable to my house, and gave him charge of the prisoner: when this was done, I went to the public-house, to see if I could trace the fourth piece, but could not; they told me there was about eight or ten yards of a piece he had brought there; that was put out to be made into shirts for himself; this was what a draper had returned, being damaged, and we made no account of it. We questioned the prisoner about it at another time, and he confessed the taking of it. (Three pieces produced in court, and deposed to). When I told Mrs. Austin they were stolen, I said, as to the proof of it, here is a paper that has the number of the cloth; I told her, she would find the numbers wrote with a pen, in red-ink, on the cloth, correspond with the paper; there was Number 98 on the back of the first pieces I lost; on the second, 56 on one piece, and 73 on the other: when she went up stairs with me, she saw the Number on the piece; they were sent me from the factor in Ireland; the maker of the linnen stamps them at the end, to show there is no fraud in the inside; for, if there was, the man's name that stampt them, is liable to the damage. This is a new method established by the board at Ireland; (the maker of these linnens has so much confidence on the goodness of them, that he stamps them with his own name), the maker's name was stampt on the ends of the cloth; the prisoner owned, he had stole three pieces, but denied knowing of the fourth; and that he stole them at two different times.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-54-person511">
                  William 
                  Austin 
               <interp inst="t17631207-54-person511" type="surname" value="Austin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-54-person511" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-54-person511" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner lodged with me about ten days; he offered the linnen for sale in my house; he said, he had them on board a ship, and that the captain gave him them in lieu of wages. I always took him to be an honest man.</p>
               <p>The prisoner said nothing in his defence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-54-person512">
                  Joseph 
                  Gill 
               <interp inst="t17631207-54-person512" type="surname" value="Gill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-54-person512" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-54-person512" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner from June last; he always behaved very well with me, in the character of a journeyman; I never had the least reason to suspect his honesty.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17631207-54-verdict297" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631207-54-verdict297" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17631207-54-punish298" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631207-54-punish298" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-54-defend506 t17631207-54-punish298"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
