<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610916-57">
               <interp inst="t17610916-57" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-57" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-57" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610916"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-57" type="date" value="17610916"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610916-57-off297-c425" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-57-defend524 t17610916-57-off297 t17610916-57-verdict301"></join>
         
               <p>277. (M) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610916-57-defend524" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Grant 
                  <interp inst="t17610916-57-defend524" type="surname" value="Grant"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-57-defend524" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-57-defend524" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17610916-57-off297" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-57-off297" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-57-off297" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing one canvas bag, value one farthing, and 20 guineas in money, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17610916-57-victim526" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Law 
                        <interp inst="t17610916-57-victim526" type="surname" value="Law"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610916-57-victim526" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610916-57-victim526" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-57-off297 t17610916-57-victim526"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately, from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17610916-57-cd298" type="crimeDate">June 25</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-57-off297 t17610916-57-cd298"></join> ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-57-person527">
                  William 
                  Law 
               <interp inst="t17610916-57-person527" type="surname" value="Law"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-57-person527" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-57-person527" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17610916-57-viclabel299" type="occupation">linnen-draper</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-57-victim526 t17610916-57-viclabel299"></join>, and live in Piccadilly; I went to drink a pint of beer with my neighbour, Mr. Holloway, at <placeName id="t17610916-57-crimeloc300">the Cock and Harp in Germain-Street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-57-crimeloc300" type="placeName" value="the Cock and Harp in Germain-Street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-57-crimeloc300" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-57-off297 t17610916-57-crimeloc300"></join>; I said to him, I had a horse to dispose of. The prisoner was there; he joined company with us, and said he should want one, but thought mine would not go fast enough. I never saw the prisoner before. This was because I told him he was but four years old. I said, perhaps, you want a horse to go a hundred miles a day. I said I could procure one that would go a hundred miles in 12 hours. Then he offered to bet 100 l. he said he would lay the money down in 20 minutes. I went home, and fetched 20 guineas in a canvas-bag. I took out five guineas, and laid it on the table. He had no money to stake. Mr. Holloway was there; he said, put your money up. I did. Then we talked about weighing. The prisoner laid me half a gallon of beer that I was heavier than so much. We went to a tallow chandler's at next door, and I was weighed. I won the beer. Then we came back again, and talked of indifferent things, all for wagers, while drinking this gallon of beer. The company went away, and left him and I together. We staid 'till within a few minutes of eleven o'clock. When I was for going home, he said, I am going your way, I'll go and see you home. At going away, I asked what I had to pay. The landlord told me Mr. Holloway had left me three-halfpence to pay. I paid it. I had my bag and money then. When we got into Eagle-Street, it being a dark night, and Eagle-Street a dark one, I was for going through Darby-court; he gets hold of my left-arm, with his right, and said, Come, come, let us; o up here? We went on the street. When we got beyond the middle of the street, he gave his arm a hasty jark, and put his hand in my pocket, and twitched out my bag, with the money in it, and ran back again as fast as ever he could. I saw nobody in the street, and was to struck with terror, I did not offer to run. I went home and told my wife; she and I went to the alehouse where I had been drinking. The landlord said he never saw the man before, but one of his company he had seen before. This was the 25th of June; and on the Monday following Mr. Holloway and I went and got intelligence of the other man, who is a tallow-chandler in Bond-Street. I went to him, he told me who the prisoner was, and where he lived. Then I went to justice Wright, and got a warrant, and took him up. He said he knew nothing of my money, and that he was so drunk he did not know how he got home.</p>

               <p>On his cross-examination, he said, he could not tell who offered first to wager; that the prisoner urged him to lay the 100 l. divers times; that he did not at that time know the prisoner was a journeyman-baker, and not worth that money; that when he went out of the house, he himself was not drunk, nor quite sober: that he felt the prisoner twitch the money out of his pocket; that he was to troubled for the loss of his money that he did not get up out of his bed the next day till near twelve at noon.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-57-person528">
                  John 
                  Holloway 
               <interp inst="t17610916-57-person528" type="surname" value="Holloway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-57-person528" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-57-person528" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I and the prosecutor went in at the Cock and Harp to drink a pint of beer each. I staid only the drinking two pints, and went away in about half an hour. Part of the account he has given I heard while I was there. I left him three halfpence to pay.</p>
               <p>On his cross-examination, he said, he was there when the prosecutor brought in the money; that he saw him lay down five guineas of it on the table, and that be bid him put it in his pocket again; that the prisoner did insist on producing a hundred guineas in a quarter of an hour. The wager was about riding a house an hundred miles, which should ride it soonest. The prisoner to ride one horse, and he the other.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-57-person529">
                  John 
                  Ayres 
               <interp inst="t17610916-57-person529" type="surname" value="Ayres"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-57-person529" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-57-person529" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the landlord of the house; I was backwards and forwards in my business, I know nothing of the affair, only this; the prosecutor came to my house again that night, in five or six minutes after he and the prisoner went out together, and said, he was robbed of his money by that man that he went out with, and asked me if I knew him. I had never seen him before to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the place where he says he lost his money?</p>
               <p>Ayres. Yes, the ground that he went was not above 60 yards, I believe. He went away again, and in about a quarter of an hour brought his wife, and asked the same question.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-57-person530">
                  Samuel 
                  Lankfield 
               <interp inst="t17610916-57-person530" type="surname" value="Lankfield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-57-person530" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-57-person530" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner is a countryman of mine; he came into that alehouse, and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160065"></xptr> called for a tankard of beer. I had not seen him for 11 years, till that day. The prosecutor and last evidence came in. Words arose between the prisoner and prosecutor about riding for a sum of money. The prosecutor went home for his money. What money he brought I do not know. He put five guineas on the table, and Mr. Holloway took it up, and bid him put it in his pocket again. He was eager to lay, and offered it to any that would lay. Thus they continued talking of wagering till I went away at near ten o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner's character?</p>
               <p>Lankfield. I know nothing of his character.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I am quite innocent of the charge; the man possibly might lose his money; I never saw it, nor had it.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-57-person531">
                  William 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17610916-57-person531" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-57-person531" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-57-person531" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Tyburn-road, the prisoner lived with me about a year and half; I always took him to be a very honest, diligent man, one that behaved well to my customers.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-57-person532">
                  Edward 
                  Nichols 
               <interp inst="t17610916-57-person532" type="surname" value="Nichols"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-57-person532" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-57-person532" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a master-baker, and live at Islington; I have known the prisoner about four years; he lived with me about a year and quarter; he is a very honest fellow, was he clear I would take him now into my service. I would trust him with a hundred pounds; he has taken divers bills for me, and always gave me a true account.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-57-person533">
                  John 
                  Acton 
               <interp inst="t17610916-57-person533" type="surname" value="Acton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-57-person533" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-57-person533" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When the prisoner was taken up, his master White came to me. I being constable, I went with him. The prisoner's room door was open, and so was his box. There was not a single farthing to be found. I have known the prisoner about a year and half; I never knew him to be quarrelsome, or saw any ill of him, and have been out with him divers times; if I had ten thousand pounds, I would trust him with it this moment.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-57-person534">
                  Thomas 
                  Beard 
               <interp inst="t17610916-57-person534" type="surname" value="Beard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-57-person534" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-57-person534" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner nine or ten years; I was a journeyman baker, when I first knew him; I have kept company with him then, and since I was a master; he is a sober, creditable, honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-57-person535">
                  Daniel 
                  Bird 
               <interp inst="t17610916-57-person535" type="surname" value="Bird"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-57-person535" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-57-person535" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a master-baker, I have known him about eight years; I have been particularly acquainted with him, I never saw him in liquor in my life; I believe him to be a very honest man, and innocent of this affair; was he clear, I would take him as a journeyman now.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610916-57-verdict301" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-57-verdict301" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
