<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17631207-47">
               <interp inst="t17631207-47" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-47" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-47" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17631207"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-47" type="date" value="17631207"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17631207-47-off254-c340" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-47-defend436 t17631207-47-off254 t17631207-47-verdict257"></join>
         
               <p>(M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17631207-47-defend436" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Bodger 
                  <interp inst="t17631207-47-defend436" type="surname" value="Bodger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-47-defend436" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-47-defend436" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17631207-47-off254" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631207-47-off254" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-47-off254" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing two linnen shirts, value 2 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17631207-47-victim438" type="victimName">
                           Stephen 
                           Reader 
                        <interp inst="t17631207-47-victim438" type="surname" value="Reader"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17631207-47-victim438" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17631207-47-victim438" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , and 23 s. in money, numbered
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17631207-47-victim440" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Cooper 
                  <interp inst="t17631207-47-victim440" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-47-victim440" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-47-victim440" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17631207-47-cd255" type="crimeDate">Nov. 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-47-off254 t17631207-47-cd255"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-47-person441">
                  John 
                  Cooper 
               <interp inst="t17631207-47-person441" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-47-person441" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-47-person441" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17631207-47-crimeloc256">Sweet-Apple court, Bishopsgate-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17631207-47-crimeloc256" type="placeName" value="Sweet-Apple court, Bishopsgate-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17631207-47-crimeloc256" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-47-off254 t17631207-47-crimeloc256"></join>: I went out last Sunday sennight; my wife was going out to an acquaintances, where I was to call for her, I called in the evening for her; I was told she was gone home: I went home, and was much surprized to find the door open, and the house all in darkness: I called to the lodgers, to know if they had seen my wife: they said they had not. I went back again, where my wife was to have been, and found her. I told her the door was open; we went home directly, and found we had been robb'd of 23 s. and 2 d. out of a small leather trunk that was in a drawer, and locked; the shirts were lost out of the same room; we found the trunk was unlocked, and not forced; the key of the trunk was in a nest of drawers, so that we supposed it was somebody that knew it took the key, and unlocked the trunk, and took them; and on Monday the prisoner came into the yard where I was at work; he shook me by the hand, and said he was very sorry for my misfortune: he said it must be my lodgers, or somebody that knew me. I clapt my hand on his shoulder, and said, My friend, was you not nigh my house yesterday? he said no nigher than Hog-lane, which is about a quarter of a mile from my house. I had no suspicion of the prisoner. I went to Justice Fielding's, who advis'd me to advertise the shirts, as they were marked: on the next day (Tuesday) Mrs. Philips, a neighbour, told me that the prisoner had been by my house the day I was robb'd: when she saw him, she thought that he was disappointed of his usual house, as my wife and I were out: upon this, suspicion arose, I pursued him to Tottenham, searched him, and found one of the shirts upon him. I said this is one of the shirts; he denied it. I bid him turn his money out of his pocket; there was a Queen Ann's silver Three-pence, and a George the Second's Two-pence, wrapped up in a piece of paper, which was part of the money stole out of the trunk, and belonged to my child, and also 7 s. I said, what think you of this? He said, Master Cooper, that money is yours, and I am the man that robb'd you. He confess'd the taking of them before the Justice; the shirt he had on was marked with S. R. on the hip.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Cooper. I lock'd my door when I went out to a neighbour's, on Sunday evening. I staid there till my husband called; when I locked the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176312070038"></xptr> door, the money and shirts were safe. (The shirts produced in court, and deposed to by Reader.)</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I met a woman on Tuesday, in Brown's lane, I bought a shirt and a pair of stockings of her, from thence I went to Tottenham; I call'd in at a public house for a pint of beer, there I met with the prosecutor; he call'd me into another room, and said he was informed I was the man that robb'd him; I told him I was not; the shirt he swore to, but would not to the stockings; they took me to the justice, and I was committed to Clerkenwell.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-47-person442">
                  Joshua 
                  Dolphin 
               <interp inst="t17631207-47-person442" type="surname" value="Dolphin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-47-person442" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-47-person442" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner has worked for me on and of, 20 months; I thought myself very happy in having such a man to do my business; his general character is that of a very honest sober man; he is as hard a working fellow as ever I knew. I never heard him swear an oath.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-47-person443">
                  William 
                  Barnard 
               <interp inst="t17631207-47-person443" type="surname" value="Barnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-47-person443" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-47-person443" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have employed the prisoner; I would trust him with untold gold; I never had any suspicion of him, and would employ him again, if he was clear of this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-47-person444">
                  Jonathan 
                  Turner 
               <interp inst="t17631207-47-person444" type="surname" value="Turner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-47-person444" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-47-person444" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a collar-maker, I have known the prisoner 20 months. I never heard any thing amiss of him.</p>
               <p>They were all questioned as to the character of the prosecutor, and said they knew nothing but that he was an honest man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17631207-47-verdict257" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631207-47-verdict257" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17631207-47-punish258" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631207-47-punish258" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-47-defend436 t17631207-47-punish258"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
