<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640912-13">
               <interp inst="t17640912-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-13" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640912"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-13" type="date" value="17640912"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640912-13-off68-c90" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-13-defend114 t17640912-13-off68 t17640912-13-verdict70"></join>
         
               <p>489. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17640912-13-defend114" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Derbin 
                  <interp inst="t17640912-13-defend114" type="surname" value="Derbin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-13-defend114" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-13-defend114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17640912-13-off68" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-13-off68" type="offenceCategory" value="miscellaneous"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-13-off68" type="offenceSubcategory" value="returnFromTransportation"></interp>
               returning from transportation before the expiration of his time
            </rs>, <rs id="t17640912-13-cd69" type="crimeDate">June 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-13-off68 t17640912-13-cd69"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176409120009"></xptr>The, record of his conviction was read, wherein it appeared, that he was tried on the eighth of December 1762, at the Old Bailey, for stealing a large quantity of wearing apparel and other things, the property of 
               <persName id="t17640912-13-person115">
                  William 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17640912-13-person115" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-13-person115" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-13-person115" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in Bell-Court, near Abchurch Lane; found guilty, and received sentence of transportation for seven years.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is the prosecutor?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-13-person116">
                  William 
                  Godfrey 
               <interp inst="t17640912-13-person116" type="surname" value="Godfrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-13-person116" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-13-person116" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . He is not here.</p>
               <p>Q. Then who proves the prisoner to be the identical person mentioned in this Record?</p>
               <p>Godfrey. Mr. Gurney, the Short Hand writer, must remember the prisoner being tried here.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-13-person117">
                  Thomas 
                  Gurney 
               <interp inst="t17640912-13-person117" type="surname" value="Gurney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-13-person117" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-13-person117" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My Lord, I am very sorry the prosecutor is not here; I had no knowledge of my being called upon till Mr. Godfrey mentioned my name. Considering the place I am in here, I should be glad was I never to be call'd upon to give evidence on such an affair as this.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember the prisoner being tried here before?</p>
               <p>Gurney. I am not prepared with my book; but I well remember he was tried in this place in December sessions 1762. It was for stealing some goods in a dwelling house in or near Abchurch Lane; the prosecutor's name I cannot recollect. I remember it was on a Sabbath day, about the time people were at church. There was an evidence mentioned seeing the prisoner loitering about the place about that time. He was found guilty, and received sentence to be transported for seven years.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you recollect him again, from once seeing him?</p>
               <p>Gurney. I have seen him more than once.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I never had any acquaintance with Mr. Gurney.</p>
               <p>Gurney. That is true, I never was acquainted with him, but I have seen him four times before now.</p>
               <p>Q. Where?</p>
               <p>Gurney. I saw him tried in this court three several times, and once I stood over him while he was searched for stealing a watch from a near neighbour of mine, near Christ-church, Surry, which was found upon him, and for which he was tried at Croydon; upon which account he severely threatened to do for me where-ever he met with me; which, if he had not, I should have petitioned the court to have been excused giving evidence on his trial. I once met him after that on Snow Hill, and made no doubt by his eye that he knew me. I was very sorry when I heard he was returned from transportation.</p>
               <p>Godfrey. I am one of my Lord Mayor's houshold; my business here is to keep the bench, to see that nobody incommodes the worthy Aldermen. I went out of the Mansion house on the 19th of June. I happened to turn my head, and saw the prisoner; he turned and ran down Walbrook; I pursued him; I saw he had a bag full of things: I said, Derbin, had I seen you without any thing about you. I should have taken no notice of you; but I fear you are got to your old trade again, and I think it my duty to stop you; I brought him and his bag to the Mansion-house, and delivered the bag to the care of Mr. White the Marshal's man, and he searched it. There was a watch and some clothes in it. I remember seeing him tried here when he was cast for transportation.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-13-person118">
                  William 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17640912-13-person118" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-13-person118" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-13-person118" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Godfrey charged me with the prisoner. I searched him in the Mansion-house; there was in his bag a mettle watch with a tortoise shell case, two gold lac'd hats, and a plain one; two coats, a pair of breeches, and a jacket. Twelve pick-lock keys, a pair of pumps, and a gimblet, were in his coat pocket; the two lac'd hats, two coats, and watch, are own'd, and bills found here in order to prosecute him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I am the man that was cast for transportation: the question is, Whether or no I lose my freedom of being a free subject of either this kingdom, or any of his Majesty's plantations. In purchasing my freedom, I think I have a right to be here; my friends paid my passage; here is the copy of the paper they granted me. He delivers it in, it is read to this purport.</p>
               <p>"On Board the Neptune, Captain 
               <persName id="t17640912-13-person119">
                  Somervell
               <interp inst="t17640912-13-person119" type="given" value="Somervell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-13-person119" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ,</p>
               <p>"June 17th, 1763. 
               <persName id="t17640912-13-person120">
                  Joseph 
                  Derbin 
               <interp inst="t17640912-13-person120" type="surname" value="Derbin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-13-person120" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-13-person120" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is a freeman.</p>
               <p>"Any Magistrate may grant him a</p>
               <p>"pass by destroying this. Witness my hand,</p>
               <p>"
               <persName id="t17640912-13-person121">
                  David 
                  Ross 
               <interp inst="t17640912-13-person121" type="surname" value="Ross"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-13-person121" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-13-person121" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ."</p>
               <p>Dr. 
               <persName id="t17640912-13-person122">
                  David 
                  Ross 
               <interp inst="t17640912-13-person122" type="surname" value="Ross"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-13-person122" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-13-person122" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is the person the people are consigned to; he lives at a place called Bladensburg in Maryland: and Colonel 
               <persName id="t17640912-13-person123">
                  William 
                  Harrison 
               <interp inst="t17640912-13-person123" type="surname" value="Harrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-13-person123" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-13-person123" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             granted me a pass; he is a Justice of the peace for Charles county.</p>
               <p>Court. You can't be so weak as to imagine they have power to reverse the sentence you received here.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640912-13-verdict70" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-13-verdict70" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17640912-13-punish71" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-13-punish71" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-13-defend114 t17640912-13-punish71"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176409120010"></xptr>See him tried No. 93. in Sir Matthew Blackision's mayoralty, and No. 159. in Sir 
               <persName id="t17640912-13-person124">
                  Samuel 
                  Fludyer 
               <interp inst="t17640912-13-person124" type="surname" value="Fludyer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-13-person124" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-13-person124" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's. He was convicted and branded at Croydon, August 3, 1761. and tried by four prosecutors on four several indictments in Mr. Alderman Beckford's mayoralty; for which see No. 5. &amp;c. in that mayoralty.</p>
            </div1>
