<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640728-53">
               <interp inst="t17640728-53" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640728-53" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640728-53" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640728"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640728-53" type="date" value="17640728"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640728-53-off271-c398" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640728-53-defend514 t17640728-53-off271 t17640728-53-verdict273"></join>
         
               <p>454. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17640728-53-defend514" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Muckle 
                  <interp inst="t17640728-53-defend514" type="surname" value="Muckle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-53-defend514" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-53-defend514" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17640728-53-off271" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640728-53-off271" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-53-off271" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               feloniously forging the name of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640728-53-victim516" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Edwards 
                        <interp inst="t17640728-53-victim516" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640728-53-victim516" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640728-53-victim516" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640728-53-off271 t17640728-53-victim516"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , to a promissary note, for the payment of 10 l. to himself and 
                     <persName id="t17640728-53-person517">
                        Abraham 
                        Wood 
                     <interp inst="t17640728-53-person517" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640728-53-person517" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640728-53-person517" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  ; and for publishing the same, well knowing it was falsly made
            </rs>, <rs id="t17640728-53-cd272" type="crimeDate">July 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640728-53-off271 t17640728-53-cd272"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640728-53-person518">
                  William 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17640728-53-person518" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-53-person518" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-53-person518" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 18th of this instant, there was an advertisement in the paper, that if a person could advance 40 l. he might get a hundred a year by it; I went to the public house, in Long-acre, according to it, and was introduced into a room, to the prisoner and one Wood: they told me, the thing would bring in an hundred a year, as they advertised: I said, I had a friend that could advance the money; upon which, the prisoner drew up a writing, and desired me to set my name to it, at the bottom of the paper; I put my name to it, and they told me, if my friend did not approve of it, I might have it again: then they went with me, from the Golden-head, to Holborn, and my friend was not at home: they went back again; on the Saturday following, they brought<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176407280034"></xptr> a man that I never saw in my life; I met them at the end of Warwick-court, Holborn: said they, Don't you know this man? I said, no: said they, we have a note of 10 l. against you, and if you do not pay it, he has power to arrest you, and shewed me the note. I said, I did not owe any body 10 s. and that I never signed a note; I begged they would go into some public-house; we went into the Griffin: Muckle gave me the note to look at; I saw my name, and said, let my friend look at it; they said he should not, and were for pulling me out of the house, when the landlord, his servant, and others, came to my assistance; I delivered the note to a gentleman, and as he was reading it, the prisoner snatched it out of his hand, and tore it in two pieces: I laid hold of the prisoner, and the other two got off as fast as they could. I got the prisoner into a coach, and carried him before Sir 
               <persName id="t17640728-53-person519">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17640728-53-person519" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-53-person519" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-53-person519" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640728-53-person520">
                  John 
                  Mountstevens 
               <interp inst="t17640728-53-person520" type="surname" value="Mountstevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-53-person520" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-53-person520" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I happened accidentally to be there when this outcry was; the prosecutor called out Thieves and Robbers, and desired help: I was shewed a note; the prosecutor said they demanded 10 l. for that note. He said, he had been with them in Long-acre, according to an advertisement, and signed something of a memorandum or agreement, but no promissory note, nor never undertook to pay the least sum whatever. (The note produced, and read to this purport:</p>
               <p>"I promise to pay to 
               <persName id="t17640728-53-person521">
                  Abraham 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17640728-53-person521" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-53-person521" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-53-person521" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and</p>
               <p>"
               <persName id="t17640728-53-person522">
                  Thomas 
                  Muckle 
               <interp inst="t17640728-53-person522" type="surname" value="Muckle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-53-person522" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-53-person522" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Ten Pounds, upon demand,</p>
               <p>"for value received, this 18th day of July, 1764.</p>
               <p>"
               <persName id="t17640728-53-person523">
                  William 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17640728-53-person523" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-53-person523" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-53-person523" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .")</p>
               <p>The prisoner snatched the note out of my hand, and said I had no business with it, and immediately tore it, and put it into his pocket, which made me suspect there was something bad, and the other two made off as soon as he was laid hold of. I thought proper he should give an account of himself, and we carried him to Sir 
               <persName id="t17640728-53-person524">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17640728-53-person524" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-53-person524" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-53-person524" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's: previous to our going to Sir John, I persuaded the prisoner to let me have part of this note; I got the better half, and at Sir John's we got the other part; but upon putting them together, it was still defective: we searched his pocket by order of Sir John, for the supposed agreement which the prosecutor had mentioned, I found the remaining part, and made it compleat: I stuck them together, on a blank paper, and the prisoner confessed the body of this note to be his own hand writing, and the name, 
               <persName id="t17640728-53-person525">
                  Thomas 
                  Muckle 
               <interp inst="t17640728-53-person525" type="surname" value="Muckle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-53-person525" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-53-person525" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , indorsed to it, to be his hand writing; but withal, said, that at the time this note was signed, Edwards knew the contents of it. Upon searching his pocket, we found a similar paper, intended for another person (Producing it).</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640728-53-person526">
                  Thomas 
                  Keys 
               <interp inst="t17640728-53-person526" type="surname" value="Keys"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-53-person526" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-53-person526" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the public-house in Long-acre, where this thing was done. When I carried them up some brandy and water, the prisoner was writing on a sheet of paper: I looked upon it to be an agreement between them in partnership; he read it, and handed it to Edwards, and he wrote his name under it; I cannot recollect a word of it, After that, the prisoner delivered it to me to lay by; I did, and in the evening he asked for it, and I delivered it to him.</p>
               <p>The prisoner said nothing in his defence.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640728-53-verdict273" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640728-53-verdict273" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
