<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17611209-19">
               <interp inst="t17611209-19" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611209-19" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611209-19" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17611209"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611209-19" type="date" value="17611209"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17611209-19-off113-c157" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-19-defend190 t17611209-19-off113 t17611209-19-verdict115"></join>
         
               <p>20. (M) 
               
                  <persName id="t17611209-19-defend190" type="defendantName">
                     Daniel 
                     Looney 
                  <interp inst="t17611209-19-defend190" type="surname" value="Looney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-defend190" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-defend190" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17611209-19-deflabel112" type="occupation">Mariner</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-19-defend190 t17611209-19-deflabel112"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17611209-19-off113" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-off113" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-off113" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               the wilful murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17611209-19-victim192" type="victimName">
                           Joseph 
                           Shanks 
                        <interp inst="t17611209-19-victim192" type="surname" value="Shanks"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17611209-19-victim192" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17611209-19-victim192" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-19-off113 t17611209-19-victim192"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , by shooting him with a gun charged with leaden bullets
            </rs>: He stood likewise charged on the coroner's inquest for the said murder, <rs id="t17611209-19-cd114" type="crimeDate">Nov. 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-19-off113 t17611209-19-cd114"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-19-person193">
                  Robert 
                  Shanks 
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person193" type="surname" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person193" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person193" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am son to the deceased; in the year 1752, about the month of June or July my mother died; and very unfortunately, just after, my father going down to see the ship he late commanded, he fell in with a woman reckoned to be a common woman, the wife of the prisoner at the bar. They cohabited together for some time; and the prisoner being out of business, my father went and bought a sloop, and gave the command of her to him; and my father used to go to and fro to this woman, who lived in a mean low way; and his own character being excessively good, he could not bear to be told from time to time what a shame it was to go to this vile woman. I represented to him what I had heard upon the occasion; he seemed sometimes to give heed to what I said, and I did all in my power in order to bring him to reason.</p>
               <p>Court. This may not be material on the present occasion: What do you know concerning the murder?</p>
               <p>Shanks. In regard to that, it was on Saturday the 7th of Nov. I was at the Portugal coffee-house at the Royal Exchange, where a servant of my Brother-in-law came to me, and told me my father was shot.</p>
               <p>Q. Is that servant here?</p>
               <p>Shanks. It was a maid servant; she is not here. She desired I would immediately come down to the house to see him (I had not been there for some time).</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he live?</p>
               <p>Shanks. He lived at his own house, Worcester-street, Old Gravel Lane. I made the best of my way to my brother-in-law's, who lives near Bell-Dock. Wapping?</p>
               <p>Q. What is his name?</p>
               <p>Shanks. His name is 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person194">
                  William 
                  Honeychurch 
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person194" type="surname" value="Honeychurch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person194" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person194" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; and he and I went together to my father's house, where there were a great number of people assembled.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did the prisoner's wife live?</p>
               <p>Shanks. She lived with my father at that time, as well as the prisoner; they all lived together.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had they lived so?</p>
               <p>Shanks. Ever since July 1752, not always in one house, but they always lived together when the prisoner was from sea. I went up stairs, where I saw my father lying in bed: I saw him alive, but senseless. I invoked him several times to speak to me, in order to see whether he knew me or not; he did not know me, he was quite senseless.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the wound?</p>
               <p>Shanks. I saw no wound: I could not bear to see it, in about three or four minutes time after he expired.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you see there?</p>
               <p>Shanks. The prisoner's wife stood at the foot of the bed, very much intoxicated with liquor?</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was this?</p>
               <p>Shanks. I believe it was between eight and nine in the evening.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the prisoner at that time?</p>
               <p>Shanks. He was at the next house, a public house. I did not see him. As soon as my father was dead, I went to a friend of mine, who lived hard by, to be informed where I should find a constable; and he and I went together, and found one. We came to this public house, where the prisoner was sitting in a back room, it was the sign of the shepherd and shepherdess. Somebody had him then in custody, but who I know not. I charged that same officer with him; and afterwards I charged that same officer with his wife; they were carried before justice Pell in Wellclose-square.</p>
               <p>Q. What happened when you first seized the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Shanks. Nothing at all; I could not bear to see him. The justice examined him relative to the murder: He then acknowleged the fact; I have his very words, I took them down in writing, upon his re-examination.</p>
               <p>Q. First of all, tell by your memory what he said on his first examination.</p>
               <p>Shanks. He then did acknowlege he had fired a gun, and shot the captain, but that he meant him no ill will. After this, on the re-examination on the Monday following, the 9th, at noon -</p>
               <p>Court. You may read what you have wrote.</p>
               <p>Shanks. He there declared before justice Pell,</p>
               <p>"that he heard the deceased d - n him, and then he</p>
               <p>"asked him why he d - d him: The prisoner then</p>
               <p>"went into the kitchen to the deceased; and his</p>
               <p>"wife went to the street-door, where abundance of</p>
               <p>"people were gathered; and some little time after</p>
               <p>"the deceased came into the passage or entry, and</p>
               <p>"said, D - n you, Looney, where are you? Upon</p>
               <p>"which the prisoner took up a piece, and said</p>
               <p>"aloud, I will shoot any one that comes in to molest</p>
               <p>"me; when the deceased rushed in upon him, and</p>
               <p>"received the fire in his body. He then declared,</p>
               <p>"that the gun was in its case, and that he did not</p>
               <p>"know that it was loaded."</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176112090014"></xptr>Q. Did he say who fired the piece?</p>
               <p>Shanks. No, he did not. I can say nothing more relative to the fact. In order to be convinced of that of the piece being in the case, Mr. Pell sent for it, and asked the prisoner whether that was the case belonging to the gun: He declared it was; upon which Mr. Pell looked at the end of the case, to see if there was any hole that the powder had gone through, and there was no such hole.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you look at it?</p>

               <p>Shanks. I did; there was no hole at all, nor mark of any powder or shot; I examined it all over.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the case made of?</p>
               <p>Shanks. It was made of a kind of listing, such as is usual for cases; it was quite whole, and seemed to be a new one.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had this accident happened before you got there?</p>
               <p>Shanks. I was told my father was shot about a quarter before or a quarter after six o'clock, and it was between eight or nine when I saw the gun.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you say whether that lock had been fired off?</p>
               <p>Shanks. I doubt not but that had been put to and fro several times by people in the intervals.</p>
               <p>Q. Whose gun was it?</p>
               <p>Shanks. I know very well that it belonged to my father; it was a very long gun, it was given him by a gentleman deceased.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know where it used to be put in that house?</p>
               <p>Shanks. I never was in that house before, since my father lived in it; I would have brought it here, but, my father having left all his effects to that woman, I could not obtain it.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen the will?</p>
               <p>Shanks. I have the copy of it here.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-19-person195">
                  Henry 
                  Hemer 
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person195" type="surname" value="Hemer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person195" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person195" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I served part of my time to Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person196">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person196" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person196" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the deceased. I was with him at half an hour after five o'clock in the afternoon that day. I saw him and the prisoner in the kitchen together at Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person197">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person197" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person197" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's house. When I first went in, Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person198">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person198" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person198" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and the prisoner's wife were in the parlour together. I had served him three years and a half before I went on board a man of war. I had been out; and, coming home, there was some money due from the Bluecoat Hospital, where I had my education, and I desired the captain to go and get that money, and give me a few cloaths. He said he would. While I was talking to him, Mrs. Looney went backwards into the kitchen; then I heard some words pass between the prisoner and she.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Hemer. I did. I heard him say to her, It is very hard he could not have a halfpeny roll and butter for his breakfast, when he brought so much money home, Mrs. Looney came to the parlour, and told Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person199">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person199" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person199" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             what he had said. Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person200">
                  Shank
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person200" type="given" value="Shank"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person200" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             called, and said, Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person201">
                  Looney
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person201" type="given" value="Looney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person201" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , it is d - d hard I cannot live in peace and quietness in my own house. The prisoner was then in the kitchen, but he might hear him very well. Mrs. Looney presently went out of the parlour into the kitchen again. As soon as she got there, there were high words between his wife and he, and she called out to Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person202">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person202" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person202" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to come to her assistance. Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person203">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person203" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person203" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had not long been there before he called me. Then there were high words between the three. The prisoner had a sugar hatchet in his hand, it was a small one, with a hammer on one side, and the hatchet on the other; he made two or three blows at his wife with it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he strike her with it?</p>
               <p>Hemer. He did, but not to fetch any blood, as I saw; it was upon her shoulder. He then threw that out of his hand, and went backwards into a little place, and fetched a small cleaver; he made a blow at her with that, and cut her on the left side of the head; after that, Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person204">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person204" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person204" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             went to push him out of the way, and he shoved Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person205">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person205" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person205" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             against the partition.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person206">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person206" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person206" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             only shove him?</p>
               <p>Hemer. I cannot say whether he struck or shoved him; I believe he went to separate them, that the prisoner should not do any more mischief. Then I went between him and the prisoner, and shoved the prisoner away with my stick. Then Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person207">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person207" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person207" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and the prisoner's wife went into the parlour again.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember what words were said?</p>
               <p>Hemer. They were at high words, but what words I know not; the prisoner mentioned the words whore and rogue a great many times. Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person208">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person208" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person208" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said, he would not be troubled with such people, for he would turn them both out of the house. With great persuasion the prisoner went out at the door, and said some reproachful words, and d - d them for whore and rogue. I saw no more of it. Then I settled the affair with Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person209">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person209" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person209" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and went home: I went from thence between five and six o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see a gun there?</p>
               <p>Hemer. No, I did not then: I did after the murder.</p>
               <p>Q. How soon did you see Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person210">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person210" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person210" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             after he was wounded?</p>
               <p>Hemer. I saw him about ten minutes after. I came to the house again, upon the report of his being wounded, about seven o'clock. I saw him lie on his back on his bed in the chamber; I spoke to him, he made no answer.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were the prisoner and his wife?</p>
               <p>Hemer. She was in the chamber at the time, and I was told that the prisoner was in custody.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176112090015"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-19-person211">
                  Alexander 
                  Crow 
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person211" type="surname" value="Crow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person211" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person211" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 7th of November last, about three quarters or half an hour after six o'clock, I was in a public house the next door to captain Shanks's. I was drinking a pot of beer. Mr. Shanks, the deceased, came in, and called Mrs. Bonherrin, the landlady, to come and see what distraction there was at his house. She went out with him, and I and two other young men followed them out to the door; that was 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person212">
                  John 
                  Newland 
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person212" type="surname" value="Newland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person212" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person212" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person213">
                  John 
                  Fergerson 
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person213" type="surname" value="Fergerson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person213" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person213" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . We stood on the steps of Mr. Bonherrin's door; I listened to hear what was going on. I heard a man in Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person214">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person214" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person214" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's house call out and say, keep out of the house, or the first man or woman that comes in I'll shoot them. I don't know whether it was we will, or I will, shoot them. At that time Mr. Shanks was in the street along with the woman, close by his own door. Then we ran down the steps, and before we got down the musket was fired off. Mr. Shanks had then got within his own door; Newland ran into the captain's house directly. There was a woman in the entry. I ran in and shoved her in before me, and Fergerson followed me. When we came there Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person215">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person215" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person215" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was lying on his right side, with his head against the skreen, and the prisoner was walking about in the same room; and I saw a gun lying on the floor in the room, but I can't recollect what part of the room.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any case upon the gun?</p>
               <p>Crow. I am certain there was not a case on it. When I went in Mrs. Looney said, there was only powder in the musket; he is not shot, he is only frightened. She was raising his side up with a napkin, I thought he was not shot at first; for I saw no blood. He looked her up in the face, and said, You wicked woman, you vile woman, it is through you this has happened.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you recollect, when you first went into the room, who was there?</p>
               <p>Crow. There was only the prisoner, besides us that went in.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after you got in before you saw Mrs. Looney?</p>
               <p>Crow. I saw her soon after I got in; the house was full presently. There was one Mrs. Lane came in; she said, for God's sake, let us lift him up into a chair. Then the prisoner desired we would go with him to a Justice of the peace to deliver himself up. Then Newland, I, and another man, went with him to Justice Pell's; he was not at home. Then we went to Justice Scott's; he was out of the way. Then we brought the prisoner to Mr. Bonherrin's, and he sent me for a warrant to take charge of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you seen the wound before you went out?</p>
               <p>Crow. I had; it was on the left side, a very large one. I believe the deceased was in a night-gown. The wound on his body was bigger a great deal than a musket-ball could have made it; I could put two or three fingers in it; it was bleeding, and his shirt was full of blood.</p>
               <p>Q. What did it appear to have been done with?</p>
               <p>Crow. It appeared to have been done with fire arms?</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the prisoner say any thing?</p>
               <p>Crow. I did; he said he did not know how it happened; if he had killed the man he was very sorry for it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear him say who fired the gun.</p>
               <p>Crow. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the gun in his hand?</p>
               <p>Crow. No, I did not; that was on the floor when I first saw it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-19-person216">
                  John 
                  Newland 
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person216" type="surname" value="Newland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person216" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person216" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was called; but did not appear.</p>
               <p>Mr. Shanks. He was arrested, and put into confinement in the Borough. I made application to the court last night for instructions how to get him here. Then I sent to know if he was come out of confinement. I had word brought, that he was out; but they could give no account where he was gone.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-19-person217">
                  John 
                  Fergerson 
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person217" type="surname" value="Fergerson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person217" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person217" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 7th of November I was come from work, and was sitting at my lodgings at Mr. Bonherrin's; I heard a noise in the street. I went out upon the head of the stairs, and heard Mr. Looney say, he would shoot the first person that entered the door. I went with Newland and Crow.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did that voice come from?</p>
               <p>Fergerson. From out of Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person218">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person218" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person218" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's house, which was next door to the alehouse. I saw Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person219">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person219" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person219" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in the street before his own door, and other people in the street. I turned into the Alehouse again, till I heard the report of the gun.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you been in the alehouse before you heard the gun?</p>
               <p>Fergerson. I had not been in a quarter of an hour; the report came from captain Shank's. Then I went there, and saw him lying on his side, just by the passage in the kitchen, on the floor; and I lent a hand to help him into a chair. I was the third person who entered the house.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you see in the kitchen?</p>
               <p>Fergerson. I saw the prisoner walking about there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see a gun there?</p>
               <p>Fergerson. I did; it stood upon one end against a chest of drawers.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you been in the kitchen before you saw the gun?</p>
               <p>Fergerson. About a minute or half a minute.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it in a case?</p>
               <p>Fergerson. No, it was not; I am sure of that. I heard Mr. Shanks say something, but cannot tell what it was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the prisoner say any thing?</p>
               <p>Fergerson. No, I did not hear him say any thing.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176112090016"></xptr> I believe it was half a minute before we could get Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person220">
                  Shank
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person220" type="given" value="Shank"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person220" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's cloaths off, to see where the wound was. I saw it; it was a large wound on his side; a fresh wound; it appoared to be made with a gun. After that I returned back to the alehouse, and left Looney in Mr. Shank's house.</p>
               <p>Q. to Crow. When you came into the room, did you hear Newland say any thing to the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Crow. He was talking to him; but what about I cannot tell. I heard the prisoner say, it was about a roll and butter that they had quarreled that morning. This he told to Newland. I felt about the prisoner to see if he had any more fire-arms about him. I heard him say, he had brought a great deal of money home for five or six years, and it was very hard he could not get a roll and butter.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear him tell Newland how the accident happened?</p>
               <p>Crow. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. to Fergerson. Did you hear the prisoner say any thing to Newland?</p>
               <p>Fergerson. No; nor did I hear Newland say any thing to him,</p>
               <p>Mary Lane. On the 7th of November, I was going by Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person221">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person221" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person221" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's door, just at candle-light. I heard a great noise; people said Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person222">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person222" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person222" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was shot.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the report of the gun?</p>
               <p>M. Lane. No, I did not. I went in and saw Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person223">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person223" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person223" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             lie on the floor dying. A doctor was sent for to dress his wound, and they went to get him to bed. Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person224">
                  Looney
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person224" type="given" value="Looney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person224" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was at that time walking about backwards and forwards in the room.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see a gun there?</p>
               <p>M. Lane. I did; it was lying on the floor.</p>
               <p>Q. Had it a case upon it?</p>
               <p>M. Lane. I cannot tell whether it had or not. I was affrighted.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the prisoner say any thing?</p>
               <p>M. Lane. He said it was very hard he had worked so long for her, and could not have a peny or three halfpence to buy him a roll and butter.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the prisoner say how the accident happened, or what provocation was given him?</p>

               <p>M. Lane. No, I did not; only about the roll and butter.</p>
               <p>Q. After they had got the deceased up stairs, what happened then?</p>
               <p>M. Lane. Then the doctor dressed his wound; some body asked him if it was proper to give him a little wine. I went down and mull'd him some; and I and another woman held his head up and gave it him. Then he lay down. I asked him if I could speak. He said, yes. I asked him, if I should send for his son? He said, no. Then he said, a poor innocent man killed; but never mentioned who killed him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you by when he died?</p>
               <p>M. Lane. I was; that was about an hour and half after this.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>M. Lane. I live in the next street to that where the captain did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-19-person225">
                  Ann 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person225" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person225" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person225" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I happened to be down that way that night, and heard a piece go off. I went into the deceased's house, and saw him lying on the floor.</p>
               <p>Q. to Crow. Is this the woman that you pushed into the house before you?</p>
               <p>Crow. It is.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the first thing you saw?</p>
               <p>A King. The deceased lying on the floor; and I saw the prisoner walking up and down the kitchen.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see a gun?</p>
               <p>A. King. No, I did not all the time I was there. I heard the deceased say, I am wounded, I am an innocent man. This was as he lay on the ground in the kitchen; and Mr. Looney made answer. flesh and blood was not able to bear it, for she would not allow me so much as a peny to buy me a roll and butter.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did he say that to?</p>
               <p>A. King. He said that to Mrs. Looney. A little while after the deceased said, I am an innocent man.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear Newland speak to the prisoner?</p>
               <p>A. King. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the prisoner say any thing else?</p>
               <p>A. King. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-19-person226">
                  Ann 
                  Bonberrin 
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person226" type="surname" value="Bonberrin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person226" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person226" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live next door to Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person227">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person227" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person227" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's. I was in the street at this time, and heard the report of a gun.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know who fired it?</p>
               <p>A. Bouberrin. No, I do not; it was fired in Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person228">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person228" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person228" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's house; then I went home.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person229">
                  Looney
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person229" type="given" value="Looney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person229" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             afterwards?</p>
               <p>A. Bonberrin. I did, that night.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear him say any thing?</p>
               <p>A. Bonberrin. He said nothing in my hearing. I saw him likewise on the Monday after; but was not in the room with him; neither did I hear him say any thing, as I remember.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-19-person230">
                  Mary 
                  Embley 
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person230" type="surname" value="Embley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person230" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person230" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live facing Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person231">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person231" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person231" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's house. I was coming out at my own door, and heard a piece go off; but who let it off I cannot say. It frighted me very much. I can't say whether it was let off in the house or out of the house; and who was there I cannot say. I was wounded by it, it took away my senses; the shot went into my shoe, and touched the edge of my toe. There was a little bit of something in my shoe; I took it out and threw it away; I don't know what it was.</p>
               <p>Q. How big was it?</p>
               <p>M. Embley. It was about as big as the head of a pin, rather square than round.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176112090017"></xptr>Q. Was Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person232">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person232" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person232" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's door open or shut at that time?</p>
               <p>M. Embley. I cannot say. I was just come out at my own door when the piece went off.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-19-person233">
                  John 
                  Tear 
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person233" type="surname" value="Tear"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person233" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Saturday, November the seventh, as I was going to my house in Ratcliff-highway, I met a gentleman who asked me if I heard Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person234">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person234" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person234" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was shot. I being intimate with his sons, I went to see if any of them were there. I had another gentleman along with me; I went up stairs. The doctor said, have you a mind to see the wound? He turned the body round, and shewed me the wounds; there was a ragged wound on his left side, into which he put his hand, almost all of it; it seemed as if it had been torn by pieces of lead; it went in on the left side and out on the right, so that there was a wound quite through the body. After that I went down stairs, and heard the woman in the house make a very great noise. The dog shall be hang'd, the dog shall be hang'd; meaning the prisoner at the bar. We went out of the house, and into the Shepherd and Shepherdess. I went up to the prisoner, and asked him, how he could be guilty of so rash an action as to murder Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person235">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person235" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person235" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>Tear. This was about nine or ten o'clock. He asked a gentleman that was by, if Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person236">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person236" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person236" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was dead or not. The gentleman said, he was dead. The prisoner said he was sorry for it; for he had been the death of an innocent man. He walked about a little. Soon after he was carried to Mr. Pell; where he acknowledged, that he had been the death of an innocent man, and that he was sorry for it; that it was all through that vile woman, pointing to his wife with his finger; for she has been the whole instigation of it Mr. Pell asked him, I think, who the house belonged to, relating to him and Mr. Shanks. He said he knew nothing of the house belonging to him; and said he thought he paid the ground-rent; but was not sure. He said, the first falling out was about a roll; he said, It was very hard he had worked so many voyages, and she would not allow him a roll for his breakfast. I think he twice said before Mr. Pell, that he shot him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-19-person237">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Osmond 
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person237" type="surname" value="Osmond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person237" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person237" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard the deceased say, God's curse light upon him; for he shot me with such vengeance just as if I had been a dog.</p>
               <p>Q. When did Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person238">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person238" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person238" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             say that?</p>
               <p>E. Osmond. That was after he was in bed.</p>
               <p>Q. How was that introduced?</p>
               <p>E. Osmond. No body spoke to him; he was talking this to himself as he lay.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think he was in his senses at that time?</p>
               <p>E. Osmond. I dare say he was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he mention any body's name?</p>
               <p>E. Osmond. No, he did not, or who did it; he said I am an innocent man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-19-person239">
                  Mary 
                  Uxtaby 
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person239" type="surname" value="Uxtaby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person239" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person239" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw Mrs. Looney holding Mr. Shanks from going into the house; but he would go in, and the piece went off directly.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were they when she was holding him?</p>
               <p>M. Uxtaby. They were at Mr. Bonherrin's door. Who let the piece off I cannot say. I stood at my own door, so could not see how far he was got in when the piece went off.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-19-person240">
                  James 
                  Darby 
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person240" type="surname" value="Darby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person240" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at Mr. Bonherrin's. I saw the deceased go into his own house, and just then the gun went off.</p>
               <p>Mr. Germain. I was at the public house next door to Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person241">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person241" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person241" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's. I heard the report of a gun, and went into the house. I saw a gun standing facing the kitchen door; there was no covering upon it. I imagined it to be Looney's house; it went by his name.</p>
               <p>Mr. Towle. On the 7th of November, about seven in the evening, I was sent for to Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person242">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person242" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person242" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's. I found him lying upon some chairs almost dead, and the room full of people. I desired some of them to carry him up to a bed. When we had got his cloaths off, I found he had been shot in on the left side, and out again on the small of his back, on the same side, slanting downwards about six inches. It went through his lungs; because I saw the air of his lungs coming through his body. He must have been very near the mouth of the piece; for his banjan was scorched; one of his ribs was broke, and carried into his body, as large a piece as half a crown, or thereabouts.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>Please you, my lord, in the morning we had some words. I went out to make peace, and dined with a friend over the water. Then I said I would go home, and see if my house is calmer now. When I went in, some words arose between my wife and me. This man ( meaning Hemer) was there in the room. He said, Mr. Looney, I came to settle with my captain; don't make any words, you was always accounted a quiet man. I took my hat, and went out of the house, and said God bless you. I had no design upon any person in the world; about seven o'clock I thought it high time to go home. When I came in this affair happened. Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person243">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person243" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person243" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said he would rout me. I was in the kitchen; he and my wife went into the street. Rout me, said I, who shall rout me? I pay ground-rent and all taxes; it is not that man that ever was born that shall rout me. The gun happened to be there, I don't know who loaded her; I had not had it in my hand for weeks before. I said, that man, be who he will, man or woman, shall not rout me. As for any malice, I had none at all; I had no more malice against Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person244">
                  Shanks
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person244" type="given" value="Shanks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person244" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             than I had against my own heart. I took the gun in my hand; he run himself<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176112090018"></xptr> against the gun, and how the gun went off I know no more than any man who never saw the gun.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-19-person245">
                  Daniel 
                  Bonberrin 
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person245" type="surname" value="Bonberrin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person245" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner four or five years; he is a very honest, quiet, sober, peaceable neighbour.</p>
               <p>Morgan Tizard. I have known him upwards of fifty years; he was born at Weymouth, and so was I. I never heard but that he was a sober peaceable man, of a quiet disposition, far from that of cruel.</p>
               <p>Captain 
               <persName id="t17611209-19-person246">
                  William 
                  Danvers 
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person246" type="surname" value="Danvers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person246" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him three years; he always behaved well; a quiet, easy, inoffensive man, of a good character. I was with him nine months in one ship.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-19-person247">
                  William 
                  Jinkins 
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person247" type="surname" value="Jinkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person247" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at sea with him about the first commencement of the late French war. He was an officer over me. I have heard him reprove men when they have been guilty of passion and wroth. I never saw him use mankind ill in my life; a man of a very meek, mild disposition; I never saw him in liquor. He was a very compassionate man. He was master of a hoy; all under his command gave him the character of a good-natur'd man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-19-person248">
                  Joshua 
                  Young 
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person248" type="surname" value="Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person248" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him seventeen or eighteen years. He was a very sober man, not passionate; but very assable and agreeable in conversation. I never saw him to have any words in wroth; he was always reckoned good temper'd, and I always thought him so in reality; but to be sure he has a sad wife.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-19-person249">
                  John 
                  Willmore 
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person249" type="surname" value="Willmore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person249" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him thirty years; he bears the character of a good-natur'd man, and a very honest sober man, not quarrelsome nor cruel; a very honest man, I have taken a great deal of his money.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-19-person250">
                  Robert 
                  Keith 
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person250" type="surname" value="Keith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person250" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about thirty-four years; a very honest, sober, industrious man. That character he bears by every body. I never heard to the contrary.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-19-person251">
                  James 
                  Larman 
               <interp inst="t17611209-19-person251" type="surname" value="Larman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person251" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about four years. I failed under him. He had a very good character all the time. He was master of a privateer out of Bristol; he was very peaceable and quiet.</p>
               <p>Barker Russel. I have known him between thirty and forty years. He was my father's cook, when I was his cabin boy. He was a very quiet honest man. I never heard the contrary.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17611209-19-verdict115" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-verdict115" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17611209-19-punish116" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-punish116" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-19-punish116" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="deathAndDissection"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-19-defend190 t17611209-19-punish116"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He received sentence to be executed on the Monday following, and his body to be dissected and anatomized.</p>
            </div1>
