<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640502-43">
               <interp inst="t17640502-43" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640502-43" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640502-43" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640502"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640502-43" type="date" value="17640502"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640502-43-off239-c277" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-43-defend355 t17640502-43-off239 t17640502-43-verdict243"></join>
         
               <p>270. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17640502-43-defend355" type="defendantName">
                     Francis 
                     Welch 
                  <interp inst="t17640502-43-defend355" type="surname" value="Welch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-43-defend355" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-43-defend355" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17640502-43-off239" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640502-43-off239" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-43-off239" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a cotton handkerchief, value 12 d.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17640502-43-victim357" type="victimName">
                     Henry 
                     Wiggins 
                  <interp inst="t17640502-43-victim357" type="surname" value="Wiggins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-43-victim357" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-43-victim357" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-43-off239 t17640502-43-victim357"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17640502-43-cd240" type="crimeDate">April 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-43-off239 t17640502-43-cd240"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640502-43-person358">
                  Henry 
                  Wiggins 
               <interp inst="t17640502-43-person358" type="surname" value="Wiggins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-43-person358" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-43-person358" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On a Sunday night, between the 15th and 16th of April, I was coming down <placeName id="t17640502-43-crimeloc241">Ludgate-hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640502-43-crimeloc241" type="placeName" value="Ludgate-hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640502-43-crimeloc241" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-43-off239 t17640502-43-crimeloc241"></join> as the watch went 12; there came the prisoner and five or six more, rushing by us in a ruffian-like manner; they said nothing to us. nor we to them: just as we came to the corner of the Old-Bailey, a girl took my companion by the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176405020023"></xptr> hand, and, in the mean time, all these fellows came back again, and gathered round him, that I could not see him: I returned back, the prisoner came close to me, and immediately I saw my handkerchief in the prisoner's hand: he went to toss it from his right hand to his left, and the handkerchief fell all open. I was afraid to say any thing then, being by myself: I ran and told my companion of it: said he, do you know the man? I said, I did: then said he, we will go and get the handkerchief again. When the prisoner saw me see he had my handkerchief, he shuffled up to hide it, and another of them came and catched it out of his hand, but I could not take notice of him. My companion and I went up to the prisoner: I said, you are the young man that took my handkerchief out of my pocket: he said, I know nothing of it: we took him, and met the watchman, and charged him with him: just before we came to the watch-house, he slipped his arm out of my hand, and struck me on the breast: he denied having the handkerchief: he said his name was Smith: but the next morning he said he was a copper-plate printer, and lived by Charing-cross, and that he was a master.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it light or dark?</p>
               <p>Wiggins. It was just under a lamp. I have no doubt at all as to the man.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you your handkerchief last?</p>
               <p>Wiggins. I had it in my hand not above three minutes before.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Wiggins. I am a journeyman peruke-maker: I have not been long out of the country.</p>
               <p>Fildue Morey. I was with the prosecutor at this time; he told me he had lost his handkerchief; I asked him if he knew the man that took it; he said, he did; then we went, and he pitched upon the prisoner; and said, he took it out of his pocket.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was coming down Ludgate-hill; said the gentlemen, these are very pretty girls; yes, said I, so they are. He goes down the hill, and after that, brings up a watchman, and charged me with picking his pocket of a handkerchief. I know no more of the handkerchief than your Lordship. I am a <rs id="t17640502-43-deflabel242" type="occupation">copper-plate printer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-43-defend355 t17640502-43-deflabel242"></join>. My father is dead, and my father-in-law's name is Smith. I left Bristol about a month ago, and have been with my father-in-law, in the Strand, ever since.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640502-43-verdict243" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640502-43-verdict243" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>. </p>
            </div1>
