<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680114-13">
               <interp inst="t17680114-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680114-13" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680114-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680114"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680114-13" type="date" value="17680114"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680114-13-off80-c159" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-13-defend186 t17680114-13-off80 t17680114-13-verdict83"></join>
         
               <p>116. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17680114-13-defend186" type="defendantName">
                     Daniel 
                     Asgood 
                  <interp inst="t17680114-13-defend186" type="surname" value="Asgood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-defend186" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-defend186" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for the <rs id="t17680114-13-off80" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-off80" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-off80" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               wilful murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17680114-13-victim188" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Ridley 
                        <interp inst="t17680114-13-victim188" type="surname" value="Ridley"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680114-13-victim188" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680114-13-victim188" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-13-off80 t17680114-13-victim188"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  ; he stood also charged on the Coroner's inquest for the said murder, with 
                     <persName id="t17680114-13-person189">
                        William 
                        Bear 
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person189" type="surname" value="Bear"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680114-13-person189" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680114-13-person189" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , 
                     <persName id="t17680114-13-person190">
                        John 
                        Aldridge 
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person190" type="surname" value="Aldridge"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680114-13-person190" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680114-13-person190" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , and 
                     <persName id="t17680114-13-person191">
                        Walter 
                        Stoaks 
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person191" type="surname" value="Stoaks"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680114-13-person191" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680114-13-person191" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   not in custody, for being present in aiding and assisting him to commit the said murder
            </rs>, <rs id="t17680114-13-cd81" type="crimeDate">Dec. 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-13-off80 t17680114-13-cd81"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-13-person192">
                  Robert 
                  Newton 
               <interp inst="t17680114-13-person192" type="surname" value="Newton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person192" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person192" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I <placeName id="t17680114-13-crimeloc82">keep the Last and Sugar Loaf, Water-lane Black-friars</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17680114-13-crimeloc82" type="placeName" value="keep the Last and Sugar Loaf, Water-lane Black-friars"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17680114-13-crimeloc82" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-13-off80 t17680114-13-crimeloc82"></join>. On the 10th of December, about half an hour past ten in the night, there came in five bargemen or lightermen; they called for a pot of beer, it was drawn them; they said it stank; no body said any thing to contradict them; they drank it, and wanted another; I said it was past our hour, and desired them to go; they asked if they might have a glass of gin each; I said yes; they had a penny glass each; without any provocation the prisoner swore and blasted his eyes, called me booger, and came and struck me with his fist; after that two others of them sell to beating 
               <persName id="t17680114-13-person193">
                  Edward 
                  Crowther 
               <interp inst="t17680114-13-person193" type="surname" value="Crowther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person193" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person193" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a lodger in the house; then I expected murder, or some mischief; I ran out to call the watch; the first man that passed me was 
               <persName id="t17680114-13-person194">
                  William 
                  Ridley 
               <interp inst="t17680114-13-person194" type="surname" value="Ridley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person194" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person194" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I said run quick to our house, for I expect murder will be committed; I ran farther on, and another watchman passed me; I told him to run for God's sake; I returned back with him, with an intent to assist the watchmen, but I was pulled into my house, and told my wife was in sits; when they heard me say I would call the watch, three of the bargemen had came out after me, while the other two were beating Crowther; the watchman received his hurt abroad, I saw nothing of that; about half an hour after came the deceased and Bartene, another watchman, into my house; the deceased said I have been most cruelly used; he pulled up his wig, and shewed me some blood in his right ear; he put his little finger in and pulled out a clot of blood, and threw it down on the floor.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had the deceased been a watchman?</p>
               <p>Newton. He has been a watchman a considerable time, very likely before I came into the parish.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure the prisoner heard you say you would go for the watch?</p>
               <p>Newton. I said in their hearing I would send for or call the watch; they seemed to come into the house on purpose to breed a riot, and they said to him that is an evidence, you brought us here on purpose; they all heard me say I would call the watch; I had told them they were welcome to go without paying any thing, and I was not paid; there was one of them offered to pay, but I do not know which; I had sent for the constable, and he was not at home; the prisoner knew of my sending; this was before I went for the watch.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-13-person195">
                  Edw 
                  Crowther 
               <interp inst="t17680114-13-person195" type="surname" value="Crowther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person195" type="given" value="Edw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person195" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a lodger in Mr. Newton's house; there came in five men about a quarter before 11 on the 10th of Dec. the prisoner was one of them; one of them is in court an evidence, the other three not taken; they called for a pot of beer; when they had it they found fault with it, saying it stank; the prisoner began to abuse one 
               <persName id="t17680114-13-person196">
                  Charles 
                  Duncomb 
               <interp inst="t17680114-13-person196" type="surname" value="Duncomb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person196" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person196" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a person that used the house; he told him he should like to put him upon the fire and broil him; Duncomb said what can be your reason, I never had no acquaintance with you, he had given him no provocation in my hearing; the prisoner made use of many blasphemous oaths and vile expressions; Mr. Newton said, gentlemen, I will not have this usage in my house; no customer shall be used in this manner, I must immediately send for an officer; he sent his maid out for one; the prisoner said send for them; he and one or two more said they would stay for them; the prisoner got up and strock Mr. Newton twice on the ribs; Mrs. Newton seeing this, cried to me for God's sake to stop him; upon that the prisoner knocked Duncomb down with his head against the sender; then he came up to me, and said, are you the man that, is to stop us, and struck me; I had not spoke a word to them; after that another of them came<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176801140014"></xptr> and struck me on the other side; when Mr. Newton was out calling the watch they quitted the house; I heard Mr. Newton almost up to the watch-house calling the watch; I met the two watchmen about twenty yards from Mr. Newton's house, they had their slaves with them: I saw the bargemen run down the alley by the house corner, towards Fleetditch, I and 
               <persName id="t17680114-13-person197">
                  Charles 
                  Duncomb 
               <interp inst="t17680114-13-person197" type="surname" value="Duncomb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person197" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person197" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             went after them; when we came almost to the head of the steps, the men had secreted themselves under the houses by Fleet-ditch; they jumped out upon the watchmen; I immediately returned and saw no more of it, having been ill used enough before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-13-person198">
                  Charles 
                  Bartene 
               <interp inst="t17680114-13-person198" type="surname" value="Bartene"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person198" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person198" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watchman, Mr. Newton called watch; I was along with Ridley, he had been a watchman about twelve months; when we were going down the Paved Alley there were four or five of the other men in company, Ridley was knocked down; I was forced to run for it; they broker his lanthorn all to pieces, I did not see who did it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-13-person199">
                  John 
                  Catlin 
               <interp inst="t17680114-13-person199" type="surname" value="Catlin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person199" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person199" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a bargeman; on the 10th of December about a quarter before eleven, 
               <persName id="t17680114-13-person200">
                  William 
                  Bear 
               <interp inst="t17680114-13-person200" type="surname" value="Bear"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person200" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person200" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17680114-13-person201">
                  Walter 
                  Stoaks 
               <interp inst="t17680114-13-person201" type="surname" value="Stoaks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person201" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person201" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17680114-13-person202">
                  John 
                  Aldridge 
               <interp inst="t17680114-13-person202" type="surname" value="Aldridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person202" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person202" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the prisoner, and I, we called for a tankard of beer, that was found fault with; then they said let us have some gin; Mr. Newton served us; Mr. Duncomb was in discourse with Mr. Newton by the fire-side, the prisoner took Mr. Duncomb up in discourse, he swore and got up and struck him and Mr. Newton; Mr. Newton sent his servant for an officer, none came; he went out for the watch, then they were for going out without paying; I took a shilling out, and said if no body would pay I would; no body took it up, I put it in my pocket; they went out, I followed them, and wished Mr. Duncomb a good night, and said I would come and pay to-morrow; going down the passage, I said all the blame will be laid upon me as I was known, Mr. Duncomb being my acquaintance; the watchmen coming down after them, four of them stopt at the bottom of the steps, I walked on a little way; I saw the prisoner take and draw the watchman's staff out of his hands and struck at him, but whether he hit him I cannot tell, he struck with the staff; as Thompson was coming down the steps the prisoner struck him, the watchman was then on the ground; Thompson's wife was there, she said for God's sake gentlemen do not kill my husband; I went and took hold of her arm, and said your husband shall not be hurt, and desired the prisoner to be quiet; I pulled the prisoner off from Thompson, and we went along about our business, then the watchman got up; I had been with them all the afternoon almost; the prisoner being betwixt me and the lanthorns I saw all that passed.</p>
               <p>- Thompson. I am a coal porter, I was going down the Paved Alley at the time this happened; there was a neighbour or two with a candle; I turned up the ditch side, there were five men standing all together, just turning the steps of that side near the market; I went to go by them, said the prisoner what do you want; I said I am only going home with my wife; he struck me three or four times with his left hand; I never saw him before, but I am positive to the man, the other four stood over me helping him; I was struck by one or two of them; the prisoner went from me for about two or three minutes, and came again with a stick about four feet-long, and struck at me twice; I cannot say he hurt me, for I fell down to escape the blows; I catched hold of the middle of the stick with my two hands; they kept haling me backwards and forwards a minute or two, d - ing me, and bidding me let the stick go; I said I would, if you will not use me ill; one of them said, d - m his blood, do not hit him no more, you have given him enough, do not strike him; then they went away towards Fleet-street, and I went home.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Catlin strike you?</p>
               <p>Thompson. He stood over me, but he never struck me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-13-person203">
                  Hannah 
                  Ridley 
               <interp inst="t17680114-13-person203" type="surname" value="Ridley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person203" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person203" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am widow to the deceased; on the morning of the 11th of December, my husband was led home by one of the watchmen, I let him in; I asked him what what was the matter; he told me he had been badly used, he had been beat in a most cruel manner, by five villainous fellows; I asked him where his staff and lanthorn was; he said he was afraid his staff had been his death, for they took it out of his hand and beat him over the head; he took the candle and shewed me his right ear, running down with blood, and his right nostril; I begged of him to come to bed and compose himself; he said he was so bad, that he believed he could not get into bed; with persuasion he got into bed; he cried out Hannah, my head! Hannah! my head! as soon as he was in bed, he called upon the Lord and said, O! my head, my head, I am afraid I have got my fatal stroke; he called upon his poor children and said, O! was I but sit to die! and I never heard him speak after, he never opened his eyes after that, this was about one in the morning; he had cried out of his head prodigiously; he died on the Saturday morning the 12th of December, about half an hour after nine; he was sent to the hospital senseless; when the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176801140015"></xptr> surgeon opened his head, he did not seem to feel it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-13-person204">
                  Robert 
                  Bird 
               <interp inst="t17680114-13-person204" type="surname" value="Bird"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person204" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person204" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a surgeon, and attend St. Bartholemew's-hospital; Ridley was brought there on the Friday morning about ten o'clock, that was the 11th of December; he was then sensible, bleeding at the eyes, mouth, and ears, the right ear more than the left; I sent for Mr. 
               <persName id="t17680114-13-person205">
                  Young
               <interp inst="t17680114-13-person205" type="given" value="Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person205" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the surgeon, whom I am pupil to, he examined his head; I was present when he opened the sclap, but did not immediately find a fracture, therefore he gave me orders to blend him, and do what was necessary; the next morning upon visiting him, I found him upon the point of death; upon representing the case to me, Mr. Young desired I would open the head in case he died, and examine it; I did so, and upon examining it, I found a large fracture from the hind part of the head, to the orbit of the eye, on the right side, with a large depression of the bone, which I really believe was the cause of his death.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you discover with what the wound was given?</p>
               <p>Bird. That is impossible.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was very much in liquor, but do not know that I struck any body; I thought to make my escape from them, rather than to go to the watch-house.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-13-person206">
                  Leonard 
                  Phillips 
               <interp inst="t17680114-13-person206" type="surname" value="Phillips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person206" type="given" value="Leonard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person206" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a coal-merchant, I have known the prisoner about four or five years, he is a very honest, industrious, sober young fellow; he has been servant to me upwards of twelve months, I never had an honester man; I do not know that there is a humaner man in that employ living, I have seen frequent instances of it; I employ him as a bargeman, he always behaved himself extremely well; he came to me with a very good recommendation, and always executed all orders given him with great punctuality.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-13-person207">
                  Richard 
                  Phillips 
               <interp inst="t17680114-13-person207" type="surname" value="Phillips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person207" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person207" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a lime-merchant, I have known him upwards of twelve months; he has been very assiduous in his master's business, he used to go frequently to Northfleet; I never knew him drunk or negligent of his master's business.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-13-person208">
                  Henry 
                  Phelps 
               <interp inst="t17680114-13-person208" type="surname" value="Phelps"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person208" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person208" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a lighterman and dealer in coals; I have known him about seven years, I never saw any things amiss of him in my life time; was he out of this court I should be glad to employ him; I never knew him cruel, I know no man that I would employ sooner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-13-person209">
                  Edmund 
                  Ball 
               <interp inst="t17680114-13-person209" type="surname" value="Ball"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person209" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person209" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him near twelve months, I am a victualler; he lodged with me about six months, he left me about five months ago; I never saw him what may be called drunk, he is a good tempered civil man; he and his company were at my house the night after this affair happened.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he in liquor?</p>
               <p>Ball. I did not perceive him to be in liquor, I never found him disposed to be quarrelsome.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-13-person210">
                  Joseph 
                  Chaterton 
               <interp inst="t17680114-13-person210" type="surname" value="Chaterton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person210" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-person210" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about seven months, he is very dutiful in regard to his business, and very sober; I never saw him in a quarrel all the time I sailed with him, we both sailed in one barge together.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17680114-13-verdict83" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-verdict83" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17680114-13-punish84" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-punish84" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-punish84" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="deathAndDissection"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-13-defend186 t17680114-13-punish84"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>This being Friday, he received sentence immediately afterwards to be executed the Monday following, and his body to be dissected and anotomized; <rs id="t17680114-13-punish85" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-punish85" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-13-punish85" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="executed"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-13-defend186 t17680114-13-punish85"></join>
               he was executed accordingly
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
