<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17620714-12">
               <interp inst="t17620714-12" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620714-12" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620714-12" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17620714"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620714-12" type="date" value="17620714"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620714-12-off51-c78" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620714-12-defend99 t17620714-12-off51 t17620714-12-verdict53"></join>
         
               <p>187. (L). 
               
                  <persName id="t17620714-12-defend99" type="defendantName">
                     Jacob 
                     Moses 
                  <interp inst="t17620714-12-defend99" type="surname" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-12-defend99" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-12-defend99" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17620714-12-off51" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620714-12-off51" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-12-off51" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one hempen bag, value two pence, and ninety pounds weight of pimento, value sixty shillings
            </rs>, the goods of 
               
                  <persName id="t17620714-12-victim101" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Robinson 
                  <interp inst="t17620714-12-victim101" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-12-victim101" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-12-victim101" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620714-12-off51 t17620714-12-victim101"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17620714-12-cd52" type="crimeDate">July the 2 d</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620714-12-off51 t17620714-12-cd52"></join> ++ .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620714-12-person102">
                  William 
                  Plain 
               <interp inst="t17620714-12-person102" type="surname" value="Plain"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-12-person102" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-12-person102" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the prisoner by sight. I belong to Mr. Robinson. My master has lost pimento three different times out of his warehouse, but by whom I cannot tell. I sat up several nights to watch the thief; and when he was taken I was gone home to bed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620714-12-person103">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Whitehead 
               <interp inst="t17620714-12-person103" type="surname" value="Whitehead"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-12-person103" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-12-person103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . We took the prisoner in my master's warehouse, concealed in a closet in the warehouse: we found him about half an hour after four in the morning. The prisoner came up the court where Mr. Robinson lives, and looked on both sides the court. About a quarter after four he went down the court again, and went under a gateway in a posture to ease himself. I looked up the court to see if any thing was stirring, and afterwards we found him in the warehouse: the place he got over is upwards of seven foot high: we took him there. His excuse was, he came to look after a pidgeon.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620714-12-person104">
                  Thomas 
                  Branham 
               <interp inst="t17620714-12-person104" type="surname" value="Branham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-12-person104" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-12-person104" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had been in the warehouse on the evening, and had put the bags and things to rights in the yard. I never saw the prisoner before that morning. I found the bag removed from the warehouse into the yard, and a ladder set at the gate.</p>
               <p>Q. How high is the warehouse?</p>
               <p>Branham. Three story high. He offered his watch, and what money he had about him, to let him go.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I am a baker, and was at work till five o'clock in the morning, and went to buy some mackerel at Billingsgate. As I came past Mincing-lane, I saw a pidgeon, and it flew away; and I saw a man with a drawn sword, and I jumped over to save myself, and I run up stairs to hide myself.</p>
               <p>Q. from the prisoner. Did any of you see me move the bag to the first floor?</p>
               <p>Robinson. No.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620714-12-person105">
                  Jonas 
                  Nathan 
               <interp inst="t17620714-12-person105" type="surname" value="Nathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-12-person105" type="given" value="Jonas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-12-person105" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the prisoner. I have known him about twelve months. I have intrusted him with things of value, and never missed any thing through him.</p>
               <p>First Witness. I have known the prisoner ever since he was born; he was always a sober, honest, hardworking man. I have employed him to carry goods into the country, and with bills, and never lost any thing.</p>
               <p>Second Witness. I have known him between ten and eleven years. He used to bring bread to my house. I am a merchant. I never missed any thing.</p>
               <p>Third Witness. I have known the prisoner 12 years. I never heard any harm of him. I have supplied him with money. I take him to be an honest boy.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17620714-12-verdict53" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620714-12-verdict53" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
