<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17630914-85">
               <interp inst="t17630914-85" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630914-85" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630914-85" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17630914"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630914-85" type="date" value="17630914"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17630914-85-off460-c498" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630914-85-defend674 t17630914-85-off460 t17630914-85-verdict464"></join>
         
               <p>457. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17630914-85-defend674" type="defendantName">
                     George 
                     Drewet 
                  <interp inst="t17630914-85-defend674" type="surname" value="Drewet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-defend674" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-defend674" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17630914-85-off460" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-off460" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-off460" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               robbing 
                     
                        <persName id="t17630914-85-victim676" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Leader 
                        <interp inst="t17630914-85-victim676" type="surname" value="Leader"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630914-85-victim676" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17630914-85-victim676" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630914-85-off460 t17630914-85-victim676"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   in <placeName id="t17630914-85-crimeloc461">Hyde-park</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-crimeloc461" type="placeName" value="Hyde-park"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-crimeloc461" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630914-85-off460 t17630914-85-crimeloc461"></join> of 5 guineas and 7 s. and 3 d.
            </rs> the money of the said John, <rs id="t17630914-85-cd462" type="crimeDate">September 4</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630914-85-off460 t17630914-85-cd462"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630914-85-person677">
                  John 
                  Leader 
               <interp inst="t17630914-85-person677" type="surname" value="Leader"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-person677" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-person677" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, that he lived at the Swan at Hay-hill, and is <rs id="t17630914-85-viclabel463" type="occupation">a carver</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630914-85-victim676 t17630914-85-viclabel463"></join>; that on Sunday the 4th of Sept. about 9 at night, the prisoner and another man came to him as he and 
               <persName id="t17630914-85-person678">
                  Mary 
                  Hubridge 
               <interp inst="t17630914-85-person678" type="surname" value="Hubridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-person678" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-person678" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             were going from Kensington gardens home, as he was a little on that side of the parcel of trees nearest his own house, the prisoner laid hold on his collar with his left hand, bid him stand, and asked him for his money, then he let go his coat with his left hand, and put it into his right hand breeches pocket; that at the same time the other man went and laid hold of 
               <persName id="t17630914-85-person679">
                  Mary 
                  Hubridge 
               <interp inst="t17630914-85-person679" type="surname" value="Hubridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-person679" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-person679" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , she cried she had no money; that he left her, and came to him on his left hand, and took 3 d. in halfpence out of his waistcoat pocket; that the prisoner took out 7 s. from his breeches pocket, the other man felt without side his left breeches pocket, and finding there was money within he unbuttoned the pocket, and took out five guineas which he had there; that he had never seen the prisoner before but was positive he was the man that first stopped him, and was at his right hand side while the other was on the left and took the five guineas; that they left him, and seemed to walk gently towards the garden wall; that the prisoner was in a white fustian frock, a sharp cock'd hat, and his hair tied behind, but did not see what colour it was; that he looked in his face when he stopped him, and was certain to him. Being asked how it was for light? said, it was dark. That the next morning, being Monday, he saw the prisoner go up Hay-hill, in company with another man, he followed them into Dover-street, ann came pretty close to him, and looked at him; that he followed them along St. James's-Street, into St. James's-park, from thence to Bridge-street, over the Bridge, and into the Borough; that he asked several people as he was following them how he must proceed in taking up a thief, and said, that man ( meaning the prisoner) had robbed him, but got no assistance till he got there, the other man that was with him he thought was something like the other man, but he could not sware to him. Being told that that man was then near him in the Court, to see if he knew him again, looked a good while, and at last pitched on another man that stood very near him, and said, he was the most like him of any he saw.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630914-85-person680">
                  Mary 
                  Hubridge 
               <interp inst="t17630914-85-person680" type="surname" value="Hubridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-person680" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-person680" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             confirmed the account as to their being stopped by two men in Hyde-park at the time, but could not swear to the prisoner.</p>
               <p>The prisoner, in his defence, said, he had that Sunday come from Highfield-court, in Sussex, which is 31 miles from Westminster-bridge; that he came to the Swan, in Park-street, between 6 and 7 in the afternoon, that he went out to speak to Mr. Caruthas, and was gone about a quarter of an hour, then he went into that house, and spent the evening there with several gentlemen before he went to bed; that he went to bed about a quarter after 9, and the landlady lighted him to bed, and he never was out of the house till next morning.</p>
               <p>He called 
               <persName id="t17630914-85-person681">
                  Robert 
                  Robey 
               <interp inst="t17630914-85-person681" type="surname" value="Robey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-person681" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-person681" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who keeps the Swan, in Park-street, who deposed, that he had known the prisoner three years, that he was a Life-guard man, and had been in the country about two months, and came to his house that Sunday the 4th, about half an hour after 6; that he went out, and he saw him standing talking with Mr. Caruthas in the street about 10 minutes, and then came in and sat down and supped in the house, and went to bed about a quarter after 9, or it might be half an hour after, and his wife lighted him to bed. Being asked how far his house was from the place where the prosecutor said he was robbed? said, it was a good mile distant; and that he was positive the prisoner was never out of his house after he came back from speaking to Mr. Caruthas till next morning.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630914-85-person682">
                  Frances 
                  Robey 
               <interp inst="t17630914-85-person682" type="surname" value="Robey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-person682" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-person682" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , his wife, deposed, that he came about half an hour after 6 o'clock, that she and her husband were at the door, and saw him while talking to Caruthas; that she lighted him to bed about a quarter or half an hour after 9; that if he had went out they must have seen him as he lay up two pair of stairs, and must come through the tap-room, and was clear in it he was not out of the house after till next morning.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630914-85-person683">
                  William 
                  Caruthas 
               <interp inst="t17630914-85-person683" type="surname" value="Caruthas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-person683" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-person683" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed, that he belongs to the Life-guards, that he was standing at the gate at the stables, about four doors from the Swan, the 4th of Sept. that the prisoner came to him, and was with him about a quarter of an hour, that it was before it was dark, and after he left him he saw him go towards the Swan.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630914-85-person684">
                  Charles 
                  Rock 
               <interp inst="t17630914-85-person684" type="surname" value="Rock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-person684" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-person684" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Mr. Brookprat, 
               <persName id="t17630914-85-person685">
                  James 
                  Longmires 
               <interp inst="t17630914-85-person685" type="surname" value="Longmires"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-person685" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-person685" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17630914-85-person686">
                  Simon 
                  Harrison 
               <interp inst="t17630914-85-person686" type="surname" value="Harrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-person686" type="given" value="Simon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-person686" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , all of the Life-guards, confirmed that of his coming out of the country that afternoon, and being in company with him at the Swan from before 7, or between 7 and 8, till he went to bed, about half an hour after 9.</p>
               <p>Mr. Robertson, the riding-master, deposed, he shook hands with him between 7 and 8, and was<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176309140040"></xptr> in his company there till he went to bed between 9 and 10.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630914-85-person687">
                  James 
                  Terry 
               <interp inst="t17630914-85-person687" type="surname" value="Terry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-person687" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-person687" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the waiter at the Swan, deposed to the prisoner's being in his company from 7 o'clock till the time of his going to bed.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630914-85-person688">
                  Robert 
                  Summers 
               <interp inst="t17630914-85-person688" type="surname" value="Summers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-person688" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-person688" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a life guard man, deposed, that on Monday the 5th, in the morning, the prisoner came to bring him a message, that he went and breakfasted with him at the Swan, in Park-street, that he asked him to take a walk with him into the Borough; that he went with him, the prisoner having things sent up there out of the country, which he went in order to get them conveyed to his home.</p>
               <p>Mr. Spencer deposed, that the prisoner came to take his leave of him in Sussex before he came up, on the 4th; that he was a person of exceeding good character, that he also had a very good estate.</p>
               <p>Justice Miller deposed, that he had reason to believe the prosecutor was mistaken in point of the man, and that he spoke to this purport, that if he had got his money he would not prosecute.</p>
               <p>Justice Keeling deposed to the same purport.</p>
               <p>Colonel 
               <persName id="t17630914-85-person689">
                  Benjamin 
                  Carpenter 
               <interp inst="t17630914-85-person689" type="surname" value="Carpenter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-person689" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-person689" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and Captain 
               <persName id="t17630914-85-person690">
                  Cunningham
               <interp inst="t17630914-85-person690" type="given" value="Cunningham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-person690" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , under whom the prisoner served, gave him the character of a very worthy, honest, sober, orderly, and well-behaved person, not only as a soldier, but as a moral man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17630914-85-verdict464" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630914-85-verdict464" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
