<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660903-53">
               <interp inst="t17660903-53" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-53" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-53" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660903"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-53" type="date" value="17660903"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660903-53-off283-c383" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-53-defend489 t17660903-53-off283 t17660903-53-verdict287"></join>
         
               <p>451. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660903-53-defend489" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Webb 
                  <interp inst="t17660903-53-defend489" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-53-defend489" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-53-defend489" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17660903-53-off283" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660903-53-off283" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-53-off283" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a silver mug, value 3 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17660903-53-victim491" type="victimName">
                     Samuel 
                     Holme 
                  <interp inst="t17660903-53-victim491" type="surname" value="Holme"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-53-victim491" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-53-victim491" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-53-off283 t17660903-53-victim491"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17660903-53-cd284" type="crimeDate">June 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-53-off283 t17660903-53-cd284"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-53-person492">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Holme 
               <interp inst="t17660903-53-person492" type="surname" value="Holme"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-53-person492" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-53-person492" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to 
               <persName id="t17660903-53-person493">
                  Samuel 
                  Holme 
               <interp inst="t17660903-53-person493" type="surname" value="Holme"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-53-person493" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-53-person493" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; we <rs id="t17660903-53-viclabel285" type="occupation">keep <placeName id="t17660903-53-crimeloc286">the Queen's-head, Leadenhall-market</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-53-crimeloc286" type="placeName" value="the Queen's-head, Leadenhall-market"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-53-crimeloc286" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-53-off283 t17660903-53-crimeloc286"></join>, a public-house</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-53-victim491 t17660903-53-viclabel285"></join>. On the 16th of June the prisoner came into our house, between 8 and 9 o'clock in the evening, and called for a pint of beer; he had it in a silver mug; he staid about half an hour, drank part of the beer and paid for it, and said to a young man that lodged in my house, here is a little beer, and gave it to him; then he bade us a good night, and went away; he came in again in about half<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176609030044"></xptr> an hour after, and called for another pint of beer, and he was served again with the same silver mug; he called for a paper of tobacco and a pipe; I was in the kitchen, and he in the fore room, called the tap room: he sent a shilling in to change; I sent out change; he went away; I put by the plate as usual, and went to bed, and the next morning I got up at five o'clock, and brought the plate down with me; a master butcher came in and called for six-pennyworth of bumbo; I went and made it, and brought it forward, and before I put it out of my hand, I said to the servant that was up with me, somebody has changed my mug; they have left a pewter one, and taken away my silver one; I said to the person the bumbo was for, somebody has put a trick upon me, but I know who changed it, it must be the man that was here last night; there was one 
               <persName id="t17660903-53-person494">
                  John 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17660903-53-person494" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-53-person494" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-53-person494" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in the house at the time the prisoner was, that said he should know him from an hundred people, and he would lay hold of him wherever he met him. In about a fortnight after, that young man met him in Newgate-street, and brought him to me; I said, you are the young man that have got my mug; he said I am he, and for God's sake have mercy on me. I asked him what he did for his living; he said he was a barber, and he had been out of business, and poverty had induced him to do the thing. I asked him where my mug was; if you'll let me have my mug, I'll make it as easy as I can; he told me he had sold it to Mr. Popard in Smock-alley; I said I would go there and hear what he said; I went there, and said to Mr. Popard, was there not such a sort of a young man came and sold you a silver mug: he said he did not know, he might for what he knew; I told him I had the man in hold; that he had changed a bad one for it at-my house; I desired him to let me have my mug, and I would make it as easy as I could; he said his shop was his market, and he did not know but that he had bought it; he seemed to give himself no trouble about it: then I came back, and told the prisoner what he said; in the mean time the prisoner's mother went to Mr. Popard, but she came away as she went: the prisoner was committed to the Compter; the mother promised she would send the mug, which she did by the prisoner's brother-in-law, I was in bed when it came; (two mugs produced in court, one silver, the other French plate, both of one pattern; she takes up that of French plate) this is the mug the prisoner left at my house, as to the other, it may be that which was taken away of mine; but if it is, the name is taken out.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Popard. There were letters upon the mug, but we had them taken out to make it saleable.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>This metal mug was my mother's property, she made me a present of it; I called at this house and drank two or three pints of beer; I had mine under my arm; when I drank my beer, I set it down upon the table; when I went away, I by mistake took the wrong, thinking it was mine; I went and sold it to Mr. Popard.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-53-person495">
                  Robert 
                  Greenaway 
               <interp inst="t17660903-53-person495" type="surname" value="Greenaway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-53-person495" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-53-person495" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a cheesemonger, and live in Spitalfields: I have known the prisoner three years, he has been a waiter at several places; I never heard any thing amiss of him before this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-53-person496">
                  Peter 
                  Siden 
               <interp inst="t17660903-53-person496" type="surname" value="Siden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-53-person496" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-53-person496" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Whitechapel, I am a callico-glazer; I have known him about five or six years; I married his own sister; he is a very honest man.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see this base metal mug at his mother's house?</p>
               <p>Siden. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-53-person497">
                  Jane 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17660903-53-person497" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-53-person497" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-53-person497" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My husband is a cheesemonger; I have known him 12 years; I never heard any harm of him in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-53-person498">
                  Jane 
                  Rice 
               <interp inst="t17660903-53-person498" type="surname" value="Rice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-53-person498" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-53-person498" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about 11 years; I never heard of any ill laid to his charge before this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-53-person499">
                  Anne 
                  French 
               <interp inst="t17660903-53-person499" type="surname" value="French"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-53-person499" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-53-person499" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Court-street; I knew him all the time he was apprentice; I never knew any ill against him before this.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660903-53-verdict287" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660903-53-verdict287" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17660903-53-punish288" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660903-53-punish288" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-53-defend489 t17660903-53-punish288"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
