<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670115-9">
               <interp inst="t17670115-9" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670115-9" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670115-9" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670115"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670115-9" type="date" value="17670115"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670115-9-off46-c100" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670115-9-defend114 t17670115-9-off46 t17670115-9-verdict52"></join>
         
               <p>94. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17670115-9-defend114" type="defendantName">
                     Samuel 
                     Ball 
                  <interp inst="t17670115-9-defend114" type="surname" value="Ball"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-9-defend114" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-9-defend114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for that <rs id="t17670115-9-off46" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670115-9-off46" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-9-off46" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he, on the king's highway, on Mary, <rs id="t17670115-9-viclabel47" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670115-9-victim118 t17670115-9-viclabel47"></join> of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17670115-9-victim116" type="victimName">
                           Peter 
                           Orris 
                        <interp inst="t17670115-9-victim116" type="surname" value="Orris"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670115-9-victim116" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670115-9-victim116" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , did make an assault, putting her in corporal fear and danger of her life, and violently taking from her person one linen pocket, value 2 d. and 6 s. 3 d. in money numbered, the property of the said Peter
            </rs>, <rs id="t17670115-9-cd48" type="crimeDate">December 26</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670115-9-off46 t17670115-9-cd48"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
               
                  <persName id="t17670115-9-victim118" type="victimName">
                     Mary 
                     Orris 
                  <interp inst="t17670115-9-victim118" type="surname" value="Orris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-9-victim118" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-9-victim118" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            . The day after new Christmas-day, at night, I was out, between ten and eleven, at <placeName id="t17670115-9-crimeloc49">Old Brentford</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17670115-9-crimeloc49" type="placeName" value="Old Brentford"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17670115-9-crimeloc49" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670115-9-off46 t17670115-9-crimeloc49"></join>; I went into the Castle, for a pint of beer; I met the prisoner; he asked me to drink.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that the first time you ever saw him?</p>
               <p>M. Orris. I had seen him go into his own house, opposite where I lodge, but I had never spoke to him before.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you lodged there?</p>
               <p>M. Orris. From a fortnight after Michaelmas.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has he lodged in his apartment?</p>
               <p>M. Orris. I do not know; he asked me to drink, and I asked him to drink out of mine; after I went out to go home, one 
               <persName id="t17670115-9-person119">
                  Thomas 
                  Onley 
               <interp inst="t17670115-9-person119" type="surname" value="Onley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-9-person119" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-9-person119" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             asked me the question to lie with me; Ball was with him; I not being agreeable, they used me very ill, and beat me; the other fellow used me a great deal worse than the prisoner; they pulled me and dragged me about; the prisoner got my pocket; there was in it 6 s. 3 d.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he get your pocket by pulling you about, or did he pull particularly at your pocket?</p>
               <p>M. Orris. By pulling me about.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it light or dark?</p>
               <p>M. Orris. It was moon-lightish; the other fellow took away my cardinal, and they would have stripped me.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was this from where you had been drinking?</p>
               <p>M. Orris. About a couple of stones cast; they dragged me in all manner of nastiness.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you consider this as using you thus to make you go with them, or to take your money from you on the highway?</p>
               <p>M. Orris. I thought they wanted me to go with them; I went home and told my husband; he went to the prisoner the next morning, I was by; he asked him if he knew any thing of that woman (meaning me;) he said no, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see any thing of your pocket or money again?</p>
               <p>M. Orris. No, I never did, nor cardinal neither; we took the prisoner before Justice Wegg; he asked the prisoner what he had done with my pocket and money; he said he had spent the money over night and in the morning; the Justice said to him, he could not have spent it all in that time; the prisoner said he had 7 1/2 d. left; I asked him what he had done with my pocket; he said they had thrown that away; when they heard the watch they ran away.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670115-9-person120">
                  Peter 
                  Orris 
               <interp inst="t17670115-9-person120" type="surname" value="Orris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-9-person120" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-9-person120" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am husband to the woman: I went to the prisoner the next morning, about seven o'clock, and asked him whether he knew that woman or not; he said no; I said, Do you know who you used ill cross the road there? He said no, he used no body ill; I said, You have used my wife very ill, she has got several bruises about her body; I asked him whether he was willing to deliver the money and cardinal up; he said he knew nothing about them; my wife went and got a warrant and constable, and took him up.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was this after the robbery, as she calls it?</p>
               <p>Orris. This may be near three days after.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has the prisoner lived near you?</p>
               <p>Orris. He lived opposite the house I do all his life-time, I believe.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he a married man?</p>
               <p>Orris. No, he is not.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did your wife come home that night?</p>
               <p>Orris. I was very bad with a fever, and cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. When did she first complain of this to you?</p>
               <p>Orris. When I opened the door to let her in.</p>
               <p>Q. What business does your wife follow?</p>
               <p>Orris. Any thing that she can get to do.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she sober that night?</p>
               <p>Orris. I can't say she was quite sober; she went up stairs as well as ever she did in her life.</p>
               <p>Q. What was your wife's stock in her pocket that day?</p>
               <p>Orris. I can't tell; what I got I always gave her; I work at <rs id="t17670115-9-viclabel50" type="occupation">labouring work</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670115-9-victim118 t17670115-9-viclabel50"></join> for a shilling or 14 d. a day.</p>
               <p>Q. What business does your wife do?</p>
               <p>Orris. She <rs id="t17670115-9-viclabel51" type="occupation">goes a haymaking</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670115-9-victim116 t17670115-9-viclabel51"></join>, and has been obliged to ask charity since I have been ill.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you been married?</p>
               <p>Orris. I have been married three years and about twelve or thirteen weeks.</p>
               <p>Q. Where had she been that day?</p>
               <p>Orris. She had been out to ask charity.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you given her any money that day?</p>
               <p>Orris. No, I had not been able.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you been ill?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176701150008"></xptr>Orris. Fifteen weeks; she had been over at Richmond, at gentlemens houses, and to see an acquaintance.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17670115-9-person121">
                  Mary 
                  Orris 
               <interp inst="t17670115-9-person121" type="surname" value="Orris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-9-person121" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-9-person121" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . What had you been at Richmond for that day?</p>
               <p>M. Orris. I had been there to ask charity for a bit of victuals; I got some halfpence of a gardener, one Whitehouse that I knew there.</p>
               <p>Q. What money had you got?</p>
               <p>M. Orris. I had four silver six-pences, and 2 s. wrapped in a bit of rag.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I am not guilty; I know nothing of this.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670115-9-person122">
                  Jonathan 
                  Nevett 
               <interp inst="t17670115-9-person122" type="surname" value="Nevett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-9-person122" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670115-9-person122" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner lived servant with me a year and a half or upwards; he behaved very sober and very honest; I never heard to the contrary of him in my life; I live in Old Brentford, just where this pretended robbery was; as to the woman I know little of her, but her general character in the neighbourhood is very bad, I never heard a worse; it is said she is not married to this man.</p>
               <p>Stanhope Hillier. I have known the prisoner ever since he has been able to earn a shilling; I have employed him; he is an honest labouring man; I never heard a bad character of him.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17670115-9-verdict52" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670115-9-verdict52" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
