<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17611021-33">
               <interp inst="t17611021-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611021-33" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611021-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17611021"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611021-33" type="date" value="17611021"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17611021-33-off169-c339" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-33-defend391 t17611021-33-off169 t17611021-33-verdict172"></join>
         
               <p>317. (L). 
               
                  <persName id="t17611021-33-defend391" type="defendantName">
                     Samuel 
                     Lee 
                  <interp inst="t17611021-33-defend391" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-defend391" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-defend391" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17611021-33-off169" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-off169" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-off169" type="offenceSubcategory" value="fraud"></interp>
               feloniously uttering, and publishing, as true, a false bill of exchange, with the name 
                     <persName id="t17611021-33-person392">
                        Benjamin 
                        Sutton 
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person392" type="surname" value="Sutton"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17611021-33-person392" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17611021-33-person392" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   thereunto subscribed, bearing date at Leicester, 17th of October, for the payment of 50 l. with intention to defraud 
                     
                        <persName id="t17611021-33-victim394" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Price 
                        <interp inst="t17611021-33-victim394" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17611021-33-victim394" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17611021-33-victim394" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>. It was laid also with intention to defraud 
               <persName id="t17611021-33-victim395" type="victimName">
                     <rs id="t17611021-33-viclabel170" type="occupation">Mess. Frame and Co.</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-33-victim395 t17611021-33-viclabel170"></join>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-victim395" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             
                  <rs id="t17611021-33-cd171" type="crimeDate">Dec. 20</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-33-off169 t17611021-33-cd171"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-33-person396">
                  John 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person396" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person396" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person396" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have had correspondence with Mr. Powser of Leicester about 16 years.</p>
               <p>Q. In what situation is he of late?</p>
               <p>Price. He is a man deprived of sight, so is under a necessity of having a person to transact business for him.</p>
               <p>Q. The bills drawn upon you from him, who are they drawn by?</p>
               <p>Price. They are drawn by Mr. 
               <persName id="t17611021-33-person397">
                  Benjamin 
                  Sutton 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person397" type="surname" value="Sutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person397" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person397" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , most of them, he draws more than any of the clerks.</p>
               <p>Q. What is Mr. Powser?</p>
               <p>Price. He is a hosier.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Price. I am a merchant.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you correspond with him in?</p>
               <p>Price. In money only; he was a man in busisiness, in the hosiery way, and he takes the excise money for the county of Derby; he used to remit me sometimes a thousand pounds a month, it answered his purpose in the country, and I was his agent here to pay it into the Bank, when I had collected in his bills and money. Now he has of late taken up money at Leicester, to answer his occasions, and made remittances to me to answer his drafts; he made his drafts upon me, and always sent me materials to answer them.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Mr. 
               <persName id="t17611021-33-person398">
                  Benjamin 
                  Sutton 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person398" type="surname" value="Sutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person398" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person398" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             agent for him in October 1760.</p>
               <p>Price. He was.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he reside?</p>
               <p>Price. At Leicester; they both live there, Mr. Powser, and Mr. Sutton.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the bills drawn by Mr. Sutton, on the account of Mr. Powser, accepted as Mr. Powser's bills?</p>
               <p>Price. All Mr. Sutton's bills, whom I considered as agent for Mr. Powser, I always paid as Mr. Powser's bills, because I had an order so to do from Mr. Powser.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q . How many clerks had Mr. Powser at home?</p>
               <p>Price. He had two or three.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen Mr. Powser often?</p>
               <p>Price. I never saw him but once; but I had an order from him, to pay all the bills drawn by Mr. Sutton, or any of his other clerks.</p>
               <p>Q. Who gave you that order? Did not Mr. Sutton write that order?</p>
               <p>Price. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has Mr. Sutton been his agent?</p>
               <p>Price. He has near as long as I have corresponded with Mr. Powser, he used to settle accounts for his master.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you this order by letter from Mr. Powser?</p>
               <p>Price. I cannot say I received any letter from Mr. Powser, signed by his own hand.</p>
               <p>Q. When the account was settled between Mr. Powser and you, did he always allow the account?</p>
               <p>Price. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you ever settled any account with Mr. Powser?</p>
               <p>Price. Yes, a great many.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he approve of them?</p>
               <p>Price. Yes, he did.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you have not had an answer under the hand of Mr. Sutton, with regard to settling your accounts rightly?</p>
               <p>Price. Yes, generally for his master, that Mr. Powser has approved of the account. Mr. Sutton writes word back, that either it is right, or right, subject to such error.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you direct your letters to Mr. Sutton?</p>
               <p>Price. I never directed a letter to Mr. Sutton in my life, as I recollect; I write particularly to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17611021-33-person399">
                  Thomas 
                  Powser 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person399" type="surname" value="Powser"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person399" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person399" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. No money past between Mr. Sutton and you?</p>
               <p>Price. I don't know that ever a penny past between us.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether there has not been in you, transacting a great many accounts with Mr. Powser, several mistakes in the time of your correspondence together?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176110210064"></xptr>Price. None so much as lately; there has been some mistakes, but such mistakes, that have been all regulated; I have taken my right, and he his.</p>
               <p>Q. Has not the prisoner at the bar been an instrument in settling most of your mistakes?</p>
               <p>Price. No. I have trusted him to be sure.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-33-person400">
                  Benjamin 
                  Sutton 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person400" type="surname" value="Sutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person400" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person400" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have been agent for Mr. Powser of Leicester, almost 16 years; he is blind.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you his clerk in the year 1760, in October?</p>
               <p>Sutton. I was, and was imploy'd as his agent to draw bills for him.</p>
               <p>Q. About the 17th of October 1760, was you authorized to draw bills upon him in town?</p>
               <p>Sutton. I have been authorized ever since I have been with him, to draw bills upon his account.</p>
               <p>Q. What, as a partner?</p>
               <p>Sutton. No, not as a partner.</p>
               <p>Q. Look upon the name 
               <persName id="t17611021-33-person401">
                  Benjamin 
                  Sutton 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person401" type="surname" value="Sutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person401" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person401" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (upon this bill now in question) Is this your handwriting?</p>
               <p>Sutton. No, Sir, it is not my hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you draw this bill?</p>
               <p>Sutton. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen the prisoner often?</p>
               <p>Sutton. I never saw him but once that I know of, and that some years ago; therefore I cannot form any idea of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Is this like your hand-writing?</p>
               <p>Sutton. It is a great deal like my writing; I was a good deal shock'd at first, when I saw it</p>
               <p>Q. Can you undertake to say upon your oath, without any degree of doubt, that you never 
               <persName id="t17611021-33-person402">
                  drew
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person402" type="given" value="drew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person402" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             that bill?</p>
               <p>Sutton. I know I never did draw it?</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Counsel. You say, when you first saw it, it shock'd you</p>
               <p>Sutton. It did a good deal; it was a good deal like my hand writing.</p>

               <p>Counsel. Then you could not be certain at first.</p>
               <p>Sutton. No, I could not.</p>
               <p>Q. What has made you more certain since?</p>
               <p>Sutton. By searching Mr. Powser's books.</p>
               <p>Q. Is that the only reason?</p>
               <p>Sutton. No, there are two indorsers; I went to them, and they had no such account on their books.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath, whether is this your handwriting or not?</p>
               <p>Sutton. It is not my hand-writing, upon my oath it is not; I am very certain of it.</p>
               <p>Q. When you 
               <persName id="t17611021-33-person403">
                  drew
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person403" type="given" value="drew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person403" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             these sort of bills, on the account of your principal, Mr. Powser, do you enter it in a book?</p>
               <p>Sutton. Yes, always.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you recollect you omitted entering one of this sort?</p>
               <p>Sutton. We always enter them down in two books.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain you enter them?</p>
               <p>Sutton. I am very certain of that.</p>
               <p>Q. Is there any entry made of this bill</p>
               <p>Sutton. No, there is not, I am very certain of that.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do the indorsers live?</p>
               <p>Sutton. They live at Leicester; I was with them both; they are Pitts, Ward, and 
               <persName id="t17611021-33-person404">
                  Charles 
                  Whiteman 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person404" type="surname" value="Whiteman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person404" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person404" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-33-person405">
                  George 
                  Arnold 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person405" type="surname" value="Arnold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person405" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person405" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a waiter at the Amsterdam-coffee-house, behind the Royal Exchange.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of any bill delivered to you, in order to be carried for payment? Look upon the bill in question?</p>
               <p>Arnold. Here is my name, 
               <persName id="t17611021-33-person406">
                  George 
                  Arnold 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person406" type="surname" value="Arnold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person406" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person406" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , upon the back of this, which I wrote; this is the bill; I received the money for it, of a clerk of Mess. Frame and Barclay, bankers, in Lombard-street.</p>
               <p>Q. Of whom did you receive the bill?</p>
               <p>Arnold. I received it of the prisoner at the bar; he directed me at the same time, to carry it, and receive the money.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any particular circumstances attended it? Or were there any particular directions of any sort? Or was there any particular behaviour of the person?</p>
               <p>Arnold. The prisoner came to the Amsterdam coffee-house, about four o'clock in the afternoon, I think on the 20th of December; I was not in the coffee-room, when he came in (my mistress is an antient gentlewoman) I was down in the kitchen; my mistress called me up from dinner, and said, a gentleman wanted me; I went to the table to the prisoner at the bar, he had this bill in his hand; he asked me, if I knew Frome and Barclay's, in Lombard-street; I said, I did not know directly. He began and told me where it was, and said, Will you go and receive this bill for me of 50 l. I said, I had rather you<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176110210065"></xptr> would send some-body else, I do not understand those bills. He said, you will have no difficulty in it, you are only to receive the money, and write your name. I went, and they asked me where I came from, I told them; they paid me the money, and I wrote upon the back of the bill, my name, and Amsterdam coffee-house. I received it all in cash, and came immediately to the coffee-house. As I was coming down the alley. I saw the prisoner at the door, and as soon as I presume he saw me, he advanced to me; he asked me if I had the money, I said yes; we immediately went into the coffee-room, and I delivered the money to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Look upon the prisoner, are you sure you know him?</p>
               <p>Arnold. I am certain the prisoner is the man.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever seen him before?</p>
               <p>Arnold. I had one day before, and know him particularly well.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him after that?</p>
               <p>Arnold. I did, he came to our house afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. How soon after you went and brought him the money?</p>
               <p>Arnold. About six or eight days after, he called me to him, and said, if any person came there, and asked him any questions about the bill, I was to tell them, I received it of a fat, lusty, broad-shoulder'd gentleman. [Note, The prisoner was the reverse.]</p>

               <p>Q. Are you certain to the number of days it was after you paid him the money?</p>
               <p>Arnold. I am not certain, but I believe it was about six or eight days after that.</p>
               <p>Q. What reply did you make him?</p>
               <p>Arnold. I do not recollect that I made him any reply at all; but immediately I went away, having some suspicion it was not right.</p>
               <p>The bill read, to this purport.</p>
               <p>Directed to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17611021-33-person407">
                  John 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person407" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person407" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person407" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Bush-lane Cannon street, London.</p>
               <p>Leicester, 17 Oct. 1760.</p>
               <p>Two months after date, pay Mess. Pitts, Ward, and Co. or order, 50 l. value received, for Mr. Thomas Powser, as advice, by Sir,</p>
               <p>Your Humble Servant, 
               <persName id="t17611021-33-person408">
                  Benj 
                  Sutton 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person408" type="surname" value="Sutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person408" type="given" value="Benj"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person408" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>50 l. 0 s. 0 d. Accepted per 
               <persName id="t17611021-33-person409">
                  John 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person409" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person409" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person409" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>On the back, Mess. Freame and Barclay, pray pay this bill.</p>
               <p>Counsel. This was a direction on the back to the evidence, in order for him to go and carry the bill.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. When was it you saw the prisoner, before he brought the bill to you?</p>
               <p>Arnold. It was the day before he brought the bill, in December last.</p>
               <p>Q. You say, he came about four in the afternoon; were the candles lighted at that time?</p>
               <p>Arnold. I do not say it was absolutely four; I believe we lighted candles soon after he was gone; it was near dusk.</p>
               <p>Counsel. We shall next prove, that Mess. Freame and Barclay, upon the bill being tendered with Mr. Price's acceptance upon it, paid the bill to the person that brought it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-33-person410">
                  Ambrose 
                  Benning 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person410" type="surname" value="Benning"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person410" type="given" value="Ambrose"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person410" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 20th of December, 1760, I paid 50 l. for Mr. Price, on a bill; I cannot take upon me to say, I know the bill; I know I paid nothing else that day upon his credit.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you pay it?</p>
               <p>Benning. I paid it at Freame and Barclay's, I am clerk there; I paid it by the direction of Mr. Price, upon the back of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Does Mr. Price keep cash at your house?</p>
               <p>Benning. He does.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the witness Arnold?</p>
               <p>Benning. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Do not you make a mark upon a bill in order to show who paid it?</p>
               <p>Benning. No, Sir, but I chiefly pay all, if it is in paid money.</p>
               <p>Q. to Arnold. Do you know this witness?</p>
               <p>Arnold. I think I saw him that day, but I cannot take upon me to say who paid me; but some-body did pay me there.</p>
               <p>Q. to Benning. Do you know this man Arnold?</p>
               <p>Benning. I cannot take upon me to swear I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at the back of the bill, see if you know to whom it was paid?</p>
               <p>Benning. I see it is witnessed 
               <persName id="t17611021-33-person411">
                  George 
                  Arnold 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person411" type="surname" value="Arnold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person411" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person411" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , undoubtedly it was paid to 
               <persName id="t17611021-33-person412">
                  George 
                  Arnold 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person412" type="surname" value="Arnold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person412" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person412" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. to Arnold. Look at this note again; who wrote the name 
               <persName id="t17611021-33-person413">
                  George 
                  Arnold 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person413" type="surname" value="Arnold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person413" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person413" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and Amsterdam-coffee-house?</p>
               <p>Arnold. I did, it is my writing.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176110210066"></xptr>Q. from Prisoner to Arnold. What time of the day do you say I came to you with the bill?</p>
               <p>Arnold. I think it was about four o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. What light was there in the alley, that you could distinctly see I was the man; I do declare I never was in your house; consider young man what what you have done, it is upon life and death?</p>
               <p>Arnold. I am certain of the prisoner's person.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was it he came to you, to describe him as a thick person?</p>
               <p>Arnold. I do not remember the time of the day; but I think it was in the afternoon, not late; but I am certain he is the man, I am confident of that; and that he is the man that came afterwards, and desired me to describe him, as a lusty sat man.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. Upon your oath, how long did I stay with you, when I came, as you say, a second time?</p>
               <p>Arnold. I am certain I know the prisoner, I saw him three times in the coffee room, he staid with me out a very little time.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Was I upon m oath now, as I am upon life and death, I can safely swear, I do not know where the Amsterdam coffee-house stands; I never was in it in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. Were there any people in the coffee-room, when you say I was there?</p>
               <p>Arnold. It was not very full of people; there were scarce any gentlemen there at the time.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. You are a good painter, to take people off to swear plumply to me now; and when you came into Newgate to me, you was asked by Mr. Price's clerk, if you knew that person; you look'd at me and said, you thought I was the person; and trembled as if you was afraid of speaking to me, and said, you must swear to me.</p>
               <p>Arnold. I was not afraid, nor had I any occasion to speak to the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. By what means could you distinct, know I was the person, when you had never saw me for 10 months, by you own account.</p>
               <p>Arnold. I saw the prisoner within six or eight days after he delivered me the bill.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. What hour of the day was it, that I came as you say to you a second time?</p>
               <p>Arnold. I cannot particularly say the hour, but I knew then the prisoner was the same person that I delivered the money to.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. Did you pick me out in Newgate, or was I described to you by Mr. Price's clerk?</p>
               <p>Arnold. He was not described to me at all, I knew him as soon as I saw him in Newgate.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. You was five minutes looking at me before you spoke.</p>
               <p>Arnold. Mr. Price's clerk is in court, he can give an account of the matter.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>In the first place, my lord, I should be glad to know my prosecutor. Mr. Price, are you my prosecutor?</p>
               <p>Court. This is a prosecution at the suit of the public, in order to bring to justice every body guilty of these offences; it is immaterial who it is.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Mess. Freame and Barclay being the aggrieved persons, I do not find their names on the bill of indictment.</p>
               <p>Court. The first account in the indictment is laid for publishing a false bill of exchange with intend to defraud 
               <persName id="t17611021-33-person414">
                  John 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person414" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person414" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person414" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The second for publishing an acceptance of John Price, with intention to defraud 
               <persName id="t17611021-33-person415">
                  John 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person415" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person415" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person415" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The third for publishing an acceptance of 
               <persName id="t17611021-33-person416">
                  John 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person416" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person416" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person416" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , with intention to defraud Mess. Freame and Barclay. And the fourth for publishing an order of 
               <persName id="t17611021-33-person417">
                  John 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person417" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person417" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person417" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, with intention to defraud 
               <persName id="t17611021-33-person418">
                  John 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person418" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person418" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person418" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . And the fifth account with intention to defraud Mess. Freame and Barclay.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I should imagine Freame and Barclay were prosecutors, and not or Mr. Price.</p>
               <p>Court. You have made that an objection, which is none at all.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have known Mr. Price, in hurry of business, direct a bill to be paid; and I have asked him two hours afterwards, and he has not recollected he has directed such a bill at all; and if there is Mr. Price's direction on the back of the bill. I should apprehend it is his handwriting, and not mine. May it please your lordship, has there any circumstance appeared yet that I forged the bill?</p>
               <p>Counsel. You are not indicted for that; you are indicted for uttering a bill, knowing it to have been forged.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. In my servi ude to Mr. Price, I paid, I can justly say, three thousand bills of Mr. Price's; so that it is reasonable to suppose I knew Mr. Sutton's hand-writing; but this bill I am ignorant of, it is the 10 l. bill that I am to be tried upon. All of them, for three years past,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176110210067"></xptr> have come without any advice. Such a number of bills coming through his hands, there may be a number of errors. He himself has made errors while I was there, and I have convinced Mr. Sutton of the same. I am of opinion the bills are not forged at all. Mr. Sutton draws 2000 l. in a year, and many have come without advice, by letter. If he would examine into the affair, he would find the errors out. I can plead in behalf of those circumstances my own innocency, and beg the gentlemen will pass an impartial sentence. The bill is my drawing, neither did I utter it. I was a close prisoner from the 3d of December, 1760, in the King's-bench prison, and continued there 'till February.</p>
               <p>Q. to Price. How long had the prisoner lived with you?</p>
               <p>Price. He lived with me four years.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-33-person419">
                  Richard 
                  Hughes 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person419" type="surname" value="Hughes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person419" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person419" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner, I believe, three quarters of a year; I cannot be certain to the time, but I know it is a long time before Christmas.</p>
               <p>Q. How long before?</p>
               <p>Hughes. It may be three or four months before; I have seen him once or twice before he came to the King's-bench; that was some time before Christmas, but I cannot be certain how long.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you a prisoner there?</p>
               <p>Hughes. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a week before Christmas?</p>
               <p>Hughes. If I speak to the best of my knowledge, I really believe it was some time more than a week before; I was a prisoner there twelve months before.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you be positive you knew him there a week before Christmas?</p>
               <p>Hughes. I cannot; I did not know that I should be called upon, otherwise I could have enquired. Upon my oath, to the best of my knowledge, I do think it was a week before Christmas. I cannot take upon me to say positively; I could as well think two weeks as one, but cannot be positive. I think he went away a little before March, and I believe he was a prisoner there full two months.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not you at all apprized of being a witness 'till to-day?</p>
               <p>Hughes. I was not upon my oath.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you know you was to be a witness?</p>

               <p>Hughes. Never, 'till the prisoner now called upon me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you never with him in prison?</p>
               <p>Hughes. I was two or three times.</p>
               <p>Q. How long ago?</p>
               <p>Hughes. Two or three months ago; I called with a friend or two to drink a glass of wine with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he a prisoner within the walls, or not?</p>
               <p>Hughes. To the best of my knowledge he was a prisoner within the walls.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you the rules?</p>
               <p>Hughes. I had.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he the rules, or not?</p>
               <p>Hughes. I think he had not; I was then very intimate with him, and was often, and frequently, with him.</p>
               <p>Q. How comes it you cannot with certainty tell whether he had the rules or not?</p>
               <p>Hughes. We that were in prison had some sort of indulgence from the marshal to go out, and see a friend or so..</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner in execution?</p>
               <p>Hughes. I cannot take upon me to say he was; I saw him within the walls often, and frequently he lodged with Mr. Champion, who is there now; he is a bankrupt, and cannot be discharged.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he never desired you to recollect yourself, to remember when you saw him in the King's-bench?</p>
               <p>Hughes. Upon my oath never; he never proposed any such thing to me in his life.</p>
               <p>Jos. 
               <persName id="t17611021-33-person420">
                  George 
                  Holeman 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person420" type="surname" value="Holeman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person420" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person420" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am positive I saw the prisoner in the King's-bench before Christmas last.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you a prisoner there?</p>
               <p>Holeman. No, I went as an acquaintance, to see Mr. Lee; I saw him before Christmas, and after Christmas, and between whiles, and never saw him out.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-33-person421">
                  Richard 
                  Elstone 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person421" type="surname" value="Elstone"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person421" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person421" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I did not come here to give the man a character, only I have a prisoner here. He was an inside prisoner at the King's-bench; he was there about last Christmas; I cannot take upon me to say what time; I remember the man.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you take upon you to say it was before last Christmas?</p>
               <p>Elstone. I cannot, I know it was about that time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-33-person422">
                  Thomas 
                  Philips 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person422" type="surname" value="Philips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person422" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person422" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the prisoner by being a prisoner in the King's-bench in December last.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176110210068"></xptr>Q. What time in December?</p>
               <p>Philips. I cannot take upon me to say what time in particular; I know he was there in the middle of December, it was extream cold weather.</p>
               <p>Q. What time in December?</p>
               <p>Philips. I believe it might be, perhaps, the 10th of December.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he a close prisoner within the Bench?</p>
               <p>Philips. He was.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he continue there?</p>
               <p>Philips. I cannot take upon me to say how long; I cannot take upon me to say the day of the month in particular; I know I saw him after Christmas a close prisoner within the walls.</p>
               <p>Q. to Elstone. Are the prisoners ever allowed to go out of prison?</p>

               <p>Elstone. No, not unless in term-time, the turnkey would let them out into the rules.</p>
               <p>Q. Will they let them go out of the rules?</p>
               <p>Elstone. No, not unless it be term-time; but I cannot take upon me to say what is done there; I only go over with a prisoner, and deliver him there.</p>
               <p>Q. Are the prisoners within the walls by the marshal permitted to go out into the rules?</p>
               <p>Elstone. That is to take a walk for an airing; I have known a prisoner taken out, and a bond has been given for him on the Sunday; I have been with them, but then they have been taken no farther than the rules; if I do, I am fixed with the debt.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether the marshal lets them go out of the walls of the goal into the rules?</p>
               <p>Elstone. No, I told you the turnkey does it, but not with the consent of the marshal.</p>
               <p>Q. The question is plain, Whether the prisoners are suffered to go out of the King's-bench into the rules?</p>
               <p>Elstone. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen it done?</p>
               <p>Elstone. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. What to let the prisoners out upon their request?</p>
               <p>Elstone. I think I have seen them let out, but upon what account I cannot say.</p>
               <p>Q. If a man is suffered to go out into the rules, has he not an opportunity to go over the bridge to Lombard-street?</p>
               <p>Elstone. It is possible.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-33-person423">
                  John 
                  Brooks 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person423" type="surname" value="Brooks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person423" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person423" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner at the bar from an infant; I was born at Spalding, a neighbour of his father's, and knew him 'till he was 13 or fourteen years old there. He was as sober and well-behaved a youth, as any lad in town, and his father brought him up with the greatest virtue. I have known him since he lived with Mr. Price, I never was there, I have met him in the street.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Brooks. '
               <persName id="t17611021-33-person424">
                  Till
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person424" type="given" value="Till"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person424" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             this time his character has been as good as any youth in London.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-33-person425">
                  William 
                  Allen 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person425" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person425" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person425" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about ten or a dozen years, he has a very good character; he has been at my house, and lived there with me; was he to be discharged, I would employ him again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-33-person426">
                  John 
                  Earle 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person426" type="surname" value="Earle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person426" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person426" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about three years, and never knew any thing amiss of him 'till this affair.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-33-person427">
                  William 
                  James 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person427" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person427" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person427" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him ever since he was a child, and his family an honest reputeable family; I never knew any harm of him, nor heard any before this.</p>
               <p>For the crown.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-33-person428">
                  Richard 
                  Absolom 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person428" type="surname" value="Absolom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person428" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person428" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the prisoner at the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this paper, is this your handwriting? [He takes it in his hand.]</p>
               <p>Absolom. Yes, it is.</p>
               <p>Q. Look on the other side of it, did you ever see the prisoner, where, and when?</p>
               <p>Absolom. He came to me at the Cock-alehouse, at the corner of Sherborne-lane, on the 20th of December, and delivered this note into my hand.</p>
               <p>Counsel. This is a 10 l. bill.</p>
               <p>Q. Why do you know it was the 20th of December?</p>
               <p>Absolom. Because when I go upon these affairs, I generally make a memorandum; this was to receive some money of Mr. 
               <persName id="t17611021-33-person429">
                  John 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17611021-33-person429" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person429" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-person429" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , for him, and I received it in the name of one Welden; the prisoner at the bar ordered me to go, and receive it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17611021-33-verdict172" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-verdict172" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17611021-33-punish173" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611021-33-punish173" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-33-defend391 t17611021-33-punish173"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
