<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660702-11">
               <interp inst="t17660702-11" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660702-11" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660702-11" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660702"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660702-11" type="date" value="17660702"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660702-11-off59-c99" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-11-defend120 t17660702-11-off59 t17660702-11-verdict61"></join>
         
               <p>343. (L) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660702-11-defend120" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Robinson 
                  <interp inst="t17660702-11-defend120" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-11-defend120" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-11-defend120" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17660702-11-off59" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660702-11-off59" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-11-off59" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 26 yards of silk and stuff, two pair of leather boots, six yards of worsted stuff called cloth, one pair of leather breeches, a cloth coat, four pair of leather shoes, 12 yards of linen cloth, a cotton handkerchief, a brass saucepan, two copper tea-kettles, and 120 copper half-pence
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17660702-11-victim122" type="victimName">
                     James 
                     Alefounder 
                  <interp inst="t17660702-11-victim122" type="surname" value="Alefounder"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-11-victim122" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-11-victim122" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-11-off59 t17660702-11-victim122"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17660702-11-cd60" type="crimeDate">May 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-11-off59 t17660702-11-cd60"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-11-person123">
                  James 
                  Alefounder 
               <interp inst="t17660702-11-person123" type="surname" value="Alefounder"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-11-person123" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-11-person123" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 21st of May, about nine at night, my house was on fire; we removed what goods we could. The next day I had an information given, that the prisoner had got some of my goods in his house; I went with Mr. Parker to demand my goods; the prisoner told me, he would be paid for his trouble in fetching them away; I saw several things lying on the ground, breeches and other things under the bed; I found a heap of things done up in a handkerchief.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this conversation before you searched the house or after?</p>
               <p>Alefounder. It was before; he took up a chair to knock me down; there was a piece of silk and stuff lay between the bolster and the bed, about 26 yards of it; I had sent Parker for them before, but the prisoner would not let him have them. I asked the prisoner his reason for not letting the fireman have them; he said he would be paid for them, before they should go out of his house. I told him, I did not think he took them with an intent to let me have them again, as he did not let me know any thing of them, and he living but a little way from me; he said, here are all I have, meaning the things on the floor: then I searched, and found the other things; then I took him before the sitting Alderman. We searched his house three times, and every time we found things in different places; after he was committed, we searched, and found a pair of leather breeches, a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176607020009"></xptr> cloth coat, two yards and a half of muslin, three pair of shoes, a new handkerchief, a copper sauce-pan, and two tea kettles; these were found at the second and third search.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to search a third time?</p>
               <p>Alefounder. There had been seen from the next yard a gown belonging to my maid, and a pair of breeches, which made me search again. (The goods produced.)</p>
               <p>Q. Can you swear to either of the things?</p>
               <p>Alefounder. I can swear to the greatest part of them, as being in my house when the fire was.</p>
               <p>Q. Mention what you can swear to?</p>
               <p>Alefounder. The silk and stuff, the coat, the shoes and handkerchief; I do not think there is a thing among them but what I could very safely swear to.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Alefounder. He is a weaver; he has used my shop for twelve months.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-11-person124">
                  Thomas 
                  Parker 
               <interp inst="t17660702-11-person124" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-11-person124" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-11-person124" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 22d of May we were at Mr. Alefounder's house, and going about the neighbourhood, to get the things in again that the London Insurance porters had information of. We had information there were some things at the prisoner's; our foreman bid me go with my bag for them; I went, and told the prisoner I was come for the things; he said he should be paid for his time, before the things should be taken away. I told it Mr. Alefounder; he came; still the prisoner was obstinate, and would not let us have them; he took up a chair to strike at one or two of us; we took up what we saw, and put them in my bag; he said that was all. We went afterwards, and found the several things concealed in different places; there was a piece of green stuff under the bed; after that, the next door neighbour said there was something we had missed; we looked over the rails, and there was a gown and a pair of breeches; and when we came to look for them at his house they were gone, but we found them in a closet; the man was in prison then.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-11-person125">
                  Edward 
                  Maylin 
               <interp inst="t17660702-11-person125" type="surname" value="Maylin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-11-person125" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-11-person125" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the finding the several things, some under rubbish, some under the bed.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I had no goods but what I was willing to give up, when Mr. Alefounder himself came.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-11-person126">
                  Thomas 
                  Casey 
               <interp inst="t17660702-11-person126" type="surname" value="Casey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-11-person126" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-11-person126" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner above sixteen years; he bears an exceeding good character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-11-person127">
                  James 
                  Kingston 
               <interp inst="t17660702-11-person127" type="surname" value="Kingston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-11-person127" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-11-person127" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Widegate-alley, Spital-fields; I am a master weaver, the prisoner is a journeyman; I have known him between seventeen and eighteen years; he is a very honest hard-working man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660702-11-verdict61" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660702-11-verdict61" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
