<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17631207-18">
               <interp inst="t17631207-18" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-18" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-18" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17631207"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-18" type="date" value="17631207"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17631207-18-off94-c133" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-18-defend171 t17631207-18-off94 t17631207-18-verdict99"></join>
         
               <p>20. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17631207-18-defend171" type="defendantName">
                     Edward 
                     Bracken 
                  <interp inst="t17631207-18-defend171" type="surname" value="Bracken"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-18-defend171" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-18-defend171" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17631207-18-off94" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631207-18-off94" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-18-off94" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 14 lb. weight of sheep fat, value 2 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17631207-18-victim173" type="victimName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Barr 
                  <interp inst="t17631207-18-victim173" type="surname" value="Barr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-18-victim173" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-18-victim173" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-18-off94 t17631207-18-victim173"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            . <rs id="t17631207-18-viclabel95" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-18-victim173 t17631207-18-viclabel95"></join>, <rs id="t17631207-18-cd96" type="crimeDate">Nov. 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-18-off94 t17631207-18-cd96"></join> *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-18-person174">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Barr 
               <interp inst="t17631207-18-person174" type="surname" value="Barr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-18-person174" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-18-person174" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17631207-18-crimeloc97">Tottenham</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17631207-18-crimeloc97" type="placeName" value="Tottenham"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17631207-18-crimeloc97" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-18-off94 t17631207-18-crimeloc97"></join> parish, and am a <rs id="t17631207-18-viclabel98" type="occupation">farmer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-18-victim173 t17631207-18-viclabel98"></join>. On Monday was three weeks, I had a sheep in lamb found dead and part of it taken away. There being some sheep fat advertised on the Tuesday, I went as it directed, on the Wednesday, to the house of Mr. Blandford, in Featherstone-street. Bunhill-row; there I found some fat, but cannot say it was mine.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-18-person175">
                  Edward 
                  Argell 
               <interp inst="t17631207-18-person175" type="surname" value="Argell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-18-person175" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-18-person175" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mrs. Barr. I found a sheep dead on Monday the 14th of Nov. between 3 and 4 in the afternoon, in our field; it was my mistress's property; I carried what was left of it home; it was so far skinned, as to take the hind part away with the fat; the fore part and the whole skin was left: it was not a very fat sheep.</p>
               <p>Q. Did it seem to have been fresh killed?</p>
               <p>Argell. It might hav e been killed a day, it was cold.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you seen it before?</p>
               <p>Argell. I saw it on the Thursday before; there were 15 of them in all, the rest were all there.</p>
               <p>Job Blandford. I live in Featherstone street, and keep a tallow-chandler's shop. On the Tuesday morning, about 10 o'clock, the 15th of Nov. the prisoner came into my shop, with a bag in his hand, and asked me if I bought suet?</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know him before?</p>
               <p>Blandford. I never saw him before, to my knowledge; he put his bag on the counter, and shewed it me. I said, what is the price? he said, two pence half-penny a pound; he asked under the market price. It appeared to me to be the contents of the inside of a sheep, the caul-fat, the gut-fat, and kidney-fat. I saw some appearance of grass amongst it; I suspected it was stolen out of a grass field. It was not a very fat sheep; the kidneys were particularly thin in the fat.</p>
               <p>Q. What was fat worth at that time?</p>
               <p>Blandford. It was worth something more than 3 d. a pound. I asked him, how he came by it? he first mentioned some gentleman's name that lived on the farther side of Islington, that he brought it from there. I asked him. how he came to bring such fat as that from a gentleman's house? In 5 minutes time he said, he and another man bought it between them, to fell to get some soap. After that he said he bought it of a man in Islington Road. When I found he varied so much, and he was gathering his bag up in order to carry it somewhere else, I having a servant in my cellar, I said, I can't see that I can well weigh it in these scales; I made as if I would go for some scales, and call'd my man up, and got a constable, and took him and the fat to Hick's-hall to the Justices: there he stood to it, that he bought it of a man in Islington Road, and offered to send for somebody to his character, but he declin'd that.</p>
               <p>Q. How much fat was there?</p>
               <p>Blandford. There was 14 pounds and a half, bag and all; and I weigh'd the bag afterwards, and that weigh'd a pound and an half.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was going to Islington to look for some work. a man met me, and ask'd me if I would buy some<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176312070017"></xptr> sat, saying, he would sell it cheap; so I bought it.</p>
               <p>To his Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-18-person176">
                  Anne 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17631207-18-person176" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-18-person176" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-18-person176" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Holborn; my husband is a taylor. The prisoner did belong to the Ambuscade: he used to come to my sister's, who keeps a public house; he lodged and boarded there seven months ago. I never saw any harm by him.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does your sister live?</p>
               <p>A. Price. At the Hare and Hound at Deptford. My brother and sister have his will and power now: they trusted him, and have not received all the money now.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17631207-18-verdict99" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631207-18-verdict99" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
