<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680114-2">
               <interp inst="t17680114-2" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680114-2" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680114-2" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680114"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680114-2" type="date" value="17680114"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680114-2-off19-c46" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-2-defend50 t17680114-2-off19 t17680114-2-verdict24"></join>
         
               <p>103. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17680114-2-defend50" type="defendantName">
                  
                     William 
                     Hamilton 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17680114-2-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-2-defend50 t17680114-2-alias-1"></join>Scolar</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-defend50" type="surname" value="Hamilton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-defend50" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-defend50" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17680114-2-off19" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-off19" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-off19" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               robbing 
                     
                        <persName id="t17680114-2-victim53" type="victimName">
                           John
                            Thomas Du Burg
                        <interp inst="t17680114-2-victim53" type="surname" value="Thomas Du Burg"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680114-2-victim53" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680114-2-victim53" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-2-off19 t17680114-2-victim53"></join>
                     </persName>
                     
                  , <rs id="t17680114-2-viclabel20" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-2-victim53 t17680114-2-viclabel20"></join>; on the King's highway, of a gold watch, value 20 l. a stone seal set in gold, value 20 s. and two guineas, the property of the said Du Burg, against his will
            </rs>, <rs id="t17680114-2-cd21" type="crimeDate">Dec. 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-2-off19 t17680114-2-cd21"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-2-person54">
                  John Thomas
                   Du Burg
               <interp inst="t17680114-2-person54" type="surname" value="Du Burg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person54" type="given" value="John Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person54" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Coming to London in a post-chaise on the 24th of December, about five in the afternoon, I was stopt on <placeName id="t17680114-2-crimeloc22">Hounslow-heath</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17680114-2-crimeloc22" type="placeName" value="Hounslow-heath"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17680114-2-crimeloc22" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-2-off19 t17680114-2-crimeloc22"></join>, by a man on horse-back, who presented a pistol and demanded my watch and money; I delivered him my watch, it was a gold repeater; there was a stone seal set in gold, a steel chain, and two guineas: he had a great coat on, I think, of a blue colour, it was in the dusk of the evening; I cannot take upon myself to swear to the prisoner; I came immediately to London with the same horses, and went to Sir 
               <persName id="t17680114-2-person55">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17680114-2-person55" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person55" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person55" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and told him the same I have here, describing the watch and seal to be advertised; this was on the Thursday, and I received a letter from Sir John in the country, that my watch was stopt; I came up on the Monday, and went to Sir John; my watch was produced by a pawnbroker. On the Wednesday following, the seal and chain were also produced by the constable, (produced in court;) as there may be many such steel chains, I do not swear to that; the watch and seal are my property.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-2-person56">
                  Richard 
                  Sweet 
               <interp inst="t17680114-2-person56" type="surname" value="Sweet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person56" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person56" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to the prosecutor; I was in the post-chaise with him when he was robbed on Hounslow-heath; the first I saw was a pistol presented to the post-boy, in order to stop, which he immediately did; then the man came to the chaise on my master's side, and presented the pistol to the glass; I could not understand what he said; master let down the glass; then I heard the man ask him for his money; he immediately gave it him in a purse.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I delivered my money in my purse.</p>
               <p>Sweet. Then he asked me for my money; my master told him I was only a servant; the man said, he did not care what I was, he insisted on having my money if I had any; I made no answer; then he asked my master for his watch; master said he had a watch, but it was a very particular one; the man said, it is no matter how<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176801140005"></xptr> particular; master delivered it to him; then he lode off.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he dressed?</p>
               <p>Sweet. I believe he had on a blue great coat; he appeared to be a young man, of a very fresh complexion; (such was the prisoner;) I was before Sir 
               <persName id="t17680114-2-person57">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17680114-2-person57" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person57" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person57" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             when the prisoner was examined, and the watch produced, which my master swore to; I cannot take upon me to say the prisoner is the man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-2-person58">
                  William 
                  Masters 
               <interp inst="t17680114-2-person58" type="surname" value="Masters"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person58" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a pawnbroker, and live at the corner of the Bull and Gate Holbourn; some time on the 26th of December, we received a hand bill from Sir 
               <persName id="t17680114-2-person59">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17680114-2-person59" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person59" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , describing this watch to have been stolen by a single highwayman on the 24th, with a reward of ten guineas over and above the reward allowed by act of parliament; between four and five that afternoon my apprentice came to me in the parlour, and brought me this watch and the hand-bill, and told me the young man was in the shop that brought the watch; I observed the dial-plate answered to the bill, with gold hours and gold hands; by looking it through I found it answered; he said the man wanted ten guineas upon it; I said, do you go to the door, and I will get a gentleman to stand by you, that he does not get away, till I go and fetch a coach; I went and had a coach come; I went to the prisoner, and asked him how he came by this watch; his answer was, I know how I came by it; I said, here is an advertisement, this watch was taken upon the highway on Christmaseve; he again said, I know how I came by it, that was all he said; I said, I must insist upon your going before Sir 
               <persName id="t17680114-2-person60">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17680114-2-person60" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person60" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person60" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I took him in the coach there; Sir John found it was the same watch as advertised, and sent a letter to the prosecutor; the prisoner was committed till the Wednesday for farther examination: my apprentice having said, he was the same man that had called at my house on horseback, Sir John asked him how long it was ago since he was on horseback, and asked him if he had not boots and spurs; he said he had not been on horseback since he came from Scotland, and that he had not had boots, spurs, or a whip, for about seven years. On the Wednesday following he was examined, the prosecutor was there; he said the watch was his property, and he thought by the size of the prisoner, he was the man that robbed him; the servant was there, he said he was pretty sure he was the man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-2-person61">
                  John 
                  Brooks 
               <interp inst="t17680114-2-person61" type="surname" value="Brooks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person61" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person61" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Masters; the hand-bill came from Sir 
               <persName id="t17680114-2-person62">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17680114-2-person62" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person62" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person62" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's on the 26th of December; I saw it in the shop between three and four, and the prisoner-came in the evening after the was come; he told me he wanted ten guineas upon this watch, and delivered it to me; I ask'd him whose it was; he said it was his father's; I seeing it answered the description in the handbill, I took that and the bill into the parlour to my master, and told him a young man had brought it, and wanted ten guineas upon it. Master desired me to see that he did not get out at the door, and he went and fetched a coach, and took the prisoner/ to Sir 
               <persName id="t17680114-2-person63">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17680114-2-person63" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person63" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person63" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was sent for; Sir John ask'd me if I had ever seen the prisoner on horse back; I said yes, he had come to my master's door on horseback; I saw him get off, and I held his horse while he came into our shop, that was about a fortnight before, he had boots on; he then took a shirt out of pawn, he once had a pair of boots, a whip, a hat, and a pair of iron plated spurs, at our house; I took them in about the 13th of September; I lent him half a guinea upon them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-2-person64">
                  John 
                  Noaks 
               <interp inst="t17680114-2-person64" type="surname" value="Noaks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person64" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person64" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable; I was sent for to take the prisoner in custody at Sir 
               <persName id="t17680114-2-person65">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17680114-2-person65" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person65" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person65" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, he had been examined before I came. I took him in a coach to New-Prison; he desired we would leave a message for him in Exchange-court by Exeter-exchange, for one Mrs. Street; after we had carried him to goal, Mr. Marsden and I went there, we brought that woman to Sir John, who examined her, to know what time she had seen the prisoner; she said she had not seen him for a fortnight; on the Monday following we had information the prisoner had a lodging in the Fleet-lane; Sir John desired Mr. Marsden and I would go there to search; we went to the house, and asked for his lodging room; we were shewed it; we asked which was his box; the landlady shewed us one which she said was his; she got a man to break it open, in it we found some slugs and slints; then we went to New Prison, and there found the woman who lived in the room with him; we took her in a coach to Sir John; we asked her concerning the pistol; she owned she had the key in her pocket, and she would go with me and shew me where she had put it; she went to a vault joining to the house, and bid me put my hand into a hole, and said, take care, for it is loaded; there I found this pocket-pistol, (produced in court.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-2-person66">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Street 
               <interp inst="t17680114-2-person66" type="surname" value="Street"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person66" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person66" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I found this seal in 
               <persName id="t17680114-2-person67">
                  Sarah 
                  Middleton 
               <interp inst="t17680114-2-person67" type="surname" value="Middleton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person67" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person67" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's box; (produced and deposed to by prosecutor.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-2-person68">
                  Sarah 
                  Middleton 
               <interp inst="t17680114-2-person68" type="surname" value="Middleton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person68" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person68" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner went out of my room on Saturday morning, the day he was taken up, to scate on the ice; he came back again, and told me he had found a watch, it had a steel<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176801140006"></xptr> chain; I saw him take the seal off, he put the seal in my box, and took the watch out with him. I never saw him till I had a note brought by Mrs. Street, for me to come to him in New Prison; my box was broke open on the Sunday morning, and in that was found a pistol, but I never saw him have a pistol in his possession; I do not know who put it into my box.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I went out on the 26th of December with my scates, to see if the ice would bear in Hyde Park; I staid and scated about an hour; coming down the road that leads to Kensington, I saw the seal of this watch lying, the watch was covered with dirt, about the middle of the road; I picked it up, and found the watch at the end of it; I brought it to my lodging, and told Mrs. Middleton I had found a watch; after dinner I went out again, and happened to be a little distressed for money, I went to pledge it, and was stopped with it; I told Sir 
               <persName id="t17680114-2-person69">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17680114-2-person69" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person69" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person69" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I had found the watch.</p>
               <p>Mr. Marsden. He did say at Sir 
               <persName id="t17680114-2-person70">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17680114-2-person70" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person70" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-person70" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's that he found it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was at home with Mrs. Middleton, she and I were at home alone on Christmas-eve.</p>
               <p>Q. to Middleton. Where was you on Christmaseve?</p>
               <p>S. Middleton. I was at home, and the prisoner was with me at my lodgings; he went out in the evening, I cannot tell the exact time.</p>
               <p>Guilty. <rs id="t17680114-2-punish23" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-punish23" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-2-defend50 t17680114-2-punish23"></join>
               Death
            </rs>. <rs id="t17680114-2-verdict24" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-verdict24" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-2-verdict24" type="verdictSubcategory" value="withRecommendation"></interp>
               Recommended by jury and prosecutor
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
