<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650710-7">
               <interp inst="t17650710-7" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650710-7" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650710-7" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650710"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650710-7" type="date" value="17650710"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650710-7-off30-c64" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650710-7-defend76 t17650710-7-off30 t17650710-7-verdict33"></join>
         
               <p>349. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17650710-7-defend76" type="defendantName">
                     Jane 
                     Jostlin 
                  <interp inst="t17650710-7-defend76" type="surname" value="Jostlin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-7-defend76" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-7-defend76" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17650710-7-deflabel29" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650710-7-defend76 t17650710-7-deflabel29"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17650710-7-off30" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650710-7-off30" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-7-off30" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing two linen sheets, value 5 s. two pillows, value 2 s. two pillow-cases, value 2 s. six linen towels value 6 s. two linen napkins, value 2 s. and one quilt, value 10 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17650710-7-victim78" type="victimName">
                     Ann 
                     Waite 
                  <interp inst="t17650710-7-victim78" type="surname" value="Waite"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-7-victim78" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-7-victim78" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650710-7-off30 t17650710-7-victim78"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17650710-7-viclabel31" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650710-7-victim78 t17650710-7-viclabel31"></join>, <rs id="t17650710-7-cd32" type="crimeDate">June 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650710-7-off30 t17650710-7-cd32"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650710-7-person79">
                  William 
                  Waite 
               <interp inst="t17650710-7-person79" type="surname" value="Waite"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-7-person79" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-7-person79" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . At the time the fire was at Wapping, on the 22d of June, I saw the prisoner<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176507100005"></xptr> at our house; Mrs. 
               <persName id="t17650710-7-person80">
                  Ann 
                  Waite 
               <interp inst="t17650710-7-person80" type="surname" value="Waite"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-7-person80" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-7-person80" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is my mother; the prisoner had no business there at all: I bid her go out, and forewarned her from taking any thing with her: the fire began about 11 at night: we were told the next morning, that the prisoner had been offering things to pledge; the fire was on a Saturday, and we took her upon the Monday following. I heard her acknowledge she took a parcel of things in a sheet, and pitched them in the alley, and after that got assistance to carry them to her house: upon taxing her, she took the officer and I to Rag-fair, to a house where she had offered the quilt to sale, and they stop'd it: she asked for it, and the people produced it: she had pawned a pair of sheets at one Jones's, in Old Gravel-lane, for five shillings: he at first denied having them, but when he found we should search, he produced them. (The quilt and streets produced and deposed to.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650710-7-person81">
                  Jane 
                  Ross 
               <interp inst="t17650710-7-person81" type="surname" value="Ross"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-7-person81" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-7-person81" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mrs. Waite: the quilt and sheets are the property of my mistress. I did not see the prisoner at our house, at the time of the fire, to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. They have changed the sheets.</p>
               <p>Job Jones. I am a pawnbroker; I have known the prisoner almost twenty years; I never heard a dishonest thing of her before this. She brought me a pair of sheets on the 24th of June, in the morning: when the officer came for the sheets, they carried them to the bench of Justices, at Whitechapel: neither the maid nor the master could find any marks on them: these have a mark, they are not the same.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650710-7-person82">
                  William 
                  Waite 
               <interp inst="t17650710-7-person82" type="surname" value="Waite"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-7-person82" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-7-person82" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . After the fire we did not know where to find things to supply the beds; and we made use of the sheets; I do imagine these are no t the same; I believe the others were finer than these: the prisoner said she pawned them to this man for five shillings, and he owns he lent her five shillings on them.</p>
               <p>Q. to Jones. What did you do with the sheets the prisoner pledged with you?</p>
               <p>Jones. I delivered them to Mr. Knight, the officer, and Mr. Waite.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650710-7-person83">
                  Jane 
                  Ross 
               <interp inst="t17650710-7-person83" type="surname" value="Ross"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-7-person83" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-7-person83" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I do imagine the other sheets were finer than these; we having a deal of company, made use of them; and I believe these are not the same.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650710-7-person84">
                  Edward 
                  Knight 
               <interp inst="t17650710-7-person84" type="surname" value="Knight"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-7-person84" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-7-person84" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had a search-warrant delivered to me by Mr. Waite, and another, to take the prisoner: when I took her in custody, I could get no hearing that night; I said, if she would sit quiet, she should stay in my house till 11 o'clock, I keeping a public-house: after she had been at my house about two hours, I desired her to tell the truth; she desired Mrs. Waite might be sent for; she came: the prisoner said she would inform her where the things were; after which I went home with her to her own house; in searching there, we found the pillows and pillow-cases, and some towels; and she told us there was a pair of sheets she had pawned at Mr. Jones's, for five shillings: I went to Mr. Jones's, and there they were found; he said he lent her five shillings on them: when we came back again the prisoner owned she had taken a sattin quilt to Rag-fair, and it was stopt. I went, by her directions, and was told the prisoner brought it there on the Sunday morning, and asked two shillings for it: they, suspecting her, stop'd it: they delivered it; here it is.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>The maid met me on the threshold of the door, and put the things on my head, and bid me carry them to my house, and take care of them: I kept them there some time.</p>
               <p>Q. to Ross. Did you deliver the things to the prisoner?</p>
               <p>J. Ross. No, I did not; I tied up the things, but directed every body to carry what I delivered to Mr. Arnold's.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17650710-7-verdict33" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650710-7-verdict33" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17650710-7-punish34" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650710-7-punish34" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650710-7-defend76 t17650710-7-punish34"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
