<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17661217-33">
               <interp inst="t17661217-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-33" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17661217"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-33" type="date" value="17661217"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17661217-33-off172-c259" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-33-defend334 t17661217-33-off172 t17661217-33-verdict176"></join>
         
               <p>42. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17661217-33-defend334" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Thornhill 
                  <interp inst="t17661217-33-defend334" type="surname" value="Thornhill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-33-defend334" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-33-defend334" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17661217-33-off172" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-33-off172" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-33-off172" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               forging a bill of exchange, purporting to be signed by 
                     <persName id="t17661217-33-person335">
                        John 
                        Johnson 
                     <interp inst="t17661217-33-person335" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17661217-33-person335" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17661217-33-person335" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , captain of the 24th regiment of foot; directed to Mr. Matthias, for the payment of 20 l. and publishing the same with intent to defraud 
                     <persName id="t17661217-33-victim336" type="victimName">
                        <rs id="t17661217-33-viclabel173" type="occupation">Mr.</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-33-victim336 t17661217-33-viclabel173"></join> Matthias<interp inst="t17661217-33-victim336" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , and also with intent to defraud 
                     
                        <persName id="t17661217-33-victim338" type="victimName">
                           George 
                           Coote 
                        <interp inst="t17661217-33-victim338" type="surname" value="Coote"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17661217-33-victim338" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17661217-33-victim338" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17661217-33-viclabel174" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-33-victim338 t17661217-33-viclabel174"></join>
               
                  </rs>; <rs id="t17661217-33-cd175" type="crimeDate">May 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-33-off172 t17661217-33-cd175"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-33-person339">
                  Joseph 
                  Cox 
               <interp inst="t17661217-33-person339" type="surname" value="Cox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-33-person339" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-33-person339" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Coleman, a breeches-maker at Charing-cross; the prisoner at the bar came to my master's house last Whitsun Monday; he produced a note, and desired me to carry it to Mr. Matthias.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say you was to do with it?</p>
               <p>Cox. He did not say what.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say you was to receive any money?</p>
               <p>Cox. No, he did not; I asked him if I must leave it with him or his clerk; he said if my master was here, I should know what to do in a minute; I carried it to Mr. Matthias, and told him I received it of a person whom I knew; Mr. Matthias bid me call again, I left it; when I came back to my master the prisoner was gone, this was about twelve o'clock; the prisoner called about four, and asked what Mr. Matthias said; I told him Mr. Matthias said, what I carried was not good, he did not know the person's handwriting; the prisoner desired me to be sure to go again for the bill, I thought to see my master first; when my master came home I told him, he advised me not to trouble myself about it.</p>
               <p>Q. Should you know the note again?</p>
               <p>Cox. I cannot be positive, I know there was something of 20 l. upon it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-33-person340">
                  Thomas 
                  Coleman 
               <interp inst="t17661217-33-person340" type="surname" value="Coleman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-33-person340" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-33-person340" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am master to 
               <persName id="t17661217-33-person341">
                  Joseph 
                  Cox 
               <interp inst="t17661217-33-person341" type="surname" value="Cox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-33-person341" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-33-person341" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I received a note from Mr. Thornhill about Whitsun holidays.</p>
               <p>Mr. Lane. I saw the prisoner write a note of hand once.</p>
               <p>Court. Look upon this note. (he takes it in his hand.)</p>
               <p>Lane. The whole of this is the prisoner's handwriting; here is my mark upon it, I saw the prisoner write the note.</p>
               <p>Court. Look at this bill (the bill in question.)</p>
               <p>Lane. (He takes it in his hand, and compares them together;) the words sterling are remarkably alike; to be sure, the writing is very much alike; I firmly believe this bill to be his hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Mr. Merrick. I know Capt. Johnson of the 24th regiment, I have been many years acquainted with him, I have seen him write.</p>
               <p>Court. Look upon this bill (he takes it in his hand.)</p>
               <p>Merrick. I think this is not the hand-writing of Capt. Johnson.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was Capt. Johnson last April?</p>
               <p>Merrick. He was in Gibraltar, but he is now in court.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-33-person342">
                  David 
                  Roberts 
               <interp inst="t17661217-33-person342" type="surname" value="Roberts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-33-person342" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-33-person342" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I think Capt. Johnson was in Gibraltar last April, I know the regiment was there then.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you acquainted with his hand-writing?</p>
               <p>Roberts. I am.</p>
               <p>Court. Look at this bill (he takes it in his hand.)</p>
               <p>Roberts. This is nothing at all like his handwriting.</p>
               <p>Mr. Matthias. I remember 
               <persName id="t17661217-33-person343">
                  Joseph 
                  Cox 
               <interp inst="t17661217-33-person343" type="surname" value="Cox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-33-person343" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-33-person343" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             coming to my house with a bill on Whitsun Monday the 19th of May; this is it, (holding it in his hand) he brought it to me for acceptance; I was not satisfied with the hand-writing, I told him I would keep the bill for his and my safety, for it was not Capt. Johnson's hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he bring it for acceptance?</p>
               <p>Matthias. I think he mentioned the word acceptance to me.</p>
               <p>Q. to Cox. Do you recollect that?</p>
               <p>Cox. I carried the same message to Mr. Matthias that Mr. Thornhill ordered me, but I cannot recollect it now.</p>
               <p>Q. to Coleman. Have you seen the prisoner write?</p>
               <p>Coleman. I have once.</p>
               <p>Court. Look at this note ( he takes it in his hand.)</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176612170026"></xptr>Coleman. This note I did not receive of Mr. Thornhill, I received it of his servant named Hagathey.</p>
               <p>Hagathey. I delivered that to Mr. Coleman.</p>
               <p>It is read in court, to this purport.</p>
               <p>"Mr. Coleman,</p>
               <p>"I hope you will be good enough to enquire</p>
               <p>"about the bill I gave your servant, to take to</p>
               <p>"a gentleman to have passed for 20 l. which if he</p>
               <p>"does not pay, get the bill again; you need</p>
               <p>"not make use of the gentleman's name of</p>
               <p>"whom you got it, as I do it to oblige a gentleman;</p>
               <p>"if you get the money, keep it till I</p>
               <p>"return, which is all you have to do from Mr.</p>
               <p>"Coleman's humble servant,</p>
               <p>W. T."</p>
               <p>The bill read to this purport.</p>
               <p>"Gibraltar, April 12, 1766.</p>
               <p>"Sir,</p>
               <p>"Ten days after date, please to pay George</p>
               <p>"Coote, Esq; or his order, the sum of 20 l. sterling,</p>
               <p>"for value received; which you will place</p>
               <p>"to account of Sir,</p>
               <p>"Your most humble servant,</p>
               <p>"
               <persName id="t17661217-33-person344">
                  John 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17661217-33-person344" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-33-person344" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-33-person344" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ,</p>
               <p>"Captain of the 24th regiment of foot."</p>
               <p>"Directed to Mr. Matthias, Scotland-yard,</p>
               <p>"London.</p>
               <p>Q. to Hagathey. Was you servant to the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Hagathey. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he a public man?</p>
               <p>Hagathey. He went out publicly, at Vaux-hall, and other places; he went to all public places; he was at that time a half-pay officer, as far as I could understand.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever deny your master's lodgings?</p>
               <p>Hagathey. I have to some people, which came after him sometimes with bills for money, and I could not be sure of his lodgings; I was a weekly servant, and never lay in his lodgings; I knew where he was in the day-time, but I did not know where he lay at night times; sometimes he kept company, and was out at horse-races and places with gentlemen.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he ever desired you to deny his lodgings?</p>
               <p>Hagathey. No, only to certain people.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he never bid you to deny him to Mr. Merrick?</p>
               <p>Hagathey. No, I gave Mr. 
               <persName id="t17661217-33-person345">
                  Merrick
               <interp inst="t17661217-33-person345" type="given" value="Merrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-33-person345" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a direction where I thought my master was, in Church-street, St. Anne's. I did not know Mr. Merrick's name then.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you understand his business?</p>
               <p>Hagathey. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I have done all in my power to get my witnesses to shew my innocency, but could not be able to procure them; I advertised them here and in Ireland, but to no purpose, so I leave it to the honourable court.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-33-person346">
                  Andrew 
                  Lee 
               <interp inst="t17661217-33-person346" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-33-person346" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-33-person346" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner lodged with me six weeks from the 21st of March, he behaved well to me as far as ever I saw, in every respect; I had no reason to think him dishonest; he passed for a lieutenant in the army.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17661217-33-verdict176" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-33-verdict176" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17661217-33-punish177" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-33-punish177" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-33-defend334 t17661217-33-punish177"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>There were two other indictments against him of the same nature.</p>
            </div1>
