<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17600416-35">
               <interp inst="t17600416-35" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600416-35" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600416-35" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600416"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600416-35" type="date" value="17600416"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600416-35-off217-c296" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600416-35-defend360 t17600416-35-off217 t17600416-35-verdict220"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600416-35-off219-c296" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600416-35-defend360 t17600416-35-off219 t17600416-35-verdict220"></join>
         
               <p>169. 
               <persName id="t17600416-35-defend360" type="defendantName">
                  Robert 
                  Tilling 
               <interp inst="t17600416-35-defend360" type="surname" value="Tilling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-35-defend360" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-35-defend360" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for that <rs id="t17600416-35-off217" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600416-35-off217" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-35-off217" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               he, on the <rs id="t17600416-35-cd218" type="crimeDate">18th of February</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600416-35-off217 t17600416-35-cd218"></join>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600416-35-off219 t17600416-35-cd218"></join>, about the hour of three in the night of the same day, the dwelling house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17600416-35-victim362" type="victimName">
                           Samuel 
                           Lloyd 
                        <interp inst="t17600416-35-victim362" type="surname" value="Lloyd"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600416-35-victim362" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600416-35-victim362" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600416-35-off217 t17600416-35-victim362"></join>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600416-35-off219 t17600416-35-victim362"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did break and enter, with intention the goods, chattels and money, of the said Samuel, to steal, take, and carry away; he was likewise charged with stealing and carrying away an iron key, a 36 s. piece of gold, a moidore, and ten guineas
            </rs>, the property of the said Samuel; he was likewise charged with <rs id="t17600416-35-off219" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600416-35-off219" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-35-off219" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               breaking the said dwelling house, with intention, feloniously and wilfully, the said 
                     <persName id="t17600416-35-person363">
                        Samuel 
                        Lloyd 
                     <interp inst="t17600416-35-person363" type="surname" value="Lloyd"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600416-35-person363" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600416-35-person363" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   to kill and murder
            </rs>. </p>
               <p>The prisoner <rs id="t17600416-35-verdict220" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600416-35-verdict220" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-35-verdict220" type="verdictSubcategory" value="pleadedGuilty"></interp>
               pleaded guilty
            </rs> to that of the burglary and robbery, and spoke as follows:</p>
               <p>My Lord, I from my first being taken into custody intended to plead guilty. It has been reported since I have been taken up that I am a methodist, and that several masters and mistresses have discharged many such of their servants on my account. I beg leave to acquaint the honourable court that it was not the doctrine which the methodists teach that caused me to commit this robbery - I beg leave to trespass on your patience to speak a few words, as to the character of the young woman that I corresponded with. Notwithstanding my conduct in other respects, my behaviour to her was unexceptionable. I believe her to be a pious, godly young woman, and hope no centures will be cast on her on my account. I have no more to say, but to beg your Lordship's prayers, and those of the jury.</p>
               <p>[There were two other indictments against him for robberies on the highway.]</p>
               <p>Being brought to the bar the last day of the sessions to receive sentence, and asked what he had to say why sentence of death should not be past upon him, he said,</p>
               <p>I recommend myself to the mercy of God and this court, and acknowledge my crime is grievous both in the fight of God and man, for which I willingly give my life a sacrifice to the Lord. I am willing to receive the sentence due to my<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176004160037"></xptr> crimes, and hope the young people in this court will take warning by me, in seeing the dreadful consequence and effects of telling a lye. * I desire the prayers of this honourable court.</p>
               <p>* He had told the young woman, to whom he made his addresses, that he was worth more than he was, and by taking those methods, to make it appear true, he was brought into this dreadful situation.</p>
               <p>N. B. His speech to the populace, and last prayer at the place of execution, were taken in short-hand, and transcribed by the writer of these proceedings, and may be seen in the Ordinary of Newgate's account of the malefactors, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600416-35-punish221" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600416-35-punish221" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600416-35-defend360 t17600416-35-punish221"></join>
               
                     <note>[Death. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
