<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640607-51">
               <interp inst="t17640607-51" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640607-51" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640607-51" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640607"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640607-51" type="date" value="17640607"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640607-51-off289-c317" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-51-defend423 t17640607-51-off289 t17640607-51-verdict292"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640607-51-off289-c318" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-51-defend425 t17640607-51-off289 t17640607-51-verdict292"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640607-51-off289-c319" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-51-defend427 t17640607-51-off289 t17640607-51-verdict292"></join>
         
               <p>375, 376, 377. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17640607-51-defend423" type="defendantName">
                  Demarias 
                  Boswell 
               <interp inst="t17640607-51-defend423" type="surname" value="Boswell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-51-defend423" type="given" value="Demarias"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-51-defend423" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , 
               
                  <persName id="t17640607-51-defend425" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Fraster 
                  <interp inst="t17640607-51-defend425" type="surname" value="Fraster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-51-defend425" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-51-defend425" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17640607-51-defend427" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Moon 
                  <interp inst="t17640607-51-defend427" type="surname" value="Moon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-51-defend427" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-51-defend427" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17640607-51-off289" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640607-51-off289" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-51-off289" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a silver tankard, value 6 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17640607-51-victim429" type="victimName">
                     James 
                     Merry 
                  <interp inst="t17640607-51-victim429" type="surname" value="Merry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-51-victim429" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-51-victim429" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-51-off289 t17640607-51-victim429"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17640607-51-cd290" type="crimeDate">May 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-51-off289 t17640607-51-cd290"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640607-51-person430">
                  James 
                  Merry 
               <interp inst="t17640607-51-person430" type="surname" value="Merry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-51-person430" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-51-person430" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at <placeName id="t17640607-51-crimeloc291">the Bull's Head in Fleet-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640607-51-crimeloc291" type="placeName" value="the Bull's Head in Fleet-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640607-51-crimeloc291" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-51-off289 t17640607-51-crimeloc291"></join>; the three prisoners were in my kitchen on the 18th of May, about 6 in the evening; I did not go into the kitchen; I went and leaned on the bar, and talked to my wife, who was drinking tea with a gentlewoman. A little while after, I saw the three prisoners go out; Boswell had a red cardinal on, and her arms were at some distance from her body, as if she had got something under her cloak: in about three or four minutes after I missed a tankard; a waiter that had lived at my house, said the man's name was 
               <persName id="t17640607-51-person431">
                  Robert 
                  Moon 
               <interp inst="t17640607-51-person431" type="surname" value="Moon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-51-person431" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-51-person431" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; and an officer, upon enquiring, said he knew all the houses Moon frequented: we went to several houses, and at last found him at supper with his wife. He said one of the women's husbands was locked up for 30 s. I went and found her, and told her I had lost a tankard, and asked her to go along with me; she said she would with all her heart; she laid hold of my arm, and walked with me to Covent-Garden round-house. We went the next day before Sir 
               <persName id="t17640607-51-person432">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17640607-51-person432" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-51-person432" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-51-person432" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I told him the affair, and he committed her: there she was for about a week; then she was taken before Mr. Alderman Cockayne; she was admitted to bail. Boswell was in St. Catherine's round-house; Sir John granted a warrant to bring her before him. Moon said before Sir John, I'll neither sleep, eat, nor drink till I see Boswell. He went with the officer, and found her; she was brought before my Lord Mayor, and committed to the Compter. Moon never denied but that it was a silver tankard they drank out of at my house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever find it again?</p>
               <p>Merry. No, I never did. I looked upon Moon to be the honestest of the three.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176406070031"></xptr>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to indict him?</p>
               <p>Merry. Because I was afraid of meeting with trouble from him. he being in company.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you not said you believed him innocent?</p>
               <p>Merry. I may have said so.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there not one of your waiters absented himself upon this?</p>
               <p>Merry. No; he is gone away, but not upon this: he got false keys to my wine-cellar, and is since run away; he was up stairs at the time they went away.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640607-51-person433">
                  Ann 
                  Barber 
               <interp inst="t17640607-51-person433" type="surname" value="Barber"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-51-person433" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-51-person433" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Merry; I remember these three prisoners coming into our house about six o'clock; they went into the kitchen, and drank a tankard of porter; after that they had a quartern of aniseed; a little boy drew their beer; I drank out of the tankard along with them; they staid about half an hour: I was in the kitchen when they went away: they paid my mistress for their porter before they drank it, and they paid me 3 d. for the aniseed.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the tankard when they called for the aniseed?</p>
               <p>A. Barber. The tankard was not upon the table when they called for the aniseed; I did not see it; it was there when I went out for the aniseed, but I did not see it when they went out.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was in the kitchen when you went for the aniseed, besides the prisoners?</p>
               <p>A. Barber. There was my fellow-servant, and one that had been a waiter at our house.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was you gone for the aniseed?</p>
               <p>A. Barber. I was not gone two minutes, I believe.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had they been gone out before you missed the tankard?</p>
               <p>A. Barber. They had not been gone above four minutes.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640607-51-person434">
                  Matthew 
                  Polter 
               <interp inst="t17640607-51-person434" type="surname" value="Polter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-51-person434" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-51-person434" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the kitchen at the Bull's-head tavern in Fleet-street, when the three prisoners came in, and called for a tankard of beer. It was brought them; I sat down to my supper, drinking a pint of beer; they drank to one another; the women stood with their backs toward me, and the man talking and playing with them: they asked this girl to drink; she did; they seemed to be all very merry. By and by they called for a quartern of aniseed; it came in; they drank a glass.</p>
               <p>Q. How long might they be there in the whole?</p>
               <p>Polter. About a quarter of an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you a servant then in the house.</p>
               <p>Polter. No, I was not; I was dismissed from the house, but I was there; I lived there a good many years; I had been over to the barber's: when these people were gone, there was a hue-and-cry after them, the tankard was lost; I saw the tankard; it was a silver one.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you there, as you was dismissed the service?</p>
               <p>Polter. Master gave me leave to lodge there.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be turned away?</p>
               <p>Polter. I had been out a girling, and lay out on nights, and got fuddled.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body come into the kitchen the time they were there?</p>
               <p>Polter. There did come in one 
               <persName id="t17640607-51-person435">
                  Matthew 
                  Reeves 
               <interp inst="t17640607-51-person435" type="surname" value="Reeves"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-51-person435" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-51-person435" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; he is an officer in the Marshal's court; he just stepped in, but did not stay a minute; he did not come a yard into the kitchen.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was Will, the waiter, when they were in the kitchen?</p>
               <p>Polter. He was not in the kitchen when they were there.</p>
               <p>Boswell's Defence.</p>
               <p>I went with these people there, and after that I went home to bed; they came for me, and said the other two were detained, and I must go up to Mr. Fielding's. Mr. Merry said, he wished he had not troubled himself with it, and said, he believed the women were not guilty.</p>
               <p>All three <rs id="t17640607-51-verdict292" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640607-51-verdict292" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
