<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610625-10">
               <interp inst="t17610625-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-10" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610625"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-10" type="date" value="17610625"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610625-10-off52-c77" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-10-defend93 t17610625-10-off52 t17610625-10-verdict55"></join>
         
               <p>187. (M) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610625-10-defend93" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17610625-10-defend93" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-10-defend93" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-10-defend93" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17610625-10-deflabel51" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-10-defend93 t17610625-10-deflabel51"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17610625-10-off52" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610625-10-off52" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-10-off52" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one pair of silver shoe-buckles, value 7 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17610625-10-victim95" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Hastings 
                  <interp inst="t17610625-10-victim95" type="surname" value="Hastings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-10-victim95" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-10-victim95" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-10-off52 t17610625-10-victim95"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17610625-10-cd53" type="crimeDate">June 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-10-off52 t17610625-10-cd53"></join>. *</p>
               <p>William Hastings. I am <rs id="t17610625-10-viclabel54" type="occupation">a chocolate-maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-10-victim95 t17610625-10-viclabel54"></join>, and live in Carnaby-market; I was coming home on Sunday was se'ennight, at night, we walked together.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the night?</p>
               <p>Hastings. Between twelve and one at night, as near as I can guess.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you meet with her?</p>
               <p>Hastings. I met with her in the street.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go into any house?</p>
               <p>Hastings. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know her before?</p>
               <p>Hastings. I never saw her before, as I know of.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you charge her with?</p>
               <p>Hastings. She took my silver buckles out of my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were you then?</p>
               <p>Hastings. This was as we were walking along the street.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you perceive her take them?</p>
               <p>Hastings. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in liquor?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176106250008"></xptr>Hastings. I was a little elevated; but I was sober enough to take care of her, when I missed my buckles, 'till the watchman came up to my assistance.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to miss them?</p>
               <p>Hastings. I happened to put my hand in my pocket, and missed them; but I did not say any thing, 'till the watchman came up; then I charged him with the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. What street was this in?</p>
               <p>Hastings. It was a sort of a bye place.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you not charge her as soon as you missed them?</p>
               <p>Hastings. I was afraid of mischief, so I staid till he came up. She delivered them to the watchman.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her deliver them?</p>
               <p>Hastings. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you deal in silver buckles?</p>
               <p>Hastings. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to have them in your pocket?</p>
               <p>Hastings. I put them there for safety.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you take them out of your shoes, and put them into your pocket?</p>
               <p>Hastings. Yes, I did.</p>
               <p>Q What time did you do that?</p>
               <p>Hastings. After I met with her.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you put your money, in your shoes?</p>
               <p>Hastings. No, I had none.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath, did not you give these buckles to the woman?</p>
               <p>Hastings. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Nor lend them to her.</p>
               <p>Hastings. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not give them to her to pawn for a little money? You said, you had none.</p>
               <p>Hastings. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain you were not together in a house?</p>
               <p>Hastings. No, there was no house open.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you make any attempt to go into a house together?</p>
               <p>Hastings. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Nor no cellar?</p>
               <p>Hastings. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you intend, had there been a house open, to have got some money on your buckles?</p>
               <p>Hastings. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you enquire of the prisoner where she lodged?</p>
               <p>Hastings. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-10-person96">
                  John 
                  Henley 
               <interp inst="t17610625-10-person96" type="surname" value="Henley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-10-person96" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-10-person96" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watchman, I was calling the hour two in Dyot-street, and the prosecutor charged me with the prisoner at the bar, for stealing a pair of silver buckles.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say from where she took them?</p>
               <p>Henley. He said he had put them in his pocket in Compton-street. Said I to her, give me the buckles directly. She gave them me. I would have had him made it easy with the poor creature, and said it would cost him a great deal to prosecute her; but he would not take my advice. Then I gave the buckles to the constable of the night. [ The constable produced them.]</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. These are my property, which she took from me that night.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was in Knaves-acre; this gentleman came by; he tapped me on the shoulder, and asked me where I was going. I said I was going home I would ask him a question: Did not you take your buckles out of your shoes, when we were in Compton-street, and put your hand under my coats, and say, I have no money; if you will take these buckles and leave them for some money, I will come again in the morning?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Said I, perhaps the woman will not let you have money enough on them so as to give me any thing. Said he, It is time enough to talk of that, let us have a job first.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610625-10-verdict55" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610625-10-verdict55" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acq
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
