<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17600116-24">
               <interp inst="t17600116-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600116-24" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600116-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600116-24" type="date" value="17600116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600116-24-off128-c180" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600116-24-defend227 t17600116-24-off128 t17600116-24-verdict131"></join>
         
               <p>68. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17600116-24-defend227" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Mac Call 
                  <interp inst="t17600116-24-defend227" type="surname" value="Mac Call"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-24-defend227" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-24-defend227" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17600116-24-off128" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600116-24-off128" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-24-off128" type="offenceSubcategory" value="extortion"></interp>
               endeavouring to extort money from <rs id="t17600116-24-viclabel129" type="occupation">Mr.</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600116-24-victim228 t17600116-24-viclabel129"></join> 
                  
                     <persName id="t17600116-24-victim228" type="victimName">
                        Stafford 
                        Briscoe 
                     <interp inst="t17600116-24-victim228" type="surname" value="Briscoe"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600116-24-victim228" type="given" value="Stafford"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600116-24-victim228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600116-24-off128 t17600116-24-victim228"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , by sending him a letter, purporting, that he had given her a blow in the street on her breast, which had occasioned her to make use of a surgeon, and that if he did not give her some money, she should employ an attorney against him, &amp;c
            </rs>. <rs id="t17600116-24-cd130" type="crimeDate">December 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600116-24-off128 t17600116-24-cd130"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>Stafford Briscoe. On the 1st of December I received a letter from one Mr. 
               <persName id="t17600116-24-person229">
                  Alexander 
                  How 
               <interp inst="t17600116-24-person229" type="surname" value="How"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-24-person229" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-24-person229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , an attorney, in Bearbinder Lane.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you prove the prisoner employed that attorney to write it?</p>
               <p>Briscoe. I will pass that by, and give an account of another, which the prisoner own'd. Last Saturday was seven-night I received this letter, which I have now in my hand. (Producing one.) It was sent by the prisoner at the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that she sent it?</p>
               <p>Briscoe. The porter is here that brought it.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his name?</p>
               <p>Briscoe. His name is King; and yesterday the prisoner sent me another letter, telling me she was in a very deplorable condition; that she lay upon boards, and was not likely to live.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600116-24-person230">
                  William 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17600116-24-person230" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-24-person230" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-24-person230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The woman at the bar delivered this letter to me. (He takes it in his hand.)</p>
               <p>Q. Where?</p>
               <p>King. I was at the Nag's Head in Cheapside, where I have plied ever since the year 1732. The prisoner came to me, and asked me if I would carry this letter to Mr. Briscoe's. I said I would. She gave me two-pence, and I received it of her in the passage.</p>
               <p>Q. How was it directed?</p>
               <p>King. It was directed to Mr. Briscoe.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you carry it?</p>
               <p>King. I did: I had but about the length of six doors to carry it.</p>
               <p>Q. What said Mr. Briscoe?</p>
               <p>King. He took and opened it, and the first word he said to me was, read that letter, where had you it? I said, a woman at the Nag's Head gave it me. He said, where is she? I said, at the Nag's Head now. He went along with me to the Nag's Head passage, and there he saw the woman, whom he desired to walk along with him to his shop, and he desired me to go also. Then he took the woman<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176001160026"></xptr> to the back part of the shop, and said, you may go away Mr. King, and when I want you, I will send for you.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you been in the shop before he bid you go away?</p>
               <p>King. Not half a minute, but in an hour's time he sent for me to go along with them before my Lord-mayor; when we came there, there was alderman Cockayne sitting in his room.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this letter produced there?</p>
               <p>King. It was, and read to him by a gentleman that was there?</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner present?</p>
               <p>King. She was.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say?</p>
               <p>King. She said before the alderman, that about two or three months ago she was going down Ludgate Hill, or Ludgate Street, and as Mr. Briscoe was coming along, he gave her a knock on her breast, or pushed her, so that she had not been able to get her bread ever since.</p>
               <p>Q. What said Mr. Briscoe to that?</p>
               <p>King. Upon my word I have forgot what answer he made.</p>
               <p>Stafford Briscoe. In consequence of this letter, I sent for my attorney, and, upon my shewing him the letter, he directed me to send for a constable.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your attorney's name?</p>
               <p>Briscoe. His name is Carrah; I don't know his Christian name. I carried her to the Mansion-House; alderman Cockayne was there: I told him I brought her there in regard to publick justice, more than in regard to myself, as I looked upon it to be done in order to extort money from me. She there said she did live servant with me for six months, about ten years ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Had she ever lived with you?</p>
               <p>Briscoe. I believe she had, I remember something of her face.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she charge you before the alderman with assaulting or abusing her?</p>
               <p>Briscoe. She did, but after her commitment was wrote she changed her tone; she persisted in it at first that I hit her with my elbow, but at last she did not insist upon it that I did it on purpose.</p>
               <p>Q. What were her words?</p>
               <p>Briscoe. She said I had struck her, or hit her, in the street, which was the reason of her writing this letter. I told the alderman I left it to what he thought proper to do, if he thought it necessary for me to prosecute I was ready to do it; he said he thought it was a thing of some consequence, and committed her; after that she fell a crying, and said she was very sorry she had given me any offence. I have no other motive to trouble the court with this affair but the publick good.</p>
               <p>Q. Mention the words she made use of after the commitment was wrote.</p>
               <p>Briscoe. The words as I understood them were, as near as I can recollect, she desired I would have compassion on her, for she had a child thirteen months old, and was with child again, desiring me not to be cruel, as she was sorry she had offended me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever strike her?</p>
               <p>Briscoe. No, to the best of my knowledge; there is not the least foundation for what she has wrote, not the least in the world; if I knew there was, I should be very sorry to give the court this trouble.</p>
               <p>The letter is read to this purport.</p>
               <p>"Mr. Briscoe,</p>
               <p>"SIR, I sent to you some time ago, and the</p>
               <p>"gentleman desired me to call on you, but I have</p>
               <p>"not been out of doors since before to day; I have</p>
               <p>"a surgeon to attend my breast, and it is very hard</p>
               <p>"I must suffer so much and have no recompence,</p>
               <p>"but as I am a poor woman I hope you will consider</p>
               <p>"me, for you are the person that gave me the</p>
               <p>"blow; if you will give me one guinea I will not</p>
               <p>"proceed any farther, but if you will not, you may</p>
               <p>"expect to hear from me soon; pray send an answer</p>
               <p>"by the bearer. I had one by me that saw</p>
               <p>"it done, and I have a lawyer who will take</p>
               <p>"it in hand, tho' I have got no money. I expect</p>
               <p>"your answer now.</p>
               <p>"
               <persName id="t17600116-24-person231">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Mac Call 
               <interp inst="t17600116-24-person231" type="surname" value="Mac Call"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-24-person231" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600116-24-person231" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ."</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>The day before thanksgiving day I was coming up Ludgate-hill, and another woman along with me, when this gentleman met me in the street, the other woman being close by me, and gave me a push from the wall, by which push I have had a sore breast, and was for three weeks an out patient in the Middlesex hospital; I could not lift my hand to my head, and was desired to apply to the gentleman, to see if he would make me satisfaction, as I had no mind to go to law, but thought if he would give me a trifle, it would be some satisfaction. I have a young child fourteen months old, and am with child again. I sent to him when I found my breast was bad, and called at his house once, but they said he was not at home.</p>
               <p>Q. Is the person here that was with you?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176001160027"></xptr>Prisoner. No.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600116-24-verdict131" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600116-24-verdict131" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
