<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640222-58">
               <interp inst="t17640222-58" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640222-58" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640222-58" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640222"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640222-58" type="date" value="17640222"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640222-58-off319-c424" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-58-defend547 t17640222-58-off319 t17640222-58-verdict322"></join>
         
               <p>196. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17640222-58-defend547" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Tompson 
                  <interp inst="t17640222-58-defend547" type="surname" value="Tompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-defend547" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-defend547" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for <rs id="t17640222-58-off319" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-off319" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-off319" type="offenceSubcategory" value="housebreaking"></interp>
               that she, on the <rs id="t17640222-58-cd320" type="crimeDate">23d of January</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-58-off319 t17640222-58-cd320"></join>, about the hour of six in the morning, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640222-58-victim549" type="victimName">
                           Rebecca Fernandes 
                           Nunas 
                        <interp inst="t17640222-58-victim549" type="surname" value="Nunas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640222-58-victim549" type="given" value="Rebecca Fernandes"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640222-58-victim549" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                     
                  , did break and enter, and stealing one blue and gold silk gown, a tabby silk gown, two quilted petticoats, a black velvet cloak, a black silk cloak, a silk bonnet, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640222-58-victim551" type="victimName">
                           Sarah Fernandes 
                           Nunas 
                        <interp inst="t17640222-58-victim551" type="surname" value="Nunas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640222-58-victim551" type="given" value="Sarah Fernandes"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640222-58-victim551" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                     
                  ; a silver snuffer-stand, and a quilt, and other things, the property of the said Rebecca, in her dwelling-house
            </rs>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640222-58-person552">
                  Sarah Fernandes 
                  Nunas 
               <interp inst="t17640222-58-person552" type="surname" value="Nunas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person552" type="given" value="Sarah Fernandes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person552" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with my daughter, 
               <persName id="t17640222-58-person553">
                  Rebecca Fernandes 
                  Nunas 
               <interp inst="t17640222-58-person553" type="surname" value="Nunas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person553" type="given" value="Rebecca Fernandes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person553" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in <placeName id="t17640222-58-crimeloc321">New Broad-street-buildings</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640222-58-crimeloc321" type="placeName" value="New Broad-street-buildings"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640222-58-crimeloc321" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-58-off319 t17640222-58-crimeloc321"></join>. On Tuesday morning, the 23 d of January, my servant came down to my room, and took out the key; I remember her coming in for it. About half an hour after eight, another servant came to me, and said, we had been robbed: I got up, and missed my wearing apparel, a box, and other things, out of a press, that was in the next room to mine; the snuffer-stand was taken out of the parlour; I had seen best part of the things over night. My daughter lost three negligee petticoats, a white sattin petticoat, a yellow sattin quilted petticoat, a crimson sattin cloak, a black silk cloak, a bonnet, and several other gowns; the door was shut, and all the windows; there was no visible place for a person to come in at. My servant absented herse lf, and at night she came and surrendered herself; and owned, she let two people in, and they robbed us; her name is 
               <persName id="t17640222-58-person554">
                  Sarah 
                  Beardsley 
               <interp inst="t17640222-58-person554" type="surname" value="Beardsley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person554" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person554" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and she lived with me near two years: I know nothing of the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640222-58-person555">
                  Henry 
                  Lyon 
               <interp inst="t17640222-58-person555" type="surname" value="Lyon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person555" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person555" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am turnkey in the Poultry-Compter. On the 27th of January, between 9 and 10 o'clock at night, Sarash Beardsley came to me, with three women along with her; she desired me to put her in the Compter, saying, she had robbed the house of Mrs. Nunas, in company with 
               <persName id="t17640222-58-person556">
                  Solomon 
                  Barnard 
               <interp inst="t17640222-58-person556" type="surname" value="Barnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person556" type="given" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person556" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (a) and 
               <persName id="t17640222-58-person557">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Tompson 
               <interp inst="t17640222-58-person557" type="surname" value="Tompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person557" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person557" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; she told me what locks they broke, and how it was done. I said, I dare not put her into the Compter, without I had a charge from a constable. I advised her to go to Mrs. Nunas, and tell her, and then I would accept of her. She went away, and in about two hours after, was brought by a constable.</p>
               <p>(a) See 
               <persName id="t17640222-58-person558">
                  Solomon 
                  Barnard 
               <interp inst="t17640222-58-person558" type="surname" value="Barnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person558" type="given" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person558" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             tried for stealing a hat, No. 8. in this mayoralty.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176402220044"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17640222-58-person559">
                  Sarah 
                  Beardsley 
               <interp inst="t17640222-58-person559" type="surname" value="Beardsley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person559" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person559" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 23d of January, about 6 at night, after I had done my work, I asked my mistress leave to go out: I went to 
               <persName id="t17640222-58-person560">
                  Jacob 
                  Levi 
               <interp inst="t17640222-58-person560" type="surname" value="Levi"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person560" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person560" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (b) in Newgate; the woman at the bar kept company with him: she was there, and lives with him there; I have known her three quarters of a year. I cohabited with Levi 7 years ago, and have a fine girl by him, 15 or 16 years old. She and I came out together; I believe it then did not want above 8 or 9 minutes of 9 at night: 
               <persName id="t17640222-58-person561">
                  Solomon 
                  Barnard 
               <interp inst="t17640222-58-person561" type="surname" value="Barnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person561" type="given" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person561" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             met us just under Newgate; he went with us as far as Bishopsgate-street; the prisoner and he persuaded me to do this thing: she wanted money to buy Levi off from transportation. He was to come at four o'clock in the morning, and as soon as he saw the light come down stairs, was to give a whistle; then I was to open the door. I lay in bed till it was almost half an hour after six; I went as usual, and opened the latch of the door, my Mrs. 
               <persName id="t17640222-58-person562">
                  drew
               <interp inst="t17640222-58-person562" type="given" value="drew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person562" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the lock, and opened her chamber door; I went in, and took the key, and went down stairs immediately. I had a candle with me; he whistled, and I opened the door; there was 
               <persName id="t17640222-58-person563">
                  Solomon 
                  Barnard 
               <interp inst="t17640222-58-person563" type="surname" value="Barnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person563" type="given" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person563" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and the prisoner: they came came in, and wanted to have the plate; I said, I could not come at it: the first thing they took, was the strong box, out of my mistress's room; that was carried down into the coal-hole. I gave 
               <persName id="t17640222-58-person564">
                  Solomon 
                  Barnard 
               <interp inst="t17640222-58-person564" type="surname" value="Barnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person564" type="given" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person564" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the clever and a square, and he broke it open, but there was nothing in it; he took a tea-chest, and a great many things out of the press: I saw the prisoner tie up a gold embroidered gown; they would have had me stay behind them, and say somebody had come and robbed the house, but I could not face my mistress, so I followed them to St. Paul's church-yard. They carried the things to Mrs. Wood's house, by Black-fryars; Barnard and I carried the things, and the prisoner quitted us, and went to Newgate, to 
               <persName id="t17640222-58-person565">
                  Jacob 
                  Levi 
               <interp inst="t17640222-58-person565" type="surname" value="Levi"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person565" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person565" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            : the prisoner was to come to Mrs. Wood's, on the Tuesday in the afternoon, but she did not come till the Wednesday; then I saw the things there; I sent Mrs. Wood to the Minories to fetch my gown out of pawn: they were to bring somebody to buy these things; Mrs. Wood took an empty room of her landlady, in her house, where the things were put. Solomon was to bring a person to buy them, and I was to be there, to see I was not cheated; but when I came there, Mrs. Wood went up first, and the door was broke open; she clapped her hands together, and said, D - n my blood, they're all gone; there was nothing left: I believe it was a juggle amongst themselves. Then I went and surrendered myself.</p>
               <p>(b) See 
               <persName id="t17640222-58-person566">
                  Jacob 
                  Levi 
               <interp inst="t17640222-58-person566" type="surname" value="Levi"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person566" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person566" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's trial, No. 83. in last Session's Paper.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640222-58-person567">
                  Mary 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17640222-58-person567" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person567" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person567" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Black-fryars: I buy and sell old cloaths. On the Tuesday morning, I believe to-morrow will be five weeks, 
               <persName id="t17640222-58-person568">
                  Sarah 
                  Beardsley 
               <interp inst="t17640222-58-person568" type="surname" value="Beardsley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person568" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person568" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             brought some things to my house, wrapped up in a quilt; she was alone; 
               <persName id="t17640222-58-person569">
                  Barnard 
                  Solomon 
               <interp inst="t17640222-58-person569" type="surname" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person569" type="given" value="Barnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-person569" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came the next day, I never saw him before; I was in bed, and asked who was there? she said, why, don't you know me? then I looked, and knew her face. She said, she had had words at home, and begged I would be kind enough to take an empty room to put her bed into; she gave me a shilling to give earnest: she carried the things into the room, and I never saw the things opened. Solomon came the next day, and asked me if my husband was at home? I said, I had not seen him for 9 or 10 days. He said, Sall had robbed her mistress of a great many hundred pounds, and he would take her to her mistress. She begged and prayed he would not, and fell into a swoon; this did not look as if he was the thief: he said to her, you never could do this your self: she confessed she did it herself, and brought them herself. The prisoner came there; Solomon and she went away together.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640222-58-verdict322" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640222-58-verdict322" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
