<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640502-27">
               <interp inst="t17640502-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640502-27" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640502-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640502"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640502-27" type="date" value="17640502"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640502-27-off146-c177" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-27-defend225 t17640502-27-off146 t17640502-27-verdict149"></join>
         
               <p>250. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17640502-27-defend225" type="defendantName">
                  William 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17640502-27-defend225" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-27-defend225" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-27-defend225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17640502-27-off146" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640502-27-off146" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-27-off146" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing a cow, value 7 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               <persName id="t17640502-27-victim226" type="victimName">
                  John 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17640502-27-victim226" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-27-victim226" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-27-victim226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-27-off146 t17640502-27-victim226"></join>
                  </persName>
             , <rs id="t17640502-27-cd147" type="crimeDate">March 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-27-off146 t17640502-27-cd147"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>John Clark. I have a field butts down to <placeName id="t17640502-27-crimeloc148">Cambridge heath, just at Hackney turnpike</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640502-27-crimeloc148" type="placeName" value="Cambridge heath, just at Hackney turnpike"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640502-27-crimeloc148" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-27-off146 t17640502-27-crimeloc148"></join>, on the common road; I missed a cow out of it, on the 7th of March, in the morning; she was safe over night; and it was fastened well all round; I could see where they brought her out at the gate, and I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176405020014"></xptr> could see where she turned back again, to jump into the field again: I found her hide in Leaden-hall market on the 9th: she was a very remarkable cow: were there a thousand hides, I could know her hide from all, mine was so particular: my son-in-law was with me: I found the salesman that sells the hides in the market: he told me Mr. Harlow, a Butcher, in Fleet-market, brought the hide there: I told my son, if he met with Mr. Harlow to secure him, if he did not produce the man that he bought her of: Mr. Harlow said he could produce the man: then the prisoner was taken, and brought to Leaden-hall. The prisoner has brought many a beast to me from Smithfield and Islington: I said, William, you knew the way to bring me beasts when I buy them, but I did not know you knew how to come and steal them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640502-27-person227">
                  Joseph 
                  Harlow 
               <interp inst="t17640502-27-person227" type="surname" value="Harlow"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-27-person227" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-27-person227" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a butcher in the Fleet-market. On the 7th of March the prisoner came to me, between 9 and 10 in the morning, and said, he had a good cow to sell, and she was at the Bell Inn, in Smithfield: I went and saw her: he asked 5 l. 10 s. it was but poor middling sort of meat: I bid him 4 l. he fell to five guineas: then I bid 4 l. 5 s. and then up to 4 l. 10 s. we could not agree: I went half way over Smithfield: he sent a man to call me back, and said, I must give him a little more: I said, I would not give him any more: then he took my luck with it: he brought her to my slaughter-house, in Wheat-sheaf yard: I gave him 43 s. what I had in my pocket: he came the next morning, and I gave him 2 l. 7 s. the remainder. I sent the hide to Mr. Martin, a hide salesman, at Leaden-hall market; there Mr. Clark found it. It was a brown mottle; pretty much mottled: a very remarkable cow. When Mr. Clark's son asked me if I could find the man I bought the cow of, I said, I believed I could. I went and found the prisoner leaning upon a post at the Crown-tavern door, in Smithfield: we took him to the Nag's-head, Leaden-hall, to Mr. Clark. I saw the hide that Mr. Clark owned: it was the hide of the cow which I bought of the prisoner at the bar.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>The cow was brought to me just at Shoreditch church: a man was coming along with her: he thought I knew better than he how to sell her: and he desired me to go and sell her for him. I gave the man the money at Islington: I met him there by accident: I sold her for 4 l. 10 s.: I had seen the man before, but not to have any acquaintance with him: I gave him the money at the Red-lion alehouse: I had but 18 d. for selling her, the same as in the market: the man stood by me while I sold her.</p>
               <p>Q. to Harlow. Did you see a man with the prisoner when you bought the cow?</p>
               <p>Harlow. There was a man with him, but he did not seem to take any notice: the prisoner and I agreed about the price. When we were before Mr. Clark, he said, he had the cow in exchange for a cow and calf at Lewisham.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640502-27-person228">
                  John 
                  Procter 
               <interp inst="t17640502-27-person228" type="surname" value="Procter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-27-person228" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-27-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Leighton, in Bedfordshire. I have known the prisoner from a lad: he has served me these two last years at times: I have trusted him with hundreds of pounds: I have sent him out of Smithfield with a hundred pounds, a hundred and fifty pounds at a time, to Mr. Child, the banker: I always found him honest: he has ofen sold beasts for me, and always gave me the money, I believe.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640502-27-person229">
                  Thomas 
                  Knight 
               <interp inst="t17640502-27-person229" type="surname" value="Knight"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-27-person229" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-27-person229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Islington, at the Three Wheat-sheafs. I have known the prisoner five or six years: I never heard any thing bad of him at all: he has received money of Mr. Procter, and brought it to me for his use. I have lent him money to buy calves with; he has honestly paid me.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640502-27-verdict149" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640502-27-verdict149" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17640502-27-punish150" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640502-27-punish150" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-27-defend225 t17640502-27-punish150"></join>
               Death
            </rs>. </p>
            </div1>
