<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640607-40">
               <interp inst="t17640607-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640607-40" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640607-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640607"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640607-40" type="date" value="17640607"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640607-40-off231-c267" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-40-defend353 t17640607-40-off231 t17640607-40-verdict236"></join>
         
               <p>363. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17640607-40-defend353" type="defendantName">
                     Hannah 
                     Dickinson 
                  <interp inst="t17640607-40-defend353" type="surname" value="Dickinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-40-defend353" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-40-defend353" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17640607-40-deflabel230" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-40-defend353 t17640607-40-deflabel230"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17640607-40-off231" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640607-40-off231" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-40-off231" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one gold ring, set with diamonds, value 30 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               <persName id="t17640607-40-victim354" type="victimName">
                  Jacob 
                  Potoo 
               <interp inst="t17640607-40-victim354" type="surname" value="Potoo"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-40-victim354" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-40-victim354" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-40-off231 t17640607-40-victim354"></join>
                  </persName>
             , <rs id="t17640607-40-cd232" type="crimeDate">February 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-40-off231 t17640607-40-cd232"></join>. *</p>
               <p>Mrs. Potoo. I am wife to the prosecutor; we live in <placeName id="t17640607-40-crimeloc233">Pye-corner, West-Smithfield</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640607-40-crimeloc233" type="placeName" value="Pye-corner, West-Smithfield"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640607-40-crimeloc233" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-40-off231 t17640607-40-crimeloc233"></join>: my husband is a <rs id="t17640607-40-viclabel234" type="occupation">cooper</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-40-victim354 t17640607-40-viclabel234"></join>. The prisoner was a <rs id="t17640607-40-deflabel235" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640607-40-defend353 t17640607-40-deflabel235"></join> to me five months and upwards: I discharged her the 2d of February last; I had lost this ring two months before I discharged her: I used to leave it loose in my bedchamber, when I was undressed; I had no other woman-servant but she. I sent her up to make the bed, and bid her be careful that she did not throw it down, nor tread upon it; it had been pulled off in the evening, with another, and left there: she came down, and said she had made the bed, and found the other, but could not find the ring with the diamonds in it. After we had some disputes, and warning given having thought in my own mind, that she was not so honest as I could with, I chose at her going away, to examine her box; I saw her take something out of a small trunk, and her countenance changed. I said, what have you in your hand? she said, nothing. I clasped hold of her hand, and in it she had my ring, and a stock-buckle, wrapped up in a bit of cotton; (the ring produced in court, and deposed to): then she said she found it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>Miss was out on a Sunday, and said she lost two rings: she desired me on the Monday, after my mistress got up, to go and look for them; miss found one upon the landing-place. On the Wednesday, I asked miss what ring she had left? she answered, a diamond ring. My mistress and I had a few words, and I gave her warning: miss being very ill, she got a gentleman to ask me to stay till she was better, I said I would; then my mistress came to me, and said, Hannah, will you go today? I said, yes I would. She desired to look over my things, and I said, you are very welcome. I let her see every thing: it was far from my knowledge to think this was my mistress's ring: she told me it was a diamond ring, and this is a red stone ring.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Pottoo. I told her it had four small diamonds, and a red stone in the middle: I said, it was a ring she had seen my daughter wear; she had seen my daughter wear it several times.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640607-40-person355">
                  William 
                  Hulord 
               <interp inst="t17640607-40-person355" type="surname" value="Hulord"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-40-person355" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-40-person355" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner four or five months; during which time, I well know she is a very honest person, by all I know of her. Every body that knew her, knows she has an exceeding good character; she is a very saving person in all families where she lived: my wife is a landress, and has a considerable quantity of linen: I have her in my apartment alone, and never lost any thing.</p>
               <p>Mr. Harwood. The prisoner lived with me two months and odd days, and behaved as a very honest, faithful servant. I have no reason to suspect<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176406070027"></xptr> her honesty. She was taken up in my service: I would take her again, was she discharged with a great deal of pleasure</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640607-40-person356">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Watts 
               <interp inst="t17640607-40-person356" type="surname" value="Watts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-40-person356" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640607-40-person356" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her two years; she has an exceeding good honest character; she has been trusted at different times in my house and shop; I never had any reason to suspect her: was she discharged here, I would take her again.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Snow. I live on Ludgate-hill: the prisoner lived with me four months, about three years and a half ago. I had so good an opinion of her, that I would have had her live with me to this time: I offered her great wages, but she wanted to go where there were more servants</p>
               <p>Mrs. Hall I have known her about twelve months, she has a very honest careful good character, that I have in general heard of her.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutrix. How came you not to take her up, at the time you found this ring?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. My daughter then was exceeding ill, and so she is at this time, not in a condition to be brought here.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640607-40-verdict236" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640607-40-verdict236" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>She was detained, to take her trial for another offence, at Hicks's-hall.</p>
            </div1>
