<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640113-27">
               <interp inst="t17640113-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640113-27" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640113-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640113"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640113-27" type="date" value="17640113"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640113-27-off144-c207" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-27-defend256 t17640113-27-off144 t17640113-27-verdict145"></join>
         
               <p>96. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17640113-27-defend256" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Murphy 
                  <interp inst="t17640113-27-defend256" type="surname" value="Murphy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-27-defend256" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-27-defend256" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17640113-27-off144" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640113-27-off144" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-27-off144" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a metal watch, value 40 s. and two pair of shoes, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640113-27-victim258" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Carnes 
                        <interp inst="t17640113-27-victim258" type="surname" value="Carnes"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640113-27-victim258" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640113-27-victim258" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-27-off144 t17640113-27-victim258"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling-house of the said John
            </rs>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640113-27-person259">
                  John 
                  Carnes 
               <interp inst="t17640113-27-person259" type="surname" value="Carnes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-27-person259" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-27-person259" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was at my house on Christmas-eve; I being ill, desired him to go away; he did not seem inclined to go. I went to bed about 11 o'clock; I hung my watch behind the head of the bed; the next morning I missed my watch and two pair of shoes.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640113-27-person260">
                  Robert 
                  Commey 
               <interp inst="t17640113-27-person260" type="surname" value="Commey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-27-person260" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-27-person260" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I took the prisoner up last Saturday; I searched him, but found nothing upon him; he owned he took the prosecutor's watch, and offered me 2 s. to let him go; and said, he had 3 s. due to him at another place, which he would give me also: I would not let him go; he offered to make his escape from me, but I kept him secure.</p>
               <p>Job Biffen. I am an officer, and live five or six doors from the prosecutor. I had the prisoner in charge; he would not confess to me till the prosecutor came in; then he said to him, I have fed you and served you, how could you go and serve me so? you could not do it for want, as you have 10 s. a week; then the prisoner owned he took the watch, to us; the prosecutor asked him, where the watch was, and said, if he would tell him, he would go and take it out, and he should go about his business; the prisoner said it was somewhere in St. Giles's. We took him before Justice Berry; there he would not speak; the Justice said, you rascal, why don't you speak? then he said, I took the watch. What have you done with it? I have pledged it. Where? I don't know, it is somewhere by St. Giles's Pound. Go and shew the man where it is. The Justice wrote his mittimus to Newgate: we took him first to St. Giles's, then he said it was not there: we went farther; he wanted to make his escape, when we were going back again, down Tyburn-road; he said, this is the house, I believe, but cannot tell. We could not find it, then we took him to Newgate.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was going cross Tower hill; Commey was tossing up; he said, he had lost a shilling; so I offered to give it him, when we were going to Newgate: I said, it does not signify to look for it; I know nothing where it is; he said, come, go along to please the old man, whether you get it or not.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640113-27-verdict145" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640113-27-verdict145" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-27-verdict145" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder40s"></interp>
               Guilty. 39 s.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640113-27-punish146" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640113-27-punish146" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-27-defend256 t17640113-27-punish146"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
