<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610625-27">
               <interp inst="t17610625-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-27" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610625"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-27" type="date" value="17610625"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610625-27-off158-c199" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-27-defend245 t17610625-27-off158 t17610625-27-verdict161"></join>
         
               <p>206. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610625-27-defend245" type="defendantName">
                     Frances 
                     Henderick 
                  <interp inst="t17610625-27-defend245" type="surname" value="Henderick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-27-defend245" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-27-defend245" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17610625-27-deflabel157" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-27-defend245 t17610625-27-deflabel157"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17610625-27-off158" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610625-27-off158" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-27-off158" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one glass pint bottle, filled with violet cordial, value 1 s. 4 d. and one shilling in money
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17610625-27-victim247" type="victimName">
                     Edward 
                     Calvert 
                  <interp inst="t17610625-27-victim247" type="surname" value="Calvert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-27-victim247" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-27-victim247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-27-off158 t17610625-27-victim247"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17610625-27-cd159" type="crimeDate">May 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-27-off158 t17610625-27-cd159"></join>.~</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-27-person248">
                  Edward 
                  Calvert 
               <interp inst="t17610625-27-person248" type="surname" value="Calvert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-27-person248" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-27-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Norton Falgate; I am <rs id="t17610625-27-viclabel160" type="occupation">a druggist</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-27-victim247 t17610625-27-viclabel160"></join>. On the 28th of May I had left my key in my bureau, after which I missed four guineas and a half The Saturday following, I marked three shillings, and put them into her mistress's room, and one of them was missing. On the Monday morning I went to justice Scott, and got a search-warrant, and charged a peace-officer with her; and in searching her box, in her own room, there we found some violet cordial, and the shilling in her purse: [produced in court. ] this is one of them that I marked, and put in my wife's room. She confessed she had it there, and that she took the cordial out of the shop. I took her in a coach to justice Scott, and he committed her.</p>
               <p>Q. What part of the room was that shilling put in?</p>
               <p>Calvert. It was put on the left-hand side of the bed, under the castor of the bed; and when she scoured the room, she saw and took it; I found in her purse also two guineas and a half, and 11 shillings in silver.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-27-person249">
                  William 
                  Barrat 
               <interp inst="t17610625-27-person249" type="surname" value="Barrat"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-27-person249" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-27-person249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to the prosecutor; on the 27th of May we were at breakfast, the prisoner was cleaning the stairs, we thought we heard something in the shop: master after that thought he had lost some money, then three shillings were marked on the Saturday, so that we could know them again, and on the Monday one of the shillings was missing; a search-warrant was got, and an officer to search; in her box was found a bottle of violet cordial.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it full?</p>
               <p>Barrat. It was not quite full: then there was a purse found, in which was two guineas and a half, and eleven shillings in silver, the mark'd shilling was among them. She was asked how she came by that shilling; she said she picked it up about the house, and that she had done very wrong in not telling Mr. or Mrs. Calvert of it. She own'd she took the cordial out of the shop. Sometimes this cordial stands open in the shop in stone-bottles.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-27-person250">
                  John 
                  Martin 
               <interp inst="t17610625-27-person250" type="surname" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-27-person250" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-27-person250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am beadle and headborough. I was charg'd with the prisoner, I opened her box, there we found the bottle of cordial, and the marked shilling, which she said she found about the house: she owned she had found two shillings, but had given my master one of them.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176106250032"></xptr> Q. to Prosecutor. Did the maid deliver one shilling that she found to you?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. The child was playing where one shilling was put under a cushion, and it dropp'd thro', and the prisoner picked it up, and gave it to her mistress.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I am not guilty, I received that money for wages where I lived before.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Henderick. I remember the Sunday before the prisoner went to this place she dined with me; she sent for a pot of beer, I saw in her purse two guineas and a half, and some silver, about eight or ten shillings; that was near two months ago; she turned it out into her hand, and said, You see I am not pennyless.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you related to her?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Henderick. No, not at all; I have known her four years, I always looked upon her to have a good character.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Watkins. I live in High Holbourn, the prisoner was servant with me above a year and a half: I keep a pawnbroker's shop, I used to leave my money in my till, I never missed any thing, she had an opportunity of wronging me if she chose it.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Mason. I live at Lambeth, my husband is a tallow-chandler and soap-boiler; the prisoner lived with me between eight and nine months, she has been gone about three months, I never found any thing dishonest by her, I believe her to be honest.</p>
               <p>Q. What wages did you pay her when she left you?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Mason. I paid her 30 shillings in halfpence, and a guinea in gold, and eight shillings in silver.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Shaw. I have known her seven years, I never heard any thing of her, but that she was a very honest, just girl.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610625-27-verdict161" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610625-27-verdict161" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
