<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660116-28">
               <interp inst="t17660116-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660116-28" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660116-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660116-28" type="date" value="17660116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660116-28-off176-c293" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-28-defend349 t17660116-28-off176 t17660116-28-verdict180"></join>
         
               <p>105. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17660116-28-defend349" type="defendantName">
                  Peter 
                  Deal 
               <interp inst="t17660116-28-defend349" type="surname" value="Deal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-28-defend349" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-28-defend349" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17660116-28-off176" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660116-28-off176" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-28-off176" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one pair of linen sheets, value 5 s. one linen table cloth, value 1 s. one linen towel, value 6 d. one pair of worsted stockings, value 6 d. two neckcloths, value 1 s. one linen night cap, value 6 d. and three silk and cotton handkerchiefs, value 1 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17660116-28-victim351" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Hibditch 
                  <interp inst="t17660116-28-victim351" type="surname" value="Hibditch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-28-victim351" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-28-victim351" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-28-off176 t17660116-28-victim351"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17660116-28-cd177" type="crimeDate">January 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-28-off176 t17660116-28-cd177"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660116-28-person352">
                  William 
                  Hibditch 
               <interp inst="t17660116-28-person352" type="surname" value="Hibditch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-28-person352" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-28-person352" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Holborn. I happenned to be at a public house, the <placeName id="t17660116-28-crimeloc178">Three Cups, in Bedford-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17660116-28-crimeloc178" type="placeName" value="Three Cups, in Bedford-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660116-28-crimeloc178" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-28-off176 t17660116-28-crimeloc178"></join>, last Wednesday night. The prisoner was there also.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Hibditch. No, I never saw him before. I had a parcel of things. There was two sheets, a table cloth, a pair of worsted stockings, two neck-cloths, a night cap, three handkerchiefs, and a towel, in a bundle all together. I put them down on the table in the tap-house. I missed them. I enquired who had taken them away, and 
               <persName id="t17660116-28-person353">
                  John 
                  Lee 
               <interp inst="t17660116-28-person353" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-28-person353" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-28-person353" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             told me he saw the prisoner take them; but whether he carried them out of the house, or up stairs, he could not tell. I found the prisoner was quartered there; he is a <rs id="t17660116-28-deflabel179" type="occupation">soldier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-28-defend349 t17660116-28-deflabel179"></join>. The Landlord, named Hopperton, went up with me to the garret, where the prisoner lodges. I met the prisoner upon the one pair of stairs; he was coming down. I asked him if he had any thing about him, and told him what I had lost; he denied having any such thing, and threatened to throw me over into the well of the stair-case, if I said a word about the things to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find any thing in the garret ?</p>
               <p>Hibditch. We searched, and between the sacking and the bed, I found my bundle. I had a bill of the things in my pocket, which I gave into the landlord's hand, and the things were turned out upon the table, and they all agreed to the paper.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660116-28-person354">
                  John 
                  Lee 
               <interp inst="t17660116-28-person354" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-28-person354" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-28-person354" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I happened to go into that alehouse. The prosecutor laid his bundle on the table; he began to talk to me. While we were talking, I saw the prisoner take the bundle up, and move away, but did not observe whether he went out at the door, or up stairs. There are two doors near each other.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see it afterwards?</p>
               <p>Lee. I saw it found in the garret, in the prisoner's bed, between the sacking and the bed: it was brought down stairs; then the prosecutor produced the bill, and the things and that corresponded.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660116-28-person355">
                  Nathaniel 
                  Morgan 
               <interp inst="t17660116-28-person355" type="surname" value="Morgan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-28-person355" type="given" value="Nathaniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-28-person355" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am headborough. I was called in. I saw the bundle in the manner it is now.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not see it opened, and the things looked at?</p>
               <p>Morgan. No. I imagine that was done before I came. I saw it opened before Justice Girdler, and observed all the different articles there.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I had been out with my bundle of cloaths, intending to go to my washer-woman. I met a man that had been in the same regiment with me. Staying some time with him, I came home again, instead of going to her, and staid drinking in the same room where the prosecutor was drinking. I was got pretty much in liquor. I went up stairs, and took that handkerchief instead of my own. I put it upon the bed, or under the bed, I do not know which, and going down again for a candle, I met the prosecutor on the stairs: he asked me if I had any thing belonging to him. I said, I had not as I know of. The gentleman found the handkerchief on the bed. I said it was my handkerchief.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Did the prisoner appear to be in liquor?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. He did not appear to be at all in liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. to Lee. What do you say, was he sober or not?</p>
               <p>Lee. He did not appear to be in liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Did you see the prisoner bring a bundle into the house?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. He brought no bundle into that house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any other bundle there besides your own?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No, there was no other but mine.</p>
               <p>Lee being asked, answered the same.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660116-28-verdict180" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660116-28-verdict180" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-28-verdict180" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder1s"></interp>
               Guilty 10 d.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17660116-28-punish181" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660116-28-punish181" type="punishmentCategory" value="corporal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-28-punish181" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="whipping"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-28-defend349 t17660116-28-punish181"></join>
               W
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
