<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660514-13">
               <interp inst="t17660514-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660514-13" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660514-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660514"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660514-13" type="date" value="17660514"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660514-13-off77-c113" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-13-defend140 t17660514-13-off77 t17660514-13-verdict81"></join>
         
               <p>297. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660514-13-defend140" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Waldern 
                  <interp inst="t17660514-13-defend140" type="surname" value="Waldern"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-13-defend140" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-13-defend140" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-13-defend140" type="age" value="17 years"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17660514-13-deflabel76" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-13-defend140 t17660514-13-deflabel76"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17660514-13-off77" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660514-13-off77" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-13-off77" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one 3 l. 12 s. piece, one guinea, and a steel tobacco-stopper, the property of 
                     <persName id="t17660514-13-person141">
                        William 
                        Fricker 
                     <interp inst="t17660514-13-person141" type="surname" value="Fricker"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660514-13-person141" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660514-13-person141" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , in the dwelling-house of the said William
            </rs>, <rs id="t17660514-13-cd78" type="crimeDate">March 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-13-off77 t17660514-13-cd78"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
               
                  <persName id="t17660514-13-victim143" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Fricker 
                  <interp inst="t17660514-13-victim143" type="surname" value="Fricker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-13-victim143" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-13-victim143" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-13-off77 t17660514-13-victim143"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            . I live in <placeName id="t17660514-13-crimeloc79">Shoreditch</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17660514-13-crimeloc79" type="placeName" value="Shoreditch"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660514-13-crimeloc79" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-13-off77 t17660514-13-crimeloc79"></join>; the prisoner was my <rs id="t17660514-13-deflabel80" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-13-defend140 t17660514-13-deflabel80"></join>. About the 29th of March I lost a 3 l. 12 s. piece out of one bag, and a guinea out of another, in a drawer in my chamber where I lie, and also a steel tobacco-stopper from the same drawer.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you seen the money last?</p>
               <p>Fricker. About a week or a fortnight before they were missing. There were between 30 and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176605140010"></xptr> 40 l. in the bag where the guinea was, and there were six 3 l. 12 s. pieces, a guinea and a half where the other was. I put a piece of paper in each bag of the quantity of money in them, and the drawer was locked. The prisoner went away the 3d of April; we suspected her, and sent for her to the Angel and Crown, Whitechapel, on the 14th of April; I asked her what she had done with the 3 l. 12 s. and guinea; she would not own any thing to it at first, but at last she did.</p>
               <p>Q. What was said to her in order to induce her to own it?</p>
               <p>Fricker. I said, if she would, I would be kind to her; we were apprehensive there was some body concerned with her. So Mr. Lewis talked to her to persuade her to tell what she had done with the money; and at last she confessed she had taken a 3 l. 2 s. and a guinea out of the drawer in my room. This key (producing one) she took out of her pocket; it will open every lock in my house of the size, except the flap of my bureau; and my wife found this steel tobacco-stopper (producing one) upon the prisoner; this was in my bureau where the money was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see your wife find the tobacco stopper?</p>
               <p>Fricker. No; I was not present then.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How long time might it take from the first of her denying it, till she acknowledged it?</p>
               <p>Fricker. I believe it was a couple of hours.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she come without a constable to the Angel and Crown?</p>
               <p>Fricker. She did voluntarily.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you over and over again tell her, if she would confess she took the money, she should have no harm done to her?</p>
               <p>Fricker. I did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-13-person144">
                  William 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17660514-13-person144" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-13-person144" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-13-person144" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Monday the 14th of April, I was sent for by the prosecutor, to know if I knew the tobacco-stopper; I looked at it, and said I made it for Mr. Fricker; we went to Whitechapel; I went to the prisoner's new master, I desired him to let her go a little way with me; as we were coming in the street, she cry'd, and begged of me not to take her up, before I said a word about the affair.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you told her who wanted her?</p>
               <p>Lewis. I told her her master was at the Angel and Crown; she begged I would not take her up and put her into goal, for she knew nothing at all of what was laid to her charge. When we got her to the Angel and Crown, she was asked if she would tell what was become of the money; and it was told her, if she would tell, her master would be favourable to her; she said, she knew nothing at all of the matter. I had this tobacco-stopper in my hand, I shewed it her, and asked her how she came by that? She said first of all, she took it out of a bag from off a shelf one day as she was dusting the room; but there is never a shelf in that room; I said, her master and mistress would take their oaths it was in the drawer where the money was taken from; then she confessed directly the taking the 3 l. 12 s. I asked her what day of the month it was? She could give no answer to that, but said it was between two or three o'clock in the afternoon; I asked her for the key with which she unlocked her master's drawers; she said she had left her keys at home; I said, feel in your pocket; she pulled out a bunch of keys; I said, Which is the key you opened the drawers with? She gave it me; I took it from the bunch; then she asked to go out into the yard with me; we went out; then I asked her concerning the money her master missed; she said she took but one guinea; I asked her what use she had put it to She said one half guinea went towards buying a pair of new stays; I asked her what she did with the other half guinea? She said she had bought coloured aprons with it; I said, I am certain sure your master will be favourable to you. if you do but let him know what you have done with the cash. She owned to me, she opened four drawers several times in the same chest.</p>
               <p>Q. How old is she?</p>
               <p>Lewis. She is not 18 years of age.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she make any confession before Mr. Fricker and you had made a promise to be favourable?</p>
               <p>Lewis. No, she did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-13-person145">
                  William 
                  Goodman 
               <interp inst="t17660514-13-person145" type="surname" value="Goodman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-13-person145" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-13-person145" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 14th of April, after dinner, I was at a public-house, Mr. Fricker and Mr. Lewis were there, they asked me to take a walk to Whitechapel; I went with them; we went into the Angel and Crown, and Mr. Lewis went and brought the girl; this tobacco-stopper was produced, Mr. Lewis said he made it. I told the girl there was a 3 l. 12 s. and a guinea missing, and if she would tell what was become of them, they would be kind to her. I heard her say she had taken the guinea out of Mr. Fricker's bag, and the 3 l. 12 s. out of the other bag.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you understand by their being kind to her?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176605140011"></xptr>Goodman. I understood it in that light, that if she would confess, no farther harm should come to her.</p>
               <p>Q. Supposing no promise had been made, was there any probability of any confession being made?</p>
               <p>Goodman. No, there was not.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this promise first made?</p>
               <p>Goodman. It was made her before she was carried before the Justice.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she in custody at the time?</p>
               <p>Goodman. She was not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-13-person146">
                  Henry 
                  Urswell 
               <interp inst="t17660514-13-person146" type="surname" value="Urswell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-13-person146" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-13-person146" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know just as much as has been said. She was asked to confess, and I heard her master promise to be favourable; and not only so, but after all this, there was a gentleman, a grocer, who was sent for; Mr. Fricker and that gentleman had some discourse together; she did confess it upon their discourse. The girl was set at liberty.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I am innocent. The gentleman told me, if I would not confess, he would take away my life.</p>
               <p>To her character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-13-person147">
                  William 
                  Pratt 
               <interp inst="t17660514-13-person147" type="surname" value="Pratt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-13-person147" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-13-person147" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Wantage in Berkshire, I have known the prisoner 7 years.</p>
               <p>Q. How old is she?</p>
               <p>Pratt. I believe she is about 17 years of age; her friends live at Wantage; she lived with me more than two years, during that time she behaved honest and faithful; she left me about two years ago; her family are people of credit and reputation.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Armstead. I have known her twelve months, she is of good character as far as ever I heard, till this affair; I know her friends in the country well, they are all people of reputation.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660514-13-verdict81" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660514-13-verdict81" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
