<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17600227-11">
               <interp inst="t17600227-11" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600227-11" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600227-11" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600227"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600227-11" type="date" value="17600227"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600227-11-off48-c87" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600227-11-defend108 t17600227-11-off48 t17600227-11-verdict51"></join>
         
               <p>88. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17600227-11-defend108" type="defendantName">
                     Simon 
                     Webb 
                  <interp inst="t17600227-11-defend108" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-11-defend108" type="given" value="Simon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-11-defend108" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17600227-11-off48" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600227-11-off48" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-11-off48" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch, value 10 s.
            </rs> the property of persons unknown, <rs id="t17600227-11-cd49" type="crimeDate">February 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600227-11-off48 t17600227-11-cd49"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600227-11-person109">
                  Benjamin 
                  Veals 
               <interp inst="t17600227-11-person109" type="surname" value="Veals"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-11-person109" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-11-person109" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable of the parish of Marybone, and the prisoner is <rs id="t17600227-11-deflabel50" type="occupation">servant to Mr. Marsh, a butcher</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600227-11-defend108 t17600227-11-deflabel50"></join>; his master came to me and told me the prisoner had got a watch which he thought he could not come honestly by. I went, and charged him about it, he was fuddled. Then he said his grandfather gave it him. We put him in the round-house, till he was sober, and the next day he said his master sent him to Esq; Calderwood's, in Great<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176002270008"></xptr> Portland-Street; that he there saw a watch lying upon a table, and went in and took it away. I went there and examined the servants, but none of the family knew of any watch being lost there. Justice Wright, before whom we carried him, went also, and could not find any watch lost.</p>
               <p>Mr. Marsh. I am the prisoner's master, I sent him to Esq; Calderwood's to see if any thing was wanted, as I serve the family. He returned in liquor, with this watch. First he said he had it from his grand father, after that, when sober, he said he had it from out of Esq; Calderwood's parlour, from off a table; I went, but found no-body there had lost a watch; since he says he found the watch. He has lived with me about eight months. He is a sober, careful lad; he has taken money for me, I never could find that he ever wronged me of a farthing. He is of a poor family in the country. I should not scruple to take him again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600227-11-person110">
                  Thomas 
                  Meres 
               <interp inst="t17600227-11-person110" type="surname" value="Meres"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-11-person110" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-11-person110" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a butcher in the same market. I heard the prisoner say he stood in the passage near Esq; Calderwood's, the door was open and he saw the watch laying on a table in the parlour, so went in and took it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I found this watch in Cavendish-Square.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600227-11-person111">
                  Richard 
                  Fletcher 
               <interp inst="t17600227-11-person111" type="surname" value="Fletcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-11-person111" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600227-11-person111" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was down in Gloucestershire, this lad then had lately had the small pox; his father is a poor man, and has got a large family. He desired I would get this lad a place, I came up and recommended him to Mr. Marsh, who was willing to have him, so I sent a letter for him to come up, and I never heard but that he has behaved exceeding well.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600227-11-verdict51" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600227-11-verdict51" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>, the jury being of opinion he found the watch.</p>
            </div1>
