<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17620714-21">
               <interp inst="t17620714-21" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620714-21" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620714-21" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17620714"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620714-21" type="date" value="17620714"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620714-21-off89-c141" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620714-21-defend180 t17620714-21-off89 t17620714-21-verdict91"></join>
         
               <p>196.(L) 
               
                  <persName id="t17620714-21-defend180" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Robertson 
                  <interp inst="t17620714-21-defend180" type="surname" value="Robertson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-21-defend180" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-21-defend180" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17620714-21-off89" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620714-21-off89" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-21-off89" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one deal box, value three pence, and a German flute, value ten shillings
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17620714-21-victim182" type="victimName">
                     Richard 
                     Gray 
                  <interp inst="t17620714-21-victim182" type="surname" value="Gray"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-21-victim182" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-21-victim182" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620714-21-off89 t17620714-21-victim182"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            . ++.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620714-21-person183">
                  Richard 
                  Gray 
               <interp inst="t17620714-21-person183" type="surname" value="Gray"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-21-person183" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-21-person183" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a<rs id="t17620714-21-viclabel90" type="occupation">book keeper to the Winchester stage </rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620714-21-victim182 t17620714-21-viclabel90"></join>. The prisoner took an outside place to go to Winchester. The box was sent to go to Bristol by the Bristol machine. The prisoner sat in the room for three or four hours with two others. The box was left in the window where he sat. I saw it when the other men left the room. I just stepped from the bar, and the box was missing, and the prisoner was gone in the yard among the people. I caused the Winchester and Bath coaches to be unloaded; and it was not found; being in a hurry I thought it might be put in through mistake. The prisoner went out into the other yard; when he came back, I told him he must know something of the box. I laid hold of him by the collar. Before the constable came he desired me to walk into the room with him, and he said if we would forgive him he would tell where the box was; he went and took the lanthorn and candle, and took the box out of the boot of the Winchester coach; he owned he had taken it, and gave it to me.</p>
               <p>Q. from the prisoner. Whether there was not a woman in the room besides?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620714-21-person184">
                  Richard 
                  Gray 
               <interp inst="t17620714-21-person184" type="surname" value="Gray"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-21-person184" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-21-person184" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Yes, after the box was gone, there were several.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620714-21-person185">
                  Ann 
                  Richards 
               <interp inst="t17620714-21-person185" type="surname" value="Richards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-21-person185" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-21-person185" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the prisoner put the box-up in the boot of the coach. I lighted him up with it to the Winchester coach with a candle and lanthorn.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Whether the coach was unloaded at all?</p>
               <p>Richards. It was loaded and unloaded; and after it was loaded again the prisoner put it in.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620714-21-person186">
                  Walter 
                  Lesley 
               <interp inst="t17620714-21-person186" type="surname" value="Lesley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-21-person186" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-21-person186" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went into the room where the prisoner was. The box was missing before I went in. The gentleman and his wife asked me if I took the box. I said, I did not see the box; but that two ladies had been in the room. Mr. Gray said, he did not suspect me. The prisoner said, take me into another room and I will confess it; he said it would be the ruin of him if he was convicted; he went up to the coach, and took it out of the boot.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620714-21-person187">
                  William 
                  Bodington 
               <interp inst="t17620714-21-person187" type="surname" value="Bodington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-21-person187" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-21-person187" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am constable. They sent for me to take the prisoner into custody. He said<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176207140011"></xptr> it was the first fact, and he hoped they would forgive him. I thought it had been lace; but, on breaking it open before the sitting alderman, it was found to be a German flute.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was ordered down to Winchester to be a captain's clerks there. I went on the Sunday with a friend to the gravel pits, and got in liquor; from thence I went to St. James's and got worse; I was so much in liquor I could not tell what happened afterwards.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mr. Hamilton. I have known the prisoner ever since he was a child. I know both his father and mother. I have known him since he came to London. I never heard any thing to his discredit.</p>
               <p>Mr. Mitchell. I have known him since he has been two years old. I have known him ever since he came to London. He came of honest creditable parents: and his character was always a good one.</p>
               <p>A witness. I went to school with him. I never knew any thing of him, but as an honest person.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620714-21-person188">
                  John 
                  Watts 
               <interp inst="t17620714-21-person188" type="surname" value="Watts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-21-person188" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-21-person188" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him above twenty years. I believe him to be very honest and well behaved; and that has been his general character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620714-21-person189">
                  Mark 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17620714-21-person189" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-21-person189" type="given" value="Mark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-21-person189" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him above five years. I was the person that was out of town with him. The day that this happened we went into the country, and drank very plentifully. The prisoner was in liquor when this affair happened. I have known him between five and six years. He has been an honest man as far as ever I heard.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Light. I have known him but a little time. He lodged with me. I took him in as an honest seafa ring gentleman. He always behaved as such.</p>
               <p>Mr. Cummins. I have known him about twelve months. I thought him an honest man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17620714-21-verdict91" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620714-21-verdict91" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17620714-21-punish92" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620714-21-punish92" type="punishmentCategory" value="corporal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620714-21-punish92" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="whipping"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620714-21-defend180 t17620714-21-punish92"></join>
               W
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
