<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17611021-6">
               <interp inst="t17611021-6" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611021-6" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611021-6" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17611021"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611021-6" type="date" value="17611021"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17611021-6-off23-c22" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-6-defend33 t17611021-6-off23 t17611021-6-verdict25"></join>
         
               <p>289. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17611021-6-defend33" type="defendantName">
                  Dorothy, <rs id="t17611021-6-deflabel22" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-6-defend33 t17611021-6-deflabel22"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17611021-6-person34">
                        William 
                        Morrison 
                     <interp inst="t17611021-6-person34" type="surname" value="Morrison"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17611021-6-person34" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17611021-6-person34" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
                     <interp inst="t17611021-6-defend33" type="surname" value="Morrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-6-defend33" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-6-defend33" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17611021-6-off23" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611021-6-off23" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-6-off23" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one black cloak, value 20 s. one half firkin, value one penny, one pewter pot, value 2 d. and one tin lamp, value 2 d.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17611021-6-victim36" type="victimName">
                     Robert 
                     Mason 
                  <interp inst="t17611021-6-victim36" type="surname" value="Mason"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-6-victim36" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-6-victim36" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-6-off23 t17611021-6-victim36"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17611021-6-cd24" type="crimeDate">March 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-6-off23 t17611021-6-cd24"></join>.~</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-6-person37">
                  Robert 
                  Mason 
               <interp inst="t17611021-6-person37" type="surname" value="Mason"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-6-person37" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-6-person37" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Peter-street, St. James's. I took three empty rooms of the prisoner's husband, and came into them the 24th of March. I brought my goods up stairs, the chest of drawers were too big to go up; one of the drawers was open, where my wife's best things were. I left that below, with a cloth over the cloaths, and went to fetch the rest of the things up; I missed my wife's black silk cloak the next morning, which I had seen in the drawer over night.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you carried that drawer up into your room?</p>
               <p>Mason. I had. As to the firkin, that was what I had nailed a bale on, so as to make use of it for a pail, that and the other things being all in it, were missing. We found the pail about four or five months after upon the prisoner. On the 5th of July, my wife was looking out at our window; she said, Bob, there is my cloak. I said, your cloak, you foolish woman you! how should it be your cloak? I look'd out, there was a woman in the street, a stranger to us, had such a one on. My wife said, I will go down and stop her. Said I, people will think you are mad; I will go and follow her. The woman went into Orchard-street, and into a good handsome house. I stood about half an hour at the door, and concluded she lived there. I came back and told my wife. Said she, Bob, we will go to-morrow, and inquire what she is; I should know it, could I see the lining, by two spots. We went next morning, my wife knock'd at the door and went in. I staid at the door. She staid there about an hour, and came to me, and said, Bob, I have seen the inside of the cloak, there are the two spots, it is my cloak. The woman told my wife she bought it of the prisoner at the bar. I went home, and got a constable, and charged her with selling my wife's cloak. Said she, I bought it at a pawnbroker's. Said I, does a pawnbroker sell my wife's cloak. The woman that had it came the next morning with the cloak, and told her to her face, she bought it of her for 13 shillings. The prisoner said, she could prove where she bought it, and made a laugh at it. The other woman<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176110210005"></xptr> said, she had bought it of her, about a month before, and that was the first time she had worn it.</p>
               <p>Q. What is that woman's name?</p>
               <p>Mason. Her name is 
               <persName id="t17611021-6-person38">
                  Martha 
                  Robintson 
               <interp inst="t17611021-6-person38" type="surname" value="Robintson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-6-person38" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-6-person38" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; the prisoner owned she sold it to her for 13 s. We all went with the constable to the pawnbroker's house, where she said she bought it at the corner of Crown-Court. The cloak was shewed to the man; he said he knew something of it, he thought he had seen it at his house, but was not sure. After that, he said, he knew nothing of it, and bid us begone; but the man that had lived there, and was gone, whom the prisoner said she bought it off, lived in Fleet-street, as the pawnbroker told us. Then we went to the justice, my wife swore to her cloak, the justice committed the prisoner to the Gatehouse. After that, my wife said to me, Bob, there is your pail, the prisoner had got some water, and her mop in it. I asked her what she did with our pail, and what was become of the things that were in it; we never found the other things.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to let her out?</p>
               <p>Mason. Her husband said, he would make us satisfaction. I said, I did not care, if the justice agreed to it.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was the justice?</p>
               <p>Mason. Justice Wright, he never bound us over to prosecute.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after she was in the Gatehouse, did he discharge her?</p>
               <p>Mason. I believe she was there but two days.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you receive any thing?</p>
               <p>Mason. They promised to give me 3 s. for a blanket I had lost.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any agreement entered into before the justice?</p>
               <p>Mason. No, he said, have you agreed it? I said yes, the man would have paid the money, if he could have got change for a guinea, but he could not get change.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you take out the warrant against the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Mason. On the 6th of July.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to take her up a second time?</p>
               <p>Mason. Because she said, she would go and transport the old bitch, (meaning my wife) for concealing a felony.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any thing done in the Marshal's court?</p>
               <p>Mason. There was a verdict against us; they got acquainted with one Jack, Matthews, he swore my wife struck the prisoner with a quart pot, full of beer, on the arm and breast, and spit in her face.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-6-person39">
                  Martha 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17611021-6-person39" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-6-person39" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-6-person39" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I imployed the prisoner at the bar to buy this cloak for me, I paid her 13 s. for it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17611021-6-verdict25" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611021-6-verdict25" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
