<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650918-11">
               <interp inst="t17650918-11" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650918-11" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650918-11" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650918"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650918-11" type="date" value="17650918"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650918-11-off63-c120" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-11-defend144 t17650918-11-off63 t17650918-11-verdict67"></join>
         
               <p>428. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17650918-11-defend144" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Devene 
                  <interp inst="t17650918-11-defend144" type="surname" value="Devene"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-11-defend144" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-11-defend144" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17650918-11-off63" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650918-11-off63" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-11-off63" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a cloth coat, value 6 s. a duffil waistcoat, value 2 s. three silver tea-spoons, value 4 s. four linen shirts, value 12 s. one pair of cotton stockings, value 4 d. two pair of worsted stockings, value 8 d. one periwig, value 2 s. one hat, value 6 d. two linen handkerchiefs, value 1 s one silk and cotton handkerchief, value 6 d.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17650918-11-victim146" type="victimName">
                     Henry 
                     Seyers 
                  <interp inst="t17650918-11-victim146" type="surname" value="Seyers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-11-victim146" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-11-victim146" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-11-off63 t17650918-11-victim146"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17650918-11-cd64" type="crimeDate">March 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-11-off63 t17650918-11-cd64"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650918-11-person147">
                  Henry 
                  Seyers 
               <interp inst="t17650918-11-person147" type="surname" value="Seyers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-11-person147" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-11-person147" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17650918-11-crimeloc65">Catherine-wheel alley, Whitechapel</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17650918-11-crimeloc65" type="placeName" value="Catherine-wheel alley, Whitechapel"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17650918-11-crimeloc65" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-11-off63 t17650918-11-crimeloc65"></join>: I am a <rs id="t17650918-11-viclabel66" type="occupation">taylor</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-11-victim146 t17650918-11-viclabel66"></join>, and have only two rooms. On the 3d of March the prisoner left his lodging; he lodged in the same house, and that day all the things mentioned in the indictment (mentioning them) were missing. I never saw him afterwards, till about a month ago, in prison; he then had my coat and waistcoat on; he desired I would be favourable to him; I never found any of my other things.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650918-11-person148">
                  James 
                  Horn 
               <interp inst="t17650918-11-person148" type="surname" value="Horn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-11-person148" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-11-person148" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Clarkenwell, and deal in brandy and tea; I hearing the prosecutor say he had been robbed by the prisoner, and he wish'd he could find him; I knowing him, and that he belong'd to the Surry militia, got intelligence of him, and took him up: he was dress'd in a lapell'd blue grey coat, and duffil waistcoat: he was carried to Bridewell at Chatham: I came up to London for the prosecutor: when the prisoner was taken out to go before Mr. Best, to be examined, he went without coat or waistcoat: we went to Bridewell; there we found the coat and waistcoat torn all to pieces, and some of them put into one hole, and some in another. (Produced all in pieces, and a periwig in two pieces).</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I know these pieces are part of my coat, which I lost at the time: I made it myself.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I gave very proper notice that I was going away: the prosecutor gave but very little heed to it: Mr. Horn took me up and carried me before 'Squire Best; he told him there were some things belonging to the cloaths I had on that he could swear to; I shewed them to the gentleman, and he said Horn was a very bad man for saying so: I was ordered to put on my cloaths, and was taken to Chatham watch-house; I thought I had people against me that would swear any thing: I sent my cloaths to a house where I owed money, for I always love to pay where I owe; presently Mr. Horn came and tore best part of the place down, and found a parcel of rags that were torn to pieces by a man that had been out of his senses, and confined there. I desired the constable to go to my lodging, to fetch my cloaths, but I could never get them again: I was obliged to go naked through the streets to the justice's; this coat I have on I bought<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176509180011"></xptr> of the marine society; as I have served his Majesty, I always love to wear the cloth. I am as innocent as the child unborn.</p>
               <p>Q. to Horn. Did you ever hear of this story of a madman before?</p>
               <p>Horn. No, I never did?</p>
               <p>Q. What reason did he give for his coming in that undress before the justice?</p>
               <p>Horn. He said he had sold the cloaths to a cloaths-man: I know these pieces belong to the coat I took the prisoner in.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17650918-11-verdict67" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650918-11-verdict67" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17650918-11-punish68" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650918-11-punish68" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-11-defend144 t17650918-11-punish68"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
