<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640912-10">
               <interp inst="t17640912-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-10" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640912"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-10" type="date" value="17640912"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640912-10-off52-c68" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-10-defend85 t17640912-10-off52 t17640912-10-verdict55"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640912-10-off56-c68" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-10-defend85 t17640912-10-off56 t17640912-10-verdict55"></join>
         
               <p>486. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17640912-10-defend85" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Slifford 
                  <interp inst="t17640912-10-defend85" type="surname" value="Slifford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-defend85" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-defend85" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for that <rs id="t17640912-10-off52" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-off52" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-off52" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he, in a certain field, or open place, near the King's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640912-10-victim87" type="victimName">
                           Brian 
                           Newman 
                        <interp inst="t17640912-10-victim87" type="surname" value="Newman"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640912-10-victim87" type="given" value="Brian"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640912-10-victim87" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and violently taking from his person one hat, value 2 s. one silver watch, value 20 s. and one shilling in money, his property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17640912-10-cd53" type="crimeDate">May 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-10-off52 t17640912-10-cd53"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-10-off56 t17640912-10-cd53"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-10-person88">
                  Brian 
                  Newman 
               <interp inst="t17640912-10-person88" type="surname" value="Newman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-person88" type="given" value="Brian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-person88" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 21st of May, about half an hour after nine at night, I and Mr. Dale were coming from <placeName id="t17640912-10-crimeloc54">Stepney</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640912-10-crimeloc54" type="placeName" value="Stepney"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640912-10-crimeloc54" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-10-off52 t17640912-10-crimeloc54"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-10-off56 t17640912-10-crimeloc54"></join>: we said, as soon as we got over the fields, we would have a draught of beer; we said one to another, we would not<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176409120007"></xptr> be robbed: we had hardly said the words, when three fellows came up; one said, D - n your eyes, you said you would not be robbed, and flashed a pistol at us, but it did not go off; after that they took a shilling, if not more, out of my pocket. They bid me go up the bank, or they would blow my brains out. I endeavoured to get up the bank to go over, and fell down once or twice into the ditch; then one of them, a little fellow came to me, and said he had a good mind to blow my brains out, and snatched my watch out of my fob. he went a little way from me, and came back again, and snatched my hat away: then they all went off.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of your companion?</p>
               <p>Newman. He ran away.</p>
               <p>Q. What led you to suppose the prisoner is one of them?</p>
               <p>Newman. I do not suppose he is one of them; I was so much frighted I did not take much notice of them: one was in a blue great coat; it hung over his shoulders; his arms were not in it; and the little fellow had a hair cap on.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-10-person89">
                  William 
                  Daies 
               <interp inst="t17640912-10-person89" type="surname" value="Daies"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-person89" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-person89" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was with Mr. Newman that night; we were walking by the side of each other over Stepney fields; a little fellow hail'd me, and said, yo ho; I said, yo ho; Mr. Newman said, You will not be robbed: I said, no. I had no sooner said it, than a little fellow came and ran his hand by my face, and flash'd a pistol in the pan. I was so frighted, I put my hand in my pocket and gave him about 11 or 12 s. he retreated from me, and then came back again, and swore, d - n your eyes, I have not half done with you yet: he rifted all my pockets; I thought I should receive some hurt: when he came to put his thumb and finger into my breeches to feel for my watch. I turn'd round and ran away, and he after me, threatening to blow my brains out if I did not stop; but I happened to have the heels of him, and I ran home. There were two men standing by Mr. Newman at the time he was rifling of me: one of them had a blue coat over his shoulders; he seemed to be a tall man, and the other much about the same size; but I can't tell how he was dress'd.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-10-person90">
                  James 
                  Wallis 
               <interp inst="t17640912-10-person90" type="surname" value="Wallis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-person90" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-person90" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a pawnbroker; on the 23d of May, in the forenoon, a man came in with a silver watch, and offered to pledge it; I asked him how he came by it; he said it was his own, and that he bought it; I asked him the name and number, and who he bought it of? he could not tell me: I said I should detain it; he said he could fetch a Person that could ascertain it to be his; he went out, and brought in a man, who said it was his watch, and that he had sent him with it to pledge, I asked them where they lived? they said in Whitechapel, opposite the Green Cannister; they said they could bring their landlady to prove it was their watch; they went out pretending to bring her; I sent my boy after them; he not returning, I went out as far as the London Hospital; coming back I met my boy by Whitechapel church; after that I saw them going towards Blue-coat-fields; I made all the haste I could after them: I had sent my boy to go another way; I met my boy again by Sun Tavern Fields; we went into the highway, expecting to meet them, but never saw them after: then I advertised the watch, and the prosecutor came and owned it. ( Produced and deposed to.)</p>
               <p>Q. How were the men dressed?</p>
               <p>Wallis. One of them had a blue surtout coat on, a pretty long one; the other looked like a seafaring man, with a piece of black silk round his neck. I cannot say that either of them was the prisoner or evidence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-10-person91">
                  Thomas 
                  Galton 
               <interp inst="t17640912-10-person91" type="surname" value="Galton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-person91" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-person91" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When the Prisoner and evidence were in custody, the prisoner told me that 
               <persName id="t17640912-10-person92">
                  William 
                  Bond 
               <interp inst="t17640912-10-person92" type="surname" value="Bond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-person92" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-person92" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17640912-10-person93">
                  John 
                  Bottom 
               <interp inst="t17640912-10-person93" type="surname" value="Bottom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-person93" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-person93" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             were the first that drew him into this affair, and that it was the first time he ever was out, and that he had but seven-pence halfpenny of the money: we had had information of him two months before.</p>
               <p>Q. When was he taken up?</p>
               <p>Galton. About a week ago, upon Bottom's information.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-10-person94">
                  Robert 
                  Nailer 
               <interp inst="t17640912-10-person94" type="surname" value="Nailer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-person94" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-person94" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17640912-10-person95">
                  John 
                  Bottom 
               <interp inst="t17640912-10-person95" type="surname" value="Bottom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-person95" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-person95" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             lodged a great while with me: the prisoner and he were coming together along Petticoat Lane, they asked me to go and drink: this was on the 23d of May, about eight in the morning: we went and drank facing Mr. Wallis's; he had a watch in his pocket; Bottom said the prisoner bought it for 30 s. Bottom went out to pawn it, and said he would be back in half an hour; he came in again in about ten minutes, and whispered with the prisoner; then they both went out together. I never had seen the prisoner before that time in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-10-person96">
                  John 
                  Bottom 
               <interp inst="t17640912-10-person96" type="surname" value="Bottom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-person96" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-person96" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner and 
               <persName id="t17640912-10-person97">
                  William 
                  Bond 
               <interp inst="t17640912-10-person97" type="surname" value="Bond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-person97" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-person97" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             lay at the house where I did. I happened to get a little in liquor one night; he persuaded me to go this way a robbing with him: we went out, and met two men in Stepney fields: Bond went up to them and bid them stand; we flashed a pistol at them, it missed fire; the prisoner went to one gentleman, and took all he had in his pocket, and after that his hat; I had about seven-pence half penny of the money. The day after, the prisoner wanted me to go with him again; he said, Come along; I have<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176409120008"></xptr> got a watch; I did not know that he had a watch before; he did not tell me when he got it, or where; but going along, he said he would pawn it; we went in and had two pots of beer; then I went to pawn it. 
               <persName id="t17640912-10-person98">
                  Robert 
                  Nailer 
               <interp inst="t17640912-10-person98" type="surname" value="Nailer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-person98" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-person98" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was with us when we drank the beer: I came back and said it was stopt. Then the prisoner went and said it was his watch.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you go to pawn it?</p>
               <p>Bottom. It was somewhere in Petticoat Lane; I asked a guinea and a half upon it; the pawnbroker asked me how I came by it? I said, I could not tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Who fired the pistol?</p>
               <p>Bottom. 
               <persName id="t17640912-10-person99">
                  William 
                  Bond 
               <interp inst="t17640912-10-person99" type="surname" value="Bond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-person99" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-person99" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             did; I was quite in liquor, I never did such a thing before.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you discover this?</p>
               <p>Bottom. I discovered it last Wednesday, after I was taken up.</p>
               <p>Q. to Wallis. Can you recollect seeing this evidence?</p>
               <p>Wallis. No, I cannot; I am more inclined to believe the prisoner was one of the men that came with the watch, but I cannot be clear in that.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing at all of the affair; I am very innocent of it.</p>
               <p>Q. to Bottom. How was the prisoner dressed when he went to Wallis's?</p>
               <p>Bottom. He had a black stock on; I had the same clothes on I have now.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640912-10-verdict55" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-verdict55" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>There was another indictment against him for <rs id="t17640912-10-off56" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-off56" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-off56" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               robbing 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640912-10-victim101" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Dale 
                        <interp inst="t17640912-10-victim101" type="surname" value="Dale"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640912-10-victim101" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640912-10-victim101" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>; but as no farther evidence could be given, he was <rs id="t17640912-10-verdict57" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-10-verdict57" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs> on that.</p>
            </div1>
