<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610916-13">
               <interp inst="t17610916-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-13" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610916"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-13" type="date" value="17610916"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610916-13-off69-c86" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-13-defend105 t17610916-13-off69 t17610916-13-verdict72"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610916-13-off69-c87" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-13-defend106 t17610916-13-off69 t17610916-13-verdict71"></join>
         
               <p>23. (M) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610916-13-defend105" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Spencer 
                  <interp inst="t17610916-13-defend105" type="surname" value="Spencer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-13-defend105" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-13-defend105" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               <persName id="t17610916-13-defend106" type="defendantName">
                  Mary 
                  Hughes 
               <interp inst="t17610916-13-defend106" type="surname" value="Hughes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-13-defend106" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-13-defend106" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , <rs id="t17610916-13-deflabel68" type="occupation">spinsters</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-13-defend105 t17610916-13-deflabel68"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-13-defend106 t17610916-13-deflabel68"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17610916-13-off69" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-13-off69" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-13-off69" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch, value 40 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17610916-13-victim108" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Hughes 
                  <interp inst="t17610916-13-victim108" type="surname" value="Hughes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-13-victim108" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-13-victim108" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-13-off69 t17610916-13-victim108"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17610916-13-cd70" type="crimeDate">July 6</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-13-off69 t17610916-13-cd70"></join>~</p>
               <p>William Hughes. I gave 
               <persName id="t17610916-13-person109">
                  John 
                  Thomas 
               <interp inst="t17610916-13-person109" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-13-person109" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-13-person109" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             my watch to clean about the 2 d of July.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a watch is it?</p>
               <p>Hughes. It is a silver one; I know nothing of the stealing of it.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the name and number?</p>
               <p>Hughes. The name was Kover, number 9430.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-13-person110">
                  John 
                  Thomas 
               <interp inst="t17610916-13-person110" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-13-person110" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-13-person110" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a clock-maker, and live on Snow-hill; the prosecutor brought the watch to me, the Thursday before the 6th of July. On that day I lost it. I cleaned it, and went on the Sunday morning with it in my pocket, in order to carry it to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does he live?</p>
               <p>Thomas. He lives in the Strand; the door was not open. So I went to see an acquaintance of mine, who was upon guard. Then I went to Westminster; and at coming home, I went with my friend towards the Seven-dials; then it was about twelve at night. Coming along, we met a couple of girls; he went to them, and asked where was a Night-house. We went to one Mr. Capstick's, at the King's-arms, near the Seven-dials. The two girls knew the house; we had half a pint of gin, then another. We staid till almost three, then they took me to the Black-horse in St. Giles's.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the girls the two prisoners at the bar.</p>
               <p>Thomas. No. we had the girls along with us to the Black-horse. I had the watch in my pocket there. I pulled it out there.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the prisoners there?</p>
               <p>Thomas. I do not remember I saw the prisoners before I saw them at justice Welch's. My friend went away, being in liquor. I went from that Black-horse to another Black-horse, in Church-lane; there I had a pint of beer by myself; there I fell asleep in the box. The man said, Do not sleep, your watch is picked out of your pocket. I found my fob turned wrong-side outwards, and my watch gone. I found my money all was gone. I went home, and the owner came for his watch, and I told him how it was lost. Then I went up to the house where it was lost, and told the landlord I had lost my watch there. He said there was a watch and woman carried then to justice Welch's. The prosecutor was with me. I went to justice Welch's, and there I found my watch. I first described the name and number. [ The watch produced in court, and deposed to by the prosecutor.]</p>
               <p>Thomas. This is the watch I lost that night. I told the justice I believed I was robbed of it. A woman was brought to me, it was 
               <persName id="t17610916-13-person111">
                  Mary 
                  Hughes 
               <interp inst="t17610916-13-person111" type="surname" value="Hughes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-13-person111" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-13-person111" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I did not know her. The justice asked her how she came by the watch She said she took it out of 
               <persName id="t17610916-13-person112">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Spencer 
               <interp inst="t17610916-13-person112" type="surname" value="Spencer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-13-person112" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-13-person112" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's hand in a joke. Spencer was brought. I said I did not know that ever I saw her. The prisoners both said they never saw me in their lives before.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you your watch at the last Black-horse you was at?</p>
               <p>Thomas. I had and had pulled it out there. Hughes said to me. I was there, and that I was drunk, it was the first Black-horse that she saw me at. Spencer swore she never saw me.</p>
               <p>Q. from 
               <persName id="t17610916-13-person113">
                  Hughes 
                  Did 
               <interp inst="t17610916-13-person113" type="surname" value="Did"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-13-person113" type="given" value="Hughes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-13-person113" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             not you desire me to say I found the watch?</p>
               <p>Thomas. No, that is false, I never did.</p>
               <p>William cross. I am a constable, the prisoner Hughes was brought to the Round house; I heard she had a watch about her; I went to her, it was on the 7th of July; I asked her for the watch; she took it out of her bosom, and gave it to me; the same that is here produced. I asked her how she came by it. She said she had been along with Mrs. Spencer, and Mrs. Spencer had it in her hand, and she in a joke pulled it out of her hand, by which means the chain was pulled from the watch. I asked her whose property it was. She said, Mrs. Spencer's husband's. Then she was brought to Mr. Welch's, there she<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160008"></xptr> said the same; then a warrant was granted to take Spencer, she was brought there; she said she knew nothing about it; Mr. Welch desired me to keep the watch 'till farther light abo ut it, and the prisoners were committed; there was a seal to it.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. There were two seals to it when it went from me.</p>
               <p>Hughes's Defence.</p>
               <p>As for the gentleman, I know nothing of him, I never saw him 'till before the justice. This young woman (meaning Spencer) and I had been out, and both very much in liquor, as much as could be; we came home, and went in at the door; and after that this young man came into our house very dirty, he took a knife and scraped his coat, and asked if he could have a bed; we told him yes; Spencer took him up stairs; he asked the price of a bed; she told him six-pence; he said it was cheap enough, but he had no money about him, this was between two and three in the morning, he said he had been in a fray; then he said God bless me, he had got his watch and he would leave it; Spencer said she would not take it, except there were witness to it, and asked him what he would leave it for; he said for a crown; she called my landlady up stairs; said Spencer, you see this gentleman leaves his watch with me, without any thing to it, for a crown, 'till he comes again; I went out in the morning between four and five, and got my self into a scrape, and was taken up and put into the round-house, for stabbing a boy in the back; I having the watch, pulled it out of my bosom, after the gentleman asked me for it, and told him how I came by it, and delivered it to him.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-13-person114">
                  Sarah 
                  Marshall 
               <interp inst="t17610916-13-person114" type="surname" value="Marshall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-13-person114" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-13-person114" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the bottom of Dyot-street, Church-lane; the two prisoners lodge in my house; on the 6th of July a woman came and knocked at my door, between one and two o'clock; I asked who was there, and said I did not chuse to get up; she said, God bless you, I have been an old lodger with you, let this man wash him; I said it is an odd time of night, to wash people here; he came in all mud and dirt, and scraped his coat, and washed himself, then he asked to lie down, and he went to lie down, I did not get out of my bed.</p>
               <p>Q. Who let the man in?</p>
               <p>S. Marshall. The girls that worked on soldiers cloaths in my house let him in, as he took a girl up on the account of this watch, and she was cleared before justice Welch, he came to my bed-side after he was washed.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say to you?</p>
               <p>S. Marshall. He said nothing to me any farther than to ask to lie down; I said the constable lives at the next door, and perhaps I may get into trouble for betting you in; I took one of the girls a box for letting him in.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>S. Marshall. This might be between one and two o'clock. he said he had no money at all, and he would leave his watch with them.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this that he said he would leave his watch?</p>
               <p>S. Marshall. This was in the kitchen, I told him I did not take in any pawns.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did he say he would leave it with?</p>

               <p>S. Marshall. He said he would leave it with 
               <persName id="t17610916-13-person115">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Spencer 
               <interp inst="t17610916-13-person115" type="surname" value="Spencer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-13-person115" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-13-person115" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , for she was the first girl he spoke to in the house.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he speak with her about?</p>
               <p>S. Marshall. It was because I refused to let him lie down, and he asked her to let him lie there. I never take no more than two pence a night, or a groat if they come at that time of the night.</p>
               <p>Q. How much money was the watch pawned for?</p>
               <p>S. Marshall. I cannot say how much, for the girls came down stairs, and told me he had left his watch with them; after that Hughes got out of the house and got into a scrape; he was not in my house half an hour in all the time, he went up stairs a small trifle of time, then he came down and went away.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this talk about pawning the watch, after that of washing himself or before?</p>
               <p>S Marshall. It was after that.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he wash himself?</p>
               <p>S. Marshall. In the kitchen; he was very full of liquor and rolled up and down, and could not stand I would not let him lie down; at last the girl said, come landlady, perhaps this man may get into bad company let him lie down on the bed.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160009"></xptr>Q. Where was the prosecutor then?</p>
               <p>S. Marshall. He was up stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. How came he to go up stairs?</p>
               <p>S. Marshall. He went up to the prisoners, and came down again, and they went out all together; he made the offer of the watch before he went up stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was Spencer?</p>
               <p>S. Marshall. She was up stairs when he first came in, he asked for 
               <persName id="t17610916-13-person116">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Spencer 
               <interp inst="t17610916-13-person116" type="surname" value="Spencer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-13-person116" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-13-person116" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             at his coming in, he said he would leave the watch with her.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was she when he offered to leave the watch with her?</p>
               <p>S. Marshall. She was not in the room then at that time, she was up stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did he go up stairs along with?</p>
               <p>S. Marshall. He went up along with the other two girls that work at soldiers cloaths.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see him afterwards?</p>
               <p>S. Marshall. Never, 'till I saw him before the justice, I saw him go up, and I saw him come down.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he leave his watch in your presence?</p>
               <p>S. Marshall. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Who came down stairs along with him?</p>
               <p>S. Marshall. He came down stairs alone, very full of liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he any liquor in your house?</p>
               <p>S. Marshall. No, none at all, every body were in bed, only some that were at soldiers work.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you before justice Welch?</p>
               <p>S. Marshall. I was; all I heard the good man say, was, he left the watch with them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see the prosecutor before?</p>
               <p>S. Marshall. No, never in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he ever been in your house before?</p>
               <p>S. Marshall. No.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had the prisoners lodged in your house?</p>
               <p>S. Marshall. Ever since last Easter.</p>
               <p>Q. to Thomas. Was you at this woman's house that night?</p>
               <p>Thomas. No, I never was in her house in my life, nor never saw her 'till before the justice.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you take upon you to swear you was not there?</p>
               <p>Thomas. I can, and this woman and one Lee, were before justice Welch; and then she told quite another story.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say there?</p>
               <p>Thomas. She said Spencer desired her to go to Mary Hughes, and get the watch from her, to make money of, to keep her while she was in the gaol,</p>
               <p>Q. Did she mention any thing about your being at her house?</p>
               <p>Thomas. No, she said not a word of such a thing; she there said, she never saw me before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did either of the prisoners at the bar pretend to have you at their lodgings?</p>
               <p>Thomas. No, they both said they did not know me, and that they had never seen me.</p>
               <p>Q. In what condition was you? Had you been fighting?</p>
               <p>Thomas. A man struck me a blow, and I had then a black eye.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember your cloaths being scraped?</p>
               <p>Thomas. I was washed at the Black Horse, and no where else.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you so drunk, as not to be able to know what you did? Or was you sober enough to know each circumstance?</p>
               <p>Thomas. I was sober enough to know what past.</p>
               <p>Q. to Cross. Do you remember this woman being before justice Welch?</p>
               <p>Cross. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. What did Spencer say there?</p>
               <p>Cross. She said, she knew nothing at all of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say she knew Thomas?</p>
               <p>Cross. She said, she did not; that she never saw him before she saw him there.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Marshall present in the hearing of that?</p>
               <p>Cross. She was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any thing about his being at Marshall's house?</p>
               <p>Cross. No, I never heard a word of his being there, or of seeing either the man or the watch before, by Marshall.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she there above once?</p>
               <p>Cross. No, only once.</p>
               <p>Q. What was she sent there for?</p>
               <p>Cross. She came to give a character to the women, because they lodged in her house; I am sure that in all that past before the justice, she never talked of her seeing that man in her house.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you can recollect with certainty, that Marshall said, she had not seen the man before?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160010"></xptr>Cross. I can't recollect any word was mentioned of seeing him before.</p>
               <p>Hughes <rs id="t17610916-13-verdict71" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-13-verdict71" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Spencer <rs id="t17610916-13-verdict72" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-13-verdict72" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The jury declared they believed Marshall had perjured herself, on which she was committed to Newgate.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610916-13-punish73" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-13-punish73" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-13-defend106 t17610916-13-punish73"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
