<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660116-2">
               <interp inst="t17660116-2" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660116-2" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660116-2" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660116-2" type="date" value="17660116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660116-2-off7-c36" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-2-defend38 t17660116-2-off7 t17660116-2-verdict12"></join>
         
               <p>73. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660116-2-defend38" type="defendantName">
                     Brian 
                     Swinney 
                  <interp inst="t17660116-2-defend38" type="surname" value="Swinney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-2-defend38" type="given" value="Brian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-2-defend38" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for that <rs id="t17660116-2-off7" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660116-2-off7" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-2-off7" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he, on the King's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17660116-2-victim40" type="victimName">
                           Timothy 
                           Dunn 
                        <interp inst="t17660116-2-victim40" type="surname" value="Dunn"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660116-2-victim40" type="given" value="Timothy"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660116-2-victim40" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-2-off7 t17660116-2-victim40"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and taking from his person one hat, value 12 d. one perriwig, value 12 d. one silver knee-buckle, value 2 s. and one Pinchbeck seal, his property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17660116-2-cd8" type="crimeDate">Nov. 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-2-off7 t17660116-2-cd8"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660116-2-person41">
                  Timothy 
                  Dunn 
               <interp inst="t17660116-2-person41" type="surname" value="Dunn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-2-person41" type="given" value="Timothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-2-person41" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Old Gravel lane, Wapping: I work at <rs id="t17660116-2-viclabel9" type="occupation">water work and engine work</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-2-victim40 t17660116-2-viclabel9"></join> with Mr. Gregory at Execution-dock. On the 20th of November I had been at Ratcliff-cross to one Mrs. More's, at the Bull-Head, Mr. Cohan went with me. I came back, he parted with me at the Fox. I had left some tools at 
               <persName id="t17660116-2-person42">
                  Timothy
                   M'Donnel's
               <interp inst="t17660116-2-person42" type="surname" value="M'Donnel's"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-2-person42" type="given" value="Timothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-2-person42" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             house, Old Gravel-lane, about a week or two before. I called for them: I took nothing with me but a chissel which I wanted to use next day. I went towards my lodgings near where I work. I went in at the Swan in <placeName id="t17660116-2-crimeloc10">King-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17660116-2-crimeloc10" type="placeName" value="King-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660116-2-crimeloc10" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-2-off7 t17660116-2-crimeloc10"></join>, a public-house, about a stone's throw from my lodging: while I sat there I had two or three pints of beer. I treated two or three men there to make a friend, because a man is in danger of his life, if out late, it is a bad place: I staid about half an hour, I saw people I did not like made me go the sooner; this was between nine and ten. I was knocked down in the street before I was aware of it. The first blow I received on my shoulder, had it been on my head I am sure I should never eat a bit; it was with an iron bar. The next blow was on my head, then I fell: at first I was a little stunned, but soon recovered my senses, and saw it was the prisoner. I felt a tug at my watch, the chain broke; I put my hand to my watch and held it, he did not get it out. I lost a pinchbeck mettle seal: then he took my knee-buckle, and tore part of the strap of my breaches away with it; then he took my hat and wig.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any body near you besides the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Dunn. I did several, but I did not know them: they came to assist him, there were some men and some women. I had hold of the prisoner, and I ran the chissel at him: I intended it at his throat, but I cut him on the left cheek. I was then standing up and the blood spirting upon me. Then I got out of his hands, and made the best of my way back to M'Donnel's, and told him what had happened; there I borrowed his hat and wig, and went home to my lodgings. The next morning I went and got a warrant from Justice Fielding, and brought two officers from there to take the man. I was told that day his name was Swinney. I met him in the street about a fortnight after, opposite M'Donnel's house: I seized him and said, You villain, you are the man that robbed me. I led him in at M'Donnel's; I charged four men with him, and went for an officer: when I returned he had made his escape. I found a bill of indictment against him last sessions, and on Christmas-eve I happened to meet with him again near the same place, and brought him into the same house, and got an officer and took him before Justice Fielding, and he was committed. I do not remember that he said a word in his defence, only that he said I struck him in the street.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe the wound then?</p>
               <p>Dunn. I did: there was a sear, and it was a little raw.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it light or dark?</p>
               <p>Dunn. It was a dark night; when I was making my escape from him, I could not see the posts, but I am sure it was the prisoner, I could see his face when he had hold of me, there is the same scar now on his cheek. About a week after the widow Doudle, that keeps the house, delivered me my hat and wig before the Justice in Shadwell.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he dressed?</p>
               <p>Dunn. He had a blue jacket and trousers on.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he dressed the other two times you saw him?</p>
               <p>Dunn. In the same dress.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know him before this happened?</p>
               <p>Dunn. No I did not. I got the warrant for one Swinney, whose christian name was unknown.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I went in at that house, the Swan, and got a pint of beer after supper, the prosecutor was sitting there; he went out and I sat in his seat: he came in and asked me what business I had in his seat, and bid me go and sit in my own seat. I said do not be angry. Said he, do you know who you are speaking to, you are talking to a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176601160004"></xptr> gentleman, and took a stick and struck me in the house; I took up the poker and said, if you strike me I'll strike you. Come out at the door, said he: with all my heart, said I. As I was coming out at the door he struck me four times with the stick, and almost stunned me; he got hold of me and knocked me down upon the stones, and ran a chissel into my cheek, with intent to take my life away. He lost his hat and wig, and I lost mine. There was a man named Mahony saw it all, he is here.</p>
               <p>Q to prosecutor. Did you see the prisoner when you was in at the Swan?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No; not to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any quarrel there with any body?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No, I had not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you strike any body in that house?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of an iron bar was you knocked down with?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. It was an iron poker.</p>
               <p>Q. What countryman are you?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I am an Irishman.</p>
               <p>(The witnesses for the prisoner were examined apart.)</p>
               <p>Cha. Mahony. I lodge in Mrs. Doudle's house at the Swan. The prisoner used to come there almost every night for a fortnight or three weeks before this happened.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you lodged there?</p>
               <p>Mahony. About nine months. I draw beer there. Dunn used to breakfast and dine there very often.</p>
               <p>Q. What business is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Mahony. He <rs id="t17660116-2-deflabel11" type="occupation">works with the bricklayers</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-2-defend38 t17660116-2-deflabel11"></join>. I cannot mention the day to be certain, but I was by when this dispute was. It was on an evening, between nine and ten o'clock; Dunn came in first and called for a pint of beer, I drawed it, then he called for a full pot; before that was out, in came the prisoner and a woman with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the woman?</p>
               <p>Mahony. I never saw her before to my knowledge. They sat down in the same room, Dunn on one side the fire, and the prisoner and woman on the other facing him.</p>
               <p>Q. What company else was in the room?</p>
               <p>Mahony. There was nobody else but a young fellow, a sailor.</p>
               <p>Q. How long were the prosecutor and prisoner in the house together ?</p>
               <p>Mahony. I believe about an hour, drinking together. Dunn said to the prisoner I know that woman: the prisoner said, what do you know of her? Said Dunn, I know her to be a bad woman. The prisoner said she was a married woman and an honest woman. Said Dunn, Do you know who you are talking with, and called for another pot; the sailor and I helped him drink it. When that was out he got up and said he would lick Swinney. He went out at the door and desired Swinney to come out. Swinney took the poker from the fire side in his hand, and when he was at the threshold of the door, Dunn struck him with a stick; Swinney throwed him down close to the street door; then Dunn got the prisoner down; they got both up; then Dunn made a step forward and struck Swinney with the chissel; Swinney never struck him with the poker. I said for God Almighty's sake do not strike him with it. The prisoner bled very fast where he was cut with the chissel; he came into the house and bled a great quantity. I went out and found Dunn's hat and wig, and Swinney's hat, they lay just by the door. Dunn went off.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did the prisoner stay after this?</p>
               <p>Mahony. He staid better than half an hour in the house after.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Do you remember seeing this witness in the street when you was thus used?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. He came with a candle and lanthorn to us.</p>
               <p>Mahony. I had a lighted candle, but no lanthorn.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. How far was you got from the house before you was attacked?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Seven or eight yards from the house.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you been out of the house?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. It was rather under two minutes before I was attacked.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660116-2-person43">
                  Margaret 
                  Doudle 
               <interp inst="t17660116-2-person43" type="surname" value="Doudle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-2-person43" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-2-person43" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Swan. The prosecutor and prisoner both used my house. Dunn was in that night before the prisoner; and called for a pint of beer; after that he called for a pot, and sat down by the fire. The prisoner came in and called for a pint of purl, a woman came with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the woman?</p>
               <p>M. Doudle. She lives in the neighbourhood. They sat down by the fire opposite to Dunn. There was no body else in my house but Mahony and one M'Carty, a sailor; they both lodge in my house, they are seafaring men.</p>
               <p>Q. How long were the prisoner and prosecutor in your house?</p>
               <p>M. Doudle. I believe Dunn was in the house about an hour; the prisoner not above half an hour. Dunn said to the woman, he knew her: the prisoner said, what do you know of her? Dunn said she was a bad woman. The prisoner said she was a lawful married woman, so words<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176601160005"></xptr> arose. Dunn said, You puppy, who do you talk to? If you speak much, I shall get up and lick you well. He had a chissel in one hand, and a stick in the other. He was dressed in his holiday dress. He got up. The prisoner seeing that, got up too. Dunn ran out at the door, and the prisoner went after him; there was some engagement without, but I did not see it. I never left the house.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the prisoner any thing in his hand?</p>
               <p>M. Doudle. I said, take care, he has got a chissel in his hand, he will do you a mischief; so the prisoner took the first thing that came to hand: he took the poker, and the engagement was at the door.</p>
               <p>Q. What dress was the prisoner in?</p>
               <p>Doudle. He was in a blue jacket.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660116-2-person44">
                  Edward
               <interp inst="t17660116-2-person44" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-2-person44" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             M'Carty. I live in the house of Mrs. Doudle. I was above. I heard a noise below stairs. I looked out at the window; I saw Dunn come out first, and Swinney after him. Dunn struck at him once or twice with a stick. Swinney struck at him again, and knocked him down; he got up again, and came with a chissel and drove it at Swinney. I saw the blood come out, then Dunn ran away and dropt his hat and wig.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it light or dark?</p>
               <p>M'Carty. There was a candle in the street, and I had a candle in my own room.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was the fray from the door?</p>
               <p>M'Carty. About the distance of three yards.</p>
               <p>Q. Who held the candle in the street?</p>
               <p>M'Carty. Mahony held it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660116-2-verdict12" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660116-2-verdict12" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The jury declared they had a very bad opinion of the prosecutor.</p>
            </div1>
