<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650522-39">
               <interp inst="t17650522-39" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-39" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-39" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650522"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-39" type="date" value="17650522"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650522-39-off254-c403" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-39-defend489 t17650522-39-off254 t17650522-39-verdict257"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650522-39-off254-c404" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-39-defend491 t17650522-39-off254 t17650522-39-verdict257"></join>
         
               <p>342. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17650522-39-defend489" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Trivers 
                  <interp inst="t17650522-39-defend489" type="surname" value="Trivers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-39-defend489" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-39-defend489" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17650522-39-defend491" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Knight 
                  <interp inst="t17650522-39-defend491" type="surname" value="Knight"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-39-defend491" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-39-defend491" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted, for that <rs id="t17650522-39-off254" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-39-off254" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-39-off254" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               they, on the <rs id="t17650522-39-cd255" type="crimeDate">18th of May</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-39-off254 t17650522-39-cd255"></join>, about the hour of 12 in the night, the dwelling house of 
                     <persName id="t17650522-39-victim492" type="victimName">
                        Joakim 
                        Taximer 
                     <interp inst="t17650522-39-victim492" type="surname" value="Taximer"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650522-39-victim492" type="given" value="Joakim"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650522-39-victim492" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-39-off254 t17650522-39-victim492"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , did break and enter, and stealing a metal watch, value 20 s. a steel chain and stone seal, two pair of silver buckles, five guineas and half a guinea, the property of the said Joakim, in his dwelling house
            </rs>. ++</p>
               <p>The prosecutor being a foreigner, an interpreter was sworn.</p>
               <p>Joakim Taximer. I am an Italian, and trade by commission in many sorts of things: I have been in England six months, and live in <placeName id="t17650522-39-crimeloc256">Gerrard-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17650522-39-crimeloc256" type="placeName" value="Gerrard-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17650522-39-crimeloc256" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-39-off254 t17650522-39-crimeloc256"></join>: I went to bed between twelve and one last Saturday night, and when I got up in the morning I found my house broke open; my shop is repairing; there I found a plank down, and a hole about 15 or 16 inches diameter; I missed a striking watch, my knee and shoe buckles; my breeches were removed, and in my pockets I had about 15 or 16 guineas, the morning before; what I had spent I cannot say; but my money was taken away.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-39-person493">
                  John 
                  Coulson 
               <interp inst="t17650522-39-person493" type="surname" value="Coulson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-39-person493" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-39-person493" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I met the two lads at the bar in Piccadilly; a girl of the town had told them this place was easily to be got through: they took me to the house at the corner of Gerrard-street; I got in at a hole, and went strait forward, and felt a door; I pushed it open; I heard a watch going on my left hand; I found it lay upon a shelf; I took and gave it to Trivers; he gave it to the other: I came out, and we went into a night-house, in the Haymarket; then we went back and found the door open as before; it was then day-light: I went in, and saw the gentleman asleep in bed; it was a ground floor; I took a hat, and his buckles out of his shoes and breeches, and about five guineas out of his pocket; I gave the hat and buckles to Trivers; the money I did not tell him of; then we went to Duke's Place; Knight was born there; a man offered us 7 s. 6 d. for the buckles; there came a hump backed Jew. and said we should be catched if we staid there: he desired us to go along with him; so took us to a house; the Jew held the buckles in his hand: Knight shewed the watch, and would not deliver the chain out of his hand; he asked six guineas for it. They said they would give him the money;<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176505220042"></xptr> they wanted to get it from him: after that Mr. Bareau twitched it from him; he gave us half a guinea, and desired us never to do such a thing again; he pulled out a pair of hand-cuffs, and threatened us, so we were glad to go away and leave it, and after that he said he lost it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-39-person494">
                  John 
                  Ross 
               <interp inst="t17650522-39-person494" type="surname" value="Ross"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-39-person494" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-39-person494" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed he called upon Bareau, by which means he got the watch, (produced and deposed to by the prosecutor.)</p>
               <p>Triver's Defence.</p>
               <p>I never was in any fact with the evidence before.</p>
               <p>Knight's Defence.</p>
               <p>I never was in company with him before that Saturday night; and I was a little in liquor, and was over persuaded by him.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17650522-39-verdict257" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-39-verdict257" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
