<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670429-30">
               <interp inst="t17670429-30" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670429-30" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670429-30" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670429"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670429-30" type="date" value="17670429"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670429-30-off170-c197" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-30-defend260 t17670429-30-off170 t17670429-30-verdict176"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670429-30-off170-c198" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-30-defend262 t17670429-30-off170 t17670429-30-verdict178"></join>
         
               <p>222, 223. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17670429-30-defend260" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Harris 
                  <interp inst="t17670429-30-defend260" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-30-defend260" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-30-defend260" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17670429-30-defend262" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Hencher 
                  <interp inst="t17670429-30-defend262" type="surname" value="Hencher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-30-defend262" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-30-defend262" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted, for that <rs id="t17670429-30-off170" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670429-30-off170" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-30-off170" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               they on the <rs id="t17670429-30-cd171" type="crimeDate">16th of March</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-30-off170 t17670429-30-cd171"></join>, about the hour of one in the night, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17670429-30-victim264" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           White 
                        <interp inst="t17670429-30-victim264" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670429-30-victim264" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670429-30-victim264" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did break and enter, and stealing one pair of leather shoes, value 1 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17670429-30-victim266" type="victimName">
                           Charles 
                           Walker 
                        <interp inst="t17670429-30-victim266" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670429-30-victim266" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670429-30-victim266" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling-house of the said Thomas
            </rs>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-30-person267">
                  Thomas 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17670429-30-person267" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-30-person267" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-30-person267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17670429-30-crimeloc172">Red-lion-street, Clerkenwell</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17670429-30-crimeloc172" type="placeName" value="Red-lion-street, Clerkenwell"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17670429-30-crimeloc172" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-30-off170 t17670429-30-crimeloc172"></join>; I <rs id="t17670429-30-viclabel173" type="occupation">have a shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-30-victim264 t17670429-30-viclabel173"></join> and a lower apartment in a house; my shop was broke open on the 16th of March at night. I am a <rs id="t17670429-30-viclabel174" type="occupation">watchman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-30-victim264 t17670429-30-viclabel174"></join>; as I was upon my duty, about one o'clock, I was called from my watch-box, and told my shop was broke open. (I knew I had bolted and key'd it, and <note>[Text unreadable in original.]</note>fa street door when I left it.) I went a was taken down, and a great 13 inches square, was broke, taken out which belong to ker; a pair that I made him, ght to be mended. The two prisoner both in custody, and the shoes found.  acknowledged before the Justice that H broke the place open, and enticed him to go in.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-30-person268">
                  Samuel 
                  Elson 
               <interp inst="t17670429-30-person268" type="surname" value="Elson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-30-person268" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-30-person268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I took Harris as he stuck in the prosecutor's window; his face was in the shop. He had been in; there were the marks of his feet in the shop, and the glass was pushed in; he was with his back downwards; he was cut, and bleeding very much. The other prisoner is a watchman; he and the boy Harris were in company about two hours before, and two other boys with them; they went into a public-house and called for beer; the woman was afraid to draw them beer. Hencher said, what are you afraid of, do you think I will bring any bad people here; then she drawed them some beer: after that Harris pulled out some money, seemingly to me to distribute among them; the woman was frighted, and begged we would not leave her while they were in the house, her husband not being within. About one o'clock the two prisoners went out of the house and returned again; Harris came in first and sat a little time; then Hencher came in; then there was some whispering; then they went out again. After that I went out, and saw Harris in the plight I mentioned in the prosecutor's window. We got a candle; there lay his hat under the side of the window. After I took him out, we asked him how he came to do such a thing. He said, Hencher broke the place open, and told him he knew there were a number of shoes in the shop, and if he got them he would take them to his watch-box, and there they would be safe.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you by when Hencher was taken?</p>
               <p>Elson. I was. He said he knew nothing of it; he was in the alehouse before I went in again; he had not returned from crying the hour one above ten minutes, when I brought Harris into the house.</p>
               <p>Q. How wide is the window where Harris was in?</p>
               <p>Elson. I take it to be about ten inches and a half one way, and twelve the other. It was part of an old sash turned sideways; it was the upper pane that was broke; the shoes were lying on the outside, one in Harris's hat, and the other by the side of it. Harris owned it to be his hat.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670429-30-person269">
                  John 
                  Fisher 
               <interp inst="t17670429-30-person269" type="surname" value="Fisher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-30-person269" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670429-30-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am going into the 15th year of my age. I was sitting at the One Tun, in came Hencher; he said to Harris, if his master was gone to bed he might stay in his watch-house all night. We asked if there were room for us all; there were Harris, I, and another. He said there were; we all crowded into his box; it being a rainy night we got a pot of purl. Hencher said he knew of a good shop to break into, and wanted Harris to get into it. Harris shook his head, but said nothing to it. Hencher said he would go round his beat and come again to us; he said there were a good many boots and shoes in it; he went out, and we with him; we went into an alehouse and had two pots of purl; then Harris and he went out to cry the beat. I heard Harris cry it. Then they came in; and afterwards Harris went out and Hencher staid in; soon after that Harris was brought in bleeding.</p>
               <p>Q. What does, Harris do for a livelihood?</p>
               <p>Fisher. He rides horses about; he used to come to the One Tun alehouse at the corner of Field-lane. I heard him say he got twelve shillings once by knocking the lobb.</p>
               <p>Q. What is that?</p>
               <p>Fisher. That is breaking open a place.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>Fisher. I go about with a jack-ass; and sell potatoes and other things.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176704290016"></xptr>Harris's defence.</p>
               <p>I never had any money, Hencher can witness that. I am a <rs id="t17670429-30-deflabel175" type="occupation">bricklayer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-30-defend260 t17670429-30-deflabel175"></join> by trade.</p>
               <p>Harris <rs id="t17670429-30-verdict176" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670429-30-verdict176" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17670429-30-punish177" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670429-30-punish177" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670429-30-defend260 t17670429-30-punish177"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Hencher <rs id="t17670429-30-verdict178" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670429-30-verdict178" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
