<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17600416-22">
               <interp inst="t17600416-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600416-22" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600416-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600416"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600416-22" type="date" value="17600416"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600416-22-off140-c197" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600416-22-defend236 t17600416-22-off140 t17600416-22-verdict143"></join>
         
               <p>155. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17600416-22-defend236" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Lloyd 
                  <interp inst="t17600416-22-defend236" type="surname" value="Lloyd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-22-defend236" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-22-defend236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17600416-22-off140" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600416-22-off140" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-22-off140" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing thirty yards of woollen cloth, value 40 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17600416-22-victim238" type="victimName">
                     Joseph 
                     Swain 
                  <interp inst="t17600416-22-victim238" type="surname" value="Swain"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-22-victim238" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-22-victim238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600416-22-off140 t17600416-22-victim238"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17600416-22-cd141" type="crimeDate">March 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600416-22-off140 t17600416-22-cd141"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600416-22-person239">
                  Daniel 
                  Rider 
               <interp inst="t17600416-22-person239" type="surname" value="Rider"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-22-person239" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-22-person239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Whitecross Street, by Cripplegate. I had been to the fire in <placeName id="t17600416-22-crimeloc142">Lad Lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17600416-22-crimeloc142" type="placeName" value="Lad Lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17600416-22-crimeloc142" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600416-22-off140 t17600416-22-crimeloc142"></join>, on the 2d of March. I came back on the Sunday morning, about half an hour after two. The prisoner came by me as I stood at the White Horse door, a publick-house; he had been gone out of that house about half an hour before. I had seen him there.</p>
               <p>Q. How near is that house to where the fire was?</p>
               <p>Rider. I take it to be about a quarter of a mile. As he came by my door, he had this piece of cloth under his left arm. (A piece of woollen cloth produced.) I said to two women that were standing there, I believed here was a thief coming from the fire. One of the woman knew him, and said he was just gone from the White Horse. They wanted me to stop him, but I thought it was dangerous at that time of the morning. As one of them knew where he lodged, I thought it best to let him alone till day light. I got up the same morning about 9, and told people of it, and they blamed me for not stopping him. I went to the fire about 11 o'clock, and found a man belonging to Mr. Swain, who told me his master had lost such stuff. They got a warrant, in order to take up the prisoner. We went to his lodgings in Old Street with the constable, who knock'd at the door, and the prisoner got off his bed.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>Rider. This was about 2 o'clock in the day; he opened the door, and said he knew what we were come about, you come about this piece of stuff that I have got; it was locked up in a box, and his wife was gone out with the key. He called her up. She brought the key, and he delivered the piece to us. The constable took charge of the prisoner, whom we took before the justice, and he committed him.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he say he had it?</p>
               <p>Rider. He said he had it from the Swan with two necks Yard. Mr. Swain has a warehouse in that yard.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600416-22-person240">
                  John 
                  Willis 
               <interp inst="t17600416-22-person240" type="surname" value="Willis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-22-person240" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-22-person240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This piece of woollen cloth is the property of Mr. Swain.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Willis. I live with Mr. Swain, as a clerk.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you lose any such cloth as this at the fire?</p>
               <p>Willis. We lost a great many goods that night. This piece was thrown over the gallery amongst the mob. Many of the people took them to their own houses, and restored them again the next day, or two or three days after.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you deliver any pieces to people that you did not know?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176004160027"></xptr>Willis. I did many, to people I never saw before.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Willis. I do not. We lost a great many pieces.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I happened to be in this yard at the time of the fire. A man came and desired me to lend him a hand with some goods that lay under the piazza's. We rolled out one pack into the street, with some more help. After that I came into the yard again, and a man gave me this piece of stuff, and bid me carry it away. I do not know the man, he was a stranger to me; he said take care of it. I went to go along with other people, and not knowing where they carried theirs to, going through the croud, I lost fight of them. Then I did not know what to do with it; but I knowing my wife was well acquainted with the gentleman that keeps the Swan with two Necks, where I had it, I thought I would carry it home, and my wife should carry it the next day. When they came for it, I did not deny having it.</p>
               <p>To his Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600416-22-person241">
                  John 
                  Lee 
               <interp inst="t17600416-22-person241" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-22-person241" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-22-person241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about three years, or better.</p>
               <p>Q. What is he?</p>
               <p>Lee. He is a bricklayer, and has work'd for me almost two years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Lee. He is a very industrious honest man.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is it since he work'd for you?</p>
               <p>Lee. I believe it is pretty near a year ago.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600416-22-person242">
                  William 
                  Norman 
               <interp inst="t17600416-22-person242" type="surname" value="Norman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-22-person242" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-22-person242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner two years, or upwards.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Norman. I never knew nothing but that he was as honest a man as ever I employed, and I have had three score at a time. He has been to work at places where he had an opportunity of carrying away six times the value of this cloth. I sincerely believe he did it with no other intent but to carry it back again. His wife was born in the same town as the man that keeps the inn. If I thought he did not intend to carry the cloth again, I would not have gone over the threshold of my door to speak for him.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he work for you last?</p>
               <p>Lee. He work'd for me at the same time, the time of the fire.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600416-22-person243">
                  Richard 
                  Grace 
               <interp inst="t17600416-22-person243" type="surname" value="Grace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-22-person243" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-22-person243" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner is a tenant of mine, and has been these two years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character?</p>
               <p>Grace. I know very little of him; he pays me my rent, and I have seen him come and go very orderly to his work. I never heard to the contrary but that he was an honest man, and I have seen him industrious.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Grace. I am a carpenter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600416-22-person244">
                  John 
                  Southwell 
               <interp inst="t17600416-22-person244" type="surname" value="Southwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-22-person244" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-22-person244" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner almost two years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Southwell. I never knew or heard but that he was an honest man. I have trusted him in my house and he never wronged me of a pin's point, he might have wrong'd me of a great deal if he would.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600416-22-person245">
                  William 
                  Sell 
               <interp inst="t17600416-22-person245" type="surname" value="Sell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-22-person245" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-22-person245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about a year and a half.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Sell. He is an honest hard working man, to maintain his wife and family.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600416-22-verdict143" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600416-22-verdict143" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
