<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610225-12">
               <interp inst="t17610225-12" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610225-12" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610225-12" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610225"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610225-12" type="date" value="17610225"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610225-12-off57-c89" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-12-defend108 t17610225-12-off57 t17610225-12-verdict60"></join>
         
               <p>89. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610225-12-defend108" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Newman 
                  <interp inst="t17610225-12-defend108" type="surname" value="Newman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-defend108" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-defend108" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            . was indicted for <rs id="t17610225-12-off57" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-off57" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-off57" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one bed-side carpet, value 9 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17610225-12-victim110" type="victimName">
                     David 
                     Stautsbury 
                  <interp inst="t17610225-12-victim110" type="surname" value="Stautsbury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-victim110" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-victim110" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-12-off57 t17610225-12-victim110"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17610225-12-cd58" type="crimeDate">February 9. 1760</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-12-off57 t17610225-12-cd58"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-12-person111">
                  David 
                  Stautsbury 
               <interp inst="t17610225-12-person111" type="surname" value="Stautsbury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-person111" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-person111" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am <rs id="t17610225-12-viclabel59" type="occupation">an auctioneer, and dealer in household goods</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-12-victim110 t17610225-12-viclabel59"></join>; I live in Whitechapel. On Saturday the 9th of February, 1760, about ten o'clock, I was coming to Will's Coffee-house, I met the prisoner? he said, You have got a little beautiful chest in your warehouse, what will you have for it? I said seven guineas; but, said I, let us go and take a dish of coffee. We went into Will's Coffee-house, and there bargained for the chest; upon which I took a note, and gave him an order to receive the chest. I wrote to my brother, to deliver to the bearer, Mr. Newman, that large mahogony chest. Mr. Newman afterwards shewed that order before my lord mayor. I did not come home till ten or eleven o'clock that night; but on the Monday morning, I went into the warehouse to look round; and said, George, have you sent that chest to Mr. Newman; he said, I have, but we miss the carpet. I said, when did you miss it? He said, just after the chest was gone. I asked him where the chest was carried to; he said, to Mr. Milner's. I went there two or three days after, and in about a month after, I was there, and went up into the dining room, and from the chamber door, on the left hand, I saw a bed side carpet; I said, that looks like mine. Mrs. Milner said, we bought that in the city. I said, it is hard that I should get no money at all, and lose my carpet into the bargain.</p>

               <p>Q. Was the prisoner by at the time?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250010"></xptr>Stoutsbury. He was, said Mr. Milner, you had better hold your tongue, we shall do so and so. Then I came away, and afterwards went to Hicks's-Hall, and there preferred a bill of indictment against the prisoner, for stealing my carpet; I knew that carpet which I saw there to be mine.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you know it; by what marks?</p>
               <p>Stoutsbury. There was a large ink spot upon it, an ink-stand had fallen upon it.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure it was your carpet?</p>
               <p>Stoutsbury. I really think it was, by that mark and the pattern too; but by that mark in particular.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known the prisoner at the bar?</p>
               <p>Stoutsbury. I have known him better than 12 months, or a year and half; I had but very little acquaintance with him before.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you had any knowledge of him?</p>
               <p>Stoutsbury. I have not known him above two years.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you known him six months before this affair?</p>
               <p>Stoutsbury. I cannot say indeed.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you never dealt with him before, upon your oath?</p>
               <p>Stoutsbury. I had never dealt with him in my life-time before, and I wish I had not dealt with him then.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never borrow money of him?</p>
               <p>Stoutsbury. I never borrowed a shilling of him in my life time, as I have a soul to be saved.</p>
               <p>Counsel. I must ask you how this chest was paid for?</p>
               <p>Stoutsbury. By this note, which has never been paid. [Producing a note.]</p>
               <p>Counsel. [takes it in his hand.] Here is a note signed by one Perry, promising to pay to 
               <persName id="t17610225-12-person112">
                  John 
                  Christmas 
               <interp inst="t17610225-12-person112" type="surname" value="Christmas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-person112" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-person112" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , or order.</p>
               <p>Stoutsbury. This note was 12 l. 13 s. too much, so I gave him a note of hand for the remainder of the money. I said, why will you not give me your indorsement upon it; said he, I have a reason for that; but, said he, you will be paid, you know I will not wrong you.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you give for the difference?</p>
               <p>Stoutsbury. He had the chest, which was seven guineas, and he had my note, bearing date for the 12 l. 13 s. three months after date.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you give him a note for 12 l. 13 s. as a note payable to him, or order; or in this manner; Received of such a one, such a note of 20 l. seven guineas of which is for a chest, and the remainder of which I promise to pay, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Stoutsbury. I gave him a negotiable note, I was weak enough to do it.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see the carpet?</p>
               <p>Stoutsbury. I cannot ascertain the time.</p>
               <p>Counsel. As near as you can recollect?</p>
               <p>Stoutsbury. It might be about a month after.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you mention to the prisoner, that this carpet you saw, was supposed to be stolen?</p>
               <p>Stoutsbury. I declared that was the carpet I had been robbed of. I was sure it was my carpet.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you make any such declaration as this: I am a friend to Mr. Newman, and cannot afford to let him have the carpet with the chest. I must be paid separate for the carpet?</p>
               <p>Stoutsbury. No, never.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not say the price of the carpet was seven shillings and sixpence?</p>
               <p>Stoutsbury. No; I never said for in my life</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never receive seven shillings and six-pence for it?</p>
               <p>Stoutsbury. No, never.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did it use, to?</p>
               <p>Stoutsbury. For a week before, it generally lay on the chest that I sold the prisoner, to keep it from damage.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you never seen Mr. Newman before the month of March following?</p>
               <p>Stoutsbury. Yes; and when I came home, I declared I would prosecute him; and so I did before his face.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you not prosecute sooner?</p>
               <p>Stoutsbury. I had a great many of my notes in their hands, and I was afraid to go on till I got some of the notes out of their hands.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you indict him at Hicks's-Hall?</p>
               <p>Stoutsbury. I did not indict him there till July.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen him often since July.</p>
               <p>Stoutsbury. I have a great many times since.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you take him up?</p>
               <p>Stoutsbury. I took him up the 10th of this instant February; I will give you a good reason for that; I had been arrested in the Court of Common-pleas.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you arrested on the note for the 12 l. 13 s.?</p>
               <p>Stoutsbury. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever apprehend Mr. Newman for this felony, till after you was arrested on this note for 12 l. 13 s.</p>
               <p>Stoutsbury. No, they arrested me after I indicted him.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250011"></xptr>Q. When he treated with you about that chest, was there no mention made about any thing else?</p>
               <p>Stoutsbury. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the carpet damaged by the ink?</p>
               <p>Stoutsbury. No, it was-a-bran new one.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-12-person113">
                  George 
                  Stoutsbury 
               <interp inst="t17610225-12-person113" type="surname" value="Stoutsbury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-person113" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-person113" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am brother to the prosecutor. I remember the prisoner coming to me with an order for a cloaths-chest.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>G Stoutsbury. I attend my brother's shop in his absence. I said to the prisoner when he brought the order, there it stands; there was a carpet upon it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any body else in your shop at that time?</p>
               <p>G. Stoutsbury. No, nobody but the prisoner and myself. I said to him our porter has not been at work to-day. He bid me fetch one. Then he said, George, took a quarter of brandy. I went and fetch it at a public-house, and left him above in the shop.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was you gone?</p>
               <p>G. Stoutsbury. I was gone I believe about three minutes; when I came with the brandy, the chest who at the door, and a porter was come. We all three drank each a glass, and I helped the chest on the poiter's back, and away he and the prisoner went together.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did they go to?</p>
               <p>G. Stoutsbury. That I did not know till the portor came back again. I asked him where he had carried it to. He said to Mr. Milner's, in my life-street.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you miss the carpet?</p>
               <p>G. Stoutsbury. I missed that directly almost. We always regulate the Shop on a night I said, when I missed it, nobody could have it but Mr. Newman. I did not tell my brother of it that night, for four of uneasiness; but on the Monday morning I said to him, I believe Mr. Newman has got the carpet; and all my brother said was, he would endeavour to find it out, and if he did he would prosecute Newman.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he not say he had bargained with him for a carpet?</p>
               <p>G. Stoutsbury. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Newman bargain with you for a carpet?</p>
               <p>G. Stoutsbury. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in the shop all that day?</p>
               <p>G. Stoutsbury. I was, I said in the shop till the evening, and then I shut up the shop myself. I do not imagine any body could take it, but the prisoner on the person.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there no conversation between Mr. Newman and you as that time, that as it was a fine piece of mahogany, that carpet belonged to the chest, that it might not get damage?</p>
               <p>G. Stoutsbury. No not to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you did not tell him at that time, you did not know whether he was to have the carpet along with it; and he told you he must have the carpet along with the chest?</p>
               <p>G. Stoutsbury. I remember nothing of that.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether Mr. Newman did not insist upon it, that the carpet that lay on the chest was part of what he purchased, and he was to have it along with the chest?</p>
               <p>G. Stoutsbury. He never mentioned any such thing to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether, or not, you yourself did not say to Mr. Newman: Sir, you may take it along with the chest if you please, and you may pay my brother for it when you meet?</p>
               <p>G. Stoutsbury. I do not know that I said such a word.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Mr. 
               <persName id="t17610225-12-person114">
                  George 
                  Gardener 
               <interp inst="t17610225-12-person114" type="surname" value="Gardener"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-person114" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-person114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>G. Stoutsbury. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath, have you not declared to him, that at the time Mr. Newman came for the chest, it was to cover it: that Mr. Newman might take it along with him, and pay your brother if he had not bargained for it?</p>
               <p>G. Stoutsbury. I never told him so to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Counsel for prisoner. Supposing such an accident had happened, that you had indulged a person with a carpet in order to carry goods home in it, is it not usual to have them sent home again?</p>
               <p>G. Stoutsbury. There was no such thing proposed.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a chest was it?</p>
               <p>G. Stoutsbury. It was a long cloaths-chest, with two drawers at the bottom of it.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was the carpet?</p>
               <p>G. Stoutsbury. It might be about three feet long, and three quarters of a yard wide; it was just of a size to cover the chest.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it possible for that carpet to be on the chest when it was carried away, and you not see it?</p>
               <p>G. Stoutsbury. There was nothing at all upon the chest then.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had it laid on the chest in the shop?</p>
               <p>G. Stoutsbury. About two months.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had the chest been in your warehouse?</p>
               <p>G. Stoutsbury. That had been there about five months, to the best of my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there not things of more value in the warehouse, when you went for the brandy?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250012"></xptr>G. Stoutsbury. There were.</p>
               <p>Counsel. What! little things easily to be concealed?</p>
               <p>G. Stoutsbury. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you miss any thing else?</p>
               <p>G. Stoutsbury. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Now, upon your oath, was this carpet taken away without your knowledge?</p>
               <p>G. Stoutsbury. Upon my oath it was.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-12-person115">
                  John 
                  Keeble 
               <interp inst="t17610225-12-person115" type="surname" value="Keeble"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-person115" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-person115" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a porter. My Mr. Stoutsbury's sister came for me to carry this chest.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a chest was it?</p>
               <p>Keeble. It was a large mahogany chest: 
               <persName id="t17610225-12-person116">
                  George 
                  Stoutsbury 
               <interp inst="t17610225-12-person116" type="surname" value="Stoutsbury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-person116" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-person116" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave me orders to carry it, and the prisoner went all the way along with me, and stopped where I rested. I carried it to Mr. Milner's, overagainst the old playhouse, about three quarters of a mile from Mr. Stoutsbury's house.</p>
               <p>Q. What was about it?</p>
               <p>Keeble. I brought a cord of my own, and bound it about it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any thing else upon it?</p>
               <p>Keeble. No, nothing but my rope.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there nothing about it to prevent the cord from gauling of it?</p>
               <p>Keeble. No, there was not, I am sure of that.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any mention made about your carrying a carpet at the same time?</p>
               <p>Keeble. No, there was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you there when George went for the brandy?</p>
               <p>Keeble. I was there about half a minute before he went for it.</p>
               <p>Q. Who helped you up with the chest?</p>
               <p>Keeble. They both did.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember when you was going to tie up the chest, how Mr. Newman came by the keys of the chest?</p>
               <p>Keeble. The keys I never saw, it was locked before I came.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-12-person117">
                  William 
                  Gee 
               <interp inst="t17610225-12-person117" type="surname" value="Gee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-person117" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-person117" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have been a linnen-draper; Mr. Newman and Mr Milner were with me, and Mr. Milner said Mr. Newman had bought a chest, and had taken a carpet and put into the chest.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he mention this, as a serious matter?</p>
               <p>Gee. He spoke of it in a laughing way; he did not mention it as if Mr. Newman had purchased it, but laughed at it.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this this conversation with you?</p>
               <p>Gee. It was after the indictment was found at Hicks's-hall.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he speak of it as a matter necessary to be concealed, that Mr. Newman might not be prosecuted.</p>
               <p>Gee. Not at all; he smil'd, and told me there was a prosecution against Mr. Newman.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he mention it as a trick, or that Mr. Newman intended to steal it.</p>
               <p>Gee. No, there was not a word of that.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I bought this chest at Will's coffee-house of Mr. Stoutsbury, and received an order fr om him to have it delivered to me. I went with the order, and delivered it to his brother George. Very well, he said, where shall I send it? I said to Mr. Milner's, where I lodge. There were two gentlemen present, whom I never saw before nor after. There lay a carpet upon it, about the size of the chest. I said, George, does this carpet belong to the chest as a covering, to preserve it from scratches? He answered, Sir, whether it does belong to the chest or not I can't determine, but you may take it; and if my brother can't afford to give it you into the chest, you and he will have no difference about such a trifle as that; I know you will pay him for it the first time you see him. Then I said, Let it lay on the chest, it will keep the rope from chasing it. He sent for a porter by a girl that he called sister; then he said, No, do not let it lay on the chest, but let us see if there be no Bank-notes at the bottom of the chest. He opened the drawers, and pulled out some loose papers; then he said, The best way will be to put the carpet into the drawer. I put it in, and he locked it up, and gave the key to me; this was before the porter came: then he said, It is unlucky to have a dry bargain: we both went out together to the publick-house, and had a quartern of brandy, and before it was drank the porter came, and had the remainder of it. The porter carried the chest to my lodging, and about two or three days afterwards David came to Mr. Milner's, and said, How do you like your chest? I said, Very well, but I think it is dear. He began with a great deal of his, As I hope to be saved, it is very cheap; I cannot afford the carpet my brother gave you into the bargain. I said, I'll pay you for it, but have not the money about me now. He said he wished it was as many hundred pounds, and went away. He came after<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250013"></xptr> that to Mr. Milner's; I said, As you cannot afford to give me the carpet into the chest, tell me what you must have for it. He said, Seven shillings and six-pence. I borrowed half a crown of Mrs. Milner, and gave him the seven shillings and six-pence for the carpet; I had at the same time a note on him for twelve pounds thirteen shillings; this note was become due, and was in the possession of Mr. Wright, a carpenter: he was asked for the money, and proposed to pay it in a day or two: after that he called upon him three or four times; then he said he would not pay it at all, for he would indict me for stealing a carpet. This transaction was in July, and in February he found this indictment: he paid no regard to it when called upon, so was arrested, and is now under bail; I have now the note in my pocket, and no consideration for it.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Milner. The prisoner has boarded at our house upwards of a year.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know 
               <persName id="t17610225-12-person118">
                  David 
                  Stoasbury 
               <interp inst="t17610225-12-person118" type="surname" value="Stoasbury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-person118" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-person118" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Milner. I do very well, and have about three years. I remember Mr. Newman having a chest sent home to our house, I believe it is above a year ago; there was a carpet in one of the drawers: a little boy that I have, about twelve years old, went up with the key, and took it out.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any attempt made to conceal it?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Milner. No, there was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember Mr. Stoatsbury coming to your house after that?</p>

               <p>Mrs. Milner. I do, it was three or four days after: he asked Mr. Newman how he liked the chest, and he asked me how I liked it. I said, It is not for my liking, it is for the young gentleman's liking; then Mr. Stoatsbury said, Mr. Newman, I cannot afford to give that carpet in with the chest that my brother sent home. Mr. Newman said, If you can't, what will you have for it? He answered, seven shillings and sixpence, but he always sold them for nine shillings. Mr. Newman said, Give me change. The other said, Never mind it; if it was for an hundred pounds I should not mind it. He has come to my house to borrow money, four or five pounds at a time.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear him say he had borrowed money of Newman?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Milner. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of this carpet being paid for?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Milner. I saw it paid for, it was about two months after it was brought to our house. I can't tell justly the time, but I know it was in warm weather, we had no fire in the parlour. I remember Mr. Newman said to him, Now I will pay you for the carpet, and put his hand in his pocket, and had not silver enough. He said to Mr. Milner, Lend me two shillings, or half a crown; he lent it him, and he paid for the carpet.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Newman tell Mr. Milner he had stole or trick'd the prosecutor out of a carpet?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Milner. No; the chest and carpet were put in a two-pair of stairs room, and Mr. Stoatsbury was never in that room in his life, he has been in the dining-room several times.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever know of his challenging the carpet by a spot of ink?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Milner. No, I never did, there is no spot of ink upon it: there came four fellows, George was one of them, and he saw that in my room. Here is the carpet, he said; he said he would swear to that which lay by my bed-side: then the constable went up stairs, and brought down that which lay upon the chest. Then George said, He could not swear to that. Said the constable, Have you any private mark upon it? No, said he, I have not. They looked upon it, and turned it about; there was no difference in the two for length and breadth.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you wife to Mr. Milner in Ayliffe-street?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Milner. I am.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he lend Mr Newman the half-crown to pay for the carpet?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Milner. He did, it came to 7 s. 6 d.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is your husband, why is he not here?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Milner. He is in an ill state of health, I can give a good reason why he is not here.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your reason?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Milner. One of my husband's bail is a bankrupt, and he thought the other might surrender him up.</p>
               <p>Q. Has not your husband been here in the court within this hour?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Milner. No, he has not.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he not been attending here with you the whole day?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Milner. No, he has not.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he leave you?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Milner. He left me about four or five in the afternoon. He was obliged to go away, because he was afraid he should be surrendered.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did not you bring the carpet here with you?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250014"></xptr>Mrs. Milner. I had a good mind to bring them both, but I did not know whether it was proper.</p>
               <p>Q. Is the constable here?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Milner. I have not seen him here.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the chest when it was brought into your house?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Milner. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any thing upon it?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Milner. No, there was only a rope and a wrapper tied about it.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you first see the carpet?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Milner. I saw no carpet till it was spread on the chest by the little boy.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is Mr. Newman's room?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Milner. Up two pair of stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. Does your bed-chamber join to your dining-room?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Milner. It does.</p>
               <p>Q. Has Mr. Stoatsbury been in that room?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Milner. He has, but not when he came to Mr. Newman about the carpet, for the difference about that was in a little room below stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. Is not there a great friendship between your husband, and the prisoner at the bar?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Milner. Yes, there is; my husband will do any thing, consistent with reason; to serve him.</p>
               <p>Q. How came it he did not stay to serve him now?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Milner. I have told the reason.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not the prisoner partner with your husband once?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Milner. He was about three years ago, but that is dissolved now.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not the carpet in question in your bed-chamber?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Milner. No, never till it was brought down by the constable.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-12-person119">
                  Geo 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17610225-12-person119" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-person119" type="given" value="Geo"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-person119" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had a note drawn by 
               <persName id="t17610225-12-person120">
                  David 
                  Stoutsbury 
               <interp inst="t17610225-12-person120" type="surname" value="Stoutsbury"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-person120" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-person120" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             paid to me by Mr. Newman.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this note. [He takes one in his hand.]</p>
               <p>Wright. I believe this is the very same note.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it ever paid?</p>
               <p>Wright. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Who had you it of?</p>
               <p>Wright. I had it of the person to whom it was indors'd. It became due May the 12th. He promised me he would pay it in about a week's time. I believe I attended him near two months by different appointments, and, at last, he told me he would not pay me at all. In several times coming he never found any fault with the note at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say what he would do if the note was put in suit against him?</p>
               <p>Wright. He said, they tell me Mr. Milner and Mr. Newman are two bad men, and he would transport one, or both, of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he give any reason why he would not pay it?</p>
               <p>Wright. Not till the last time of seeing him, then he said he had no value for it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-12-person121">
                  Miles 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17610225-12-person121" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-person121" type="given" value="Miles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-person121" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I arrested Mr. Stoatsbury on a note of hand, on the 29th of July last, for Mr. Newman.</p>
               <p>Council for the Crown. Our indictment was found July 7.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-12-person122">
                  William 
                  Kemp 
               <interp inst="t17610225-12-person122" type="surname" value="Kemp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-person122" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-person122" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The warrant for taking Mr. Newman was backed Feb 10, 1761; that is six months distance, then he was taken.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610225-12-verdict60" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610225-12-verdict60" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
