<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17630114-1">
               <interp inst="t17630114-1" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630114-1" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630114-1" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17630114"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17630114-1" type="date" value="17630114"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17630114-1-off2-c30" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630114-1-defend31 t17630114-1-off2 t17630114-1-verdict5"></join>
         
               <p>39. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17630114-1-defend31" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     West 
                  <interp inst="t17630114-1-defend31" type="surname" value="West"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-1-defend31" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-1-defend31" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17630114-1-deflabel1" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630114-1-defend31 t17630114-1-deflabel1"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17630114-1-off2" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630114-1-off2" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-1-off2" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one pair of muslin ruffles, val. 1 s. one piece of muslin worked for ruffles, val. 1 s. seven muslin handkerchiefs, val. 10 s. four pair of cotton stockings, val. 4 s. one pair of cotton mittins, one silk handkerchief, half a yard of black sattin, two muslin caps, one gause cap, two cotton aprons, and one sword knot made of gold twist and silk
            </rs>, the property of 
               <persName id="t17630114-1-victim32" type="victimName">
                  Thomas 
                  Hill 
               <interp inst="t17630114-1-victim32" type="surname" value="Hill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-1-victim32" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-1-victim32" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630114-1-off2 t17630114-1-victim32"></join>
                  </persName>
             , <rs id="t17630114-1-cd3" type="crimeDate">Nov. 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630114-1-off2 t17630114-1-cd3"></join>.~</p>
               <p>Thomas Hill. I live in <placeName id="t17630114-1-crimeloc4">Chandois-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17630114-1-crimeloc4" type="placeName" value="Chandois-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17630114-1-crimeloc4" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17630114-1-off2 t17630114-1-crimeloc4"></join>, the prisoner lived servant with me from the 17th of Sept. to the 23d of Nov. I had reason to suspect her robbing us, my wife had lost half a guinea out of her pocket from under the pillow, and we had found our drawers open, and missed money at several times; the prisoner was taxed with taking the money, she confest to the taking a half guinea; (that is not in the indictment) she gave warning to go away, and when she was going, I asked her for the key of her box, that I might see what was in it; it being too dark to look then, I let her take the key away, but she left the box; the next morning a woman, whom she called sister, brought me the key; the woman said she had forced the key from her, then we opened the box and found the things mentioned in the indictment, except the two cotton apron which were found by her direction at a pawnbroker's, mentioning<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176301140003"></xptr> them by name) then we sent for the prisoner, she owned they were not her property.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do upon that?</p>
               <p>Hill. I did not send for a constable, my wife persuaded me to the contrary. She pleaded with and said she was big, and my wife being child herself, would fain have excused her it on her power, but I would not agree to it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any money given?</p>
               <p>Hill. I know no farther than what my wife told me, which was, that she had received 2 guineas and a half of the prisoner, for the money she had taken from out of the drawers.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this told you?</p>
               <p>Hill. My wife told me this some time after.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she permitted to go away that day without being taken into custody?</p>
               <p>Hill. She was, and she went to some house in the neighbourhood.</p>
               <p>Q. How long might she remain in that house?</p>
               <p>Hill. I believe it might be about a month before I took her up.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you take her up?</p>
               <p>Hill. I took her up the 27th of Dec.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to take her up then?</p>
               <p>Hill. Because I could not be quiet in my house for her, she came abusing and threatening me, threatening to pull my sign down, and to get a constable for me, otherwise I should not have meddled with her.</p>
               <p>Q. How does this agree with what you said your wife persuaded you not to prosecute her, and you would not agree to it?</p>
               <p>Hill. Had she gone away I believe I should not have taken her up.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do with her when you did take her up?</p>
               <p>Hill. I carried her before Sir 
               <persName id="t17630114-1-person33">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17630114-1-person33" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-1-person33" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-1-person33" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you consent for her to go away?</p>
               <p>Hill. I never did for or against it.</p>
               <p>Q. Has this money been returned to the prisoner since?</p>
               <p>Hill No, my wife has kept it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she own she had taken the things that were found at the pawnbrokers?</p>
               <p>Hill. She did. They were found at Mr. Keats, a pawnbroker, in Charles-street, on the 23d of Nov.</p>
               <p>Racheal Hill. I am wife to the prosecutor. I missed several things during the time the prisoner was with me, unknown to my husband, 14 handkerchiefs from out of my drawers, and a great many other things, and money at several times, half guineas at a time, and silver. On the day that she would go away, she came to me, and said, Here is the key of my box, see that I have not got any of your things. I called my husband, and said, Here is your maid going away, she wants you to look in her box. The woman that brought the key was there; she said, Sally confess, for I know you are a thief.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>R. Hill. This was on the 23d of Nov. in the afternoon between 4 and 5 o'clock; before we knew what was in the box, she and the woman went up with my husband to look in the box. I staid below, they came down again, and my husband said it was too dark to look into it, and that they had not looked in it; they went away. The next day, that woman came with the key, and said she would have us look into the box, and certainly we should find some of our things in it, She said, She has been a notorious girl to you. She, I, and another woman, and a gentleman, went to the box; I opened it, there I found the things mentioned in the indictment, except the 2 cotton aprons, which were found at the pawnbrokers. ( Produced in court and deposed to) I desired the woman that she called sister to go and bring her; she did: then the prisoner went on her knees, and begged hard, and said, If I would let her go, she would go to Bath, and never come here any more. My husband and I had a great many words about it.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say about the two aprons?</p>
               <p>R. Hill. She owned she took them out of my drawers, and pawned them for 4 s. with that money she bought a pair of shoes. I desired her to tell me, where my shifts and other things were, and said, if she would I would get her out of the way of her master. I said, how much money have you got? it is very hard I should be robbed in this manner; she said, she had none. My husband went to see his Majesty go to the house in his new coach, and in his absence they begged of me to take 2 guineas and an half, and the sister and she said, she would go out of London and never be seen here any more. After that she never would tell me where my things were, but came abusing me and my husband, and said, I encouraged her in this thing; then her master declared, he would not be kept off from prosecuting her any longer. I said, it would kill me to have her taken up; he said, if it killed me he would take her up.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you first tell your husband you had taken the money?</p>
               <p>R. Hill. I told him the same afternoon. He said, if I took an hundred guineas, he would answer to none of it, he would screen no roguery of<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176301140004"></xptr> that kind. What I did was out of pity; I did not think I was doing any thing amiss.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630114-1-person34">
                  John
               <interp inst="t17630114-1-person34" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-1-person34" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             M'dowell. I was present when Mrs. Hill opened the box, and saw these things taken out.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17630114-1-person35">
                  Alexander 
                  Grigg 
               <interp inst="t17630114-1-person35" type="surname" value="Grigg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-1-person35" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17630114-1-person35" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to Mr. Keats's, the pawnbroker, with the prisoner, she demanded the two aprons, and they were delivered to her; they were owned by Mrs. Hill as her property.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing of the things.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17630114-1-verdict5" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17630114-1-verdict5" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
