<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17651211-38">
               <interp inst="t17651211-38" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651211-38" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651211-38" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17651211"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651211-38" type="date" value="17651211"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17651211-38-off219-c265" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-38-defend350 t17651211-38-off219 t17651211-38-verdict223"></join>
         
               <p>42. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17651211-38-defend350" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Atkins 
                  <interp inst="t17651211-38-defend350" type="surname" value="Atkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-38-defend350" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-38-defend350" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17651211-38-off219" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651211-38-off219" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-38-off219" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a silver shirt buckle set with diamonds, value 10 l. and a gold ring with an emerald set with diamonds
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17651211-38-victim352" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Edwards 
                  <interp inst="t17651211-38-victim352" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-38-victim352" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-38-victim352" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-38-off219 t17651211-38-victim352"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17651211-38-cd220" type="crimeDate">November 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-38-off219 t17651211-38-cd220"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>Mrs. Edwards. I am wife to the prosecutor, we live in <placeName id="t17651211-38-crimeloc221">Long-acre</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17651211-38-crimeloc221" type="placeName" value="Long-acre"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17651211-38-crimeloc221" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-38-off219 t17651211-38-crimeloc221"></join>. The prisoner was <rs id="t17651211-38-deflabel222" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-38-defend350 t17651211-38-deflabel222"></join> to us near 5 months, since the beginning of June last On the 10th of November he absconded; we did not suspect he had wronged us till the 13th; then Mr. Davidson, a pawn broker, brought the buckle to our house, and asked us if we had lost such a thing. I know it; it was set with some diamonds which I had. He said it was brought to him by one 
               <persName id="t17651211-38-person353">
                  Thomas 
                  Atkins 
               <interp inst="t17651211-38-person353" type="surname" value="Atkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-38-person353" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-38-person353" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , that had been our servant.</p>
               <p>Mr. Davidson. I am a pawn-broker, and live by London-wall; the lad at the bar was brought up in our ward school: I knew he could not come honestly by the buckle, which he brought to my house the 5th of November to be valued. I was not at home, but my young man stopped it, and gave me an account that the prisoner brought it. On the Wednesday morning the prisoner came again, and said to me, as he did not offer it to pledge or sell, I had no right to stop it. I said, tell me how you came by it; I know you must have stole it, as he had told my young man that a jeweller had offered him 15 s. for it. He said a young woman gave it him upon her death-bed in Holborn. I said that would not do for me: where do you live? He said he lived at 'Squire Grant's in Long-acre. I desired his mother would come to satisfy me it was his own: he said she could not come till Sunday. She not coming, I advertised it on the Thursday. I sent, and could find no such person as 'Squire Grant in Long-acre. On the Wednesday in the afternoon the prisoner came with a gentleman, which I suppose was sent by one Lewis an attorney, to make a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176512110022"></xptr> legal demand of it. I did not deliver it; and on the Wednesday following a shabby sort of a fellow brought a writ, and served me with it, in the name of 
               <persName id="t17651211-38-person354">
                  Thomas 
                  Atkins 
               <interp inst="t17651211-38-person354" type="surname" value="Atkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-38-person354" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-38-person354" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I asked the man where this attorney lived; he said in New Ormand-street; that his name was Lewis: I went to him, he told me that Atkins was recommended to him by one Yates, clerk to a register-office, near Temple-bar. Lewis went there with me; Yates said it is the young gentleman's own buckle. Said Lewis, if you do not give him 7 or 8 guineas for the buckle, the writ is returnable on the Friday; said Yates, I can prove it to be the young man's own property: said I, do you know where he lives; he said he lived at the land fish-carriage-office in Long-acre, and that the young gentleman should not make it up; you have used him very ill. I went to Long-acre, and found Mr. Edwards; I asked if such a person lived with him; he said he went away on the Sunday, and he did not know where he was; then I shewed him that buckle; he said it was his buckle. We then went to Yates, who showed Mr. Edwards the diamond ring. Mr. Edwards said that was his property: Yates said he had lent the prisoner a guinea on it. We took the prisoner, and charged a constable with him, and brought him to the Compter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-38-person355">
                  James 
                  Yates 
               <interp inst="t17651211-38-person355" type="surname" value="Yates"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-38-person355" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-38-person355" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Harris, that keeps a lottery-office by St. Dunstan's Church; the prisoner came to our office one evening, in the beginning of November, and said he was going to the play, and asked me to take care of this ring; he said he had wore it 4 or 5 days, he was afraid of losing it; so I took it and put it on my finger, he said it was his own mother's ring before she married; then he said he should be obliged to me, if I would lend him a guinea: I said, you will not spend a guinea to night; said he, let me have a crown; so I did, he went to the play as I imagined; I gave Mr. 
               <persName id="t17651211-38-person356">
                  Lewis
               <interp inst="t17651211-38-person356" type="given" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-38-person356" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a guinea by his order, on account of an action that he was going to bring against one Lovet, for collaring of him; he never left the ring with me as a pledge: this guinea was some time before he left the ring with me.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to be so very officious in this affair?</p>
               <p>Yates. The boy came to me, and said he had been at London-wall to Mr. Davidson's, a pawnbroker, and said he had stopt a buckle that he had used to wear in his shirt; and that this he had done, because he owed the boy a spite when he was an apprentice. I said, did you offer to pawn it; he said no; but he had been there before to redeem a watch, and he only went then to ask the value of the buckle. The boy said the buckle was given him by a young woman (a cousin) that lived in Holborn, and that she was a milliner, and lived in credit; but he said, he could not prove by any body that she gave it him. I said, do you go to Mr. Davidson's, and I will tell him it is your property, and he will deliver it up.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray how long have you known the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Yates. I have known him eleven months, he always behaved with a good character.</p>
               <p>Court. You cannot be justified in giving yourself these airs with Mr. Davidson. (The buckle and ring produced.)</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs. Edwards. Look at these things, do you know them?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Edwards. I am certain the buckle and ring are mine.</p>
               <p>Q. Where had you used to keep them?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Edwards. I used to keep them in a small cabinet, that stands in my dining-room; there was no lock broke: I cannot tell which way the prisoner got at them. I suppose I might inadvertently have left the key in the door.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was cleaning the plate on the slab, these things lay behind the knife-case, in a little shagreen-case; I took it up, and saw what was in it: I did not think it was of any consequence. I put the buckle in my bosom, and went flashing among people that were smartish drest; after that I went to Mr. Yates: a young fellow there laid a wager it was not worth 3 s. and to decide the wager I went to Mr. Davidson, to know the value of it. I asked what it was worth, and said I had laid a wager about it. He stopped it, and said it was a diamond buckle; I went to Mr. Yates, and told him it was stopped; Mr. Yates said, if you will take an action out against Mr. Davidson, I will help you to a lawyer, and I will sware I saw the buckle given to you. One day I was disguised in liquor; Mr. Yates said if I would stay, he would take me to a house where I should lay all night; and I was going to the play with a young man: I asked him to take care of the ring, I did not ask him to lend me any money upon it; he lent me 4 s. I told him at the same time, I would not part with the ring upon any account.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17651211-38-verdict223" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651211-38-verdict223" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17651211-38-punish224" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651211-38-punish224" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-38-defend350 t17651211-38-punish224"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
