<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650918-41">
               <interp inst="t17650918-41" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650918-41" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650918-41" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650918"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650918-41" type="date" value="17650918"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650918-41-off217-c295" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-41-defend374 t17650918-41-off217 t17650918-41-verdict220"></join>
         
               <p>460. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17650918-41-defend374" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Jones 
                  <interp inst="t17650918-41-defend374" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-41-defend374" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-41-defend374" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17650918-41-off217" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650918-41-off217" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-41-off217" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing two guineas, one half guinea, and nine shillings in money, numbered
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17650918-41-victim376" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Davis 
                  <interp inst="t17650918-41-victim376" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-41-victim376" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-41-victim376" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-41-off217 t17650918-41-victim376"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17650918-41-cd218" type="crimeDate">February 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-41-off217 t17650918-41-cd218"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650918-41-person377">
                  John 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17650918-41-person377" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-41-person377" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-41-person377" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Hooley in Surrey. On the 21st of February the prisoner met me in Holbourn, and asked me if I wanted a place; that a gentleman's man had broke his leg; that he had put him in the hospital, and wanted another man, and said, that, if I would go, he would take me to the gentleman. He took me to the <placeName id="t17650918-41-crimeloc219">Two Blue Posts in Holbourn</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17650918-41-crimeloc219" type="placeName" value="Two Blue Posts in Holbourn"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17650918-41-crimeloc219" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-41-off217 t17650918-41-crimeloc219"></join>, and said he must stop there, for the gentleman, or his kinsman, were to be there. He went in and call'd for half a pint of wine: he said the gentleman's kinsman was to meet him there: he gave me a glass, and the kinsman came in, and began talking about tossing up, and how they came on the night before: he said he had lost six-and-twenty at tossing up with the butcher; he did not mention of what: the prisoner wanted him to toss up again; he said, I had very bad luck last night, and I can't toss up again; but however, he tossed with him for a guinea; they put a halfpenny under a hat, and tossed at what they call the best two in three; the prisoner got the guinea of him; the other pulled out a large purse, which seem'd full of money, and paid the guinea immediately; he went out, and said he had very bad luck; the prisoner wanted me to go his halves; he said it was only venturing, there was no danger but that I should get money; you see, says he, I get money; so I agreed, that if he won, he should give me six-pence, and if he lost, I would give him six-pence; the man came in again; they tossed; the prisoner won, and gave me six-pence; the other man went out again, and said he had bad luck; the prisoner wanted me to go more; he said, If you come to London. you must not mind a trifle; what is sixpence? you might as well get more as that; I had two guineas and a half, and nine shillings in silver; I put my hand into my pocket, and took my money out to see what silver I had; he said, Young man, that is just right, we will toss him for five pounds when he comes in again, we shall be sure to win, and put his hand upon mine: I said, that is all the money I have; I will not go all that; says he, You will be sure to win as much more; I did not consent to it; he took the money out of my hand; the man came in; they tossed up, and he said it is all gone, Davis: as soon as it was lost, the landlord came into the room, and said, Gentlemen, I understand you are gaming, and I beg you will go out of the house: the prisoner said, Come along, countryman, I'll lend you a guinea. and help you to a good place: they ran into Cursitor street, and said they would go to another house, and I should have the money again; but I lost them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you put the money on the board?</p>
               <p>Davis. It was in my hand, and he took my hand and held it, and kept talking to me all the while, that I should have the money again.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176509180028"></xptr>Q. Was the other man by?</p>
               <p>Davis. No; he came in afterwards, and then the prisoner said he would toss with him for ten pounds; I said nothing; I was frightened, and did not know what to do; and it was all done in so little a time: I described them to a shoemaker at the Rose-Tavern in Cursitor-street, who gave me their names; Justice Fielding granted me a warrant, and I took them up.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was coming up Holbourn; looking at the register-office, this man was there, and said there was nothing that would suit him; he wanted a place to look after a couple of horses; he asked me the way to Red Lion-Square; I told him I was going that way as far as the Blue Posts: we went there; I wish'd him a good night; he said, You have been very civil, Sir, and if you will take share of a pot of beer, you are welcome; I told him, I believed they did not sell beer there; but I was just going to have a glass of wine: I was just taking my leave of him, and in he came; I said. Now I will show you the readiest way to Red-Lion-Square: I was going to the door; my friend said to me, I shall not detain you long, if you will stay, and then you may shew the young man. I did not imagine I was going to gaming: the night before, I had been in his company, and he had lost some money; I had gone the young man's halves that won it of him; then he said, I was loser last night, and if you have a mind to give me a chance, I will toss now; he would not toss, unless I tossed for ten pounds: I told him I would not do that, without he would give me some odds; if you'll lay you guess three times out of four, I will lay you: the countryman said it was ten to one that no man could name three times out of four what a half-penny was; he pulled out all his money and laid it on the table, and his money and mine made eight or nine pounds, and we lost it. As I was lamentin g my ill luck, the landlord hearing me say it was unfortunate, he asked what was the matter; and said, Gentleman, I hope you have not been gaming; for he would not allow of it; the young fellow paid the reckoning: we went to the Rose in Cursitor-street; when we came there, the young fellow was not there: I told him he might find me at Mr. Jones's, opposite Sir 
               <persName id="t17650918-41-person378">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17650918-41-person378" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-41-person378" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-41-person378" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, where I lived. The first salutation I met with, was he and one of Sir 
               <persName id="t17650918-41-person379">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17650918-41-person379" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-41-person379" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-41-person379" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's men, with a warrant to take me up for playing at an unlawful game, for which he indicted me at Hicks's Hall: I had been committed, and was obliged to get bail: I have been in the Compter two months, for winning this money at an unlawful game, and now he swears a robbery: he swore that I cheated him out of it; but I did not take it forcibly away. I can produce copies of my commitment: this man, knowing I have friends, is led on to extort money from me. He offered to make it up for a guinea and a half, which I sent by one of Mr. Fielding's men; then he said, he would not make it up under the whole money.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. Where was the landlord?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. He was in another room; when he came in, the prisoner said, Come along, we must not stay here, and paid three-pence more than his reckoning.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to indict him for winning your money?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. He told me then that he had won it fairly.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you play with him?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No: says he, Countryman, put your money under the hat; then he said, D - n you, I have lost it all.</p>
               <p>Q. What was call'd?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I don't know whether it was heads or tails; but he said, It is all lost, Davey; don't grieve, I will lend you a guinea, and then he lost me.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17650918-41-verdict220" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650918-41-verdict220" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted of the robbery, and detained to be tried for a misdemeanor
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
