<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610225-10">
               <interp inst="t17610225-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610225-10" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610225-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610225"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610225-10" type="date" value="17610225"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610225-10-off47-c80" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-10-defend95 t17610225-10-off47 t17610225-10-verdict49"></join>
         
               <p>87. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610225-10-defend95" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Williams 
                  <interp inst="t17610225-10-defend95" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-10-defend95" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-10-defend95" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17610225-10-off47" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610225-10-off47" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-10-off47" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               cutting and breaking, with an intent to steal, two iron bars, value 8 d. and also for stealing one iron bar, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17610225-10-victim97" type="victimName">
                           Edward 
                           Ashhurst 
                        <interp inst="t17610225-10-victim97" type="surname" value="Ashhurst"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610225-10-victim97" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610225-10-victim97" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-10-off47 t17610225-10-victim97"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , fix'd to his dwelling-house
            </rs>, <rs id="t17610225-10-cd48" type="crimeDate">February 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-10-off47 t17610225-10-cd48"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-10-person98">
                  Richard 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17610225-10-person98" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-10-person98" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-10-person98" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Yesterday was se'ennight, about a quarter after nine at night, the maid and I were both up in the kitchen, we heard a thumping in the street; I went to the door, there was Mr Harris, who told me a person had been wrenching the bars of the window; we went to look, and found one bar quite off, and another loose; the window had three bars in length, and one a-cross.</p>
               <p>Q. How many window are there to the cellar?</p>
               <p>Jones. There are two.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your master's name?</p>
               <p>Jones. His name is 
               <persName id="t17610225-10-person99">
                  Edward 
                  Ashhurst 
               <interp inst="t17610225-10-person99" type="surname" value="Ashhurst"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-10-person99" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-10-person99" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he lives in Avemary-Lane; Mr. Harris said, if you look out, perhaps he will come again. I went out, and stood in a passage; the prisoner came from Ludgate-street, up the lane, and looked about him; then he fell to wrenching the bar again. I went over to him, and laid hold on his collar, and pulled him down in the kennel.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say for himself?</p>
               <p>Jones. He said he was making water.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he hold of the bar?</p>
               <p>Jones. I cannot swear that he had, he was stooping at the window.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was this after the time of thumping at the door?</p>
               <p>Jones. It was about six or eight minutes after, it could not be more.</p>
               <p>Q. Had Mr. Harris described the man that he saw to you?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250009"></xptr>Jones. He told me he was a dirty sort of man, with an apron before him; when I laid hold of him, the bar was quite loose.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-10-person100">
                  Tho 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17610225-10-person100" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-10-person100" type="given" value="Tho"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-10-person100" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Tuesday was se'ennight I was coming down Avemary-lane, I saw a man at Mr. Ashhurst's cellar window, either on his knees, or with his hands on the ground. I went to him, he stood upright, and pretended to be drunk. ||</p>
               <p>Q. Do you kn ow who that man was?</p>
               <p>Harris. It was the prisoner at the bar, he turned about to the wall, as if making water, I went past him, and he went off. Then I went to the window to look at the place where he was standing, to see if he had made water, he had not made water; but I found one of the bars was taken up from the window, which I had seen in its place not two hours before. I knocked at Mr. Ashurst's door, Mr. Jones came to me, I told him there had been a fellow breaking in at the cellar window, and desired he would put out his candles, and watch, and said I was going down Ludgate-hill, and would be back in a few minutes. On my coming back, Mr. Jones had secured the prisoner at the bar, and told me had carried him to the watch-house. I went to the watch-house, and found it to be the same man I had seen at the window before.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to take notice of this window, before you saw the prisoner at it?</p>
               <p>Harris. The window is within two yards of my door; I knew the three bars, and the cross bar, were all safe when we shut up shop about seven o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. How were the iron bars fastened to the window?</p>
               <p>Harris. They were fastened to the frame of the window.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>When I went to make water, they laid hold of me, and pulled me into an alehouse, before I could make water.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610225-10-verdict49" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610225-10-verdict49" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
