<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17601022-13">
               <interp inst="t17601022-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17601022-13" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17601022-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17601022"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17601022-13" type="date" value="17601022"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17601022-13-off77-c136" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-13-defend161 t17601022-13-off77 t17601022-13-verdict80"></join>
         
               <p>303. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17601022-13-defend161" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Pilmore 
                  <interp inst="t17601022-13-defend161" type="surname" value="Pilmore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-13-defend161" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-13-defend161" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17601022-13-off77" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17601022-13-off77" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-13-off77" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one stuff gown, value 6 d. one white petticoat, value 1 s. one pair of cotton stockings, value 1 s. one pair of stuff shoes, value 3 s. two colour'd aprons, one white apron, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17601022-13-victim163" type="victimName">
                           Elizabeth 
                           Murrell 
                        <interp inst="t17601022-13-victim163" type="surname" value="Murrell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17601022-13-victim163" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17601022-13-victim163" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  ; two linnen shirts, one pair of cotton stockings, one pair of worstead stockings, and one pocket-book
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17601022-13-victim165" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Price 
                  <interp inst="t17601022-13-victim165" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-13-victim165" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-13-victim165" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            . <rs id="t17601022-13-cd78" type="crimeDate">Oct. 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-13-off77 t17601022-13-cd78"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601022-13-person166">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Murrell 
               <interp inst="t17601022-13-person166" type="surname" value="Murrell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-13-person166" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-13-person166" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 7th of this month I was going to a lodging; I had some things that were loosish tied up in a bundle; I call'd to see Mr Price, it rained very hard; he desired me to stay all night; the prisoner at the bar lodg'd there; he took my things, and put them into Mr. Price's room.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>E. Murrell. At the <placeName id="t17601022-13-crimeloc79">Barley-mow in Milford lane, facing St. Mildred's church</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17601022-13-crimeloc79" type="placeName" value="Barley-mow in Milford lane, facing St. Mildred's church"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17601022-13-crimeloc79" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-13-off77 t17601022-13-crimeloc79"></join>; the prisoner desired me to leave the key of the room with him, saying, perhaps he might want to go to bed before Mr. Price came home; and I left the key with him, and went to Mr. Price, and he and I came back in the evening; when I came back the door was open, and Mr. Price's things and mine were gone.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you lose?</p>
               <p>E. Murrell. I lost a stuff gown, a white callaco quilted petticoat, a pair of cotton stockings, a pair of stuff shoes, two colour'd aprons, a white apron, and several other things not mentioned in the indictment.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever meet with them again?</p>
               <p>E. Murrell. I found them all again; I took the prisoner before justice 
               <persName id="t17601022-13-person167">
                  Welch
               <interp inst="t17601022-13-person167" type="given" value="Welch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-13-person167" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the next morning, there he confess'd the taking them, and sent his father and 
               <persName id="t17601022-13-person168">
                  John 
                  Rowell 
               <interp inst="t17601022-13-person168" type="surname" value="Rowell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-13-person168" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-13-person168" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to fetch them again, and they brought them again, only he had left two of my aprons at the Green Dragon.</p>
               <p>Q. Where had he carried your other things?</p>
               <p>E. Murrell. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>E. Murrell. He is a waiter, I believe.</p>
               <p>Q Where did he say he took the things from?</p>
               <p>E. Murrell. He own'd he took them from out of Mr. Price's lodgings.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601022-13-person169">
                  William 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17601022-13-person169" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-13-person169" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-13-person169" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodge at the Barley-mow in Milford lane; the prisoner lodg'd there with me; we took the lodging together, and were to give two shillings a week for the room. The day before those things were lost 
               <persName id="t17601022-13-person170">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Murrell 
               <interp inst="t17601022-13-person170" type="surname" value="Murrell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-13-person170" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-13-person170" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came with a bundle, and it rain'd, and we persuaded her to stay all night; she staid all night, having an acquaintance in the house; I went to Hungerford Market, and there staid the evening; between eight and nine she came to me; I came home with her about eleven; I miss'd out of the room two shifts, two neckcloths, two pair of stockings, one pocket-book, and a colour'd handkerchief; the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176010220017"></xptr> prisoner, upon being charg'd with taking them, own'd he did, and sent his father and 
               <persName id="t17601022-13-person171">
                  John 
                  Rowell 
               <interp inst="t17601022-13-person171" type="surname" value="Rowell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-13-person171" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-13-person171" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             for them; he own'd he took her things and mine all together; my white waistcoat he has pawned, his father since has brought it to me.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Please to enquire into that fellow's character; how he has lived for four years past, he has done nothing for a living but kept a Bawdy-house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601022-13-person172">
                  John 
                  Rowell 
               <interp inst="t17601022-13-person172" type="surname" value="Rowell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-13-person172" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-13-person172" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the prisoner to be a very honest young fellow, as any in England; I was with him before the justice; I went with his father, and we found two bundles at the Faulcon the corner of Gough's-square.</p>
               <p>Q What is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Rowell. I believe the last place he lived at was the Three Tuns in New street; (the goods produc'd in court, and depos'd to by their respective owners)</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>Ask Mr. Price, if he thinks I took these things away with intent to keep them. We had been together all night; Mrs. Murrell lay along with Mr. Price and I, four or five nights running; and Mr. Price went out, and she said, she was going to him, and I went up stairs, and hid those things to frighten them, but not with intent to take them away; please to ask Rowell their characters.</p>

               <p>Q. to Rowell. What is Murrell's character?</p>
               <p>Rowell. I know nothing of the woman's character; she is a stranger to me.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known Price?</p>
               <p>Rowell. I have known him some time.</p>
               <p>Q. What is he?</p>
               <p>Rowell. I believe he is a waiter, but I never knew him in business; when I lived at Tumble-down-dicks, in the Borough, I happened to come acquainted with him.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Rowell. He lived in place where I have; I never heard that he wrong'd any one.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character?</p>
               <p>Rowell. I can't answer for the character of him, or Mr. Price. I know the prisoner to be a worthy, good-natured, civil young fellow.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601022-13-person173">
                  Isaac 
                  Pooley 
               <interp inst="t17601022-13-person173" type="surname" value="Pooley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-13-person173" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-13-person173" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about three or four months.</p>
               <p>Q What is his character?</p>
               <p>Pooley. All that I know of him is, I keep a public house, he has used my house several times; I always saw he behaved well, is all I have to say of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of Price's character?</p>
               <p>Pooley. I suppose he is a notorious Bawdy house keeper.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he ever keep a house?</p>
               <p>Pooley. He kept one in Silver street, and in New street, both notorious bawdy-houses; he has always appear'd a man of a very bad character.</p>
               <p>Q Do you know any thing of Murrell's character?</p>
               <p>Pooley. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601022-13-person174">
                  Thomas 
                  Carrol 
               <interp inst="t17601022-13-person174" type="surname" value="Carrol"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-13-person174" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-13-person174" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about three years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Carrol. His character is very clear and fair.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Price?</p>
               <p>Carrol. I have known him very near two years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character?</p>
               <p>Carrol. He has a very barefac'd, infamous character, by all that ever I could hear; he had a pretended wife, he and she us'd to use my house.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of Murrell?</p>
               <p>Carrol. I know nothing of her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601022-13-person175">
                  Joseph 
                  Bowman 
               <interp inst="t17601022-13-person175" type="surname" value="Bowman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-13-person175" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-13-person175" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner between three and four years; I always took him to be a very honest man.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Price?</p>
               <p>Bowman. I did a few years ago; he waited at White Conduit House, he was turn'd away for -</p>
               <p>Q. You are to say what is his general character, without entering into particulars.</p>
               <p>Bowman. Upon my oath I never heard any good of Price.</p>
               <p>Cha. Green. I have known the prisoner about four or five months.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character?</p>
               <p>Green. I know nothing bad of him; he us'd to use a house that I liv'd at; he was a waiter in the Borough, but I can't remember the place.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Green. I live at the Crown and Anchor, White Friars, Fleet-street.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did the prisoner live?</p>
               <p>Green. I can't name any place.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Price?</p>
               <p>Green. I do; he has kept a house in Silver-street, and another in great New-street.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character?</p>
               <p>Green. His character was very bad at that time; they were what they call disorderly houses.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601022-13-person176">
                  William 
                  Griffin 
               <interp inst="t17601022-13-person176" type="surname" value="Griffin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-13-person176" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-13-person176" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner six years, or more.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176010220018"></xptr>Q. What is his character?</p>
               <p>Griffin. His character since I knew him was very good; he at this time was out of place, when taken up; he had lived at the three Tuns in New street, Shoe lane.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he live there?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601022-13-person177">
                  Griffin
               <interp inst="t17601022-13-person177" type="given" value="Griffin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-13-person177" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I believe he lived there between three and four months.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Price?</p>
               <p>Griffin. I don't know much of him; his character by all Accounts, is very bad; I have lent the prisoner money and things, and he always paid me again.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Griffin. I am a waiter.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Griffin. I lived at the Angel and Crown tavern, White Chapel, six years.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17601022-13-verdict80" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17601022-13-verdict80" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
