<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640728-57">
               <interp inst="t17640728-57" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640728-57" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640728-57" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640728"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640728-57" type="date" value="17640728"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640728-57-off285-c419" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640728-57-defend544 t17640728-57-off285 t17640728-57-verdict287"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640728-57-off285-c420" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640728-57-defend546 t17640728-57-off285 t17640728-57-verdict287"></join>
         
               <p>459, 460. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17640728-57-defend544" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Moody 
                  <interp inst="t17640728-57-defend544" type="surname" value="Moody"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-57-defend544" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-57-defend544" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17640728-57-defend546" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Dunn 
                  <interp inst="t17640728-57-defend546" type="surname" value="Dunn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-57-defend546" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-57-defend546" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted for <rs id="t17640728-57-off285" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640728-57-off285" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-57-off285" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a watch, made of yellow metal, value 40 s.
            </rs> the property of a person unknown, <rs id="t17640728-57-cd286" type="crimeDate">May 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640728-57-off285 t17640728-57-cd286"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176407280035"></xptr>- Magennis. We had a search warrant under the hand of Mr. Welch, to apprehend all vagrants. About twelve or one o'clock at night, we met a man in Church-lane, with a soldier's hat and coat *; the next morning, when we brought what prisoners we had got, to Mr. Welch's office; we found the two prisoners had been in company with Etridge and one Husk: Mr. Welch examined Etridge, who told us where to find the prisoners: I was ordered, with others, to go and see for them. About six in the evening, I met with Husk and Dunn together; I said, there is a young led in the round-house, pray take a walk and see him; I got them there, and ordered the keeper to secure them: then Husk, when before Mr. Welch, said they were in company together, and they robbed a gentleman of a yellow watch: Moody could not be found, but was taken at last in Tottenham-court-road: Husk told me I should find the watch in a cellar, in Monmouth-street; Mr. Welch sent me there, and the woman brought it to the justices.</p>
               <p>* See trial of Etridge, No. 445.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640728-57-person547">
                  Christopher 
                  Husk 
               <interp inst="t17640728-57-person547" type="surname" value="Husk"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-57-person547" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-57-person547" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I and Dunn were going down the Haymarket, between eleven and twelve, on a Sunday night; we met with Moody; he came along with us down Jermyn-street; we overtook a gentleman in the Strand; he asked us the way to Berkley-square; I laid hold on one of his arms, and Dunn on the other, and Moody took his watch and ran away with it; and we followed him: then we went about the Strand till Monday morning nine o'clock; then Moody went into a cellar in Monmouth-street to sell it; he left it there in pawn for 12 s. we shared the money, 4 s. each. Moody was a school-fellow of mine; and I got acquainted with Dunn by seeing him at play in St. Giles's, when I came from school: I am seventeen years old</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640728-57-person548">
                  Lucy 
                  Variot 
               <interp inst="t17640728-57-person548" type="surname" value="Variot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-57-person548" type="given" value="Lucy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-57-person548" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I sell old cloaths in a cellar in Monmouth-street: a customer that was in my shop lent Moody 12 s. upon it; he came with it between nine and ten o'clock in the morning, and offered to sell it me: It was a yellow watch: I don't know who that person was; he left word where he was to be found, in Earl-street, near the Seven Dials. When the evidence came for it, I sent my child, about eleven years old, for it; he gave it her, and I delivered it.</p>
               <p>Moody's Defence.</p>
               <p>Dunn, Husk, and I, came through the park; we came up James-street, and into Jermyn-street; we crossed the way to see what was the matter; there was a mob; I saw something; I stooped, and found it was a watch; I took it up; said Husk, let's look at it; I gave it him in his hand; we were so late we were forced to be out all night: the next morning I came down Monmouth-street; by a cellar window I asked the woman if she would buy it; she said, she had no money: a friend of hers was by; he lent me 12 s. upon it.</p>
               <p>Dunn's Defence.</p>
               <p>I came along with Moody, and saw him pick up this watch.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17640728-57-verdict287" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640728-57-verdict287" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17640728-57-punish288" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640728-57-punish288" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640728-57-defend544 t17640728-57-punish288"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640728-57-defend546 t17640728-57-punish288"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
