<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17631019-33">
               <interp inst="t17631019-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631019-33" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631019-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17631019"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631019-33" type="date" value="17631019"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17631019-33-off168-c253" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631019-33-defend324 t17631019-33-off168 t17631019-33-verdict172"></join>
         
               <p>495. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17631019-33-defend324" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Gadby 
                  <interp inst="t17631019-33-defend324" type="surname" value="Gadby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-33-defend324" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-33-defend324" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17631019-33-deflabel167" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631019-33-defend324 t17631019-33-deflabel167"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17631019-33-off168" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631019-33-off168" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-33-off168" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one pair of muslin ruffles, val. 2 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17631019-33-victim326" type="victimName">
                     Robert 
                     Stevens 
                  <interp inst="t17631019-33-victim326" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-33-victim326" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-33-victim326" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631019-33-off168 t17631019-33-victim326"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17631019-33-cd169" type="crimeDate">Oct. 3</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631019-33-off168 t17631019-33-cd169"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631019-33-person327">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Stevens 
               <interp inst="t17631019-33-person327" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-33-person327" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-33-person327" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My husband is named John, we live at <placeName id="t17631019-33-crimeloc170">Isleworth</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17631019-33-crimeloc170" type="placeName" value="Isleworth"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17631019-33-crimeloc170" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631019-33-off168 t17631019-33-crimeloc170"></join>, the prisoner was my <rs id="t17631019-33-deflabel171" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631019-33-defend324 t17631019-33-deflabel171"></join>: I missed things at sundry times, but would not lay any thing to her charge till last washing day. She always kept the room door locked, and kept the key in her pocket for 6 weeks together; I never could get into her room till last washing day, that was the 3 d of this instant; I found her box open; the first thing I saw was a pair of muslin ruffles, I brought them down, and said, Sarah, do you know these ruffles? she could not speak for some time; I went and shewed them to the washer-woman in the wash-house; then the prisoner clapped her hands together an said, since it was come to that she would sware to them, that they were her own; and she would have given them up at last if I would let her go; these are my property. ( Produced in court.)</p>
               <p>Q. Is there any mark upon them?</p>
               <p>E. Stevens. There is not.</p>
               <p>Q. Then what do you know them by?</p>
               <p>E. Stevens. The binding is my own wo I know them by the making of them.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say when you shewed them first to her?</p>
               <p>E. Stevens. She vowed, by her Maker, they were her ruffles.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never charge her with other things that you found yourself mistaken in, especially in an apron?</p>
               <p>E. Stevens. I never charged her with an apron, there is an apron or two gone, but I never charged her with them.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the key of her room that washing day?</p>
               <p>E. Stevens. That was in her room door.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631019-33-person328">
                  Mary 
                  Bailey 
               <interp inst="t17631019-33-person328" type="surname" value="Bailey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-33-person328" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-33-person328" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am sister to the prosecutrix, (she takes the ruffles in her hand). I took particular notice of these ruffles when my sister was making them.</p>
               <p>Q. By what do you know them?</p>
               <p>Bailey. I am certain to them by a piece of ruff edge, it is so, that I could almost swear to them; I believe I can swear to them, they are my sister's, I am sure.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631019-33-person329">
                  John 
                  Lewis 
               <interp inst="t17631019-33-person329" type="surname" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-33-person329" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-33-person329" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an officer, on the 3d of this instant I was sent for to Mr. Stevens's house, there was the prisoner and prosecutrix sitting together in the back parlour, there were a pair of ruffles lying on a table; the prosecutrix said, she had lost a pair of ruffles, and had found them in the prisoner's box that was open; the prisoner said they were her own ruffles. Upon talking a good deal to her, and telling her the consequence would be very bad, she seemed to be a little flusterated, but before the Justice she insisted on them as her own; she said, in the entry, if they are your property you may take them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say any thing to you about letting her go.</p>
               <p>Lewis. No, she did not.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>The ruffles are mine; she went up stairs, and took them out of my box, and called me out of the wash-house, and asked me if I knew them? I said I did; after that she said she would take her oath they were her own; she is now taking a very false oath. I have witnesses here that know they are my ruffles.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176310190020"></xptr>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631019-33-person330">
                  Sarah 
                  Shephard 
               <interp inst="t17631019-33-person330" type="surname" value="Shephard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-33-person330" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-33-person330" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . (She takes the ruffles in her hand.) To the best of my knowledge I think this is the same muslin that I bought for the prisoner; I bought a yard of muslin on purpose to make a pair of double ruffles last January, cost either 5 s. or 9 s and 6 d. I do not know which.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see them after they were made up?</p>
               <p>Shepherd. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutrix. How long has the prisoner lived with you?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. She has lived with me 5 months the 10th of this instant.</p>
               <p>Q. to Shepherd. What are you?</p>
               <p>Shepherd. I am servant to the Hon. Mrs. Shirley.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631019-33-person331">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Godby 
               <interp inst="t17631019-33-person331" type="surname" value="Godby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-33-person331" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-33-person331" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am aunt to the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>E. Godby. We are button-makers; I cut out a pair of ruffles for the prisoner, my maid made them up, (she takes the ruffles in her hand) to the best of my knowledge these are the same I cut out.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see them after they were made?</p>
               <p>Godby. I can't say I did.</p>
               <p>Q. May not one muslin be like another?</p>
               <p>Godby. It may.</p>
               <p>Q. And one pattern like another?</p>
               <p>Godby. Yes, they may. I left a piece, I did not put the whole yard in, the girl had a cap made of the piece left. (The prisoner hands a cap to the evidence; she compares them.) They seem to me to be the same muslin.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Godby. I live in Naked Boy's Court, in the Strand.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did the prisoner live when you cut the ruffles out?</p>
               <p>Godby. She lived with Mr. Angish, accomptant general in the Court of Chancery.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631019-33-person332">
                  Ann 
                  Cap 
               <interp inst="t17631019-33-person332" type="surname" value="Cap"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-33-person332" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-33-person332" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I really think these are the ruffles I made, I put in such a piece as here; (pointing to a small piece put into each) I made them in the same manner as these are, the prisoner brought a piece of cloth and desired I would put it in, because it would iron better; my mistress cut them, that is Mrs. Godby.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631019-33-person333">
                  James 
                  Godby 
               <interp inst="t17631019-33-person333" type="surname" value="Godby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-33-person333" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-33-person333" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was present when Mrs. Stevens and 
               <persName id="t17631019-33-person334">
                  Sarah 
                  Godby 
               <interp inst="t17631019-33-person334" type="surname" value="Godby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-33-person334" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631019-33-person334" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             were together after the ruffles were found. I am her brother, I went to demand her cloaths and wages of Mrs. Stevens; she desired us to take the cloaths away; I desired her to come and see that there was nothing but her own; we went into the kitchen, a candle was lighted, the prisoner went to look for her cloaths, lying wet in a dish; the first thing she took up was an apron, after that an handkerchief, Mrs. Stevens gave the girl a push against the dresser, and said the things were her's.</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. She had cut a handkerchief of mine to make a flounce to her apron at the bottom, and I claimed the flounce.</p>
               <p>Mr. Angish. The prisoner came to live in my family in January 61, and stay'd a year and three quarters, she went away about this time twelve months; she behaved herself faithfully and honestly the whole time she was in my service, she was never suspected of any thing.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the reason she left your service?</p>
               <p>Angish. The reason she went away was we thought her rather too young to take care of children.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17631019-33-verdict172" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631019-33-verdict172" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
