<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17600910-25">
               <interp inst="t17600910-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600910-25" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600910-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600910"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600910-25" type="date" value="17600910"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600910-25-off128-c199" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-25-defend257 t17600910-25-off128 t17600910-25-verdict130"></join>
         
               <p>268 (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17600910-25-defend257" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Thompson 
                  <interp inst="t17600910-25-defend257" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-25-defend257" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-25-defend257" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17600910-25-deflabel127" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-25-defend257 t17600910-25-deflabel127"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17600910-25-off128" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600910-25-off128" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-25-off128" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 3 s. in money
            </rs>, the money of 
               <persName id="t17600910-25-victim258" type="victimName">
                  Lion 
                  Solomon 
               <interp inst="t17600910-25-victim258" type="surname" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-25-victim258" type="given" value="Lion"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-25-victim258" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-25-off128 t17600910-25-victim258"></join>
                  </persName>
             , <rs id="t17600910-25-cd129" type="crimeDate">Aug. 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-25-off128 t17600910-25-cd129"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>Lion Solomon. My master sent me to market, and gave me half a guinea to buy some meat; I bought as much as came to 13 d. a woman took hold of me, and would have me go along with her; I would not at first, but there she took me in the grass, and made me do what I would not do, so I could not help myself, she was a strong woman, and I could not get loose from her; she took 3 s and 3 d. from me, I was crying out murder, and they brought her to the century box; so I went for a constable, I met with a constable's wife, and she came along with me; the woman desir'd to speak to the constable's wife.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176009100032"></xptr>Q. Who was that woman?</p>
               <p>Solomon. It was the prisoner at the bar; I told her it was my mother's money, and she must give it me again; she gave me half a crown again in the century box; then a corporal came and turned her out of the century-box, and turned me away too; so the people took hold of her, and hold of me, and brought us before justice Cox in the Strand.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this done?</p>
               <p>Solomon. In St. James's park.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Solomon. I live in Petty France.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you go to market?</p>
               <p>Solomon. I went to market in Chandois-street, Charing-cross, they kept me in the watchhouse all night.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600910-25-person259">
                  Jane 
                  Wilmot 
               <interp inst="t17600910-25-person259" type="surname" value="Wilmot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-25-person259" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-25-person259" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The young lad the prosecutor came to my house.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>J. Wilmot. I live in Long-ditch, Westminster; he knocked at the door, and asked if the constable was at home; I said no.</p>
               <p>Q. Is your husband a constable?</p>
               <p>J. Wilmot. Yes; he said can you tell me where another lives; saying, he was a stranger, and had nobody to take his part, and that he was robbed in the park, by a woman, and it was his master's money; I unhappily went with the lad up to the century box, there was a woman; I said to the century you must take care of this woman; then she put her hand out of the box, and said, I want to speak with you; said I, do you know good woman what you have done, you have done a thing that will hang you; she said, I know what I have done; said I, return the money, for if you are turned out, the mob will tare you to pieces; said she, I will return him 2 shillings; she took her money out of her apron, and returned him a shillings and 6 pence; then the corporal came up, and said, what is here; the century said, I have got a prisoner for a robbery; who is she, said he, then he looked into the box, and said, so you bitch is it you; he turned her out of the box, and away she and the boy went together, I know no more of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Is this the same woman?</p>
               <p>J. Wilmot. Indeed I do not know that it is the same.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I am not the woman, I never did such a thing; indeed I never took anything from him.</p>
               <p>Q. to Solomon. What time of night was this?</p>
               <p>Solomon. It was about 9 at night, to-morrow night will be 3 weeks.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600910-25-verdict130" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600910-25-verdict130" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
