<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610506-8">
               <interp inst="t17610506-8" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610506-8" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610506-8" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610506"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610506-8" type="date" value="17610506"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610506-8-off45-c105" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-8-defend117 t17610506-8-off45 t17610506-8-verdict48"></join>
         
               <p>164. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610506-8-defend117" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17610506-8-defend117" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-8-defend117" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-8-defend117" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17610506-8-off45" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610506-8-off45" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-8-off45" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               the wilful murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17610506-8-victim119" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Alsop 
                        <interp inst="t17610506-8-victim119" type="surname" value="Alsop"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610506-8-victim119" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610506-8-victim119" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-8-off45 t17610506-8-victim119"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>. He stood charged on the coroner's inquest for manslaughter, <rs id="t17610506-8-cd46" type="crimeDate">March 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-8-off45 t17610506-8-cd46"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-8-person120">
                  Richard 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17610506-8-person120" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-8-person120" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-8-person120" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I did not know either the prisoner or Alsop by name, before I saw them on Easter Tuesday. Alsop was throwing at oranges, having got some before; he knocked down five, Smith the prisoner and several more were alongside of them, Smith took the oranges up, after that the deceased came up to the prisoner at the bar, and asked for his oranges; the prisoner had then only one in his hand as I saw; the prisoner said he would not give him the orange; he ask'd him again, and said he would have the orange; the other said he would not give it him, and gave him a chuck under the chin directly; the deceased put up with that, and asked him again for his orange; he answered he would not give it him, and hit him directly both with his right and left hand over his face; then the deceased hit him, and they both fell into the ditch together against a bank; after that the deceased got out of the ditch, and walked away about twenty yards from him, and the prisoner followed him, and dragg'd him back again; the prisoner had him by the waistcoat collar, and swore he should fight it out; when he came to the ditch side the mob lifted him over the bank, and Smith went after him, and the mob followed.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Alsop go of his own accord?</p>
               <p>Brown. No, they brought him back.</p>
               <p>Q. What happened when they were in the field?</p>
               <p>Brown. There was a ring beat out, Smith stripp'd to his skin, and Alsop stood with his waistcoat and apron on, he did not want to fight, he wanted to go home; they fought half an hour or more; after they had fought 4 or 5 and twenty minutes, the prisoner's second told him, if he did not mind to hit him a streight punch or two, he could never do for him, nor yet beat him.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his name?</p>
               <p>Brown. He goes by the name of 
               <persName id="t17610506-8-person121">
                  David 
                  Buck 
               <interp inst="t17610506-8-person121" type="surname" value="Buck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-8-person121" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-8-person121" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The deceased's second is named Chapman, a man that came there by chance.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner hit him as he bid him?</p>
               <p>Brown. He did, and the deceased died of his blow, he never arose any more.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did they fight after the prisoner's second bid him hit him a streight punch?</p>
               <p>Brown. They fought about two or three minutes after; Smith gave the deceased a blow under the car, and after that another under his nose, and with one of them blows he killed him. Buck was very active in backing the prisoner all the while.</p>
               <p>Q. How old might the deceased be?</p>
               <p>Brown. I take him to be about twenty years old.</p>
               <p>Q. How old do you take the prisoner to be?</p>
               <p>Brown. I take him to be about nineteen.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-8-person122">
                  Anne 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17610506-8-person122" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-8-person122" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-8-person122" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the field at the beginning of the quarrel, the deceased threw with me for oranges, the fourth throw he knocked down the oranges.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>A. Brown. This was in <placeName id="t17610506-8-crimeloc47">Marybone-fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17610506-8-crimeloc47" type="placeName" value="Marybone-fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610506-8-crimeloc47" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-8-off45 t17610506-8-crimeloc47"></join>, behind the Angel, there was a good many more people, I did not see the prisoner take up the oranges; the deceased ran from me to take up the oranges, and I never saw any dispute, or blow struck. After that I saw Smith in his shirt, and said, For God's sake do not go to fight about the oranges, I will give you an orange or two myself, rather than you should fight; he swore he would fight it out, but I never saw them fight.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-8-person123">
                  John 
                  Sims 
               <interp inst="t17610506-8-person123" type="surname" value="Sims"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-8-person123" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-8-person123" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in Marybone fields on Easter Tuesday, I saw young Alsop there, they fought, I saw the beginning of it; I saw Alsop slinging at oranges, and the prisoner pick them up; Alsop asked him for them, and Smith hit him two knocks on the face; Alsop ran away, and the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176105060015"></xptr> other after him, and flung him into a ditch; he got out of the ditch, and went away, and the other followed him twenty yards.</p>
               <p>Q. Did one or both fall into the ditch?</p>
               <p>Sims. I cannot say whether one or both were in the ditch, but I am sure Alsop was in it, and I believe the prisoner fell in too.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was you at that time?</p>
               <p>Sims. I was not four yards from them; Smith's cloaths were off, the other had only his frock off, when he was throwing at oranges; they fought after that, but I did not see the fight, I saw them go over a new bank into the field.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Alsop strike the prisoner at all?</p>
               <p>Sims. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-8-person124">
                  Edmund 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17610506-8-person124" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-8-person124" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-8-person124" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in Marybone-fields on Easter-Tuesday, they began the battle before I got into the field, they had two seconds, they were over-persuaded by their seconds to fight longer than they would have done, having both of them enough; they had several falls, the last fall but three the prisoner fell with his backside on the deceased's belly, and the deceased was never able to stand afterwards; I believe that fall killed him; his second, a coachman, lifted him up, and they called out for oranges for him to suck; after that they had not strength to carry a blow to do any mischief; the deceas'd was sick and dying all the time after that fall, though they had two falls; after that he died the last and third fall; there were two people there that bled him, an apothecary's apprentice and a life-guard man, but he bled but very little.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think the last blow did not hurt him?</p>
               <p>Price. I do not think it came with force enough to hurt him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>On Easter-Tuesday I was in Marybone-fields, I saw a mob, I ran to see what was the matter; I fell down, and the deceased gave me a kick; I got up, and laughed at him; upon that we fell a fighting, the men would not let us fight there, they pulled off his frock, and he jump'd upon a bank, and got into a field, and I went after him; they told me not to be afraid of him, and made a ring for us to fight, we fought near half an hour.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610506-8-verdict48" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610506-8-verdict48" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-8-verdict48" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of Manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610506-8-punish49" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610506-8-punish49" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-8-punish49" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-8-defend117 t17610506-8-punish49"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
