<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17661217-56">
               <interp inst="t17661217-56" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-56" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-56" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17661217"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-56" type="date" value="17661217"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17661217-56-off290-c483" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-56-defend609 t17661217-56-off290 t17661217-56-verdict294"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176612170049"></xptr>70. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17661217-56-defend609" type="defendantName">
                     Anne 
                     Davis 
                  <interp inst="t17661217-56-defend609" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-56-defend609" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-56-defend609" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17661217-56-off290" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-56-off290" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-56-off290" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a half guinea and a quarter guinea
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17661217-56-victim611" type="victimName">
                     Benjamin 
                     Blundey 
                  <interp inst="t17661217-56-victim611" type="surname" value="Blundey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-56-victim611" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-56-victim611" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-56-off290 t17661217-56-victim611"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17661217-56-cd291" type="crimeDate">Oct. 26</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-56-off290 t17661217-56-cd291"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-56-person612">
                  Benjamin 
                  Blundey 
               <interp inst="t17661217-56-person612" type="surname" value="Blundey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-56-person612" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-56-person612" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17661217-56-viclabel292" type="occupation">journeyman carpenter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-56-victim611 t17661217-56-viclabel292"></join>, and live at Marybone; about six o'clock one evening above three months ago, I was taken to a house in <placeName id="t17661217-56-crimeloc293">St. Giles's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17661217-56-crimeloc293" type="placeName" value="St. Giles's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17661217-56-crimeloc293" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-56-off290 t17661217-56-crimeloc293"></join>, by another person, a man, there we drank; there were two women there; my companion went away, and left me with them.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you fuddled?</p>
               <p>Blundey. No, I was not.</p>
               <p>Court. If you was not, you would not have been there.</p>
               <p>Blundey. One of them sat upon my knee, while the other took my money out of my pocket; the prisoner was one of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you perceive her doing it?</p>
               <p>Blundey. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Which of them took your money?</p>
               <p>Blundey. The prisoner did; she took it out of my fob; I asked her for it again, she would not give it me; I perceived her put her hand into my fob two or three times; she said, all that she got was her own; then one of their bullies took me to another house, and called for a pint of beer, and left me to pay for it, and I had no money to pay for it; then I went and complained to Master Dinkles; the next morning he went along with me to see after them, and we found them both in the room, and a man with them; the other woman fled, and after that, the prisoner; we went for a warrant, and took the prisoner, just after last sessions.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever find your money again?</p>
               <p>Blundey. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you had your money at the time you went into that house?</p>
               <p>Blundey. I am sure I had.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-56-person613">
                  Nicholas 
                  Dinkles 
               <interp inst="t17661217-56-person613" type="surname" value="Dinkles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-56-person613" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-56-person613" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prosecutor is an acquaintance of mine; he told me what had happened; I went with him to the room where he said he had lost his money, there he found the girl; I asked her why she did not deliver the money back; she said, what she got was her own, if there had been ten times more: I said, you had better return it, or I will have you before your betters; she said, I don't care for that, you may do your best and your worst. We went down to Justice Welch, and left a man in care of the door, and when we came back, she was gone; we were after her all that day, and could not find her; this passed on for two months; after that, an acquaintance of mine told me where she was; we went and took her in St. Giles's; then I asked her, if she would make the affair up; she said she would not; then said I, you must go to some other place; I said to the constable, take her to the round-house; she lay there all night, and the next morning Mr. Welch committed her to Bridewell; before the Justice she said she had the 5 s. 3 d. but that the young fellow gave it her, and that he gave her 4 s. in silver besides; he owned there he gave her the 4 s. but not the 5 s. 3 d. piece; she said the other girl had the half guinea.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>What they say is false; I went into a public-house, the young man was sitting there, and an elderly man with him, and a young man or two with them; I sat down in another place; the elderly man called to me, and bid me sit down by that young man; I said, I did not know him; the elderly man said, why will you not go to the door and speak to him; he asked me where I lived; I told him he might go over the way; he went there, and gave me 2 s. and was there about half an hour; then he went over to the public-house; I followed him; he drank to me, and asked me where I lodged; I said I had a room of my own, where is none but a young woman of my acquaintance; he urged many times to go, and said he would not use me ill; I went with him to my own room; he asked me if I had no coals to put on the fire; I made up a fire; he gave me a shilling; the other girl and he sat together; I asked him if he would have something to eat; he said he would; he gave me a 5 s. 3 d. I went to the pastry-cook's, and got a giblet-pye and a neat's-tongue, and we had our supper, and three or four pots of half-and-half, and four or five half pints of gin; then he would have another pot of twopenny hot; the old man was waiting in the public-house; when I came there, he asked me how the young man behaved; I told him he gave me a 5 s. 3 d. piece; he asked me to give him something to drink; so I carried the half-and-half home; the other girl told me he gave her half a guinea while I was gone, and she was to return him some change out of it, but she would not return any; he came in the morning, and knocked at the door; I let him in, and sent for half a pint of gin; then he drank it; he wanted something out of the 5 s. 3 d. I said I had not much left, and I would keep what I had; he said, if you will not give me something out of it, I will go and fetch some body that shall make you; he went and fetched that man; then they asked me for the whole money again, and I would not give it them.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17661217-56-verdict294" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-56-verdict294" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
