<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17620421-25">
               <interp inst="t17620421-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620421-25" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620421-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17620421"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620421-25" type="date" value="17620421"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620421-25-off131-c227" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-25-defend267 t17620421-25-off131 t17620421-25-verdict136"></join>
         
               <p>140. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17620421-25-defend267" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Barnes 
                  <interp inst="t17620421-25-defend267" type="surname" value="Barnes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-25-defend267" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-25-defend267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17620421-25-off131" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620421-25-off131" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-25-off131" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               sacrilegiously stealing one communion table-cloth, value 21 s. three damask napkins, four brass candle-branches, and one reading-desk cover, made of crimson velvet, in the cathedral church of St. Paul's, the property of the 
                     <persName id="t17620421-25-victim268" type="victimName">
                        right
                         reverend 
                        John
                         lord 
                        <rs id="t17620421-25-viclabel132" type="occupation">bishop</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-25-victim268 t17620421-25-viclabel132"></join> of Oxford<interp inst="t17620421-25-victim268" type="surname" value="reverend lord"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620421-25-victim268" type="given" value="right John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620421-25-victim268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , and the 
                     <persName id="t17620421-25-victim269" type="victimName">
                        <rs id="t17620421-25-viclabel133" type="occupation">dean and chapter</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-25-victim269 t17620421-25-viclabel133"></join> of St. Paul's<interp inst="t17620421-25-victim269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17620421-25-cd134" type="crimeDate">April 6</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-25-off131 t17620421-25-cd134"></join>. ||.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-25-person270">
                  Benjamin 
                  Pierce 
               <interp inst="t17620421-25-person270" type="surname" value="Pierce"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-25-person270" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-25-person270" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am sacrist of the <placeName id="t17620421-25-crimeloc135">cathedral church of St. Paul's</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17620421-25-crimeloc135" type="placeName" value="cathedral church of St. Paul's"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17620421-25-crimeloc135" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-25-off131 t17620421-25-crimeloc135"></join>, and as such I have the charge of all the plate, linen, and several things belonging to the church. Most of those things, when not in use, are put in a chest or press, by a person whom I call my deputy. That deputy has been in a very ill state of health for some time, and therefore he has been forced to call in a person to his assistance: He very unluckily called in the prisoner at the bar. On the 5th or 6th of this instant, Mr. Fosset, one of the vergers of St. Paul's, took me into the vestry to examine there. I found the surplices all there, but instead of four napkins, there were only two. We reported this to the bishop of Oxford, who is dean of St. Paul's. He ordered us to wait upon Mr. Alderman Dickenson, to know what must be done: He granted a search warrant. We took up Barnes, and he confessed that the linen table-cloth was pawned at Mr. Harrison's. a pawnbroker in Bride-lane, in the name of Cook: and the two napkins in Blackfriars, at Mr. Radbard's, by the same Cook. I asked him, what was become of Cook? He said, he was somewhere about the church-yard. I desired one of the vergers to give a good look out for him. We soon took him, and brought him to Barnes; who confirmed what Barnes had confessed. We carried them before Mr. alderman Dickenson: He sent for the pawnbrokers, who came, and acknowledged the pawing of the said goods. They were bound over to appear, and Barnes and Cook were committed to the Compter. The next day we searched the chest of plate; there was the pulpit candle-branch missing. I went to Barnes in the Compter, and asked him what was become of the branches? He told me, they were pawned at Mr. Wilmot's, in St. Bride's-alley. I called upon Mr. Wilmot. He owned he had such in his custody, and was ready to produce them. Two or three days after this, we missed a velvet desk-cloth. Barnes was then removed to Newgate. I was told Barnes had pawned it at Mr. Cates's, a pawnbroker in Chandois-street. I went there, and took one of the vergers with me. We asked Mr. Cates's son or servant, if one Barnes had pawned a velvet cover or cloth at his house? He said, yes, We desired to see it. He produced it; and Mr. Argent the verger, was very sure, that that very cloth produced, was the property of the dean and chapter of St. Paul's.</p>

               <p>Mr. Fosset. I am a verger of St. Paul's. I have heard what has been said by Mr. Pierce. I can say no more than he has said, except the two<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176204210019"></xptr> branches, which were brought to me on Good-Friday from Mr. Harrison's. I know there were two arms belonging to the branch of St. Paul's. I heard the prisoner confess, that he ordered Cook to pawn the table-cloth at Mr. Harrison's; and also the napkins at Mr. Radbard's, in Blackfriars.</p>
               <p>Q. from the Prisoner. Did you ever miss any things before these mentioned?</p>
               <p>Fosset. No.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-25-person271">
                  James 
                  Tapper 
               <interp inst="t17620421-25-person271" type="surname" value="Tapper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-25-person271" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-25-person271" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Harrison, a pawnbroker. I took a table-cloth and two brass arms in of one Cook, on the and 12th of January. [ Produced in court.]</p>
               <p>Mr. Pierce. Here are the letters St. P. the dean and chapter's mark on the table-cloth, by which I know it to be St. Paul's communion tablecloth. Cook owned he pawned it there by the prisoner's consent.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-25-person272">
                  John 
                  Isaac 
               <interp inst="t17620421-25-person272" type="surname" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-25-person272" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-25-person272" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Radbard. [He produced two napkins.] I took these in of 
               <persName id="t17620421-25-person273">
                  William 
                  Cook 
               <interp inst="t17620421-25-person273" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-25-person273" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-25-person273" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             on the 1st of March.</p>
               <p>Mr. Pierce. These have the same mark upon them. These the prisoner also owned were pawned by Cook, by his consent.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-25-person274">
                  John 
                  Cates 
               <interp inst="t17620421-25-person274" type="surname" value="Cates"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-25-person274" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-25-person274" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a pawnbroker, and live in Chandois-street. [He produced a velvet cloth, with fringe round it.] This was taken in by my servant. Justice Cox told me, it was sufficient if I came here without bringing him. It was brought to my house on the 5th of June last. It has been in and out, and in and out again. It was taken in in June last, and out in November; and in again in December the 8th: When it was brought, my son wanted a voucher. The man went and brought one 
               <persName id="t17620421-25-person275">
                  John 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17620421-25-person275" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-25-person275" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-25-person275" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; who said he was a broker, and lived in Vine-street.</p>
               <p>Q. What could you imagine it to be? Did you ever see such a thing in any place except a church?</p>
               <p>Cates. I don't know that I ever saw such a thing in a church.</p>
               <p>Mr. Pierce. I heard Barnes say, he pawned the desk cloth at this man's house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-25-person276">
                  Henry 
                  Argent 
               <interp inst="t17620421-25-person276" type="surname" value="Argent"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-25-person276" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-25-person276" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am one of the vergers of St. Paul's. This velvet cloth belongs to the cathedral church of St. Paul's.</p>
               <p>Q. to Cate. Do you know 
               <persName id="t17620421-25-person277">
                  John 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17620421-25-person277" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-25-person277" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-25-person277" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Cates. I do: He is a journeyman taylor.</p>
               <p>Mr. Argent. Upon the prisoner's confessing in Newgate, this cloth was in this man's house, we went there. The pawnbroker did not behave so well as he should have done. He would not let us have a sight of it, till we went to Sir 
               <persName id="t17620421-25-person278">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620421-25-person278" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-25-person278" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-25-person278" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and brought a search warrant. When we were going out of the house, he asked us, if it was stolen? I said, it was. This is a cover to a reading desk. It is used when a prebend is installed into his office: They are obliged to read the whole service, that is what is called Reading in.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-25-person279">
                  John 
                  Peers 
               <interp inst="t17620421-25-person279" type="surname" value="Peers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-25-person279" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-25-person279" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a pawnbroker; I live with Mr. Wilmot, in St. Bride's church-yard. [He produced a pair of brass arms.] Those were brought to me by Cook: I refused taking them in, and sent the man away. He returned with a man belonging to Mr. Harrison, who was about leaving off trade. Who said, he had had them several times in their shop. Cook told me, his master lived in the Commons. Mr. Pierce called upon me, and asked, if there were such things with us? I said, there were.</p>
               <p>Mr. Pierce. The prisoner owned to me these arms were pawned in Bride's-alley, to Mr. Wilmot.</p>
               <p>Peers. Had the prisoner at the bar offered them to me, I should not have taken them in, because I know he belongs to St. Paul's.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-25-person280">
                  Richard 
                  Gold 
               <interp inst="t17620421-25-person280" type="surname" value="Gold"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-25-person280" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-25-person280" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a dean's verger. I was desired by Mr. Fosset, to examine whether the cloth was present or missing; and I missed the tablecloth and two napkins.</p>
               <p>Mr. Jenkins. I am a brasier. I cleaned these branches last June was twelve-months. I know they belong to St. Paul's church. [Taking them all four into his hand]</p>
               <p>Q. to Pierce. Whose property are those goods here produced?</p>
               <p>Mr. Pierce. They are the property of the dean and chapter of St. Paul's. They used to be kept, some in the dean's vestry, and some in the vestry in the north isle.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>When I took those things, which were at several times, my circumstances were very low. I was under several dilemmas in debt. I own I took them to help me in my necessity. I intended to restore them to their proper places again.</p>
               <p>Q. from the Prisoner to Mr. Pierce. Did you ever know any thing amiss of me before?</p>
               <p>Mr. Pierce. No.</p>
               <p>Q. from the Prisoner to Mr. Argent. Did you ever?</p>
               <p>Mr. Argent. I could not accuse him with any thing before of my own knowledge.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17620421-25-verdict136" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620421-25-verdict136" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17620421-25-punish137" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620421-25-punish137" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-25-defend267 t17620421-25-punish137"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
