<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17661022-31">
               <interp inst="t17661022-31" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661022-31" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661022-31" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17661022"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661022-31" type="date" value="17661022"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17661022-31-off157-c247" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661022-31-defend314 t17661022-31-off157 t17661022-31-verdict160"></join>
         
               <p>507. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17661022-31-defend314" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Clark 
                  <interp inst="t17661022-31-defend314" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-31-defend314" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-31-defend314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17661022-31-off157" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661022-31-off157" type="offenceCategory" value="royalOffences"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-31-off157" type="offenceSubcategory" value="coiningOffences"></interp>
               high treason, in feloniously and traiterously impairing and lightening a guinea and a half guinea, the current coin of this realm, contrary to the statute in that case made and provided
            </rs>, <rs id="t17661022-31-cd158" type="crimeDate">Aug. 30</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661022-31-off157 t17661022-31-cd158"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661022-31-person315">
                  John 
                  Garner 
               <interp inst="t17661022-31-person315" type="surname" value="Garner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-31-person315" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-31-person315" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was an apprentice to the prisoner, he lives in Primrose-street; as near as I can guess, he worked in gold last January, and not since; he is a <rs id="t17661022-31-deflabel159" type="occupation">watchcase-maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661022-31-defend314 t17661022-31-deflabel159"></join>; a man brought a job, what we call a pendant hole, to be soldered, about last November; I went up with it into the shop; there was a guinea lay in the leather that is fastened to the board to catch the filings, which lies upon his lap when he is sitting to work; he was then sitting at his work; he was angry, and said I had no business to come up, but when any job was brought, to ring the bell. He sent me out often with guineas; may be in one day, to get two half guineas, and when I had got them, in about an hour after he would send me out with them to get quarter guineas; I thought there was something not right; I bored a hole through the wainscot,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176610220020"></xptr> through which I saw him, as near as I can guess, but cannot be positive, with a guinea in his hand, I cannot directly tell the day.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you mean you are not positive as to the piece of money?</p>
               <p>Garner. I could not tell what it was; it looked like gold, about the size of a guinea; I saw him hold it in his fingers, and use the file to it; I looked through this hole two or three times, and always saw something of the same sort going on, as near as I can guess they were guineas; they were gold, but what pieces I cannot tell: I can speak to looking through this hole four times; he shut the door, and the key was on the outside.</p>
               <p>Q. When he gave you guineas, or half guineas to change, did you make any observations on them?</p>
               <p>Garner. I cannot say I did; the people have sent me back with them not being weight.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you apply to on this affair?</p>
               <p>Garner. I applied to my father, and I believe he went to the solicitor.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever take notice of any other pieces of money, that was of any other shape than that of a guinea?</p>
               <p>Garner. There might be some less, I cannot say to that</p>
               <p>Q. Was you ever sent out with any other money besides guineas and half guineas?</p>
               <p>Garner. I have with five and threepenny pieces; I have seen him file money, it was bigger than quarter guineas; I am sure it was money.</p>
               <p>Q. What leads you to believe that?</p>
               <p>Garner. Because he used to send me out so to change money; I have minded sometimes I have been sent back with one of the half guineas, to get two five and threepenny pieces.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What distance was the place where he worked from the hole you made?</p>
               <p>Garner. About two yards and a half.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you near enough to see any sort of impression?</p>
               <p>Garner. I was not.</p>
               <p>Council. Then you suppose it was money from the size, and the circumstance of being sent out to change money?</p>
               <p>Garner. That is all I speak from.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he do any thing to the guinea you saw in the skin?</p>
               <p>Garner. No, nothing at all as I saw.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any filings in the skin at that time?</p>
               <p>Garner. I cannot be positive.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any gold besides the guinea there?</p>
               <p>Garner. No, none at all; there were silver filings, no silver money.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he working any pieces of silver?</p>
               <p>Garner. There were pieces of silver lying near him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he use this skin in his trade?</p>
               <p>Garner. Yes, to catch the filings.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether the filings do not remain in a file till they are brushed out?</p>
               <p>Garner. They do.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661022-31-person316">
                  Thomas 
                  Rothwell 
               <interp inst="t17661022-31-person316" type="surname" value="Rothwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-31-person316" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-31-person316" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an officer; I apprehended the prisoner the 30th of August, Mr. Nash was with me; we were called up stairs; he was locked into a garret where they worked; we went in suddenly upon him, he heard the noise, and was standing up when we went into the room; we looked about, but did not observe any thing at first; my partner searched him, and found three guineas and a half in his pocket; and in the mean time the prisoner took a guinea out of his pocket, and laid it upon a block where a cloth lay hollow, he seemed to lay it under the hollow part of the cloth, but I saw it between his fingers and thumb before he laid it down; the other three guineas and a half were found in the other waistcoat pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. Had that guinea he put under the cloth any particular marks upon it?</p>
               <p>Rothwell. It had been just fresh filed.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it filed all round?</p>
               <p>Rothwell. No, there was but about two thirds of it filed; (the guinea produced) I saw several files, one of which had gold in the teeth, that lay on the bench directly over the skin, near the filing place; the other files lay near to the same place.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any filings in this skin or apron?</p>
               <p>Rothwell. I took out the filings and put them in a paper, and brought them away, and delivered them to the master of the Assay-office at the Mint; I have part of the filings that were left, which the gentleman did not take of me; (produced in court.)</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any gold work in the shop?</p>
               <p>Rothwell. We could not find any, and we searched very narrowly.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ask the prisoner whether he had any gold work about?</p>
               <p>Rothwell. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find any books in his custody?</p>
               <p>Rothwell. Yes; the next witness will give an account of that.</p>
         
               <p>*** The Last Part of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17661022-31">
                  <interp inst="t17661022-31" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17661022-31" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17661022-31" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17661022"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17661022-31" type="date" value="17661022"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176610220021"></xptr>THE WHOLE PROCEEDINGS ON THE KING's COMMISSIONS of the PEACE, OYER and TERMINER, and GOAL DELIVERY FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the GOAL DELIVERY FOR THE COUNTY of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 22d, Thursday the 23d, and Friday the 24th, of OCTOBER, 1766.</p>
                  <p>In the Sixth Year of His MAJESTY's Reign. Being the Eighth SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of THE RIGHT HONOURABLE 
                  <persName id="t17661022-31-person317">
                     GEORGE 
                     NELSON 
                  <interp inst="t17661022-31-person317" type="surname" value="NELSON"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17661022-31-person317" type="given" value="GEORGE"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17661022-31-person317" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Esq; LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>NUMBER VIII. PART II.</p>
                  <p>LONDON,</p>
                  <p>Printed for J. WILKIE, at the Bible, in St. Paul's Church-Yard.</p>
                  <p>[Price Six-Pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176610220022"></xptr>THE WHOLE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Goal Delivery held for the City of LONDON, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Continuation of the Trial of 
               <persName id="t17661022-31-person318">
                  John 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17661022-31-person318" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-31-person318" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-31-person318" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661022-31-person319">
                  Richard 
                  Nash 
               <interp inst="t17661022-31-person319" type="surname" value="Nash"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-31-person319" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-31-person319" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>I WAS employed with Mr. Rothwell in making this search; we had a warrant against the prisoner, it was some time before we could execute it; when we came into the room, he was very much confused, and stood up; I searched his breeches pocket, and found some silver, but no gold; in his waistcoat pocket I found two guineas and two half guineas; while I was searching his waistcoat pocket, my partner saw something pass, I cannot say I did; I saw some dust in the skin, that looked like gold.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it two guineas and two half guineas, or three guineas.</p>
               <p>Nash. My partner made a mistake, there were two whole guineas and two half guineas; as to the other guinea, I saw it on the block. I did not see it put there, it was designed, I believe, to be concealed; I took all the books I could find, and brought them to Mr. Chamberlaine; we found no gold-work, notwithstanding we searched.</p>
               <p>Mr. Chamberlaine. I received these books of Nash the officer, they are in the same condition I received them (produced in court.)</p>
               <p>Q. to clerk of arraigns. Read (it is read.)</p>
               <p>April 25, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>l. s.</p>
               <p>Recd a light 1 : 7</p>
               <p>Crowns 18 pennyweights</p>
               <p>1/2 Crowns 9</p>
               <p>Shillings 3 pennyweights 16 grains</p>
               <p>Guineas 5 pennyweights 4 grains</p>
               <p>1/2 Guineas 2 pennyweights 14 grains.</p>
               <p>Council for Crown Now your Lordship will see by the assay-master, what the proper weight is of the several pieces.</p>
               <p>Court. This looks like a rule, how much may be taken off to reduce them; here is one grain upon a port, repeated in different columns.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661022-31-person320">
                  Joseph 
                  Lucas 
               <interp inst="t17661022-31-person320" type="surname" value="Lucas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-31-person320" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-31-person320" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am assay-master.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the proper weight a guinea should weigh?</p>
               <p>Lucas. A guinea should weigh 5 penny-weights, 9 grains, and very near a half. In the book, against a guinea, is put 5 pennyweights, 4 grains, that is, 5 grains and a half lighter; so that 5 grains and a half must be taken off to bring them down to that weight.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever weigh this guinea here produced?</p>
               <p>Lucas. It weighs 4 pennyweights, 21 grains, and a half, that is, about 11 grains and a half under the true weight.</p>
               <p>Q. How much is that guinea worth?</p>
               <p>Lucas. About 20 pence short of the real value.</p>
               <p>Q. There were some filings found by the man, part of which he delivered to you, and the other part are now produced in court, Did you ever weigh these filings?</p>
               <p>Lucas. The whole filings weighed about 10 grains.</p>
               <p>Q. How much does that guinea and the filings weigh?</p>
               <p>Lucas. It is within a grain and a half of the true weight.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you try the filings?</p>
               <p>Lucas. I tried a part, which I found worse than the standard, about a ninetieth part below the standard.</p>
               <p>Q. I should be glad to know, whether by sweeping the filings from the skin, a small particle of other metal might not get among it?</p>
               <p>Lucas. A small particle of another matter might cause it.</p>
               <p>Q. What coin is this guinea?</p>
               <p>Lucas. It is of 
               <persName id="t17661022-31-person321">
                  George
               <interp inst="t17661022-31-person321" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-31-person321" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the first, the date is 1722.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I acknowledge the files, that they had gold sticking in them; I have files for gold, and files for silver; when I work in gold, I use gold files, and let them lie till I work in gold again; as for the guinea, I believe I can prove where I took it; I always have gold and silver in my shop; I have<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176610220023"></xptr> two shops, which are always open for any body to come in, the keys are on the outside.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>- Goadby. I live at Lambeth, and am a grocer; the prisoner received 3 guineas of me the day before he was taken up, for a watch which I bought of him; one of the guineas he scrupled, on account of its being a light one; I agreed to take it back again, provided he did not get it off; how I came by it I do not know; whether this is the guinea in dispute I cannot say.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any thing remarkable in that guinea?</p>
               <p>Goadby. Yes, it rather looked smaller, some part smooth, some rough, it had a very remarkable look.</p>
               <p>Q. Did it look as if part of it had been taken away?</p>
               <p>Goadby. It did; I thought it was rather too light, and he proved it to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a new guinea or an old one?</p>
               <p>Goadby. I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any thing particular in the appearance of it?</p>
               <p>Goadby. The edges were in some places smooth, in others rough; I do not know how it came so.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it dirty, as many are?</p>
               <p>Goadby. No, it was a bright guinea.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any part particularly bright?</p>
               <p>Goadby. Yes, it looked as if it had not been in common use.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take it in your hand, or observe any thing particular in the feel of it?</p>
               <p>Goadby. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever deal with the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Goadby. Yes, we have had dealings.</p>
               <p>Q. He has had guineas of you before, I suppose?</p>
               <p>Goadby. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he ever object to your money, or you to his?</p>
               <p>Goadby. No, never.</p>
               <p>Q. What has he dealt with you in?</p>
               <p>Goadby. In tea, and other articles in the grocery way; I have received of him to the amount of 14 and 15 shillings at a time.</p>
               <p>- Blaney. I went into the prisoner's workshop, and looked through the hole to see if I could see what a person was doing of as he sat at the board; I went again last Saturday, and sat in the same position a person would that was to work. I have known the prisoner about 8 years, I always looked upon him to be a very honest man, and one that lived in credit.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell the meaning of these words in the book, May 25, began gaming.</p>
               <p>Blaney. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661022-31-person322">
                  John 
                  Buckley 
               <interp inst="t17661022-31-person322" type="surname" value="Buckley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-31-person322" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-31-person322" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went into the prisoner's workshop, and looked through the hole, to see Mr. Blaney sitting at work on the prisoner's seat; I looked as nigh as I could into every place, there was no such thing as seeing what he was filing, he sat about 2 yards from the hole, he sat with his back to the hole; we were let into the room afterwards, and stood within a foot of him; if he sat sideways, I could not see what he was filing of; I have known him four or five years; I believe he has pretty good business; I never heard any thing of him but a good character.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you look through all the holes?</p>
               <p>Buckley. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you discover whether he was filing a tankard, or a thing the size of a guinea?</p>
               <p>Buckley. Not if he sat sideways, I could not see his hand nor his apron.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661022-31-person323">
                  John 
                  Lloyd 
               <interp inst="t17661022-31-person323" type="surname" value="Lloyd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-31-person323" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-31-person323" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Long-alley, by the end of Skinner's-street; I have known the prisoner five or six years, he has dealt with me for coals, he paid me honestly.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character?</p>
               <p>Lloyd. I never trouble myself with any of my neighbours, I keep no company, or go to an alehouse once in a quarter of a year; I do not remember I ever had light money of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661022-31-person324">
                  John 
                  Lapier 
               <interp inst="t17661022-31-person324" type="surname" value="Lapier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-31-person324" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-31-person324" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Primrose-street; I have known the prisoner about seven years, he has bore a very good character.</p>
               <p>- Jackson. I keep a public-house in the neighbourhood; the prisoner uses my house, his character is that of an honest man; I have received a great deal of gold of him, I suppose I have changed him an hundred pounds at times, I never had any objection to any money he brought.</p>
               <p>- Delacourt. I live in Slaughter-street, I have known him seven years, he has the character of an honest man.</p>
               <p>- Brisace. I am a pattern-drawer, I have known him five or six years, he has a fair and just character.</p>
               <p>- Harvey. I am a shoemaker, I have worked for him and his family, he always paid me, and he bore a good character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661022-31-person325">
                  Tho 
                  Dutfield 
               <interp inst="t17661022-31-person325" type="surname" value="Dutfield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-31-person325" type="given" value="Tho"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-31-person325" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him ever since I can remember, he has always had the character of an honest man.</p>
               <p>Hen. Aldwin. I live in Primrose-street, I have<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176610220024"></xptr> known him five years, I never heard any thing of him but that of a worthy honest man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17661022-31-verdict160" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661022-31-verdict160" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17661022-31-punish161" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661022-31-punish161" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661022-31-defend314 t17661022-31-punish161"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
