<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660116-4">
               <interp inst="t17660116-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660116-4" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660116-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660116-4" type="date" value="17660116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660116-4-off20-c53" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-4-defend59 t17660116-4-off20 t17660116-4-verdict26"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660116-4-off20-c54" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-4-defend60 t17660116-4-off20 t17660116-4-verdict26"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660116-4-off20-c56" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-4-defend64 t17660116-4-off20 t17660116-4-verdict26"></join>
         
               <p>75, 76, 77. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660116-4-defend59" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Higley 
                  <interp inst="t17660116-4-defend59" type="surname" value="Higley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-4-defend59" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-4-defend59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               <persName id="t17660116-4-defend60" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Martha 
                     Higley 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17660116-4-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-4-defend60 t17660116-4-alias-1"></join>
                     Martha, <rs id="t17660116-4-deflabel18" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-4-defend60 t17660116-4-deflabel18"></join> of 
                        <persName id="t17660116-4-person62">
                           William 
                           Buterfield 
                        <interp inst="t17660116-4-person62" type="surname" value="Buterfield"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17660116-4-person62" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17660116-4-person62" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        </persName>
                     
                     </rs>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-4-defend60" type="surname" value="Higley Buterfield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-4-defend60" type="given" value="Martha Martha William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-4-defend60" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17660116-4-defend64" type="defendantName">
                     Anne 
                     Higley 
                  <interp inst="t17660116-4-defend64" type="surname" value="Higley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-4-defend64" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-4-defend64" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17660116-4-deflabel19" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-4-defend64 t17660116-4-deflabel19"></join>, were indicted, for that <rs id="t17660116-4-off20" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660116-4-off20" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-4-off20" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               they, on the <rs id="t17660116-4-cd21" type="crimeDate">16th of December</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-4-off20 t17660116-4-cd21"></join>, about the hour of 8 in the night, on the same day, the dwelling-house of 
                     <persName id="t17660116-4-victim65" type="victimName">
                        Anne 
                        Furnican 
                     <interp inst="t17660116-4-victim65" type="surname" value="Furnican"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660116-4-victim65" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660116-4-victim65" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-4-off20 t17660116-4-victim65"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , <rs id="t17660116-4-viclabel22" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-4-victim65 t17660116-4-viclabel22"></join>, did break and enter, and stealing one gold ring, value 5 s. a pair of gold ear-rings, a flat iron, a silk sack and coat, five linen aprons, four linen frocks, a piece of linen cloth, three yards of thread lace, three gauze handkerchiefs laced, one gauze apron, a French bead necklace, a stone necklace, a muslin gown, two guineas and three shillings in money numbered, the property of the said Anne, in her dwelling-house
            </rs>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660116-4-person66">
                  Anne 
                  Furnican 
               <interp inst="t17660116-4-person66" type="surname" value="Furnican"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-4-person66" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-4-person66" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17660116-4-crimeloc23">Sugarloaf-court, Goodman's-yard, Goodman's-fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17660116-4-crimeloc23" type="placeName" value="Sugarloaf-court, Goodman's-yard, Goodman's-fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660116-4-crimeloc23" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-4-off20 t17660116-4-crimeloc23"></join>. I am a <rs id="t17660116-4-viclabel24" type="occupation">
                     <rs id="t17660116-4-deflabel25" type="occupation">laundress</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-4-defend64 t17660116-4-deflabel25"></join>
                  </rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660116-4-victim65 t17660116-4-viclabel24"></join>. The prisoners lived next door but one to me; they are mother,son, and daughter; she follows the same business that I do. On the 16th of December, I went out between 5 and 6 in the evening; one of my neighbours sent to me to make all the haste I could home, for my house was broke open. This was a little past 8 o'clock. I was about a quarter of a mile from home upon business.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you leave any body in your house when you went out?</p>
               <p>Furnican. No, I did not. I locked the door, and took the key in my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. How had you fastened your window?</p>
               <p>Furnican. I fasten that with a shutter with a bolt; sometimes I pin it with a pair of scissars, and sometimes other things. I came home, and found my window shutter down on the ground: it was a sash window; one pane was broke. I went in and missed the things mentioned in the indictment, which were in my drawers when I went out: there were three locks broke. 
               <persName id="t17660116-4-person67">
                  Martha 
                  Higley 
               <interp inst="t17660116-4-person67" type="surname" value="Higley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-4-person67" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-4-person67" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             brought the muslin gown, which was the property of a person I wash for, and a gauze handkerchief, and delivered them to me in my room. I was so much frighted, I don't remember what she said, how she came by them. I went to the Swan, to tell a friend of mine I had been robbed. My neighbour that lives between the prisoners and I happened to be there; his name is Blaze; he told me he had reason to suspect the boy at the bar. The next morning I went to the headborough to know what I must do; there I saw the old woman, 
               <persName id="t17660116-4-person68">
                  Martha 
                  Higley 
               <interp inst="t17660116-4-person68" type="surname" value="Higley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-4-person68" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-4-person68" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , sitting by the fire. I told the headborough's wife I had been robbed the night before: in the mean time her husband came in. I told him. He bid me to go to the Justices in Whitechapel for a search warrant, if I had a suspicion of any body. I went, but was told I could not have a warrant without I could swear against some body. As I was coming home, I met 
               <persName id="t17660116-4-person69">
                  Anne 
                  Higley 
               <interp inst="t17660116-4-person69" type="surname" value="Higley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-4-person69" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-4-person69" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            : she told me Mr. Coves the headborough wanted me at the house of her father and mother: I went there: there were some of my goods lay wrapped up in an apron: they asked me if they were mine; I said they were part of what I had lost.</p>
               <p>Q. from 
               <persName id="t17660116-4-person70">
                  Martha 
                  Higley 
               <interp inst="t17660116-4-person70" type="surname" value="Higley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-4-person70" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-4-person70" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Whether you caused any of your things to be put down into my cellar?</p>
               <p>Furnican. No, never; I never had a word of ill with her in my life.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176601160007"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17660116-4-person71">
                  Charles 
                  Blaze 
               <interp inst="t17660116-4-person71" type="surname" value="Blaze"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-4-person71" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-4-person71" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live next door to the prosecutrix. On the 16th of December, about half an hour after 6 at night; it was sharp frosty weather, I was filling my two water tubs in the yard, the water running flush. I sent my girl to Mrs. Buterfield's, to borrow a pail. She went and borrowed one. The boy at the bar came out and walked backwards and forwards before my door. As I was coming with water I heard something Shap. I said, halloo, who is there? He answered, it is only I.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is it from the cock to the prosecutrix's window?</p>
               <p>Blaze. I imagine it to be about 30 yards.</p>
               <p>Q. How far from the window was you when you heard that noise?</p>
               <p>Blaze. I was coming with my pail: it might be 5 or 6 yards distant.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660116-4-person72">
                  Charles 
                  Coves 
               <interp inst="t17660116-4-person72" type="surname" value="Coves"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-4-person72" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660116-4-person72" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 17th of December I had been in the city about business. When I returned about 11 in the forenoon, I found the prosecutrix in my house. My wife said, this woman has been robbed. Said I, who do you suspect? She said, she suspected some neighbours, and desired my advice how to proceed. I told her to go to the Rotation-Office, and make her complaint, and I apprehended they would grant a warrant on suspicion. Mrs. Buterfield was there at the same time, and heard me tell the prosecutrix to get a warrant on suspicion.</p>
               <p>Q. What was her business at your house?</p>
               <p>Coves. She came to tell us of a neighbour that was deceased. I had business out. When I returned, my wife told me the boy at the bar had been at my house, and desired me to go immediately to his mother's. I went there. Then he and the prisoner Anne, told me there were part of Mrs. Furnican's things below in their cellar. I went down with them, there I found this parcel of things (producing best part of the things lost.) They lay in an old sieve, squeezed up together. The muslin gown was delivered into my care before the Justices. I asked the mother how the things came into the cellar; she and the other two answered, they were entirely ignorant how they came there. They desired me to go again into the cellar, and take notice there was a window that looked into their yard; it was flat to the ground; no shutter to it. Whoever, put them down, must come into their yard and poke them down.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prosecutrix before?</p>
               <p>Coves. I don't know that ever I saw her before she came to my house.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known the prisoners?</p>
               <p>Coves. I have known them a great while. I have been acquainted with them 8 years. I always took the boy to be an honest sincere had.</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. I never heard but that the lad was a very harmless lad.</p>
               <p>The mother was asked if she chose to have her character asked of Mr. Coves. She answered, no.</p>
               <p>William's defence.</p>
               <p>I know no more of the things than the child unborn.</p>
               <p>Martha's defence the same.</p>
               <p>All three <rs id="t17660116-4-verdict26" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660116-4-verdict26" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
