<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650417-33">
               <interp inst="t17650417-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650417-33" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650417-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650417"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650417-33" type="date" value="17650417"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650417-33-off190-c249" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-33-defend317 t17650417-33-off190 t17650417-33-verdict192"></join>
         
               <p>253. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17650417-33-defend317" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Jones 
                  <interp inst="t17650417-33-defend317" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-33-defend317" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-33-defend317" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17650417-33-deflabel189" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-33-defend317 t17650417-33-deflabel189"></join>, was indicted, for <rs id="t17650417-33-off190" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650417-33-off190" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-33-off190" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that she, on the King's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17650417-33-victim319" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Halfpenny 
                        <interp inst="t17650417-33-victim319" type="surname" value="Halfpenny"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650417-33-victim319" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650417-33-victim319" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting her in bodily fear and danger of her life, and stealing from her person a guinea and 2 s. in money numbered
            </rs>, the property of 
               <persName id="t17650417-33-victim320" type="victimName">
                  Bailey 
                  Halfpenny 
               <interp inst="t17650417-33-victim320" type="surname" value="Halfpenny"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-33-victim320" type="given" value="Bailey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-33-victim320" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , <rs id="t17650417-33-cd191" type="crimeDate">March 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-33-off190 t17650417-33-cd191"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650417-33-person321">
                  Mary 
                  Halfpenny 
               <interp inst="t17650417-33-person321" type="surname" value="Halfpenny"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-33-person321" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-33-person321" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am twelve years of age.</p>
               <p>Q. If you should say falsely, what will be the consequence?</p>
               <p>M. Halfpenny. If I do, God Almighty will d - n me; but I will speak the truth.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does your mother live?</p>
               <p>M. Halfpenny. She lives on Artichoke-hill.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your father?</p>
               <p>M. Halfpenny. My father is a coleheaver.</p>
               <p>Court. Now take care, and say nothing but what is exactly true.</p>

               <p>M. Halfpenny. I will. On Thursday before quarter day last the prisoner said, Molly, will you go with me out of Rosemary-lane, to see my sick mother? going through an alley, first she said, Will you give me that money you have in your pocket? I said I can take care of it myself: she then knock'd me down, and took it out of my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she take out of your pocket?</p>
               <p>M. Halfpenny. She took a guinea, two six-pences, a shilling, and some halfpence.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you by that money?</p>
               <p>M. Halfpenny. My mamma gave it to me, to carry home, to put in a drawer to pay a quarter's rent.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you told the prisoner any thing about the money?</p>
               <p>M. Halfpenny. No: I had not.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she knock you down with?</p>
               <p>M. Halfpenny. With her fist; I arose up again, and ran from her, and cried out she had robbed me; she was going to stamp upon me.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did your mamma give it you?</p>
               <p>M. Halfpenny. In Rosemary-lane; here is the woman who was with my mamma then.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it in a house, or in the street?</p>
               <p>M. Halfpenny. It was in the street.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner with you there?</p>
               <p>M. Halfpenny. She came to me two or three minutes after my mamma gave it to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she see your mamma give it to you?</p>
               <p>M. Halfpenny. I believe she might.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did the prisoner take the money from you?</p>
               <p>M. Halfpenny. It was between six and seven in the evening.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure it was the prisoner at the bar?</p>
               <p>M. Halfpenny. I know it was her; I followed her all the way, till she was taken up by Shoreditch church.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you keep sight of her all the way?</p>
               <p>M. Halfpenny. I did; I never lost sight of her: I called out she had robbed me, and a gentleman charged a constable with her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know her before?</p>
               <p>M. Halfpenny. No: I did not.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you do any business?</p>
               <p>M. Halfpenny. I go out to service.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you say you never saw the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>M. Halfpenny. I never saw her before?</p>
               <p>Q. Was your mother sent for to you?</p>
               <p>M. Halfpenny. She was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not your mamma say to you, you was a naughty girl, she had not seen you from eight that morning?</p>
               <p>M. Halfpenny. No; she did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What was your mamma's business in Rosemary-lane?</p>
               <p>M. Halfpenny. My mamma went to buy a bit of meat.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did she go there?</p>
               <p>M. Halfpenny. She had been there all day, till she sent me home with the money.</p>

               <p>Q. What did you say to the prisoner, when she asked you to go with her?</p>
               <p>M. Halfpenny. I said yes, I would, with all my heart.</p>
               <p>Q. What words did she make use of?</p>
               <p>M. Halfpenny. She said, Polly, Will you go along with me?</p>
               <p>Q. Then she knew you before?</p>
               <p>M. Halfpenny. I thought she did by that; we went into the Hackney road, and I thought it might be some of the neighbours.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650417-33-person322">
                  Oliver 
                  Welch 
               <interp inst="t17650417-33-person322" type="surname" value="Welch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-33-person322" type="given" value="Oliver"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-33-person322" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The child came crying to my house, and said the girl had robbed her. ( I am a constable and live in Shoreditch.)</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Welch. This was a month ago, to-day, I believe: I took the prisoner in custody; there came up a marine, and said the prisoner had some of his money; he searched her, and got 8 s. 6 d.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176504170020"></xptr> which she owned was his property; he took it from her; she denied seeing any money of the girl's; I found only that 8 s. 6 d. upon her; when the girl's mother was sent for to the watch-house, she said her daughter had not a farthing in her pocket, only six pence.</p>
               <p>Mr. Slipper. I happened to go to a public house; I saw the house in confusion; I enquired the reason of it; there was a marine, and some women that appeared to be girls of the town: the marine said he had been robbed of upwards of 30 l. by the woman at the bar; she was then in our watch-house in Shore-ditch: I said, How came you by so much money? said the marine, I received it at the pay-office, and have been along with her, and she has robb'd me of it: When the mother of the girl was sent for, she came, about ten at night; I desired she might be kept from the daughter; I said to the daughter, How much money has this woman robb'd you of? she answered, of a guinea, a nine-shilling piece, and eighteen-pence (three six-pences): I said, How came you by so much money? she said her mother gave it her: I asked her where her mother lived; she said she keeps a shop in Rag-fair; but lives somewhere in Ratcliff-Highway; she said her mother gave her that money in order to lock up, to pay the rent, and not to let her father see it; for he is a coal-heaver, and a very drunken man. I said, Why did you go with this woman? she said she knew her very well, she had been servant with her mother three days; that she came to the shop that afternoon, and saw her mother give her the money, and she inveigled her to go with her to see her mother in Shoreditch: that she went with her, and she brought her up some turnings, and asked her for the money, and knocked her down, and took it from her. When the mother came, I spoke to her; the girl said, don't you speak to my mother; she will go into fits, and I shall also fall into fits: I said to the mother, Pray, good woman, where did you see your daughter last? she looked, and said, O! there she is! O you impudent wretch! I have not seen you since eight o'clock this morning; how dare you be out so long. Said I, Does she often go out? She said, Yes, too often. Said I, Do you trust this girl with any money? she said, No; I have none to trust her with: said the girl, Did not you give me a guinea? said the mother, I have not a shilling in the world: said the girl, Don't you remember you gave me a guinea? O! said the mother, I gave you two guineas; I hope you have not lost them: Yes, said the girl, Bett Jones has robb'd me. Then said I, are not you a wicked woman, to behave in this manner? then the mother sham'd fits. I never in my days saw so iniquitous an affair.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Slipper. I am school-master at Shoreditch.</p>
               <p>Q. to the daughter. You said, when I asked you if you knew the consequence of an oath, that if you did not speak truth, God Almighty would d - n you; do you consider what that is?</p>
               <p>Girl. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. How could you dare to give such an account as you now have done, that appears entirely false?</p>
               <p>Girl. Sir, indeed she took and knock'd me down, and took the money out of my pocket.</p>
               <p>Court. You said you did not know her before, and you told that witness you did know her.</p>
               <p>Girl. I never said I knew her before.</p>

               <p>Court. I expect you will tell me who set you to say as you have done: there is no way of saving yourself in this world or the next, but by telling the truth: I expect you will tell me directly.</p>
               <p>Girl. No body but myself, indeed, Sir.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I am clear of every thing.</p>
               <p>The mother to the girl. I desire to be examined.</p>
               <p>Court. Here are two people swear positively against what your daughter has swore; and if I find you are perjured, I shall immediately commit you; so consider of it: you declared you gave the girl no money at all till she talked to you. Do you know the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Mother. I can't say I know her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she live servant to you.</p>
               <p>Mother. She did once; that was three days.</p>
               <p>She declined being sworn.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17650417-33-verdict192" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650417-33-verdict192" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
