<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650918-17">
               <interp inst="t17650918-17" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650918-17" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650918-17" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650918"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650918-17" type="date" value="17650918"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650918-17-off97-c147" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-17-defend181 t17650918-17-off97 t17650918-17-verdict99"></join>
         
               <p>434. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17650918-17-defend181" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Elizabeth 
                     Sutherland 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17650918-17-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-17-defend181 t17650918-17-alias-3"></join>Levand</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-17-defend181" type="surname" value="Sutherland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-17-defend181" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-17-defend181" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17650918-17-deflabel96" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-17-defend181 t17650918-17-deflabel96"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17650918-17-off97" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650918-17-off97" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-17-off97" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a linen sheet, value 3 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17650918-17-victim184" type="victimName">
                           Edward 
                           Belcher 
                        <interp inst="t17650918-17-victim184" type="surname" value="Belcher"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650918-17-victim184" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650918-17-victim184" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-17-off97 t17650918-17-victim184"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in a certain lodging-room let by contract by the said Edward to the said Elizabeth
            </rs>, <rs id="t17650918-17-cd98" type="crimeDate">Aug. 6</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-17-off97 t17650918-17-cd98"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650918-17-person185">
                  Edward 
                  Belcher 
               <interp inst="t17650918-17-person185" type="surname" value="Belcher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-17-person185" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-17-person185" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Short's Gardens: the prisoner came to lodge at my house about five weeks before she did this fact, which was on the 6th of August: I let her the lodgings myself for 3 s. 6 d. a-week; the sheet was part of the furniture: she went out, and did not come home: one of my lodgers met with her, and they charg'd each other, and were both in the round house all night: she would not tell where the sheet was when I charg'd her with it, till I took her before Justice Welch: she sent me to twenty pawnbrokers; then Mr. Welch said she should go to Bridewell; at last she said it was at Mr. Stockdale's.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you give her liberty to pawn it?</p>
               <p>Belcher. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650918-17-person186">
                  John 
                  Nash 
               <interp inst="t17650918-17-person186" type="surname" value="Nash"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-17-person186" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-17-person186" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am apprentice to Mr. Stockdale in Great Pultney-Street: the prisoner pledg'd this sheet to me on the 5th of 
               <persName id="t17650918-17-person187">
                  August. 
               <interp inst="t17650918-17-person187" type="given" value="August."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-17-person187" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            (Produced and deposed to).</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. The pawnbroker at first denied it; and when the justice threatened to send the constable, then he sent the sheet.</p>
               <p>Q. to Nash. Did the prisoner give you any directions about this sheet?</p>
               <p>Nash. No; only she said it was her own property.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to deny that you had it?</p>
               <p>Nash. It is not customary with us to own any thing when people come for them, till we know the right owner?</p>
               <p>Q. What did you say to the man?</p>
               <p>Nash. I told him to bring the person that pledg'd it, and they should have it.</p>
               <p>Court. Whenever a person comes again from a magistrate for things supposed to be stolen, and you deny them, you will richly deserve to stand where that woman does.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>The prosecutor gave me leave to pawn it, and a blanket too: we had been together to a gentleman that owned me money; after that, he said he was going to Rotherhithe; I said I wanted to go and get a gown and petticoat out of pawn: said he, if you want money, you may go and pledge a sheet.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. We had been together, and I went to Rotherhithe, and she came home; but I did not give her liberty to pawn it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know of her pawning a bl anket of your's?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I did know of that, and I forgave her.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He came to Clerkenwell Bridewell, and wanted me to turn my money over to him,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176509180014"></xptr> and he got a gold ring from my finger. Here is a letter he sent to me in prison (producing a letter).</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I never could write in my life; I know nothing of this letter.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you order any letter to be wrote to her?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No, I never did: she told me she had some money to receive; I said, if she would give me an order to receive it, I'll go and get it for you, and assist you in prison: she would not do any thing: she now owes me above 40 shillings, money lent and for lodging. I told her, if she would agree to that when she got out, she shall have the rest of her money.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never send a paper to her in prison?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I sent a line or two by a woman.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. This is it in my hand.</p>
               <p>It was read, to this purport:</p>
               <p>"I am sorry you have made such a fool of me</p>
               <p>"and yourself too. If you had done as I ask'd,</p>
               <p>"you would not have wanted for any thing; but</p>
               <p>"if you don't let me know, I will come to-morrow,</p>
               <p>"but not to be made a fool of again, as</p>
               <p>"before. If you do, all shall be made easy.</p>
               <p>"Pray send me word to-morrow or to-night by</p>
               <p>"the bearer."</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. What I sent by the woman was in such a manner.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17650918-17-verdict99" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650918-17-verdict99" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
