<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670909-69">
               <interp inst="t17670909-69" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670909-69" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670909-69" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670909"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670909-69" type="date" value="17670909"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670909-69-off408-c601" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-69-defend749 t17670909-69-off408 t17670909-69-verdict414"></join>
         
               <p>494. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17670909-69-defend749" type="defendantName">
                  Joseph 
                  Payne 
               <interp inst="t17670909-69-defend749" type="surname" value="Payne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-69-defend749" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-69-defend749" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17670909-69-off408" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670909-69-off408" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-69-off408" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               feloniously and carnally knowing and abusing 
                     
                        <persName id="t17670909-69-victim751" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Brand 
                        <interp inst="t17670909-69-victim751" type="surname" value="Brand"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670909-69-victim751" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670909-69-victim751" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-69-off408 t17670909-69-victim751"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17670909-69-viclabel409" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-69-victim751 t17670909-69-viclabel409"></join>, an <rs id="t17670909-69-viclabel410" type="occupation">infant</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-69-victim751 t17670909-69-viclabel410"></join> under the age of ten years
            </rs>, <rs id="t17670909-69-cd411" type="crimeDate">Aug. 6</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-69-off408 t17670909-69-cd411"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-69-person752">
                  Hannah 
                  Burch 
               <interp inst="t17670909-69-person752" type="surname" value="Burch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-69-person752" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-69-person752" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live by the Seven-dials, but I was at my brother's house, named 
               <persName id="t17670909-69-person753">
                  Richard 
                  Brand 
               <interp inst="t17670909-69-person753" type="surname" value="Brand"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-69-person753" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-69-person753" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in <placeName id="t17670909-69-crimeloc412">Somerset-street, by Whitechapel</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17670909-69-crimeloc412" type="placeName" value="Somerset-street, by Whitechapel"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17670909-69-crimeloc412" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-69-off408 t17670909-69-crimeloc412"></join>; his wife was ill; he was upon letting the house; they lived in a public-house; he is a barber, the prisoner is his <rs id="t17670909-69-deflabel413" type="occupation">apprentice</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-69-defend749 t17670909-69-deflabel413"></join>; the house is opposite that public-house. On the 6th of August the prisoner was ordered to carry drawers and things over to that house; I sent the child 
               <persName id="t17670909-69-person754">
                  Anne 
                  Brand 
               <interp inst="t17670909-69-person754" type="surname" value="Brand"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-69-person754" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-69-person754" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             over to that house, to Mary her sister, to know the reason of her staying: Anne is near eleven years of age; the day after, she told me her sister Mary was ill: an acquaintance of mine called to see me the day after; when we were at tea, she said to Anne, how do you do, when will you go into the country; Anne said, something ails my sister, she is very bad; upon that, I took Mary, and examined her; I was very much frighted, her parts were very much hurt; this was on the eighth.</p>
               <p>Q. How old is 
               <persName id="t17670909-69-person755">
                  Mary 
                  Brand 
               <interp inst="t17670909-69-person755" type="surname" value="Brand"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-69-person755" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-69-person755" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>H. Burch. She is eight years of age; a surgeon examined her on Tuesday the 11th; I told my brother of it the day I examined her; we took the prisoner before my Lord-Mayor; the child was asked why she could let the boy serve her so, and not cry out; she said she did cry out, and he stopped her mouth, and said, if ever she told of it, he would whip her till the blood run at her heels; this was on the 10th; the prisoner was by at the time, he denied it.</p>
               <p>Q. How did the parts appear when you examined her?</p>
               <p>H. Burch. They appeared swelled, and to be torn; there was a great running; I observed it very much on her linen.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any blood?</p>
               <p>H. Burch. No, I did not, she kept it from me, she said because the prisoner had promised to give her some halfpence to buy some doll's clothes.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176709090060"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-69-person756">
                  Richard 
                  Brand 
               <interp inst="t17670909-69-person756" type="surname" value="Brand"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-69-person756" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-69-person756" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am father to the child; I first heard of this on Saturday the 8th, from my sister; I did not examine the child then; the child and I lay together that night; I examined her in the morning very closely; I found her linen and the sheet in a very bad condition; I looked upon it that somebody had been concerned with the child; I spoke to her in a very soft mild manner; I said, child, somebody has been doing you an injury, do not be frighted, tell me the truth, and you may depend upon it I shall not do you any harm; she said the prisoner threw her down upon the bed, and said, Polly, my dear, if you will let me put my d - le into your c - y, I will give you all the money I can get to buy you some cherries; she said he lay upon her a considerable time, and hurt her very much, and she tried to cry out, but he stopped her mouth with both his hands, so that she could hardly fetch her breath, and afterwards if she told, he threatened he would whip her till the blood ran down her heels. On the Monday the surgeon was going by the door, I called him in, and told him the child said she had been injured by my apprentice; he examined her, and he is here to give the court an account of what he observed. I took the prisoner up, and took him before my Lord-Mayor, and they were separately examined.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-69-person757">
                  Anne 
                  Brand 
               <interp inst="t17670909-69-person757" type="surname" value="Brand"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-69-person757" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-69-person757" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I believe I am between ten and eleven years old.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-69-person758">
                  Richard 
                  Brand 
               <interp inst="t17670909-69-person758" type="surname" value="Brand"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-69-person758" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-69-person758" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She is eleven years old.</p>
               <p>Q. to A. Brand. Do you know it is a bad thing if you do not tell the truth?</p>
               <p>A. Brand. I know it is a very bad thing, I will tell the truth.</p>
               <p>She is Sworn.</p>
               <p>Court. Now you have promised to tell the truth.</p>
               <p>A. Brand. My sister is 
               <persName id="t17670909-69-person759">
                  Mary 
                  Brand 
               <interp inst="t17670909-69-person759" type="surname" value="Brand"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-69-person759" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-69-person759" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , she is eight years old; my aunt sent me over to the other house on a Thursday about eleven o'clock, to see what Joe was about, as he staid very long; I went over, and peeped through the crack in the garret, the door was shut.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it locked?</p>
               <p>A. Brand. No, I pushed, and it opened a little, just to see through the crack; I saw the sweep of my sister's petticoat upon a chair, and I saw something white like his shirt, I thought I saw the fore-part of it as I went into the room; he was standing up with his back towards me; my sister took up a box with some things in it, and he snatched it out of her hand; I said to my sister, why did you not send Joe down; he snuggled down stairs as fast as ever he could.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he his clothes on when you went first into the room?</p>
               <p>A. Brand. He had; the next day we had half a holiday; I said to my sister, let us go up into the garret to play; we did; she wanted to make water; she said, I cannot make water; I said, what is the matter; I looked, and saw her private parts were all like a yellow ribbon; I said to her, you cannot think what a deal of nasty stuff there is; said she, never mind it; I told my aunt of it the next day.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-69-person760">
                  Thomas 
                  Brand 
               <interp inst="t17670909-69-person760" type="surname" value="Brand"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-69-person760" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-69-person760" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am seventeen years of age; I am a cousin; I lived at the public-house; the prisoner was taken up, and before my Lord-Mayor he said I was in the room all the time, but I was not, I was in the public-house.</p>
         
               <p>*** The last Part of these Proceedings will be Published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17670909-69">
                  <interp inst="t17670909-69" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17670909-69" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17670909-69" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670909"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17670909-69" type="date" value="17670909"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176709090061"></xptr>THE WHOLE PROCEEDINGS ON THE KING's COMMISSIONS of the PEACE, OYER and TERMINER, and GOAL DELIVERY FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the GOAL DELIVERY FOR THE COUNTY of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 9th, Thursday the 10th, Friday the 11th, Saturday the 12th, Monday the 14th, Tuesday the 15th, and Wednesday the 16th, of SEPTEMBER,</p>
                  <p>In the Seventh Year of His MAJESTY's Reign. Being the Seventh SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of THE RIGHT HONOURABLE SIR 
                  <persName id="t17670909-69-person761">
                     ROBERT 
                     KITE 
                  <interp inst="t17670909-69-person761" type="surname" value="KITE"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670909-69-person761" type="given" value="ROBERT"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670909-69-person761" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , KNT. LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>NUMBER VII. PART IV.</p>
                  <p>LONDON,</p>
                  <p>Printed for J. WILKIE, at the Bible, in St. Paul's Church-Yard.</p>
                  <p>[Price Six-Pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176709090062"></xptr>THE WHOLE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Goal Delivery held for the City of LONDON, &amp;c.</p>
                  <p>Continuation of the Trial of 
                  <persName id="t17670909-69-person762">
                     Joseph 
                     Payne 
                  <interp inst="t17670909-69-person762" type="surname" value="Payne"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670909-69-person762" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670909-69-person762" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               .</p>
               </div1>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-69-person763">
                  William 
                  Toleman 
               <interp inst="t17670909-69-person763" type="surname" value="Toleman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-69-person763" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-69-person763" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>I Am a surgeon; I examined the child on Monday the 10th of August, as near as I can recollect between three and four in the afternoon; I found her much lacerated and torn; she was in a very deplorable condition, and could hardly stir about without crying out; it appeared to me beyond a doubt she had been injured, but I could not determine by who.</p>
               <p>Q. How injured?</p>
               <p>Toleman. I believe she had been penetrated, and carnally known; I examined her as strictly as possible in the presence of her aunt; I have reason to believe there was some venereal taint.</p>
               <p>Q. From what do you form your judgment?</p>
               <p>Toleman. We judge from the discharge frequently; I believe it certainly was so; I treated it as venereal; the child has been under a slight course of salivation for ten days.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner examined as to that?</p>
               <p>Toleman. He was, after he was at the Poultry Compter; I myself examined him; he had a little of it, but I have reason, from some circumstances, to believe he had been so lately, and was so at the time of the injury given.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after the time he was taken up was it you examined him?</p>
               <p>Toleman. I believe it was six or eight days after he had been before my Lord-Mayor.</p>
               <p>Q. By what circumstances do you judge?</p>
               <p>Toleman. There was a number of ugly livid blotches about him, many upon his legs, some on his arms, and upon different parts of his body.</p>
               <p>Q. What other circumstance?</p>
               <p>Toleman. I not only was convinced by this, but it appeared there had been a running a few days before from what I saw, because the inflammation had not already subsided from the corrosive discharge.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you venture to say, from these appearances, with certainty, that this lad had had the venereal taint?</p>
               <p>Toleman. I think I can venture to affirm it for a certainty; and, in my judgment, I do believe the child had been penetrated.</p>
               <p>The child examined, but not upon oath.</p>
               <p>Q. How old are you?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-69-person764">
                  Mary 
                  Brand 
               <interp inst="t17670909-69-person764" type="surname" value="Brand"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-69-person764" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-69-person764" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am eight years old.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you so ill, who hurt you?</p>
               <p>M. Brand. Joe did.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was it he hurt you?</p>
               <p>M. Brand. My b - y.</p>
               <p>Q. In what room?</p>
               <p>M. Brand. In the garret.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he hurt you?</p>
               <p>M. Brand. He put his d - le into my b - y.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to let him do so?</p>
               <p>M. Brand. He said he would give me some money and some cherries.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was in the room at the time?</p>
               <p>M. Brand. There was no body but him; I was put down on the bed.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you not to tell of it?</p>
               <p>M. Brand. He said he would whip me if I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell any body of it?</p>
               <p>M. Brand. I told my sister of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any thing the matter with you?</p>
               <p>M. Brand. Yes, a running, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you first find it out that you was ill?</p>
               <p>M. Brand. When I made water.</p>
               <p>Q. How soon was that after you was hurt?</p>
               <p>M. Brand. I believe it was the next day.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176709090063"></xptr>Q. Had Joe ever moddled with you so before?</p>
               <p>M. Brand. No.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you not to cry out?</p>
               <p>M. Brand. He stopped my mouth with his hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body else hurt you but Joe?</p>
               <p>M. Brand. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I protest I never had the venereal disease in my life, these blotches were occasioned by the itch.</p>
               <p>Q. to Toleman. Could the blotches be the effect of the itch?</p>
               <p>Toleman. The blotches occasioned by the itch are not like these, there is a material difference.</p>
               <p>Q. Could that of a running have happened in consequence of so recent an injury given but the day before?</p>
               <p>Toleman. The discharge of a recent injury, is very different in colour from that of a longer time; the shift was as if it had been dipped in something of the buckram kind; I have seen some others very bad, but I never saw any so lacerated as this child.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I am innocent as the child unborn; the father has instilled these notions into the child's head; he stood behind her, before my Lord-Mayor, and told her what to say: there are other lads that resort there besides me; the mother of the child packed up the bed; I took and carried it over, and threw it down in the shop; my master came over, and desired me to make haste; the child was not there when I carried it up.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17670909-69-verdict414" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670909-69-verdict414" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17670909-69-punish415" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670909-69-punish415" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-69-punish415" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="respited"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-69-defend749 t17670909-69-punish415"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
