<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17601204-12">
               <interp inst="t17601204-12" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17601204-12" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17601204-12" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17601204"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17601204-12" type="date" value="17601204"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17601204-12-off70-c98" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601204-12-defend123 t17601204-12-off70 t17601204-12-verdict74"></join>
         
               <p>13 (M) 
               
                  <persName id="t17601204-12-defend123" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Roundson 
                  <interp inst="t17601204-12-defend123" type="surname" value="Roundson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-defend123" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-defend123" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for the <rs id="t17601204-12-off70" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-off70" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-off70" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               wilful murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17601204-12-victim125" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Fowler 
                        <interp inst="t17601204-12-victim125" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17601204-12-victim125" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17601204-12-victim125" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601204-12-off70 t17601204-12-victim125"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>: he stood charged on the coroner's inquest, for manslaughter. <rs id="t17601204-12-cd71" type="crimeDate">Nov. 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601204-12-off70 t17601204-12-cd71"></join>.*</p> 
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601204-12-person126">
                  Jos 
                  Guy 
               <interp inst="t17601204-12-person126" type="surname" value="Guy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person126" type="given" value="Jos"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person126" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew the deceased 
               <persName id="t17601204-12-person127">
                  John 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17601204-12-person127" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person127" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person127" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. How old was he?</p>
               <p>Guy. He was a lighter-man's son, about eleven years old.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he dead?</p>
               <p>Guy. He is.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he come by his death?</p>
               <p>Guy. I saw 
               <persName id="t17601204-12-person128">
                  Richard 
                  Roundson 
               <interp inst="t17601204-12-person128" type="surname" value="Roundson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person128" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person128" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and his wife coming along: she had a child in her arms.</p>
               <p>Q. When was it?</p>
               <p>Guy. It was three weeks ago yesterday.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day?</p>
               <p>Guy. Between six and seven in the evening, there was a bonfire just by <placeName id="t17601204-12-crimeloc72">Pelican-stairs, near the Swan-alehouse</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17601204-12-crimeloc72" type="placeName" value="Pelican-stairs, near the Swan-alehouse"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17601204-12-crimeloc72" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601204-12-off70 t17601204-12-crimeloc72"></join>; they were coming towards the fire, and many people were about the fire.</p>
               <p>Q. How far distance was he from the fire when you first saw him?</p>
               <p>Guy. About four yards.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he any thing in his hand?</p>
               <p>Guy. Nothing but his stuff on his left-shoulder.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by a staff?</p>
               <p>Guy. It was a boat hook. [A boat-hook produced in court, the staff about seven or eight feet long, an iron socket at the biggest end, with a sharp iron point to push forwards, and a hook to lay hold of any thing to pull it to.]</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Guy. He is a <rs id="t17601204-12-deflabel73" type="occupation">coal-heaver</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601204-12-defend123 t17601204-12-deflabel73"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it is business to make use of such an instrument?</p>
               <p>Guy. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Tell what happened.</p>
               <p>Guy. We had a tar barrel burning, and he took the hook and shoved it down. We asked him what that was for. He said for sun. Then said we, lend us the staff, and we will haul it up again. He said. I will haul it up myself. He was going to haul it up, and there came a serpent and hit him on the breast. Some call them squibs.</p>
               <p>Q. How near the fire was he then?</p>
               <p>Guy. He was within a yard or two of it, he had not taken the staff off his shoulder then: he took it from his left shoulder, and brought it over his right-shoulder, and made a violent blow right down.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know who threw the squib?</p>
               <p>Guy. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Fowler throw it?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176012040012"></xptr>Guy. No, he did not; he stood with his hands before him.</p>
               <p>Q. Whereabouts did the serpent come from?</p>
               <p>Guy. It came from towards Pelican-stairs, from a good way distance, it touched his breast, and fell directly between his legs.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there many people about the fire?</p>
               <p>Guy. There was a vast fight of people about, but only that boy 
               <persName id="t17601204-12-person129">
                  John 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17601204-12-person129" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person129" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person129" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and a surgeon's little boy, that was the minute before talking to him: he was gone a little way from Fowler; there were only these two boys near the prisoner: it hit Fowler over his head.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner say any thing?</p>
               <p>Guy. No, he never spoke, but shoved the hook backwards and forwards, to get it out of the child's brains.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there a space between those two boys and the rest of the folks?</p>
               <p>Guy. There was; they were on one side of the way, and the rest of the people on the other.</p>
               <p>Q. Whereabouts was you?</p>
               <p>Guy. I was standing just by, on the other side of the way.</p>
               <p>Q. How far distance?</p>
               <p>Guy. About five yards.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the blow fall?</p>
               <p>Guy. Yes, it light on the child's head, and he fell directly: he hauled the child between his legs, with the hook, before he got it out.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take notice which part of the iron went into the child's head?</p>
               <p>Guy. I did not take notice then: I took the child up, and put my foot on the staff, that no body should take it away.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not the prisoner speak at all?</p>
               <p>Guy. He never spoke till he had got the hook out of the child's head: then he said, O Lord, what have I done! and let the staff fall out of his hands. I saw the child's brains come through his cap. I could not find him fetch any breath. I thought him dead.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he live?</p>
               <p>Guy. He lived till the Saturday morning, and died about five minutes after three o'clock. Several people took hold of the prisoner, and he was carried before justice Berry.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe he had a serpent flung at him before he got to the fire?</p>
               <p>Guy. I did not observe that he had.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there not such a staff as this made use of at the fire?</p>
               <p>Guy. No, never a one.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you keep the fire up?</p>
               <p>Guy. We took our hands to it, and put the tar-barrel on with our hands.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he put the tar-barrel on again?</p>
               <p>Guy. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think he would have gone away if the serpent had not been flung at him?</p>
               <p>Guy. I believe he would.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it towards the way that the serpent came, that he struck?</p>
               <p>Guy. No, that came before him, and he struck towards his left-hand, and the other little boy had left Fowler; so that he was alone standing by a post. The prisoner turned and struck directly as he turned.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it light where Fowler stood?</p>
               <p>Guy. There was the light of the fire.</p>
               <p>Q. Might not that be to rest it from his shoulder, in order to see who threw the squib; or will you take upon yourself to say, that he mean, or levelled it at the lad?</p>
               <p>Guy. No, I do not think he meant to level it at the lad, it was at somebody I believe; if it had been at any of us, it had been all the same: he struck with revenge, as I thought with resentment</p>
               <p>Q. What was done then?</p>
               <p>Guy. He pulled him down in the channel: I believe he was the worse for liquor: he let go the staff the minute he got it out of the child's head.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he seem sorry?</p>
               <p>Guy. He cried very much.</p>
               <p>Q. On what part of the head was this wound?</p>
               <p>Guy. On the right-side of the head: the lad was standing upright, and the blow came right down.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601204-12-person130">
                  Isaac 
                  Newton 
               <interp inst="t17601204-12-person130" type="surname" value="Newton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person130" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person130" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the bonfire that night; the first thing I observed was the tar-barrel on the fire; there were three or four of us talking: then I observed the barrel was thrown down.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see who threw it off?</p>
               <p>Newton. No, I did not; then I said, who has thrown the barrel off? Somebody in the mob made answer, that man with the boat-hook. I went up to him, and asked him the reason for so doing. I will not be sure whether he said for fun, or what. Then I asked him for the boat-hook, to put it on again; he said no, he would put it on himself; and I really think he was going |to put it on. Then somebody threw a squib from the mob, and it hit him on the breast.</p>
               <p>Q. How far from the fire was he when you spoke to him?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176012040013"></xptr>Newton. He was got about four yards from it, when the squib hit him; whether the staff was on his shoulder, or not, I cannot say; but he up with the staff, and made a blow. He put both hands to it, and struck down right.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him turn himself about at the time?</p>
               <p>Newton. I did not, the blow light on 
               <persName id="t17601204-12-person131">
                  John 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17601204-12-person131" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person131" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person131" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who stood just before him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any body else standing before him besides 
               <persName id="t17601204-12-person132">
                  John 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17601204-12-person132" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person132" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person132" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Newton. I cannot say who else was standing before him; there were several people standing about there; they were all round about, as people commonly are about a fire.</p>
               <p>Q. On what part of the head did the blow light?</p>
               <p>Newton. On the right-side of the head; and when the boy was on the ground (by the violence of the blow) I saw the prisoner wriggle the staff two or three times. Then I turned myself, and went over the channel.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him draw the hook out of the child's head?</p>
               <p>Newton. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see what part of the staff hit the boy?</p>
               <p>Newton. No, I did not; but it must be the hook, because he was troubled to get it out of the boy's head. When I was over the channel, I turned myself round, and saw the prisoner by the Swan-door: I went and took hold on him: we had help presently: then we hauled him down in the channel.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say?</p>
               <p>Newton. I did not hear him speak a word, only he cried much, and made a noise.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the child throw the serpent?</p>
               <p>Newton. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the child given him any affront?</p>
               <p>Newton. I cannot say that he had. When we were going down the street to carry him to the watch-house, he said two or three times: O! what have I done!</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see such another boat-hook as this used at the fire?</p>
               <p>Newton. I can't say I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you present at the watch-house?</p>
               <p>Newton. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Where there any serpents thrown at him afterwards?</p>
               <p>Newton. I did not see any.</p>
               <p>Q. When he came into the watch house, was his face hurt?</p>
               <p>Newton. I cannot say it was: it was dark.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think he was going to put up the tar-barrel?</p>
               <p>Newton. I dare say he was.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601204-12-person133">
                  John 
                  Platt 
               <interp inst="t17601204-12-person133" type="surname" value="Platt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person133" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person133" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the bonfire: I saw this man coming along with a boat-hook on his shoulder, and his wife along with him, with a child in her arms: he hauled the tar-barrel down. We bid him put it up again. He said, he would. Somebody threw a serpent at him, and struck him on his breast. He took the hook and t hrew it down with his two hands, and it light on the child's skull. He struck down-right from off his left-shoulder.</p>
               <p>Q. Who threw the serpent?</p>
               <p>Platt. I do not know that.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him turn about?</p>
               <p>Platt. I cannot say I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he flourish the staff about?</p>
               <p>Platt. I did not see him flourish it; he intended to make a blow at somebody, I believe; but who, I do not know. With that he took and wriggled the staff to get it out of the child's skull. Then we took and hauled the prisoner down in the chanel, and carried him before justice Berry. He said, O Lord, have mercy on me! as we were carrying him along: and Lord have mercy on my poor wife and children!</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Would he have put up the tar-barrel, do you think, if it had not been for the squib being thrown?</p>
               <p>Platt. I believe he would.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he seem pleased that he had done a thing of this sort?</p>
               <p>Platt. No, he seemed concerned for it, and cry'd.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure the child did not throw the squib?</p>
               <p>Platt. I am sure the child did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Which way did it come?</p>
               <p>Platt. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body throw any thing else at him?</p>
               <p>Platt. I did not see any thing else thrown at him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601204-12-person134">
                  Thomas 
                  Fox 
               <interp inst="t17601204-12-person134" type="surname" value="Fox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person134" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person134" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the prisoner coming by the White Swan, with a boat-hook on his shoulder. He took the hook, and threw the tar-barrel down from the fire. He went about three or four yards; they laid hold of him, and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176012040014"></xptr> said, what did you heave the tar barrel down for? he said, for fun, or some such words; we said, lend us your boat hook, and we'll put it up again; he said, no, I'll put it up myself; he went to put it up, and a serpent came and hit him on his breast.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know who threw it?</p>
               <p>Fox. No, I do not; it came from a distance.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the hook at that time?</p>
               <p>Fox. At that time the hook was on his shoulder; then he step'd forward and struck with as much force as ever he cou'd, and struck 
               <persName id="t17601204-12-person135">
                  John 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17601204-12-person135" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person135" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person135" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             over his head. He struck right forward.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think he aimed particularly at 
               <persName id="t17601204-12-person136">
                  John 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17601204-12-person136" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person136" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person136" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Fox. No, I don't think he did? he aim'd at somebody, for he step'd forward and struck with as much force as he could; after that he said, O Lord, have mercy on me! O Lord, have mercy on me, and upon my poor wife and family! and cry'd: we seiz'd him and heav'd him into the channel. He cry'd out, What have I done. We took him up, and carried him to the watch house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any hurt upon his face?</p>
               <p>Fox. No, I did not. The serpent hit him on his breast; it did not come near his face.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What was he doing at the time this happen'd?</p>
               <p>Fox. I believe he was going to put up the barrel again. I do not think he went to strike this poor lad. The lad stood with his hands in his pockets. He was quite a stranger to me. I saw the prisoner wriggle the hook to get it out, so that we should not see him, and I believe he was sorry for it immediately. He gave himself up, but his wife made more noise than he did by a great deal.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601204-12-person137">
                  William 
                  Bean 
               <interp inst="t17601204-12-person137" type="surname" value="Bean"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person137" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person137" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw this man coming with a staff; one tar barrel was burnt, and we had got another fresh one on; he, with his staff, shov'd the tar barrel down. I, and another young man, went up to him, and said, what did you shove that down for? he said, for fun, or some such words; we said, lend us the staff, and we will put it up again; he said, no, I'll put it up again. There came a serpent and hit him on his breast, he took the staff from his shoulder and struck right down, and it happen'd to light on 
               <persName id="t17601204-12-person138">
                  John 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17601204-12-person138" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person138" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person138" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's head. I saw it go into his skull, and the prisoner wriggle and wriggle it to get it out again: it was either the hook or the sharp point that went into the skull. I don't know which. I ran a way to fetch the child's mother, so did not hear him say any thing.</p>

               <p>Barnet Watts. I saw the prisoner coming along with a boat hook on his shoulder, immediately he shov'd the tar barrel down; he was going on a little further. we ask'd him for the hook to haul it up again, he said, he would haul it up himself: as he was going to do it, there came a serpent and hit him on his breast, which breast I can't tell. He immediately took the staff from his shoulder and struck right down.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he brandish it about before he struck?</p>
               <p>Watts. I can't say he did; I believe it was the hook part that went into Fowler's head. I saw the prisoner wriggle it backwards and forwards in the child's skull to get it out; he lifted the child up from the ground with it.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say?</p>
               <p>Watts. I did not hear him say any thing.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the man seem sorry for what he had done?</p>
               <p>Watts. I believe he was sorry, but I can't say he was. I did not observe it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe the prisoner's face?</p>
               <p>Watts. No, I took no notice at all of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601204-12-person139">
                  Thomas 
                  Eaton 
               <interp inst="t17601204-12-person139" type="surname" value="Eaton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person139" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person139" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the bonfire and saw the prisoner coming with his staff on his shoulder. He shov'd the tar-barrel down, one of the young lads ask'd him, what he did it for; he said, for fun; they ask'd him for the staff to haul it up again, he said, he would haul it up himself. There came a serpent and hit him on the breast, he took the staff from his shoulder and struck right down, and it fell on 
               <persName id="t17601204-12-person140">
                  John 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17601204-12-person140" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person140" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person140" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he shov'd it backwards and forwards once or twice to get it out of his head. People cry'd murder! he let the staff go, and the people took hold of him; he began to cry out very much, and roar; Lord, have mercy on me! What have I done! They took him to the watch-house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any hurt on the prisoner's face?</p>
               <p>Eaton. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there a great many people there?</p>
               <p>Eaton. There were.</p>
               <p>Q. How did Fowler stand?</p>
               <p>Eaton. He was standing by a post, and it hit him on the skull.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601204-12-person141">
                  John 
                  Dulin 
               <interp inst="t17601204-12-person141" type="surname" value="Dulin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person141" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person141" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am grand-father to the child; I did not see this done. The wound was on the right side of the head: the child liv'd with me; I was drinking a pint of beer, and as I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176012040015"></xptr> came out of the ale-house, I heard these words (
               <persName id="t17601204-12-person142">
                  Jack 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17601204-12-person142" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person142" type="given" value="Jack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person142" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is killed.) I was affrighted.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you with the prisoner before the justice?</p>
               <p>Dulin. He roared out very much, Lord! what must I do: what have I done! I did not know him before I found he knew me. He said to me, O Mr. Dulin! what must I do! what have I done!</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I had been at my day's work, and was come on shore. We went to the house where we use, to get a little money, and had two or three pots of beer. My wife came for me with the child to come home to get my supper. I took the child in my arms, and carried it along the streets; it being uneasy, I gave it to the mother. Coming just by Pelican-stairs, there was a mob and a bonfire; there were several squibs thrown, one of which came in my face, and another against my wife and child. I looked amongst the mob, and missing my wife, took up a stick, (I did not know it was a boat hook) shoved the fire down, and looked about for my wife: they were for getting the staff from me, and were hanging about me. Hearing my wife was in danger, I did not know what I was doing. The boys had me down in the mud amongst their feet; directly as they were pulling to get the hook from me, it fell down, and did this thing.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601204-12-person143">
                  Samuel 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17601204-12-person143" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person143" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person143" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had been to work along with the prisoner on the day this thing happened: in the evening we went to a publick house at Cole stairs to refresh ourselves with liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was you there?</p>
               <p>Jones. We were there from about five till about seven, or a little after. The prisoner's wife came there with her child after him, and he went away with her.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he any thing in his hand when he left you?</p>
               <p>Jones. No, he had nothing at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he not a boat hook?</p>
               <p>Jones. No, no boat hook; he had his child in his arms, when he went out of the room to go away.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of your own knowledge what happened afterwards?</p>
               <p>Jones. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known him?</p>
               <p>Jones. I have known him about a year and half.</p>
               <p>Q. In what manner does he support himself and his family?</p>
               <p>Jones. He works at coal-heaving, and sometimes he goes a voyage to sea.</p>
               <p>Q. How has he behaved himself during the time you have known him?</p>
               <p>Jones. As a peaceable quiet man: I never knew him to behave otherwise.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601204-12-person144">
                  William 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17601204-12-person144" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person144" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person144" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had been at work with the prisoner that day.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you and the other witness brothers?</p>
               <p>Jones. No, we are not. We had done a very hard day's work together; we went and had twopennyworth of beer each of us, and got our money as usual. His wife had been somewhere that way; she came in, and he took the child in his arms, and they went away.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is this house from the place where the accident happened?</p>
               <p>Jones. It is about 400 yards distance.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he any thing in his hands at going away?</p>
               <p>Jones. No, he had nothing in the world in his hands but his child.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known him?</p>
               <p>Jones. I have known him about five years, during which time I never saw a more peaceable man in my life. He is a man that strives for his family as much as any man in England; he is a very hard working man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601204-12-person145">
                  William 
                  Campbell 
               <interp inst="t17601204-12-person145" type="surname" value="Campbell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person145" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person145" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodge at the Lebeck's-head, near where this bonfire was. I saw the prisoner coming along that night: I saw a squib lodge on the left side of his nose, just as he came up to the fire.</p>
               <p>Q. When you first saw him, had he any pole in his hand?</p>
               <p>Campbell. Not to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you seen any such thing used about the fire that night?</p>
               <p>Campbell. Yes, here are more evidences can prove that.</p>
               <p>Q. When he received the squib in his face, what was done?</p>
               <p>Campbell. He came up directly, and put down the fire.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he put it down with?</p>
               <p>Campbell. With a boat hook.</p>
               <p>Q. How long before he came there, had you seen a boat hook used at the fire?</p>
               <p>Campbell. I had seen one about 3 quarters of an hour before that. I imagine he threw down the fire on the receiving that squib in his face. He was going away from the fire, and they followed him, demanding the boat hook of him to put up the fire.</p>
               <p>Q. What was his answer?</p>
               <p>Campbell. The words he made use of, I can't readily say; something past between the boys and him. As they were demanding the boat hook, a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176012040016"></xptr> serpent came, and hit him on his breast, and in the struggle they called out a child was killed.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the boat hook hit the child?</p>
               <p>Campbell. No, I did not. After they had got him in the channel, I came up to him, laid hold on his collar as he was down in the channel, and said to the people, if you have a mind to take him a prisoner, do: don't murder him in the street.</p>
               <p>Q. What were they doing to him?</p>
               <p>Campbell. They were beating him in a very barbarous manner. I said, carry him into a house, and send for an officer. He never resisted, but cryed, O my wife and child! all the words we had from him in the channel, and when we had him up at the corner of the house, his words were only, O my wife and child! I am a stranger to both parties.</p>
               <p>Captain 
               <persName id="t17601204-12-person146">
                  Horrsby
               <interp inst="t17601204-12-person146" type="given" value="Horrsby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person146" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am captain of a vessel. I was in the expedition against Quebeck. The prisoner sailed along with me three or four years in different voyages; he was with me at Quebeck last year; two years before he was with me at Greenland.</p>
               <p>Q. Of your knowledge of him how has he behaved himself?</p>
               <p>Horrsby. He never was addicted to passion, but a peaceable, good natured, orderly man; never disobeyed my command. I have been told that a great many people received injuries by squibs that night.</p>
               <p>Mr. Webb. I keep the White Horse right opposite where the fire was. When I shut my windows, I went out to see what was done; there were squibs flying about for 3 quarters of an hour before this accident happened: I saw also a staff thereabout 3 quarters of an hour before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe whether there was a hook to it, or not?</p>
               <p>Webb. No, I did not observe that.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this (here produced) Was it such a one?</p>
               <p>Webb. It was much like it.</p>
               <p>Mr. Dyer. I have known the prisoner going on three years.</p>
               <p>Q. How has he behaved?</p>
               <p>Dyer. He has behaved extremely well. I am a coal-shovel-maker, and would take his word as soon as I would the best man that uses them.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you look upon him to be a peaceable man, or otherwise?</p>
               <p>Dyer. I really believe him to be a peaceable honest man.</p>
               <p>Mr. Herrington. I have known him about seven or eight year.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character as to temper and behaviour?</p>
               <p>Herrington. He is as honest and quiet a creature as ever drew breath.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601204-12-person147">
                  Thomas 
                  Fox 
               <interp inst="t17601204-12-person147" type="surname" value="Fox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person147" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person147" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I failed with the prisoner three years, and have known him five.</p>
               <p>Q. What has been his character with regard to his temper and behaviour?</p>
               <p>Fox. A peaceable man as need to go on board of ship, as far as I ever saw of him.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17601204-12-verdict74" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-verdict74" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-verdict74" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>We judge it necessary, as a caution to such who delight in flinging about firebrands, &amp;c. to disturb their peaceable neighbours, here to insert the penalty and punishment in the act of parliament of the 9th and 10th of 
               <persName id="t17601204-12-person148">
                  William
               <interp inst="t17601204-12-person148" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-person148" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the 3 d, made to prevent throwing squibs, serpents, and other fireworks: for every offence Five Pounds, and any person permitting them to be thrown out of their houses, or aiding and assisting therein, Twenty Shillings; and For want of goods or chattles, to pay the penalty, to be committed to the house of correction for a month.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17601204-12-punish75" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-punish75" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601204-12-punish75" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601204-12-defend123 t17601204-12-punish75"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
