<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660702-27">
               <interp inst="t17660702-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660702-27" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660702-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660702"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660702-27" type="date" value="17660702"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660702-27-off151-c204" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-27-defend255 t17660702-27-off151 t17660702-27-verdict154"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176607020023"></xptr>361. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660702-27-defend255" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Bolton 
                  <interp inst="t17660702-27-defend255" type="surname" value="Bolton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-27-defend255" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-27-defend255" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17660702-27-off151" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660702-27-off151" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-27-off151" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one hundred weight of cam wood, value 40 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17660702-27-victim257" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Crosier 
                  <interp inst="t17660702-27-victim257" type="surname" value="Crosier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-27-victim257" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-27-victim257" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17660702-27-viclabel152" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-27-victim257 t17660702-27-viclabel152"></join>; and 
               
                  <persName id="t17660702-27-victim259" type="victimName">
                     Joseph 
                     Waugh 
                  <interp inst="t17660702-27-victim259" type="surname" value="Waugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-27-victim259" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-27-victim259" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            . It was laid over again to be the property of persons unknown, <rs id="t17660702-27-cd153" type="crimeDate">June 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-27-off151 t17660702-27-cd153"></join>. +</p>
               <p>Jos. Hargrave. On the 10th of last month I met the prisoner with two sticks of cam, or red wood, on his shoulder in Cloak lane, about six o'clock in the morning; he threw them down at a smith's shop; he seeing me go in at one door, he went out at the other, and left them there. The smith's man, named Tull, went with me after him; he ran so fast we could not overtake him: (one of the pieces produced in court.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-27-person260">
                  William 
                  Tull 
               <interp inst="t17660702-27-person260" type="surname" value="Tull"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-27-person260" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-27-person260" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Tremble, a smith; I was opening the shop-windows on the 10th of June in the morning, about six o'clock; the prisoner came and asked leave to leave the two sticks, and he would fetch them in a day or two, and satisfy me for my trouble. When he came with them, Mr. Hargrave followed him into the shop. Whether the prisoner saw him or not, I cannot say, but he went out at the passage door, and up Walbrook, and was soon out of sight.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he run or walk?</p>
               <p>Tull. I did not see him; Mr. Hargrave ordered me to keep the wood, and he would go and acquaint his master of it; his master came and looked at it, and ordered me not to let it go.</p>
               <p>Q. to Hargrave. Who is your master?</p>
               <p>Hargrave. Mr. Crosier is.</p>
               <p>Tull. The prisoner called for it about ten or eleven days after, towards ten o'clock at night; as soon as he set eyes on me, he held out his hand to give me sixpence for my trouble. I told him I should not take it; I was ordered to charge a constable. My master being constable, I said to him, you know what you have to do. Master took him in custody, and ordered me to aid and assist: master ordered his kinsman to go and tell Mr. Crosier the man was come for the wood: the prisoner hearing Mr. Crosier's name, he began to wriggle; (I had hold of him) I said he should not get away; then he offered to kick up my heels, but we secured him: we asked him how he came by it; he was a considerable time before he gave any answer, and when he did, he said he bought it for about 4 s. he was ordered to the Counter, and the next morning he was carried to the Mansion-house; there he said he found it in the mud by the shore-side, on the other side the water.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-27-person261">
                  Thomas 
                  Tremble 
               <interp inst="t17660702-27-person261" type="surname" value="Tremble"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-27-person261" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-27-person261" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a blacksmith; I pulled out my short staff, being constable, and ordered my man to assist me; the prisoner struggled a good deal with my man. I sent word to Mr. Crosier, that the man was come for the wood, and I had got him. I asked the prisoner how he came by the wood; he said he bought it of a sailor for about 4 s. but did not know where to find him. I was at the Mansion-house when he was there; he said there he found the wood in the mud, in the river Thames, and that he imagined it fell from a wharf, or from on board some vessel.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-27-person262">
                  Charles 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17660702-27-person262" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-27-person262" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-27-person262" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a wharsinger; the prisoner worked for me several months; Mr. Crosier sent me word, there had been a man taken up, and such wood stopped.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is Mr. Crosier's partner?</p>
               <p>Harris. Mr. Waugh is his partner; they had some of this wood at our wharf. I examined the prisoner; he said he found it on the way at low-water-mark, one stick lately, and the other two or three months before.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know whose property this piece is here produced?</p>
               <p>Harris. I do not know; we have many gentlemen's property in our yard of the same sort of wood, it is very valuable wood.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you weigh this sort of wood when you take it in?</p>
               <p>Harris. We do; we had weighed in for Mess. Crosier and Co. red wood, and in weighing it again, we found a deficiency of above two hundred weight. We have every gentleman's property put in different parcels; we always keep a particular account at coming in and going out.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-27-person263">
                  William 
                  Maurel 
               <interp inst="t17660702-27-person263" type="surname" value="Maurel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-27-person263" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-27-person263" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am clerk to Mr. Harris; after Bolton was taken, I was desired to order Mess. Crosier and Co.'s wood to be weighed off; and casting up the weight, there was between two and three hundred weight deficient.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Crosier. What is an hundred weight of this wood worth?</p>
               <p>Mr. Crosier. It is worth above 40 s.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>We are ordered to pile the wood up in different piles and different parcels, and very often a stick is left unpiled, and now and then all the loose sticks are picked up, and carried up into a lost; I have worked on this wharf eight or nine months; I was as faithful and as handy as any one there; I was used to do work within and without; while I was there I happened to pick up some wood; I would say, it deserves a pint of beer. I have been told they did not know whether I should have a pint or not: after that, I found some in the water; I got a brush, and cleaned them, and put them under my bed; having found no encouragement<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176607020024"></xptr> for picking them up, I thought I might as well do it as other people.</p>
               <p>He called 
               <persName id="t17660702-27-person264">
                  James 
                  Woredall 
               <interp inst="t17660702-27-person264" type="surname" value="Woredall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-27-person264" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-27-person264" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17660702-27-person265">
                  William 
                  Hodges 
               <interp inst="t17660702-27-person265" type="surname" value="Hodges"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-27-person265" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-27-person265" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17660702-27-person266">
                  Brown 
                  Maning 
               <interp inst="t17660702-27-person266" type="surname" value="Maning"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-27-person266" type="given" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-27-person266" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17660702-27-person267">
                  Henry 
                  Wilson 
               <interp inst="t17660702-27-person267" type="surname" value="Wilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-27-person267" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-27-person267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who gave him a good character; he also called 
               <persName id="t17660702-27-person268">
                  John Anthony 
                  Horner 
               <interp inst="t17660702-27-person268" type="surname" value="Horner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-27-person268" type="given" value="John Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-27-person268" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who said he knew nothing of him.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660702-27-verdict154" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660702-27-verdict154" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
