<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610506-21">
               <interp inst="t17610506-21" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610506-21" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610506-21" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610506"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610506-21" type="date" value="17610506"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610506-21-off112-c235" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-21-defend275 t17610506-21-off112 t17610506-21-verdict116"></join>
         
               <p>180. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610506-21-defend275" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Walley 
                  <interp inst="t17610506-21-defend275" type="surname" value="Walley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-21-defend275" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-21-defend275" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17610506-21-off112" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610506-21-off112" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-21-off112" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he, on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17610506-21-victim277" type="victimName">
                           David 
                           Supino 
                        <interp inst="t17610506-21-victim277" type="surname" value="Supino"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610506-21-victim277" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610506-21-victim277" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-21-off112 t17610506-21-victim277"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   feloniously did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and taking from his person one gold watch, value 7 l. one gold watch chain, value 21 s. one gold seal, value 10 s. and ten guineas in gold, the property of the said David, and against his will
            </rs>, <rs id="t17610506-21-cd113" type="crimeDate">December 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-21-off112 t17610506-21-cd113"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-21-person278">
                  David 
                  Supino 
               <interp inst="t17610506-21-person278" type="surname" value="Supino"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-21-person278" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-21-person278" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going to Stanmore in a post-chaise; a little beyond Hampstead, between <placeName id="t17610506-21-crimeloc114">Hampstead</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17610506-21-crimeloc114" type="placeName" value="Hampstead"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610506-21-crimeloc114" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-21-off112 t17610506-21-crimeloc114"></join> and <placeName id="t17610506-21-crimeloc115">Hendon</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17610506-21-crimeloc115" type="placeName" value="Hendon"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610506-21-crimeloc115" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-21-off112 t17610506-21-crimeloc115"></join>, between the hours of six and eight, on Christmas evening, a person stopped the chaise, it was very dark, and small rain, I cannot tell who that person was, I saw but one man.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you alone?</p>
               <p>Supino. There was Mr. 
               <persName id="t17610506-21-person279">
                  Jacob Henriques
                   de Souza
               <interp inst="t17610506-21-person279" type="surname" value="de Souza"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-21-person279" type="given" value="Jacob Henriques"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-21-person279" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             with me in the same chaise, the man said, gentleman your watches and money; upon which, we gave him our watches, and both gave him some money. I gave him about 15 l. in money, but it is not said so much in the indictment. The person was very civil to us, and said, I wish you a good night, I heard nothing more of him then. After that, Mr. Fielding wrote me a card on the 29th of April, desiring my attendance there as soon as I could after the receipt of it; upon which I went to him, and he<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176105060034"></xptr> told me there was information given him, of a gold watch and chain which had been stolen, and he believed it to be mine, that I had been robbed of. He said, he had not seen it himself, but it was at Mr. Townsend's, a silver-smith in the Borough. I went there, and found the watch to be mine, but no chain; I knew the watch, by the name and number. Mr. Fielding desired to see the watch, it was carried to him.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Supino. I never saw the prisoner before I saw him this night. I cannot say who it was robbed me.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you a Jew?</p>
               <p>Supino. I am.</p>
               <p>Jacob Henriques de Souza. I was in the post-chaise along with Mr. 
               <persName id="t17610506-21-person280">
                  David 
                  Supino 
               <interp inst="t17610506-21-person280" type="surname" value="Supino"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-21-person280" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-21-person280" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , we were going to Stanmore; a little beyond Hampstead we were attacked by a man on horseback, I do not know who he was, we delivered our watches and money to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you heard Mr. Supino describe how it was?</p>
               <p>Henriques de Souza. I have, it was done in the same manner.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you lose?</p>
               <p>Henriques de Souza. A metal watch, and about 7 l. in money.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know how many men attacked you?</p>
               <p>Henriques de Souza. I believe only one.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he make use of any threatnings?</p>
               <p>Henriques de Souza. I do not remember he did, he only desired our money and watches, and used us with good manners; it was so dark we could not distinguish his person at all. Justice Fielding sent me a card to appear, but I never saw the prisoner before now.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. Did not the justice appoint a particular time for you to come when the prisoner would be before him.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No, he did not appoint any particular time at all.</p>
               <p>Henriques de Souza. The first time we went was on a Wednesday; the second time he appointed us to come, was on the Friday. He said, he could not shew us the person, because he was not well.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was very very ill then.</p>
               <p>Henriques de Souza. I saw my watch at Mr. Fielding's, in the hands of one Stockdale a pawnbroker, it was the same that I was robbed of that night.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-21-person281">
                  Ann 
                  Limpsey 
               <interp inst="t17610506-21-person281" type="surname" value="Limpsey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-21-person281" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-21-person281" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . All I know is, the gentleman ( meaning the prisoner) said to me, he was distressed for money.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you acquainted with him?</p>
               <p>A. Limpsey. He is a stranger to me, only he lodged in the house that I did; then he desired me to sell a watch for him. [A gold watch produced, she looked at it.] Really I cannot take my oath whether it be or be not the same; by the weight of it, I should think it may be the watch; I sold it to this gentlewoman for nine guineas, ( pointing to Mrs. Townsend.) There was a great deal of it then, there was a gold chain, and some seals to it.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. Look at that watch, do you know it?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. This is the very watch that I was robbed of that night.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Townsend. I live in the Borough of Southwark.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you a husband?</p>
               <p>Townsend. I have; about the fourth of March, the last witness brought me a watch to sell; I bought it of her for nine guineas.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know that watch again when you see it?</p>
               <p>Townsend. I believe that is it that is here produced; the gentleman, the prosecutor, came and owned it.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Townsend. I never saw him in my life before now, the woman that brought it said, it was a seafaring gentleman that owned it, and he was distressed for want of money, and I understood her, he was in the King's-bench.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there a chain to it when you bought it?</p>
               <p>Townsend. There was; that was taken from the watch the day it was bought; we put by that as old gold, it not being good enough to do up again.</p>
               <p>Mr. Stockdale. [Produced another watch.] This watch I took in of the prisoner at the bar.</p>
               <p>Henriques de Souza. This is my property, the same I lost that night.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was going to my masters, French and Bowman, for them to set me to work. I met in the Haymarket, one 
               <persName id="t17610506-21-person282">
                  Daniel 
                  Carr 
               <interp inst="t17610506-21-person282" type="surname" value="Carr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-21-person282" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-21-person282" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he said, Joseph, I should take it as a favour, if you will come and drink a pint of beer along with me. We went in at the black-horse in Coventry-street, and had a pint of beer; he said, I am in a little distress, if you will oblige me in disposing<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176105060035"></xptr> of a couple of watches for me. I said, I did not chuse to be concerned with watches, for my character was never stained before; he said, he would give me a crown. I took the watches of him, and told him I would if possible, but I could not dispose of them myself, but would get one to dispose of them for me, which was a woman that lived in the same place where I did the woman that is here. Accordingly, I gave her that watch, not the same day, but three, four, five or six days after. Then he said, he wished I would get a couple of guineas on the other; I said, I do not doubt but I can. Then I went away to the pawnbroker's, and got a couple of guineas upon it. After that, he said to me, have you disposed of the other watch? I said no; I do not know how to go about it. Then I gave it to this woman, and she disposed of it for nine guineas, and gave me the money, and I gave it to Carr. When I was examined before Justice Fielding, I told him the same, to the best of my knowledge; but Carr being apprehensive of my being taken, I imagine he is gone out of the way, and I do not know the place of his residence, so he has left me in the lurch, which is a cruel thing, I will not tell a lie, I have no witnesses.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610506-21-verdict116" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610506-21-verdict116" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17610506-21-punish117" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610506-21-punish117" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-21-defend275 t17610506-21-punish117"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
