<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660702-48">
               <interp inst="t17660702-48" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660702-48" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660702-48" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660702"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660702-48" type="date" value="17660702"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660702-48-off254-c328" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-48-defend421 t17660702-48-off254 t17660702-48-verdict257"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660702-48-off258-c328" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-48-defend421 t17660702-48-off258 t17660702-48-verdict257"></join>
         
               <p>386. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17660702-48-defend421" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Thomas 
                     Wise 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17660702-48-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-48-defend421 t17660702-48-alias-3"></join>Young</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-defend421" type="surname" value="Wise"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-defend421" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-defend421" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17660702-48-off254" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-off254" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-off254" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing a black gelding, value 10 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17660702-48-victim424" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Starr 
                  <interp inst="t17660702-48-victim424" type="surname" value="Starr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-victim424" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-victim424" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17660702-48-cd255" type="crimeDate">May 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-48-off254 t17660702-48-cd255"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-48-off258 t17660702-48-cd255"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-48-person425">
                  John 
                  Starr 
               <interp inst="t17660702-48-person425" type="surname" value="Starr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person425" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person425" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lost a black gelding out of a field in the parish of <placeName id="t17660702-48-crimeloc256">Rumford in Essex</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17660702-48-crimeloc256" type="placeName" value="Rumford in Essex"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660702-48-crimeloc256" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-48-off254 t17660702-48-crimeloc256"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-48-off258 t17660702-48-crimeloc256"></join>; he had a white face, and a white foot behind; he was turned into the field between six and seven over night, and in the morning between one and two he was missing; Mr. Howard found him the same day, and told me of it, in the stable of Mr. Bennet in Liquorpond-street, there I saw him; Mr. Howard had taken the prisoner before I got there.</p>
               <p>Q. What countryman is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Starr. I think they say he comes out of Yorkshire.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-48-person426">
                  Thomas 
                  Twyford 
               <interp inst="t17660702-48-person426" type="surname" value="Twyford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person426" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person426" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Starr, I know the horse to be my master's property; he was missed on the 16th of May, between one and two in the morning.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-48-person427">
                  Richard 
                  Bennet 
               <interp inst="t17660702-48-person427" type="surname" value="Bennet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person427" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person427" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner came to my house in Liquorpond-street about a month before this time, and brought two horses and sold them; he behaved honest and just: he used to be to and fro; I never heard any ill of his character in the world; he was recommended to my house by a neighbour, he lodged, and eat and drank at my house about a month; I did not see him bring these two last horses in, I was in bed at the time, but I saw them both in the stable, and the prisoner cleaning, I think, the bay horse, about nine o'clock; I was desired to buy the bay horse for Mr. Cotterel; I said, I suppose that horse is for sale; he would set no price upon him.</p>
               <p>Q. We are enquiring about the black horse; did that belong to you, or any of your customers?</p>
               <p>Bennet. No, it did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-48-person428">
                  Richard 
                  Bennet 
               <interp inst="t17660702-48-person428" type="surname" value="Bennet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person428" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person428" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the younger. The prisoner brought two horses to my uncle's the 16th of May, about three in the morning, he called me up; I gave him the key, but did not see the horses then, but I saw them in the stable about five minutes after; there were a bay one and a black one; there was another man with him, I did not see his face, his hat was slapped; the prisoner said afterwards the man was one of his countrymen, and was gone home; Mr. Starr came the same day and owned the black one, and took him away on the Monday following.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I came from Reading in Berkshire the night before in the machine, and was going to Chatham in a Gravesend hoy; I met one Brown by London-bridge, I told him where I was going, the tide did not serve; he asked me to go home with him, and said I might ride home with him if I would stay till between eleven and twelve; I went with him to the house of Mr. Bennet, he being an acquaintance of mine; that was the man with a slapped hat, he hearing I was before the Justice, so he got off.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-48-person429">
                  George 
                  Fell 
               <interp inst="t17660702-48-person429" type="surname" value="Fell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person429" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person429" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner is my countryman from Yorkshire, I have known him seven or eight years, he always bore a good character.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176607020035"></xptr>Q. Have you been acquainted with him lately?</p>
               <p>Fell. I have not seen him these six years before.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660702-48-verdict257" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-verdict257" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>(M.) He was a second time indicted for <rs id="t17660702-48-off258" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-off258" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-off258" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing a bay gelding, value 10 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17660702-48-victim431" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Howard 
                  <interp inst="t17660702-48-victim431" type="surname" value="Howard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-victim431" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-victim431" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17660702-48-cd259" type="crimeDate">May 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-48-off254 t17660702-48-cd259"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-48-off258 t17660702-48-cd259"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-48-person432">
                  Thomas 
                  Howard 
               <interp inst="t17660702-48-person432" type="surname" value="Howard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person432" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person432" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 16th of May a bay gelding of mine was missing out of a field in the parish of <placeName id="t17660702-48-crimeloc260">North-Ockenden in Essex</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17660702-48-crimeloc260" type="placeName" value="North-Ockenden in Essex"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660702-48-crimeloc260" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-48-off254 t17660702-48-crimeloc260"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-48-off258 t17660702-48-crimeloc260"></join>, about four in the morning; I came that same day to London, and got intelligence a man had got two horses at Mr. Bennet's in Liquorpond-street. I went there and found my gelding in the stable; the prisoner was standing at the door, and upon hearing me enquire of a woman whether that was the man that belonged to the horses in the stable, he drew himself backwards into the house; I went in and took him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know him before?</p>
               <p>Howard. No, I did not; he was taken before the Justice: there he said the horses were brought to him in Kent-street, and that he was in bed at the time; I turned the horse out the night before, about nine o'clock.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-48-person433">
                  Richard 
                  Bennet 
               <interp inst="t17660702-48-person433" type="surname" value="Bennet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person433" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person433" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a public-house in Liquorpond-street; my boy told me the prisoner came to my house about three in the morning, I was in bed at the time; Mr. Cotterel came to my bed-side about four or five, and desired that I would buy this bay gelding of the prisoner for him; he had seen him, and thought him a useful horse. I went into the stable about nine, there was the prisoner and two horses; the prosecutor's horse. I found to be what Cotterel had described to me; I said to the prisoner, That is a good likely sort of a horse, I suppose he is upon sale; no, said the prisoner, he is not; I said, If you have a mind to sell him, I can help you to a customer; he would put no price upon him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say the horse was his property?</p>
               <p>Bennet. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he expected the owner to come for him?</p>
               <p>Bennet. No; the prisoner had been at my house about a month once before; he eat and drank, and brought two horses then, and sold them; he behaved as civilly as any man in England, and paid me honestly.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-48-person434">
                  Richard 
                  Bennet 
               <interp inst="t17660702-48-person434" type="surname" value="Bennet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person434" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person434" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the younger. Mr. Bennet is my uncle; I shall be fourteen years of age the 2d of September; the prisoner called me up about three o'clock that morning; I let him in at that time; I saw no horse; I gave him the key; I went into the stable afterwards, there was he and another man, and two horses; the prisoner was loosening the girth of the bay horse.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-48-person435">
                  William 
                  Cotterel 
               <interp inst="t17660702-48-person435" type="surname" value="Cotterel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person435" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person435" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had some hogs in Smithfield-market; I went to Mr. Bennet's and saw this bay horse in his stable; I liked him; I went to Mr. Bennet and asked him who those horses belonged to; he said to a man that had been there before, which he believed came from Yorkshire; I desired him to buy the bay one for me; after that I heard the ostler at the Bear and Ragged Staff in Smithfield, say, there is a horse marked so and so, do not buy him, he is a stolen horse. The farmer that owns the horse, had just told him he had lost such a one; he shewed me the farmer, I called him back, and told him where I had seen such a one, then I took him to Mr. Bennet's.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-48-person436">
                  Thomas 
                  Ryland 
               <interp inst="t17660702-48-person436" type="surname" value="Ryland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person436" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person436" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Cotterel having told me he had seen such a horse at the White-hart in Liquorpond-street, I went there with him; after that, the ostler was saying such a horse was a stolen horse; we told the prosecutor where we had seen such a one; we went with him to Mr. Bennet's; Mr. Cotterel asked Mr. Bennet if he had bought the horse; Mr. Bennet said no; the man says he is a useful horse, and he will not sell him, he'll keep him for his own use, he is a bit of a smugg (that is a smuggler.)</p>
               <p>Q. to Bennet. When the prisoner said he would not sell the horse, did he give you any reason why?</p>
               <p>Bennet. No, he said not a word more.</p>
               <p>The prisoner said nothing in his defence.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-48-person437">
                  Robert 
                  Theobald 
               <interp inst="t17660702-48-person437" type="surname" value="Theobald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person437" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person437" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner between two and three years, he has a very good character as any man in England; I never knew a man of a better character dealing in horses.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-48-person438">
                  John 
                  Hutton 
               <interp inst="t17660702-48-person438" type="surname" value="Hutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person438" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person438" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have bought horses of him, and sold horses to him; he is an honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-48-person439">
                  Anne 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17660702-48-person439" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person439" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person439" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him three years and a half, he is an honest man as far as I know.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-48-person440">
                  John 
                  Truman 
               <interp inst="t17660702-48-person440" type="surname" value="Truman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person440" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person440" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him three years, he is a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-48-person441">
                  George 
                  Bulmore 
               <interp inst="t17660702-48-person441" type="surname" value="Bulmore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person441" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person441" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him between five and six years, he is a very honest man as far as ever I saw; he lived at Greenwich when I knew him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-48-person442">
                  Thomas 
                  Jolley 
               <interp inst="t17660702-48-person442" type="surname" value="Jolley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person442" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-person442" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him from his infancy, he has a good character, and comes of creditable parents.</p>
               <p>Q. to Bennet. If this horse had not been owned; who should you have expected to pay for his keeping?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176607020036"></xptr>Bennet. I should have looked upon the man that brought him to pay me, that is the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660702-48-verdict261" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-verdict261" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17660702-48-punish262" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660702-48-punish262" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-48-defend421 t17660702-48-punish262"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
